<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Computer Science -- Computation and Language (cs.CL) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2023-12-17T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Computer Science -- Computation and Language</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09265" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09299" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09300" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09304" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09366" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09390" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09411" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09424" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09430" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09451" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09457" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09463" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09469" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09494" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09508" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09536" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09541" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09542" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09545" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09571" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09572" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09582" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09583" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09601" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09625" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09670" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09718" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09736" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09781" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09785" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09801" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09806" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09818" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09890" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09895" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09907" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09917" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09932" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09966" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09979" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09993" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.10003" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.10007" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.01528" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.16230" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.14160" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.18396" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2306.04308" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2307.14132" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2308.10822" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.07597" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.03985" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.08903" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.13859" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.14360" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.15539" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.16218" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.18333" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.05741" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.11844" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.15786" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.04103" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.07559" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08078" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08274" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08282" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08688" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09211" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09265">
<title>Acoustic models of Brazilian Portuguese Speech based on Neural Transformers. (arXiv:2312.09265v1 [cs.SD])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09265</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;An acoustic model, trained on a significant amount of unlabeled data,
consists of a self-supervised learned speech representation useful for solving
downstream tasks, perhaps after a fine-tuning of the model in the respective
downstream task. In this work, we build an acoustic model of Brazilian
Portuguese Speech through a Transformer neural network. This model was
pretrained on more than $800$ hours of Brazilian Portuguese Speech, using a
combination of pretraining techniques. Using a labeled dataset collected for
the detection of respiratory insufficiency in Brazilian Portuguese speakers, we
fine-tune the pretrained Transformer neural network on the following tasks:
respiratory insufficiency detection, gender recognition and age group
classification. We compare the performance of pretrained Transformers on these
tasks with that of Transformers without previous pretraining, noting a
significant improvement. In particular, the performance of respiratory
insufficiency detection obtains the best reported results so far, indicating
this kind of acoustic model as a promising tool for speech-as-biomarker
approach. Moreover, the performance of gender recognition is comparable to the
state of the art models in English.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gauy_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marcelo Matheus Gauy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Finger_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marcelo Finger&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09299">
<title>Weight subcloning: direct initialization of transformers using larger pretrained ones. (arXiv:2312.09299v1 [cs.LG])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09299</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Training large transformer models from scratch for a target task requires
lots of data and is computationally demanding. The usual practice of transfer
learning overcomes this challenge by initializing the model with weights of a
pretrained model of the same size and specification to increase the convergence
and training speed. However, what if no pretrained model of the required size
is available? In this paper, we introduce a simple yet effective technique to
transfer the knowledge of a pretrained model to smaller variants. Our approach
called weight subcloning expedites the training of scaled-down transformers by
initializing their weights from larger pretrained models.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weight subcloning involves an operation on the pretrained model to obtain the
equivalent initialized scaled-down model. It consists of two key steps: first,
we introduce neuron importance ranking to decrease the embedding dimension per
layer in the pretrained model. Then, we remove blocks from the transformer
model to match the number of layers in the scaled-down network. The result is a
network ready to undergo training, which gains significant improvements in
training speed compared to random initialization. For instance, we achieve 4x
faster training for vision transformers in image classification and language
models designed for next token prediction.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Samragh_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mohammad Samragh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Farajtabar_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mehrdad Farajtabar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Mehta_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sachin Mehta&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Vemulapalli_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Raviteja Vemulapalli&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Faghri_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fartash Faghri&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Naik_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Devang Naik&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tuzel_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Oncel Tuzel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Rastegari_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mohammad Rastegari&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09300">
<title>Self-Evaluation Improves Selective Generation in Large Language Models. (arXiv:2312.09300v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09300</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Safe deployment of large language models (LLMs) may benefit from a reliable
method for assessing their generated content to determine when to abstain or to
selectively generate. While likelihood-based metrics such as perplexity are
widely employed, recent research has demonstrated the limitations of using
sequence-level probability estimates given by LLMs as reliable indicators of
generation quality. Conversely, LLMs have demonstrated strong calibration at
the token level, particularly when it comes to choosing correct answers in
multiple-choice questions or evaluating true/false statements. In this work, we
reformulate open-ended generation tasks into token-level prediction tasks, and
leverage LLMs&apos; superior calibration at the token level. We instruct an LLM to
self-evaluate its answers, employing either a multi-way comparison or a
point-wise evaluation approach, with the option to include a ``None of the
above&apos;&apos; option to express the model&apos;s uncertainty explicitly. We benchmark a
range of scoring methods based on self-evaluation and evaluate their
performance in selective generation using TruthfulQA and TL;DR. Through
experiments with PaLM-2 and GPT-3, we demonstrate that self-evaluation based
scores not only improve accuracy, but also correlate better with the overall
quality of generated content.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ren_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jie Ren&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhao_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yao Zhao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Vu_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tu Vu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Peter J. Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lakshminarayanan_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Balaji Lakshminarayanan&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09304">
<title>Well-calibrated Confidence Measures for Multi-label Text Classification with a Large Number of Labels. (arXiv:2312.09304v1 [cs.LG])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09304</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We extend our previous work on Inductive Conformal Prediction (ICP) for
multi-label text classification and present a novel approach for addressing the
computational inefficiency of the Label Powerset (LP) ICP, arrising when
dealing with a high number of unique labels. We present experimental results
using the original and the proposed efficient LP-ICP on two English and one
Czech language data-sets. Specifically, we apply the LP-ICP on three deep
Artificial Neural Network (ANN) classifiers of two types: one based on
contextualised (bert) and two on non-contextualised (word2vec) word-embeddings.
In the LP-ICP setting we assign nonconformity scores to label-sets from which
the corresponding p-values and prediction-sets are determined. Our approach
deals with the increased computational burden of LP by eliminating from
consideration a significant number of label-sets that will surely have p-values
below the specified significance level. This reduces dramatically the
computational complexity of the approach while fully respecting the standard CP
guarantees. Our experimental results show that the contextualised-based
classifier surpasses the non-contextualised-based ones and obtains
state-of-the-art performance for all data-sets examined. The good performance
of the underlying classifiers is carried on to their ICP counterparts without
any significant accuracy loss, but with the added benefits of ICP, i.e. the
confidence information encapsulated in the prediction sets. We experimentally
demonstrate that the resulting prediction sets can be tight enough to be
practically useful even though the set of all possible label-sets contains more
than $1e+16$ combinations. Additionally, the empirical error rates of the
obtained prediction-sets confirm that our outputs are well-calibrated.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Maltoudoglou_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lysimachos Maltoudoglou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Paisios_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andreas Paisios&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lenc_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ladislav Lenc&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Martinek_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ji&amp;#x159;&amp;#xed; Mart&amp;#xed;nek&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kral_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pavel Kr&amp;#xe1;l&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Papadopoulos_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Harris Papadopoulos&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09366">
<title>Arabic Mini-ClimateGPT : A Climate Change and Sustainability Tailored Arabic LLM. (arXiv:2312.09366v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09366</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Climate change is one of the most significant challenges we face together as
a society. Creating awareness and educating policy makers the wide-ranging
impact of climate change is an essential step towards a sustainable future.
Recently, Large Language Models (LLMs) like ChatGPT and Bard have shown
impressive conversational abilities and excel in a wide variety of NLP tasks.
While these models are close-source, recently alternative open-source LLMs such
as Stanford Alpaca and Vicuna have shown promising results. However, these
open-source models are not specifically tailored for climate related domain
specific information and also struggle to generate meaningful responses in
other languages such as, Arabic. To this end, we propose a light-weight Arabic
Mini-ClimateGPT that is built on an open-source LLM and is specifically
fine-tuned on a conversational-style instruction tuning curated Arabic dataset
Clima500-Instruct with over 500k instructions about climate change and
sustainability. Further, our model also utilizes a vector embedding based
retrieval mechanism during inference. We validate our proposed model through
quantitative and qualitative evaluations on climate-related queries. Our model
surpasses the baseline LLM in 88.3% of cases during ChatGPT-based evaluation.
Furthermore, our human expert evaluation reveals an 81.6% preference for our
model&apos;s responses over multiple popular open-source models. Our open-source
demos, code-base and models are available here
https://github.com/mbzuai-oryx/ClimateGPT.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Mullappilly_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sahal Shaji Mullappilly&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shaker_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Abdelrahman Shaker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Thawakar_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Omkar Thawakar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cholakkal_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hisham Cholakkal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Anwer_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rao Muhammad Anwer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Khan_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Salman Khan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Khan_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fahad Shahbaz Khan&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09390">
<title>Weak-to-Strong Generalization: Eliciting Strong Capabilities With Weak Supervision. (arXiv:2312.09390v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09390</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Widely used alignment techniques, such as reinforcement learning from human
feedback (RLHF), rely on the ability of humans to supervise model behavior -
for example, to evaluate whether a model faithfully followed instructions or
generated safe outputs. However, future superhuman models will behave in
complex ways too difficult for humans to reliably evaluate; humans will only be
able to weakly supervise superhuman models. We study an analogy to this
problem: can weak model supervision elicit the full capabilities of a much
stronger model? We test this using a range of pretrained language models in the
GPT-4 family on natural language processing (NLP), chess, and reward modeling
tasks. We find that when we naively finetune strong pretrained models on labels
generated by a weak model, they consistently perform better than their weak
supervisors, a phenomenon we call weak-to-strong generalization. However, we
are still far from recovering the full capabilities of strong models with naive
finetuning alone, suggesting that techniques like RLHF may scale poorly to
superhuman models without further work. We find that simple methods can often
significantly improve weak-to-strong generalization: for example, when
finetuning GPT-4 with a GPT-2-level supervisor and an auxiliary confidence
loss, we can recover close to GPT-3.5-level performance on NLP tasks. Our
results suggest that it is feasible to make empirical progress today on a
fundamental challenge of aligning superhuman models.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Burns_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Collin Burns&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Izmailov_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pavel Izmailov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kirchner_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jan Hendrik Kirchner&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Baker_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bowen Baker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gao_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Leo Gao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Aschenbrenner_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Leopold Aschenbrenner&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yining Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ecoffet_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Adrien Ecoffet&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Joglekar_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Manas Joglekar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Leike_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jan Leike&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sutskever_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ilya Sutskever&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jeff Wu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09411">
<title>OTOv3: Automatic Architecture-Agnostic Neural Network Training and Compression from Structured Pruning to Erasing Operators. (arXiv:2312.09411v1 [cs.LG])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09411</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Compressing a predefined deep neural network (DNN) into a compact sub-network
with competitive performance is crucial in the efficient machine learning
realm. This topic spans various techniques, from structured pruning to neural
architecture search, encompassing both pruning and erasing operators
perspectives. Despite advancements, existing methods suffers from complex,
multi-stage processes that demand substantial engineering and domain knowledge,
limiting their broader applications. We introduce the third-generation
Only-Train-Once (OTOv3), which first automatically trains and compresses a
general DNN through pruning and erasing operations, creating a compact and
competitive sub-network without the need of fine-tuning. OTOv3 simplifies and
automates the training and compression process, minimizes the engineering
efforts required from users. It offers key technological advancements: (i)
automatic search space construction for general DNNs based on dependency graph
analysis; (ii) Dual Half-Space Projected Gradient (DHSPG) and its enhanced
version with hierarchical search (H2SPG) to reliably solve (hierarchical)
structured sparsity problems and ensure sub-network validity; and (iii)
automated sub-network construction using solutions from DHSPG/H2SPG and
dependency graphs. Our empirical results demonstrate the efficacy of OTOv3
across various benchmarks in structured pruning and neural architecture search.
OTOv3 produces sub-networks that match or exceed the state-of-the-arts. The
source code will be available at https://github.com/tianyic/only_train_once.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tianyi Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ding_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tianyu Ding&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhu_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhihui Zhu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zeyu Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wu_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;HsiangTao Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zharkov_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ilya Zharkov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liang_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Luming Liang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09424">
<title>Open Domain Knowledge Extraction for Knowledge Graphs. (arXiv:2312.09424v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09424</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The quality of a knowledge graph directly impacts the quality of downstream
applications (e.g. the number of answerable questions using the graph). One
ongoing challenge when building a knowledge graph is to ensure completeness and
freshness of the graph&apos;s entities and facts. In this paper, we introduce ODKE,
a scalable and extensible framework that sources high-quality entities and
facts from open web at scale. ODKE utilizes a wide range of extraction models
and supports both streaming and batch processing at different latency. We
reflect on the challenges and design decisions made and share lessons learned
when building and deploying ODKE to grow an industry-scale open domain
knowledge graph.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Qian_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kun Qian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Belyi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Anton Belyi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wu_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fei Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Khorshidi_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Samira Khorshidi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Nikfarjam_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Azadeh Nikfarjam&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Khot_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rahul Khot&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yisi Sang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Luna_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Katherine Luna&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chu_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xianqi Chu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Choi_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Eric Choi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Govind_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yash Govind&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Seivwright_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chloe Seivwright&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sun_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yiwen Sun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Fakhry_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ahmed Fakhry&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Rekatsinas_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Theo Rekatsinas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ilyas_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ihab Ilyas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Qi_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaoguang Qi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yunyao Li&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09430">
<title>Deep Representation Learning for Open Vocabulary Electroencephalography-to-Text Decoding. (arXiv:2312.09430v1 [eess.SP])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09430</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Previous research has demonstrated the potential of using pre-trained
language models for decoding open vocabulary Electroencephalography (EEG)
signals captured through a non-invasive Brain-Computer Interface (BCI).
However, the impact of embedding EEG signals in the context of language models
and the effect of subjectivity, remain unexplored, leading to uncertainty about
the best approach to enhance decoding performance. Additionally, current
evaluation metrics used to assess decoding effectiveness are predominantly
syntactic and do not provide insights into the comprehensibility of the decoded
output for human understanding. We present an end-to-end deep learning
framework for non-invasive brain recordings that brings modern representational
learning approaches to neuroscience. Our proposal introduces the following
innovations: 1) an end-to-end deep learning architecture for open vocabulary
EEG decoding, incorporating a subject-dependent representation learning module
for raw EEG encoding, a BART language model, and a GPT-4 sentence refinement
module; 2) a more comprehensive sentence-level evaluation metric based on the
BERTScore; 3) an ablation study that analyses the contributions of each module
within our proposal, providing valuable insights for future research. We
evaluate our approach on two publicly available datasets, ZuCo v1.0 and v2.0,
comprising EEG recordings of 30 subjects engaged in natural reading tasks. Our
model achieves a BLEU-1 score of 42.75%, a ROUGE-1-F of 33.28%, and a
BERTScore-F of 53.86%, outperforming the previous state-of-the-art methods by
3.38%, 8.43%, and 6.31%, respectively.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Amrani_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hamza Amrani&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Micucci_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniela Micucci&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Napoletano_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Paolo Napoletano&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09451">
<title>MANTIS at #SMM4H 2023: Leveraging Hybrid and Ensemble Models for Detection of Social Anxiety Disorder on Reddit. (arXiv:2312.09451v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09451</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This paper presents our system employed for the Social Media Mining for
Health 2023 Shared Task 4: Binary classification of English Reddit posts
self-reporting a social anxiety disorder diagnosis. We systematically
investigate and contrast the efficacy of hybrid and ensemble models that
harness specialized medical domain-adapted transformers in conjunction with
BiLSTM neural networks. The evaluation results outline that our best performing
model obtained 89.31% F1 on the validation set and 83.76% F1 on the test set.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zanwar_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sourabh Zanwar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wiechmann_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniel Wiechmann&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Qiao_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yu Qiao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kerz_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Elma Kerz&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09457">
<title>Functional Analytics for Document Ordering for Curriculum Development and Comprehension. (arXiv:2312.09457v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09457</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We propose multiple techniques for automatic document order generation for
(1) curriculum development and for (2) creation of optimal reading order for
use in learning, training, and other content-sequencing applications. Such
techniques could potentially be used to improve comprehension, identify areas
that need expounding, generate curricula, and improve search engine results. We
advance two main techniques: The first uses document similarities through
various methods. The second uses entropy against the backdrop of topics
generated through Latent Dirichlet Allocation (LDA). In addition, we try the
same methods on the summarized documents and compare them against the results
obtained using the complete documents. Our results showed that while the
document orders for our control document sets (biographies, novels, and
Wikipedia articles) could not be predicted using our methods, our test
documents (textbooks, courses, journal papers, dissertations) provided more
reliability. We also demonstrated that summarized documents were good stand-ins
for the complete documents for the purposes of ordering.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Villanueva_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Arturo N. Villanueva Jr.&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Simske_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Steven J. Simske&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09463">
<title>Partial Rewriting for Multi-Stage ASR. (arXiv:2312.09463v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09463</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;For many streaming automatic speech recognition tasks, it is important to
provide timely intermediate streaming results, while refining a high quality
final result. This can be done using a multi-stage architecture, where a small
left-context only model creates streaming results and a larger left- and
right-context model produces a final result at the end. While this
significantly improves the quality of the final results without compromising
the streaming emission latency of the system, streaming results do not benefit
from the quality improvements. Here, we propose using a text manipulation
algorithm that merges the streaming outputs of both models. We improve the
quality of streaming results by around 10%, without altering the final results.
Our approach introduces no additional latency and reduces flickering. It is
also lightweight, does not require retraining the model, and it can be applied
to a wide variety of multi-stage architectures.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bruguier_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Antoine Bruguier&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Qiu_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;David Qiu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+He_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yanzhang He&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09469">
<title>Clinical Text Deduplication Practices for Efficient Pretraining and Improved Clinical Tasks. (arXiv:2312.09469v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09469</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Despite being a unique source of information on patients&apos; status and disease
progression, clinical notes are characterized by high levels of duplication and
information redundancy. In general domain text, it has been shown that
deduplication does not harm language model (LM) pretraining, thus helping
reduce the training cost. Although large LMs have proven to learn medical
knowledge, they still require specialized domain adaptation for improved
downstream clinical tasks. By leveraging large real-world clinical corpora, we
first provided a fine-grained characterization of duplicates stemming from
common writing practices and clinical relevancy. Second, we demonstrated that
deduplicating clinical text can help clinical LMs encode less redundant
information in a more efficient manner and do not harm classification tasks via
prompt-based learning.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Landi_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Isotta Landi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Alleva_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Eugenia Alleva&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Valentine_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alissa A. Valentine&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lepow_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lauren A. Lepow&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Charney_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alexander W. Charney&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09494">
<title>No-Skim: Towards Efficiency Robustness Evaluation on Skimming-based Language Models. (arXiv:2312.09494v1 [cs.CR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09494</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;To reduce the computation cost and the energy consumption in large language
models (LLM), skimming-based acceleration dynamically drops unimportant tokens
of the input sequence progressively along layers of the LLM while preserving
the tokens of semantic importance. However, our work for the first time reveals
the acceleration may be vulnerable to Denial-of-Service (DoS) attacks. In this
paper, we propose No-Skim, a general framework to help the owners of
skimming-based LLM to understand and measure the robustness of their
acceleration scheme. Specifically, our framework searches minimal and
unnoticeable perturbations at character-level and token-level to generate
adversarial inputs that sufficiently increase the remaining token ratio, thus
increasing the computation cost and energy consumption. We systematically
evaluate the vulnerability of the skimming acceleration in various LLM
architectures including BERT and RoBERTa on the GLUE benchmark. In the worst
case, the perturbation found by No-Skim substantially increases the running
cost of LLM by over 145% on average. Moreover, No-Skim extends the evaluation
framework to various scenarios, making the evaluation conductible with
different level of knowledge.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shengyao Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mi Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Pan_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xudong Pan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yang_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Min Yang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09508">
<title>IndicIRSuite: Multilingual Dataset and Neural Information Models for Indian Languages. (arXiv:2312.09508v1 [cs.IR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09508</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we introduce Neural Information Retrieval resources for 11
widely spoken Indian Languages (Assamese, Bengali, Gujarati, Hindi, Kannada,
Malayalam, Marathi, Oriya, Punjabi, Tamil, and Telugu) from two major Indian
language families (Indo-Aryan and Dravidian). These resources include (a)
INDIC-MARCO, a multilingual version of the MSMARCO dataset in 11 Indian
Languages created using Machine Translation, and (b) Indic-ColBERT, a
collection of 11 distinct Monolingual Neural Information Retrieval models, each
trained on one of the 11 languages in the INDIC-MARCO dataset. To the best of
our knowledge, IndicIRSuite is the first attempt at building large-scale Neural
Information Retrieval resources for a large number of Indian languages, and we
hope that it will help accelerate research in Neural IR for Indian Languages.
Experiments demonstrate that Indic-ColBERT achieves 47.47% improvement in the
MRR@10 score averaged over the INDIC-MARCO baselines for all 11 Indian
languages except Oriya, 12.26% improvement in the NDCG@10 score averaged over
the MIRACL Bengali and Hindi Language baselines, and 20% improvement in the
MRR@100 Score over the Mr.Tydi Bengali Language baseline. IndicIRSuite is
available at https://github.com/saifulhaq95/IndicIRSuite
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Haq_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Saiful Haq&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sharma_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ashutosh Sharma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bhattacharyya_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pushpak Bhattacharyya&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09536">
<title>Riveter: Measuring Power and Social Dynamics Between Entities. (arXiv:2312.09536v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09536</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Riveter provides a complete easy-to-use pipeline for analyzing verb
connotations associated with entities in text corpora. We prepopulate the
package with connotation frames of sentiment, power, and agency, which have
demonstrated usefulness for capturing social phenomena, such as gender bias, in
a broad range of corpora. For decades, lexical frameworks have been
foundational tools in computational social science, digital humanities, and
natural language processing, facilitating multifaceted analysis of text
corpora. But working with verb-centric lexica specifically requires natural
language processing skills, reducing their accessibility to other researchers.
By organizing the language processing pipeline, providing complete lexicon
scores and visualizations for all entities in a corpus, and providing
functionality for users to target specific research questions, Riveter greatly
improves the accessibility of verb lexica and can facilitate a broad range of
future research.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Antoniak_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Maria Antoniak&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Field_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Anjalie Field&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Mun_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jimin Mun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Walsh_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Melanie Walsh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Klein_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lauren F. Klein&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sap_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Maarten Sap&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09541">
<title>Picking the Underused Heads: A Network Pruning Perspective of Attention Head Selection for Fusing Dialogue Coreference Information. (arXiv:2312.09541v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09541</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The Transformer-based models with the multi-head self-attention mechanism are
widely used in natural language processing, and provide state-of-the-art
results. While the pre-trained language backbones are shown to implicitly
capture certain linguistic knowledge, explicitly incorporating structure-aware
features can bring about further improvement on the downstream tasks. However,
such enhancement often requires additional neural components and increases
training parameter size. In this work, we investigate the attention head
selection and manipulation strategy for feature injection from a network
pruning perspective, and conduct a case study on dialogue summarization. We
first rank attention heads in a Transformer-based summarizer with layer-wise
importance. We then select the underused heads through extensive analysis, and
inject structure-aware features by manipulating the selected heads.
Experimental results show that the importance-based head selection is effective
for feature injection, and dialogue summarization can be improved by
incorporating coreference information via head manipulation.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhengyuan Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nancy F. Chen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09542">
<title>Marathon: A Race Through the Realm of Long Context with Large Language Models. (arXiv:2312.09542v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09542</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Although there are currently many benchmarks available for evaluating the
long context understanding and reasoning capability of large language models,
with the expansion of the context window in these models, the existing long
context benchmarks are no longer sufficient for evaluating the long context
understanding and reasoning capability of large language models. In this paper,
we have developed a fresh long context evaluation benchmark, which we name it
Marathon in the form of multiple choice questions, inspired by benchmarks such
as MMLU, for assessing the long context comprehension capability of large
language models quickly, accurately, and objectively. We have evaluated several
of the latest and most popular large language models, as well as three recent
and effective long context optimization methods, on our benchmark. This
showcases the long context reasoning and comprehension capabilities of these
large language models and validates the effectiveness of these optimization
methods. Marathon is available at
https://huggingface.co/datasets/Lemoncoke/Marathon.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lei Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yunshui Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ziqiang Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+yang_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiaxi yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Junhao Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yang_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Min Yang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09545">
<title>GPT-4 Surpassing Human Performance in Linguistic Pragmatics. (arXiv:2312.09545v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09545</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;As Large Language Models (LLMs) become increasingly integrated into everyday
life, their capabilities to understand and emulate human cognition are under
steady examination. This study investigates the ability of LLMs to comprehend
and interpret linguistic pragmatics, an aspect of communication that considers
context and implied meanings. Using Grice&apos;s communication principles, LLMs and
human subjects (N=76) were evaluated based on their responses to various
dialogue-based tasks. The findings revealed the superior performance and speed
of LLMs, particularly GPT4, over human subjects in interpreting pragmatics.
GPT4 also demonstrated accuracy in the pre-testing of human-written samples,
indicating its potential in text analysis. In a comparative analysis of LLMs
using human individual and average scores, the models exhibited significant
chronological improvement. The models were ranked from lowest to highest score,
with GPT2 positioned at 78th place, GPT3 ranking at 23rd, Bard at 10th, GPT3.5
placing 5th, Best Human scoring 2nd, and GPT4 achieving the top spot. The
findings highlight the remarkable progress made in the development and
performance of these LLMs. Future studies should consider diverse subjects,
multiple languages, and other cognitive aspects to fully comprehend the
capabilities of LLMs. This research holds significant implications for the
development and application of AI-based models in communication-centered
sectors.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bojic_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ljubisa Bojic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kovacevic_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Predrag Kovacevic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cabarkapa_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Milan Cabarkapa&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09571">
<title>Extending Context Window of Large Language Models via Semantic Compression. (arXiv:2312.09571v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09571</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Transformer-based Large Language Models (LLMs) often impose limitations on
the length of the text input to ensure the generation of fluent and relevant
responses. This constraint restricts their applicability in scenarios involving
long texts. We propose a novel semantic compression method that enables
generalization to texts that are 6-8 times longer, without incurring
significant computational costs or requiring fine-tuning. Our proposed
framework draws inspiration from source coding in information theory and
employs a pre-trained model to reduce the semantic redundancy of long inputs
before passing them to the LLMs for downstream tasks. Experimental results
demonstrate that our method effectively extends the context window of LLMs
across a range of tasks including question answering, summarization, few-shot
learning, and information retrieval. Furthermore, the proposed semantic
compression method exhibits consistent fluency in text generation while
reducing the associated computational overhead.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Fei_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Weizhi Fei&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Niu_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xueyan Niu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhou_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pingyi Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hou_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lu Hou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bai_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bo Bai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Deng_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lei Deng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Han_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei Han&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09572">
<title>IR-UWB Radar-Based Contactless Silent Speech Recognition of Vowels, Consonants, Words, and Phrases. (arXiv:2312.09572v1 [eess.AS])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09572</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Several sensing techniques have been proposed for silent speech recognition
(SSR); however, many of these methods require invasive processes or sensor
attachment to the skin using adhesive tape or glue, rendering them unsuitable
for frequent use in daily life. By contrast, impulse radio ultra-wideband
(IR-UWB) radar can operate without physical contact with users&apos; articulators
and related body parts, offering several advantages for SSR. These advantages
include high range resolution, high penetrability, low power consumption,
robustness to external light or sound interference, and the ability to be
embedded in space-constrained handheld devices. This study demonstrated IR-UWB
radar-based contactless SSR using four types of speech stimuli (vowels,
consonants, words, and phrases). To achieve this, a novel speech feature
extraction algorithm specifically designed for IR-UWB radar-based SSR is
proposed. Each speech stimulus is recognized by applying a classification
algorithm to the extracted speech features. Two different algorithms,
multidimensional dynamic time warping (MD-DTW) and deep neural network-hidden
Markov model (DNN-HMM), were compared for the classification task.
Additionally, a favorable radar antenna position, either in front of the user&apos;s
lips or below the user&apos;s chin, was determined to achieve higher recognition
accuracy. Experimental results demonstrated the efficacy of the proposed speech
feature extraction algorithm combined with DNN-HMM for classifying vowels,
consonants, words, and phrases. Notably, this study represents the first
demonstration of phoneme-level SSR using contactless radar.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Lee_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sunghwa Lee&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Shin_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Younghoon Shin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Kim_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Myungjong Kim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Seo_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiwon Seo&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09582">
<title>Phoneme-aware Encoding for Prefix-tree-based Contextual ASR. (arXiv:2312.09582v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09582</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In speech recognition applications, it is important to recognize
context-specific rare words, such as proper nouns. Tree-constrained Pointer
Generator (TCPGen) has shown promise for this purpose, which efficiently biases
such words with a prefix tree. While the original TCPGen relies on
grapheme-based encoding, we propose extending it with phoneme-aware encoding to
better recognize words of unusual pronunciations. As TCPGen handles biasing
words as subword units, we propose obtaining subword-level phoneme-aware
encoding by using alignment between phonemes and subwords. Furthermore, we
propose injecting phoneme-level predictions from CTC into queries of TCPGen so
that the model better interprets the phoneme-aware encodings. We conducted ASR
experiments with TCPGen for RNN transducer. We observed that proposed
phoneme-aware encoding outperformed ordinary grapheme-based encoding on both
the English LibriSpeech and Japanese CSJ datasets, demonstrating the robustness
of our approach across linguistically diverse languages.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Futami_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hayato Futami&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tsunoo_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Emiru Tsunoo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kashiwagi_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yosuke Kashiwagi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ogawa_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hiroaki Ogawa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Arora_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Siddhant Arora&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Watanabe_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shinji Watanabe&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09583">
<title>Leveraging Language ID to Calculate Intermediate CTC Loss for Enhanced Code-Switching Speech Recognition. (arXiv:2312.09583v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09583</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In recent years, end-to-end speech recognition has emerged as a technology
that integrates the acoustic, pronunciation dictionary, and language model
components of the traditional Automatic Speech Recognition model. It is
possible to achieve human-like recognition without the need to build a
pronunciation dictionary in advance. However, due to the relative scarcity of
training data on code-switching, the performance of ASR models tends to degrade
drastically when encountering this phenomenon. Most past studies have
simplified the learning complexity of the model by splitting the code-switching
task into multiple tasks dealing with a single language and then learning the
domain-specific knowledge of each language separately. Therefore, in this
paper, we attempt to introduce language identification information into the
middle layer of the ASR model&apos;s encoder. We aim to generate acoustic features
that imply language distinctions in a more implicit way, reducing the model&apos;s
confusion when dealing with language switching.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yang_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tzu-Ting Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hsin-Wei Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Berlin Chen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09601">
<title>Binary Code Summarization: Benchmarking ChatGPT/GPT-4 and Other Large Language Models. (arXiv:2312.09601v1 [cs.CR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09601</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Binary code summarization, while invaluable for understanding code semantics,
is challenging due to its labor-intensive nature. This study delves into the
potential of large language models (LLMs) for binary code comprehension. To
this end, we present BinSum, a comprehensive benchmark and dataset of over 557K
binary functions and introduce a novel method for prompt synthesis and
optimization. To more accurately gauge LLM performance, we also propose a new
semantic similarity metric that surpasses traditional exact-match approaches.
Our extensive evaluation of prominent LLMs, including ChatGPT, GPT-4, Llama 2,
and Code Llama, reveals 10 pivotal insights. This evaluation generates 4
billion inference tokens, incurred a total expense of 11,418 US dollars and 873
NVIDIA A100 GPU hours. Our findings highlight both the transformative potential
of LLMs in this field and the challenges yet to be overcome.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jin_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xin Jin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Larson_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jonathan Larson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yang_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Weiwei Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lin_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhiqiang Lin&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09625">
<title>Weakly-Supervised 3D Visual Grounding based on Visual Linguistic Alignment. (arXiv:2312.09625v1 [cs.CV])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09625</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Learning to ground natural language queries to target objects or regions in
3D point clouds is quite essential for 3D scene understanding. Nevertheless,
existing 3D visual grounding approaches require a substantial number of
bounding box annotations for text queries, which is time-consuming and
labor-intensive to obtain. In this paper, we propose \textbf{3D-VLA}, a weakly
supervised approach for \textbf{3D} visual grounding based on \textbf{V}isual
\textbf{L}inguistic \textbf{A}lignment. Our 3D-VLA exploits the superior
ability of current large-scale vision-language models (VLMs) on aligning the
semantics between texts and 2D images, as well as the naturally existing
correspondences between 2D images and 3D point clouds, and thus implicitly
constructs correspondences between texts and 3D point clouds with no need for
fine-grained box annotations in the training procedure. During the inference
stage, the learned text-3D correspondence will help us ground the text queries
to the 3D target objects even without 2D images. To the best of our knowledge,
this is the first work to investigate 3D visual grounding in a weakly
supervised manner by involving large scale vision-language models, and
extensive experiments on ReferIt3D and ScanRefer datasets demonstrate that our
3D-VLA achieves comparable and even superior results over the fully supervised
methods.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xu_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaoxu Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yuan_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yitian Yuan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qiudan Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wu_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wenhui Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jie_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zequn Jie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ma_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lin Ma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xu Wang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09670">
<title>Probing Pretrained Language Models with Hierarchy Properties. (arXiv:2312.09670v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09670</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Since Pretrained Language Models (PLMs) are the cornerstone of the most
recent Information Retrieval (IR) models, the way they encode semantic
knowledge is particularly important. However, little attention has been given
to studying the PLMs&apos; capability to capture hierarchical semantic knowledge.
Traditionally, evaluating such knowledge encoded in PLMs relies on their
performance on a task-dependent evaluation approach based on proxy tasks, such
as hypernymy detection. Unfortunately, this approach potentially ignores other
implicit and complex taxonomic relations. In this work, we propose a
task-agnostic evaluation method able to evaluate to what extent PLMs can
capture complex taxonomy relations, such as ancestors and siblings. The
evaluation is based on intrinsic properties that capture the hierarchical
nature of taxonomies. Our experimental evaluation shows that the
lexico-semantic knowledge implicitly encoded in PLMs does not always capture
hierarchical relations. We further demonstrate that the proposed properties can
be injected into PLMs to improve their understanding of hierarchy. Through
evaluations on taxonomy reconstruction, hypernym discovery and reading
comprehension tasks, we show that the knowledge about hierarchy is moderately
but not systematically transferable across tasks.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lovon_Melgarejo_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jes&amp;#xfa;s Lov&amp;#xf3;n-Melgarejo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Moreno_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jose G. Moreno&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Besancon_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Romaric Besan&amp;#xe7;on&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ferret_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Olivier Ferret&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tamine_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lynda Tamine&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09718">
<title>Discovering Highly Influential Shortcut Reasoning: An Automated Template-Free Approach. (arXiv:2312.09718v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09718</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Shortcut reasoning is an irrational process of inference, which degrades the
robustness of an NLP model. While a number of previous work has tackled the
identification of shortcut reasoning, there are still two major limitations:
(i) a method for quantifying the severity of the discovered shortcut reasoning
is not provided; (ii) certain types of shortcut reasoning may be missed. To
address these issues, we propose a novel method for identifying shortcut
reasoning. The proposed method quantifies the severity of the shortcut
reasoning by leveraging out-of-distribution data and does not make any
assumptions about the type of tokens triggering the shortcut reasoning. Our
experiments on Natural Language Inference and Sentiment Analysis demonstrate
that our framework successfully discovers known and unknown shortcut reasoning
in the previous work.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Haraguchi_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daichi Haraguchi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shirai_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kiyoaki Shirai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Inoue_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Naoya Inoue&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kertkeidkachorn_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Natthawut Kertkeidkachorn&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09736">
<title>HEAR: Hearing Enhanced Audio Response for Video-grounded Dialogue. (arXiv:2312.09736v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09736</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Video-grounded Dialogue (VGD) aims to answer questions regarding a given
multi-modal input comprising video, audio, and dialogue history. Although there
have been numerous efforts in developing VGD systems to improve the quality of
their responses, existing systems are competent only to incorporate the
information in the video and text and tend to struggle in extracting the
necessary information from the audio when generating appropriate responses to
the question. The VGD system seems to be deaf, and thus, we coin this symptom
of current systems&apos; ignoring audio data as a deaf response. To overcome the
deaf response problem, Hearing Enhanced Audio Response (HEAR) framework is
proposed to perform sensible listening by selectively attending to audio
whenever the question requires it. The HEAR framework enhances the accuracy and
audibility of VGD systems in a model-agnostic manner. HEAR is validated on VGD
datasets (i.e., AVSD@DSTC7 and AVSD@DSTC8) and shows effectiveness with various
VGD systems.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yoon_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sunjae Yoon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kim_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dahyun Kim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yoon_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Eunseop Yoon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yoon_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hee Suk Yoon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kim_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Junyeong Kim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yoo_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chnag D. Yoo&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09781">
<title>GSQA: An End-to-End Model for Generative Spoken Question Answering. (arXiv:2312.09781v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09781</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In recent advancements in spoken question answering (QA), end-to-end models
have made significant strides. However, previous research has primarily focused
on extractive span selection. While this extractive-based approach is effective
when answers are present directly within the input, it falls short in
addressing abstractive questions, where answers are not directly extracted but
inferred from the given information. To bridge this gap, we introduce the first
end-to-end Generative Spoken Question Answering (GSQA) model that empowers the
system to engage in abstractive reasoning. The challenge in training our GSQA
model lies in the absence of a spoken abstractive QA dataset. We propose using
text models for initialization and leveraging the extractive QA dataset to
transfer knowledge from the text generative model to the spoken generative
model. Experimental results indicate that our model surpasses the previous
extractive model by 3% on extractive QA datasets. Furthermore, the GSQA model
has only been fine-tuned on the spoken extractive QA dataset. Despite not
having seen any spoken abstractive QA data, it can still closely match the
performance of the cascade model. In conclusion, our GSQA model shows the
potential to generalize to a broad spectrum of questions, thus further
expanding spoken question answering capabilities of abstractive QA. Our code is
available at
\href{https://voidful.github.io/GSQA}{https://voidful.github.io/GSQA}
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shih_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Min-Han Shih&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chung_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ho-Lam Chung&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Pai_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yu-Chi Pai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hsu_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ming-Hao Hsu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lin_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Guan-Ting Lin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shang-Wen Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lee_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hung-yi Lee&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09785">
<title>RJUA-QA: A Comprehensive QA Dataset for Urology. (arXiv:2312.09785v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09785</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We introduce RJUA-QA, a novel medical dataset for question answering (QA) and
reasoning with clinical evidence, contributing to bridge the gap between
general large language models (LLMs) and medical-specific LLM applications.
RJUA-QA is derived from realistic clinical scenarios and aims to facilitate
LLMs in generating reliable diagnostic and advice. The dataset contains 2,132
curated Question-Context-Answer pairs, corresponding about 25,000 diagnostic
records and clinical cases. The dataset covers 67 common urological disease
categories, where the disease coverage exceeds 97.6\% of the population seeking
medical services in urology. Each data instance in RJUA-QA comprises: (1) a
question mirroring real patient to inquiry about clinical symptoms and medical
conditions, (2) a context including comprehensive expert knowledge, serving as
a reference for medical examination and diagnosis, (3) a doctor response
offering the diagnostic conclusion and suggested examination guidance, (4) a
diagnosed clinical disease as the recommended diagnostic outcome, and (5)
clinical advice providing recommendations for medical examination. RJUA-QA is
the first medical QA dataset for clinical reasoning over the patient inquiries,
where expert-level knowledge and experience are required for yielding
diagnostic conclusions and medical examination advice. A comprehensive
evaluation is conducted to evaluate the performance of both medical-specific
and general LLMs on the RJUA-QA dataset.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lyu_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shiwei Lyu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chi_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chenfei Chi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cai_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hongbo Cai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shi_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lei Shi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yang_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaoyan Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lei Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiang Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhao_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Deng Zhao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhiqiang Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lyu_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xianguo Lyu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ming Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fangzhou Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ma_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaowei Ma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shen_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yue Shen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jinjie Gu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xue_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei Xue&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Huang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yiran Huang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09801">
<title>ProCoT: Stimulating Critical Thinking and Writing of Students through Engagement with Large Language Models (LLMs). (arXiv:2312.09801v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09801</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We introduce a novel writing method called Probing Chain of Thought (ProCoT),
which prevents students from cheating using a Large Language Model (LLM), such
as ChatGPT, while enhancing their active learning through such models. LLMs
have disrupted education and many other feilds. For fear of students cheating,
many educationists have resorted to banning their use, as their outputs can be
human-like and hard to detect in some cases. These LLMs are also known for
hallucinations (i.e. fake facts). We conduct studies with ProCoT in two
different courses with a combined total of about 66 students. The students in
each course were asked to prompt an LLM of their choice with one question from
a set of four and required to affirm or refute statements in the LLM output by
using peer reviewed references. The results show two things: (1) ProCoT
stimulates creative/critical thinking and writing of students through
engagement with LLMs when we compare the LLM solely output to ProCoT output and
(2) ProCoT can prevent cheating because of clear limitations in existing LLMs
when we compare students ProCoT output to LLM ProCoT output. We also discover
that most students prefer to give answers in fewer words than LLMs, which are
typically verbose. The average word counts for students, ChatGPT (v3.5) and
Phind (v8) are 208, 391 and 383, respectively.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Adewumi_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tosin Adewumi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Alkhaled_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lama Alkhaled&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Buck_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Claudia Buck&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hernandez_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sergio Hernandez&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Brilioth_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Saga Brilioth&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kekung_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mkpe Kekung&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ragimov_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yelvin Ragimov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Barney_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Elisa Barney&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09806">
<title>Improving Biomedical Entity Linking with Retrieval-enhanced Learning. (arXiv:2312.09806v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09806</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Biomedical entity linking (BioEL) has achieved remarkable progress with the
help of pre-trained language models. However, existing BioEL methods usually
struggle to handle rare and difficult entities due to long-tailed distribution.
To address this limitation, we introduce a new scheme $k$NN-BioEL, which
provides a BioEL model with the ability to reference similar instances from the
entire training corpus as clues for prediction, thus improving the
generalization capabilities. Moreover, we design a contrastive learning
objective with dynamic hard negative sampling (DHNS) that improves the quality
of the retrieved neighbors during inference. Extensive experimental results
show that $k$NN-BioEL outperforms state-of-the-art baselines on several
datasets.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lin_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhenxi Lin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ziheng Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wu_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xian Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zheng_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yefeng Zheng&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09818">
<title>SMILE: Multimodal Dataset for Understanding Laughter in Video with Language Models. (arXiv:2312.09818v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09818</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Despite the recent advances of the artificial intelligence, building social
intelligence remains a challenge. Among social signals, laughter is one of the
distinctive expressions that occurs during social interactions between humans.
In this work, we tackle a new challenge for machines to understand the
rationale behind laughter in video, Video Laugh Reasoning. We introduce this
new task to explain why people laugh in a particular video and a dataset for
this task. Our proposed dataset, SMILE, comprises video clips and language
descriptions of why people laugh. We propose a baseline by leveraging the
reasoning capacity of large language models (LLMs) with textual video
representation. Experiments show that our baseline can generate plausible
explanations for laughter. We further investigate the scalability of our
baseline by probing other video understanding tasks and in-the-wild videos. We
release our dataset, code, and model checkpoints on
https://github.com/SMILE-data/SMILE.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hyun_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lee Hyun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sung_Bin_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kim Sung-Bin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Han_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Seungju Han&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Youngjae Yu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Oh_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tae-Hyun Oh&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09890">
<title>Grammatical information in BERT sentence embeddings as two-dimensional arrays. (arXiv:2312.09890v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09890</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Sentence embeddings induced with various transformer architectures encode
much semantic and syntactic information in a distributed manner in a
one-dimensional array. We investigate whether specific grammatical information
can be accessed in these distributed representations. Using data from a task
developed to test rule-like generalizations, our experiments on detecting
subject-verb agreement yield several promising results. First, we show that
while the usual sentence representations encoded as one-dimensional arrays do
not easily support extraction of rule-like regularities, a two-dimensional
reshaping of these vectors allows various learning architectures to access such
information. Next, we show that various architectures can detect patterns in
these two-dimensional reshaped sentence embeddings and successfully learn a
model based on smaller amounts of simpler training data, which performs well on
more complex test data. This indicates that current sentence embeddings contain
information that is regularly distributed, and which can be captured when the
embeddings are reshaped into higher dimensional arrays. Our results cast light
on representations produced by language models and help move towards developing
few-shot learning approaches.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Nastase_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vivi Nastase&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Merlo_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Paola Merlo&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09895">
<title>Generative Context-aware Fine-tuning of Self-supervised Speech Models. (arXiv:2312.09895v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09895</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;When performing tasks like automatic speech recognition or spoken language
understanding for a given utterance, access to preceding text or audio provides
contextual information can improve performance. Considering the recent advances
in generative large language models (LLM), we hypothesize that an LLM could
generate useful context information using the preceding text. With appropriate
prompts, LLM could generate a prediction of the next sentence or abstractive
text like titles or topics. In this paper, we study the use of LLM-generated
context information and propose an approach to distill the generated
information during fine-tuning of self-supervised speech models, which we refer
to as generative context-aware fine-tuning. This approach allows the fine-tuned
model to make improved predictions without access to the true surrounding
segments or to the LLM at inference time, while requiring only a very small
additional context module. We evaluate the proposed approach using the SLUE and
Libri-light benchmarks for several downstream tasks: automatic speech
recognition, named entity recognition, and sentiment analysis. The results show
that generative context-aware fine-tuning outperforms a context injection
fine-tuning approach that accesses the ground-truth previous text, and is
competitive with a generative context injection fine-tuning approach that
requires the LLM at inference time.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shon_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Suwon Shon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kim_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kwangyoun Kim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sridhar_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Prashant Sridhar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hsu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yi-Te Hsu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Watanabe_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shinji Watanabe&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Livescu_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Karen Livescu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09907">
<title>Exploring Automatic Text Simplification of German Narrative Documents. (arXiv:2312.09907v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09907</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we apply transformer-based Natural Language Generation (NLG)
techniques to the problem of text simplification. Currently, there are only a
few German datasets available for text simplification, even fewer with larger
and aligned documents, and not a single one with narrative texts. In this
paper, we explore to which degree modern NLG techniques can be applied to
German narrative text simplifications. We use Longformer attention and a
pre-trained mBART model. Our findings indicate that the existing approaches for
German are not able to solve the task properly. We conclude on a few directions
for future research to address this problem.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Schomacker_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thorben Schomacker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Donicke_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tillmann D&amp;#xf6;nicke&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tropmann_Frick_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marina Tropmann-Frick&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09917">
<title>Red AI? Inconsistent Responses from GPT3.5 Models on Political Issues in the US and China. (arXiv:2312.09917v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09917</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The rising popularity of ChatGPT and other AI-powered large language models
(LLMs) has led to increasing studies highlighting their susceptibility to
mistakes and biases. However, most of these studies focus on models trained on
English texts. Taking an innovative approach, this study investigates political
biases in GPT&apos;s multilingual models. We posed the same question about
high-profile political issues in the United States and China to GPT in both
English and simplified Chinese, and our analysis of the bilingual responses
revealed that GPT&apos;s bilingual models&apos; political &quot;knowledge&quot; (content) and the
political &quot;attitude&quot; (sentiment) are significantly more inconsistent on
political issues in China. The simplified Chinese GPT models not only tended to
provide pro-China information but also presented the least negative sentiment
towards China&apos;s problems, whereas the English GPT was significantly more
negative towards China. This disparity may stem from Chinese state censorship
and US-China geopolitical tensions, which influence the training corpora of GPT
bilingual models. Moreover, both Chinese and English models tended to be less
critical towards the issues of &quot;their own&quot; represented by the language used,
than the issues of &quot;the other.&quot; This suggests that GPT multilingual models
could potentially develop a &quot;political identity&quot; and an associated sentiment
bias based on their training language. We discussed the implications of our
findings for information transmission and communication in an increasingly
divided world.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhou_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Di Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yinxian Zhang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09932">
<title>RDR: the Recap, Deliberate, and Respond Method for Enhanced Language Understanding. (arXiv:2312.09932v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09932</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Natural language understanding (NLU) using neural network pipelines often
requires additional context that is not solely present in the input data.
Through Prior research, it has been evident that NLU benchmarks are susceptible
to manipulation by neural models, wherein these models exploit statistical
artifacts within the encoded external knowledge to artificially inflate
performance metrics for downstream tasks. Our proposed approach, known as the
Recap, Deliberate, and Respond (RDR) paradigm, addresses this issue by
incorporating three distinct objectives within the neural network pipeline.
Firstly, the Recap objective involves paraphrasing the input text using a
paraphrasing model in order to summarize and encapsulate its essence. Secondly,
the Deliberation objective entails encoding external graph information related
to entities mentioned in the input text, utilizing a graph embedding model.
Finally, the Respond objective employs a classification head model that
utilizes representations from the Recap and Deliberation modules to generate
the final prediction. By cascading these three models and minimizing a combined
loss, we mitigate the potential for gaming the benchmark and establish a robust
method for capturing the underlying semantic patterns, thus enabling accurate
predictions. To evaluate the effectiveness of the RDR method, we conduct tests
on multiple GLUE benchmark tasks. Our results demonstrate improved performance
compared to competitive baselines, with an enhancement of up to 2\% on standard
metrics. Furthermore, we analyze the observed evidence for semantic
understanding exhibited by RDR models, emphasizing their ability to avoid
gaming the benchmark and instead accurately capture the true underlying
semantic patterns.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zi_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuxin Zi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Veeramani_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hariram Veeramani&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Roy_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kaushik Roy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sheth_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Amit Sheth&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09966">
<title>Data and Approaches for German Text simplification -- towards an Accessibility-enhanced Communication. (arXiv:2312.09966v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09966</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This paper examines the current state-of-the-art of German text
simplification, focusing on parallel and monolingual German corpora. It reviews
neural language models for simplifying German texts and assesses their
suitability for legal texts and accessibility requirements. Our findings
highlight the need for additional training data and more appropriate approaches
that consider the specific linguistic characteristics of German, as well as the
importance of the needs and preferences of target groups with cognitive or
language impairments. The authors launched the interdisciplinary OPEN-LS
project in April 2023 to address these research gaps. The project aims to
develop a framework for text formats tailored to individuals with low literacy
levels, integrate legal texts, and enhance comprehensibility for those with
linguistic or cognitive impairments. It will also explore cost-effective ways
to enhance the data with audience-specific illustrations using image-generating
AI.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more and up-to-date information, please visit our project homepage
https://open-ls.entavis.com
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Schomacker_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thorben Schomacker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gille_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michael Gille&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hulls_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J&amp;#xf6;rg von der H&amp;#xfc;lls&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tropmann_Frick_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marina Tropmann-Frick&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09979">
<title>The Art of Balancing: Revolutionizing Mixture of Experts for Maintaining World Knowledge in Language Model Alignment. (arXiv:2312.09979v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09979</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Supervised fine-tuning (SFT) is a crucial step for large language models
(LLMs), enabling them to align with human instructions and enhance their
capabilities in downstream tasks. When the models are required to align with a
broader range of downstream tasks, or there is a desire to notably improve the
performance on a specific task, a substantial increase in fine-tuning data
often emerges as the solution. However, we find that large-scale increases in
instruction data can disrupt the world knowledge previously stored in the LLMs,
i.e., world knowledge forgetting. In this paper, we introduce LoRAMoE to
address above challenge. The LoRAMoE is a plugin version of Mixture of Experts
(MoE). The plugin-form ensures the integrity of world knowledge by freezing the
backbone model during the training phase. And we propose the use of localized
balancing constraints to coordinate parts of experts for task utilization,
meanwhile enables other experts to to fully leverage the world knowledge stored
in the models. Experimental results demonstrate that LoRAMoE can reasonly
coordinate experts based on data type during inference, and even dramatically
increasing instruction data does not result in knowledge forgetting. Moreover,
LoRAMoE provides additional benefits for the performance of downstream tasks,
indicating the potential of our approach for multi-task learning.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Dou_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shihan Dou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhou_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Enyu Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yan Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gao_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Songyang Gao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhao_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jun Zhao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shen_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei Shen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhou_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuhao Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xi_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhiheng Xi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiao Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Fan_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaoran Fan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Pu_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shiliang Pu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiang Zhu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zheng_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rui Zheng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gui_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tao Gui&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qi Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Huang_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xuanjing Huang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09993">
<title>LLaMAntino: LLaMA 2 Models for Effective Text Generation in Italian Language. (arXiv:2312.09993v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09993</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Large Language Models represent state-of-the-art linguistic models designed
to equip computers with the ability to comprehend natural language. With its
exceptional capacity to capture complex contextual relationships, the LLaMA
(Large Language Model Meta AI) family represents a novel advancement in the
field of natural language processing by releasing foundational models designed
to improve the natural language understanding abilities of the transformer
architecture thanks to their large amount of trainable parameters (7, 13, and
70 billion parameters). In many natural language understanding tasks, these
models obtain the same performances as private company models such as OpenAI
Chat-GPT with the advantage to make publicly available weights and code for
research and commercial uses. In this work, we investigate the possibility of
Language Adaptation for LLaMA models, explicitly focusing on addressing the
challenge of Italian Language coverage. Adopting an open science approach, we
explore various tuning approaches to ensure a high-quality text generated in
Italian suitable for common tasks in this underrepresented language in the
original models&apos; datasets. We aim to release effective text generation models
with strong linguistic properties for many tasks that seem challenging using
multilingual or general-purpose LLMs. By leveraging an open science philosophy,
this study contributes to Language Adaptation strategies for the Italian
language by introducing the novel LLaMAntino family of Italian LLMs.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Basile_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pierpaolo Basile&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Musacchio_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Elio Musacchio&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Polignano_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marco Polignano&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Siciliani_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lucia Siciliani&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Fiameni_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Giuseppe Fiameni&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Semeraro_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Giovanni Semeraro&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.10003">
<title>ReST meets ReAct: Self-Improvement for Multi-Step Reasoning LLM Agent. (arXiv:2312.10003v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.10003</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Answering complex natural language questions often necessitates multi-step
reasoning and integrating external information. Several systems have combined
knowledge retrieval with a large language model (LLM) to answer such questions.
These systems, however, suffer from various failure cases, and we cannot
directly train them end-to-end to fix such failures, as interaction with
external knowledge is non-differentiable. To address these deficiencies, we
define a ReAct-style LLM agent with the ability to reason and act upon external
knowledge. We further refine the agent through a ReST-like method that
iteratively trains on previous trajectories, employing growing-batch
reinforcement learning with AI feedback for continuous self-improvement and
self-distillation. Starting from a prompted large model and after just two
iterations of the algorithm, we can produce a fine-tuned small model that
achieves comparable performance on challenging compositional question-answering
benchmarks with two orders of magnitude fewer parameters.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Aksitov_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Renat Aksitov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Miryoosefi_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sobhan Miryoosefi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zonglin Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daliang Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Babayan_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sheila Babayan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kopparapu_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kavya Kopparapu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Fisher_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zachary Fisher&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Guo_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ruiqi Guo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Prakash_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sushant Prakash&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Srinivasan_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pranesh Srinivasan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zaheer_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Manzil Zaheer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yu_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Felix Yu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kumar_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sanjiv Kumar&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.10007">
<title>Faithful Persona-based Conversational Dataset Generation with Large Language Models. (arXiv:2312.10007v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.10007</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;High-quality conversational datasets are essential for developing AI models
that can communicate with users. One way to foster deeper interactions between
a chatbot and its user is through personas, aspects of the user&apos;s character
that provide insights into their personality, motivations, and behaviors.
Training Natural Language Processing (NLP) models on a diverse and
comprehensive persona-based dataset can lead to conversational models that
create a deeper connection with the user, and maintain their engagement. In
this paper, we leverage the power of Large Language Models (LLMs) to create a
large, high-quality conversational dataset from a seed dataset. We propose a
Generator-Critic architecture framework to expand the initial dataset, while
improving the quality of its conversations. The Generator is an LLM prompted to
output conversations. The Critic consists of a mixture of expert LLMs that
control the quality of the generated conversations. These experts select the
best generated conversations, which we then use to improve the Generator. We
release Synthetic-Persona-Chat, consisting of 20k conversations seeded from
Persona-Chat. We evaluate the quality of Synthetic-Persona-Chat and our
generation framework on different dimensions through extensive experiments, and
observe that the losing rate of Synthetic-Persona-Chat against Persona-Chat
during Turing test decreases from 17.2% to 8.8% over three iterations.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jandaghi_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pegah Jandaghi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sheng_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;XiangHai Sheng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bai_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xinyi Bai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Pujara_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jay Pujara&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sidahmed_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hakim Sidahmed&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.01528">
<title>Effective and Imperceptible Adversarial Textual Attack via Multi-objectivization. (arXiv:2111.01528v4 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.01528</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The field of adversarial textual attack has significantly grown over the last
few years, where the commonly considered objective is to craft adversarial
examples (AEs) that can successfully fool the target model. However, the
imperceptibility of attacks, which is also essential for practical attackers,
is often left out by previous studies. In consequence, the crafted AEs tend to
have obvious structural and semantic differences from the original
human-written text, making them easily perceptible. In this work, we advocate
leveraging multi-objectivization to address such issue. Specifically, we
reformulate the problem of crafting AEs as a multi-objective optimization
problem, where the attack imperceptibility is considered as an auxiliary
objective. Then, we propose a simple yet effective evolutionary algorithm,
dubbed HydraText, to solve this problem. To the best of our knowledge,
HydraText is currently the only approach that can be effectively applied to
both score-based and decision-based attack settings. Exhaustive experiments
involving 44237 instances demonstrate that HydraText consistently achieves
competitive attack success rates and better attack imperceptibility than the
recently proposed attack approaches. A human evaluation study also shows that
the AEs crafted by HydraText are more indistinguishable from human-written
text. Finally, these AEs exhibit good transferability and can bring notable
robustness improvement to the target model by adversarial training.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shengcai Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lu_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ning Lu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hong_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wenjing Hong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Qian_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chao Qian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tang_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ke Tang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.16230">
<title>Evaluation of semantic relations impact in query expansion-based retrieval systems. (arXiv:2203.16230v4 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.16230</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;With the increasing demand of intelligent systems capable of operating in
different contexts (e.g. users on the move) the correct interpretation of the
user-need by such systems has become crucial to give consistent answers to the
user questions. The most effective applications addressing such task are in the
fields of natural language processing and semantic expansion of terms. These
techniques are aimed at estimating the goal of an input query reformulating it
as an intent, commonly relying on textual resources built exploiting different
semantic relations like \emph{synonymy}, \emph{antonymy} and many others. The
aim of this paper is to generate such resources using the labels of a given
taxonomy as source of information. The obtained resources are integrated into a
plain classifier for reformulating a set of input queries as intents and
tracking the effect of each relation, in order to quantify the impact of each
semantic relation on the classification. As an extension to this, the best
tradeoff between improvement and noise introduction when combining such
relations is evaluated. The assessment is made generating the resources and
their combinations and using them for tuning the classifier which is used to
reformulate the user questions as labels. The evaluation employs a wide and
varied taxonomy as a use-case, exploiting its labels as basis for the semantic
expansion and producing several corpora with the purpose of enhancing the
pseudo-queries estimation.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Massai_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lorenzo Massai&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.14160">
<title>Label Words are Anchors: An Information Flow Perspective for Understanding In-Context Learning. (arXiv:2305.14160v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.14160</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In-context learning (ICL) emerges as a promising capability of large language
models (LLMs) by providing them with demonstration examples to perform diverse
tasks. However, the underlying mechanism of how LLMs learn from the provided
context remains under-explored. In this paper, we investigate the working
mechanism of ICL through an information flow lens. Our findings reveal that
label words in the demonstration examples function as anchors: (1) semantic
information aggregates into label word representations during the shallow
computation layers&apos; processing; (2) the consolidated information in label words
serves as a reference for LLMs&apos; final predictions. Based on these insights, we
introduce an anchor re-weighting method to improve ICL performance, a
demonstration compression technique to expedite inference, and an analysis
framework for diagnosing ICL errors in GPT2-XL. The promising applications of
our findings again validate the uncovered ICL working mechanism and pave the
way for future studies.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lean Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lei Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Dai_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Damai Dai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Deli Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhou_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hao Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Meng_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fandong Meng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhou_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jie Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sun_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xu Sun&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.18396">
<title>LLMs Can Understand Encrypted Prompt: Towards Privacy-Computing Friendly Transformers. (arXiv:2305.18396v3 [cs.LG] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.18396</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The community explored to build private inference frameworks for
transformer-based large language models (LLMs) in a server-client setting,
where the server holds the model parameters and the client inputs its private
data (or prompt) for inference. However, these frameworks impose significant
overhead when the private inputs are forward propagated through the original
LLMs. In this paper, we show that substituting the computation- and
communication-heavy operators in the transformer architecture with
privacy-computing friendly approximations can greatly reduce the private
inference costs while incurring very minor impact on model performance.
Compared to state-of-the-art Iron (NeurIPS 2022), our privacy-computing
friendly model inference pipeline achieves a $5\times$ acceleration in
computation and an 80% reduction in communication overhead, while retaining
nearly identical accuracy.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xuanqi Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhuotao Liu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2306.04308">
<title>Personality testing of GPT-3: Limited temporal reliability, but highlighted social desirability of GPT-3&apos;s personality instruments results. (arXiv:2306.04308v2 [cs.AI] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2306.04308</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;As AI-bots continue to gain popularity due to their human-like traits and the
intimacy they offer to users, their societal impact inevitably expands. This
leads to the rising necessity for comprehensive studies to fully understand
AI-bots and reveal their potential opportunities, drawbacks, and overall
societal impact. With that in mind, this research conducted an extensive
investigation into ChatGPT3, a renowned AI bot, aiming to assess the temporal
reliability of its personality profile. Psychological questionnaires were
administered to the chatbot on two separate occasions, followed by a comparison
of the responses to human normative data. The findings revealed varying levels
of agreement in chatbot&apos;s responses over time, with some scales displaying
excellent agreement while others demonstrated poor agreement. Overall,
Davinci-003 displayed a socially desirable and pro-social personality profile,
particularly in the domain of communion. However, the underlying basis of the
chatbot&apos;s responses-whether driven by conscious self reflection or
predetermined algorithms-remains uncertain.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bodroza_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bojana Bodroza&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Dinic_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bojana M. Dinic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bojic_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ljubisa Bojic&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2307.14132">
<title>CIF-T: A Novel CIF-based Transducer Architecture for Automatic Speech Recognition. (arXiv:2307.14132v3 [cs.SD] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2307.14132</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;RNN-T models are widely used in ASR, which rely on the RNN-T loss to achieve
length alignment between input audio and target sequence. However, the
implementation complexity and the alignment-based optimization target of RNN-T
loss lead to computational redundancy and a reduced role for predictor network,
respectively. In this paper, we propose a novel model named CIF-Transducer
(CIF-T) which incorporates the Continuous Integrate-and-Fire (CIF) mechanism
with the RNN-T model to achieve efficient alignment. In this way, the RNN-T
loss is abandoned, thus bringing a computational reduction and allowing the
predictor network a more significant role. We also introduce Funnel-CIF,
Context Blocks, Unified Gating and Bilinear Pooling joint network, and
auxiliary training strategy to further improve performance. Experiments on the
178-hour AISHELL-1 and 10000-hour WenetSpeech datasets show that CIF-T achieves
state-of-the-art results with lower computational overhead compared to RNN-T
models.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tian-Hao Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhou_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dinghao Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhong_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Guiping Zhong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhou_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiaming Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Baoxiang Li&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2308.10822">
<title>A Novel Ehanced Move Recognition Algorithm Based on Pre-trained Models with Positional Embeddings. (arXiv:2308.10822v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2308.10822</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The recognition of abstracts is crucial for effectively locating the content
and clarifying the article. Existing move recognition algorithms lack the
ability to learn word position information to obtain contextual semantics. This
paper proposes a novel enhanced move recognition algorithm with an improved
pre-trained model and a gated network with attention mechanism for unstructured
abstracts of Chinese scientific and technological papers. The proposed
algorithm first performs summary data segmentation and vocabulary training. The
EP-ERNIE$\_$AT-GRU framework is leveraged to incorporate word positional
information, facilitating deep semantic learning and targeted feature
extraction. Experimental results demonstrate that the proposed algorithm
achieves 13.37$\%$ higher accuracy on the split dataset than on the original
dataset and a 7.55$\%$ improvement in accuracy over the basic comparison model.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wen_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hao Wen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jie Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Qiao_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaodong Qiao&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.07597">
<title>C-Pack: Packaged Resources To Advance General Chinese Embedding. (arXiv:2309.07597v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.07597</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We introduce C-Pack, a package of resources that significantly advance the
field of general Chinese embeddings. C-Pack includes three critical resources.
1) C-MTEB is a comprehensive benchmark for Chinese text embeddings covering 6
tasks and 35 datasets. 2) C-MTP is a massive text embedding dataset curated
from labeled and unlabeled Chinese corpora for training embedding models. 3)
C-TEM is a family of embedding models covering multiple sizes. Our models
outperform all prior Chinese text embeddings on C-MTEB by up to +10% upon the
time of the release. We also integrate and optimize the entire suite of
training methods for C-TEM. Along with our resources on general Chinese
embedding, we release our data and models for English text embeddings. The
English models achieve state-of-the-art performance on MTEB benchmark;
meanwhile, our released English data is 2 times larger than the Chinese data.
All these resources are made publicly available at
https://github.com/FlagOpen/FlagEmbedding.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xiao_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shitao Xiao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zheng Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Peitian Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Muennighoff_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Niklas Muennighoff&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.03985">
<title>Dementia Assessment Using Mandarin Speech with an Attention-based Speech Recognition Encoder. (arXiv:2310.03985v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.03985</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Dementia diagnosis requires a series of different testing methods, which is
complex and time-consuming. Early detection of dementia is crucial as it can
prevent further deterioration of the condition. This paper utilizes a speech
recognition model to construct a dementia assessment system tailored for
Mandarin speakers during the picture description task. By training an
attention-based speech recognition model on voice data closely resembling
real-world scenarios, we have significantly enhanced the model&apos;s recognition
capabilities. Subsequently, we extracted the encoder from the speech
recognition model and added a linear layer for dementia assessment. We
collected Mandarin speech data from 99 subjects and acquired their clinical
assessments from a local hospital. We achieved an accuracy of 92.04% in
Alzheimer&apos;s disease detection and a mean absolute error of 9% in clinical
dementia rating score prediction.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lin_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zih-Jyun Lin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yi-Ju Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kuo_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Po-Chih Kuo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Huang_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Likai Huang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hu_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chaur-Jong Hu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Cheng-Yu Chen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.08903">
<title>SeqXGPT: Sentence-Level AI-Generated Text Detection. (arXiv:2310.08903v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.08903</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Widely applied large language models (LLMs) can generate human-like content,
raising concerns about the abuse of LLMs. Therefore, it is important to build
strong AI-generated text (AIGT) detectors. Current works only consider
document-level AIGT detection, therefore, in this paper, we first introduce a
sentence-level detection challenge by synthesizing a dataset that contains
documents that are polished with LLMs, that is, the documents contain sentences
written by humans and sentences modified by LLMs. Then we propose
\textbf{Seq}uence \textbf{X} (Check) \textbf{GPT}, a novel method that utilizes
log probability lists from white-box LLMs as features for sentence-level AIGT
detection. These features are composed like \textit{waves} in speech processing
and cannot be studied by LLMs. Therefore, we build SeqXGPT based on convolution
and self-attention networks. We test it in both sentence and document-level
detection challenges. Experimental results show that previous methods struggle
in solving sentence-level AIGT detection, while our method not only
significantly surpasses baseline methods in both sentence and document-level
detection challenges but also exhibits strong generalization capabilities.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pengyu Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Linyang Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ren_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ke Ren&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jiang_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Botian Jiang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dong Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Qiu_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xipeng Qiu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.13859">
<title>Not all Fake News is Written: A Dataset and Analysis of Misleading Video Headlines. (arXiv:2310.13859v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.13859</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Polarization and the marketplace for impressions have conspired to make
navigating information online difficult for users, and while there has been a
significant effort to detect false or misleading text, multimodal datasets have
received considerably less attention. To complement existing resources, we
present multimodal Video Misleading Headline (VMH), a dataset that consists of
videos and whether annotators believe the headline is representative of the
video&apos;s contents. After collecting and annotating this dataset, we analyze
multimodal baselines for detecting misleading headlines. Our annotation process
also focuses on why annotators view a video as misleading, allowing us to
better understand the interplay of annotators&apos; background and the content of
the videos.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sung_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yoo Yeon Sung&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Boyd_Graber_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jordan Boyd-Graber&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hassan_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Naeemul Hassan&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.14360">
<title>Is ChatGPT a game changer for geocoding -- a benchmark for geocoding address parsing techniques. (arXiv:2310.14360v4 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.14360</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The remarkable success of GPT models across various tasks, including toponymy
recognition motivates us to assess the performance of the GPT-3 model in the
geocoding address parsing task. To ensure that the evaluation more accurately
mirrors performance in real-world scenarios with diverse user input qualities
and resolve the pressing need for a &apos;gold standard&apos; evaluation dataset for
geocoding systems, we introduce a benchmark dataset of low-quality address
descriptions synthesized based on human input patterns mining from actual input
logs of a geocoding system in production. This dataset has 21 different input
errors and variations; contains over 239,000 address records that are uniquely
selected from streets across all U.S. 50 states and D.C.; and consists of three
subsets to be used as training, validation, and testing sets. Building on this,
we train and gauge the performance of the GPT-3 model in extracting address
components, contrasting its performance with transformer-based and LSTM-based
models. The evaluation results indicate that Bidirectional LSTM-CRF model has
achieved the best performance over these transformer-based models and GPT-3
model. Transformer-based models demonstrate very comparable results compared to
the Bidirectional LSTM-CRF model. The GPT-3 model, though trailing in
performance, showcases potential in the address parsing task with few-shot
examples, exhibiting room for improvement with additional fine-tuning. We open
source the code and data of this presented benchmark so that researchers can
utilize it for future model development or extend it to evaluate similar tasks,
such as document geocoding.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yin_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhengcong Yin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Diya Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Goldberg_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniel W. Goldberg&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.15539">
<title>SteloCoder: a Decoder-Only LLM for Multi-Language to Python Code Translation. (arXiv:2310.15539v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.15539</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;With the recent focus on Large Language Models (LLMs), both StarCoder (Li et
al., 2023) and Code Llama (Rozi\`ere et al., 2023) have demonstrated remarkable
performance in code generation. However, there is still a need for improvement
in code translation functionality with efficient training techniques. In
response to this, we introduce SteloCoder, a decoder-only StarCoder-based LLM
designed specifically for multi-programming language-to-Python code
translation. In particular, SteloCoder achieves C++, C#, JavaScript, Java, or
PHP-to-Python code translation without specifying the input programming
language. We modified StarCoder model architecture by incorporating a
Mixture-of-Experts (MoE) technique featuring five experts and a gating network
for multi-task handling. Experts are obtained by StarCoder fine-tuning.
Specifically, we use a Low-Rank Adaptive Method (LoRA) technique, limiting each
expert size as only 0.06% of number of StarCoder&apos;s parameters. At the same
time, to enhance training efficiency in terms of time, we adopt curriculum
learning strategy and use self-instruct data for efficient fine-tuning. As a
result, each expert takes only 6 hours to train on one single 80Gb A100 HBM.
With experiments on XLCoST datasets, SteloCoder achieves an average of 73.76
CodeBLEU score in multi-programming language-to-Python translation, surpassing
the top performance from the leaderboard by at least 3.5. This accomplishment
is attributed to only 45M extra parameters with StarCoder as the backbone and
32 hours of valid training on one 80GB A100 HBM. The source code is release
here: https://github.com/sade-adrien/SteloCoder.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Pan_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jialing Pan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sade_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Adrien Sad&amp;#xe9;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kim_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jin Kim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Soriano_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Eric Soriano&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sole_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Guillem Sole&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Flamant_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sylvain Flamant&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.16218">
<title>Knowledge Editing for Large Language Models: A Survey. (arXiv:2310.16218v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.16218</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Large language models (LLMs) have recently transformed both the academic and
industrial landscapes due to their remarkable capacity to understand, analyze,
and generate texts based on their vast knowledge and reasoning ability.
Nevertheless, one major drawback of LLMs is their substantial computational
cost for pre-training due to their unprecedented amounts of parameters. The
disadvantage is exacerbated when new knowledge frequently needs to be
introduced into the pre-trained model. Therefore, it is imperative to develop
effective and efficient techniques to update pre-trained LLMs. Traditional
methods encode new knowledge in pre-trained LLMs through direct fine-tuning.
However, naively re-training LLMs can be computationally intensive and risks
degenerating valuable pre-trained knowledge irrelevant to the update in the
model. Recently, Knowledge-based Model Editing (KME) has attracted increasing
attention, which aims to precisely modify the LLMs to incorporate specific
knowledge, without negatively influencing other irrelevant knowledge. In this
survey, we aim to provide a comprehensive and in-depth overview of recent
advances in the field of KME. We first introduce a general formulation of KME
to encompass different KME strategies. Afterward, we provide an innovative
taxonomy of KME techniques based on how the new knowledge is introduced into
pre-trained LLMs, and investigate existing KME strategies while analyzing key
insights, advantages, and limitations of methods from each category. Moreover,
representative metrics, datasets, and applications of KME are introduced
accordingly. Finally, we provide an in-depth analysis regarding the
practicality and remaining challenges of KME and suggest promising research
directions for further advancement in this field.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Song Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yaochen Zhu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Haochen Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zheng_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zaiyi Zheng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chen Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jundong Li&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.18333">
<title>She had Cobalt Blue Eyes: Prompt Testing to Create Aligned and Sustainable Language Models. (arXiv:2310.18333v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.18333</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;As the use of large language models (LLMs) increases within society, as does
the risk of their misuse. Appropriate safeguards must be in place to ensure LLM
outputs uphold the ethical standards of society, highlighting the positive role
that artificial intelligence technologies can have. Recent events indicate
ethical concerns around conventionally trained LLMs, leading to overall unsafe
user experiences. This motivates our research question: how do we ensure LLM
alignment? In this work, we introduce a test suite of unique prompts to foster
the development of aligned LLMs that are fair, safe, and robust. We show that
prompting LLMs at every step of the development pipeline, including data
curation, pre-training, and fine-tuning, will result in an overall more
responsible model. Our test suite evaluates outputs from four state-of-the-art
language models: GPT-3.5, GPT-4, OPT, and LLaMA-2. The assessment presented in
this paper highlights a gap between societal alignment and the capabilities of
current LLMs. Additionally, implementing a test suite such as ours lowers the
environmental overhead of making models safe and fair.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chatrath_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Veronica Chatrath&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bamgbose_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Oluwanifemi Bamgbose&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Raza_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shaina Raza&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.05741">
<title>Efficiently Adapting Pretrained Language Models To New Languages. (arXiv:2311.05741v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.05741</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Recent large language models (LLM) exhibit sub-optimal performance on
low-resource languages, as the training data of these models is usually
dominated by English and other high-resource languages. Furthermore, it is
challenging to train models for low-resource languages, especially from
scratch, due to a lack of high quality training data. Adapting pretrained LLMs
reduces the need for data in the new language while also providing cross
lingual transfer capabilities. However, naively adapting to new languages leads
to catastrophic forgetting and poor tokenizer efficiency. In this work, we
study how to efficiently adapt any existing pretrained LLM to a new language
without running into these issues. In particular, we improve the encoding
efficiency of the tokenizer by adding new tokens from the target language and
study the data mixing recipe to mitigate forgetting. Our experiments on
adapting an English LLM to Hungarian and Thai show that our recipe can reach
better performance than open source models on the target language, with minimal
regressions on English.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Csaki_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zoltan Csaki&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Pawakapan_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pian Pawakapan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Thakker_U/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Urmish Thakker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xu_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qiantong Xu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.11844">
<title>How to Use Large Language Models for Text Coding: The Case of Fatherhood Roles in Public Policy Documents. (arXiv:2311.11844v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.11844</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Recent advances in large language models (LLMs) like GPT-3 and GPT-4 have
opened up new opportunities for text analysis in political science. They
promise automation with better results and less programming. In this study, we
evaluate LLMs on three original coding tasks of non-English political science
texts, and we provide a detailed description of a general workflow for using
LLMs for text coding in political science research. Our use case offers a
practical guide for researchers looking to incorporate LLMs into their research
on text analysis. We find that, when provided with detailed label definitions
and coding examples, an LLM can be as good as or even better than a human
annotator while being much faster (up to hundreds of times), considerably
cheaper (costing up to 60% less than human coding), and much easier to scale to
large amounts of text. Overall, LLMs present a viable option for most text
coding projects.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lupo_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lorenzo Lupo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Magnusson_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Oscar Magnusson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hovy_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dirk Hovy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Naurin_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Elin Naurin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wangnerud_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lena W&amp;#xe4;ngnerud&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.15786">
<title>YUAN 2.0: A Large Language Model with Localized Filtering-based Attention. (arXiv:2311.15786v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.15786</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this work, we develop and release Yuan 2.0, a series of large language
models with parameters ranging from 2.1 billion to 102.6 billion. The Localized
Filtering-based Attention (LFA) is introduced to incorporate prior knowledge of
local dependencies of natural language into Attention. A data filtering and
generating system is presented to build pre-training and fine-tuning dataset in
high quality. A distributed training method with non-uniform pipeline parallel,
data parallel, and optimizer parallel is proposed, which greatly reduces the
bandwidth requirements of intra-node communication, and achieves good
performance in large-scale distributed training. Yuan 2.0 models display
impressive ability in code generation, math problem-solving, and chatting
compared with existing models. The latest version of YUAN 2.0, including model
weights and source code, is accessible at Github.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wu_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shaohua Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhao_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xudong Zhao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shenling Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Luo_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiangang Luo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lingjun Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xi Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhao_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bing Zhao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yu_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tong Yu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rongguo Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiahua Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chao Wang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.04103">
<title>Enhancing the Rationale-Input Alignment for Self-explaining Rationalization. (arXiv:2312.04103v2 [cs.AI] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.04103</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Rationalization empowers deep learning models with self-explaining
capabilities through a cooperative game, where a generator selects a
semantically consistent subset of the input as a rationale, and a subsequent
predictor makes predictions based on the selected rationale. In this paper, we
discover that rationalization is prone to a problem named \emph{rationale
shift}, which arises from the algorithmic bias of the cooperative game.
Rationale shift refers to a situation where the semantics of the selected
rationale may deviate from the original input, but the predictor still produces
accurate predictions based on the deviation, resulting in a compromised
generator with misleading feedback.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address this issue, we first demonstrate the importance of the alignment
between the rationale and the full input through both empirical observations
and theoretical analysis. Subsequently, we introduce a novel approach called
DAR (\textbf{D}iscriminatively \textbf{A}ligned \textbf{R}ationalization),
which utilizes an auxiliary module pretrained on the full input to
discriminatively align the selected rationale and the original input. We
theoretically illustrate how DAR accomplishes the desired alignment, thereby
overcoming the rationale shift problem. The experiments on two widely used
real-world benchmarks show that the proposed method significantly improves the
explanation quality (measured by the overlap between the model-selected
explanation and the human-annotated rationale) as compared to state-of-the-art
techniques. Additionally, results on two synthetic settings further validate
the effectiveness of DAR in addressing the rationale shift problem.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Haozhao Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jun Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Deng_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhiying Deng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;YuanKai Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Cheng Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ruixuan Li&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.07559">
<title>PaperQA: Retrieval-Augmented Generative Agent for Scientific Research. (arXiv:2312.07559v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.07559</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Large Language Models (LLMs) generalize well across language tasks, but
suffer from hallucinations and uninterpretability, making it difficult to
assess their accuracy without ground-truth. Retrieval-Augmented Generation
(RAG) models have been proposed to reduce hallucinations and provide provenance
for how an answer was generated. Applying such models to the scientific
literature may enable large-scale, systematic processing of scientific
knowledge. We present PaperQA, a RAG agent for answering questions over the
scientific literature. PaperQA is an agent that performs information retrieval
across full-text scientific articles, assesses the relevance of sources and
passages, and uses RAG to provide answers. Viewing this agent as a question
answering model, we find it exceeds performance of existing LLMs and LLM agents
on current science QA benchmarks. To push the field closer to how humans
perform research on scientific literature, we also introduce LitQA, a more
complex benchmark that requires retrieval and synthesis of information from
full-text scientific papers across the literature. Finally, we demonstrate
PaperQA&apos;s matches expert human researchers on LitQA.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lala_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jakub L&amp;#xe1;la&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+ODonoghue_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Odhran O&amp;#x27;Donoghue&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shtedritski_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aleksandar Shtedritski&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cox_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sam Cox&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Rodriques_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Samuel G. Rodriques&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+White_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrew D. White&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08078">
<title>Fine-Grained Image-Text Alignment in Medical Imaging Enables Cyclic Image-Report Generation. (arXiv:2312.08078v3 [cs.CV] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08078</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;To address these issues, we propose a novel Adaptive patch-word Matching
(AdaMatch) model to correlate chest X-ray (CXR) image regions with words in
medical reports and apply it to CXR-report generation to provide explainability
for the generation process. AdaMatch exploits the fine-grained relation between
adaptive patches and words to provide explanations of specific image regions
with corresponding words. To capture the abnormal regions of varying sizes and
positions, we introduce the Adaptive Patch extraction (AdaPatch) module to
acquire the adaptive patches for these regions adaptively. In order to provide
explicit explainability for CXR-report generation task, we propose an
AdaMatch-based bidirectional large language model for Cyclic CXR-report
generation (AdaMatch-Cyclic). It employs the AdaMatch to obtain the keywords
for CXR images and `keypatches&apos; for medical reports as hints to guide
CXR-report generation. Extensive experiments on two publicly available CXR
datasets prove the effectiveness of our method and its superior performance to
existing methods.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wenting Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiang Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shen_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Linlin Shen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yuan_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yixuan Yuan&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08274">
<title>High-throughput Biomedical Relation Extraction for Semi-Structured Web Articles Empowered by Large Language Models. (arXiv:2312.08274v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08274</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Objective: To develop a high-throughput biomedical relation extraction system
that takes advantage of the large language models&apos; (LLMs) reading comprehension
ability and biomedical world knowledge in a scalable and evidential manner.
Methods: We formulate the relation extraction task as a simple binary
classification problem for large language models such as ChatGPT. Specifically,
LLMs make the decision based on the external corpus and its world knowledge,
giving the reason for the judgment to factual verification. This method is
tailored for semi-structured web articles, wherein we designate the main title
as the tail entity and explicitly incorporate it into the context, and the
potential head entities are matched based on a biomedical thesaurus. Moreover,
lengthy contents are sliced into text chunks, embedded, and retrieved with
additional embedding models, ensuring compatibility with the context window
size constraints of available open-source LLMs. Results: Using an open-source
LLM, we extracted 304315 relation triplets of three distinct relation types
from four reputable biomedical websites. To assess the efficacy of the basic
pipeline employed for biomedical relation extraction, we curated a benchmark
dataset annotated by a medical expert. Evaluation results indicate that the
pipeline exhibits performance comparable to that of GPT-4. Case studies further
illuminate challenges faced by contemporary LLMs in the context of biomedical
relation extraction for semi-structured web articles. Conclusion: The proposed
method has demonstrated its effectiveness in leveraging the strengths of LLMs
for high-throughput biomedical relation extraction. Its adaptability is
evident, as it can be seamlessly extended to diverse semi-structured biomedical
websites, facilitating the extraction of various types of biomedical relations
with ease.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhou_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Songchi Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yu_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sheng Yu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08282">
<title>Prompting LLMs with content plans to enhance the summarization of scientific articles. (arXiv:2312.08282v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08282</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This paper presents novel prompting techniques to improve the performance of
automatic summarization systems for scientific articles. Scientific article
summarization is highly challenging due to the length and complexity of these
documents. We conceive, implement, and evaluate prompting techniques that
provide additional contextual information to guide summarization systems.
Specifically, we feed summarizers with lists of key terms extracted from
articles, such as author keywords or automatically generated keywords. Our
techniques are tested with various summarization models and input texts.
Results show performance gains, especially for smaller models summarizing
sections separately. This evidences that prompting is a promising approach to
overcoming the limitations of less powerful systems. Our findings introduce a
new research direction of using prompts to aid smaller models.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Creo_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aldan Creo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lama_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Manuel Lama&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Vidal_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Juan C. Vidal&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08688">
<title>TigerBot: An Open Multilingual Multitask LLM. (arXiv:2312.08688v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08688</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We release and introduce the TigerBot family of large language models (LLMs),
consisting of base and chat models, sized from 7, 13, 70 and 180 billion
parameters. We develop our models embarking from Llama-2 and BLOOM, and push
the boundary further in data, training algorithm, infrastructure, and
application tools. Our models yield meaningful performance gain over SOTA
open-source models, e.g., Llama-2, specifically 6% gain in English and 20% gain
in Chinese. TigerBot model family also achieves leading performance in major
academic and industrial benchmarks and leaderboards. We believe that TigerBot
represents just a snapshot of lightning-fast progression in LLM open-source
community. Therefore, we are thrilled to give back by publicly releasing our
models and reporting our approach behind, with additional emphases on building
SOTA LLMs in a democratized way and making LLMs of use in real-world
applications.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ye Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cai_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei Cai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wu_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Liangmin Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaowei Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xin_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhanxuan Xin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Fu_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Cong Fu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09211">
<title>Mitigating Outlier Activations in Low-Precision Fine-Tuning of Language Models. (arXiv:2312.09211v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09211</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Low-precision fine-tuning of language models has gained prominence as a
cost-effective and energy-efficient approach to deploying large-scale models in
various applications. However, this approach is susceptible to the existence of
outlier values in activation. The outlier values in the activation can
negatively affect the performance of fine-tuning language models in the
low-precision regime since they affect the scaling factor and thus make
representing smaller values harder. This paper investigates techniques for
mitigating outlier activation in low-precision integer fine-tuning of the
language models. Our proposed novel approach enables us to represent the
outlier activation values in 8-bit integers instead of floating-point (FP16)
values. The benefit of using integers for outlier values is that it enables us
to use operator tiling to avoid performing 16-bit integer matrix multiplication
to address this problem effectively. We provide theoretical analysis and
supporting experiments to demonstrate the effectiveness of our approach in
improving the robustness and performance of low-precision fine-tuned language
models.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ghaffari_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alireza Ghaffari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Justin Yu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Nejad_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mahsa Ghazvini Nejad&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Asgharian_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Masoud Asgharian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Boxing Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Nia_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vahid Partovi Nia&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>