<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Computer Science -- Computation and Language (cs.CL) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2023-12-14T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Computer Science -- Computation and Language</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08388" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08400" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08495" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08566" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08579" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08583" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08585" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08618" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08642" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08676" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08688" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08725" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08726" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08737" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08747" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08755" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08793" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08800" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08846" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08865" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08901" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08906" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08926" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08935" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08968" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08995" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09000" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2102.00225" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2104.00640" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.17255" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.07207" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.07066" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.01313" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.01903" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.03919" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.07235" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.10847" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.13721" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.14973" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2308.06385" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.03559" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.08628" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.02207" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.05804" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.10158" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.10605" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.11648" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.15140" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.15517" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.18168" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.03731" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.04915" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.14483" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.03664" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.03731" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.03818" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.04333" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.05497" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.07492" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.07622" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.07987" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08078" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08274" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08388">
<title>Exploring Graph Based Approaches for Author Name Disambiguation. (arXiv:2312.08388v1 [cs.SI])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08388</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In many applications, such as scientific literature management, researcher
search, social network analysis and etc, Name Disambiguation (aiming at
disambiguating WhoIsWho) has been a challenging problem. In addition, the
growth of scientific literature makes the problem more difficult and urgent.
Although name disambiguation has been extensively studied in academia and
industry, the problem has not been solved well due to the clutter of data and
the complexity of the same name scenario. In this work, we aim to explore
models that can perform the task of name disambiguation using the network
structure that is intrinsic to the problem and present an analysis of the
models.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Rastogi_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chetanya Rastogi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Agarwal_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Prabhat Agarwal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Singh_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shreya Singh&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08400">
<title>Beyond English: Evaluating LLMs for Arabic Grammatical Error Correction. (arXiv:2312.08400v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08400</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Large language models (LLMs) finetuned to follow human instruction have
recently exhibited significant capabilities in various English NLP tasks.
However, their performance in grammatical error correction (GEC), especially on
languages other than English, remains significantly unexplored. In this work,
we evaluate the abilities of instruction finetuned LLMs in Arabic GEC, a
complex task due to Arabic&apos;s rich morphology. Our findings suggest that various
prompting methods, coupled with (in-context) few-shot learning, demonstrate
considerable effectiveness, with GPT-4 achieving up to $65.49$ F$_{1}$ score
under expert prompting (approximately $5$ points higher than our established
baseline). Despite these positive results, we find that instruction finetuned
models, regardless of their size, are still outperformed by fully finetuned
ones, even if they are significantly smaller in size. This disparity highlights
substantial room for improvements for LLMs. Inspired by methods used in
low-resource machine translation, we also develop a method exploiting synthetic
data that significantly outperforms previous models on two standard Arabic
benchmarks. Our best model achieves a new SOTA on Arabic GEC, with $73.29$ and
$73.26$ F$_{1}$ on the 2014 and 2015 QALB datasets, respectively, compared to
peer-reviewed published baselines.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kwon_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sang Yun Kwon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bhatia_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gagan Bhatia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Nagoudi_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;El Moatez Billah Nagoudi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Abdul_Mageed_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Muhammad Abdul-Mageed&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08495">
<title>Beyond Accuracy: Automated De-Identification of Large Real-World Clinical Text Datasets. (arXiv:2312.08495v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08495</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Recent research advances achieve human-level accuracy for de-identifying
free-text clinical notes on research datasets, but gaps remain in reproducing
this in large real-world settings. This paper summarizes lessons learned from
building a system used to de-identify over one billion real clinical notes, in
a fully automated way, that was independently certified by multiple
organizations for production use. A fully automated solution requires a very
high level of accuracy that does not require manual review. A hybrid
context-based model architecture is described, which outperforms a Named Entity
Recogniton (NER) - only model by 10% on the i2b2-2014 benchmark. The proposed
system makes 50%, 475%, and 575% fewer errors than the comparable AWS, Azure,
and GCP services respectively while also outperforming ChatGPT by 33%. It
exceeds 98% coverage of sensitive data across 7 European languages, without a
need for fine tuning. A second set of described models enable data obfuscation
-- replacing sensitive data with random surrogates -- while retaining name,
date, gender, clinical, and format consistency. Both the practical need and the
solution architecture that provides for reliable &amp;amp; linked anonymized documents
are described.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kocaman_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Veysel Kocaman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Haq_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hasham Ul Haq&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Talby_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;David Talby&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08566">
<title>Learning adaptive planning representations with natural language guidance. (arXiv:2312.08566v1 [cs.AI])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08566</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Effective planning in the real world requires not only world knowledge, but
the ability to leverage that knowledge to build the right representation of the
task at hand. Decades of hierarchical planning techniques have used
domain-specific temporal action abstractions to support efficient and accurate
planning, almost always relying on human priors and domain knowledge to
decompose hard tasks into smaller subproblems appropriate for a goal or set of
goals. This paper describes Ada (Action Domain Acquisition), a framework for
automatically constructing task-specific planning representations using
task-general background knowledge from language models (LMs). Starting with a
general-purpose hierarchical planner and a low-level goal-conditioned policy,
Ada interactively learns a library of planner-compatible high-level action
abstractions and low-level controllers adapted to a particular domain of
planning tasks. On two language-guided interactive planning benchmarks (Mini
Minecraft and ALFRED Household Tasks), Ada strongly outperforms other
approaches that use LMs for sequential decision-making, offering more accurate
plans and better generalization to complex tasks.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wong_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lionel Wong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Mao_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiayuan Mao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sharma_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pratyusha Sharma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Siegel_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zachary S. Siegel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Feng_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiahai Feng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Korneev_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Noa Korneev&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tenenbaum_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Joshua B. Tenenbaum&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Andreas_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jacob Andreas&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08579">
<title>Identifying Planetary Names in Astronomy Papers: A Multi-Step Approach. (arXiv:2312.08579v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08579</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The automatic identification of planetary feature names in astronomy
publications presents numerous challenges. These features include craters,
defined as roughly circular depressions resulting from impact or volcanic
activity; dorsas, which are elongate raised structures or wrinkle ridges; and
lacus, small irregular patches of dark, smooth material on the Moon, referred
to as &quot;lake&quot; (Planetary Names Working Group, n.d.). Many feature names overlap
with places or people&apos;s names that they are named after, for example, Syria,
Tempe, Einstein, and Sagan, to name a few (U.S. Geological Survey, n.d.). Some
feature names have been used in many contexts, for instance, Apollo, which can
refer to mission, program, sample, astronaut, seismic, seismometers, core, era,
data, collection, instrument, and station, in addition to the crater on the
Moon. Some feature names can appear in the text as adjectives, like the lunar
craters Black, Green, and White. Some feature names in other contexts serve as
directions, like craters West and South on the Moon. Additionally, some
features share identical names across different celestial bodies, requiring
disambiguation, such as the Adams crater, which exists on both the Moon and
Mars. We present a multi-step pipeline combining rule-based filtering,
statistical relevance analysis, part-of-speech (POS) tagging, named entity
recognition (NER) model, hybrid keyword harvesting, knowledge graph (KG)
matching, and inference with a locally installed large language model (LLM) to
reliably identify planetary names despite these challenges. When evaluated on a
dataset of astronomy papers from the Astrophysics Data System (ADS), this
methodology achieves an F1-score over 0.97 in disambiguating planetary feature
names.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shapurian_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Golnaz Shapurian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kurtz_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michael J Kurtz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Accomazzi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alberto Accomazzi&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08583">
<title>ZeroQuant(4+2): Redefining LLMs Quantization with a New FP6-Centric Strategy for Diverse Generative Tasks. (arXiv:2312.08583v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08583</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This study examines 4-bit quantization methods like GPTQ in large language
models (LLMs), highlighting GPTQ&apos;s overfitting and limited enhancement in
Zero-Shot tasks. While prior works merely focusing on zero-shot measurement, we
extend task scope to more generative categories such as code generation and
abstractive summarization, in which we found that INT4 quantization can
significantly underperform. However, simply shifting to higher precision
formats like FP6 has been particularly challenging, thus overlooked, due to
poor performance caused by the lack of sophisticated integration and system
acceleration strategies on current AI hardware. Our results show that FP6, even
with a coarse-grain quantization scheme, performs robustly across various
algorithms and tasks, demonstrating its superiority in accuracy and
versatility. Notably, with the FP6 quantization, \codestar-15B model performs
comparably to its FP16 counterpart in code generation, and for smaller models
like the 406M it closely matches their baselines in summarization. Neither can
be achieved by INT4. To better accommodate various AI hardware and achieve the
best system performance, we propose a novel 4+2 design for FP6 to achieve
similar latency to the state-of-the-art INT4 fine-grain quantization. With our
design, FP6 can become a promising solution to the current 4-bit quantization
methods used in LLMs.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wu_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaoxia Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xia_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Haojun Xia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Youn_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stephen Youn&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zheng_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhen Zheng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shiyang Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bakhtiari_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Arash Bakhtiari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wyatt_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michael Wyatt&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+He_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuxiong He&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ruwase_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Olatunji Ruwase&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Song_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Leon Song&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yao_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhewei Yao&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08585">
<title>Unraveling Key Factors of Knowledge Distillation. (arXiv:2312.08585v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08585</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Knowledge distillation, a technique for model compression and performance
enhancement, has gained significant traction in Neural Machine Translation
(NMT). However, existing research primarily focuses on empirical applications,
and there is a lack of comprehensive understanding of how student model
capacity, data complexity, and decoding strategies collectively influence
distillation effectiveness. Addressing this gap, our study conducts an in-depth
investigation into these factors, particularly focusing on their interplay in
word-level and sequence-level distillation within NMT. Through extensive
experimentation across datasets like IWSLT13 En$\rightarrow$Fr, IWSLT14
En$\rightarrow$De, and others, we empirically validate hypotheses related to
the impact of these factors on knowledge distillation. Our research not only
elucidates the significant influence of model capacity, data complexity, and
decoding strategies on distillation effectiveness but also introduces a novel,
optimized distillation approach. This approach, when applied to the IWSLT14
de$\rightarrow$en translation task, achieves state-of-the-art performance,
demonstrating its practical efficacy in advancing the field of NMT.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wei_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jingxuan Wei&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sun_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Linzhuang Sun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tan_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xu Tan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yu_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bihui Yu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Guo_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ruifeng Guo&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08618">
<title>Zebra: Extending Context Window with Layerwise Grouped Local-Global Attention. (arXiv:2312.08618v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08618</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This paper introduces a novel approach to enhance the capabilities of Large
Language Models (LLMs) in processing and understanding extensive text
sequences, a critical aspect in applications requiring deep comprehension and
synthesis of large volumes of information. Recognizing the inherent challenges
in extending the context window for LLMs, primarily built on Transformer
architecture, we propose a new model architecture, referred to as Zebra. This
architecture efficiently manages the quadratic time and memory complexity
issues associated with full attention in the Transformer by employing grouped
local-global attention layers. Our model, akin to a zebra&apos;s alternating
stripes, balances local and global attention layers, significantly reducing
computational requirements and memory consumption. Comprehensive experiments,
including pretraining from scratch, continuation of long context adaptation
training, and long instruction tuning, are conducted to evaluate the Zebra&apos;s
performance. The results show that Zebra achieves comparable or superior
performance on both short and long sequence benchmarks, while also enhancing
training and inference efficiency.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Song_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kaiqiang Song&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaoyang Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cho_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sangwoo Cho&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Pan_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaoman Pan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yu_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dong Yu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08642">
<title>Metacognition-Enhanced Few-Shot Prompting With Positive Reinforcement. (arXiv:2312.08642v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08642</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Few-shot prompting elicits the remarkable abilities of large language models
by equipping them with a few demonstration examples in the input. However, the
traditional method of providing large language models with all demonstration
input-output pairs at once may not effectively guide large language models to
learn the specific input-output mapping relationship. In this paper, inspired
by the regulatory and supportive role of metacognition in students&apos; learning,
we propose a novel metacognition-enhanced few-shot prompting, which guides
large language models to reflect on their thought processes to comprehensively
learn the given demonstration examples. Furthermore, considering that positive
reinforcement can improve students&apos; learning motivation, we introduce positive
reinforcement into our metacognition-enhanced few-shot prompting to promote the
few-shot learning of large language models by providing response-based positive
feedback. The experimental results on two real-world datasets show that our
metacognition-enhanced few-shot prompting with positive reinforcement surpasses
traditional few-shot prompting in classification accuracy and macro F1.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ji_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yu Ji&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wu_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wen Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yi Hu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zheng_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hong Zheng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+He_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Liang He&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08676">
<title>SEF-VC: Speaker Embedding Free Zero-Shot Voice Conversion with Cross Attention. (arXiv:2312.08676v1 [cs.SD])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08676</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Zero-shot voice conversion (VC) aims to transfer the source speaker timbre to
arbitrary unseen target speaker timbre, while keeping the linguistic content
unchanged. Although the voice of generated speech can be controlled by
providing the speaker embedding of the target speaker, the speaker similarity
still lags behind the ground truth recordings. In this paper, we propose
SEF-VC, a speaker embedding free voice conversion model, which is designed to
learn and incorporate speaker timbre from reference speech via a powerful
position-agnostic cross-attention mechanism, and then reconstruct waveform from
HuBERT semantic tokens in a non-autoregressive manner. The concise design of
SEF-VC enhances its training stability and voice conversion performance.
Objective and subjective evaluations demonstrate the superiority of SEF-VC to
generate high-quality speech with better similarity to target reference than
strong zero-shot VC baselines, even for very short reference speeches.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Junjie Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Guo_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yiwei Guo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xie Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yu_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kai Yu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08688">
<title>TigerBot: An Open Multilingual Multitask LLM. (arXiv:2312.08688v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08688</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We release and introduce the TigerBot family of large language models (LLMs),
consisting of base and chat models, sized from 7, 13, 70 and 180 billion
parameters. We develop our models embarking from Llama-2 and BLOOM, and push
the boundary further in data, training algorithm, infrastructure, and
application tools. Our models yield meaningful performance gain over SOTA
open-source models, e.g., Llama-2, specifically 6\% gain in English and 20\%
gain in Chinese. TigerBot model family also achieves leading performance in
major academic and industrial benchmarks and leaderboards. We believe that
TigerBot represents just a snapshot of lightning-fast progression in LLM
open-source community. Therefore, we are thrilled to give back by publicly
releasing our models and reporting our approach behind, with additional
emphases on building SOTA LLMs in a democratized way and making LLMs of use in
real-world applications.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ye Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cai_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei Cai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wu_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Liangmin Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaowei Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xin_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhanxuan Xin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Fu_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Cong Fu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08725">
<title>A Comparative Analysis of Fine-Tuned LLMs and Few-Shot Learning of LLMs for Financial Sentiment Analysis. (arXiv:2312.08725v1 [cs.LG])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08725</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Financial sentiment analysis plays a crucial role in uncovering latent
patterns and detecting emerging trends, enabling individuals to make
well-informed decisions that may yield substantial advantages within the
constantly changing realm of finance. Recently, Large Language Models (LLMs)
have demonstrated their effectiveness in diverse domains, showcasing remarkable
capabilities even in zero-shot and few-shot in-context learning for various
Natural Language Processing (NLP) tasks. Nevertheless, their potential and
applicability in the context of financial sentiment analysis have not been
thoroughly explored yet. To bridge this gap, we employ two approaches:
in-context learning (with a focus on gpt-3.5-turbo model) and fine-tuning LLMs
on a finance-domain dataset. Given the computational costs associated with
fine-tuning LLMs with large parameter sizes, our focus lies on smaller LLMs,
spanning from 250M to 3B parameters for fine-tuning. We then compare the
performances with state-of-the-art results to evaluate their effectiveness in
the finance-domain. Our results demonstrate that fine-tuned smaller LLMs can
achieve comparable performance to state-of-the-art fine-tuned LLMs, even with
models having fewer parameters and a smaller training dataset. Additionally,
the zero-shot and one-shot performance of LLMs produces comparable results with
fine-tuned smaller LLMs and state-of-the-art outcomes. Furthermore, our
analysis demonstrates that there is no observed enhancement in performance for
finance-domain sentiment analysis when the number of shots for in-context
learning is increased.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Fatemi_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sorouralsadat Fatemi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuheng Hu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08726">
<title>Labels Need Prompts Too Mask Matching for Natural Language Understanding Tasks. (arXiv:2312.08726v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08726</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Textual label names (descriptions) are typically semantically rich in many
natural language understanding (NLU) tasks. In this paper, we incorporate the
prompting methodology, which is widely used to enrich model input, into the
label side for the first time. Specifically, we propose a Mask Matching method,
which equips an input with a prompt and its label with another, and then makes
predictions by matching their mask representations. We evaluate our method
extensively on 8 NLU tasks with 14 datasets. The experimental results show that
Mask Matching significantly outperforms its counterparts of fine-tuning and
conventional prompt-tuning, setting up state-of-the-art performances in several
datasets. Mask Matching is particularly good at handling NLU tasks with large
label counts and informative label names. As pioneering efforts that
investigate the label-side prompt, we also discuss open issues for future
study.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bo Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ye_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei Ye&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Quansen Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhao_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wen Zhao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shikun Zhang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08737">
<title>JPIS: A Joint Model for Profile-based Intent Detection and Slot Filling with Slot-to-Intent Attention. (arXiv:2312.08737v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08737</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Profile-based intent detection and slot filling are important tasks aimed at
reducing the ambiguity in user utterances by leveraging user-specific
supporting profile information. However, research in these two tasks has not
been extensively explored. To fill this gap, we propose a joint model, namely
JPIS, designed to enhance profile-based intent detection and slot filling. JPIS
incorporates the supporting profile information into its encoder and introduces
a slot-to-intent attention mechanism to transfer slot information
representations to intent detection. Experimental results show that our JPIS
substantially outperforms previous profile-based models, establishing a new
state-of-the-art performance in overall accuracy on the Chinese benchmark
dataset ProSLU.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Pham_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thinh Pham&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Nguyen_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dat Quoc Nguyen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08747">
<title>Dissecting vocabulary biases datasets through statistical testing and automated data augmentation for artifact mitigation in Natural Language Inference. (arXiv:2312.08747v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08747</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In recent years, the availability of large-scale annotated datasets, such as
the Stanford Natural Language Inference and the Multi-Genre Natural Language
Inference, coupled with the advent of pre-trained language models, has
significantly contributed to the development of the natural language inference
domain. However, these crowdsourced annotated datasets often contain biases or
dataset artifacts, leading to overestimated model performance and poor
generalization. In this work, we focus on investigating dataset artifacts and
developing strategies to address these issues. Through the utilization of a
novel statistical testing procedure, we discover a significant association
between vocabulary distribution and text entailment classes, emphasizing
vocabulary as a notable source of biases. To mitigate these issues, we propose
several automatic data augmentation strategies spanning character to word
levels. By fine-tuning the ELECTRA pre-trained language model, we compare the
performance of boosted models with augmented data against their baseline
counterparts. The experiments demonstrate that the proposed approaches
effectively enhance model accuracy and reduce biases by up to 0.66% and 1.14%,
respectively.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Nguyen_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dat Thanh Nguyen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08755">
<title>PROPRES: Investigating the Projectivity of Presupposition with Various Triggers and Environments. (arXiv:2312.08755v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08755</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;What makes a presupposition of an utterance -- information taken for granted
by its speaker -- different from other pragmatic inferences such as an
entailment is projectivity (e.g., the negative sentence the boy did not stop
shedding tears presupposes the boy had shed tears before). The projectivity may
vary depending on the combination of presupposition triggers and environments.
However, prior natural language understanding studies fail to take it into
account as they either use no human baseline or include only negation as an
entailment-canceling environment to evaluate models&apos; performance. The current
study attempts to reconcile these issues. We introduce a new dataset,
projectivity of presupposition (PROPRES, which includes 12k premise-hypothesis
pairs crossing six triggers involving some lexical variety with five
environments. Our human evaluation reveals that humans exhibit variable
projectivity in some cases. However, the model evaluation shows that the
best-performed model, DeBERTa, does not fully capture it. Our findings suggest
that probing studies on pragmatic inferences should take extra care of the
human judgment variability and the combination of linguistic items.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Asami_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daiki Asami&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sugawara_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Saku Sugawara&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08793">
<title>Forbidden Facts: An Investigation of Competing Objectives in Llama-2. (arXiv:2312.08793v1 [cs.LG])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08793</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;LLMs often face competing pressures (for example helpfulness vs.
harmlessness). To understand how models resolve such conflicts, we study
Llama-2-chat models on the forbidden fact task. Specifically, we instruct
Llama-2 to truthfully complete a factual recall statement while forbidding it
from saying the correct answer. This often makes the model give incorrect
answers. We decompose Llama-2 into 1000+ components, and rank each one with
respect to how useful it is for forbidding the correct answer. We find that in
aggregate, around 35 components are enough to reliably implement the full
suppression behavior. However, these components are fairly heterogeneous and
many operate using faulty heuristics. We discover that one of these heuristics
can be exploited via a manually designed adversarial attack which we call The
California Attack. Our results highlight some roadblocks standing in the way of
being able to successfully interpret advanced ML systems. Project website
available at https://forbiddenfacts.github.io .
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tony T. Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Miles Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hariharan_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kaivu Hariharan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shavit_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nir Shavit&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08800">
<title>Evaluating Large Language Models for Health-related Queries with Presuppositions. (arXiv:2312.08800v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08800</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;As corporations rush to integrate large language models (LLMs) to their
search offerings, it is critical that they provide factually accurate
information that is robust to any presuppositions that a user may express. In
this work, we introduce UPHILL, a dataset consisting of health-related queries
with varying degrees of presuppositions. Using UPHILL, we evaluate the factual
accuracy and consistency of InstructGPT, ChatGPT, and BingChat models. We find
that while model responses rarely disagree with true health claims (posed as
questions), they often fail to challenge false claims: responses from
InstructGPT agree with 32% of the false claims, ChatGPT 26% and BingChat 23%.
As we increase the extent of presupposition in input queries, the responses
from InstructGPT and ChatGPT agree with the claim considerably more often,
regardless of its veracity. Responses from BingChat, which rely on retrieved
webpages, are not as susceptible. Given the moderate factual accuracy, and the
inability of models to consistently correct false assumptions, our work calls
for a careful assessment of current LLMs for use in high-stakes scenarios.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kaur_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Navreet Kaur&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Choudhury_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Monojit Choudhury&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Pruthi_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Danish Pruthi&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08846">
<title>TiMix: Text-aware Image Mixing for Effective Vision-Language Pre-training. (arXiv:2312.08846v1 [cs.LG])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08846</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Self-supervised Multi-modal Contrastive Learning (SMCL) remarkably advances
modern Vision-Language Pre-training (VLP) models by aligning visual and
linguistic modalities. Due to noises in web-harvested text-image pairs,
however, scaling up training data volume in SMCL presents considerable
obstacles in terms of computational cost and data inefficiency. To improve data
efficiency in VLP, we propose Text-aware Image Mixing (TiMix), which integrates
mix-based data augmentation techniques into SMCL, yielding significant
performance improvements without significantly increasing computational
overhead. We provide a theoretical analysis of TiMixfrom a mutual information
(MI) perspective, showing that mixed data samples for cross-modal contrastive
learning implicitly serve as a regularizer for the contrastive loss. The
experimental results demonstrate that TiMix exhibits a comparable performance
on downstream tasks, even with a reduced amount of training data and shorter
training time, when benchmarked against existing methods. This work empirically
and theoretically demonstrates the potential of data mixing for data-efficient
and computationally viable VLP, benefiting broader VLP model adoption in
practical scenarios.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jiang_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chaoya Jiang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+ye_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei ye&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xu_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Haiyang Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ye_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qinghao Ye&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yan_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ming Yan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ji Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shikun Zhang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08865">
<title>Improving Cross-modal Alignment with Synthetic Pairs for Text-only Image Captioning. (arXiv:2312.08865v1 [cs.CV])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08865</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Although image captioning models have made significant advancements in recent
years, the majority of them heavily depend on high-quality datasets containing
paired images and texts which are costly to acquire. Previous works leverage
the CLIP&apos;s cross-modal association ability for image captioning, relying solely
on textual information under unsupervised settings. However, not only does a
modality gap exist between CLIP text and image features, but a discrepancy also
arises between training and inference due to the unavailability of real-world
images, which hinders the cross-modal alignment in text-only captioning. This
paper proposes a novel method to address these issues by incorporating
synthetic image-text pairs. A pre-trained text-to-image model is deployed to
obtain images that correspond to textual data, and the pseudo features of
generated images are optimized toward the real ones in the CLIP embedding
space. Furthermore, textual information is gathered to represent image
features, resulting in the image features with various semantics and the
bridged modality gap. To unify training and inference, synthetic image features
would serve as the training prefix for the language decoder, while real images
are used for inference. Additionally, salient objects in images are detected as
assistance to enhance the learning of modality alignment. Experimental results
demonstrate that our method obtains the state-of-the-art performance on
benchmark datasets.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhiyue Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jinyuan Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ma_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fanrong Ma&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08901">
<title>Boosting LLM Reasoning: Push the Limits of Few-shot Learning with Reinforced In-Context Pruning. (arXiv:2312.08901v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08901</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Large language models (LLMs) have shown impressive capabilities in various
tasks, yet they still struggle with math reasoning. Despite efforts to optimize
Chain-of-Thoughts (CoT) prompts and fine-tune LLMs, the potential of few-shot
learning remains unexplored. In this work, we propose CoT-Max, a novel approach
pushing the boundaries of few-shot CoT learning to improve LLM math reasoning
capabilities. CoT-Max addresses the challenges of the selection of useful
examples and limited number of examples due to restricted context window
length. Inspired by our observation that natural language inputs contain many
redundancy, we propose a coarse-to-fine pruner as a plug-and-play module for
LLMs, which first identifies crucial CoT examples from a large batch and then
further prunes unimportant tokens. To train the pruner, we collect a math
reasoning dataset with diverse difficulty and steps, introduce a reward to
measure both the input&apos;s effectiveness for math reasoning and token length
constraints, and propose a novel training approach with reinforcement learning.
As a result, CoT-Max significantly outperforms CoT and few-shot prompting
baselines across various LLMs (LLaMA2-7B, 13B, 70B) and 5 mathematical
datasets, achieving up to 4.55% absolute improvements. Remarkably, without any
fine-tuning, LLaMA2-70B with CoT-Max surpasses GPT-3.5 and a wide range of
larger LLMs (PaLM, Minerva, etc.) on the GSM8K.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Huang_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xijie Huang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Li Lyna Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cheng_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kwang-Ting Cheng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yang_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mao Yang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08906">
<title>Using eye tracking to investigate what native Chinese speakers notice about linguistic landscape images. (arXiv:2312.08906v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08906</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Linguistic landscape is an important field in sociolinguistic research. Eye
tracking technology is a common technology in psychological research. There are
few cases of using eye movement to study linguistic landscape. This paper uses
eye tracking technology to study the actual fixation of the linguistic
landscape and finds that in the two dimensions of fixation time and fixation
times, the fixation of native Chinese speakers to the linguistic landscape is
higher than that of the general landscape. This paper argues that this
phenomenon is due to the higher information density of linguistic landscapes.
At the same time, the article also discusses other possible reasons for this
phenomenon.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wei_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zichao Wei&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Qin_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yewei Qin&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08926">
<title>Modeling Complex Mathematical Reasoning via Large Language Model based MathAgent. (arXiv:2312.08926v1 [cs.AI])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08926</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Large language models (LLMs) face challenges in solving complex mathematical
problems that require comprehensive capacities to parse the statements,
associate domain knowledge, perform compound logical reasoning, and integrate
the intermediate rationales. Tackling all these problems once could be arduous
for LLMs, thus leading to confusion in generation. In this work, we explore the
potential of enhancing LLMs with agents by meticulous decomposition and
modeling of mathematical reasoning process. Specifically, we propose a formal
description of the mathematical solving and extend LLMs with an agent-based
zero-shot framework named
$\bf{P}$lanner-$\bf{R}$easoner-$\bf{E}$xecutor-$\bf{R}$eflector (PRER). We
further provide and implement two MathAgents that define the logical forms and
inherent relations via a pool of actions in different grains and orientations:
MathAgent-M adapts its actions to LLMs, while MathAgent-H aligns with
humankind. Experiments on miniF2F and MATH have demonstrated the effectiveness
of PRER and proposed MathAgents, achieving an increase of
$12.3\%$($53.9\%\xrightarrow{}66.2\%$) on the MiniF2F, $9.2\%$
($49.8\%\xrightarrow{}59.0\%$) on MATH, and
$13.2\%$($23.2\%\xrightarrow{}35.4\%$) for level-5 problems of MATH against
GPT-4. Further analytical results provide more insightful perspectives on
exploiting the behaviors of LLMs as agents.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liao_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Haoran Liao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Du_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qinyi Du&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hu_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shaohua Hu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+He_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hao He&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yanyan Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tian_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jidong Tian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jin_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yaohui Jin&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08935">
<title>Math-Shepherd: A Label-Free Step-by-Step Verifier for LLMs in Mathematical Reasoning. (arXiv:2312.08935v1 [cs.AI])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08935</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated remarkable capabilities across
a wide range of tasks. However, even the most advanced open-source LLMs, such
as the LLaMA family models, still face challenges when it comes to accurately
solving complex multi-step mathematical problems. In this paper, we present an
innovative process-oriented math verifier called \textbf{Math-Shepherd}, which
assigns a reward score to each step of the LLM&apos;s outputs on math problems. The
training of Math-Shepherd is achieved using automatically constructed
process-wise supervision data, breaking the bottleneck of heavy reliance on
manual annotation in existing work. With the guidance of Math-Shepherd, a
series of open-source LLMs demonstrate exceptional performance. Among them,
DeepSeek 67B \citep{DeepSeek-llm} stands out by achieving accuracy rates of
93.3\% on the GSM8K dataset and 48.1\% on the MATH dataset, without external
enhancement such as tool usage. Our Math-Shepherd also outperforms the
self-consistency method and other existing verification models. We believe that
automatic process supervision holds significant potential for the future
evolution of LLMs.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Peiyi Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lei Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shao_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhihong Shao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xu_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R.X. Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Dai_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Damai Dai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yifei Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Deli Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Y.Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sui_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhifang Sui&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08968">
<title>Detecting value-expressive text posts in Russian social media. (arXiv:2312.08968v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08968</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Basic values are concepts or beliefs which pertain to desirable end-states
and transcend specific situations. Studying personal values in social media can
illuminate how and why societal values evolve especially when the stimuli-based
methods, such as surveys, are inefficient, for instance, in hard-to-reach
populations. On the other hand, user-generated content is driven by the massive
use of stereotyped, culturally defined speech constructions rather than
authentic expressions of personal values. We aimed to find a model that can
accurately detect value-expressive posts in Russian social media VKontakte. A
training dataset of 5,035 posts was annotated by three experts, 304
crowd-workers and ChatGPT. Crowd-workers and experts showed only moderate
agreement in categorizing posts. ChatGPT was more consistent but struggled with
spam detection. We applied an ensemble of human- and AI-assisted annotation
involving active learning approach, subsequently trained several LLMs and
selected a model based on embeddings from pre-trained fine-tuned rubert-tiny2,
and reached a high quality of value detection with F1 = 0.75 (F1-macro = 0.80).
This model provides a crucial step to a study of values within and between
Russian social media users.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Milkova_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Maria Milkova&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Rudnev_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Maksim Rudnev&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Okolskaya_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lidia Okolskaya&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08995">
<title>FrameFinder: Explorative Multi-Perspective Framing Extraction from News Headlines. (arXiv:2312.08995v1 [cs.IR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08995</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Revealing the framing of news articles is an important yet neglected task in
information seeking and retrieval. In the present work, we present FrameFinder,
an open tool for extracting and analyzing frames in textual data. FrameFinder
visually represents the frames of text from three perspectives, i.e., (i) frame
labels, (ii) frame dimensions, and (iii) frame structure. By analyzing the
well-established gun violence frame corpus, we demonstrate the merits of our
proposed solution to support social science research and call for subsequent
integration into information interactions.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Reiter_Haas_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Markus Reiter-Haas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Klosch_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Beate Kl&amp;#xf6;sch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hadler_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Markus Hadler&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lex_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Elisabeth Lex&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09000">
<title>ComOM at VLSP 2023: A Dual-Stage Framework with BERTology and Unified Multi-Task Instruction Tuning Model for Vietnamese Comparative Opinion Mining. (arXiv:2312.09000v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09000</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The ComOM shared task aims to extract comparative opinions from product
reviews in Vietnamese language. There are two sub-tasks, including (1)
Comparative Sentence Identification (CSI) and (2) Comparative Element
Extraction (CEE). The first task is to identify whether the input is a
comparative review, and the purpose of the second task is to extract the
quintuplets mentioned in the comparative review. To address this task, our team
proposes a two-stage system based on fine-tuning a BERTology model for the CSI
task and unified multi-task instruction tuning for the CEE task. Besides, we
apply the simple data augmentation technique to increase the size of the
dataset for training our model in the second stage. Experimental results show
that our approach outperforms the other competitors and has achieved the top
score on the official private test.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Thin_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dang Van Thin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hao_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Duong Ngoc Hao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Nguyen_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ngan Luu-Thuy Nguyen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2102.00225">
<title>Learning From How Humans Correct. (arXiv:2102.00225v18 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2102.00225</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In industry NLP application, our manually labeled data has a certain number
of noisy data. We present a simple method to find the noisy data and relabel
them manually, meanwhile we collect the correction information. Then we present
novel method to incorporate the human correction information into deep learning
model. Human know how to correct noisy data. So the correction information can
be inject into deep learning model. We do the experiment on our own text
classification dataset, which is manually labeled, because we need to relabel
the noisy data in our dataset for our industry application. The experiment
result shows that our learn-on-correction method improve the classification
accuracy from 91.7% to 92.5% in test dataset. The 91.7% accuracy is trained on
the corrected dataset, which improve the baseline from 83.3% to 91.7% in test
dataset. The accuracy under human evaluation achieves more than 97%.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Guo_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tong Guo&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2104.00640">
<title>AmbiFC: Fact-Checking Ambiguous Claims with Evidence. (arXiv:2104.00640v4 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2104.00640</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Automated fact-checking systems verify claims against evidence to predict
their veracity. In real-world scenarios, the retrieved evidence may not
unambiguously support or refute the claim and yield conflicting but valid
interpretations. Existing fact-checking datasets assume that the models
developed with them predict a single veracity label for each claim, thus
discouraging the handling of such ambiguity. To address this issue we present
AmbiFC, a fact-checking dataset with 10k claims derived from real-world
information needs. It contains fine-grained evidence annotations of 50k
passages from 5k Wikipedia pages. We analyze the disagreements arising from
ambiguity when comparing claims against evidence in AmbiFC, observing a strong
correlation of annotator disagreement with linguistic phenomena such as
underspecification and probabilistic reasoning. We develop models for
predicting veracity handling this ambiguity via soft labels and find that a
pipeline that learns the label distribution for sentence-level evidence
selection and veracity prediction yields the best performance. We compare
models trained on different subsets of AmbiFC and show that models trained on
the ambiguous instances perform better when faced with the identified
linguistic phenomena.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Glockner_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Max Glockner&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Staliunaite_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ieva Stali&amp;#x16b;nait&amp;#x117;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Thorne_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;James Thorne&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Vallejo_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gisela Vallejo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Vlachos_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andreas Vlachos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gurevych_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Iryna Gurevych&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.17255">
<title>A Cognitive Architecture for Machine Consciousness and Artificial Superintelligence: Thought Is Structured by the Iterative Updating of Working Memory. (arXiv:2203.17255v6 [q-bio.NC] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.17255</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This article provides an analytical framework for how to simulate human-like
thought processes within a computer. It describes how attention and memory
should be structured, updated, and utilized to search for associative additions
to the stream of thought. The focus is on replicating the dynamics of the
mammalian working memory system, which features two forms of persistent
activity: sustained firing (preserving information on the order of seconds) and
synaptic potentiation (preserving information from minutes to hours). The
article uses a series of over 40 original figures to systematically demonstrate
how the iterative updating of these working memory stores provides functional
structure to behavior, cognition, and consciousness.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an AI implementation, these two memory stores should be updated
continuously and in an iterative fashion, meaning each state should preserve a
proportion of the coactive representations from the state before it. Thus, the
set of concepts in working memory will evolve gradually and incrementally over
time. This makes each state a revised iteration of the preceding state and
causes successive states to overlap and blend with respect to the information
they contain. Transitions between states happen as persistent activity spreads
activation energy throughout the hierarchical network searching long-term
memory for the most appropriate representation to be added to the global
workspace. The result is a chain of associatively linked intermediate states
capable of advancing toward a solution or goal. Iterative updating is
conceptualized here as an information processing strategy, a model of working
memory, a theory of consciousness, and an algorithm for designing and
programming artificial general intelligence.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Reser_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jared Edward Reser&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.07207">
<title>Beyond Grounding: Extracting Fine-Grained Event Hierarchies Across Modalities. (arXiv:2206.07207v2 [cs.CV] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.07207</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Events describe happenings in our world that are of importance. Naturally,
understanding events mentioned in multimedia content and how they are related
forms an important way of comprehending our world. Existing literature can
infer if events across textual and visual (video) domains are identical (via
grounding) and thus, on the same semantic level. However, grounding fails to
capture the intricate cross-event relations that exist due to the same events
being referred to on many semantic levels. For example, in Figure 1, the
abstract event of &quot;war&quot; manifests at a lower semantic level through subevents
&quot;tanks firing&quot; (in video) and airplane &quot;shot&quot; (in text), leading to a
hierarchical, multimodal relationship between the events.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we propose the task of extracting event hierarchies from
multimodal (video and text) data to capture how the same event manifests itself
in different modalities at different semantic levels. This reveals the
structure of events and is critical to understanding them. To support research
on this task, we introduce the Multimodal Hierarchical Events (MultiHiEve)
dataset. Unlike prior video-language datasets, MultiHiEve is composed of news
video-article pairs, which makes it rich in event hierarchies. We densely
annotate a part of the dataset to construct the test benchmark. We show the
limitations of state-of-the-art unimodal and multimodal baselines on this task.
Further, we address these limitations via a new weakly supervised model,
leveraging only unannotated video-article pairs from MultiHiEve. We perform a
thorough evaluation of our proposed method which demonstrates improved
performance on this task and highlight opportunities for future research.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ayyubi_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hammad A. Ayyubi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Thomas_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Christopher Thomas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chum_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lovish Chum&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lokesh_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rahul Lokesh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Long Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Niu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yulei Niu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lin_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xudong Lin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Feng_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xuande Feng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Koo_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jaywon Koo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ray_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sounak Ray&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chang_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shih-Fu Chang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.07066">
<title>Controllable Citation Sentence Generation with Language Models. (arXiv:2211.07066v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.07066</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Citation generation aims to generate a citation sentence that refers to a
chosen paper in the context of a manuscript. However, a rigid citation
generation process is at odds with an author&apos;s desire to control specific
attributes, such as 1) the citation intent, e.g., either introducing background
information or comparing results, and 2) keywords that should appear in the
citation text. To provide these degrees of controllability during citation
generation, we propose to integrate the manuscript context, the context of the
referenced paper, and the desired control attributes into a structured template
and use it to fine-tune a language model (LM) via next-token prediction. We
then utilize Proximal Policy Optimization to directly optimize the LM in favor
of a high score of our proposed controllability metric. The proposed workflow
harmoniously combines citation attribute suggestion and conditional citation
generation into one LM, allowing for better user control.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gu_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nianlong Gu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hahnloser_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Richard H.R. Hahnloser&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.01313">
<title>Double Equivariance for Inductive Link Prediction for Both New Nodes and New Relation Types. (arXiv:2302.01313v7 [cs.LG] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.01313</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The task of inductive link prediction in knowledge graphs (KGs) generally
focuses on test predictions with solely new nodes but not both new nodes and
new relation types. In this work, we formally define the concept of double
permutation-equivariant representations that are equivariant to permutations of
both node identities and edge relation types. We then show how
double-equivariant architectures are able to self-supervise pre-train on
distinct KG domains and zero-shot predict links on a new KG domain (with
completely new entities and new relation types). We also introduce the concept
of distributionally double equivariant positional embeddings designed to
perform the same task. Finally, we empirically demonstrate the capability of
the proposed models against baselines on a set of novel real-world benchmarks.
More interestingly, we show that self-supervised pre-training on more KG
domains increases the zero-shot ability of our model to predict on new relation
types over new entities on unseen KG domains.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gao_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jianfei Gao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhou_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yangze Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhou_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jincheng Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ribeiro_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bruno Ribeiro&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.01903">
<title>Prophet: Prompting Large Language Models with Complementary Answer Heuristics for Knowledge-based Visual Question Answering. (arXiv:2303.01903v3 [cs.CV] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.01903</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Knowledge-based visual question answering (VQA) requires external knowledge
beyond the image to answer the question. Early studies retrieve required
knowledge from explicit knowledge bases (KBs), which often introduces
irrelevant information to the question, hence restricting the performance of
their models. Recent works have resorted to using a powerful large language
model (LLM) as an implicit knowledge engine to acquire the necessary knowledge
for answering. Despite the encouraging results achieved by these methods, we
argue that they have not fully activated the capacity of the blind LLM as the
provided textual input is insufficient to depict the required visual
information to answer the question. In this paper, we present Prophet -- a
conceptually simple, flexible, and general framework designed to prompt LLM
with answer heuristics for knowledge-based VQA. Specifically, we first train a
vanilla VQA model on a specific knowledge-based VQA dataset without external
knowledge. After that, we extract two types of complementary answer heuristics
from the VQA model: answer candidates and answer-aware examples. Finally, the
two types of answer heuristics are jointly encoded into a formatted prompt to
facilitate the LLM&apos;s understanding of both the image and question, thus
generating a more accurate answer. By incorporating the state-of-the-art LLM
GPT-3, Prophet significantly outperforms existing state-of-the-art methods on
four challenging knowledge-based VQA datasets. To demonstrate the generality of
our approach, we instantiate Prophet with the combinations of different VQA
models (i.e., both discriminative and generative ones) and different LLMs
(i.e., both commercial and open-source ones).
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yu_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhou Yu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ouyang_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xuecheng Ouyang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shao_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhenwei Shao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Meng Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jun Yu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.03919">
<title>Data Portraits: Recording Foundation Model Training Data. (arXiv:2303.03919v2 [cs.LG] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.03919</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Foundation models are trained on increasingly immense and opaque datasets.
Even while these models are now key in AI system building, it can be difficult
to answer the straightforward question: has the model already encountered a
given example during training? We therefore propose a widespread adoption of
Data Portraits: artifacts that record training data and allow for downstream
inspection. First we outline the properties of such an artifact and discuss how
existing solutions can be used to increase transparency. We then propose and
implement a solution based on data sketching, stressing fast and space
efficient querying. Using our tools, we document a popular language modeling
corpus (The Pile) and a recently released code modeling dataset (The Stack). We
show that our solution enables answering questions about test set leakage and
model plagiarism. Our tool is lightweight and fast, costing only 3% of the
dataset size in overhead. We release a live interface of our tools at
https://dataportraits.org/ and call on dataset and model creators to release
Data Portraits as a complement to current documentation practices.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Marone_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marc Marone&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Durme_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Benjamin Van Durme&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.07235">
<title>What does self-attention learn from Masked Language Modelling?. (arXiv:2304.07235v2 [cond-mat.dis-nn] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.07235</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Transformers are neural networks which revolutionised natural language
processing and machine learning. They process sequences of inputs, like words,
using a mechanism called self-attention, which is trained via masked language
modelling (MLM). In MLM, a word is randomly masked in an input sequence, and
the network is trained to predict the missing word. Despite the practical
success of transformers, it remains unclear what type of data distribution
self-attention can learn efficiently. Here, we show analytically that if one
decouples the treatment of word positions and embeddings, a single layer of
self-attention learns the conditionals of a generalised Potts model with
interactions between sites and Potts colours. Moreover, we show that training
this neural network is exactly equivalent to solving the inverse Potts problem
by the so-called pseudo-likelihood method, well known in statistical physics.
Using this mapping, we compute the generalisation error of self-attention in a
model scenario analytically using the replica method.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Rende_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Riccardo Rende&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Gerace_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Federica Gerace&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Laio_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alessandro Laio&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Goldt_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sebastian Goldt&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.10847">
<title>Large Language Models can be Guided to Evade AI-Generated Text Detection. (arXiv:2305.10847v5 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.10847</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Large language models (LLMs) have shown remarkable performance in various
tasks and have been extensively utilized by the public. However, the increasing
concerns regarding the misuse of LLMs, such as plagiarism and spamming, have
led to the development of multiple detectors, including fine-tuned classifiers
and statistical methods. In this study, we equip LLMs with prompts, rather than
relying on an external paraphraser, to evaluate the vulnerability of these
detectors. We propose a novel Substitution-based In-Context example
Optimization method (SICO) to automatically construct prompts for evading the
detectors. SICO is cost-efficient as it requires only 40 human-written examples
and a limited number of LLM inferences to generate a prompt. Moreover, once a
task-specific prompt has been constructed, it can be universally used against a
wide range of detectors. Extensive experiments across three real-world tasks
demonstrate that SICO significantly outperforms the paraphraser baselines and
enables GPT-3.5 to successfully evade six detectors, decreasing their AUC by
0.5 on average. Furthermore, a comprehensive human evaluation as well as a
validation experiment in the wild show that the SICO-generated text achieves
human-level readability and task completion rates. Finally, the strong
performance of SICO exhibits its potential as a reliable evaluation tool for
future detectors. The codes and data are located on
https://github.com/ColinLu50/Evade-GPT-Detector.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lu_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ning Lu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shengcai Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+He_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rui He&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qi Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ong_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yew-Soon Ong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tang_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ke Tang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.13721">
<title>Continual Dialogue State Tracking via Example-Guided Question Answering. (arXiv:2305.13721v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.13721</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Dialogue systems are frequently updated to accommodate new services, but
naively updating them by continually training with data for new services in
diminishing performance on previously learnt services. Motivated by the insight
that dialogue state tracking (DST), a crucial component of dialogue systems
that estimates the user&apos;s goal as a conversation proceeds, is a simple natural
language understanding task, we propose reformulating it as a bundle of
granular example-guided question answering tasks to minimize the task shift
between services and thus benefit continual learning. Our approach alleviates
service-specific memorization and teaches a model to contextualize the given
question and example to extract the necessary information from the
conversation. We find that a model with just 60M parameters can achieve a
significant boost by learning to learn from in-context examples retrieved by a
retriever trained to identify turns with similar dialogue state changes.
Combining our method with dialogue-level memory replay, our approach attains
state of the art performance on DST continual learning metrics without relying
on any complex regularization or parameter expansion methods.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cho_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hyundong Cho&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Madotto_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrea Madotto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lin_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhaojiang Lin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chandu_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Khyathi Raghavi Chandu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kottur_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Satwik Kottur&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jing Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+May_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jonathan May&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sankar_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chinnadhurai Sankar&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.14973">
<title>OverPrompt: Enhancing ChatGPT through Efficient In-Context Learning. (arXiv:2305.14973v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.14973</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The remarkable performance of pre-trained large language models has
revolutionised various natural language processing applications. Due to huge
parametersizes and extensive running costs, companies or organisations tend to
transfer the models to the target task by zero-shot prompting techniques.
However, the prohibitive costs of tokens and time have hindered their adoption
in applications. We propose OverPrompt, leveraging the in-context learning
capability of LLMs to handle multiple task inputs, thereby reducing token and
time costs. This approach could potentially improve task performance during API
queries due to better conditional distribution mapping. Evaluated across
diverse classification datasets, our experiments show that OverPrompt can
achieve cost-efficient zero-shot classification without causing significant
detriment to task performance, and in some cases, even improving it. An
ablation study conducted on various LLMs, along with an investigation into the
robustness of our prompting strategy to different input ordering, offers
valuable insights into the broader applicability of our method across diverse
tasks. These findings also suggest a more seamless integration of our method
with LLMs through an API.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiazheng Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhao_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Runcong Zhao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yongxin Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+He_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yulan He&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gui_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lin Gui&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2308.06385">
<title>ZYN: Zero-Shot Reward Models with Yes-No Questions for RLAIF. (arXiv:2308.06385v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2308.06385</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this work, we address the problem of directing the text generation of a
language model (LM) towards a desired behavior, aligning the generated text
with the preferences of the human operator. We propose using another,
instruction-tuned language model as a critic reward model in a zero-shot way
thanks to the prompt of a Yes-No question that represents the user preferences,
without requiring further labeled data. This zero-shot reward model provides
the learning signal to further fine-tune the base LM using Reinforcement
Learning from AI Feedback (RLAIF); yet our approach is also compatible in other
contexts such as quality-diversity search. Extensive evidence of the
capabilities of the proposed ZYN framework is provided through experiments in
different domains related to text generation, including detoxification;
optimizing sentiment of movie reviews, or any other attribute; steering the
opinion about a particular topic the model may have; and personalizing prompt
generators for text-to-image tasks. Code available at
\url{https://github.com/vicgalle/zero-shot-reward-models/}.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gallego_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Victor Gallego&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.03559">
<title>An Anchor Learning Approach for Citation Field Learning. (arXiv:2309.03559v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.03559</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Citation field learning is to segment a citation string into fields of
interest such as author, title, and venue. Extracting such fields from
citations is crucial for citation indexing, researcher profile analysis, etc.
User-generated resources like academic homepages and Curriculum Vitae, provide
rich citation field information. However, extracting fields from these
resources is challenging due to inconsistent citation styles, incomplete
sentence syntax, and insufficient training data. To address these challenges,
we propose a novel algorithm, CIFAL (citation field learning by anchor
learning), to boost the citation field learning performance. CIFAL leverages
the anchor learning, which is model-agnostic for any Pre-trained Language
Model, to help capture citation patterns from the data of different citation
styles. The experiments demonstrate that CIFAL outperforms state-of-the-art
methods in citation field learning, achieving a 2.68% improvement in
field-level F1-scores. Extensive analysis of the results further confirms the
effectiveness of CIFAL quantitatively and qualitatively.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yuan_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zilin Yuan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Borun Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Dai_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yimeng Dai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yinghui Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zheng_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hai-Tao Zheng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rui Zhang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.08628">
<title>Recovering from Privacy-Preserving Masking with Large Language Models. (arXiv:2309.08628v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.08628</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Model adaptation is crucial to handle the discrepancy between proxy training
data and actual users data received. To effectively perform adaptation, textual
data of users is typically stored on servers or their local devices, where
downstream natural language processing (NLP) models can be directly trained
using such in-domain data. However, this might raise privacy and security
concerns due to the extra risks of exposing user information to adversaries.
Replacing identifying information in textual data with a generic marker has
been recently explored. In this work, we leverage large language models (LLMs)
to suggest substitutes of masked tokens and have their effectiveness evaluated
on downstream language modeling tasks. Specifically, we propose multiple
pre-trained and fine-tuned LLM-based approaches and perform empirical studies
on various datasets for the comparison of these methods. Experimental results
show that models trained on the obfuscation corpora are able to achieve
comparable performance with the ones trained on the original data without
privacy-preserving token masking.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Vats_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Arpita Vats&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhe Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Su_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Peng Su&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Paul_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Debjyoti Paul&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ma_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yingyi Ma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Pang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yutong Pang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ahmed_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zeeshan Ahmed&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kalinli_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ozlem Kalinli&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.02207">
<title>Language Models Represent Space and Time. (arXiv:2310.02207v2 [cs.LG] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.02207</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The capabilities of large language models (LLMs) have sparked debate over
whether such systems just learn an enormous collection of superficial
statistics or a coherent model of the data generation process -- a world model.
We find preliminary evidence for the latter by analyzing the learned
representations of three spatial datasets (world, US, NYC places) and three
temporal datasets (historical figures, artworks, news headlines) in the Llama-2
family of models. We discover that LLMs learn linear representations of space
and time across multiple scales. These representations are robust to prompting
variations and unified across different entity types (e.g. cities and
landmarks). In addition, we identify individual ``space neurons&apos;&apos; and ``time
neurons&apos;&apos; that reliably encode spatial and temporal coordinates. While further
investigation is needed, our results suggest modern LLMs learn rich
spatiotemporal representations of the real world and possess basic ingredients
of a world model.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gurnee_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wes Gurnee&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tegmark_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Max Tegmark&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.05804">
<title>Learning Language-guided Adaptive Hyper-modality Representation for Multimodal Sentiment Analysis. (arXiv:2310.05804v2 [cs.AI] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.05804</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Though Multimodal Sentiment Analysis (MSA) proves effective by utilizing rich
information from multiple sources (e.g., language, video, and audio), the
potential sentiment-irrelevant and conflicting information across modalities
may hinder the performance from being further improved. To alleviate this, we
present Adaptive Language-guided Multimodal Transformer (ALMT), which
incorporates an Adaptive Hyper-modality Learning (AHL) module to learn an
irrelevance/conflict-suppressing representation from visual and audio features
under the guidance of language features at different scales. With the obtained
hyper-modality representation, the model can obtain a complementary and joint
representation through multimodal fusion for effective MSA. In practice, ALMT
achieves state-of-the-art performance on several popular datasets (e.g., MOSI,
MOSEI and CH-SIMS) and an abundance of ablation demonstrates the validity and
necessity of our irrelevance/conflict suppression mechanism.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Haoyu Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yu Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yin_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Guanghao Yin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kejun Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuanyuan Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yu_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tianshu Yu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.10158">
<title>Character-LLM: A Trainable Agent for Role-Playing. (arXiv:2310.10158v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.10158</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Large language models (LLMs) can be used to serve as agents to simulate human
behaviors, given the powerful ability to understand human instructions and
provide high-quality generated texts. Such ability stimulates us to wonder
whether LLMs can simulate a person in a higher form than simple human
behaviors. Therefore, we aim to train an agent with the profile, experience,
and emotional states of a specific person instead of using limited prompts to
instruct ChatGPT API. In this work, we introduce Character-LLM that teach LLMs
to act as specific people such as Beethoven, Queen Cleopatra, Julius Caesar,
etc. Our method focuses on editing profiles as experiences of a certain
character and training models to be personal simulacra with these experiences.
To assess the effectiveness of our approach, we build a test playground that
interviews trained agents and evaluates whether the agents \textit{memorize}
their characters and experiences. Experimental results show interesting
observations that help build future simulacra of humankind.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shao_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yunfan Shao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Linyang Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Dai_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Junqi Dai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Qiu_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xipeng Qiu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.10605">
<title>ForceGen: End-to-end de novo protein generation based on nonlinear mechanical unfolding responses using a language diffusion model. (arXiv:2310.10605v2 [cond-mat.mtrl-sci] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.10605</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Through evolution, nature has presented a set of remarkable protein
materials, including elastins, silks, keratins and collagens with superior
mechanical performances that play crucial roles in mechanobiology. However,
going beyond natural designs to discover proteins that meet specified
mechanical properties remains challenging. Here we report a generative model
that predicts protein designs to meet complex nonlinear mechanical
property-design objectives. Our model leverages deep knowledge on protein
sequences from a pre-trained protein language model and maps mechanical
unfolding responses to create novel proteins. Via full-atom molecular
simulations for direct validation, we demonstrate that the designed proteins
are novel, and fulfill the targeted mechanical properties, including unfolding
energy and mechanical strength, as well as the detailed unfolding
force-separation curves. Our model offers rapid pathways to explore the
enormous mechanobiological protein sequence space unconstrained by biological
synthesis, using mechanical features as target to enable the discovery of
protein materials with superior mechanical properties.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Ni_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bo Ni&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Kaplan_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;David L. Kaplan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Buehler_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Markus J. Buehler&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.11648">
<title>Zero-shot Faithfulness Evaluation for Text Summarization with Foundation Language Model. (arXiv:2310.11648v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.11648</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Despite tremendous improvements in natural language generation, summarization
models still suffer from the unfaithfulness issue. Previous work evaluates
faithfulness either using models trained on the other tasks or in-domain
synthetic data, or prompting a large model such as ChatGPT. This paper proposes
to do zero-shot faithfulness evaluation simply with a moderately-sized
foundation language model. We introduce a new metric FFLM, which is a
combination of probability changes based on the intuition that prefixing a
piece of text that is consistent with the output will increase the probability
of predicting the output. Experiments show that FFLM performs competitively
with or even outperforms ChatGPT on both inconsistency detection and
faithfulness rating with 24x fewer parameters. FFLM also achieves improvements
over other strong baselines.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jia_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qi Jia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ren_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Siyu Ren&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yizhu Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhu_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kenny Q. Zhu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.15140">
<title>AutoDAN: Interpretable Gradient-Based Adversarial Attacks on Large Language Models. (arXiv:2310.15140v2 [cs.CR] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.15140</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Safety alignment of Large Language Models (LLMs) can be compromised with
manual jailbreak attacks and (automatic) adversarial attacks. Recent studies
suggest that defending against these attacks is possible: adversarial attacks
generate unlimited but unreadable gibberish prompts, detectable by
perplexity-based filters; manual jailbreak attacks craft readable prompts, but
their limited number due to the necessity of human creativity allows for easy
blocking. In this paper, we show that these solutions may be too optimistic. We
introduce AutoDAN, an interpretable, gradient-based adversarial attack that
merges the strengths of both attack types. Guided by the dual goals of
jailbreak and readability, AutoDAN optimizes and generates tokens one by one
from left to right, resulting in readable prompts that bypass perplexity
filters while maintaining high attack success rates. Notably, these prompts,
generated from scratch using gradients, are interpretable and diverse, with
emerging strategies commonly seen in manual jailbreak attacks. They also
generalize to unforeseen harmful behaviors and transfer to black-box LLMs
better than their unreadable counterparts when using limited training data or a
single proxy model. Furthermore, we show the versatility of AutoDAN by
automatically leaking system prompts using a customized objective. Our work
offers a new way to red-team LLMs and understand jailbreak mechanisms via
interpretability.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhu_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sicheng Zhu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ruiyi Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+An_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bang An&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wu_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gang Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Barrow_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Joe Barrow&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zichao Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Huang_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Furong Huang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Nenkova_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ani Nenkova&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sun_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tong Sun&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.15517">
<title>MarkQA: A large scale KBQA dataset with numerical reasoning. (arXiv:2310.15517v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.15517</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;While question answering over knowledge bases (KBQA) has shown progress in
addressing factoid questions, KBQA with numerical reasoning remains relatively
unexplored. In this paper, we focus on the complex numerical reasoning in KBQA
and propose a new task, NR-KBQA, which necessitates the ability to perform both
multi-hop reasoning and numerical reasoning. We design a logic form in Python
format called PyQL to represent the reasoning process of numerical reasoning
questions. To facilitate the development of NR-KBQA, we present a large dataset
called MarkQA, which is automatically constructed from a small set of seeds.
Each question in MarkQA is equipped with its corresponding SPARQL query,
alongside the step-by-step reasoning process in the QDMR format and PyQL
program. Experimental results of some state-of-the-art QA methods on the MarkQA
show that complex numerical reasoning in KBQA faces great challenges.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Huang_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiang Huang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cheng_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sitao Cheng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bao_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuheng Bao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Huang_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shanshan Huang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Qu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuzhong Qu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.18168">
<title>Personas as a Way to Model Truthfulness in Language Models. (arXiv:2310.18168v4 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.18168</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Large Language Models (LLMs) are trained on vast amounts of text from the
internet, which contains both factual and misleading information about the
world. Can language models discern truth from falsehood in this contradicting
data? Expanding on the view that LLMs can model different communicative agents,
we present the persona hypothesis: LLMs can cluster agents into personas using
common features of their generations. For instance, a truthful persona is a
group of agents that are likely to produce truthful text and that share similar
features like formal writing styles and scientific references. By modeling this
persona, LLMs can generalize truthfulness beyond the specific contexts in which
each agent generated the training text. For example, the model can infer that
the agent &quot;Wikipedia&quot; will behave truthfully on topics that were only generated
by &quot;Science&quot; because they both belong to the truthful persona. We show evidence
for the persona hypothesis via two observations: (1) we can probe whether a
model&apos;s answer will be truthful before it is generated; (2) finetuning a model
on a set of facts improves its truthfulness on unseen topics. Next, using
arithmetics as a synthetic environment, we show that language models can
separate true and false statements, and generalize truthfulness across agents;
but only if agents in the training data share a truthful generative process
that enables the creation of a truthful persona. Overall, our findings suggest
that models can exploit hierarchical structures in the data to learn abstract
concepts like truthfulness.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Joshi_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nitish Joshi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Rando_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Javier Rando&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Saparov_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Abulhair Saparov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kim_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Najoung Kim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+He_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;He He&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.03731">
<title>A Survey of Large Language Models Attribution. (arXiv:2311.03731v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.03731</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Open-domain generative systems have gained significant attention in the field
of conversational AI (e.g., generative search engines). This paper presents a
comprehensive review of the attribution mechanisms employed by these systems,
particularly large language models. Though attribution or citation improve the
factuality and verifiability, issues like ambiguous knowledge reservoirs,
inherent biases, and the drawbacks of excessive attribution can hinder the
effectiveness of these systems. The aim of this survey is to provide valuable
insights for researchers, aiding in the refinement of attribution methodologies
to enhance the reliability and veracity of responses generated by open-domain
generative systems. We believe that this field is still in its early stages;
hence, we maintain a repository to keep track of ongoing studies at
https://github.com/HITsz-TMG/awesome-llm-attributions.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dongfang Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sun_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zetian Sun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hu_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xinshuo Hu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhenyu Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ziyang Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hu_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Baotian Hu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wu_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aiguo Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Min Zhang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.04915">
<title>Chain of Empathy: Enhancing Empathetic Response of Large Language Models Based on Psychotherapy Models. (arXiv:2311.04915v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.04915</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present a novel method, the Chain of Empathy (CoE) prompting, that
utilizes insights from psychotherapy to induce Large Language Models (LLMs) to
reason about human emotional states. This method is inspired by various
psychotherapy approaches including Cognitive Behavioral Therapy (CBT),
Dialectical Behavior Therapy (DBT), Person Centered Therapy (PCT), and Reality
Therapy (RT), each leading to different patterns of interpreting clients&apos;
mental states. LLMs without reasoning generated predominantly exploratory
responses. However, when LLMs used CoE reasoning, we found a more comprehensive
range of empathetic responses aligned with the different reasoning patterns of
each psychotherapy model. The CBT based CoE resulted in the most balanced
generation of empathetic responses. The findings underscore the importance of
understanding the emotional context and how it affects human and AI
communication. Our research contributes to understanding how psychotherapeutic
models can be incorporated into LLMs, facilitating the development of
context-specific, safer, and empathetic AI.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lee_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yoon Kyung Lee&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lee_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Inju Lee&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shin_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Minjung Shin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bae_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Seoyeon Bae&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hahn_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sowon Hahn&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.14483">
<title>SER_AMPEL: a multi-source dataset for speech emotion recognition of Italian older adults. (arXiv:2311.14483v2 [eess.AS] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.14483</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this paper, SER_AMPEL, a multi-source dataset for speech emotion
recognition (SER) is presented. The peculiarity of the dataset is that it is
collected with the aim of providing a reference for speech emotion recognition
in case of Italian older adults. The dataset is collected following different
protocols, in particular considering acted conversations, extracted from movies
and TV series, and recording natural conversations where the emotions are
elicited by proper questions. The evidence of the need for such a dataset
emerges from the analysis of the state of the art. Preliminary considerations
on the critical issues of SER are reported analyzing the classification results
on a subset of the proposed dataset.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Grossi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alessandra Grossi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Gasparini_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Francesca Gasparini&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.03664">
<title>Generative agent-based modeling with actions grounded in physical, social, or digital space using Concordia. (arXiv:2312.03664v2 [cs.AI] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.03664</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Agent-based modeling has been around for decades, and applied widely across
the social and natural sciences. The scope of this research method is now
poised to grow dramatically as it absorbs the new affordances provided by Large
Language Models (LLM)s. Generative Agent-Based Models (GABM) are not just
classic Agent-Based Models (ABM)s where the agents talk to one another. Rather,
GABMs are constructed using an LLM to apply common sense to situations, act
&quot;reasonably&quot;, recall common semantic knowledge, produce API calls to control
digital technologies like apps, and communicate both within the simulation and
to researchers viewing it from the outside. Here we present Concordia, a
library to facilitate constructing and working with GABMs. Concordia makes it
easy to construct language-mediated simulations of physically- or
digitally-grounded environments. Concordia agents produce their behavior using
a flexible component system which mediates between two fundamental operations:
LLM calls and associative memory retrieval. A special agent called the Game
Master (GM), which was inspired by tabletop role-playing games, is responsible
for simulating the environment where the agents interact. Agents take actions
by describing what they want to do in natural language. The GM then translates
their actions into appropriate implementations. In a simulated physical world,
the GM checks the physical plausibility of agent actions and describes their
effects. In digital environments simulating technologies such as apps and
services, the GM may handle API calls to integrate with external tools such as
general AI assistants (e.g., Bard, ChatGPT), and digital apps (e.g., Calendar,
Email, Search, etc.). Concordia was designed to support a wide array of
applications both in scientific research and for evaluating performance of real
digital services by simulating users and/or generating synthetic data.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Vezhnevets_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alexander Sasha Vezhnevets&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Agapiou_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;John P. Agapiou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Aharon_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Avia Aharon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ziv_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ron Ziv&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Matyas_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jayd Matyas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Duenez_Guzman_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Edgar A. Du&amp;#xe9;&amp;#xf1;ez-Guzm&amp;#xe1;n&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cunningham_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;William A. Cunningham&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Osindero_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Simon Osindero&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Karmon_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Danny Karmon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Leibo_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Joel Z. Leibo&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.03731">
<title>MultiGPrompt for Multi-Task Pre-Training and Prompting on Graphs. (arXiv:2312.03731v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.03731</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Graphs can inherently model interconnected objects on the Web, thereby
facilitating a series of Web applications, such as web analyzing and content
recommendation. Recently, Graph Neural Networks (GNNs) have emerged as a
mainstream technique for graph representation learning. However, their efficacy
within an end-to-end supervised framework is significantly tied to the
availabilityof task-specific labels. To mitigate labeling costs and enhance
robustness in few-shot settings, pre-training on self-supervised tasks has
emerged as a promising method, while prompting has been proposed to further
narrow the objective gap between pretext and downstream tasks. Although there
has been some initial exploration of prompt-based learning on graphs, they
primarily leverage a single pretext task, resulting in a limited subset of
general knowledge that could be learned from the pre-training data. Hence, in
this paper, we propose MultiGPrompt, a novel multi-task pre-training and
prompting framework to exploit multiple pretext tasks for more comprehensive
pre-trained knowledge. First, in pre-training, we design a set of pretext
tokens to synergize multiple pretext tasks. Second, we propose a dual-prompt
mechanism consisting of composed and open prompts to leverage task-specific and
global pre-training knowledge, to guide downstream tasks in few-shot settings.
Finally, we conduct extensive experiments on six public datasets to evaluate
and analyze MultiGPrompt.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yu_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xingtong Yu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhou_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chang Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Fang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuan Fang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xinming Zhang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.03818">
<title>Alpha-CLIP: A CLIP Model Focusing on Wherever You Want. (arXiv:2312.03818v2 [cs.CV] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.03818</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Contrastive Language-Image Pre-training (CLIP) plays an essential role in
extracting valuable content information from images across diverse tasks. It
aligns textual and visual modalities to comprehend the entire image, including
all the details, even those irrelevant to specific tasks. However, for a finer
understanding and controlled editing of images, it becomes crucial to focus on
specific regions of interest, which can be indicated as points, masks, or boxes
by humans or perception models. To fulfill the requirements, we introduce
Alpha-CLIP, an enhanced version of CLIP with an auxiliary alpha channel to
suggest attentive regions and fine-tuned with constructed millions of RGBA
region-text pairs. Alpha-CLIP not only preserves the visual recognition ability
of CLIP but also enables precise control over the emphasis of image contents.
It demonstrates effectiveness in various tasks, including but not limited to
open-world recognition, multimodal large language models, and conditional 2D /
3D generation. It has a strong potential to serve as a versatile tool for
image-related tasks.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sun_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zeyi Sun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Fang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ye Fang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wu_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tong Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pan Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuhang Zang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kong_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shu Kong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xiong_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuanjun Xiong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lin_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dahua Lin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiaqi Wang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.04333">
<title>Beyond Surface: Probing LLaMA Across Scales and Layers. (arXiv:2312.04333v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.04333</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This paper presents an in-depth analysis of Large Language Models (LLMs),
focusing on LLaMA, a prominent open-source foundational model in natural
language processing. Instead of assessing LLaMA through its generative output,
we design multiple-choice tasks to probe its intrinsic understanding in
high-order tasks such as reasoning and computation. We examine the model
horizontally, comparing different sizes, and vertically, assessing different
layers. We unveil several key and uncommon findings based on the designed
probing tasks: (1) Horizontally, enlarging model sizes almost could not
automatically impart additional knowledge or computational prowess. Instead, it
can enhance reasoning abilities, especially in math problem solving, and helps
reduce hallucinations, but only beyond certain size thresholds; (2) In vertical
analysis, the lower layers of LLaMA lack substantial arithmetic and factual
knowledge, showcasing logical thinking, multilingual and recognitive abilities,
with top layers housing most computational power and real-world knowledge.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nuo Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wu_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ning Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liang_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shining Liang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gong_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ming Gong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shou_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Linjun Shou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dongmei Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jia Li&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.05497">
<title>History Matters: Temporal Knowledge Editing in Large Language Model. (arXiv:2312.05497v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.05497</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The imperative task of revising or updating the knowledge stored within large
language models arises from two distinct sources: intrinsic errors inherent in
the model which should be corrected and outdated knowledge due to external
shifts in the real world which should be updated. Prevailing efforts in model
editing conflate these two distinct categories of edits arising from distinct
reasons and directly modify the original knowledge in models into new
knowledge. However, we argue that preserving the model&apos;s original knowledge
remains pertinent. Specifically, if a model&apos;s knowledge becomes outdated due to
evolving worldly dynamics, it should retain recollection of the historical
knowledge while integrating the newfound knowledge. In this work, we introduce
the task of Temporal Knowledge Editing (TKE) and establish a benchmark AToKe
(Assessment of TempOral Knowledge Editing) to evaluate current model editing
methods. We find that while existing model editing methods are effective at
making models remember new knowledge, the edited model catastrophically forgets
historical knowledge. To address this gap, we propose a simple and general
framework termed Multi-Editing with Time Objective (METO) for enhancing
existing editing models, which edits both historical and new knowledge
concurrently and optimizes the model&apos;s prediction for the time of each fact.
Our assessments demonstrate that while AToKe is still difficult, METO maintains
the effectiveness of learning new knowledge and meanwhile substantially
improves the performance of edited models on utilizing historical knowledge.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yin_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xunjian Yin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jiang_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jin Jiang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yang_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Liming Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wan_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaojun Wan&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.07492">
<title>SocialStigmaQA: A Benchmark to Uncover Stigma Amplification in Generative Language Models. (arXiv:2312.07492v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.07492</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Current datasets for unwanted social bias auditing are limited to studying
protected demographic features such as race and gender. In this work, we
introduce a comprehensive benchmark that is meant to capture the amplification
of social bias, via stigmas, in generative language models. We start with a
comprehensive list of 93 stigmas documented in social science literature and
curate a question-answering (QA) dataset which involves simple social
situations. Our benchmark, SocialStigmaQA, contains roughly 10K prompts, with a
variety of prompt styles, carefully constructed to systematically test for both
social bias and model robustness. We present results for SocialStigmaQA with
two widely used open source generative language models and we demonstrate that
the output generated by these models considerably amplifies existing social
bias against stigmatized groups. Specifically, we find that the proportion of
socially biased output ranges from 45% to 59% across a variety of decoding
strategies and prompting styles. We discover that the deliberate design of the
templates in our benchmark (e.g., by adding biasing text to the prompt or
varying the answer that indicates bias) impact the model tendencies to generate
socially biased output. Additionally, we report on patterns in the generated
chain-of-thought output, finding a variety of problems from subtle bias to
evidence of a lack of reasoning.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warning: This paper contains examples of text which is toxic, biased, and
harmful.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Nagireddy_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Manish Nagireddy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chiazor_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lamogha Chiazor&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Singh_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Moninder Singh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Baldini_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ioana Baldini&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.07622">
<title>Mathematical Language Models: A Survey. (arXiv:2312.07622v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.07622</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In recent years, there has been remarkable progress in leveraging Language
Models (LMs), encompassing Pre-trained Language Models (PLMs) and Large-scale
Language Models (LLMs), within the domain of mathematics. This paper conducts a
comprehensive survey of mathematical LMs, systematically categorizing pivotal
research endeavors from two distinct perspectives: tasks and methodologies. The
landscape reveals a large number of proposed mathematical LLMs, which are
further delineated into instruction learning, tool-based methods, fundamental
CoT techniques, and advanced CoT methodologies. In addition, our survey entails
the compilation of over 60 mathematical datasets, including training datasets,
benchmark datasets, and augmented datasets. Addressing the primary challenges
and delineating future trajectories within the field of mathematical LMs, this
survey is positioned as a valuable resource, poised to facilitate and inspire
future innovation among researchers invested in advancing this domain.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wentao Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hu_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hanglei Hu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhou_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jie Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ding_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuyang Ding&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Junsong Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zeng_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiayi Zeng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+He_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mengliang He&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qin Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jiang_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bo Jiang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhou_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aimin Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+He_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Liang He&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.07987">
<title>SwitchHead: Accelerating Transformers with Mixture-of-Experts Attention. (arXiv:2312.07987v2 [cs.LG] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.07987</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The costly self-attention layers in modern Transformers require memory and
compute quadratic in sequence length. Existing approximation methods usually
underperform and fail to obtain significant speedups in practice. Here we
present SwitchHead - a novel method that reduces both compute and memory
requirements and achieves wall-clock speedup, while matching the language
modeling performance of baseline Transformers with the same parameter budget.
SwitchHead uses Mixture-of-Experts (MoE) layers for the value and output
projections and requires 4 to 8 times fewer attention matrices than standard
Transformers. Our novel attention can also be combined with MoE MLP layers,
resulting in an efficient fully-MoE &quot;SwitchAll&quot; Transformer model. Our code is
public.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Csordas_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R&amp;#xf3;bert Csord&amp;#xe1;s&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Piekos_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Piotr Pi&amp;#x119;kos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Irie_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kazuki Irie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Schmidhuber_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J&amp;#xfc;rgen Schmidhuber&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08078">
<title>Fine-Grained Image-Text Alignment in Medical Imaging Enables Cyclic Image-Report Generation. (arXiv:2312.08078v2 [cs.CV] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08078</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;To address these issues, we propose a novel Adaptive patch-word Matching
(AdaMatch) model to correlate chest X-ray (CXR) image regions with words in
medical reports and apply it to CXR-report generation to provide explainability
for the generation process. AdaMatch exploits the fine-grained relation between
adaptive patches and words to provide explanations of specific image regions
with corresponding words. To capture the abnormal regions of varying sizes and
positions, we introduce the Adaptive Patch extraction (AdaPatch) module to
acquire the adaptive patches for these regions adaptively. In order to provide
explicit explainability for CXR-report generation task, we propose an
AdaMatch-based bidirectional large language model for Cyclic CXR-report
generation (AdaMatch-Cyclic). It employs the AdaMatch to obtain the keywords
for CXR images and `keypatches&apos; for medical reports as hints to guide
CXR-report generation. Extensive experiments on two publicly available CXR
datasets prove the effectiveness of our method and its superior performance to
existing methods.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wenting Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiang Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shen_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Linlin Shen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yuan_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yixuan Yuan&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08274">
<title>High-throughput Biomedical Relation Extraction for Semi-Structured Web Articles Empowered by Large Language Models. (arXiv:2312.08274v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.08274</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Objective: To develop a high-throughput biomedical relation extraction system
that takes advantage of the large language models&apos; (LLMs) reading comprehension
ability and biomedical world knowledge in a scalable and evidential manner.
Methods: We formulate the relation extraction task as a simple binary
classification problem for large language models such as ChatGPT. Specifically,
LLMs make the decision based on the external corpus and its world knowledge,
giving the reason for the judgment to factual verification. This method is
tailored for semi-structured web articles, wherein we designate the main title
as the tail entity and explicitly incorporate it into the context, and the
potential head entities are matched based on a biomedical thesaurus. Moreover,
lengthy contents are sliced into text chunks, embedded, and retrieved with
additional embedding models, ensuring compatibility with the context window
size constraints of available open-source LLMs. Results: Using an open-source
LLM, we extracted 304315 relation triplets of three distinct relation types
from four reputable biomedical websites. To assess the efficacy of the basic
pipeline employed for biomedical relation extraction, we curated a benchmark
dataset annotated by a medical expert. Evaluation results indicate that the
pipeline exhibits performance comparable to that of GPT-4. Case studies further
illuminate challenges faced by contemporary LLMs in the context of biomedical
relation extraction for semi-structured web articles. Conclusion: The proposed
method has demonstrated its effectiveness in leveraging the strengths of LLMs
for high-throughput biomedical relation extraction. Its adaptability is
evident, as it can be seamlessly extended to diverse semi-structured biomedical
websites, facilitating the extraction of various types of biomedical relations
with ease.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhou_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Songchi Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yu_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sheng Yu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>