<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Computer Science -- Computation and Language (cs.CL) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2023-12-05T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Computer Science -- Computation and Language</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02179" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02181" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02188" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02206" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02219" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02227" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02249" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02251" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02296" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02310" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02314" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02317" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02331" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02334" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02337" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02382" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02406" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02418" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02431" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02436" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02439" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02441" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02496" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02532" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02549" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02554" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02578" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02590" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02598" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02614" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02706" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02730" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02748" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02780" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02783" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02798" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02803" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02820" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02869" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.16934" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2212.09917" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.16894" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.11863" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.17819" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2306.04743" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2306.11300" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2306.15448" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2306.17840" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2308.16549" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.10313" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.12307" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.01415" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.04406" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.07135" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.16570" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.20138" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.20204" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.04923" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.07989" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.13307" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.15218" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.16989" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.18743" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.01529" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.01678" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02143" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02179">
<title>Training Chain-of-Thought via Latent-Variable Inference. (arXiv:2312.02179v1 [cs.LG])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02179</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Large language models (LLMs) solve problems more accurately and interpretably
when instructed to work out the answer step by step using a
``chain-of-thought&apos;&apos; (CoT) prompt. One can also improve LLMs&apos; performance on a
specific task by supervised fine-tuning, i.e., by using gradient ascent on some
tunable parameters to maximize the average log-likelihood of correct answers
from a labeled training set. Naively combining CoT with supervised tuning
requires supervision not just of the correct answers, but also of detailed
rationales that lead to those answers; these rationales are expensive to
produce by hand. Instead, we propose a fine-tuning strategy that tries to
maximize the \emph{marginal} log-likelihood of generating a correct answer
using CoT prompting, approximately averaging over all possible rationales. The
core challenge is sampling from the posterior over rationales conditioned on
the correct answer; we address it using a simple Markov-chain Monte Carlo
(MCMC) expectation-maximization (EM) algorithm inspired by the self-taught
reasoner (STaR), memoized wake-sleep, Markovian score climbing, and persistent
contrastive divergence. This algorithm also admits a novel control-variate
technique that drives the variance of our gradient estimates to zero as the
model improves. Applying our technique to GSM8K and the tasks in BIG-Bench
Hard, we find that this MCMC-EM fine-tuning technique typically improves the
model&apos;s accuracy on held-out examples more than STaR or prompt-tuning with or
without CoT.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Phan_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Du Phan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hoffman_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Matthew D. Hoffman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Dohan_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;David Dohan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Douglas_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sholto Douglas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Le_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tuan Anh Le&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Parisi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aaron Parisi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sountsov_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pavel Sountsov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sutton_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Charles Sutton&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Vikram_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sharad Vikram&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Saurous_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rif A. Saurous&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02181">
<title>How Generative-AI can be Effectively used in Government Chatbots. (arXiv:2312.02181v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02181</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;With the rapid development of artificial intelligence and breakthroughs in
machine learning and natural language processing, intelligent
question-answering robots have become widely used in government affairs. This
paper conducts a horizontal comparison between Guangdong Province&apos;s government
chatbots, ChatGPT, and Wenxin Ernie, two large language models, to analyze the
strengths and weaknesses of existing government chatbots and AIGC technology.
The study finds significant differences between government chatbots and large
language models. China&apos;s government chatbots are still in an exploratory stage
and have a gap to close to achieve &quot;intelligence.&quot; To explore the future
direction of government chatbots more deeply, this research proposes targeted
optimization paths to help generative AI be effectively applied in government
chatbot conversations.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lin_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zeteng Lin&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02188">
<title>Video Summarization: Towards Entity-Aware Captions. (arXiv:2312.02188v1 [cs.CV])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02188</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Existing popular video captioning benchmarks and models deal with generic
captions devoid of specific person, place or organization named entities. In
contrast, news videos present a challenging setting where the caption requires
such named entities for meaningful summarization. As such, we propose the task
of summarizing news video directly to entity-aware captions. We also release a
large-scale dataset, VIEWS (VIdeo NEWS), to support research on this task.
Further, we propose a method that augments visual information from videos with
context retrieved from external world knowledge to generate entity-aware
captions. We demonstrate the effectiveness of our approach on three video
captioning models. We also show that our approach generalizes to existing news
image captions dataset. With all the extensive experiments and insights, we
believe we establish a solid basis for future research on this challenging
task.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ayyubi_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hammad A. Ayyubi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tianqi Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Nagrani_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Arsha Nagrani&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lin_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xudong Lin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mingda Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Arnab_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Anurag Arnab&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Han_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Feng Han&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yukun Zhu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jialu Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chang_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shih-Fu Chang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02206">
<title>Axiomatic Preference Modeling for Longform Question Answering. (arXiv:2312.02206v1 [cs.AI])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02206</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The remarkable abilities of large language models (LLMs) like GPT-4 partially
stem from post-training processes like Reinforcement Learning from Human
Feedback (RLHF) involving human preferences encoded in a reward model. However,
these reward models (RMs) often lack direct knowledge of why, or under what
principles, the preferences annotations were made. In this study, we identify
principles that guide RMs to better align with human preferences, and then
develop an axiomatic framework to generate a rich variety of preference signals
to uphold them. We use these axiomatic signals to train a model for scoring
answers to longform questions. Our approach yields a Preference Model with only
about 220M parameters that agrees with gold human-annotated preference labels
more often than GPT-4. The contributions of this work include: training a
standalone preference model that can score human- and LLM-generated answers on
the same scale; developing an axiomatic framework for generating training data
pairs tailored to certain principles; and showing that a small amount of
axiomatic signals can help small models outperform GPT-4 in preference scoring.
We release our model on huggingface:
https://huggingface.co/corbyrosset/axiomatic_preference_model
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Rosset_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Corby Rosset&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zheng_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Guoqing Zheng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Dibia_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Victor Dibia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Awadallah_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ahmed Awadallah&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bennett_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Paul Bennett&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02219">
<title>Behind the Magic, MERLIM: Multi-modal Evaluation Benchmark for Large Image-Language Models. (arXiv:2312.02219v1 [cs.CV])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02219</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Large Vision and Language Models have enabled significant advances in fully
supervised and zero-shot vision tasks. These large pre-trained architectures
serve as the baseline to what is currently known as Instruction Tuning Large
Vision and Language models (IT-LVLMs). IT-LVLMs are general-purpose multi-modal
assistants whose responses are modulated by natural language instructions and
arbitrary visual data. Despite this versatility, IT-LVLM effectiveness in
fundamental computer vision problems remains unclear, primarily due to the
absence of a standardized evaluation benchmark. This paper introduces a
Multi-modal Evaluation Benchmark named MERLIM, a scalable test-bed to assess
the performance of IT-LVLMs on fundamental computer vision tasks. MERLIM
contains over 279K image-question pairs, and has a strong focus on detecting
cross-modal &quot;hallucination&quot; events in IT-LVLMs, where the language output
refers to visual concepts that lack any effective grounding in the image. Our
results show that state-of-the-art IT-LVMLs are still limited at identifying
fine-grained visual concepts, object hallucinations are common across tasks,
and their results are strongly biased by small variations in the input query,
even if the queries have the very same semantics. Our findings also suggest
that these models have weak visual groundings but they can still make adequate
guesses by global visual patterns or textual biases contained in the LLM
component.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Villa_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andr&amp;#xe9;s Villa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Alcazar_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Juan Carlos Le&amp;#xf3;n Alc&amp;#xe1;zar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Soto_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alvaro Soto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ghanem_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bernard Ghanem&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02227">
<title>Improving Multimodal Sentiment Analysis: Supervised Angular Margin-based Contrastive Learning for Enhanced Fusion Representation. (arXiv:2312.02227v1 [cs.LG])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02227</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The effectiveness of a model is heavily reliant on the quality of the fusion
representation of multiple modalities in multimodal sentiment analysis.
Moreover, each modality is extracted from raw input and integrated with the
rest to construct a multimodal representation. Although previous methods have
proposed multimodal representations and achieved promising results, most of
them focus on forming positive and negative pairs, neglecting the variation in
sentiment scores within the same class. Additionally, they fail to capture the
significance of unimodal representations in the fusion vector. To address these
limitations, we introduce a framework called Supervised Angular-based
Contrastive Learning for Multimodal Sentiment Analysis. This framework aims to
enhance discrimination and generalizability of the multimodal representation
and overcome biases in the fusion vector&apos;s modality. Our experimental results,
along with visualizations on two widely used datasets, demonstrate the
effectiveness of our approach.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Nguyen_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Cong-Duy Nguyen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Nguyen_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thong Nguyen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Vu_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Duc Anh Vu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tuan_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Luu Anh Tuan&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02249">
<title>Recursive Visual Programming. (arXiv:2312.02249v1 [cs.CV])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02249</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Visual Programming (VP) has emerged as a powerful framework for Visual
Question Answering (VQA). By generating and executing bespoke code for each
question, these methods demonstrate impressive compositional and reasoning
capabilities, especially in few-shot and zero-shot scenarios. However, existing
VP methods generate all code in a single function, resulting in code that is
suboptimal in terms of both accuracy and interpretability. Inspired by human
coding practices, we propose Recursive Visual Programming (RVP), which
simplifies generated routines, provides more efficient problem solving, and can
manage more complex data structures. RVP is inspired by human coding practices
and approaches VQA tasks with an iterative recursive code generation approach,
allowing decomposition of complicated problems into smaller parts. Notably, RVP
is capable of dynamic type assignment, i.e., as the system recursively
generates a new piece of code, it autonomously determines the appropriate
return type and crafts the requisite code to generate that output. We show
RVP&apos;s efficacy through extensive experiments on benchmarks including VSR, COVR,
GQA, and NextQA, underscoring the value of adopting human-like recursive and
modular programming techniques for solving VQA tasks through coding.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ge_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiaxin Ge&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Subramanian_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sanjay Subramanian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shi_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Baifeng Shi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Herzig_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Roei Herzig&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Darrell_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Trevor Darrell&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02251">
<title>Fine-Tuning Language Models for Context-Specific SQL Query Generation. (arXiv:2312.02251v1 [cs.DB])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02251</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The ability to generate SQL queries from natural language has significant
implications for making data accessible to non-specialists. This paper presents
a novel approach to fine-tuning open-source large language models (LLMs) for
the task of transforming natural language into SQL queries within the retail
domain. We introduce models specialized in generating SQL queries, trained on
synthetic datasets tailored to the Snowflake SQL and GoogleSQL dialects. Our
methodology involves generating a context-specific dataset using GPT-4, then
fine-tuning three open-source LLMs(Starcoder Plus, Code-Llama, and Mistral)
employing the LoRa technique to optimize for resource constraints. The
fine-tuned models demonstrate superior performance in zero-shot settings
compared to the baseline GPT-4, with Code-Llama achieving the highest accuracy
rates, at 81.58% for Snowflake SQL and 82.66% for GoogleSQL. These results
underscore the effectiveness of fine-tuning LLMs on domain-specific tasks and
suggest a promising direction for enhancing the accessibility of relational
databases through natural language interfaces.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Rebei_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Amine Rebei&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02296">
<title>LLMs Accelerate Annotation for Medical Information Extraction. (arXiv:2312.02296v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02296</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The unstructured nature of clinical notes within electronic health records
often conceals vital patient-related information, making it challenging to
access or interpret. To uncover this hidden information, specialized Natural
Language Processing (NLP) models are required. However, training these models
necessitates large amounts of labeled data, a process that is both
time-consuming and costly when relying solely on human experts for annotation.
In this paper, we propose an approach that combines Large Language Models
(LLMs) with human expertise to create an efficient method for generating ground
truth labels for medical text annotation. By utilizing LLMs in conjunction with
human annotators, we significantly reduce the human annotation burden, enabling
the rapid creation of labeled datasets. We rigorously evaluate our method on a
medical information extraction task, demonstrating that our approach not only
substantially cuts down on human intervention but also maintains high accuracy.
The results highlight the potential of using LLMs to improve the utilization of
unstructured clinical data, allowing for the swift deployment of tailored NLP
solutions in healthcare.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Goel_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Akshay Goel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gueta_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Almog Gueta&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gilon_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Omry Gilon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chang Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Erell_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sofia Erell&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Nguyen_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lan Huong Nguyen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hao_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaohong Hao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jaber_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bolous Jaber&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Reddy_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shashir Reddy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kartha_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rupesh Kartha&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Steiner_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jean Steiner&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Laish_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Itay Laish&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Feder_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Amir Feder&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02310">
<title>VaQuitA: Enhancing Alignment in LLM-Assisted Video Understanding. (arXiv:2312.02310v1 [cs.CV])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02310</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Recent advancements in language-model-based video understanding have been
progressing at a remarkable pace, spurred by the introduction of Large Language
Models (LLMs). However, the focus of prior research has been predominantly on
devising a projection layer that maps video features to tokens, an approach
that is both rudimentary and inefficient. In our study, we introduce a
cutting-edge framework, VaQuitA, designed to refine the synergy between video
and textual information. At the data level, instead of sampling frames
uniformly, we implement a sampling method guided by CLIP-score rankings, which
enables a more aligned selection of frames with the given question. At the
feature level, we integrate a trainable Video Perceiver alongside a
Visual-Query Transformer (abbreviated as VQ-Former), which bolsters the
interplay between the input question and the video features. We also discover
that incorporating a simple prompt, &quot;Please be critical&quot;, into the LLM input
can substantially enhance its video comprehension capabilities. Our
experimental results indicate that VaQuitA consistently sets a new benchmark
for zero-shot video question-answering tasks and is adept at producing
high-quality, multi-turn video dialogues with users.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yizhou Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ruiyi Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Haoliang Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bhattacharya_U/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Uttaran Bhattacharya&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Fu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yun Fu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wu_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gang Wu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02314">
<title>Fine-tuning pre-trained extractive QA models for clinical document parsing. (arXiv:2312.02314v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02314</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Electronic health records (EHRs) contain a vast amount of high-dimensional
multi-modal data that can accurately represent a patient&apos;s medical history.
Unfortunately, most of this data is either unstructured or semi-structured,
rendering it unsuitable for real-time and retrospective analyses. A remote
patient monitoring (RPM) program for Heart Failure (HF) patients needs to have
access to clinical markers like EF (Ejection Fraction) or LVEF (Left
Ventricular Ejection Fraction) in order to ascertain eligibility and
appropriateness for the program. This paper explains a system that can parse
echocardiogram reports and verify EF values. This system helps identify
eligible HF patients who can be enrolled in such a program. At the heart of
this system is a pre-trained extractive QA transformer model that is fine-tuned
on custom-labeled data. The methods used to prepare such a model for deployment
are illustrated by running experiments on a public clinical dataset like
MIMIC-IV-Note. The pipeline can be used to generalize solutions to similar
problems in a low-resource setting. We found that the system saved over 1500
hours for our clinicians over 12 months by automating the task at scale.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sharma_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ashwyn Sharma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Feldman_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;David I. Feldman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jain_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aneesh Jain&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02317">
<title>GNN2R: Weakly-Supervised Rationale-Providing Question Answering over Knowledge Graphs. (arXiv:2312.02317v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02317</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Most current methods for multi-hop question answering (QA) over knowledge
graphs (KGs) only provide final conclusive answers without explanations, such
as a set of KG entities that is difficult for normal users to review and
comprehend. This issue severely limits the application of KG-based QA in
real-world scenarios. However, it is non-trivial to solve due to two
challenges: First, annotations of reasoning chains of multi-hop questions,
which could serve as supervision for explanation generation, are usually
lacking. Second, it is difficult to maintain high efficiency when explicit KG
triples need to be retrieved to generate explanations. In this paper, we
propose a novel Graph Neural Network-based Two-Step Reasoning model (GNN2R) to
solve this issue. GNN2R can provide both final answers and reasoning subgraphs
as a rationale behind final answers efficiently with only weak supervision that
is available through question-final answer pairs. We extensively evaluated
GNN2R with detailed analyses in experiments. The results demonstrate that, in
terms of effectiveness, efficiency, and quality of generated explanations,
GNN2R outperforms existing state-of-the-art methods that are applicable to this
task. Our code and pre-trained models are available at
https://github.com/ruijie-wang-uzh/GNN2R.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ruijie Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Rossetto_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Luca Rossetto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cochez_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michael Cochez&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bernstein_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Abraham Bernstein&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02331">
<title>Revisiting Topic-Guided Language Models. (arXiv:2312.02331v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02331</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A recent line of work in natural language processing has aimed to combine
language models and topic models. These topic-guided language models augment
neural language models with topic models, unsupervised learning methods that
can discover document-level patterns of word use. This paper compares the
effectiveness of these methods in a standardized setting. We study four
topic-guided language models and two baselines, evaluating the held-out
predictive performance of each model on four corpora. Surprisingly, we find
that none of these methods outperform a standard LSTM language model baseline,
and most fail to learn good topics. Further, we train a probe of the neural
language model that shows that the baseline&apos;s hidden states already encode
topic information. We make public all code used for this study.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zheng_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Carolina Zheng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Vafa_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Keyon Vafa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Blei_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;David M. Blei&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02334">
<title>An Evaluation Framework for Mapping News Headlines to Event Classes in a Knowledge Graph. (arXiv:2312.02334v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02334</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Mapping ongoing news headlines to event-related classes in a rich knowledge
base can be an important component in a knowledge-based event analysis and
forecasting solution. In this paper, we present a methodology for creating a
benchmark dataset of news headlines mapped to event classes in Wikidata, and
resources for the evaluation of methods that perform the mapping. We use the
dataset to study two classes of unsupervised methods for this task: 1)
adaptations of classic entity linking methods, and 2) methods that treat the
problem as a zero-shot text classification problem. For the first approach, we
evaluate off-the-shelf entity linking systems. For the second approach, we
explore a) pre-trained natural language inference (NLI) models, and b)
pre-trained large generative language models. We present the results of our
evaluation, lessons learned, and directions for future work. The dataset and
scripts for evaluation are made publicly available.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Mbouadeu_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Steve Fonin Mbouadeu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lorenzo_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Martin Lorenzo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Barker_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ken Barker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hassanzadeh_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Oktie Hassanzadeh&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02337">
<title>Measuring Distributional Shifts in Text: The Advantage of Language Model-Based Embeddings. (arXiv:2312.02337v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02337</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;An essential part of monitoring machine learning models in production is
measuring input and output data drift. In this paper, we present a system for
measuring distributional shifts in natural language data and highlight and
investigate the potential advantage of using large language models (LLMs) for
this problem. Recent advancements in LLMs and their successful adoption in
different domains indicate their effectiveness in capturing semantic
relationships for solving various natural language processing problems. The
power of LLMs comes largely from the encodings (embeddings) generated in the
hidden layers of the corresponding neural network. First we propose a
clustering-based algorithm for measuring distributional shifts in text data by
exploiting such embeddings. Then we study the effectiveness of our approach
when applied to text embeddings generated by both LLMs and classical embedding
algorithms. Our experiments show that general-purpose LLM-based embeddings
provide a high sensitivity to data drift compared to other embedding methods.
We propose drift sensitivity as an important evaluation metric to consider when
comparing language models. Finally, we present insights and lessons learned
from deploying our framework as part of the Fiddler ML Monitoring platform over
a period of 18 months.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gupta_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gyandev Gupta&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Rastegarpanah_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bashir Rastegarpanah&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Iyer_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Amalendu Iyer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Rubin_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Joshua Rubin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kenthapadi_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Krishnaram Kenthapadi&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02382">
<title>New Evaluation Metrics Capture Quality Degradation due to LLM Watermarking. (arXiv:2312.02382v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02382</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;With the increasing use of large-language models (LLMs) like ChatGPT,
watermarking has emerged as a promising approach for tracing machine-generated
content. However, research on LLM watermarking often relies on simple
perplexity or diversity-based measures to assess the quality of watermarked
text, which can mask important limitations in watermarking. Here we introduce
two new easy-to-use methods for evaluating watermarking algorithms for LLMs: 1)
evaluation by LLM-judger with specific guidelines; and 2) binary classification
on text embeddings to distinguish between watermarked and unwatermarked text.
We apply these methods to characterize the effectiveness of current
watermarking techniques. Our experiments, conducted across various datasets,
reveal that current watermarking methods are detectable by even simple
classifiers, challenging the notion of watermarking subtlety. We also found,
through the LLM judger, that watermarking impacts text quality, especially in
degrading the coherence and depth of the response. Our findings underscore the
trade-off between watermark robustness and text quality and highlight the
importance of having more informative metrics to assess watermarking quality.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Singh_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Karanpartap Singh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zou_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;James Zou&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02406">
<title>Efficient Online Data Mixing For Language Model Pre-Training. (arXiv:2312.02406v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02406</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The data used to pretrain large language models has a decisive impact on a
model&apos;s downstream performance, which has led to a large body of work on data
selection methods that aim to automatically determine the most suitable data to
use for pretraining. Existing data selection methods suffer from slow and
computationally expensive processes, a problem amplified by the increasing size
of models and of pretraining datasets. Data mixing, on the other hand, reduces
the complexity of data selection by grouping data points together and
determining sampling probabilities across entire groups. However, data mixing
proportions are typically fixed before training and therefore cannot adapt to
changing training dynamics. To address these limitations, we develop an
efficient algorithm for Online Data Mixing (ODM) that combines elements from
both data selection and data mixing. Based on multi-armed bandit algorithms,
our online approach optimizes the data mixing proportions during training.
Remarkably, our method trains a model that reaches the final perplexity of the
next best method with 19\% fewer training iterations, and improves performance
on the 5-shot MMLU benchmark by 1.9% relative accuracy, while adding negligible
wall-clock time during pretraining.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Albalak_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alon Albalak&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Pan_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Liangming Pan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Raffel_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Colin Raffel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;William Yang Wang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02418">
<title>Decoding Data Quality via Synthetic Corruptions: Embedding-guided Pruning of Code Data. (arXiv:2312.02418v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02418</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Code datasets, often collected from diverse and uncontrolled sources such as
GitHub, potentially suffer from quality issues, thereby affecting the
performance and training efficiency of Large Language Models (LLMs) optimized
for code generation. Previous studies demonstrated the benefit of using
embedding spaces for data pruning, but they mainly focused on duplicate removal
or increasing variety, and in other modalities, such as images. Our work
focuses on using embeddings to identify and remove &quot;low-quality&quot; code data.
First, we explore features of &quot;low-quality&quot; code in embedding space, through
the use of synthetic corruptions. Armed with this knowledge, we devise novel
pruning metrics that operate in embedding space to identify and remove
low-quality entries in the Stack dataset. We demonstrate the benefits of this
synthetic corruption informed pruning (SCIP) approach on the well-established
HumanEval and MBPP benchmarks, outperforming existing embedding-based methods.
Importantly, we achieve up to a 3% performance improvement over no pruning,
thereby showing the promise of insights from synthetic corruptions for data
pruning.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yu Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Singh_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aaditya K. Singh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Elhoushi_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mostafa Elhoushi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Mahmoud_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Anas Mahmoud&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tirumala_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kushal Tirumala&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gloeckle_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fabian Gloeckle&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Roziere_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Baptiste Rozi&amp;#xe8;re&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wu_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Carole-Jean Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Morcos_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ari S. Morcos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ardalani_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Newsha Ardalani&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02431">
<title>Visually Grounded Language Learning: a review of language games, datasets, tasks, and models. (arXiv:2312.02431v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02431</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In recent years, several machine learning models have been proposed. They are
trained with a language modelling objective on large-scale text-only data. With
such pretraining, they can achieve impressive results on many Natural Language
Understanding and Generation tasks. However, many facets of meaning cannot be
learned by ``listening to the radio&quot; only. In the literature, many
Vision+Language (V+L) tasks have been defined with the aim of creating models
that can ground symbols in the visual modality. In this work, we provide a
systematic literature review of several tasks and models proposed in the V+L
field. We rely on Wittgenstein&apos;s idea of `language games&apos; to categorise such
tasks into 3 different families: 1) discriminative games, 2) generative games,
and 3) interactive games. Our analysis of the literature provides evidence that
future work should be focusing on interactive games where communication in
Natural Language is important to resolve ambiguities about object referents and
action plans and that physical embodiment is essential to understand the
semantics of situations and events. Overall, these represent key requirements
for developing grounded meanings in neural models.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Suglia_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alessandro Suglia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Konstas_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ioannis Konstas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lemon_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Oliver Lemon&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02436">
<title>MUFFIN: Curating Multi-Faceted Instructions for Improving Instruction-Following. (arXiv:2312.02436v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02436</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In the realm of large language models (LLMs), enhancing instruction-following
capability often involves curating expansive training data. This is achieved
through two primary schemes: i) Scaling-Inputs: Amplifying (input, output)
pairs per task instruction, aiming for better instruction adherence. ii)
Scaling Input-Free Tasks: Enlarging tasks, each composed of an (instruction,
output) pair (without requiring a separate input anymore). However, LLMs under
Scaling-Inputs tend to be overly sensitive to inputs, leading to
misinterpretation or non-compliance with instructions. Conversely, Scaling
Input-Free Tasks demands a substantial number of tasks but is less effective in
instruction following when dealing with instances in Scaling-Inputs. This work
introduces MUFFIN, a new scheme of instruction-following dataset curation.
Specifically, we automatically Scale Tasks per Input by diversifying these
tasks with various input facets. Experimental results across four zero-shot
benchmarks, spanning both Scaling-Inputs and Scaling Input-Free Tasks schemes,
reveal that LLMs, at various scales, trained on MUFFIN generally demonstrate
superior instruction-following capabilities compared to those trained on the
two aforementioned schemes.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lou_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Renze Lou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kai Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xie_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jian Xie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sun_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuxuan Sun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ahn_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Janice Ahn&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xu_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hanzi Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Su_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yu Su&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yin_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wenpeng Yin&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02439">
<title>Let&apos;s Think Outside the Box: Exploring Leap-of-Thought in Large Language Models with Creative Humor Generation. (arXiv:2312.02439v1 [cs.AI])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02439</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Chain-of-Thought (CoT) guides large language models (LLMs) to reason
step-by-step, and can motivate their logical reasoning ability. While effective
for logical tasks, CoT is not conducive to creative problem-solving which often
requires out-of-box thoughts and is crucial for innovation advancements. In
this paper, we explore the Leap-of-Thought (LoT) abilities within LLMs -- a
non-sequential, creative paradigm involving strong associations and knowledge
leaps. To this end, we study LLMs on the popular Oogiri game which needs
participants to have good creativity and strong associative thinking for
responding unexpectedly and humorously to the given image, text, or both, and
thus is suitable for LoT study. Then to investigate LLMs&apos; LoT ability in the
Oogiri game, we first build a multimodal and multilingual Oogiri-GO dataset
which contains over 130,000 samples from the Oogiri game, and observe the
insufficient LoT ability or failures of most existing LLMs on the Oogiri game.
Accordingly, we introduce a creative Leap-of-Thought (CLoT) paradigm to improve
LLM&apos;s LoT ability. CLoT first formulates the Oogiri-GO dataset into
LoT-oriented instruction tuning data to train pretrained LLM for achieving
certain LoT humor generation and discrimination abilities. Then CLoT designs an
explorative self-refinement that encourages the LLM to generate more creative
LoT data via exploring parallels between seemingly unrelated concepts and
selects high-quality data to train itself for self-refinement. CLoT not only
excels in humor generation in the Oogiri game but also boosts creative
abilities in various tasks like cloud guessing game and divergent association
task. These findings advance our understanding and offer a pathway to improve
LLMs&apos; creative capacities for innovative applications across domains. The
dataset, code, and models will be released online.
https://github.com/sail-sg/CLoT.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhong_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shanshan Zhong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Huang_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhongzhan Huang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gao_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shanghua Gao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wen_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wushao Wen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lin_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Liang Lin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zitnik_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marinka Zitnik&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhou_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pan Zhou&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02441">
<title>MedDM:LLM-executable clinical guidance tree for clinical decision-making. (arXiv:2312.02441v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02441</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;It is becoming increasingly emphasis on the importance of LLM participating
in clinical diagnosis decision-making. However, the low specialization refers
to that current medical LLMs can not provide specific medical advice, which are
more like a medical Q\&amp;amp;A. And there is no suitable clinical guidance tree data
set that can be used directly with LLM. To address this issue, we first propose
LLM-executavle clinical guidance tree(CGT), which can be directly used by large
language models, and construct medical diagnostic decision-making dataset
(MedDM), from flowcharts in clinical practice guidelines. We propose an
approach to screen flowcharts from medical literature, followed by their
identification and conversion into standardized diagnostic decision trees.
Constructed a knowledge base with 1202 decision trees, which came from 5000
medical literature and covered 12 hospital departments, including internal
medicine, surgery, psychiatry, and over 500 diseases.Moreover, we propose a
method for reasoning on LLM-executable CGT and a Patient-LLM multi-turn
dialogue framework.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Binbin Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Meng_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tianxin Meng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shi_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaoming Shi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhai_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jie Zhai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ruan_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tong Ruan&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02496">
<title>MKA: A Scalable Medical Knowledge Assisted Mechanism for Generative Models on Medical Conversation Tasks. (arXiv:2312.02496v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02496</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Using natural language processing (NLP) technologies to develop medical
chatbots makes the diagnosis of the patient more convenient and efficient,
which is a typical application in healthcare AI. Because of its importance,
lots of research have been come out. Recently, the neural generative models
have shown their impressive ability as the core of chatbot, while it cannot
scale well when directly applied to medical conversation due to the lack of
medical-specific knowledge. To address the limitation, a scalable Medical
Knowledge Assisted mechanism, MKA, is proposed in this paper. The mechanism
aims to assist general neural generative models to achieve better performance
on the medical conversation task. The medical-specific knowledge graph is
designed within the mechanism, which contains 6 types of medical-related
information, including department, drug, check, symptom, disease, food.
Besides, the specific token concatenation policy is defined to effectively
inject medical information into the input data. Evaluation of our method is
carried out on two typical medical datasets, MedDG and MedDialog-CN. The
evaluation results demonstrate that models combined with our mechanism
outperform original methods in multiple automatic evaluation metrics. Besides,
MKA-Bert-GPT achieves state-of-the-art performance. The open-sourced codes are
public:
https://github.com/LIANGKE23/Knowledge_Assisted_Medical_Dialogue_Generation_Mechanism
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liang_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ke Liang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wu_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sifan Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiayi Gu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02532">
<title>DRAFT: Dense Retrieval Augmented Few-shot Topic classifier Framework. (arXiv:2312.02532v1 [cs.IR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02532</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;With the growing volume of diverse information, the demand for classifying
arbitrary topics has become increasingly critical. To address this challenge,
we introduce DRAFT, a simple framework designed to train a classifier for
few-shot topic classification. DRAFT uses a few examples of a specific topic as
queries to construct Customized dataset with a dense retriever model.
Multi-query retrieval (MQR) algorithm, which effectively handles multiple
queries related to a specific topic, is applied to construct the Customized
dataset. Subsequently, we fine-tune a classifier using the Customized dataset
to identify the topic. To demonstrate the efficacy of our proposed approach, we
conduct evaluations on both widely used classification benchmark datasets and
manually constructed datasets with 291 diverse topics, which simulate diverse
contents encountered in real-world applications. DRAFT shows competitive or
superior performance compared to baselines that use in-context learning, such
as GPT-3 175B and InstructGPT 175B, on few-shot topic classification tasks
despite having 177 times fewer parameters, demonstrating its effectiveness.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kim_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Keonwoo Kim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lee_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Younggun Lee&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02549">
<title>DemaFormer: Damped Exponential Moving Average Transformer with Energy-Based Modeling for Temporal Language Grounding. (arXiv:2312.02549v1 [cs.CV])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02549</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Temporal Language Grounding seeks to localize video moments that semantically
correspond to a natural language query. Recent advances employ the attention
mechanism to learn the relations between video moments and the text query.
However, naive attention might not be able to appropriately capture such
relations, resulting in ineffective distributions where target video moments
are difficult to separate from the remaining ones. To resolve the issue, we
propose an energy-based model framework to explicitly learn moment-query
distributions. Moreover, we propose DemaFormer, a novel Transformer-based
architecture that utilizes exponential moving average with a learnable damping
factor to effectively encode moment-query inputs. Comprehensive experiments on
four public temporal language grounding datasets showcase the superiority of
our methods over the state-of-the-art baselines.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Nguyen_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thong Nguyen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wu_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaobao Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Dong_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xinshuai Dong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Nguyen_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Cong-Duy Nguyen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ng_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;See-Kiong Ng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tuan_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Luu Anh Tuan&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02554">
<title>ULMA: Unified Language Model Alignment with Demonstration and Point-wise Human Preference. (arXiv:2312.02554v1 [cs.LG])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02554</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Language model alignment is a cutting-edge technique in large language model
training to align the model output to user&apos;s intent, e.g., being helpful and
harmless. Recent alignment framework consists of two steps: supervised
fine-tuning with demonstration data and preference learning with human
preference data. Previous preference learning methods, such as RLHF and DPO,
mainly focus on pair-wise preference data. However, in many real-world
scenarios where human feedbacks are intrinsically point-wise, these methods
will suffer from information loss or even fail. To fill this gap, in this
paper, we first develop a preference learning method called point-wise DPO to
tackle point-wise preference data. Further revelation on the connection between
supervised fine-tuning and point-wise preference learning enables us to develop
a unified framework for both human demonstration and point-wise preference
data, which sheds new light on the construction of preference dataset.
Extensive experiments on point-wise datasets with binary or continuous labels
demonstrate the superior performance and efficiency of our proposed methods. A
new dataset with high-quality demonstration samples on harmlessness is
constructed and made publicly available.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cai_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tianchi Cai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Song_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xierui Song&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jiang_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiyan Jiang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Teng_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fei Teng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jinjie Gu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Guannan Zhang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02578">
<title>Empathy and Distress Detection using Ensembles of Transformer Models. (arXiv:2312.02578v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02578</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This paper presents our approach for the WASSA 2023 Empathy, Emotion and
Personality Shared Task. Empathy and distress are human feelings that are
implicitly expressed in natural discourses. Empathy and distress detection are
crucial challenges in Natural Language Processing that can aid our
understanding of conversations. The provided dataset consists of several
long-text examples in the English language, with each example associated with a
numeric score for empathy and distress. We experiment with several BERT-based
models as a part of our approach. We also try various ensemble methods. Our
final submission has a Pearson&apos;s r score of 0.346, placing us third in the
empathy and distress detection subtask.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chavan_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tanmay Chavan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Deshpande_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kshitij Deshpande&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sonawane_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sheetal Sonawane&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02590">
<title>Text Intimacy Analysis using Ensembles of Multilingual Transformers. (arXiv:2312.02590v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02590</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Intimacy estimation of a given text has recently gained importance due to the
increase in direct interaction of NLP systems with humans. Intimacy is an
important aspect of natural language and has a substantial impact on our
everyday communication. Thus the level of intimacy can provide us with deeper
insights and richer semantics of conversations. In this paper, we present our
work on the SemEval shared task 9 on predicting the level of intimacy for the
given text. The dataset consists of tweets in ten languages, out of which only
six are available in the training dataset. We conduct several experiments and
show that an ensemble of multilingual models along with a language-specific
monolingual model has the best performance. We also evaluate other data
augmentation methods such as translation and present the results. Lastly, we
study the results thoroughly and present some noteworthy insights into this
problem.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chavan_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tanmay Chavan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Patwardhan_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ved Patwardhan&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02598">
<title>Impact of Tokenization on LLaMa Russian Adaptation. (arXiv:2312.02598v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02598</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Latest instruction-tuned large language models (LLM) show great results on
various tasks, however, they often face performance degradation for non-English
input. There is evidence that the reason lies in inefficient tokenization
caused by low language representation in pre-training data which hinders the
comprehension of non-English instructions, limiting the potential of target
language instruction-tuning. In this work we investigate the possibility of
addressing the issue with vocabulary substitution in the context of LLaMa
Russian language adaptation. We explore three variants of vocabulary adaptation
and test their performance on Saiga instruction-tuning and fine-tuning on
Russian Super Glue benchmark. The results of automatic evaluation show that
vocabulary substitution not only improves the model&apos;s quality in Russian but
also accelerates fine-tuning (35%) and inference (up to 60%) while reducing
memory consumption. Additional human evaluation of the instruction-tuned models
demonstrates that models with Russian-adapted vocabulary generate answers with
higher user preference than the original Saiga-LLaMa model.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tikhomirov_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mikhail Tikhomirov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chernyshev_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniil Chernyshev&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02614">
<title>Prompt Optimization via Adversarial In-Context Learning. (arXiv:2312.02614v1 [cs.LG])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02614</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We propose a new method, Adversarial In-Context Learning (adv-ICL), to
optimize prompt for in-context learning (ICL) by employing one LLM as a
generator, another as a discriminator, and a third as a prompt modifier. As in
traditional adversarial learning, adv-ICL is implemented as a two-player game
between the generator and discriminator, where the generator tries to generate
realistic enough output to fool the discriminator. In each round, given an
input prefixed by task instructions and several exemplars, the generator
produces an output. The discriminator is then tasked with classifying the
generator input-output pair as model-generated or real data. Based on the
discriminator loss, the prompt modifier proposes possible edits to the
generator and discriminator prompts, and the edits that most improve the
adversarial loss are selected. We show that adv-ICL results in significant
improvements over state-of-the-art prompt optimization techniques for both open
and closed-source models on 11 generation and classification tasks including
summarization, arithmetic reasoning, machine translation, data-to-text
generation, and the MMLU and big-bench hard benchmarks. In addition, because
our method uses pre-trained models and updates only prompts rather than model
parameters, it is computationally efficient, easy to extend to any LLM and
task, and effective in low-resource settings.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Do_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xuan Long Do&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhao_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yiran Zhao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Brown_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hannah Brown&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xie_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuxi Xie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhao_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;James Xu Zhao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nancy F. Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kawaguchi_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kenji Kawaguchi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xie_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michael Qizhe Xie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+He_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Junxian He&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02706">
<title>Large Knowledge Model: Perspectives and Challenges. (arXiv:2312.02706v1 [cs.AI])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02706</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Humankind&apos;s understanding of the world is fundamentally linked to our
perception and cognition, with \emph{human languages} serving as one of the
major carriers of \emph{world knowledge}. In this vein, \emph{Large Language
Models} (LLMs) like ChatGPT epitomize the pre-training of extensive,
sequence-based world knowledge into neural networks, facilitating the
processing and manipulation of this knowledge in a parametric space. This
article explores large models through the lens of ``knowledge&apos;&apos;. We initially
investigate the role of symbolic knowledge such as Knowledge Graphs (KGs) in
enhancing LLMs, covering aspects like knowledge-augmented language model,
structure-inducing pre-training, knowledgeable prompts, structured CoT,
knowledge editing, semantic tools for LLM and knowledgeable AI agents.
Subsequently, we examine how LLMs can amplify traditional symbolic knowledge
bases, encompassing aspects like using LLM as KG builder and controller,
structured knowledge pretraining, LLM-enhanced symbolic reasoning, and the
amalgamation of perception with cognition. Considering the intricate nature of
human knowledge, we advocate for the creation of \emph{Large Knowledge Models}
(LKM), specifically engineered to manage diversified spectrum of knowledge
structures. This ambitious undertaking could entail several key challenges,
such as disentangling knowledge representation from language models,
restructuring pre-training with structured knowledge, and building large
commonsense models, among others. We finally propose a five-``A&apos;&apos; principle to
distinguish the concept of LKM.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Huajun Chen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02730">
<title>Towards Measuring Representational Similarity of Large Language Models. (arXiv:2312.02730v1 [cs.LG])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02730</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Understanding the similarity of the numerous released large language models
(LLMs) has many uses, e.g., simplifying model selection, detecting illegal
model reuse, and advancing our understanding of what makes LLMs perform well.
In this work, we measure the similarity of representations of a set of LLMs
with 7B parameters. Our results suggest that some LLMs are substantially
different from others. We identify challenges of using representational
similarity measures that suggest the need of careful study of similarity scores
to avoid false conclusions.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Klabunde_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Max Klabunde&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Amor_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mehdi Ben Amor&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Granitzer_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michael Granitzer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lemmerich_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Florian Lemmerich&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02748">
<title>Compositional Generalization for Data-to-Text Generation. (arXiv:2312.02748v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02748</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Data-to-text generation involves transforming structured data, often
represented as predicate-argument tuples, into coherent textual descriptions.
Despite recent advances, systems still struggle when confronted with unseen
combinations of predicates, producing unfaithful descriptions (e.g.
hallucinations or omissions). We refer to this issue as compositional
generalisation, and it encouraged us to create a benchmark for assessing the
performance of different approaches on this specific problem. Furthermore, we
propose a novel model that addresses compositional generalization by clustering
predicates into groups. Our model generates text in a sentence-by-sentence
manner, relying on one cluster of predicates at a time. This approach
significantly outperforms T5~baselines across all evaluation metrics.Notably,
it achieved a 31% improvement over T5 in terms of a metric focused on
maintaining faithfulness to the input.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xu_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xinnuo Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Titov_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ivan Titov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lapata_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mirella Lapata&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02780">
<title>Scaling Laws for Adversarial Attacks on Language Model Activations. (arXiv:2312.02780v1 [cs.LG])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02780</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We explore a class of adversarial attacks targeting the activations of
language models. By manipulating a relatively small subset of model
activations, $a$, we demonstrate the ability to control the exact prediction of
a significant number (in some cases up to 1000) of subsequent tokens $t$. We
empirically verify a scaling law where the maximum number of target tokens
$t_\mathrm{max}$ predicted depends linearly on the number of tokens $a$ whose
activations the attacker controls as $t_\mathrm{max} = \kappa a$. We find that
the number of bits of control in the input space needed to control a single bit
in the output space (what we call attack resistance $\chi$) is remarkably
constant between $\approx 16$ and $\approx 25$ over 2 orders of magnitude of
model sizes for different language models. Compared to attacks on tokens,
attacks on activations are predictably much stronger, however, we identify a
surprising regularity where one bit of input steered either via activations or
via tokens is able to exert control over a similar amount of output bits. This
gives support for the hypothesis that adversarial attacks are a consequence of
dimensionality mismatch between the input and output spaces. A practical
implication of the ease of attacking language model activations instead of
tokens is for multi-modal and selected retrieval models, where additional data
sources are added as activations directly, sidestepping the tokenized input.
This opens up a new, broad attack surface. By using language models as a
controllable test-bed to study adversarial attacks, we were able to experiment
with input-output dimensions that are inaccessible in computer vision,
especially where the output dimension dominates.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Fort_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stanislav Fort&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02783">
<title>Large Language Models on Graphs: A Comprehensive Survey. (arXiv:2312.02783v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02783</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Large language models (LLMs), such as ChatGPT and LLaMA, are creating
significant advancements in natural language processing, due to their strong
text encoding/decoding ability and newly found emergent capability (e.g.,
reasoning). While LLMs are mainly designed to process pure texts, there are
many real-world scenarios where text data are associated with rich structure
information in the form of graphs (e.g., academic networks, and e-commerce
networks) or scenarios where graph data are paired with rich textual
information (e.g., molecules with descriptions). Besides, although LLMs have
shown their pure text-based reasoning ability, it is underexplored whether such
ability can be generalized to graph scenarios (i.e., graph-based reasoning). In
this paper, we provide a systematic review of scenarios and techniques related
to large language models on graphs. We first summarize potential scenarios of
adopting LLMs on graphs into three categories, namely pure graphs, text-rich
graphs, and text-paired graphs. We then discuss detailed techniques for
utilizing LLMs on graphs, including LLM as Predictor, LLM as Encoder, and LLM
as Aligner, and compare the advantages and disadvantages of different schools
of models. Furthermore, we mention the real-world applications of such methods
and summarize open-source codes and benchmark datasets. Finally, we conclude
with potential future research directions in this fast-growing field. The
related source can be found at
https://github.com/PeterGriffinJin/Awesome-Language-Model-on-Graphs.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jin_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bowen Jin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gang Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Han_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chi Han&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jiang_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Meng Jiang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ji_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Heng Ji&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Han_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiawei Han&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02798">
<title>Weakly Supervised Detection of Hallucinations in LLM Activations. (arXiv:2312.02798v1 [cs.LG])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02798</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We propose an auditing method to identify whether a large language model
(LLM) encodes patterns such as hallucinations in its internal states, which may
propagate to downstream tasks. We introduce a weakly supervised auditing
technique using a subset scanning approach to detect anomalous patterns in LLM
activations from pre-trained models. Importantly, our method does not need
knowledge of the type of patterns a-priori. Instead, it relies on a reference
dataset devoid of anomalies during testing. Further, our approach enables the
identification of pivotal nodes responsible for encoding these patterns, which
may offer crucial insights for fine-tuning specific sub-networks for bias
mitigation. We introduce two new scanning methods to handle LLM activations for
anomalous sentences that may deviate from the expected distribution in either
direction. Our results confirm prior findings of BERT&apos;s limited internal
capacity for encoding hallucinations, while OPT appears capable of encoding
hallucination information internally. Importantly, our scanning approach,
without prior exposure to false statements, performs comparably to a fully
supervised out-of-distribution classifier.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Rateike_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Miriam Rateike&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cintas_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Celia Cintas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wamburu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;John Wamburu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Akumu_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tanya Akumu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Speakman_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Skyler Speakman&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02803">
<title>Leveraging Domain Adaptation and Data Augmentation to Improve Qur&apos;anic IR in English and Arabic. (arXiv:2312.02803v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02803</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this work, we approach the problem of Qur&apos;anic information retrieval (IR)
in Arabic and English. Using the latest state-of-the-art methods in neural IR,
we research what helps to tackle this task more efficiently. Training retrieval
models requires a lot of data, which is difficult to obtain for training
in-domain. Therefore, we commence with training on a large amount of general
domain data and then continue training on in-domain data. To handle the lack of
in-domain data, we employed a data augmentation technique, which considerably
improved results in MRR@10 and NDCG@5 metrics, setting the state-of-the-art in
Qur&apos;anic IR for both English and Arabic. The absence of an Islamic corpus and
domain-specific model for IR task in English motivated us to address this lack
of resources and take preliminary steps of the Islamic corpus compilation and
domain-specific language model (LM) pre-training, which helped to improve the
performance of the retrieval models that use the domain-specific LM as the
shared backbone. We examined several language models (LMs) in Arabic to select
one that efficiently deals with the Qur&apos;anic IR task. Besides transferring
successful experiments from English to Arabic, we conducted additional
experiments with retrieval task in Arabic to amortize the scarcity of general
domain datasets used to train the retrieval models. Handling Qur&apos;anic IR task
combining English and Arabic allowed us to enhance the comparison and share
valuable insights across models and languages.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Pavlova_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vera Pavlova&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02820">
<title>Clustering Pseudo Language Family in Multilingual Translation Models with Fisher Information Matrix. (arXiv:2312.02820v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02820</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In multilingual translation research, the comprehension and utilization of
language families are of paramount importance. Nevertheless, clustering
languages based solely on their ancestral families can yield suboptimal results
due to variations in the datasets employed during the model&apos;s training phase.
To mitigate this challenge, we introduce an innovative method that leverages
the fisher information matrix (FIM) to cluster language families, anchored on
the multilingual translation model&apos;s characteristics. We hypothesize that
language pairs with similar effects on model parameters exhibit a considerable
degree of linguistic congruence and should thus be grouped cohesively. This
concept has led us to define pseudo language families. We provide an in-depth
discussion regarding the inception and application of these pseudo language
families. Empirical evaluations reveal that employing these pseudo language
families enhances performance over conventional language families in adapting a
multilingual translation model to unfamiliar language pairs. The proposed
methodology may also be extended to scenarios requiring language similarity
measurements. The source code and associated scripts can be accessed at
https://github.com/ecoli-hit/PseudoFamily.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ma_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xinyu Ma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xuebo Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Min Zhang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02869">
<title>Can a Tabula Recta provide security in the XXI century?. (arXiv:2312.02869v1 [cs.CR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02869</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In the not so unlikely scenario of total compromise of computers accessible
to a group of users, they might be tempted to resort to human-computable
paper-and-pencil cryptographic methods aided by a classic Tabula Recta, which
helps to perform addition and subtraction directly with letters. But do these
classic algorithms, or some new ones using the same simple tools, have any
chance against computer-aided cryptanalysis? In this paper I discuss how some
human-computable algorithms can indeed afford sufficient security in this
situation, drawing conclusions from computer-based statistical analysis. Three
kinds of algorithms are discussed: those that concentrate entropy from shared
text sources, stream ciphers based on arithmetic of non-binary spaces, and
hash-like algorithms that may be used to generate a password from a challenge
text.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ruiz_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Francisco Ruiz&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.16934">
<title>VideoDubber: Machine Translation with Speech-Aware Length Control for Video Dubbing. (arXiv:2211.16934v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.16934</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Video dubbing aims to translate the original speech in a film or television
program into the speech in a target language, which can be achieved with a
cascaded system consisting of speech recognition, machine translation and
speech synthesis. To ensure the translated speech to be well aligned with the
corresponding video, the length/duration of the translated speech should be as
close as possible to that of the original speech, which requires strict length
control. Previous works usually control the number of words or characters
generated by the machine translation model to be similar to the source
sentence, without considering the isochronicity of speech as the speech
duration of words/characters in different languages varies. In this paper, we
propose a machine translation system tailored for the task of video dubbing,
which directly considers the speech duration of each token in translation, to
match the length of source and target speech. Specifically, we control the
speech length of generated sentence by guiding the prediction of each word with
the duration information, including the speech duration of itself as well as
how much duration is left for the remaining words. We design experiments on
four language directions (German -&amp;gt; English, Spanish -&amp;gt; English, Chinese &amp;lt;-&amp;gt;
English), and the results show that the proposed method achieves better length
control ability on the generated speech than baseline methods. To make up the
lack of real-world datasets, we also construct a real-world test set collected
from films to provide comprehensive evaluations on the video dubbing task.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yihan Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Guo_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Junliang Guo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tan_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xu Tan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chen Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bohan Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Song_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ruihua Song&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+He_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lei He&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhao_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sheng Zhao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Menezes_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Arul Menezes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bian_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiang Bian&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2212.09917">
<title>Inverse Reinforcement Learning for Text Summarization. (arXiv:2212.09917v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2212.09917</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We introduce inverse reinforcement learning (IRL) as an effective paradigm
for training abstractive summarization models, imitating human summarization
behaviors. Our IRL model estimates the reward function using a suite of
important sub-rewards for summarization and concurrently optimizes the policy
network. Experimental results across datasets in different domains
(CNN/DailyMail and WikiHow) and various model sizes (BART-base and BART-large)
demonstrate the superiority of our proposed IRL model for summarization over
MLE and RL baselines. The resulting summaries exhibit greater similarity to
human-crafted gold references, outperforming MLE and RL baselines on metrics
such as ROUGE, coverage, novelty, compression ratio, factuality, and human
evaluations.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Fu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yu Fu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xiong_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Deyi Xiong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Dong_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yue Dong&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.16894">
<title>ViewRefer: Grasp the Multi-view Knowledge for 3D Visual Grounding with GPT and Prototype Guidance. (arXiv:2303.16894v4 [cs.CV] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.16894</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Understanding 3D scenes from multi-view inputs has been proven to alleviate
the view discrepancy issue in 3D visual grounding. However, existing methods
normally neglect the view cues embedded in the text modality and fail to weigh
the relative importance of different views. In this paper, we propose
ViewRefer, a multi-view framework for 3D visual grounding exploring how to
grasp the view knowledge from both text and 3D modalities. For the text branch,
ViewRefer leverages the diverse linguistic knowledge of large-scale language
models, e.g., GPT, to expand a single grounding text to multiple
geometry-consistent descriptions. Meanwhile, in the 3D modality, a transformer
fusion module with inter-view attention is introduced to boost the interaction
of objects across views. On top of that, we further present a set of learnable
multi-view prototypes, which memorize scene-agnostic knowledge for different
views, and enhance the framework from two perspectives: a view-guided attention
module for more robust text features, and a view-guided scoring strategy during
the final prediction. With our designed paradigm, ViewRefer achieves superior
performance on three benchmarks and surpasses the second-best by +2.8%, +1.5%,
and +1.35% on Sr3D, Nr3D, and ScanRefer. Code is released at
https://github.com/Ivan-Tang-3D/ViewRefer3D.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Guo_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zoey Guo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yiwen Tang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ray Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dong Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhigang Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhao_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bin Zhao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xuelong Li&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.11863">
<title>Scaling laws for language encoding models in fMRI. (arXiv:2305.11863v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.11863</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Representations from transformer-based unidirectional language models are
known to be effective at predicting brain responses to natural language.
However, most studies comparing language models to brains have used GPT-2 or
similarly sized language models. Here we tested whether larger open-source
models such as those from the OPT and LLaMA families are better at predicting
brain responses recorded using fMRI. Mirroring scaling results from other
contexts, we found that brain prediction performance scales logarithmically
with model size from 125M to 30B parameter models, with ~15% increased encoding
performance as measured by correlation with a held-out test set across 3
subjects. Similar logarithmic behavior was observed when scaling the size of
the fMRI training set. We also characterized scaling for acoustic encoding
models that use HuBERT, WavLM, and Whisper, and we found comparable
improvements with model size. A noise ceiling analysis of these large,
high-performance encoding models showed that performance is nearing the
theoretical maximum for brain areas such as the precuneus and higher auditory
cortex. These results suggest that increasing scale in both models and data
will yield incredibly effective models of language processing in the brain,
enabling better scientific understanding as well as applications such as
decoding.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Antonello_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Richard Antonello&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Vaidya_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aditya Vaidya&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Huth_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alexander G. Huth&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.17819">
<title>Large Language Models, scientific knowledge and factuality: A systematic analysis in antibiotic discovery. (arXiv:2305.17819v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.17819</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Inferring over and extracting information from Large Language Models (LLMs)
trained on a large corpus of scientific literature can potentially drive a new
era in biomedical research, reducing the barriers for accessing existing
medical evidence. This work examines the potential of LLMs for dialoguing with
biomedical background knowledge, using the context of antibiotic discovery. The
systematic analysis is applied to ten state-of-the-art models, from models
specialised on biomedical scientific corpora to general models such as ChatGPT,
GPT-4 and Llama 2 in two prompting-based tasks: chemical compound definition
generation and chemical compound-fungus relation determination. The work
provides a systematic assessment on the ability of LLMs to encode and express
these relations, verifying for fluency, prompt-alignment, semantic coherence,
factual knowledge and specificity of generated responses. Results show that
while recent models have improved in fluency, factual accuracy is still low and
models are biased towards over-represented entities. The ability of LLMs to
serve as biomedical knowledge bases is questioned, and the need for additional
systematic evaluation frameworks is highlighted. The best performing GPT-4
produced a factual definition for 70% of chemical compounds and 43.6% factual
relations to fungi, whereas the best open source model BioGPT-large 30% of the
compounds and 30% of the relations for the best-performing prompt. The results
show that while LLMs are currently not fit for purpose to be used as biomedical
factual knowledge bases, there is a promising emerging property in the
direction of factuality as the models become domain specialised, scale-up in
size and level of human feedback.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wysocka_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Magdalena Wysocka&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wysocki_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Oskar Wysocki&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Delmas_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Maxime Delmas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Mutel_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vincent Mutel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Freitas_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andre Freitas&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2306.04743">
<title>ScienceBenchmark: A Complex Real-World Benchmark for Evaluating Natural Language to SQL Systems. (arXiv:2306.04743v2 [cs.DB] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2306.04743</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Natural Language to SQL systems (NL-to-SQL) have recently shown a significant
increase in accuracy for natural language to SQL query translation. This
improvement is due to the emergence of transformer-based language models, and
the popularity of the Spider benchmark - the de-facto standard for evaluating
NL-to-SQL systems. The top NL-to-SQL systems reach accuracies of up to 85\%.
However, Spider mainly contains simple databases with few tables, columns, and
entries, which does not reflect a realistic setting. Moreover, complex
real-world databases with domain-specific content have little to no training
data available in the form of NL/SQL-pairs leading to poor performance of
existing NL-to-SQL systems.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we introduce ScienceBenchmark, a new complex NL-to-SQL
benchmark for three real-world, highly domain-specific databases. For this new
benchmark, SQL experts and domain experts created high-quality NL/SQL-pairs for
each domain. To garner more data, we extended the small amount of
human-generated data with synthetic data generated using GPT-3. We show that
our benchmark is highly challenging, as the top performing systems on Spider
achieve a very low performance on our benchmark. Thus, the challenge is
many-fold: creating NL-to-SQL systems for highly complex domains with a small
amount of hand-made training data augmented with synthetic data. To our
knowledge, ScienceBenchmark is the first NL-to-SQL benchmark designed with
complex real-world scientific databases, containing challenging training and
test data carefully validated by domain experts.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yi Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Deriu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jan Deriu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Katsogiannis_Meimarakis_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;George Katsogiannis-Meimarakis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kosten_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Catherine Kosten&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Koutrika_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Georgia Koutrika&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Stockinger_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kurt Stockinger&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2306.11300">
<title>RS5M: A Large Scale Vision-Language Dataset for Remote Sensing Vision-Language Foundation Model. (arXiv:2306.11300v4 [cs.CV] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2306.11300</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Pre-trained Vision-Language Models (VLMs) utilizing extensive image-text
paired data have demonstrated unprecedented image-text association
capabilities, achieving remarkable results across various downstream tasks. A
critical challenge is how to make use of existing large-scale pre-trained VLMs,
which are trained on common objects, to perform the domain-specific transfer
for accomplishing domain-related downstream tasks. A critical challenge is how
to make use of existing large-scale pre-trained VLMs, which are trained on
common objects, to perform the domain-specific transfer for accomplishing
domain-related downstream tasks. In this paper, we propose a new framework that
includes the Domain pre-trained Vision-Language Model (DVLM), bridging the gap
between the General Vision-Language Model (GVLM) and domain-specific downstream
tasks. Moreover, we present an image-text paired dataset in the field of remote
sensing (RS), RS5M, which has 5 million RS images with English descriptions.
The dataset is obtained from filtering publicly available image-text paired
datasets and captioning label-only RS datasets with pre-trained VLM. These
constitute the first large-scale RS image-text paired dataset. Additionally, we
fine-tuned the CLIP model and tried several Parameter-Efficient Fine-Tuning
methods on RS5M to implement the DVLM. Experimental results show that our
proposed dataset is highly effective for various tasks, and our model GeoRSCLIP
improves upon the baseline or previous state-of-the-art model by $3\%\sim20\%$
in Zero-shot Classification (ZSC), $3\%\sim6\%$ in Remote Sensing Cross-Modal
Text-Image Retrieval (RSCTIR) and $4\%\sim5\%$ in Semantic Localization (SeLo)
tasks. Dataset and models have been released in:
\url{https://github.com/om-ai-lab/RS5M}.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zilun Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhao_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tiancheng Zhao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Guo_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yulong Guo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yin_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jianwei Yin&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2306.15448">
<title>Understanding Social Reasoning in Language Models with Language Models. (arXiv:2306.15448v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2306.15448</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;As Large Language Models (LLMs) become increasingly integrated into our
everyday lives, understanding their ability to comprehend human mental states
becomes critical for ensuring effective interactions. However, despite the
recent attempts to assess the Theory-of-Mind (ToM) reasoning capabilities of
LLMs, the degree to which these models can align with human ToM remains a
nuanced topic of exploration. This is primarily due to two distinct challenges:
(1) the presence of inconsistent results from previous evaluations, and (2)
concerns surrounding the validity of existing evaluation methodologies. To
address these challenges, we present a novel framework for procedurally
generating evaluations with LLMs by populating causal templates. Using our
framework, we create a new social reasoning benchmark (BigToM) for LLMs which
consists of 25 controls and 5,000 model-written evaluations. We find that human
participants rate the quality of our benchmark higher than previous
crowd-sourced evaluations and comparable to expert-written evaluations. Using
BigToM, we evaluate the social reasoning capabilities of a variety of LLMs and
compare model performances with human performance. Our results suggest that
GPT4 has ToM capabilities that mirror human inference patterns, though less
reliable, while other LLMs struggle.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gandhi_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kanishk Gandhi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Franken_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jan-Philipp Fr&amp;#xe4;nken&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gerstenberg_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tobias Gerstenberg&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Goodman_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Noah D. Goodman&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2306.17840">
<title>Statler: State-Maintaining Language Models for Embodied Reasoning. (arXiv:2306.17840v3 [cs.RO] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2306.17840</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;There has been a significant research interest in employing large language
models to empower intelligent robots with complex reasoning. Existing work
focuses on harnessing their abilities to reason about the histories of their
actions and observations. In this paper, we explore a new dimension in which
large language models may benefit robotics planning. In particular, we propose
Statler, a framework in which large language models are prompted to maintain an
estimate of the world state, which are often unobservable, and track its
transition as new actions are taken. Our framework then conditions each action
on the estimate of the current world state. Despite being conceptually simple,
our Statler framework significantly outperforms strong competing methods (e.g.,
Code-as-Policies) on several robot planning tasks. Additionally, it has the
potential advantage of scaling up to more challenging long-horizon planning
tasks. We release our code at https://github.com/ripl/statler
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yoneda_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Takuma Yoneda&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Fang_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiading Fang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Peng Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Huanyu Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jiang_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tianchong Jiang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lin_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shengjie Lin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Picker_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ben Picker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yunis_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;David Yunis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Mei_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hongyuan Mei&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Walter_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Matthew R. Walter&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2308.16549">
<title>Thesis Distillation: Investigating The Impact of Bias in NLP Models on Hate Speech Detection. (arXiv:2308.16549v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2308.16549</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This paper is a summary of the work done in my PhD thesis. Where I
investigate the impact of bias in NLP models on the task of hate speech
detection from three perspectives: explainability, offensive stereotyping bias,
and fairness. Then, I discuss the main takeaways from my thesis and how they
can benefit the broader NLP community. Finally, I discuss important future
research directions. The findings of my thesis suggest that the bias in NLP
models impacts the task of hate speech detection from all three perspectives.
And that unless we start incorporating social sciences in studying bias in NLP
models, we will not effectively overcome the current limitations of measuring
and mitigating bias in NLP models.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Elsafoury_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fatma Elsafoury&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.10313">
<title>Investigating the Catastrophic Forgetting in Multimodal Large Language Models. (arXiv:2309.10313v4 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.10313</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Following the success of GPT4, there has been a surge in interest in
multimodal large language model (MLLM) research. This line of research focuses
on developing general-purpose LLMs through fine-tuning pre-trained LLMs and
vision models. However, catastrophic forgetting, a notorious phenomenon where
the fine-tuned model fails to retain similar performance compared to the
pre-trained model, still remains an inherent problem in multimodal LLMs (MLLM).
In this paper, we introduce EMT: Evaluating MulTimodality for evaluating the
catastrophic forgetting in MLLMs, by treating each MLLM as an image classifier.
We first apply EMT to evaluate several open-source fine-tuned MLLMs and we
discover that almost all evaluated MLLMs fail to retain the same performance
levels as their vision encoders on standard image classification tasks.
Moreover, we continue fine-tuning LLaVA, an MLLM and utilize EMT to assess
performance throughout the fine-tuning. Interestingly, our results suggest that
early-stage fine-tuning on an image dataset improves performance across other
image datasets, by enhancing the alignment of text and visual features.
However, as fine-tuning proceeds, the MLLMs begin to hallucinate, resulting in
a significant loss of generalizability, even when the image encoder remains
frozen. Our results suggest that MLLMs have yet to demonstrate performance on
par with their vision models on standard image classification tasks and the
current MLLM fine-tuning procedure still has room for improvement.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhai_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuexiang Zhai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tong_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shengbang Tong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiao Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cai_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mu Cai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Qu_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qing Qu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lee_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yong Jae Lee&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ma_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yi Ma&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.12307">
<title>LongLoRA: Efficient Fine-tuning of Long-Context Large Language Models. (arXiv:2309.12307v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.12307</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present LongLoRA, an efficient fine-tuning approach that extends the
context sizes of pre-trained large language models (LLMs), with limited
computation cost. Typically, training LLMs with long context sizes is
computationally expensive, requiring extensive training hours and GPU
resources. For example, training on the context length of 8192 needs 16x
computational costs in self-attention layers as that of 2048. In this paper, we
speed up the context extension of LLMs in two aspects. On the one hand,
although dense global attention is needed during inference, fine-tuning the
model can be effectively and efficiently done by sparse local attention. The
proposed shifted sparse attention (S$^2$-Attn) effectively enables context
extension, leading to non-trivial computation saving with similar performance
to fine-tuning with vanilla attention. Particularly, it can be implemented with
only two lines of code in training, while being optional in inference. On the
other hand, we revisit the parameter-efficient fine-tuning regime for context
expansion. Notably, we find that LoRA for context extension works well under
the premise of trainable embedding and normalization. LongLoRA combines this
improved LoRA with S$^2$-Attn. LongLoRA demonstrates strong empirical results
on various tasks on Llama2 models from 7B/13B to 70B. LongLoRA adopts Llama2 7B
from 4k context to 100k, or Llama2 70B to 32k on a single 8x A100 machine.
LongLoRA extends models&apos; context while retaining their original architectures,
and is compatible with most existing techniques, like Flash-Attention2. In
addition, we further conduct supervised fine-tuning with LongLoRA and our long
instruction-following LongAlpaca dataset.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yukang Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Qian_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shengju Qian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tang_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Haotian Tang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lai_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xin Lai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhijian Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Han_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Song Han&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jia_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiaya Jia&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.01415">
<title>GPT-Driver: Learning to Drive with GPT. (arXiv:2310.01415v3 [cs.CV] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.01415</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present a simple yet effective approach that can transform the OpenAI
GPT-3.5 model into a reliable motion planner for autonomous vehicles. Motion
planning is a core challenge in autonomous driving, aiming to plan a driving
trajectory that is safe and comfortable. Existing motion planners predominantly
leverage heuristic methods to forecast driving trajectories, yet these
approaches demonstrate insufficient generalization capabilities in the face of
novel and unseen driving scenarios. In this paper, we propose a novel approach
to motion planning that capitalizes on the strong reasoning capabilities and
generalization potential inherent to Large Language Models (LLMs). The
fundamental insight of our approach is the reformulation of motion planning as
a language modeling problem, a perspective not previously explored.
Specifically, we represent the planner inputs and outputs as language tokens,
and leverage the LLM to generate driving trajectories through a language
description of coordinate positions. Furthermore, we propose a novel
prompting-reasoning-finetuning strategy to stimulate the numerical reasoning
potential of the LLM. With this strategy, the LLM can describe highly precise
trajectory coordinates and also its internal decision-making process in natural
language. We evaluate our approach on the large-scale nuScenes dataset, and
extensive experiments substantiate the effectiveness, generalization ability,
and interpretability of our GPT-based motion planner. Code is now available at
https://github.com/PointsCoder/GPT-Driver.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Mao_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiageng Mao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Qian_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuxi Qian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ye_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Junjie Ye&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhao_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hang Zhao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yue Wang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.04406">
<title>Language Agent Tree Search Unifies Reasoning Acting and Planning in Language Models. (arXiv:2310.04406v2 [cs.AI] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.04406</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;While large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated impressive performance
on a range of decision-making tasks, they rely on simple acting processes and
fall short of broad deployment as autonomous agents. We introduce LATS
(Language Agent Tree Search), a general framework that synergizes the
capabilities of LLMs in planning, acting, and reasoning. Drawing inspiration
from Monte Carlo tree search in model-based reinforcement learning, LATS
employs LLMs as agents, value functions, and optimizers, repurposing their
latent strengths for enhanced decision-making. What is crucial in this method
is the use of an environment for external feedback, which offers a more
deliberate and adaptive problem-solving mechanism that moves beyond the
limitations of existing techniques. Our experimental evaluation across diverse
domains, such as programming, HotPotQA, and WebShop, illustrates the
applicability of LATS for both reasoning and acting. In particular, LATS
achieves 94.4% for programming on HumanEval with GPT-4 and an average score of
75.9 for web browsing on WebShop with GPT-3.5, demonstrating the effectiveness
and generality of our method.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhou_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andy Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yan_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kai Yan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shlapentokh_Rothman_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michal Shlapentokh-Rothman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Haohan Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yu-Xiong Wang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.07135">
<title>Comparing Styles across Languages. (arXiv:2310.07135v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.07135</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Understanding how styles differ across languages is advantageous for training
both humans and computers to generate culturally appropriate text. We introduce
an explanation framework to extract stylistic differences from multilingual LMs
and compare styles across languages. Our framework (1) generates comprehensive
style lexica in any language and (2) consolidates feature importances from LMs
into comparable lexical categories. We apply this framework to compare
politeness, creating the first holistic multilingual politeness dataset and
exploring how politeness varies across four languages. Our approach enables an
effective evaluation of how distinct linguistic categories contribute to
stylistic variations and provides interpretable insights into how people
communicate differently around the world.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Havaldar_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shreya Havaldar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Pressimone_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Matthew Pressimone&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wong_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Eric Wong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ungar_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lyle Ungar&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.16570">
<title>Give Me the Facts! A Survey on Factual Knowledge Probing in Pre-trained Language Models. (arXiv:2310.16570v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.16570</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Pre-trained Language Models (PLMs) are trained on vast unlabeled data, rich
in world knowledge. This fact has sparked the interest of the community in
quantifying the amount of factual knowledge present in PLMs, as this explains
their performance on downstream tasks, and potentially justifies their use as
knowledge bases. In this work, we survey methods and datasets that are used to
probe PLMs for factual knowledge. Our contributions are: (1) We propose a
categorization scheme for factual probing methods that is based on how their
inputs, outputs and the probed PLMs are adapted; (2) We provide an overview of
the datasets used for factual probing; (3) We synthesize insights about
knowledge retention and prompt optimization in PLMs, analyze obstacles to
adopting PLMs as knowledge bases and outline directions for future work.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Youssef_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Paul Youssef&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Koras_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Osman Alperen Kora&amp;#x15f;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Meijie Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Schlotterer_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J&amp;#xf6;rg Schl&amp;#xf6;tterer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Seifert_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Christin Seifert&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.20138">
<title>DEPN: Detecting and Editing Privacy Neurons in Pretrained Language Models. (arXiv:2310.20138v2 [cs.CR] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.20138</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Large language models pretrained on a huge amount of data capture rich
knowledge and information in the training data. The ability of data
memorization and regurgitation in pretrained language models, revealed in
previous studies, brings the risk of data leakage. In order to effectively
reduce these risks, we propose a framework DEPN to Detect and Edit Privacy
Neurons in pretrained language models, partially inspired by knowledge neurons
and model editing. In DEPN, we introduce a novel method, termed as privacy
neuron detector, to locate neurons associated with private information, and
then edit these detected privacy neurons by setting their activations to zero.
Furthermore, we propose a privacy neuron aggregator dememorize private
information in a batch processing manner. Experimental results show that our
method can significantly and efficiently reduce the exposure of private data
leakage without deteriorating the performance of the model. Additionally, we
empirically demonstrate the relationship between model memorization and privacy
neurons, from multiple perspectives, including model size, training time,
prompts, privacy neuron distribution, illustrating the robustness of our
approach.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wu_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xinwei Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Junzhuo Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xu_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Minghui Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Dong_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Weilong Dong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wu_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shuangzhi Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bian_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chao Bian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xiong_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Deyi Xiong&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.20204">
<title>General-Purpose Retrieval-Enhanced Medical Prediction Model Using Near-Infinite History. (arXiv:2310.20204v2 [cs.LG] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.20204</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Developing clinical prediction models (e.g., mortality prediction) based on
electronic health records (EHRs) typically relies on expert opinion for feature
selection and adjusting observation window size. This burdens experts and
creates a bottleneck in the development process. We propose Retrieval-Enhanced
Medical prediction model (REMed) to address such challenges. REMed can
essentially evaluate an unlimited number of clinical events, select the
relevant ones, and make predictions. This approach effectively eliminates the
need for manual feature selection and enables an unrestricted observation
window. We verified these properties through experiments on 27 clinical tasks
and two independent cohorts from publicly available EHR datasets, where REMed
outperformed other contemporary architectures that aim to handle as many events
as possible. Notably, we found that the preferences of REMed align closely with
those of medical experts. We expect our approach to significantly expedite the
development of EHR prediction models by minimizing clinicians&apos; need for manual
involvement.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kim_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Junu Kim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shim_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chaeeun Shim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yang_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bosco Seong Kyu Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Im_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chami Im&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lim_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sung Yoon Lim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jeong_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Han-Gil Jeong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Choi_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Edward Choi&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.04923">
<title>Is one brick enough to break the wall of spoken dialogue state tracking?. (arXiv:2311.04923v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.04923</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In Task-Oriented Dialogue (TOD) systems, correctly updating the system&apos;s
understanding of the user&apos;s needs (a.k.a dialogue state tracking) is key to a
smooth interaction. Traditionally, TOD systems perform this update in three
steps: transcription of the user&apos;s utterance, semantic extraction of the key
concepts, and contextualization with the previously identified concepts. Such
cascade approaches suffer from cascading errors and separate optimization.
End-to-End approaches have been proved helpful up to the semantic extraction
step. This paper goes one step further paving the path towards completely
neural spoken dialogue state tracking by comparing three approaches: (1) a
state of the art cascade approach, (2) a locally E2E approach with rule-based
contextualization and (3) a completely neural approach.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Druart_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lucas Druart&lt;/a&gt; (LIA), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Vielzeuf_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Valentin Vielzeuf&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Esteve_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yannick Est&amp;#xe8;ve&lt;/a&gt; (LIA)</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.07989">
<title>Unifying the Perspectives of NLP and Software Engineering: A Survey on Language Models for Code. (arXiv:2311.07989v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.07989</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this work we systematically review the recent advancements in code
processing with language models, covering 50+ models, 30+ evaluation tasks,
170+ datasets, and 700 related works. We break down code processing models into
general language models represented by the GPT family and specialized models
that are specifically pretrained on code, often with tailored objectives. We
discuss the relations and differences between these models, and highlight the
historical transition of code modeling from statistical models and RNNs to
pretrained Transformers and LLMs, which is exactly the same course that had
been taken by NLP. We also discuss code-specific features such as AST, CFG, and
unit tests, along with their application in training code language models, and
identify key challenges and potential future directions in this domain. We keep
the survey open and updated on GitHub at
https://github.com/codefuse-ai/Awesome-Code-LLM.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ziyin Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chaoyu Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bingchang Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liao_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Cong Liao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gong_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zi Gong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yu_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hang Yu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jianguo Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rui Wang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.13307">
<title>Rethinking Radiology Report Generation via Causal Reasoning and Counterfactual Augmentation. (arXiv:2311.13307v2 [cs.CV] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.13307</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Radiology Report Generation (RRG) draws attention as an interaction between
vision and language fields. Previous works inherited the ideology of
vision-to-language generation tasks,aiming to generate paragraphs with high
consistency as reports. However, one unique characteristic of RRG, the
independence between diseases, was neglected, leading to the injection of
disease co-occurrence as a confounder that effects the results through backdoor
path. Unfortunately, this confounder confuses the process of report generation
worse because of the biased RRG data distribution. In this paper, to rethink
this issue thoroughly, we reason about its causes and effects from a novel
perspective of statistics and causality, where the Joint Vision Coupling and
the Conditional Sentence Coherence Coupling are two aspects prone to implicitly
decrease the accuracy of reports. Then, a counterfactual augmentation strategy
that contains the Counterfactual Sample Synthesis and the Counterfactual Report
Reconstruction sub-methods is proposed to break these two aspects of spurious
effects. Experimental results and further analyses on two widely used datasets
justify our reasoning and proposed methods.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Song_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiao Song&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiafan Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yun Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lei_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wenbin Lei&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ruxin Wang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.15218">
<title>Real-Time Online Stock Forecasting Utilizing Integrated Quantitative and Qualitative Analysis. (arXiv:2311.15218v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.15218</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The application of Machine learning to finance has become a familiar
approach, even more so in stock market forecasting. The stock market is highly
volatile and huge amounts of data are generated every minute globally. The
extraction of effective intelligence from this data is of critical importance.
However, a collaboration of numerical stock data with qualitative text data can
be a challenging task. In this work, we accomplish this and provide an
unprecedented, publicly available dataset with technical and fundamental data,
sentiment that we gathered from News Archives, TV news captions, Radio
Transcripts, Tweets, Daily financial newspapers, etc. The text data entries
used for sentiment extraction total more than 1.4 Million. The dataset consists
of daily entries from January 2018 to December 2022 for 8 companies
representing diverse industrial sectors and the Dow Jones Industrial Average
(DJIA) as a whole. Holistic Fundamental and Technical data is provided training
ready for Model learning and deployment. The data generated could be used for
Incremental online learning with real-time data points retrieved daily, since
there was no stagnant data utilized, all the data was retired from APIs or
self-designed scripts. Moreover, the utilization of Spearman&apos;s rank correlation
over real-time data, linking stock returns with sentiment analysis has produced
noteworthy results for the DJIA achieving accuracy levels surpassing 60\%. The
dataset is made available at https://github.com/batking24/Huge-Stock-Dataset
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bathini_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sai Akash Bathini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cihan_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dagli Cihan&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.16989">
<title>ChatGPT&apos;s One-year Anniversary: Are Open-Source Large Language Models Catching up?. (arXiv:2311.16989v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.16989</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Upon its release in late 2022, ChatGPT has brought a seismic shift in the
entire landscape of AI, both in research and commerce. Through
instruction-tuning a large language model (LLM) with supervised fine-tuning and
reinforcement learning from human feedback, it showed that a model could answer
human questions and follow instructions on a broad panel of tasks. Following
this success, interests in LLMs have intensified, with new LLMs flourishing at
frequent interval across academia and industry, including many start-ups
focused on LLMs. While closed-source LLMs (e.g., OpenAI&apos;s GPT, Anthropic&apos;s
Claude) generally outperform their open-source counterparts, the progress on
the latter has been rapid with claims of achieving parity or even better on
certain tasks. This has crucial implications not only on research but also on
business. In this work, on the first anniversary of ChatGPT, we provide an
exhaustive overview of this success, surveying all tasks where an open-source
LLM has claimed to be on par or better than ChatGPT.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hailin Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jiao_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fangkai Jiao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xingxuan Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Qin_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chengwei Qin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ravaut_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mathieu Ravaut&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhao_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ruochen Zhao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xiong_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Caiming Xiong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Joty_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shafiq Joty&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.18743">
<title>AlignBench: Benchmarking Chinese Alignment of Large Language Models. (arXiv:2311.18743v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.18743</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Alignment has become a critical step for instruction-tuned Large Language
Models (LLMs) to become helpful assistants. However, effective evaluation of
alignment for emerging Chinese LLMs is still significantly lacking, calling for
real-scenario grounded, open-ended, challenging and automatic evaluations
tailored for alignment. To fill in this gap, we introduce AlignBench, a
comprehensive multi-dimensional benchmark for evaluating LLMs&apos; alignment in
Chinese. Equipped with a human-in-the-loop data curation pipeline, our
benchmark employs a rule-calibrated multi-dimensional LLM-as-Judge with
Chain-of-Thought to generate explanations and final ratings as evaluations,
ensuring high reliability and interpretability. Furthermore, we report
AlignBench evaluated by CritiqueLLM, a dedicated Chinese evaluator LLM that
recovers 95% of GPT-4&apos;s evaluation ability. We will provide public APIs for
evaluating AlignBench with CritiqueLLM to facilitate the evaluation of LLMs&apos;
Chinese alignment. All evaluation codes, data, and LLM generations are
available at \url{https://github.com/THUDM/AlignBench}.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiao Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lei_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xuanyu Lei&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shengyuan Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Huang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yue Huang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Feng_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhuoer Feng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wen_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bosi Wen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cheng_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiale Cheng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ke_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pei Ke&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yifan Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tam_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Weng Lam Tam&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaohan Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sun_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lichao Sun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hongning Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jing Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Huang_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Minlie Huang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Dong_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuxiao Dong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tang_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jie Tang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.01529">
<title>T3D: Towards 3D Medical Image Understanding through Vision-Language Pre-training. (arXiv:2312.01529v2 [cs.CV] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.01529</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Expert annotation of 3D medical image for downstream analysis is
resource-intensive, posing challenges in clinical applications. Visual
self-supervised learning (vSSL), though effective for learning visual
invariance, neglects the incorporation of domain knowledge from medicine. To
incorporate medical knowledge into visual representation learning,
vision-language pre-training (VLP) has shown promising results in 2D image.
However, existing VLP approaches become generally impractical when applied to
high-resolution 3D medical images due to GPU hardware constraints and the
potential loss of critical details caused by downsampling, which is the
intuitive solution to hardware constraints. To address the above limitations,
we introduce T3D, the first VLP framework designed for high-resolution 3D
medical images. T3D incorporates two text-informed pretext tasks:
(\lowerromannumeral{1}) text-informed contrastive learning;
(\lowerromannumeral{2}) text-informed image restoration. These tasks focus on
learning 3D visual representations from high-resolution 3D medical images and
integrating clinical knowledge from radiology reports, without distorting
information through forced alignment of downsampled volumes with detailed
anatomical text. Trained on a newly curated large-scale dataset of 3D medical
images and radiology reports, T3D significantly outperforms current vSSL
methods in tasks like organ and tumor segmentation, as well as disease
classification. This underlines T3D&apos;s potential in representation learning for
3D medical image analysis. All data and code will be available upon acceptance.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Che Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ouyang_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Cheng Ouyang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yinda Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Quilodran_Casas_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Cesar C&amp;#xe9;sar Quilodr&amp;#xe1;n-Casas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ma_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lei Ma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Fu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jie Fu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Guo_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yike Guo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shah_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Anand Shah&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bai_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wenjia Bai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Arcucci_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rossella Arcucci&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.01678">
<title>Jellyfish: A Large Language Model for Data Preprocessing. (arXiv:2312.01678v2 [cs.AI] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.01678</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we present Jellyfish, an open-source LLM as a universal task
solver for DP. Built on the Llama 2 13B model, Jellyfish is instruction-tuned
with the datasets of several typical DP tasks including error detection, data
imputation, schema matching, and entity matching, and delivers generalizability
to other tasks. Remarkably, Jellyfish can operate on a local, single, and
low-priced GPU with its 13 billion parameters, ensuring data security and
enabling further tuning. Its proficiency in understanding natural language
allows users to manually craft instructions for DP tasks. Unlike many existing
methods that heavily rely on prior knowledge, Jellyfish acquires domain
knowledge during its tuning process and integrates optional knowledge injection
during inference. A distinctive feature of Jellyfish is its interpreter, which
elucidates its output decisions. To construct Jellyfish, we develop a series of
pre-tuning and DP-tuning techniques. Jellyfish is equipped with an instance
serializer, which automatically translates raw data into model prompts, and a
knowledge injector, which optionally introduces task- and dataset-specific
knowledge to enhance DP performance. Our evaluation of Jellyfish, using a range
of real datasets, shows its competitiveness compared to state-of-the-art
methods and its strong generalizability to unseen tasks. Jellyfish&apos;s
performance rivals that of GPT series models, and its interpreter offers
enhanced reasoning capabilities compared to GPT-3.5. Furthermore, our
evaluation highlights the effectiveness of the techniques employed in
constructing Jellyfish. Our model is available at Hugging Face:
https://huggingface.co/NECOUDBFM/Jellyfish .
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Haochen Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Dong_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuyang Dong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xiao_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chuan Xiao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Oyamada_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Masafumi Oyamada&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02143">
<title>Competition-Level Problems are Effective LLM Evaluators. (arXiv:2312.02143v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02143</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated impressive reasoning
capabilities, yet there is ongoing debate about these abilities and the
potential data contamination problem recently. This paper aims to evaluate the
reasoning capacities of LLMs, specifically in solving recent competition-level
programming problems in Codeforces, which are expert-crafted and unique,
requiring deep understanding and robust reasoning skills. We first provide a
comprehensive evaluation of GPT-4&apos;s peiceived zero-shot performance on this
task, considering various aspects such as problems&apos; release time, difficulties,
and types of errors encountered. Surprisingly, the peiceived performance of
GPT-4 has experienced a cliff like decline in problems after September 2021
consistently across all the difficulties and types of problems, which shows the
potential data contamination, as well as the challenges for any existing LLM to
solve unseen complex reasoning problems. We further explore various approaches
such as fine-tuning, Chain-of-Thought prompting and problem description
simplification, unfortunately none of them is able to consistently mitigate the
challenges. Through our work, we emphasis the importance of this excellent data
source for assessing the genuine reasoning capabilities of LLMs, and foster the
development of LLMs with stronger reasoning abilities and better generalization
in the future.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Huang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yiming Huang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lin_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhenghao Lin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiao Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gong_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yeyun Gong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lu_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shuai Lu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lei_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fangyu Lei&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yaobo Liang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shen_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yelong Shen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lin_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chen Lin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Duan_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nan Duan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Weizhu Chen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>