<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Computer Science -- Computation and Language (cs.CL) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2023-11-21T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Computer Science -- Computation and Language</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12131" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12179" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12233" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12275" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12289" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12298" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12315" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12323" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12337" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12351" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12355" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12373" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12375" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12395" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12399" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12404" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12405" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12410" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12418" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12420" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12457" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12468" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12474" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12475" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12480" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12489" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12534" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12537" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12538" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12574" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12649" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12664" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12689" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12699" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12707" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12727" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12735" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2012.12311" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2102.00225" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.10852" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2301.02748" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.03898" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.10429" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.18098" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2306.17103" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2307.03172" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.01446" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.17453" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.02129" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.02168" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.05140" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.07161" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.17940" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.18168" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.06233" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.09387" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.10770" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.10777" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.10899" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12131">
<title>Human Learning by Model Feedback: The Dynamics of Iterative Prompting with Midjourney. (arXiv:2311.12131v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12131</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Generating images with a Text-to-Image model often requires multiple trials,
where human users iteratively update their prompt based on feedback, namely the
output image. Taking inspiration from cognitive work on reference games and
dialogue alignment, this paper analyzes the dynamics of the user prompts along
such iterations. We compile a dataset of iterative interactions of human users
with Midjourney. Our analysis then reveals that prompts predictably converge
toward specific traits along these iterations. We further study whether this
convergence is due to human users, realizing they missed important details, or
due to adaptation to the model&apos;s ``preferences&apos;&apos;, producing better images for a
specific language style. We show initial evidence that both possibilities are
at play. The possibility that users adapt to the model&apos;s preference raises
concerns about reusing user data for further training. The prompts may be
biased towards the preferences of a specific model, rather than align with
human intentions and natural manner of expression.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Don_Yehiya_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shachar Don-Yehiya&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Choshen_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Leshem Choshen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Abend_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Omri Abend&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12179">
<title>Leveraging Closed-Access Multilingual Embedding for Automatic Sentence Alignment in Low Resource Languages. (arXiv:2311.12179v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12179</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The importance of qualitative parallel data in machine translation has long
been determined but it has always been very difficult to obtain such in
sufficient quantity for the majority of world languages, mainly because of the
associated cost and also the lack of accessibility to these languages. Despite
the potential for obtaining parallel datasets from online articles using
automatic approaches, forensic investigations have found a lot of
quality-related issues such as misalignment, and wrong language codes. In this
work, we present a simple but qualitative parallel sentence aligner that
carefully leveraged the closed-access Cohere multilingual embedding, a solution
that ranked second in the just concluded #CoHereAIHack 2023 Challenge (see
https://ai6lagos.devpost.com). The proposed approach achieved $94.96$ and
$54.83$ f1 scores on FLORES and MAFAND-MT, compared to $3.64$ and $0.64$ of
LASER respectively. Our method also achieved an improvement of more than 5 BLEU
scores over LASER, when the resulting datasets were used with MAFAND-MT dataset
to train translation models. Our code and data are available for research
purposes here (https://github.com/abumafrim/Cohere-Align).
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Abdulmumin_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Idris Abdulmumin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Khalid_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Auwal Abubakar Khalid&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Muhammad_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shamsuddeen Hassan Muhammad&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ahmad_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ibrahim Said Ahmad&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Aliyu_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lukman Jibril Aliyu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sani_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Babangida Sani&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Abduljalil_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bala Mairiga Abduljalil&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hassan_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sani Ahmad Hassan&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12233">
<title>Unifying Corroborative and Contributive Attributions in Large Language Models. (arXiv:2311.12233v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12233</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;As businesses, products, and services spring up around large language models,
the trustworthiness of these models hinges on the verifiability of their
outputs. However, methods for explaining language model outputs largely fall
across two distinct fields of study which both use the term &quot;attribution&quot; to
refer to entirely separate techniques: citation generation and training data
attribution. In many modern applications, such as legal document generation and
medical question answering, both types of attributions are important. In this
work, we argue for and present a unified framework of large language model
attributions. We show how existing methods of different types of attribution
fall under the unified framework. We also use the framework to discuss
real-world use cases where one or both types of attributions are required. We
believe that this unified framework will guide the use case driven development
of systems that leverage both types of attribution, as well as the
standardization of their evaluation.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Worledge_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Theodora Worledge&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shen_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Judy Hanwen Shen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Meister_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nicole Meister&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Winston_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Caleb Winston&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Guestrin_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Carlos Guestrin&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12275">
<title>Enabling On-Device Large Language Model Personalization with Self-Supervised Data Selection and Synthesis. (arXiv:2311.12275v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12275</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;After a large language model (LLM) is deployed on edge devices, it is
desirable for these devices to learn from user-generated conversation data to
generate user-specific and personalized responses in real-time. However,
user-generated data usually contains sensitive and private information, and
uploading such data to the cloud for annotation is not preferred if not
prohibited. While it is possible to obtain annotation locally by directly
asking users to provide preferred responses, such annotations have to be sparse
to not affect user experience. In addition, the storage of edge devices is
usually too limited to enable large-scale fine-tuning with full user-generated
data. It remains an open question how to enable on-device LLM personalization,
considering sparse annotation and limited on-device storage. In this paper, we
propose a novel framework to select and store the most representative data
online in a self-supervised way. Such data has a small memory footprint and
allows infrequent requests of user annotations for further fine-tuning. To
enhance fine-tuning quality, multiple semantically similar pairs of question
texts and expected responses are generated using the LLM. Our experiments show
that the proposed framework achieves the best user-specific content-generating
capability (accuracy) and fine-tuning speed (performance) compared with vanilla
baselines. To the best of our knowledge, this is the very first on-device LLM
personalization framework.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Qin_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ruiyang Qin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xia_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jun Xia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jia_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhenge Jia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jiang_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Meng Jiang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Abbasi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ahmed Abbasi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhou_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Peipei Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jingtong Hu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shi_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yiyu Shi&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12289">
<title>ATLANTIC: Structure-Aware Retrieval-Augmented Language Model for Interdisciplinary Science. (arXiv:2311.12289v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12289</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Large language models record impressive performance on many natural language
processing tasks. However, their knowledge capacity is limited to the
pretraining corpus. Retrieval augmentation offers an effective solution by
retrieving context from external knowledge sources to complement the language
model. However, existing retrieval augmentation techniques ignore the
structural relationships between these documents. Furthermore, retrieval models
are not explored much in scientific tasks, especially in regard to the
faithfulness of retrieved documents. In this paper, we propose a novel
structure-aware retrieval augmented language model that accommodates document
structure during retrieval augmentation. We create a heterogeneous document
graph capturing multiple types of relationships (e.g., citation, co-authorship,
etc.) that connect documents from more than 15 scientific disciplines (e.g.,
Physics, Medicine, Chemistry, etc.). We train a graph neural network on the
curated document graph to act as a structural encoder for the corresponding
passages retrieved during the model pretraining. Particularly, along with text
embeddings of the retrieved passages, we obtain structural embeddings of the
documents (passages) and fuse them together before feeding them to the language
model. We evaluate our model extensively on various scientific benchmarks that
include science question-answering and scientific document classification
tasks. Experimental results demonstrate that structure-aware retrieval improves
retrieving more coherent, faithful and contextually relevant passages, while
showing a comparable performance in the overall accuracy.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Munikoti_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sai Munikoti&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Acharya_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Anurag Acharya&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wagle_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sridevi Wagle&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Horawalavithana_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sameera Horawalavithana&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12298">
<title>Noise in Relation Classification Dataset TACRED: Characterization and Reduction. (arXiv:2311.12298v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12298</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The overarching objective of this paper is two-fold. First, to explore
model-based approaches to characterize the primary cause of the noise. in the
RE dataset TACRED Second, to identify the potentially noisy instances. Towards
the first objective, we analyze predictions and performance of state-of-the-art
(SOTA) models to identify the root cause of noise in the dataset. Our analysis
of TACRED shows that the majority of the noise in the dataset originates from
the instances labeled as no-relation which are negative examples. For the
second objective, we explore two nearest-neighbor-based strategies to
automatically identify potentially noisy examples for elimination and
reannotation. Our first strategy, referred to as Intrinsic Strategy (IS), is
based on the assumption that positive examples are clean. Thus, we have used
false-negative predictions to identify noisy negative examples. Whereas, our
second approach, referred to as Extrinsic Strategy, is based on using a clean
subset of the dataset to identify potentially noisy negative examples. Finally,
we retrained the SOTA models on the eliminated and reannotated dataset. Our
empirical results based on two SOTA models trained on TACRED-E following the IS
show an average 4% F1-score improvement, whereas reannotation (TACRED-R) does
not improve the original results. However, following ES, SOTA models show the
average F1-score improvement of 3.8% and 4.4% when trained on respective
eliminated (TACRED-EN) and reannotated (TACRED-RN) datasets respectively. We
further extended the ES for cleaning positive examples as well, which resulted
in an average performance improvement of 5.8% and 5.6% for the eliminated
(TACRED-ENP) and reannotated (TACRED-RNP) datasets respectively.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Parekh_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Akshay Parekh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Anand_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ashish Anand&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Awekar_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Amit Awekar&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12315">
<title>AcademicGPT: Empowering Academic Research. (arXiv:2311.12315v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12315</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated exceptional capabilities
across various natural language processing tasks. Yet, many of these advanced
LLMs are tailored for broad, general-purpose applications. In this technical
report, we introduce AcademicGPT, designed specifically to empower academic
research. AcademicGPT is a continual training model derived from LLaMA2-70B.
Our training corpus mainly consists of academic papers, thesis, content from
some academic domain, high-quality Chinese data and others. While it may not be
extensive in data scale, AcademicGPT marks our initial venture into a
domain-specific GPT tailored for research area. We evaluate AcademicGPT on
several established public benchmarks such as MMLU and CEval, as well as on
some specialized academic benchmarks like PubMedQA, SCIEval, and our
newly-created ComputerScienceQA, to demonstrate its ability from general
knowledge ability, to Chinese ability, and to academic ability. Building upon
AcademicGPT&apos;s foundation model, we also developed several applications catered
to the academic area, including General Academic Question Answering,
AI-assisted Paper Reading, Paper Review, and AI-assisted Title and Abstract
Generation.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wei_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shufa Wei&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xu_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaolong Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Qi_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xianbiao Qi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yin_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xi Yin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xia_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jun Xia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ren_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jingyi Ren&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tang_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Peijun Tang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhong_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuxiang Zhong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yihao Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ren_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaoqin Ren&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuxin Liang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Huang_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Liankai Huang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xie_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kai Xie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gui_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Weikang Gui&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tan_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei Tan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sun_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shuanglong Sun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yongquan Hu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qinxian Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nanjin Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Dai_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chihao Dai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lihua Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaohui Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lei Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xie_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yutao Xie&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12323">
<title>Modeling Political Orientation of Social Media Posts: An Extended Analysis. (arXiv:2311.12323v1 [cs.SI])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12323</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Developing machine learning models to characterize political polarization on
online social media presents significant challenges. These challenges mainly
stem from various factors such as the lack of annotated data, presence of noise
in social media datasets, and the sheer volume of data. The common research
practice typically examines the biased structure of online user communities for
a given topic or qualitatively measuring the impacts of polarized topics on
social media. However, there is limited work focusing on analyzing polarization
at the ground-level, specifically in the social media posts themselves. Such
existing analysis heavily relies on annotated data, which often requires
laborious human labeling, offers labels only to specific problems, and lacks
the ability to determine the near-future bias state of a social media
conversations. Understanding the degree of political orientation conveyed in
social media posts is crucial for quantifying the bias of online user
communities and investigating the spread of polarized content. In this work, we
first introduce two heuristic methods that leverage on news media bias and post
content to label social media posts. Next, we compare the efficacy and quality
of heuristically labeled dataset with a randomly sampled human-annotated
dataset. Additionally, we demonstrate that current machine learning models can
exhibit improved performance in predicting political orientation of social
media posts, employing both traditional supervised learning and few-shot
learning setups. We conduct experiments using the proposed heuristic methods
and machine learning approaches to predict the political orientation of posts
collected from two social media forums with diverse political ideologies: Gab
and Twitter.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kamal_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sadia Kamal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Little_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Brenner Little&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gullic_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jade Gullic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Harms_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Trevor Harms&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Olofsson_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kristin Olofsson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bagavathi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Arunkumar Bagavathi&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12337">
<title>Do Smaller Language Models Answer Contextualised Questions Through Memorisation Or Generalisation?. (arXiv:2311.12337v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12337</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A distinction is often drawn between a model&apos;s ability to predict a label for
an evaluation sample that is directly memorised from highly similar training
samples versus an ability to predict the label via some method of
generalisation. In the context of using Language Models for question-answering,
discussion continues to occur as to the extent to which questions are answered
through memorisation. We consider this issue for questions that would ideally
be answered through reasoning over an associated context. We propose a method
of identifying evaluation samples for which it is very unlikely our model would
have memorised the answers. Our method is based on semantic similarity of input
tokens and label tokens between training and evaluation samples. We show that
our method offers advantages upon some prior approaches in that it is able to
surface evaluation-train pairs that have overlap in either contiguous or
discontiguous sequences of tokens. We use this method to identify unmemorisable
subsets of our evaluation datasets. We train two Language Models in a multitask
fashion whereby the second model differs from the first only in that it has two
additional datasets added to the training regime that are designed to impart
simple numerical reasoning strategies of a sort known to improve performance on
some of our evaluation datasets but not on others. We then show that there is
performance improvement between the two models on the unmemorisable subsets of
the evaluation datasets that were expected to benefit from the additional
training datasets. Specifically, performance on unmemorisable subsets of two of
our evaluation datasets, DROP and ROPES significantly improves by 9.0%, and
25.7% respectively while other evaluation datasets have no significant change
in performance.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hartill_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tim Hartill&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bensemann_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Joshua Bensemann&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Witbrock_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michael Witbrock&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Riddle_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Patricia J. Riddle&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12351">
<title>Advancing Transformer Architecture in Long-Context Large Language Models: A Comprehensive Survey. (arXiv:2311.12351v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12351</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;With the bomb ignited by ChatGPT, Transformer-based Large Language Models
(LLMs) have paved a revolutionary path toward Artificial General Intelligence
(AGI) and have been applied in diverse areas as knowledge bases, human
interfaces, and dynamic agents. However, a prevailing limitation exists: many
current LLMs, constrained by resources, are primarily pre-trained on shorter
texts, rendering them less effective for longer-context prompts, commonly
encountered in real-world settings. In this paper, we present a comprehensive
survey focusing on the advancement of model architecture in Transformer-based
LLMs to optimize long-context capabilities across all stages from pre-training
to inference. We firstly delineate and analyze the problems of handling
long-context input and output with the current Transformer-based models. Then,
we mainly offer a holistic taxonomy to navigate the landscape of Transformer
upgrades on architecture to solve these problems. Afterward, we provide the
investigation on wildly used evaluation necessities tailored for long-context
LLMs, including datasets, metrics, and baseline models, as well as some amazing
optimization toolkits like libraries, systems, and compilers to augment LLMs&apos;
efficiency and efficacy across different stages. Finally, we further discuss
the predominant challenges and potential avenues for future research in this
domain. Additionally, we have established a repository where we curate relevant
literature with real-time updates at
https://github.com/Strivin0311/long-llms-learning.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Huang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yunpeng Huang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jingwei Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jiang_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zixu Jiang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lai_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Junyu Lai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zenan Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yao_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuan Yao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Taolue Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yang_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lijuan Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xin_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhou Xin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ma_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaoxing Ma&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12355">
<title>Utilizing Language Models for Tour Itinerary Recommendation. (arXiv:2311.12355v1 [cs.IR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12355</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Tour itinerary recommendation involves planning a sequence of relevant
Point-of-Interest (POIs), which combines challenges from the fields of both
Operations Research (OR) and Recommendation Systems (RS). As an OR problem,
there is the need to maximize a certain utility (e.g., popularity of POIs in
the tour) while adhering to some constraints (e.g., maximum time for the tour).
As a RS problem, it is heavily related to problem or filtering or ranking a
subset of POIs that are relevant to a user and recommending it as part of an
itinerary. In this paper, we explore the use of language models for the task of
tour itinerary recommendation and planning. This task has the unique
requirement of recommending personalized POIs relevant to users and planning
these POIs as an itinerary that satisfies various constraints. We discuss some
approaches in this area, such as using word embedding techniques like Word2Vec
and GloVe for learning POI embeddings and transformer-based techniques like
BERT for generating
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;itineraries.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ho_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ngai Lam Ho&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lim_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kwan Hui Lim&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12373">
<title>Beyond Turing: A Comparative Analysis of Approaches for Detecting Machine-Generated Text. (arXiv:2311.12373v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12373</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Significant progress has been made on text generation by pre-trained language
models (PLMs), yet distinguishing between human and machine-generated text
poses an escalating challenge. This paper offers an in-depth evaluation of
three distinct methods used to address this task: traditional shallow learning,
Language Model (LM) fine-tuning, and Multilingual Model fine-tuning. These
approaches are rigorously tested on a wide range of machine-generated texts,
providing a benchmark of their competence in distinguishing between
human-authored and machine-authored linguistic constructs. The results reveal
considerable differences in performance across methods, thus emphasizing the
continued need for advancement in this crucial area of NLP. This study offers
valuable insights and paves the way for future research aimed at creating
robust and highly discriminative models.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Adilazuarda_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Muhammad Farid Adilazuarda&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Arkoulis_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nikolaos Nektarios Arkoulis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chumakov_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Oleksii Chumakov&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12375">
<title>The Obscure Limitation of Modular Multilingual Language Models. (arXiv:2311.12375v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12375</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We expose the limitation of modular multilingual language models (MLMs) in
multilingual inference scenarios with unknown languages. Existing evaluations
of modular MLMs exclude the involvement of language identification (LID)
modules, which obscures the performance of real-case multilingual scenarios of
modular MLMs. In this work, we showcase the effect of adding LID on the
multilingual evaluation of modular MLMs and provide discussions for closing the
performance gap of caused by the pipelined approach of LID and modular MLMs.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Adilazuarda_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Muhammad Farid Adilazuarda&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cahyawijaya_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Samuel Cahyawijaya&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Purwarianti_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ayu Purwarianti&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12395">
<title>Problems of Non-equivalent Words in Technical Translation. (arXiv:2311.12395v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12395</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Translating words which do not have equivalent in target language is not easy
and finding proper equivalent of those words are very important to render
correctly and understandably, the article defines some thoughts and ideas of
scientists on the common problems of non-equivalent words from English to
Russian language and includes English and Russian examples and ideas of certain
scientist. The English language is worldwide spoken and there are 1.35 billion
English speakers and over 258 million Russian speakers according to the 2021s
statistics. Inevitably, these billions of speakers around the world have
connection and they may have deal in different criteria. In order to understand
one another they need to have a pure and fully-understood language. These pure
languages understanding directly relates to translation knowledge where
linguists and translators need to work and research to eradicate
misunderstanding. Misunderstandings mostly appear in non-equivalent words
because there are different local and internal words like food, garment,
cultural and traditional words and others in every notion. Truly, most of these
words do not have equivalent in the target language and these words need to be
worked and find their equivalent in the target language to fully understand the
both languages. However, some of these non-equivalent words are already
professionally rendered to the target language but still there many other words
to be rendered. Hence, this research paper includes different ways and rules of
rendering non-equivalent words from source language to the target language.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Qani_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mohammad Ibrahim Qani&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12399">
<title>A Survey of Graph Meets Large Language Model: Progress and Future Directions. (arXiv:2311.12399v1 [cs.LG])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12399</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Graph plays a significant role in representing and analyzing complex
relationships in real-world applications such as citation networks, social
networks, and biological data. Recently, Large Language Models (LLMs), which
have achieved tremendous success in various domains, have also been leveraged
in graph-related tasks to surpass traditional Graph Neural Networks (GNNs)
based methods and yield state-of-the-art performance. In this survey, we first
present a comprehensive review and analysis of existing methods that integrate
LLMs with graphs. First of all, we propose a new taxonomy, which organizes
existing methods into three categories based on the role (i.e., enhancer,
predictor, and alignment component) played by LLMs in graph-related tasks. Then
we systematically survey the representative methods along the three categories
of the taxonomy. Finally, we discuss the remaining limitations of existing
studies and highlight promising avenues for future research. The relevant
papers are summarized and will be consistently updated at:
https://github.com/yhLeeee/Awesome-LLMs-in-Graph-tasks.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuhan Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhixun Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Peisong Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jia Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sun_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiangguo Sun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cheng_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hong Cheng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jeffrey Xu Yu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12404">
<title>InterPrompt: Interpretable Prompting for Interrelated Interpersonal Risk Factors in Reddit Posts. (arXiv:2311.12404v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12404</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Mental health professionals and clinicians have observed the upsurge of
mental disorders due to Interpersonal Risk Factors (IRFs). To simulate the
human-in-the-loop triaging scenario for early detection of mental health
disorders, we recognized textual indications to ascertain these IRFs : Thwarted
Belongingness (TBe) and Perceived Burdensomeness (PBu) within personal
narratives. In light of this, we use N-shot learning with GPT-3 model on the
IRF dataset, and underscored the importance of fine-tuning GPT-3 model to
incorporate the context-specific sensitivity and the interconnectedness of
textual cues that represent both IRFs.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we introduce an Interpretable Prompting (InterPrompt)} method
to boost the attention mechanism by fine-tuning the GPT-3 model. This allows a
more sophisticated level of language modification by adjusting the pre-trained
weights. Our model learns to detect usual patterns and underlying connections
across both the IRFs, which leads to better system-level explainability and
trustworthiness. The results of our research demonstrate that all four variants
of GPT-3 model, when fine-tuned with InterPrompt, perform considerably better
as compared to the baseline methods, both in terms of classification and
explanation generation.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sathvik_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;MSVPJ Sathvik&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sarkar_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Surjodeep Sarkar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Saxena_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chandni Saxena&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sohn_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sunghwan Sohn&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Garg_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Muskan Garg&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12405">
<title>IndoRobusta: Towards Robustness Against Diverse Code-Mixed Indonesian Local Languages. (arXiv:2311.12405v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12405</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Significant progress has been made on Indonesian NLP. Nevertheless,
exploration of the code-mixing phenomenon in Indonesian is limited, despite
many languages being frequently mixed with Indonesian in daily conversation. In
this work, we explore code-mixing in Indonesian with four embedded languages,
i.e., English, Sundanese, Javanese, and Malay; and introduce IndoRobusta, a
framework to evaluate and improve the code-mixing robustness. Our analysis
shows that the pre-training corpus bias affects the model&apos;s ability to better
handle Indonesian-English code-mixing when compared to other local languages,
despite having higher language diversity.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Adilazuarda_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Muhammad Farid Adilazuarda&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cahyawijaya_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Samuel Cahyawijaya&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Winata_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Genta Indra Winata&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Fung_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pascale Fung&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Purwarianti_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ayu Purwarianti&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12410">
<title>nach0: Multimodal Natural and Chemical Languages Foundation Model. (arXiv:2311.12410v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12410</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Large Language Models (LLMs) have substantially driven scientific progress in
various domains, and many papers have demonstrated their ability to tackle
complex problems with creative solutions. Our paper introduces a new foundation
model, nach0, capable of solving various chemical and biological tasks:
biomedical question answering, named entity recognition, molecular generation,
molecular synthesis, attributes prediction, and others. nach0 is a multi-domain
and multi-task encoder-decoder LLM pre-trained on unlabeled text from
scientific literature, patents, and molecule strings to incorporate a range of
chemical and linguistic knowledge. We employed instruction tuning, where
specific task-related instructions are utilized to fine-tune nach0 for the
final set of tasks. To train nach0 effectively, we leverage the NeMo framework,
enabling efficient parallel optimization of both base and large model versions.
Extensive experiments demonstrate that our model outperforms state-of-the-art
baselines on single-domain and cross-domain tasks. Furthermore, it can generate
high-quality outputs in molecular and textual formats, showcasing its
effectiveness in multi-domain setups.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Livne_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Micha Livne&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Miftahutdinov_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zulfat Miftahutdinov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tutubalina_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Elena Tutubalina&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kuznetsov_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Maksim Kuznetsov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Polykovskiy_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniil Polykovskiy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Brundyn_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Annika Brundyn&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jhunjhunwala_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aastha Jhunjhunwala&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Costa_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Anthony Costa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Aliper_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alex Aliper&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhavoronkov_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alex Zhavoronkov&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12418">
<title>Visual Analytics for Generative Transformer Models. (arXiv:2311.12418v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12418</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;While transformer-based models have achieved state-of-the-art results in a
variety of classification and generation tasks, their black-box nature makes
them challenging for interpretability. In this work, we present a novel visual
analytical framework to support the analysis of transformer-based generative
networks. In contrast to previous work, which has mainly focused on
encoder-based models, our framework is one of the first dedicated to supporting
the analysis of transformer-based encoder-decoder models and decoder-only
models for generative and classification tasks. Hence, we offer an intuitive
overview that allows the user to explore different facets of the model through
interactive visualization. To demonstrate the feasibility and usefulness of our
framework, we present three detailed case studies based on real-world NLP
research problems.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Raymond Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yang_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ruixin Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xiao_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wen Xiao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+AbuRaed_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ahmed AbuRaed&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Murray_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gabriel Murray&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Carenini_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Giuseppe Carenini&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12420">
<title>How Far Have We Gone in Vulnerability Detection Using Large Language Models. (arXiv:2311.12420v1 [cs.AI])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12420</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;As software becomes increasingly complex and prone to vulnerabilities,
automated vulnerability detection is critically important, yet challenging.
Given the significant successes of Large Language Models (LLMs) in various
tasks, there is growing anticipation of their efficacy in vulnerability
detection. However, a quantitative understanding of their potential in
vulnerability detection is still missing. To bridge this gap, we introduce a
comprehensive vulnerability benchmark VulBench. This benchmark aggregates
high-quality data from a wide range of CTF (Capture-the-Flag) challenges and
real-world applications, with annotations for each vulnerable function
detailing the vulnerability type and its root cause. Through our experiments
encompassing 16 LLMs and 6 state-of-the-art (SOTA) deep learning-based models
and static analyzers, we find that several LLMs outperform traditional deep
learning approaches in vulnerability detection, revealing an untapped potential
in LLMs. This work contributes to the understanding and utilization of LLMs for
enhanced software security.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gao_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zeyu Gao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hao Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhou_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuchen Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhu_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wenyu Zhu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chao Zhang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12457">
<title>LIP-RTVE: An Audiovisual Database for Continuous Spanish in the Wild. (arXiv:2311.12457v1 [cs.CV])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12457</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Speech is considered as a multi-modal process where hearing and vision are
two fundamentals pillars. In fact, several studies have demonstrated that the
robustness of Automatic Speech Recognition systems can be improved when audio
and visual cues are combined to represent the nature of speech. In addition,
Visual Speech Recognition, an open research problem whose purpose is to
interpret speech by reading the lips of the speaker, has been a focus of
interest in the last decades. Nevertheless, in order to estimate these systems
in the currently Deep Learning era, large-scale databases are required. On the
other hand, while most of these databases are dedicated to English, other
languages lack sufficient resources. Thus, this paper presents a
semi-automatically annotated audiovisual database to deal with unconstrained
natural Spanish, providing 13 hours of data extracted from Spanish television.
Furthermore, baseline results for both speaker-dependent and
speaker-independent scenarios are reported using Hidden Markov Models, a
traditional paradigm that has been widely used in the field of Speech
Technologies.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gimeno_Gomez_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;David Gimeno-G&amp;#xf3;mez&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Martinez_Hinarejos_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Carlos-D. Mart&amp;#xed;nez-Hinarejos&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12468">
<title>Analysis of Visual Features for Continuous Lipreading in Spanish. (arXiv:2311.12468v1 [cs.CV])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12468</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;During a conversation, our brain is responsible for combining information
obtained from multiple senses in order to improve our ability to understand the
message we are perceiving. Different studies have shown the importance of
presenting visual information in these situations. Nevertheless, lipreading is
a complex task whose objective is to interpret speech when audio is not
available. By dispensing with a sense as crucial as hearing, it will be
necessary to be aware of the challenge that this lack presents. In this paper,
we propose an analysis of different speech visual features with the intention
of identifying which of them is the best approach to capture the nature of lip
movements for natural Spanish and, in this way, dealing with the automatic
visual speech recognition task. In order to estimate our system, we present an
audiovisual corpus compiled from a subset of the RTVE database, which has been
used in the Albayz\&apos;in evaluations. We employ a traditional system based on
Hidden Markov Models with Gaussian Mixture Models. Results show that, although
the task is difficult, in restricted conditions we obtain recognition results
which determine that using eigenlips in combination with deep features is the
best visual approach.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gimeno_Gomez_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;David Gimeno-G&amp;#xf3;mez&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Martinez_Hinarejos_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Carlos-D. Mart&amp;#xed;nez-Hinarejos&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12474">
<title>CSMeD: Bridging the Dataset Gap in Automated Citation Screening for Systematic Literature Reviews. (arXiv:2311.12474v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12474</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Systematic literature reviews (SLRs) play an essential role in summarising,
synthesising and validating scientific evidence. In recent years, there has
been a growing interest in using machine learning techniques to automate the
identification of relevant studies for SLRs. However, the lack of standardised
evaluation datasets makes comparing the performance of such automated
literature screening systems difficult. In this paper, we analyse the citation
screening evaluation datasets, revealing that many of the available datasets
are either too small, suffer from data leakage or have limited applicability to
systems treating automated literature screening as a classification task, as
opposed to, for example, a retrieval or question-answering task. To address
these challenges, we introduce CSMeD, a meta-dataset consolidating nine
publicly released collections, providing unified access to 325 SLRs from the
fields of medicine and computer science. CSMeD serves as a comprehensive
resource for training and evaluating the performance of automated citation
screening models. Additionally, we introduce CSMeD-FT, a new dataset designed
explicitly for evaluating the full text publication screening task. To
demonstrate the utility of CSMeD, we conduct experiments and establish
baselines on new datasets.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kusa_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wojciech Kusa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Mendoza_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Oscar E. Mendoza&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Samwald_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Matthias Samwald&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Knoth_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Petr Knoth&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hanbury_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Allan Hanbury&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12475">
<title>PhayaThaiBERT: Enhancing a Pretrained Thai Language Model with Unassimilated Loanwords. (arXiv:2311.12475v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12475</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;While WangchanBERTa has become the de facto standard in transformer-based
Thai language modeling, it still has shortcomings in regard to the
understanding of foreign words, most notably English words, which are often
borrowed without orthographic assimilation into Thai in many contexts. We
identify the lack of foreign vocabulary in WangchanBERTa&apos;s tokenizer as the
main source of these shortcomings. We then expand WangchanBERTa&apos;s vocabulary
via vocabulary transfer from XLM-R&apos;s pretrained tokenizer and pretrain a new
model using the expanded tokenizer, starting from WangchanBERTa&apos;s checkpoint,
on a new dataset that is larger than the one used to train WangchanBERTa. Our
results show that our new pretrained model, PhayaThaiBERT, outperforms
WangchanBERTa in many downstream tasks and datasets.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sriwirote_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Panyut Sriwirote&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Thapiang_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jalinee Thapiang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Timtong_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vasan Timtong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Rutherford_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Attapol T. Rutherford&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12480">
<title>Speaker-Adapted End-to-End Visual Speech Recognition for Continuous Spanish. (arXiv:2311.12480v1 [cs.CV])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12480</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Different studies have shown the importance of visual cues throughout the
speech perception process. In fact, the development of audiovisual approaches
has led to advances in the field of speech technologies. However, although
noticeable results have recently been achieved, visual speech recognition
remains an open research problem. It is a task in which, by dispensing with the
auditory sense, challenges such as visual ambiguities and the complexity of
modeling silence must be faced. Nonetheless, some of these challenges can be
alleviated when the problem is approached from a speaker-dependent perspective.
Thus, this paper studies, using the Spanish LIP-RTVE database, how the
estimation of specialized end-to-end systems for a specific person could affect
the quality of speech recognition. First, different adaptation strategies based
on the fine-tuning technique were proposed. Then, a pre-trained CTC/Attention
architecture was used as a baseline throughout our experiments. Our findings
showed that a two-step fine-tuning process, where the VSR system is first
adapted to the task domain, provided significant improvements when the speaker
adaptation was addressed. Furthermore, results comparable to the current state
of the art were reached even when only a limited amount of data was available.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gimeno_Gomez_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;David Gimeno-G&amp;#xf3;mez&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Martinez_Hinarejos_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Carlos-D. Mart&amp;#xed;nez-Hinarejos&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12489">
<title>Multilingual Word Embeddings for Low-Resource Languages using Anchors and a Chain of Related Languages. (arXiv:2311.12489v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12489</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Very low-resource languages, having only a few million tokens worth of data,
are not well-supported by multilingual NLP approaches due to poor quality
cross-lingual word representations. Recent work showed that good cross-lingual
performance can be achieved if a source language is related to the low-resource
target language. However, not all language pairs are related. In this paper, we
propose to build multilingual word embeddings (MWEs) via a novel language
chain-based approach, that incorporates intermediate related languages to
bridge the gap between the distant source and target. We build MWEs one
language at a time by starting from the resource rich source and sequentially
adding each language in the chain till we reach the target. We extend a
semi-joint bilingual approach to multiple languages in order to eliminate the
main weakness of previous works, i.e., independently trained monolingual
embeddings, by anchoring the target language around the multilingual space. We
evaluate our method on bilingual lexicon induction for 4 language families,
involving 4 very low-resource (&amp;lt;5M tokens) and 4 moderately low-resource (&amp;lt;50M)
target languages, showing improved performance in both categories.
Additionally, our analysis reveals the importance of good quality embeddings
for intermediate languages as well as the importance of leveraging anchor
points from all languages in the multilingual space.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hangya_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Viktor Hangya&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Severini_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Silvia Severini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ralev_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Radoslav Ralev&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Fraser_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alexander Fraser&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Schutze_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hinrich Sch&amp;#xfc;tze&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12534">
<title>Evaluation Metrics of Language Generation Models for Synthetic Traffic Generation Tasks. (arXiv:2311.12534v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12534</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Many Natural Language Generation (NLG) tasks aim to generate a single output
text given an input prompt. Other settings require the generation of multiple
texts, e.g., for Synthetic Traffic Generation (STG). This generation task is
crucial for training and evaluating QA systems as well as conversational
agents, where the goal is to generate multiple questions or utterances
resembling the linguistic variability of real users. In this paper, we show
that common NLG metrics, like BLEU, are not suitable for evaluating STG. We
propose and evaluate several metrics designed to compare the generated traffic
to the distribution of real user texts. We validate our metrics with an
automatic procedure to verify whether they capture different types of quality
issues of generated data; we also run human annotations to verify the
correlation with human judgements. Experiments on three tasks, i.e., Shopping
Utterance Generation, Product Question Generation and Query Auto Completion,
demonstrate that our metrics are effective for evaluating STG tasks, and
improve the agreement with human judgement up to 20% with respect to common NLG
metrics. We believe these findings can pave the way towards better solutions
for estimating the representativeness of synthetic text data.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Filice_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Simone Filice&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Choi_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jason Ingyu Choi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Castellucci_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Giuseppe Castellucci&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Agichtein_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Eugene Agichtein&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Rokhlenko_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Oleg Rokhlenko&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12537">
<title>Oasis: Data Curation and Assessment System for Pretraining of Large Language Models. (arXiv:2311.12537v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12537</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Data is one of the most critical elements in building a large language model.
However, existing systems either fail to customize a corpus curation pipeline
or neglect to leverage comprehensive corpus assessment for iterative
optimization of the curation. To this end, we present a pretraining corpus
curation and assessment platform called Oasis -- a one-stop system for data
quality improvement and quantification with user-friendly interactive
interfaces. Specifically, the interactive modular rule filter module can devise
customized rules according to explicit feedback. The debiased neural filter
module builds the quality classification dataset in a negative-centric manner
to remove the undesired bias. The adaptive document deduplication module could
execute large-scale deduplication with limited memory resources. These three
parts constitute the customized data curation module. And in the holistic data
assessment module, a corpus can be assessed in local and global views, with
three evaluation means including human, GPT-4, and heuristic metrics. We
exhibit a complete process to use Oasis for the curation and assessment of
pretraining data. In addition, an 800GB bilingual corpus curated by Oasis is
publicly released.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhou_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tong Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yubo Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cao_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pengfei Cao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kang Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhao_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jun Zhao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shengping Liu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12538">
<title>In-Context Learning Functions with Varying Number of Minima. (arXiv:2311.12538v1 [cs.LG])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12538</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Large Language Models (LLMs) have proven effective at In-Context Learning
(ICL), an ability that allows them to create predictors from labeled examples.
Few studies have explored the interplay between ICL and specific properties of
functions it attempts to approximate. In our study, we use a formal framework
to explore ICL and propose a new task of approximating functions with varying
number of minima. We implement a method that allows for producing functions
with given inputs as minima. We find that increasing the number of minima
degrades ICL performance. At the same time, our evaluation shows that ICL
outperforms 2-layer Neural Network (2NN) model. Furthermore, ICL learns faster
than 2NN in all settings. We validate the findings through a set of few-shot
experiments across various hyperparameter configurations.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Oniani_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;David Oniani&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yanshan Wang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12574">
<title>IMGTB: A Framework for Machine-Generated Text Detection Benchmarking. (arXiv:2311.12574v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12574</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In the era of large language models generating high quality texts, it is a
necessity to develop methods for detection of machine-generated text to avoid
harmful use or simply due to annotation purposes. It is, however, also
important to properly evaluate and compare such developed methods. Recently, a
few benchmarks have been proposed for this purpose; however, integration of
newest detection methods is rather challenging, since new methods appear each
month and provide slightly different evaluation pipelines. In this paper, we
present the IMGTB framework, which simplifies the benchmarking of
machine-generated text detection methods by easy integration of custom (new)
methods and evaluation datasets. Its configurability and flexibility makes
research and development of new detection methods easier, especially their
comparison to the existing state-of-the-art detectors. The default set of
analyses, metrics and visualizations offered by the tool follows the
established practices of machine-generated text detection benchmarking found in
state-of-the-art literature.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Spiegel_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michal Spiegel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Macko_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dominik Macko&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12649">
<title>MathGloss: Building mathematical glossaries from text. (arXiv:2311.12649v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12649</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;MathGloss is a project to create a knowledge graph (KG) for undergraduate
mathematics from text, automatically, using modern natural language processing
(NLP) tools and resources already available on the web. MathGloss is a linked
database of undergraduate concepts in mathematics. So far, it combines five
resources: (i) Wikidata, a collaboratively edited, multilingual knowledge graph
hosted by the Wikimedia Foundation, (ii) terms covered in mathematics courses
at the University of Chicago, (iii) the syllabus of the French undergraduate
mathematics curriculum which includes hyperlinks to the automated theorem
prover Lean 4, (iv) MuLiMa, a multilingual dictionary of mathematics curated by
mathematicians, and (v) the nLab, a wiki for category theory also curated by
mathematicians. MathGloss&apos;s goal is to bring together resources for learning
mathematics and to allow every mathematician to tailor their learning to their
own preferences. Moreover, by organizing different resources for learning
undergraduate mathematics alongside those for learning formal mathematics, we
hope to make it easier for mathematicians and formal tools (theorem provers,
computer algebra systems, etc) experts to &quot;understand&quot; each other and break
down some of the barriers to formal math.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Horowitz_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lucy Horowitz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Paiva_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Valeria de Paiva&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12664">
<title>The DURel Annotation Tool: Human and Computational Measurement of Semantic Proximity, Sense Clusters and Semantic Change. (arXiv:2311.12664v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12664</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present the DURel tool that implements the annotation of semantic
proximity between uses of words into an online, open source interface. The tool
supports standardized human annotation as well as computational annotation,
building on recent advances with Word-in-Context models. Annotator judgments
are clustered with automatic graph clustering techniques and visualized for
analysis. This allows to measure word senses with simple and intuitive
micro-task judgments between use pairs, requiring minimal preparation efforts.
The tool offers additional functionalities to compare the agreement between
annotators to guarantee the inter-subjectivity of the obtained judgments and to
calculate summary statistics giving insights into sense frequency
distributions, semantic variation or changes of senses over time.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Schlechtweg_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dominik Schlechtweg&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Virk_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shafqat Mumtaz Virk&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sander_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pauline Sander&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Skoldberg_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Emma Sk&amp;#xf6;ldberg&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Linke_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lukas Theuer Linke&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tuo Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tahmasebi_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nina Tahmasebi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kuhn_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jonas Kuhn&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Walde_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sabine Schulte im Walde&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12689">
<title>Fair Text Classification with Wasserstein Independence. (arXiv:2311.12689v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12689</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Group fairness is a central research topic in text classification, where
reaching fair treatment between sensitive groups (e.g. women vs. men) remains
an open challenge. This paper presents a novel method for mitigating biases in
neural text classification, agnostic to the model architecture. Considering the
difficulty to distinguish fair from unfair information in a text encoder, we
take inspiration from adversarial training to induce Wasserstein independence
between representations learned to predict our target label and the ones
learned to predict some sensitive attribute. Our approach provides two
significant advantages. Firstly, it does not require annotations of sensitive
attributes in both testing and training data. This is more suitable for
real-life scenarios compared to existing methods that require annotations of
sensitive attributes at train time. Second, our approach exhibits a comparable
or better fairness-accuracy trade-off compared to existing methods.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Leteno_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thibaud Leteno&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gourru_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Antoine Gourru&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Laclau_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Charlotte Laclau&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Emonet_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R&amp;#xe9;mi Emonet&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gravier_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Christophe Gravier&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12699">
<title>Can Large Language Models Understand Content and Propagation for Misinformation Detection: An Empirical Study. (arXiv:2311.12699v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12699</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Large Language Models (LLMs) have garnered significant attention for their
powerful ability in natural language understanding and reasoning. In this
paper, we present a comprehensive empirical study to explore the performance of
LLMs on misinformation detection tasks. This study stands as the pioneering
investigation into the understanding capabilities of multiple LLMs regarding
both content and propagation across social media platforms. Our empirical
studies on five misinformation detection datasets show that LLMs with diverse
prompts achieve comparable performance in text-based misinformation detection
but exhibit notably constrained capabilities in comprehending propagation
structure compared to existing models in propagation-based misinformation
detection. Besides, we further design four instruction-tuned strategies to
enhance LLMs for both content and propagation-based misinformation detection.
These strategies boost LLMs to actively learn effective features from multiple
instances or hard instances, and eliminate irrelevant propagation structures,
thereby achieving better detection performance. Extensive experiments further
demonstrate LLMs would play a better capacity in content and propagation
structure under these proposed strategies and achieve promising detection
performance. These findings highlight the potential ability of LLMs to detect
misinformation.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mengyang Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wei_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lingwei Wei&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cao_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Han Cao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhou_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hu_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Songlin Hu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12707">
<title>Keeping Users Engaged During Repeated Administration of the Same Questionnaire: Using Large Language Models to Reliably Diversify Questions. (arXiv:2311.12707v1 [cs.HC])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12707</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Standardized, validated questionnaires are vital tools in HCI research and
healthcare, offering dependable self-report data. However, their repeated use
in longitudinal or pre-post studies can induce respondent fatigue, impacting
data quality via response biases and decreased response rates. We propose
utilizing large language models (LLMs) to generate diverse questionnaire
versions while retaining good psychometric properties. In a longitudinal study,
participants engaged with our agent system and responded daily for two weeks to
either a standardized depression questionnaire or one of two LLM-generated
questionnaire variants, alongside a validated depression questionnaire.
Psychometric testing revealed consistent covariation between the external
criterion and the focal measure administered across the three conditions,
demonstrating the reliability and validity of the LLM-generated variants.
Participants found the repeated administration of the standardized
questionnaire significantly more repetitive compared to the variants. Our
findings highlight the potential of LLM-generated variants to invigorate
questionnaires, fostering engagement and interest without compromising
validity.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yun_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hye Sun Yun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Arjmand_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mehdi Arjmand&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sherlock_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Phillip Raymond Sherlock&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Paasche_Orlow_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michael Paasche-Orlow&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Griffith_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;James W. Griffith&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bickmore_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Timothy Bickmore&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12727">
<title>Soft Random Sampling: A Theoretical and Empirical Analysis. (arXiv:2311.12727v1 [cs.LG])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12727</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Soft random sampling (SRS) is a simple yet effective approach for efficient
training of large-scale deep neural networks when dealing with massive data.
SRS selects a subset uniformly at random with replacement from the full data
set in each epoch. In this paper, we conduct a theoretical and empirical
analysis of SRS. First, we analyze its sampling dynamics including data
coverage and occupancy. Next, we investigate its convergence with non-convex
objective functions and give the convergence rate. Finally, we provide its
generalization performance. We empirically evaluate SRS for image recognition
on CIFAR10 and automatic speech recognition on Librispeech and an in-house
payload dataset to demonstrate its effectiveness. Compared to existing
coreset-based data selection methods, SRS offers a better accuracy-efficiency
trade-off. Especially on real-world industrial scale data sets, it is shown to
be a powerful training strategy with significant speedup and competitive
performance with almost no additional computing cost.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cui_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaodong Cui&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Mittal_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ashish Mittal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lu_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Songtao Lu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Saon_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;George Saon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kingsbury_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Brian Kingsbury&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12735">
<title>LowResource at BLP-2023 Task 2: Leveraging BanglaBert for Low Resource Sentiment Analysis of Bangla Language. (arXiv:2311.12735v1 [cs.CL])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12735</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This paper describes the system of the LowResource Team for Task 2 of
BLP-2023, which involves conducting sentiment analysis on a dataset composed of
public posts and comments from diverse social media platforms. Our primary aim
is to utilize BanglaBert, a BERT model pre-trained on a large Bangla corpus,
using various strategies including fine-tuning, dropping random tokens, and
using several external datasets. Our final model is an ensemble of the three
best BanglaBert variations. Our system has achieved overall 3rd in the Test Set
among 30 participating teams with a score of 0.718. Additionally, we discuss
the promising systems that didn&apos;t perform well namely task-adaptive pertaining
and paraphrasing using BanglaT5. Training codes and external datasets which are
used for our system are publicly available at
https://github.com/Aunabil4602/bnlp-workshop-task2-2023
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chakma_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aunabil Chakma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hasan_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Masum Hasan&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2012.12311">
<title>Influencer Videos: Unboxing the Mystique. (arXiv:2012.12311v3 [cs.LG] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2012.12311</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Influencer marketing has become a very popular tool to reach customers.
Despite the rapid growth in influencer videos, there has been little research
on the effectiveness of their constituent features in explaining video
engagement. We study YouTube influencers and analyze their unstructured video
data across text, audio and images using an &quot;interpretable deep learning&quot;
framework that accomplishes both goals of prediction and interpretation. Our
prediction-based approach analyzes unstructured data and finds that &quot;what is
said&quot; in words (text) is more influential than &quot;how it is said&quot; in imagery
(images) or acoustics (audio). Our novel interpretation-based approach is
implemented after completion of model prediction by analyzing the same source
of unstructured data to measure importance attributed to the video features. We
eliminate several spurious relationships in two steps, identifying a subset of
relationships which are confirmed using theory. We uncover novel findings that
establish distinct associations for measures of shallow and deep engagement
based on the dual-system framework of human thinking. Our approach is validated
using simulated data, and we discuss the learnings from our findings for
influencers and brands.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Rajaram_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Prashant Rajaram&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Manchanda_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Puneet Manchanda&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2102.00225">
<title>Learning From How Humans Correct. (arXiv:2102.00225v16 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2102.00225</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In industry NLP application, our manually labeled data has a certain number
of noisy data. We present a simple method to find the noisy data and re-label
them manually, meanwhile we collect the correction information. Then we present
novel method to incorporate the human correction information into deep learning
model. Human know how to correct noisy data. So the correction information can
be inject into deep learning model. We do the experiment on our own text
classification dataset, which is manually labeled, because we re-label the
noisy data in our dataset for our industry application. The experiment result
shows that our learn-on-correction method improve the classification accuracy
from 91.7% to 92.5% in test dataset. The 91.7% accuracy is trained on the
corrected dataset, which improve the baseline from 83.3% to 91.7% in test
dataset. The accuracy under human evaluation achieves more than 97%.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Guo_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tong Guo&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.10852">
<title>Relphormer: Relational Graph Transformer for Knowledge Graph Representations. (arXiv:2205.10852v6 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.10852</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Transformers have achieved remarkable performance in widespread fields,
including natural language processing, computer vision and graph mining.
However, vanilla Transformer architectures have not yielded promising
improvements in the Knowledge Graph (KG) representations, where the
translational distance paradigm dominates this area. Note that vanilla
Transformer architectures struggle to capture the intrinsically heterogeneous
structural and semantic information of knowledge graphs. To this end, we
propose a new variant of Transformer for knowledge graph representations dubbed
Relphormer. Specifically, we introduce Triple2Seq which can dynamically sample
contextualized sub-graph sequences as the input to alleviate the heterogeneity
issue. We propose a novel structure-enhanced self-attention mechanism to encode
the relational information and keep the semantic information within entities
and relations. Moreover, we utilize masked knowledge modeling for general
knowledge graph representation learning, which can be applied to various
KG-based tasks including knowledge graph completion, question answering, and
recommendation. Experimental results on six datasets show that Relphormer can
obtain better performance compared with baselines. Code is available in
https://github.com/zjunlp/Relphormer.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bi_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhen Bi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cheng_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Siyuan Cheng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jing Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liang_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaozhuan Liang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xiong_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Feiyu Xiong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ningyu Zhang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2301.02748">
<title>Generative Antibody Design for Complementary Chain Pairing Sequences through Encoder-Decoder Language Model. (arXiv:2301.02748v4 [q-bio.BM] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2301.02748</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Current protein language models (pLMs) predominantly focus on single-chain
protein sequences and often have not accounted for constraints on generative
design imposed by protein-protein interactions. To address this gap, we present
paired Antibody T5 (pAbT5), an encoder-decoder model to generate complementary
heavy or light chain from its pairing partner. We show that our model respects
conservation in framework regions and variability in hypervariable domains,
demonstrated by agreement with sequence alignment and variable-length CDR
loops. We also show that our model captures chain pairing preferences through
the recovery of ground-truth chain type and gene families. Our results showcase
the potential of pAbT5 in generative antibody design, incorporating biological
constraints from chain pairing preferences.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Chu_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Simon K.S. Chu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Wei_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kathy Y. Wei&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.03898">
<title>The Short Text Matching Model Enhanced with Knowledge via Contrastive Learning. (arXiv:2304.03898v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.03898</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In recent years, short Text Matching tasks have been widely applied in the
fields ofadvertising search and recommendation. The difficulty lies in the lack
of semantic information and word ambiguity caused by the short length of the
text. Previous works have introduced complement sentences or knowledge bases to
provide additional feature information. However, these methods have not fully
interacted between the original sentence and the complement sentence, and have
not considered the noise issue that may arise from the introduction of external
knowledge bases. Therefore, this paper proposes a short Text Matching model
that combines contrastive learning and external knowledge. The model uses a
generative model to generate corresponding complement sentences and uses the
contrastive learning method to guide the model to obtain more semantically
meaningful encoding of the original sentence. In addition, to avoid noise, we
use keywords as the main semantics of the original sentence to retrieve
corresponding knowledge words in the knowledge base, and construct a knowledge
graph. The graph encoding model is used to integrate the knowledge base
information into the model. Our designed model achieves state-of-the-art
performance on two publicly available Chinese Text Matching datasets,
demonstrating the effectiveness of our model.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ruiqiang Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cui_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mengmeng Cui&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Mai_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hanjie Mai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qiang Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xu_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shaohua Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiangzheng Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Du_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yanlong Du&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.10429">
<title>DoReMi: Optimizing Data Mixtures Speeds Up Language Model Pretraining. (arXiv:2305.10429v4 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.10429</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The mixture proportions of pretraining data domains (e.g., Wikipedia, books,
web text) greatly affect language model (LM) performance. In this paper, we
propose Domain Reweighting with Minimax Optimization (DoReMi), which first
trains a small proxy model using group distributionally robust optimization
(Group DRO) over domains to produce domain weights (mixture proportions)
without knowledge of downstream tasks. We then resample a dataset with these
domain weights and train a larger, full-sized model. In our experiments, we use
DoReMi on a 280M-parameter proxy model to set the domain weights for training
an 8B-parameter model (30x larger) more efficiently. On The Pile, DoReMi
improves perplexity across all domains, even when it downweights a domain.
DoReMi improves average few-shot downstream accuracy by 6.5% points over a
baseline model trained using The Pile&apos;s default domain weights and reaches the
baseline accuracy with 2.6x fewer training steps. On the GLaM dataset, DoReMi,
which has no knowledge of downstream tasks, even matches the performance of
using domain weights tuned on downstream tasks.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xie_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sang Michael Xie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Pham_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hieu Pham&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Dong_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xuanyi Dong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Du_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nan Du&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hanxiao Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yifeng Lu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liang_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Percy Liang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Le_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Quoc V. Le&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ma_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tengyu Ma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yu_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Adams Wei Yu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.18098">
<title>BigTranslate: Augmenting Large Language Models with Multilingual Translation Capability over 100 Languages. (arXiv:2305.18098v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.18098</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Large language models (LLMs) demonstrate promising translation performance
among various natural languages. However, many LLMs especially the open-sourced
ones, such as BLOOM and LLaMA, are English-dominant and support only dozens of
natural languages, making the potential of LLMs on language translation less
explored. In this work, we present BigTranslate which adapts LLaMA that covers
only 20 languages and enhances it with multilingual translation capability on
more than 100 languages. BigTranslate is built upon LLaMA-13B and it is
optimized in three steps. First, we continue training LLaMA with massive
Chinese monolingual data. Second, we continue training the model with a
large-scale parallel dataset that covers 102 natural languages. Third, we
instruct-tune the foundation model with multilingual translation instructions,
leading to our BigTranslate model. The preliminary experiments on multilingual
translation show that BigTranslate performs comparably with ChatGPT and Google
Translate in many languages and even outperforms ChatGPT in 8 language pairs.
We release the BigTranslate model and hope it can advance the research
progress.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yang_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wen Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chong Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiajun Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zong_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chengqing Zong&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2306.17103">
<title>LyricWhiz: Robust Multilingual Zero-shot Lyrics Transcription by Whispering to ChatGPT. (arXiv:2306.17103v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2306.17103</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We introduce LyricWhiz, a robust, multilingual, and zero-shot automatic
lyrics transcription method achieving state-of-the-art performance on various
lyrics transcription datasets, even in challenging genres such as rock and
metal. Our novel, training-free approach utilizes Whisper, a weakly supervised
robust speech recognition model, and GPT-4, today&apos;s most performant chat-based
large language model. In the proposed method, Whisper functions as the &quot;ear&quot; by
transcribing the audio, while GPT-4 serves as the &quot;brain,&quot; acting as an
annotator with a strong performance for contextualized output selection and
correction. Our experiments show that LyricWhiz significantly reduces Word
Error Rate compared to existing methods in English and can effectively
transcribe lyrics across multiple languages. Furthermore, we use LyricWhiz to
create the first publicly available, large-scale, multilingual lyrics
transcription dataset with a CC-BY-NC-SA copyright license, based on
MTG-Jamendo, and offer a human-annotated subset for noise level estimation and
evaluation. We anticipate that our proposed method and dataset will advance the
development of multilingual lyrics transcription, a challenging and emerging
task.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhuo_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Le Zhuo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yuan_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ruibin Yuan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Pan_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiahao Pan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ma_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yinghao Ma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+LI_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yizhi LI&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ge Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Si Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Dannenberg_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Roger Dannenberg&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Fu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jie Fu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lin_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chenghua Lin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Benetos_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Emmanouil Benetos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wenhu Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xue_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei Xue&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Guo_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yike Guo&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2307.03172">
<title>Lost in the Middle: How Language Models Use Long Contexts. (arXiv:2307.03172v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2307.03172</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;While recent language models have the ability to take long contexts as input,
relatively little is known about how well they use longer context. We analyze
the performance of language models on two tasks that require identifying
relevant information in their input contexts: multi-document question answering
and key-value retrieval. We find that performance can degrade significantly
when changing the position of relevant information, indicating that current
language models do not robustly make use of information in long input contexts.
In particular, we observe that performance is often highest when relevant
information occurs at the beginning or end of the input context, and
significantly degrades when models must access relevant information in the
middle of long contexts, even for explicitly long-context models. Our analysis
provides a better understanding of how language models use their input context
and provides new evaluation protocols for future long-context language models.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nelson F. Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lin_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kevin Lin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hewitt_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;John Hewitt&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Paranjape_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ashwin Paranjape&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bevilacqua_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michele Bevilacqua&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Petroni_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fabio Petroni&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liang_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Percy Liang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.01446">
<title>Open Sesame! Universal Black Box Jailbreaking of Large Language Models. (arXiv:2309.01446v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.01446</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Large language models (LLMs), designed to provide helpful and safe responses,
often rely on alignment techniques to align with user intent and social
guidelines. Unfortunately, this alignment can be exploited by malicious actors
seeking to manipulate an LLM&apos;s outputs for unintended purposes. In this paper
we introduce a novel approach that employs a genetic algorithm (GA) to
manipulate LLMs when model architecture and parameters are inaccessible. The GA
attack works by optimizing a universal adversarial prompt that -- when combined
with a user&apos;s query -- disrupts the attacked model&apos;s alignment, resulting in
unintended and potentially harmful outputs. Our novel approach systematically
reveals a model&apos;s limitations and vulnerabilities by uncovering instances where
its responses deviate from expected behavior. Through extensive experiments we
demonstrate the efficacy of our technique, thus contributing to the ongoing
discussion on responsible AI development by providing a diagnostic tool for
evaluating and enhancing alignment of LLMs with human intent. To our knowledge
this is the first automated universal black box jailbreak attack.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lapid_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Raz Lapid&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Langberg_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ron Langberg&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sipper_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Moshe Sipper&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.17453">
<title>Efficient Streaming Language Models with Attention Sinks. (arXiv:2309.17453v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.17453</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Deploying Large Language Models (LLMs) in streaming applications such as
multi-round dialogue, where long interactions are expected, is urgently needed
but poses two major challenges. Firstly, during the decoding stage, caching
previous tokens&apos; Key and Value states (KV) consumes extensive memory. Secondly,
popular LLMs cannot generalize to longer texts than the training sequence
length. Window attention, where only the most recent KVs are cached, is a
natural approach -- but we show that it fails when the text length surpasses
the cache size. We observe an interesting phenomenon, namely attention sink,
that keeping the KV of initial tokens will largely recover the performance of
window attention. In this paper, we first demonstrate that the emergence of
attention sink is due to the strong attention scores towards initial tokens as
a ``sink&apos;&apos; even if they are not semantically important. Based on the above
analysis, we introduce StreamingLLM, an efficient framework that enables LLMs
trained with a finite length attention window to generalize to infinite
sequence lengths without any fine-tuning. We show that StreamingLLM can enable
Llama-2, MPT, Falcon, and Pythia to perform stable and efficient language
modeling with up to 4 million tokens and more. In addition, we discover that
adding a placeholder token as a dedicated attention sink during pre-training
can further improve streaming deployment. In streaming settings, StreamingLLM
outperforms the sliding window recomputation baseline by up to 22.2x speedup.
Code and datasets are provided at https://github.com/mit-han-lab/streaming-llm.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xiao_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Guangxuan Xiao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tian_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuandong Tian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Beidi Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Han_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Song Han&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lewis_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mike Lewis&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.02129">
<title>Unveiling the Pitfalls of Knowledge Editing for Large Language Models. (arXiv:2310.02129v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.02129</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;As the cost associated with fine-tuning Large Language Models (LLMs)
continues to rise, recent research efforts have pivoted towards developing
methodologies to edit implicit knowledge embedded within LLMs. Yet, there&apos;s
still a dark cloud lingering overhead -- will knowledge editing trigger
butterfly effect? since it is still unclear whether knowledge editing might
introduce side effects that pose potential risks or not. This paper pioneers
the investigation into the potential pitfalls associated with knowledge editing
for LLMs. To achieve this, we introduce new benchmark datasets and propose
innovative evaluation metrics. Our results underline two pivotal concerns: (1)
Knowledge Conflict: Editing groups of facts that logically clash can magnify
the inherent inconsistencies in LLMs-a facet neglected by previous methods. (2)
Knowledge Distortion: Altering parameters with the aim of editing factual
knowledge can irrevocably warp the innate knowledge structure of LLMs.
Experimental results vividly demonstrate that knowledge editing might
inadvertently cast a shadow of unintended consequences on LLMs, which warrant
attention and efforts for future works. Code is available at
https://github.com/zjunlp/PitfallsKnowledgeEditing.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhoubo Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ningyu Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yao_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yunzhi Yao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mengru Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xi Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Huajun Chen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.02168">
<title>Editing Personality for LLMs. (arXiv:2310.02168v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.02168</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This paper introduces an innovative task focused on editing the personality
traits of Large Language Models (LLMs). This task seeks to adjust the models&apos;
responses to opinion-related questions on specified topics since an
individual&apos;s personality often manifests in the form of their expressed
opinions, thereby showcasing different personality traits. Specifically, we
construct a new benchmark dataset PersonalityEdit to address this task. Drawing
on the theory in Social Psychology, we isolate three representative traits,
namely Neuroticism, Extraversion, and Agreeableness, as the foundation for our
benchmark. We then gather data using GPT-4, generating responses that not only
align with a specified topic but also embody the targeted personality trait. We
conduct comprehensive experiments involving various baselines and discuss the
representation of personality behavior in LLMs. Our intriguing findings uncover
potential challenges of the proposed task, illustrating several remaining
issues. We anticipate that our work can provide the NLP community with
insights. Code and datasets will be released at
https://github.com/zjunlp/EasyEdit.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Mao_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shengyu Mao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ningyu Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaohan Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mengru Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yao_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yunzhi Yao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jiang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yong Jiang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xie_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pengjun Xie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Huang_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fei Huang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Huajun Chen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.05140">
<title>Harnessing the Power of Large Language Models for Empathetic Response Generation: Empirical Investigations and Improvements. (arXiv:2310.05140v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.05140</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Empathetic dialogue is an indispensable part of building harmonious social
relationships and contributes to the development of a helpful AI. Previous
approaches are mainly based on fine small-scale language models. With the
advent of ChatGPT, the application effect of large language models (LLMs) in
this field has attracted great attention. This work empirically investigates
the performance of LLMs in generating empathetic responses and proposes three
improvement methods of semantically similar in-context learning, two-stage
interactive generation, and combination with the knowledge base. Extensive
experiments show that LLMs can significantly benefit from our proposed methods
and is able to achieve state-of-the-art performance in both automatic and human
evaluations. Additionally, we explore the possibility of GPT-4 simulating human
evaluators.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Qian_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yushan Qian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei-Nan Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ting Liu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.07161">
<title>Psychoacoustic Challenges Of Speech Enhancement On VoIP Platforms. (arXiv:2310.07161v2 [cs.SD] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.07161</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Within the ambit of VoIP (Voice over Internet Protocol) telecommunications,
the complexities introduced by acoustic transformations merit rigorous
analysis. This research, rooted in the exploration of proprietary sender-side
denoising effects, meticulously evaluates platforms such as Google Meets and
Zoom. The study draws upon the Deep Noise Suppression (DNS) 2020 dataset,
ensuring a structured examination tailored to various denoising settings and
receiver interfaces. A methodological novelty is introduced via the Oaxaca
decomposition, traditionally an econometric tool, repurposed herein to analyze
acoustic-phonetic perturbations within VoIP systems. To further ground the
implications of these transformations, psychoacoustic metrics, specifically
PESQ and STOI, were harnessed to furnish a comprehensive understanding of
speech alterations. Cumulatively, the insights garnered underscore the
intricate landscape of VoIP-influenced acoustic dynamics. In addition to the
primary findings, a multitude of metrics are reported, extending the research
purview. Moreover, out-of-domain benchmarking for both time and time-frequency
domain speech enhancement models is included, thereby enhancing the depth and
applicability of this inquiry. Repository:
github.com/deepology/VoIP-DNS-Challenge
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Konan_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Joseph Konan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bhargave_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ojas Bhargave&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Agnihotri_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shikhar Agnihotri&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Han_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shuo Han&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zeng_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yunyang Zeng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shah_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ankit Shah&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Raj_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bhiksha Raj&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.17940">
<title>Unified Segment-to-Segment Framework for Simultaneous Sequence Generation. (arXiv:2310.17940v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.17940</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Simultaneous sequence generation is a pivotal task for real-time scenarios,
such as streaming speech recognition, simultaneous machine translation and
simultaneous speech translation, where the target sequence is generated while
receiving the source sequence. The crux of achieving high-quality generation
with low latency lies in identifying the optimal moments for generating,
accomplished by learning a mapping between the source and target sequences.
However, existing methods often rely on task-specific heuristics for different
sequence types, limiting the model&apos;s capacity to adaptively learn the
source-target mapping and hindering the exploration of multi-task learning for
various simultaneous tasks. In this paper, we propose a unified
segment-to-segment framework (Seg2Seg) for simultaneous sequence generation,
which learns the mapping in an adaptive and unified manner. During the process
of simultaneous generation, the model alternates between waiting for a source
segment and generating a target segment, making the segment serve as the
natural bridge between the source and target. To accomplish this, Seg2Seg
introduces a latent segment as the pivot between source to target and explores
all potential source-target mappings via the proposed expectation training,
thereby learning the optimal moments for generating. Experiments on multiple
simultaneous generation tasks demonstrate that Seg2Seg achieves
state-of-the-art performance and exhibits better generality across various
tasks.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shaolei Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Feng_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yang Feng&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.18168">
<title>Personas as a Way to Model Truthfulness in Language Models. (arXiv:2310.18168v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.18168</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Large Language Models (LLMs) are trained on vast amounts of text from the
internet, which contains both factual and misleading information about the
world. Can language models discern truth from falsehood in this contradicting
data? Expanding on the view that LLMs can model different communicative agents,
we present the persona hypothesis: LLMs can cluster agents into personas using
common features of their generations. For instance, a truthful persona is a
group of agents that are likely to produce truthful text and that share similar
features like formal writing styles and scientific references. By modeling this
persona, LLMs can generalize truthfulness beyond the specific contexts in which
each agent generated the training text. For example, the model can infer that
the agent ``Wikipedia&apos;&apos; will behave truthfully on topics that were only
generated by ``Science&apos;&apos; because they both belong to the truthful persona. We
show evidence for the persona hypothesis via two observations: (1) we can probe
whether a model&apos;s answer will be truthful before it is generated; (2)
finetuning a model on a set of facts improves its truthfulness on unseen
topics. Next, using arithmetics as a synthetic environment, we show that
language models can separate true and false statements, and generalize
truthfulness across agents; but only if agents in the training data share a
truthful generative process that enables the creation of a truthful persona.
Overall, our findings suggest that models can exploit hierarchical structures
in the data to learn abstract concepts like truthfulness.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Joshi_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nitish Joshi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Rando_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Javier Rando&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Saparov_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Abulhair Saparov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kim_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Najoung Kim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+He_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;He He&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.06233">
<title>Data Contamination Quiz: A Tool to Detect and Estimate Contamination in Large Language Models. (arXiv:2311.06233v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.06233</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We propose the Data Contamination Quiz, a simple and effective approach to
detect data contamination in large language models (LLMs) and estimate the
amount of it. Specifically, we frame data contamination detection as a series
of multiple-choice questions. We devise a quiz format wherein three perturbed
versions of each dataset instance are created. These changes only include
word-level perturbations, replacing words with their contextual synonyms,
ensuring both the semantic and sentence structure remain exactly the same as
the original instance. Together with the original instance, these perturbed
versions constitute the choices in the quiz. Given that the only distinguishing
signal among these choices is the exact wording, an LLM, when tasked with
identifying the original instance from the choices, opts for the original if it
has memorized it in its pre-training phase--a trait intrinsic to LLMs. A
dataset partition is then marked as contaminated if the LLM&apos;s performance on
the quiz surpasses what random chance suggests. Our evaluation spans seven
datasets and their respective splits (train and test/validation) on two
state-of-the-art LLMs: GPT-4 and GPT-3.5. While lacking access to the
pre-training data, our results suggest that our approach not only enhances the
detection of data contamination but also provides an accurate estimation of its
extent, even when the contamination signal is weak.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Golchin_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shahriar Golchin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Surdeanu_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mihai Surdeanu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.09387">
<title>Banach-Tarski Embeddings and Transformers. (arXiv:2311.09387v2 [cs.LG] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.09387</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We introduce a new construction of embeddings of arbitrary recursive data
structures into high dimensional vectors. These embeddings provide an
interpretable model for the latent state vectors of transformers. We
demonstrate that these embeddings can be decoded to the original data structure
when the embedding dimension is sufficiently large. This decoding algorithm has
a natural implementation as a transformer. We also show that these embedding
vectors can be manipulated directly to perform computations on the underlying
data without decoding. As an example we present an algorithm that constructs
the embedded parse tree of an embedded token sequence using only vector
operations in embedding space.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Maher_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Joshua Maher&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.10770">
<title>Exponentially Faster Language Modelling. (arXiv:2311.10770v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.10770</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Language models only really need to use an exponential fraction of their
neurons for individual inferences. As proof, we present UltraFastBERT, a BERT
variant that uses 0.3% of its neurons during inference while performing on par
with similar BERT models. UltraFastBERT selectively engages just 12 out of 4095
neurons for each layer inference. This is achieved by replacing feedforward
networks with fast feedforward networks (FFFs). While no truly efficient
implementation currently exists to unlock the full acceleration potential of
conditional neural execution, we provide high-level CPU code achieving 78x
speedup over the optimized baseline feedforward implementation, and a PyTorch
implementation delivering 40x speedup over the equivalent batched feedforward
inference. We publish our training code, benchmarking setup, and model weights.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Belcak_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Peter Belcak&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wattenhofer_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Roger Wattenhofer&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.10777">
<title>A Systematic Review of Aspect-based Sentiment Analysis (ABSA): Domains, Methods, and Trends. (arXiv:2311.10777v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.10777</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Aspect-based Sentiment Analysis (ABSA) is a type of fine-grained sentiment
analysis (SA) that identifies aspects and the associated opinions from a given
text. In the digital era, ABSA gained increasing popularity and applications in
mining opinionated text data to obtain insights and support decisions. ABSA
research employs linguistic, statistical, and machine-learning approaches and
utilises resources such as labelled datasets, aspect and sentiment lexicons and
ontology. By its nature, ABSA is domain-dependent and can be sensitive to the
impact of misalignment between the resource and application domains. However,
to our knowledge, this topic has not been explored by the existing ABSA
literature reviews. In this paper, we present a Systematic Literature Review
(SLR) of ABSA studies with a focus on the research application domain, dataset
domain, and the research methods to examine their relationships and identify
trends over time. Our results suggest a number of potential systemic issues in
the ABSA research literature, including the predominance of the
``product/service review&apos;&apos; dataset domain among the majority of studies that
did not have a specific research application domain, coupled with the
prevalence of dataset-reliant methods such as supervised machine learning. This
review makes a number of unique contributions to the ABSA research field: 1) To
our knowledge, it is the first SLR that links the research domain, dataset
domain, and research method through a systematic perspective; 2) it is one of
the largest scoped SLR on ABSA, with 519 eligible studies filtered from 4191
search results without time constraint; and 3) our review methodology adopted
an innovative automatic filtering process based on PDF-mining, which enhanced
screening quality and reliability. Suggestions and our review limitations are
also discussed.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hua_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yan Cathy Hua&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Denny_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Paul Denny&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Taskova_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Katerina Taskova&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wicker_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J&amp;#xf6;rg Wicker&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.10899">
<title>Extraction and Summarization of Explicit Video Content using Multi-Modal Deep Learning. (arXiv:2311.10899v2 [cs.CV] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.10899</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;With the increase in video-sharing platforms across the internet, it is
difficult for humans to moderate the data for explicit content. Hence, an
automated pipeline to scan through video data for explicit content has become
the need of the hour. We propose a novel pipeline that uses multi-modal deep
learning to first extract the explicit segments of input videos and then
summarize their content using text to determine its age appropriateness and age
rating. We also evaluate our pipeline&apos;s effectiveness in the end using standard
metrics.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Joshi_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shaunak Joshi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gaggar_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Raghav Gaggar&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>