<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL</link>
    <description>cs.CL updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 04:00:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Sunday</day>
      <day>Saturday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>The Mechanics of Conceptual Interpretation in GPT Models: Interpretative Insights</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11827</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11827v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Locating and editing knowledge in large language models (LLMs) is crucial for enhancing their accuracy, safety, and inference rationale. We introduce ``concept editing'', an innovative variation of knowledge editing that uncovers conceptualisation mechanisms within these models. Using the reverse dictionary task, inference tracing, and input abstraction, we analyse the Multi-Layer Perceptron (MLP), Multi-Head Attention (MHA), and hidden state components of transformer models. Our results reveal distinct patterns: MLP layers employ key-value retrieval mechanism and context-dependent processing, which are highly associated with relative input tokens. MHA layers demonstrate a distributed nature with significant higher-level activations, suggesting sophisticated semantic integration. Hidden states emphasise the importance of the last token and top layers in the inference process. We observe evidence of gradual information building and distributed representation. These observations elucidate how transformer models process semantic information, paving the way for targeted interventions and improved interpretability techniques. Our work highlights the complex, layered nature of semantic processing in LLMs and the challenges of isolating and modifying specific concepts within these models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11827v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nura Aljaafari, Danilo S. Carvalho, Andr\'e Freitas</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenFactCheck: A Unified Framework for Factuality Evaluation of LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11832</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11832v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The increased use of large language models (LLMs) across a variety of real-world applications calls for automatic tools to check the factual accuracy of their outputs, as LLMs often hallucinate. This is difficult as it requires assessing the factuality of free-form open-domain responses. While there has been a lot of research on this topic, different papers use different evaluation benchmarks and measures, which makes them hard to compare and hampers future progress. To mitigate these issues, we developed OpenFactCheck, a unified framework, with three modules: (i) RESPONSEEVAL, which allows users to easily customize an automatic fact-checking system and to assess the factuality of all claims in an input document using that system, (ii) LLMEVAL, which assesses the overall factuality of an LLM, and (iii) CHECKEREVAL, a module to evaluate automatic fact-checking systems. OpenFactCheck is open-sourced (https://github.com/hasaniqbal777/openfactcheck) and publicly released as a Python library (https://pypi.org/project/openfactcheck/) and also as a web service (https://huggingface.co/spaces/hasaniqbal777/OpenFactCheck). A video describing the system is available at https://youtu.be/-i9VKL0HleI.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11832v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hasan Iqbal, Yuxia Wang, Minghan Wang, Georgi Georgiev, Jiahui Geng, Iryna Gurevych, Preslav Nakov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Editable Fairness: Fine-Grained Bias Mitigation in Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11843</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11843v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Generating fair and accurate predictions plays a pivotal role in deploying large language models (LLMs) in the real world. However, existing debiasing methods inevitably generate unfair or incorrect predictions as they are designed and evaluated to achieve parity across different social groups but leave aside individual commonsense facts, resulting in modified knowledge that elicits unreasonable or undesired predictions. In this paper, we first establish a new bias mitigation benchmark, BiaScope, which systematically assesses performance by leveraging newly constructed datasets and metrics on knowledge retention and generalization. Then, we propose a novel debiasing approach, Fairness Stamp (FAST), which enables fine-grained calibration of individual social biases. FAST identifies the decisive layer responsible for storing social biases and then calibrates its outputs by integrating a small modular network, considering both bias mitigation and knowledge-preserving demands. Comprehensive experiments demonstrate that FAST surpasses state-of-the-art baselines with superior debiasing performance while not compromising the overall model capability for knowledge retention and downstream predictions. This highlights the potential of fine-grained debiasing strategies to achieve fairness in LLMs. Code will be publicly available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11843v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ruizhe Chen, Yichen Li, Jianfei Yang, Joey Tianyi Zhou, Zuozhu Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLaMA based Punctuation Restoration With Forward Pass Only Decoding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11845</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11845v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper introduces two advancements in the field of Large Language Model Annotation with a focus on punctuation restoration tasks. Our first contribution is the application of LLaMA for punctuation restoration, which demonstrates superior performance compared to the established benchmark.
  Despite its impressive quality, LLaMA faces challenges regarding inference speed and hallucinations. To address this, our second contribution presents Forward Pass Only Decoding (FPOD), a novel decoding approach for annotation tasks. This innovative method results in a substantial 19.8x improvement in inference speed, effectively addressing a critical bottleneck and enhancing the practical utility of LLaMA for large-scale data annotation tasks without hallucinations.
  The combination of these contributions not only solidifies LLaMA as a powerful tool for punctuation restoration but also highlights FPOD as a crucial strategy for overcoming speed constraints.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11845v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yutong Pang, Debjyoti Paul, Kevin Jiang, Xuedong Zhang, Xin Lei</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Density Matrices for Metaphor Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11846</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11846v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In physics, density matrices are used to represent mixed states, i.e. probabilistic mixtures of pure states. This concept has previously been used to model lexical ambiguity. In this paper, we consider metaphor as a type of lexical ambiguity, and examine whether metaphorical meaning can be effectively modelled using mixtures of word senses. We find that modelling metaphor is significantly more difficult than other kinds of lexical ambiguity, but that our best-performing density matrix method outperforms simple baselines as well as some neural language models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11846v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.4204/EPTCS.406.9</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>EPTCS 406, 2024, pp. 197-215</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Jay Owers, Ekaterina Shutova, Martha Lewis</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prompto: An open source library for asynchronous querying of LLM endpoints</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11847</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11847v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent surge in Large Language Model (LLM) availability has opened exciting avenues for research. However, efficiently interacting with these models presents a significant hurdle since LLMs often reside on proprietary or self-hosted API endpoints, each requiring custom code for interaction. Conducting comparative studies between different models can therefore be time-consuming and necessitate significant engineering effort, hindering research efficiency and reproducibility. To address these challenges, we present prompto, an open source Python library which facilitates asynchronous querying of LLM endpoints enabling researchers to interact with multiple LLMs concurrently, while maximising efficiency and utilising individual rate limits. Our library empowers researchers and developers to interact with LLMs more effectively and enabling faster experimentation and evaluation. prompto is released with an introductory video (https://youtu.be/-eZAmlV4ypk) under MIT License and is available via GitHub (https://github.com/alan-turing-institute/prompto).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11847v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ryan Sze-Yin Chan, Federico Nanni, Edwin Brown, Ed Chapman, Angus R. Williams, Jonathan Bright, Evelina Gabasova</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MGH Radiology Llama: A Llama 3 70B Model for Radiology</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11848</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11848v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In recent years, the field of radiology has increasingly harnessed the power of artificial intelligence (AI) to enhance diagnostic accuracy, streamline workflows, and improve patient care. Large language models (LLMs) have emerged as particularly promising tools, offering significant potential in assisting radiologists with report generation, clinical decision support, and patient communication. This paper presents an advanced radiology-focused large language model: MGH Radiology Llama. It is developed using the Llama 3 70B model, building upon previous domain-specific models like Radiology-GPT and Radiology-Llama2. Leveraging a unique and comprehensive dataset from Massachusetts General Hospital, comprising over 6.5 million de-identified medical reports across various imaging modalities, the model demonstrates significant improvements in generating accurate and clinically relevant radiology impressions given the corresponding findings. Our evaluation, incorporating both traditional metrics and a GPT-4-based assessment, highlights the enhanced performance of this work over general-purpose LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11848v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yucheng Shi, Peng Shu, Zhengliang Liu, Zihao Wu, Quanzheng Li, Xiang Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Style-Talker: Finetuning Audio Language Model and Style-Based Text-to-Speech Model for Fast Spoken Dialogue Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11849</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11849v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The rapid advancement of large language models (LLMs) has significantly propelled the development of text-based chatbots, demonstrating their capability to engage in coherent and contextually relevant dialogues. However, extending these advancements to enable end-to-end speech-to-speech conversation bots remains a formidable challenge, primarily due to the extensive dataset and computational resources required. The conventional approach of cascading automatic speech recognition (ASR), LLM, and text-to-speech (TTS) models in a pipeline, while effective, suffers from unnatural prosody because it lacks direct interactions between the input audio and its transcribed text and the output audio. These systems are also limited by their inherent latency from the ASR process for real-time applications. This paper introduces Style-Talker, an innovative framework that fine-tunes an audio LLM alongside a style-based TTS model for fast spoken dialog generation. Style-Talker takes user input audio and uses transcribed chat history and speech styles to generate both the speaking style and text for the response. Subsequently, the TTS model synthesizes the speech, which is then played back to the user. While the response speech is being played, the input speech undergoes ASR processing to extract the transcription and speaking style, serving as the context for the ensuing dialogue turn. This novel pipeline accelerates the traditional cascade ASR-LLM-TTS systems while integrating rich paralinguistic information from input speech. Our experimental results show that Style-Talker significantly outperforms the conventional cascade and speech-to-speech baselines in terms of both dialogue naturalness and coherence while being more than 50% faster.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11849v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yinghao Aaron Li, Xilin Jiang, Jordan Darefsky, Ge Zhu, Nima Mesgarani</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parallel Speculative Decoding with Adaptive Draft Length</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11850</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11850v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Speculative decoding (SD), where an extra draft model is employed to provide multiple \textit{draft} tokens first and then the original target model verifies these tokens in parallel, has shown great power for LLM inference acceleration. However, existing SD methods suffer from the mutual waiting problem, i.e., the target model gets stuck when the draft model is \textit{guessing} tokens, and vice versa. This problem is directly incurred by the asynchronous execution of the draft model and the target model, and is exacerbated due to the fixed draft length in speculative decoding. To address these challenges, we propose a conceptually simple, flexible, and general framework to boost speculative decoding, namely \textbf{P}arallel sp\textbf{E}culative decoding with \textbf{A}daptive d\textbf{R}aft \textbf{L}ength (PEARL). Specifically, PEARL proposes \textit{pre-verify} to verify the first draft token in advance during the drafting phase, and \textit{post-verify} to generate more draft tokens during the verification phase. PEARL parallels the drafting phase and the verification phase via applying the two strategies, and achieves adaptive draft length for different scenarios, which effectively alleviates the mutual waiting problem. Moreover, we theoretically demonstrate that the mean accepted tokens of PEARL is more than existing \textit{draft-then-verify} works. Experiments on various text generation benchmarks demonstrate the effectiveness of our \name, leading to a superior speedup performance up to \textbf{3.79$\times$} and \textbf{1.52$\times$}, compared to auto-regressive decoding and vanilla speculative decoding, respectively.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11850v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tianyu Liu, Yun Li, Qitan Lv, Kai Liu, Jianchen Zhu, Winston Hu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fast Training Dataset Attribution via In-Context Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11852</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11852v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We investigate the use of in-context learning and prompt engineering to estimate the contributions of training data in the outputs of instruction-tuned large language models (LLMs). We propose two novel approaches: (1) a similarity-based approach that measures the difference between LLM outputs with and without provided context, and (2) a mixture distribution model approach that frames the problem of identifying contribution scores as a matrix factorization task. Our empirical comparison demonstrates that the mixture model approach is more robust to retrieval noise in in-context learning, providing a more reliable estimation of data contributions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11852v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Milad Fotouhi, Mohammad Taha Bahadori, Oluwaseyi Feyisetan, Payman Arabshahi, David Heckerman</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PyMarian: Fast Neural Machine Translation and Evaluation in Python</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11853</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11853v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The deep learning language of choice these days is Python; measured by factors such as available libraries and technical support, it is hard to beat. At the same time, software written in lower-level programming languages like C++ retain advantages in speed. We describe a Python interface to Marian NMT, a C++-based training and inference toolkit for sequence-to-sequence models, focusing on machine translation. This interface enables models trained with Marian to be connected to the rich, wide range of tools available in Python. A highlight of the interface is the ability to compute state-of-the-art COMET metrics from Python but using Marian's inference engine, with a speedup factor of up to 7.8$\times$ the existing implementations. We also briefly spotlight a number of other integrations, including Jupyter notebooks, connection with prebuilt models, and a web app interface provided with the package. PyMarian is available in PyPI via $\texttt{pip install pymarian}$.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11853v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Thamme Gowda, Roman Grundkiewicz, Elijah Rippeth, Matt Post, Marcin Junczys-Dowmunt</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Raw Data Prevails: Are Large Language Model Embeddings Effective in Numerical Data Representation for Medical Machine Learning Applications?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11854</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11854v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The introduction of Large Language Models (LLMs) has advanced data representation and analysis, bringing significant progress in their use for medical questions and answering. Despite these advancements, integrating tabular data, especially numerical data pivotal in clinical contexts, into LLM paradigms has not been thoroughly explored. In this study, we examine the effectiveness of vector representations from last hidden states of LLMs for medical diagnostics and prognostics using electronic health record (EHR) data. We compare the performance of these embeddings with that of raw numerical EHR data when used as feature inputs to traditional machine learning (ML) algorithms that excel at tabular data learning, such as eXtreme Gradient Boosting. We focus on instruction-tuned LLMs in a zero-shot setting to represent abnormal physiological data and evaluating their utilities as feature extractors to enhance ML classifiers for predicting diagnoses, length of stay, and mortality. Furthermore, we examine prompt engineering techniques on zero-shot and few-shot LLM embeddings to measure their impact comprehensively. Although findings suggest the raw data features still prevails in medical ML tasks, zero-shot LLM embeddings demonstrate competitive results, suggesting a promising avenue for future research in medical applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11854v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yanjun Gao, Skatje Myers, Shan Chen, Dmitriy Dligach, Timothy A Miller, Danielle Bitterman, Matthew Churpek, Majid Afshar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FactorLLM: Factorizing Knowledge via Mixture of Experts for Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11855</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11855v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent research has demonstrated that Feed-Forward Networks (FFNs) in Large Language Models (LLMs) play a pivotal role in storing diverse linguistic and factual knowledge. Conventional methods frequently face challenges due to knowledge confusion stemming from their monolithic and redundant architectures, which calls for more efficient solutions with minimal computational overhead, particularly for LLMs. In this paper, we explore the FFN computation paradigm in LLMs and introduce FactorLLM, a novel approach that decomposes well-trained dense FFNs into sparse sub-networks without requiring any further modifications, while maintaining the same level of performance. Furthermore, we embed a router from the Mixture-of-Experts (MoE), combined with our devised Prior-Approximate (PA) loss term that facilitates the dynamic activation of experts and knowledge adaptation, thereby accelerating computational processes and enhancing performance using minimal training data and fine-tuning steps. FactorLLM thus enables efficient knowledge factorization and activates select groups of experts specifically tailored to designated tasks, emulating the interactive functional segmentation of the human brain. Extensive experiments across various benchmarks demonstrate the effectiveness of our proposed FactorLLM which achieves comparable performance to the source model securing up to 85% model performance while obtaining over a 30% increase in inference speed. Code: https://github.com/zhenwuweihe/FactorLLM.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11855v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhongyu Zhao, Menghang Dong, Rongyu Zhang, Wenzhao Zheng, Yunpeng Zhang, Huanrui Yang, Dalong Du, Kurt Keutzer, Shanghang Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Adaptive Optimization for Effective Sentiment Analysis Fine-Tuning on Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11856</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11856v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Sentiment analysis plays a crucial role in various domains, such as business intelligence and financial forecasting. Large language models (LLMs) have become a popular paradigm for sentiment analysis, leveraging multi-task learning to address specific tasks concurrently. However, LLMs with fine-tuning for sentiment analysis often underperforms due to the inherent challenges in managing diverse task complexities. Moreover, constant-weight approaches in multi-task learning struggle to adapt to variations in data characteristics, further complicating model effectiveness. To address these issues, we propose a novel multi-task learning framework with a dynamic adaptive optimization (DAO) module. This module is designed as a plug-and-play component that can be seamlessly integrated into existing models, providing an effective and flexible solution for multi-task learning. The key component of the DAO module is dynamic adaptive loss, which dynamically adjusts the weights assigned to different tasks based on their relative importance and data characteristics during training. Sentiment analyses on a standard and customized financial text dataset demonstrate that the proposed framework achieves superior performance. Specifically, this work improves the Mean Squared Error (MSE) and Accuracy (ACC) by 15.58% and 1.24% respectively, compared with previous work.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11856v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hongcheng Ding, Xuanze Zhao, Shamsul Nahar Abdullah, Deshinta Arrova Dewi, Zixiao Jiang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hermes 3 Technical Report</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11857</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11857v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Instruct (or "chat") tuned models have become the primary way in which most people interact with large language models. As opposed to "base" or "foundation" models, instruct-tuned models are optimized to respond to imperative statements. We present Hermes 3, a neutrally-aligned generalist instruct and tool use model with strong reasoning and creative abilities. Its largest version, Hermes 3 405B, achieves state of the art performance among open weight models on several public benchmarks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11857v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ryan Teknium, Jeffrey Quesnelle, Chen Guang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Convexity-based Pruning of Speech Representation Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11858</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11858v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Speech representation models based on the transformer architecture and trained by self-supervised learning have shown great promise for solving tasks such as speech and speaker recognition, keyword spotting, emotion detection, and more. Typically, it is found that larger models lead to better performance. However, the significant computational effort involved in such large transformer systems is a challenge for embedded and real-world applications. Recent work has shown that there is significant redundancy in the transformer models for NLP and massive layer pruning is feasible (Sajjad et al., 2023). Here, we investigate layer pruning in audio models. We base the pruning decision on a convexity criterion. Convexity of classification regions has recently been proposed as an indicator of subsequent fine-tuning performance in a range of application domains, including NLP and audio. In empirical investigations, we find a massive reduction in the computational effort with no loss of performance or even improvements in certain cases.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11858v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Teresa Dorszewski, Lenka T\v{e}tkov\'a, Lars Kai Hansen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Risks and NLP Design: A Case Study on Procedural Document QA</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11860</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11860v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: As NLP systems are increasingly deployed at scale, concerns about their potential negative impacts have attracted the attention of the research community, yet discussions of risk have mostly been at an abstract level and focused on generic AI or NLP applications. We argue that clearer assessments of risks and harms to users--and concrete strategies to mitigate them--will be possible when we specialize the analysis to more concrete applications and their plausible users. As an illustration, this paper is grounded in cooking recipe procedural document question answering (ProcDocQA), where there are well-defined risks to users such as injuries or allergic reactions. Our case study shows that an existing language model, applied in "zero-shot" mode, quantitatively answers real-world questions about recipes as well or better than the humans who have answered the questions on the web. Using a novel questionnaire informed by theoretical work on AI risk, we conduct a risk-oriented error analysis that could then inform the design of a future system to be deployed with lower risk of harm and better performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11860v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.18653/v1/2023.findings-acl.81</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics ACL (2023) 1248-1269</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Nikita Haduong (Paul G. Allen School of Computer Science &amp; Engineering, University of Washington), Alice Gao (Paul G. Allen School of Computer Science &amp; Engineering, University of Washington), Noah A. Smith (Paul G. Allen School of Computer Science &amp; Engineering, University of Washington, Allen Institute for Artificial Intelligence)</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speaking the Same Language: Leveraging LLMs in Standardizing Clinical Data for AI</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11861</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11861v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The implementation of Artificial Intelligence (AI) in the healthcare industry has garnered considerable attention, attributable to its prospective enhancement of clinical outcomes, expansion of access to superior healthcare, cost reduction, and elevation of patient satisfaction. Nevertheless, the primary hurdle that persists is related to the quality of accessible multi-modal healthcare data in conjunction with the evolution of AI methodologies. This study delves into the adoption of large language models to address specific challenges, specifically, the standardization of healthcare data. We advocate the use of these models to identify and map clinical data schemas to established data standard attributes, such as the Fast Healthcare Interoperability Resources. Our results illustrate that employing large language models significantly diminishes the necessity for manual data curation and elevates the efficacy of the data standardization process. Consequently, the proposed methodology has the propensity to expedite the integration of AI in healthcare, ameliorate the quality of patient care, whilst minimizing the time and financial resources necessary for the preparation of data for AI.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11861v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Arindam Sett, Somaye Hashemifar, Mrunal Yadav, Yogesh Pandit, Mohsen Hejrati</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment analysis of preservice teachers' reflections using a large language model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11862</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11862v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this study, the emotion and tone of preservice teachers' reflections were analyzed using sentiment analysis with LLMs: GPT-4, Gemini, and BERT. We compared the results to understand how each tool categorizes and describes individual reflections and multiple reflections as a whole. This study aims to explore ways to bridge the gaps between qualitative, quantitative, and computational analyses of reflective practices in teacher education. This study finds that to effectively integrate LLM analysis into teacher education, developing an analysis method and result format that are both comprehensive and relevant for preservice teachers and teacher educators is crucial.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11862v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yunsoo Park, Younkyung Hong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Susceptible are LLMs to Influence in Prompts?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11865</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11865v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) are highly sensitive to prompts, including additional context provided therein. As LLMs grow in capability, understanding their prompt-sensitivity becomes increasingly crucial for ensuring reliable and robust performance, particularly since evaluating these models becomes more challenging. In this work, we investigate how current models (Llama, Mixtral, Falcon) respond when presented with additional input from another model, mimicking a scenario where a more capable model -- or a system with access to more external information -- provides supplementary information to the target model. Across a diverse spectrum of question-answering tasks, we study how an LLM's response to multiple-choice questions changes when the prompt includes a prediction and explanation from another model. Specifically, we explore the influence of the presence of an explanation, the stated authoritativeness of the source, and the stated confidence of the supplementary input. Our findings reveal that models are strongly influenced, and when explanations are provided they are swayed irrespective of the quality of the explanation. The models are more likely to be swayed if the input is presented as being authoritative or confident, but the effect is small in size. This study underscores the significant prompt-sensitivity of LLMs and highlights the potential risks of incorporating outputs from external sources without thorough scrutiny and further validation. As LLMs continue to advance, understanding and mitigating such sensitivities will be crucial for their reliable and trustworthy deployment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11865v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sotiris Anagnostidis, Jannis Bulian</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crossing New Frontiers: Knowledge-Augmented Large Language Model Prompting for Zero-Shot Text-Based De Novo Molecule Design</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11866</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11866v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Molecule design is a multifaceted approach that leverages computational methods and experiments to optimize molecular properties, fast-tracking new drug discoveries, innovative material development, and more efficient chemical processes. Recently, text-based molecule design has emerged, inspired by next-generation AI tasks analogous to foundational vision-language models. Our study explores the use of knowledge-augmented prompting of large language models (LLMs) for the zero-shot text-conditional de novo molecular generation task. Our approach uses task-specific instructions and a few demonstrations to address distributional shift challenges when constructing augmented prompts for querying LLMs to generate molecules consistent with technical descriptions. Our framework proves effective, outperforming state-of-the-art (SOTA) baseline models on benchmark datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11866v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>q-bio.BM</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sakhinana Sagar Srinivas, Venkataramana Runkana</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving embedding with contrastive fine-tuning on small datasets with expert-augmented scores</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11868</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11868v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper presents an approach to improve text embedding models through contrastive fine-tuning on small datasets augmented with expert scores. It focuses on enhancing semantic textual similarity tasks and addressing text retrieval problems. The proposed method uses soft labels derived from expert-augmented scores to fine-tune embedding models, preserving their versatility and ensuring retrieval capability is improved. The paper evaluates the method using a Q\&amp;A dataset from an online shopping website and eight expert models. Results show improved performance over a benchmark model across multiple metrics on various retrieval tasks from the massive text embedding benchmark (MTEB). The method is cost-effective and practical for real-world applications, especially when labeled data is scarce.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11868v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jun Lu, David Li, Bill Ding, Yu Kang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhance Lifelong Model Editing with Continuous Data-Adapter Association</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11869</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11869v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) require model editing to efficiently update specific knowledge within them and avoid factual errors. Most model editing methods are solely designed for single-time use and lead to a significant forgetting effect after sequential edits over time, referred to as lifelong editing. Current approaches manage sequential edits by freezing original parameters and allocating new adapters for each knowledge modification. However, these methods lack robustness to minor input variations. To address this challenge, we propose ELDER, \textbf{E}nhancing \textbf{L}ifelong mo\textbf{D}el \textbf{E}diting with mixtu\textbf{R}e of Low-Rank Adapter (LoRA). ELDER is an adaptive approach that integrates multiple LoRAs through a router network. It learns to create a continuous and smooth association between data and adapters, thereby enhancing robustness and generalization to semantically equivalent inputs. Additionally, we introduce a novel loss to help learn associations between adapter allocations and edit semantics. A deferral mechanism is also proposed to retain the original LLM capabilities post-edit. Extensive experiments on GPT-2 XL and LLaMA2-7B demonstrate that ELDER effectively edits models in the lifelong setting and exhibits strong scalability, while retaining LLM's general abilities on downstream tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11869v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiaang Li, Quan Wang, Zhongnan Wang, Yongdong Zhang, Zhendong Mao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MegaFake: A Theory-Driven Dataset of Fake News Generated by Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11871</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11871v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The advent of large language models (LLMs) has revolutionized online content creation, making it much easier to generate high-quality fake news. This misuse threatens the integrity of our digital environment and ethical standards. Therefore, understanding the motivations and mechanisms behind LLM-generated fake news is crucial. In this study, we analyze the creation of fake news from a social psychology perspective and develop a comprehensive LLM-based theoretical framework, LLM-Fake Theory. We introduce a novel pipeline that automates the generation of fake news using LLMs, thereby eliminating the need for manual annotation. Utilizing this pipeline, we create a theoretically informed Machine-generated Fake news dataset, MegaFake, derived from the GossipCop dataset. We conduct comprehensive analyses to evaluate our MegaFake dataset. We believe that our dataset and insights will provide valuable contributions to future research focused on the detection and governance of fake news in the era of LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11871v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lionel Z. Wang, Yiming Ma, Renfei Gao, Beichen Guo, Zhuoran Li, Han Zhu, Wenqi Fan, Zexin Lu, Ka Chung Ng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Retrieval-Augmented Generation Model with Rethink for Multi-hop Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11875</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11875v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Multi-hop Question Answering (QA) necessitates complex reasoning by integrating multiple pieces of information to resolve intricate questions. However, existing QA systems encounter challenges such as outdated information, context window length limitations, and an accuracy-quantity trade-off. To address these issues, we propose a novel framework, the Hierarchical Retrieval-Augmented Generation Model with Rethink (HiRAG), comprising Decomposer, Definer, Retriever, Filter, and Summarizer five key modules. We introduce a new hierarchical retrieval strategy that incorporates both sparse retrieval at the document level and dense retrieval at the chunk level, effectively integrating their strengths. Additionally, we propose a single-candidate retrieval method to mitigate the limitations of multi-candidate retrieval. We also construct two new corpora, Indexed Wikicorpus and Profile Wikicorpus, to address the issues of outdated and insufficient knowledge.
  Our experimental results on four datasets demonstrate that HiRAG outperforms state-of-the-art models across most metrics, and our Indexed Wikicorpus is effective. The code for HiRAG is available at https://github.com/2282588541a/HiRAG</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11875v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoming Zhang, Ming Wang, Xiaocui Yang, Daling Wang, Shi Feng, Yifei Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open-FinLLMs: Open Multimodal Large Language Models for Financial Applications</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11878</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11878v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have advanced financial applications, yet they often lack sufficient financial knowledge and struggle with tasks involving multi-modal inputs like tables and time series data. To address these limitations, we introduce \textit{Open-FinLLMs}, a series of Financial LLMs. We begin with FinLLaMA, pre-trained on a 52 billion token financial corpus, incorporating text, tables, and time-series data to embed comprehensive financial knowledge. FinLLaMA is then instruction fine-tuned with 573K financial instructions, resulting in FinLLaMA-instruct, which enhances task performance. Finally, we present FinLLaVA, a multimodal LLM trained with 1.43M image-text instructions to handle complex financial data types. Extensive evaluations demonstrate FinLLaMA's superior performance over LLaMA3-8B, LLaMA3.1-8B, and BloombergGPT in both zero-shot and few-shot settings across 19 and 4 datasets, respectively. FinLLaMA-instruct outperforms GPT-4 and other Financial LLMs on 15 datasets. FinLLaVA excels in understanding tables and charts across 4 multimodal tasks. Additionally, FinLLaMA achieves impressive Sharpe Ratios in trading simulations, highlighting its robust financial application capabilities. We will continually maintain and improve our models and benchmarks to support ongoing innovation in academia and industry.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11878v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CE</category>
      <category>q-fin.CP</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qianqian Xie, Dong Li, Mengxi Xiao, Zihao Jiang, Ruoyu Xiang, Xiao Zhang, Zhengyu Chen, Yueru He, Weiguang Han, Yuzhe Yang, Shunian Chen, Yifei Zhang, Lihang Shen, Daniel Kim, Zhiwei Liu, Zheheng Luo, Yangyang Yu, Yupeng Cao, Zhiyang Deng, Zhiyuan Yao, Haohang Li, Duanyu Feng, Yongfu Dai, VijayaSai Somasundaram, Peng Lu, Yilun Zhao, Yitao Long, Guojun Xiong, Kaleb Smith, Honghai Yu, Yanzhao Lai, Min Peng, Jianyun Nie, Jordan W. Suchow, Xiao-Yang Liu, Benyou Wang, Alejandro Lopez-Lira, Jimin Huang, Sophia Ananiadou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Labels: Aligning Large Language Models with Human-like Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11879</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11879v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Aligning large language models (LLMs) with a human reasoning approach ensures that LLMs produce morally correct and human-like decisions. Ethical concerns are raised because current models are prone to generating false positives and providing malicious responses. To contribute to this issue, we have curated an ethics dataset named Dataset for Aligning Reasons (DFAR), designed to aid in aligning language models to generate human-like reasons. The dataset comprises statements with ethical-unethical labels and their corresponding reasons. In this study, we employed a unique and novel fine-tuning approach that utilizes ethics labels and their corresponding reasons (L+R), in contrast to the existing fine-tuning approach that only uses labels (L). The original pre-trained versions, the existing fine-tuned versions, and our proposed fine-tuned versions of LLMs were then evaluated on an ethical-unethical classification task and a reason-generation task. Our proposed fine-tuning strategy notably outperforms the others in both tasks, achieving significantly higher accuracy scores in the classification task and lower misalignment rates in the reason-generation task. The increase in classification accuracies and decrease in misalignment rates indicate that the L+R fine-tuned models align more with human ethics. Hence, this study illustrates that injecting reasons has substantially improved the alignment of LLMs, resulting in more human-like responses. We have made the DFAR dataset and corresponding codes publicly available at https://github.com/apurba-nsu-rnd-lab/DFAR.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11879v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Muhammad Rafsan Kabir, Rafeed Mohammad Sultan, Ihsanul Haque Asif, Jawad Ibn Ahad, Fuad Rahman, Mohammad Ruhul Amin, Nabeel Mohammed, Shafin Rahman</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ancient Wisdom, Modern Tools: Exploring Retrieval-Augmented LLMs for Ancient Indian Philosophy</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11903</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11903v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: LLMs have revolutionized the landscape of information retrieval and knowledge dissemination. However, their application in specialized areas is often hindered by factual inaccuracies and hallucinations, especially in long-tail knowledge distributions. We explore the potential of retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) models for long-form question answering (LFQA) in a specialized knowledge domain. We present VedantaNY-10M, a dataset curated from extensive public discourses on the ancient Indian philosophy of Advaita Vedanta. We develop and benchmark a RAG model against a standard, non-RAG LLM, focusing on transcription, retrieval, and generation performance. Human evaluations by computational linguists and domain experts show that the RAG model significantly outperforms the standard model in producing factual and comprehensive responses having fewer hallucinations. In addition, a keyword-based hybrid retriever that emphasizes unique low-frequency terms further improves results. Our study provides insights into effectively integrating modern large language models with ancient knowledge systems. Project page with dataset and code: https://sites.google.com/view/vedantany-10m</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11903v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Priyanka Mandikal</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defining Boundaries: The Impact of Domain Specification on Cross-Language and Cross-Domain Transfer in Machine Translation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11926</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11926v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent advancements in neural machine translation (NMT) have revolutionized the field, yet the dependency on extensive parallel corpora limits progress for low-resource languages. Cross-lingual transfer learning offers a promising solution by utilizing data from high-resource languages but often struggles with in-domain NMT. In this paper, we investigate three pivotal aspects: enhancing the domain-specific quality of NMT by fine-tuning domain-relevant data from different language pairs, identifying which domains are transferable in zero-shot scenarios, and assessing the impact of language-specific versus domain-specific factors on adaptation effectiveness. Using English as the source language and Spanish for fine-tuning, we evaluate multiple target languages including Portuguese, Italian, French, Czech, Polish, and Greek. Our findings reveal significant improvements in domain-specific translation quality, especially in specialized fields such as medical, legal, and IT, underscoring the importance of well-defined domain data and transparency of the experiment setup in in-domain transfer learning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11926v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lia Shahnazaryan, Meriem Beloucif</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The State of Commercial Automatic French Legal Speech Recognition Systems and their Impact on Court Reporters et al</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11940</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11940v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In Quebec and Canadian courts, the transcription of court proceedings is a critical task for appeal purposes and must be certified by an official court reporter. The limited availability of qualified reporters and the high costs associated with manual transcription underscore the need for more efficient solutions. This paper examines the potential of Automatic Speech Recognition (ASR) systems to assist court reporters in transcribing legal proceedings. We benchmark three ASR models, including commercial and open-source options, on their ability to recognize French legal speech using a curated dataset. Our study evaluates the performance of these systems using the Word Error Rate (WER) metric and introduces the Sonnex Distance to account for phonetic accuracy. We also explore the broader implications of ASR adoption on court reporters, copyists, the legal system, and litigants, identifying both positive and negative impacts. The findings suggest that while current ASR systems show promise, they require further refinement to meet the specific needs of the legal domain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11940v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nicolad Garneau, Olivier Bolduc</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoding SEC Actions: Enforcement Trends through Analyzing Blockchain litigation using LLM-based Thematic Factor Mapping</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11961</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11961v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The proliferation of blockchain entities (persons or enterprises) exposes them to potential regulatory actions (e.g., being litigated) by regulatory authorities. Regulatory frameworks for crypto assets are actively being developed and refined, increasing the likelihood of such actions. The lack of systematic analysis of the factors driving litigation against blockchain entities leaves companies in need of clarity to navigate compliance risks. This absence of insight also deprives investors of the information for informed decision-making. This study focuses on U.S. litigation against blockchain entities, particularly by the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) given its influence on global crypto regulation. Utilizing frontier pretrained language models and large language models, we systematically map all SEC complaints against blockchain companies from 2012 to 2024 to thematic factors conceptualized by our study to delineate the factors driving SEC actions. We quantify the thematic factors and assess their influence on specific legal Acts cited within the complaints on an annual basis, allowing us to discern the regulatory emphasis, patterns and conduct trend analysis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11961v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junliang Luo, Xihan Xiong, William Knottenbelt, Xue Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Language Models for Page Stream Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11981</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11981v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Page Stream Segmentation (PSS) is an essential prerequisite for automated document processing at scale. However, research progress has been limited by the absence of realistic public benchmarks. This paper works towards addressing this gap by introducing TABME++, an enhanced benchmark featuring commercial Optical Character Recognition (OCR) annotations. We evaluate the performance of large language models (LLMs) on PSS, focusing on decoder-based models fine-tuned with parameter-efficient methods. Our results show that decoder-based LLMs outperform smaller multimodal encoders. Through a review of existing PSS research and datasets, we identify key challenges and advancements in the field. Our findings highlight the key importance of robust OCR, providing valuable insights for the development of more effective document processing systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11981v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hunter Heidenreich, Ratish Dalvi, Rohith Mukku, Nikhil Verma, Neven Pi\v{c}uljan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RAG-Optimized Tibetan Tourism LLMs: Enhancing Accuracy and Personalization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12003</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12003v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: With the development of the modern social economy, tourism has become an important way to meet people's spiritual needs, bringing development opportunities to the tourism industry. However, existing large language models (LLMs) face challenges in personalized recommendation capabilities and the generation of content that can sometimes produce hallucinations. This study proposes an optimization scheme for Tibet tourism LLMs based on retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) technology. By constructing a database of tourist viewpoints and processing the data using vectorization techniques, we have significantly improved retrieval accuracy. The application of RAG technology effectively addresses the hallucination problem in content generation. The optimized model shows significant improvements in fluency, accuracy, and relevance of content generation. This research demonstrates the potential of RAG technology in the standardization of cultural tourism information and data analysis, providing theoretical and technical support for the development of intelligent cultural tourism service systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12003v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jinhu Qi, Shuai Yan, Yibo Zhang, Wentao Zhang, Rong Jin, Yuwei Hu, Ke Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Epistemic Language with a Bayesian Theory of Mind</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12022</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12022v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: How do people understand and evaluate claims about others' beliefs, even though these beliefs cannot be directly observed? In this paper, we introduce a cognitive model of epistemic language interpretation, grounded in Bayesian inferences about other agents' goals, beliefs, and intentions: a language-augmented Bayesian theory-of-mind (LaBToM). By translating natural language into an epistemic ``language-of-thought'', then evaluating these translations against the inferences produced by inverting a probabilistic generative model of rational action and perception, LaBToM captures graded plausibility judgments about epistemic claims. We validate our model in an experiment where participants watch an agent navigate a maze to find keys hidden in boxes needed to reach their goal, then rate sentences about the agent's beliefs. In contrast with multimodal LLMs (GPT-4o, Gemini Pro) and ablated models, our model correlates highly with human judgments for a wide range of expressions, including modal language, uncertainty expressions, knowledge claims, likelihood comparisons, and attributions of false belief.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12022v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lance Ying, Tan Zhi-Xuan, Lionel Wong, Vikash Mansinghka, Joshua B. Tenenbaum</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aligning (Medical) LLMs for (Counterfactual) Fairness</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12055</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12055v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have emerged as promising solutions for a variety of medical and clinical decision support applications. However, LLMs are often subject to different types of biases, which can lead to unfair treatment of individuals, worsening health disparities, and reducing trust in AI-augmented medical tools. Aiming to address this important issue, in this study, we present a new model alignment approach for aligning LLMs using a preference optimization method within a knowledge distillation framework. Prior to presenting our proposed method, we first use an evaluation framework to conduct a comprehensive (largest to our knowledge) empirical evaluation to reveal the type and nature of existing biases in LLMs used for medical applications. We then offer a bias mitigation technique to reduce the unfair patterns in LLM outputs across different subgroups identified by the protected attributes. We show that our mitigation method is effective in significantly reducing observed biased patterns. Our code is publicly available at \url{https://github.com/healthylaife/FairAlignmentLLM}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12055v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Raphael Poulain, Hamed Fayyaz, Rahmatollah Beheshti</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evidence-backed Fact Checking using RAG and Few-Shot In-Context Learning with LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12060</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12060v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Given the widespread dissemination of misinformation on social media, implementing fact-checking mechanisms for online claims is essential. Manually verifying every claim is highly challenging, underscoring the need for an automated fact-checking system. This paper presents our system designed to address this issue. We utilize the Averitec dataset to assess the veracity of claims. In addition to veracity prediction, our system provides supporting evidence, which is extracted from the dataset. We develop a Retrieve and Generate (RAG) pipeline to extract relevant evidence sentences from a knowledge base, which are then inputted along with the claim into a large language model (LLM) for classification. We also evaluate the few-shot In-Context Learning (ICL) capabilities of multiple LLMs. Our system achieves an 'Averitec' score of 0.33, which is a 22% absolute improvement over the baseline. All code will be made available on All code will be made available on https://github.com/ronit-singhal/evidence-backed-fact-checking-using-rag-and-few-shot-in-context-learning-with-llms.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12060v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ronit Singhal, Pransh Patwa, Parth Patwa, Aman Chadha, Amitava Das</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ConflictBank: A Benchmark for Evaluating the Influence of Knowledge Conflicts in LLM</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12076</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12076v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have achieved impressive advancements across numerous disciplines, yet the critical issue of knowledge conflicts, a major source of hallucinations, has rarely been studied. Only a few research explored the conflicts between the inherent knowledge of LLMs and the retrieved contextual knowledge. However, a thorough assessment of knowledge conflict in LLMs is still missing. Motivated by this research gap, we present ConflictBank, the first comprehensive benchmark developed to systematically evaluate knowledge conflicts from three aspects: (i) conflicts encountered in retrieved knowledge, (ii) conflicts within the models' encoded knowledge, and (iii) the interplay between these conflict forms. Our investigation delves into four model families and twelve LLM instances, meticulously analyzing conflicts stemming from misinformation, temporal discrepancies, and semantic divergences. Based on our proposed novel construction framework, we create 7,453,853 claim-evidence pairs and 553,117 QA pairs. We present numerous findings on model scale, conflict causes, and conflict types. We hope our ConflictBank benchmark will help the community better understand model behavior in conflicts and develop more reliable LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12076v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhaochen Su, Jun Zhang, Xiaoye Qu, Tong Zhu, Yanshu Li, Jiashuo Sun, Juntao Li, Min Zhang, Yu Cheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Quality Data Augmentation for Low-Resource NMT: Combining a Translation Memory, a GAN Generator, and Filtering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12079</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12079v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Back translation, as a technique for extending a dataset, is widely used by researchers in low-resource language translation tasks. It typically translates from the target to the source language to ensure high-quality translation results. This paper proposes a novel way of utilizing a monolingual corpus on the source side to assist Neural Machine Translation (NMT) in low-resource settings. We realize this concept by employing a Generative Adversarial Network (GAN), which augments the training data for the discriminator while mitigating the interference of low-quality synthetic monolingual translations with the generator. Additionally, this paper integrates Translation Memory (TM) with NMT, increasing the amount of data available to the generator. Moreover, we propose a novel procedure to filter the synthetic sentence pairs during the augmentation process, ensuring the high quality of the data.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12079v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hengjie Liu, Ruibo Hou, Yves Lepage</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>uMedSum: A Unified Framework for Advancing Medical Abstractive Summarization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12095</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12095v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Medical abstractive summarization faces the challenge of balancing faithfulness and informativeness. Current methods often sacrifice key information for faithfulness or introduce confabulations when prioritizing informativeness. While recent advancements in techniques like in-context learning (ICL) and fine-tuning have improved medical summarization, they often overlook crucial aspects such as faithfulness and informativeness without considering advanced methods like model reasoning and self-improvement. Moreover, the field lacks a unified benchmark, hindering systematic evaluation due to varied metrics and datasets. This paper addresses these gaps by presenting a comprehensive benchmark of six advanced abstractive summarization methods across three diverse datasets using five standardized metrics. Building on these findings, we propose uMedSum, a modular hybrid summarization framework that introduces novel approaches for sequential confabulation removal followed by key missing information addition, ensuring both faithfulness and informativeness. Our work improves upon previous GPT-4-based state-of-the-art (SOTA) medical summarization methods, significantly outperforming them in both quantitative metrics and qualitative domain expert evaluations. Notably, we achieve an average relative performance improvement of 11.8% in reference-free metrics over the previous SOTA. Doctors prefer uMedSum's summaries 6 times more than previous SOTA in difficult cases where there are chances of confabulations or missing information. These results highlight uMedSum's effectiveness and generalizability across various datasets and metrics, marking a significant advancement in medical summarization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12095v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aishik Nagar, Yutong Liu, Andy T. Liu, Viktor Schlegel, Vijay Prakash Dwivedi, Arun-Kumar Kaliya-Perumal, Guna Pratheep Kalanchiam, Yili Tang, Robby T. Tan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MDD-5k: A New Diagnostic Conversation Dataset for Mental Disorders Synthesized via Neuro-Symbolic LLM Agents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12142</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12142v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The clinical diagnosis of most mental disorders primarily relies on the conversations between psychiatrist and patient. The creation of such diagnostic conversation datasets is promising to boost the AI mental healthcare community. However, directly collecting the conversations in real diagnosis scenarios is near impossible due to stringent privacy and ethical considerations. To address this issue, we seek to synthesize diagnostic conversation by exploiting anonymous patient cases that are easier to access. Specifically, we design a neuro-symbolic multi-agent framework for synthesizing the diagnostic conversation of mental disorders with large language models. It takes patient case as input and is capable of generating multiple diverse conversations with one single patient case. The framework basically involves the interaction between a doctor agent and a patient agent, and achieves text generation under symbolic control via a dynamic diagnosis tree from a tool agent. By applying the proposed framework, we develop the largest Chinese mental disorders diagnosis dataset MDD-5k, which is built upon 1000 cleaned real patient cases by cooperating with a pioneering psychiatric hospital, and contains 5000 high-quality long conversations with diagnosis results as labels. To the best of our knowledge, it's also the first labelled Chinese mental disorders diagnosis dataset. Human evaluation demonstrates the proposed MDD-5k dataset successfully simulates human-like diagnostic process of mental disorders. The dataset and code will become publicly accessible in https://github.com/lemonsis/MDD-5k.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12142v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Congchi Yin, Feng Li, Shu Zhang, Zike Wang, Jun Shao, Piji Li, Jianhua Chen, Xun Jiang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implicit Sentiment Analysis Based on Chain of Thought Prompting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12157</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12157v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Implicit Sentiment Analysis (ISA) is a crucial research area in natural language processing. Inspired by the idea of large language model Chain of Thought (CoT), this paper introduces a Sentiment Analysis of Thinking (SAoT) framework. The framework first analyzes the implicit aspects and opinions in the text using common sense and thinking chain capabilities. Then, it reflects on the process of implicit sentiment analysis and finally deduces the polarity of sentiment. The model is evaluated on the SemEval 2014 dataset, consisting of 1120 restaurant reviews and 638 laptop reviews. The experimental results demonstrate that the utilization of the ERNIE-Bot-4+SAoT model yields a notable performance improvement. Specifically, on the restaurant dataset, the F1 score reaches 75.27, accompanied by an ISA score of 66.29. Similarly, on the computer dataset, the F1 score achieves 76.50, while the ISA score amounts to 73.46. Comparatively, the ERNIE-Bot-4+SAoT model surpasses the BERTAsp + SCAPt baseline by an average margin of 47.99%.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12157v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhihua Duan, Jialin Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preference-Guided Reflective Sampling for Aligning Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12163</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12163v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are aligned with human preferences by reinforcement learning from human feedback (RLHF). Effective data sampling is crucial for RLHF, as it determines the efficiency of model training, ensuring that models learn from the informative samples. To achieve better data generation, we propose a new sampling method called Preference-Guided Reflective Sampling (PRS). PRS frames the response generation as an optimization process to the explicitly specified user preference described in natural language. It employs a tree-based generation framework to enable an efficient sampling process, which guides the direction of generation through preference and better explores the sampling space with adaptive self-refinement. Notably, PRS can align LLMs to diverse preferences. We study preference-controlled text generation for instruction following and keyword-focused document summarization. Our findings indicate that PRS, across different LLM policies, generates training data with much higher rewards than strong baselines. PRS also excels in post-RL training.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12163v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hai Ye, Hwee Tou Ng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIRST: Teach A Reliable Large Language Model Through Efficient Trustworthy Distillation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12168</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12168v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have become increasingly prevalent in our daily lives, leading to an expectation for LLMs to be trustworthy -- - both accurate and well-calibrated (the prediction confidence should align with its ground truth correctness likelihood). Nowadays, fine-tuning has become the most popular method for adapting a model to practical usage by significantly increasing accuracy on downstream tasks. Despite the great accuracy it achieves, we found fine-tuning is still far away from satisfactory trustworthiness due to "tuning-induced mis-calibration". In this paper, we delve deeply into why and how mis-calibration exists in fine-tuned models, and how distillation can alleviate the issue. Then we further propose a brand new method named Efficient Trustworthy Distillation (FIRST), which utilizes a small portion of teacher's knowledge to obtain a reliable language model in a cost-efficient way. Specifically, we identify the "concentrated knowledge" phenomenon during distillation, which can significantly reduce the computational burden. Then we apply a "trustworthy maximization" process to optimize the utilization of this small portion of concentrated knowledge before transferring it to the student. Experimental results demonstrate the effectiveness of our method, where better accuracy (+2.3%) and less mis-calibration (-10%) are achieved on average across both in-domain and out-of-domain scenarios, indicating better trustworthiness.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12168v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>KaShun Shum, Minrui Xu, Jianshu Zhang, Zixin Chen, Shizhe Diao, Hanze Dong, Jipeng Zhang, Muhammad Omer Raza</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting the Phenomenon of Syntactic Complexity Convergence on German Dialogue Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12177</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12177v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We revisit the phenomenon of syntactic complexity convergence in conversational interaction, originally found for English dialogue, which has theoretical implication for dialogical concepts such as mutual understanding. We use a modified metric to quantify syntactic complexity based on dependency parsing. The results show that syntactic complexity convergence can be statistically confirmed in one of three selected German datasets that were analysed. Given that the dataset which shows such convergence is much larger than the other two selected datasets, the empirical results indicate a certain degree of linguistic generality of syntactic complexity convergence in conversational interaction. We also found a different type of syntactic complexity convergence in one of the datasets while further investigation is still necessary.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12177v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yu Wang, Hendrik Buschmeier</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reasoning Factual Knowledge in Structured Data with Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12188</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12188v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have made remarkable progress in various natural language processing tasks as a benefit of their capability to comprehend and reason with factual knowledge. However, a significant amount of factual knowledge is stored in structured data, which possesses unique characteristics that differ from the unstructured texts used for pretraining. This difference can introduce imperceptible inference parameter deviations, posing challenges for LLMs in effectively utilizing and reasoning with structured data to accurately infer factual knowledge. To this end, we propose a benchmark named StructFact, to evaluate the structural reasoning capabilities of LLMs in inferring factual knowledge. StructFact comprises 8,340 factual questions encompassing various tasks, domains, timelines, and regions. This benchmark allows us to investigate the capability of LLMs across five factual tasks derived from the unique characteristics of structural facts. Extensive experiments on a set of LLMs with different training strategies reveal the limitations of current LLMs in inferring factual knowledge from structured data. We present this benchmark as a compass to navigate the strengths and weaknesses of LLMs in reasoning with structured data for knowledge-sensitive tasks, and to encourage advancements in related real-world applications. Please find our code at https://github.com/EganGu/StructFact.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12188v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sirui Huang, Yanggan Gu, Xuming Hu, Zhonghao Li, Qing Li, Guandong Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Language Models as Foundations for Next-Gen Dense Retrieval: A Comprehensive Empirical Assessment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12194</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12194v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Pretrained language models like BERT and T5 serve as crucial backbone encoders for dense retrieval. However, these models often exhibit limited generalization capabilities and face challenges in improving in domain accuracy. Recent research has explored using large language models (LLMs) as retrievers, achieving SOTA performance across various tasks. Despite these advancements, the specific benefits of LLMs over traditional retrievers and the impact of different LLM configurations, such as parameter sizes, pretraining duration, and alignment processes on retrieval tasks remain unclear. In this work, we conduct a comprehensive empirical study on a wide range of retrieval tasks, including in domain accuracy, data efficiency, zero shot generalization, lengthy retrieval, instruction based retrieval, and multi task learning. We evaluate over 15 different backbone LLMs and non LLMs. Our findings reveal that larger models and extensive pretraining consistently enhance in domain accuracy and data efficiency. Additionally, larger models demonstrate significant potential in zero shot generalization, lengthy retrieval, instruction based retrieval, and multi task learning. These results underscore the advantages of LLMs as versatile and effective backbone encoders in dense retrieval, providing valuable insights for future research and development in this field.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12194v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kun Luo, Minghao Qin, Zheng Liu, Shitao Xiao, Jun Zhao, Kang Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EvalYaks: Instruction Tuning Datasets and LoRA Fine-tuned Models for Automated Scoring of CEFR B2 Speaking Assessment Transcripts</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12226</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12226v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Relying on human experts to evaluate CEFR speaking assessments in an e-learning environment creates scalability challenges, as it limits how quickly and widely assessments can be conducted. We aim to automate the evaluation of CEFR B2 English speaking assessments in e-learning environments from conversation transcripts. First, we evaluate the capability of leading open source and commercial Large Language Models (LLMs) to score a candidate's performance across various criteria in the CEFR B2 speaking exam in both global and India-specific contexts. Next, we create a new expert-validated, CEFR-aligned synthetic conversational dataset with transcripts that are rated at different assessment scores. In addition, new instruction-tuned datasets are developed from the English Vocabulary Profile (up to CEFR B2 level) and the CEFR-SP WikiAuto datasets. Finally, using these new datasets, we perform parameter efficient instruction tuning of Mistral Instruct 7B v0.2 to develop a family of models called EvalYaks. Four models in this family are for assessing the four sections of the CEFR B2 speaking exam, one for identifying the CEFR level of vocabulary and generating level-specific vocabulary, and another for detecting the CEFR level of text and generating level-specific text. EvalYaks achieved an average acceptable accuracy of 96%, a degree of variation of 0.35 levels, and performed 3 times better than the next best model. This demonstrates that a 7B parameter LLM instruction tuned with high-quality CEFR-aligned assessment data can effectively evaluate and score CEFR B2 English speaking assessments, offering a promising solution for scalable, automated language proficiency evaluation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12226v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nicy Scaria, Silvester John Joseph Kennedy, Thomas Latinovich, Deepak Subramani</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLMs are not Zero-Shot Reasoners for Biomedical Information Extraction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12249</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12249v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) are increasingly adopted for applications in healthcare, reaching the performance of domain experts on tasks such as question answering and document summarisation. Despite their success on these tasks, it is unclear how well LLMs perform on tasks that are traditionally pursued in the biomedical domain, such as structured information extration. To breach this gap, in this paper, we systematically benchmark LLM performance in Medical Classification and Named Entity Recognition (NER) tasks. We aim to disentangle the contribution of different factors to the performance, particularly the impact of LLMs' task knowledge and reasoning capabilities, their (parametric) domain knowledge, and addition of external knowledge. To this end we evaluate various open LLMs -- including BioMistral and Llama-2 models -- on a diverse set of biomedical datasets, using standard prompting, Chain-of-Thought (CoT) and Self-Consistency based reasoning as well as Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) with PubMed and Wikipedia corpora. Counter-intuitively, our results reveal that standard prompting consistently outperforms more complex techniques across both tasks, laying bare the limitations in the current application of CoT, self-consistency and RAG in the biomedical domain. Our findings suggest that advanced prompting methods developed for knowledge- or reasoning-intensive tasks, such as CoT or RAG, are not easily portable to biomedical tasks where precise structured outputs are required. This highlights the need for more effective integration of external knowledge and reasoning mechanisms in LLMs to enhance their performance in real-world biomedical applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12249v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aishik Nagar, Viktor Schlegel, Thanh-Tung Nguyen, Hao Li, Yuping Wu, Kuluhan Binici, Stefan Winkler</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Language-agnostic Model of Child Language Acquisition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12254</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12254v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This work reimplements a recent semantic bootstrapping child-language acquisition model, which was originally designed for English, and trains it to learn a new language: Hebrew. The model learns from pairs of utterances and logical forms as meaning representations, and acquires both syntax and word meanings simultaneously. The results show that the model mostly transfers to Hebrew, but that a number of factors, including the richer morphology in Hebrew, makes the learning slower and less robust. This suggests that a clear direction for future work is to enable the model to leverage the similarities between different word forms.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12254v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Louis Mahon, Omri Abend, Uri Berger, Katherine Demuth, Mark Johnson, Mark Steedman</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward the Evaluation of Large Language Models Considering Score Variance across Instruction Templates</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12263</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12263v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The natural language understanding (NLU) performance of large language models (LLMs) has been evaluated across various tasks and datasets. The existing evaluation methods, however, do not take into account the variance in scores due to differences in prompts, which leads to unfair evaluation and comparison of NLU performance. Moreover, evaluation designed for specific prompts is inappropriate for instruction tuning, which aims to perform well with any prompt. It is therefore necessary to find a way to measure NLU performance in a fair manner, considering score variance between different instruction templates. In this study, we provide English and Japanese cross-lingual datasets for evaluating the NLU performance of LLMs, which include multiple instruction templates for fair evaluation of each task, along with regular expressions to constrain the output format. Furthermore, we propose the Sharpe score as an evaluation metric that takes into account the variance in scores between templates. Comprehensive analysis of English and Japanese LLMs reveals that the high variance among templates has a significant impact on the fair evaluation of LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12263v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yusuke Sakai, Adam Nohejl, Jiangnan Hang, Hidetaka Kamigaito, Taro Watanabe</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MaVEn: An Effective Multi-granularity Hybrid Visual Encoding Framework for Multimodal Large Language Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12321</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12321v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper presents MaVEn, an innovative Multi-granularity Visual Encoding framework designed to enhance the capabilities of Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) in multi-image reasoning. Current MLLMs primarily focus on single-image visual understanding, limiting their ability to interpret and integrate information across multiple images. MaVEn addresses this limitation by combining discrete visual symbol sequences, which abstract coarse-grained semantic concepts, with traditional continuous representation sequences that model fine-grained features. This dual approach bridges the semantic gap between visual and textual data, thereby improving the model's ability to process and interpret information from multiple images effectively. Additionally, we design a dynamic reduction mechanism by for long-sequence continuous features to enhance multi-image processing efficiency. Experimental results demonstrate that MaVEn significantly enhances MLLMs' understanding in complex multi-image scenarios, while also improving performance in single-image contexts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12321v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chaoya Jiang, Jia Hongrui, Haiyang Xu, Wei Ye, Mengfan Dong, Ming Yan, Ji Zhang, Fei Huang, Shikun Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Factuality in Large Language Models via Decoding-Time Hallucinatory and Truthful Comparators</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12325</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12325v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Despite their remarkable capabilities, Large Language Models (LLMs) are prone to generate responses that contradict verifiable facts, i.e., unfaithful hallucination content. Existing efforts generally focus on optimizing model parameters or editing semantic representations, which compromise the internal factual knowledge of target LLMs. In addition, hallucinations typically exhibit multifaceted patterns in downstream tasks, limiting the model's holistic performance across tasks. In this paper, we propose a Comparator-driven Decoding-Time (CDT) framework to alleviate the response hallucination. Firstly, we construct hallucinatory and truthful comparators with multi-task fine-tuning samples. In this case, we present an instruction prototype-guided mixture of experts strategy to enhance the ability of the corresponding comparators to capture different hallucination or truthfulness patterns in distinct task instructions. CDT constrains next-token predictions to factuality-robust distributions by contrasting the logit differences between the target LLMs and these comparators. Systematic experiments on multiple downstream tasks show that our framework can significantly improve the model performance and response factuality.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12325v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dingkang Yang, Dongling Xiao, Jinjie Wei, Mingcheng Li, Zhaoyu Chen, Ke Li, Lihua Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interactive DualChecker for Mitigating Hallucinations in Distilling Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12326</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12326v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated exceptional capabilities across various machine learning (ML) tasks. Given the high costs of creating annotated datasets for supervised learning, LLMs offer a valuable alternative by enabling effective few-shot in-context learning. However, these models can produce hallucinations, particularly in domains with incomplete knowledge. Additionally, current methods for knowledge distillation using LLMs often struggle to enhance the effectiveness of both teacher and student models. To address these challenges, we introduce DualChecker, an innovative framework designed to mitigate hallucinations and improve the performance of both teacher and student models during knowledge distillation. DualChecker employs ContextAligner to ensure that the context provided by teacher models aligns with human labeling standards. It also features a dynamic checker system that enhances model interaction: one component re-prompts teacher models with more detailed content when they show low confidence, and another identifies borderline cases from student models to refine the teaching templates. This interactive process promotes continuous improvement and effective knowledge transfer between the models. We evaluate DualChecker using a green innovation textual dataset that includes binary, multiclass, and token classification tasks. The experimental results show that DualChecker significantly outperforms existing state-of-the-art methods, achieving up to a 17% improvement in F1 score for teacher models and 10% for student models. Notably, student models fine-tuned with LLM predictions perform comparably to those fine-tuned with actual data, even in a challenging domain. We make all datasets, models, and code from this research publicly available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12326v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CE</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Meiyun Wang, Masahiro Suzuki, Hiroki Sakaji, Kiyoshi Izumi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tuning Smaller Language Models for Question Answering over Financial Documents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12337</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12337v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent research has shown that smaller language models can acquire substantial reasoning abilities when fine-tuned with reasoning exemplars crafted by a significantly larger teacher model. We explore this paradigm for the financial domain, focusing on the challenge of answering questions that require multi-hop numerical reasoning over financial texts. We assess the performance of several smaller models that have been fine-tuned to generate programs that encode the required financial reasoning and calculations. Our findings demonstrate that these fine-tuned smaller models approach the performance of the teacher model.
  To provide a granular analysis of model performance, we propose an approach to investigate the specific student model capabilities that are enhanced by fine-tuning. Our empirical analysis indicates that fine-tuning refines the student models ability to express and apply the required financial concepts along with adapting the entity extraction for the specific data format. In addition, we hypothesize and demonstrate that comparable financial reasoning capability can be induced using relatively smaller datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12337v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.SY</category>
      <category>eess.SY</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Karmvir Singh Phogat, Sai Akhil Puranam, Sridhar Dasaratha, Chetan Harsha, Shashishekar Ramakrishna</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CLEANANERCorp: Identifying and Correcting Incorrect Labels in the ANERcorp Dataset</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12362</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12362v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Label errors are a common issue in machine learning datasets, particularly for tasks such as Named Entity Recognition. Such label errors might hurt model training, affect evaluation results, and lead to an inaccurate assessment of model performance. In this study, we dived deep into one of the widely adopted Arabic NER benchmark datasets (ANERcorp) and found a significant number of annotation errors, missing labels, and inconsistencies. Therefore, in this study, we conducted empirical research to understand these errors, correct them and propose a cleaner version of the dataset named CLEANANERCorp. CLEANANERCorp will serve the research community as a more accurate and consistent benchmark.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12362v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>ELRA and ICCL 2024</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Mashael Al-Duwais, Hend Al-Khalifa, Abdulmalik Al-Salman</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Positional Description for Numerical Normalization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12430</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12430v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present a Positional Description Scheme (PDS) tailored for digit sequences, integrating placeholder value information for each digit. Given the structural limitations of subword tokenization algorithms, language models encounter critical Text Normalization (TN) challenges when handling numerical tasks. Our schema addresses this challenge through straightforward pre-processing, preserving the model architecture while significantly simplifying number normalization, rendering the problem tractable. This simplifies the task and facilitates more compact production-ready models capable of learning from smaller datasets. Furthermore, our investigations reveal that PDS enhances the arithmetic processing capabilities of language models, resulting in a relative accuracy improvement of 23% to 51% on complex arithmetic tasks. We demonstrate that PDS effectively mitigates fatal numerical normalization errors in neural models, requiring only a modest amount of training data without rule-based Finite State Transducers (FST). We demonstrate that PDS is essential for both the Text-To-Speech and Speech Recognition text processing, enabling effective TN under production constraints.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12430v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Deepanshu Gupta, Javier Latorre</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Multi-hop Reasoning through Knowledge Erasure in Large Language Model Editing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12456</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12456v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) face challenges with internal knowledge inaccuracies and outdated information. Knowledge editing has emerged as a pivotal approach to mitigate these issues. Although current knowledge editing techniques exhibit promising performance in single-hop reasoning tasks, they show limitations when applied to multi-hop reasoning. Drawing on cognitive neuroscience and the operational mechanisms of LLMs, we hypothesize that the residual single-hop knowledge after editing causes edited models to revert to their original answers when processing multi-hop questions, thereby undermining their performance in multihop reasoning tasks. To validate this hypothesis, we conduct a series of experiments that empirically confirm our assumptions. Building on the validated hypothesis, we propose a novel knowledge editing method that incorporates a Knowledge Erasure mechanism for Large language model Editing (KELE). Specifically, we design an erasure function for residual knowledge and an injection function for new knowledge. Through joint optimization, we derive the optimal recall vector, which is subsequently utilized within a rank-one editing framework to update the parameters of targeted model layers. Extensive experiments on GPT-J and GPT-2 XL demonstrate that KELE substantially enhances the multi-hop reasoning capability of edited LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12456v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mengqi Zhang, Bowen Fang, Qiang Liu, Pengjie Ren, Shu Wu, Zhumin Chen, Liang Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GenderCARE: A Comprehensive Framework for Assessing and Reducing Gender Bias in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12494</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12494v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have exhibited remarkable capabilities in natural language generation, but they have also been observed to magnify societal biases, particularly those related to gender. In response to this issue, several benchmarks have been proposed to assess gender bias in LLMs. However, these benchmarks often lack practical flexibility or inadvertently introduce biases. To address these shortcomings, we introduce GenderCARE, a comprehensive framework that encompasses innovative Criteria, bias Assessment, Reduction techniques, and Evaluation metrics for quantifying and mitigating gender bias in LLMs. To begin, we establish pioneering criteria for gender equality benchmarks, spanning dimensions such as inclusivity, diversity, explainability, objectivity, robustness, and realisticity. Guided by these criteria, we construct GenderPair, a novel pair-based benchmark designed to assess gender bias in LLMs comprehensively. Our benchmark provides standardized and realistic evaluations, including previously overlooked gender groups such as transgender and non-binary individuals. Furthermore, we develop effective debiasing techniques that incorporate counterfactual data augmentation and specialized fine-tuning strategies to reduce gender bias in LLMs without compromising their overall performance. Extensive experiments demonstrate a significant reduction in various gender bias benchmarks, with reductions peaking at over 90% and averaging above 35% across 17 different LLMs. Importantly, these reductions come with minimal variability in mainstream language tasks, remaining below 2%. By offering a realistic assessment and tailored reduction of gender biases, we hope that our GenderCARE can represent a significant step towards achieving fairness and equity in LLMs. More details are available at https://github.com/kstanghere/GenderCARE-ccs24.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12494v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kunsheng Tang, Wenbo Zhou, Jie Zhang, Aishan Liu, Gelei Deng, Shuai Li, Peigui Qi, Weiming Zhang, Tianwei Zhang, Nenghai Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Russian-focused embedders' exploration: ruMTEB benchmark and Russian embedding model design</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12503</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12503v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Embedding models play a crucial role in Natural Language Processing (NLP) by creating text embeddings used in various tasks such as information retrieval and assessing semantic text similarity. This paper focuses on research related to embedding models in the Russian language. It introduces a new Russian-focused embedding model called ru-en-RoSBERTa and the ruMTEB benchmark, the Russian version extending the Massive Text Embedding Benchmark (MTEB). Our benchmark includes seven categories of tasks, such as semantic textual similarity, text classification, reranking, and retrieval. The research also assesses a representative set of Russian and multilingual models on the proposed benchmark. The findings indicate that the new model achieves results that are on par with state-of-the-art models in Russian. We release the model ru-en-RoSBERTa, and the ruMTEB framework comes with open-source code, integration into the original framework and a public leaderboard.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12503v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Artem Snegirev, Maria Tikhonova, Anna Maksimova, Alena Fenogenova, Alexander Abramov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Evaluating and Building Versatile Large Language Models for Medicine</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12547</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12547v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this study, we present MedS-Bench, a comprehensive benchmark designed to evaluate the performance of large language models (LLMs) in clinical contexts. Unlike existing benchmarks that focus on multiple-choice question answering, MedS-Bench spans 11 high-level clinical tasks, including clinical report summarization, treatment recommendations, diagnosis, named entity recognition, and medical concept explanation, among others. We evaluated six leading LLMs, e.g., MEDITRON, Mistral, InternLM 2, Llama 3, GPT-4, and Claude-3.5 using few-shot prompting, and found that even the most sophisticated models struggle with these complex tasks. To address these limitations, we developed MedS-Ins, a large-scale instruction tuning dataset for medicine. MedS-Ins comprises 58 medically oriented language corpora, totaling 13.5 million samples across 122 tasks. To demonstrate the dataset's utility, we conducted a proof-of-concept experiment by performing instruction tuning on a lightweight, open-source medical language model. The resulting model, MMedIns-Llama 3, significantly outperformed existing models across nearly all clinical tasks. To promote further advancements in the application of LLMs to clinical challenges, we have made the MedS-Ins dataset fully accessible and invite the research community to contribute to its expansion.Additionally, we have launched a dynamic leaderboard for MedS-Bench, which we plan to regularly update the test set to track progress and enhance the adaptation of general LLMs to the medical domain. Leaderboard: https://henrychur.github.io/MedS-Bench/. Github: https://github.com/MAGIC-AI4Med/MedS-Ins.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12547v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chaoyi Wu, Pengcheng Qiu, Jinxin Liu, Hongfei Gu, Na Li, Ya Zhang, Yanfeng Wang, Weidi Xie</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jamba-1.5: Hybrid Transformer-Mamba Models at Scale</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12570</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12570v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present Jamba-1.5, new instruction-tuned large language models based on our Jamba architecture. Jamba is a hybrid Transformer-Mamba mixture of experts architecture, providing high throughput and low memory usage across context lengths, while retaining the same or better quality as Transformer models. We release two model sizes: Jamba-1.5-Large, with 94B active parameters, and Jamba-1.5-Mini, with 12B active parameters. Both models are fine-tuned for a variety of conversational and instruction-following capabilties, and have an effective context length of 256K tokens, the largest amongst open-weight models. To support cost-effective inference, we introduce ExpertsInt8, a novel quantization technique that allows fitting Jamba-1.5-Large on a machine with 8 80GB GPUs when processing 256K-token contexts without loss of quality. When evaluated on a battery of academic and chatbot benchmarks, Jamba-1.5 models achieve excellent results while providing high throughput and outperforming other open-weight models on long-context benchmarks. The model weights for both sizes are publicly available under the Jamba Open Model License and we release ExpertsInt8 as open source.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12570v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator> Jamba Team, Barak Lenz, Alan Arazi, Amir Bergman, Avshalom Manevich, Barak Peleg, Ben Aviram, Chen Almagor, Clara Fridman, Dan Padnos, Daniel Gissin, Daniel Jannai, Dor Muhlgay, Dor Zimberg, Edden M Gerber, Elad Dolev, Eran Krakovsky, Erez Safahi, Erez Schwartz, Gal Cohen, Gal Shachaf, Haim Rozenblum, Hofit Bata, Ido Blass, Inbal Magar, Itay Dalmedigos, Jhonathan Osin, Julie Fadlon, Maria Rozman, Matan Danos, Michael Gokhman, Mor Zusman, Naama Gidron, Nir Ratner, Noam Gat, Noam Rozen, Oded Fried, Ohad Leshno, Omer Antverg, Omri Abend, Opher Lieber, Or Dagan, Orit Cohavi, Raz Alon, Ro'i Belson, Roi Cohen, Rom Gilad, Roman Glozman, Shahar Lev, Shaked Meirom, Tal Delbari, Tal Ness, Tomer Asida, Tom Ben Gal, Tom Braude, Uriya Pumerantz, Yehoshua Cohen, Yonatan Belinkov, Yuval Globerson, Yuval Peleg Levy, Yoav Shoham</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RuleAlign: Making Large Language Models Better Physicians with Diagnostic Rule Alignment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12579</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12579v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) like GPT-4, MedPaLM-2, and Med-Gemini achieve performance competitively with human experts across various medical benchmarks. However, they still face challenges in making professional diagnoses akin to physicians, particularly in efficiently gathering patient information and reasoning the final diagnosis. To this end, we introduce the RuleAlign framework, designed to align LLMs with specific diagnostic rules. We develop a medical dialogue dataset comprising rule-based communications between patients and physicians and design an alignment learning approach through preference learning. Experimental results demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed approach. We hope that our work can serve as an inspiration for exploring the potential of LLMs as AI physicians.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12579v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaohan Wang, Xiaoyan Yang, Yuqi Zhu, Yue Shen, Jian Wang, Peng Wei, Lei Liang, Jinjie Gu, Huajun Chen, Ningyu Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controllable Text Generation for Large Language Models: A Survey</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12599</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12599v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In Natural Language Processing (NLP), Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated high text generation quality. However, in real-world applications, LLMs must meet increasingly complex requirements. Beyond avoiding misleading or inappropriate content, LLMs are also expected to cater to specific user needs, such as imitating particular writing styles or generating text with poetic richness. These varied demands have driven the development of Controllable Text Generation (CTG) techniques, which ensure that outputs adhere to predefined control conditions--such as safety, sentiment, thematic consistency, and linguistic style--while maintaining high standards of helpfulness, fluency, and diversity.
  This paper systematically reviews the latest advancements in CTG for LLMs, offering a comprehensive definition of its core concepts and clarifying the requirements for control conditions and text quality. We categorize CTG tasks into two primary types: content control and attribute control. The key methods are discussed, including model retraining, fine-tuning, reinforcement learning, prompt engineering, latent space manipulation, and decoding-time intervention. We analyze each method's characteristics, advantages, and limitations, providing nuanced insights for achieving generation control. Additionally, we review CTG evaluation methods, summarize its applications across domains, and address key challenges in current research, including reduced fluency and practicality. We also propose several appeals, such as placing greater emphasis on real-world applications in future research. This paper aims to offer valuable guidance to researchers and developers in the field. Our reference list and Chinese version are open-sourced at https://github.com/IAAR-Shanghai/CTGSurvey.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12599v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xun Liang, Hanyu Wang, Yezhaohui Wang, Shichao Song, Jiawei Yang, Simin Niu, Jie Hu, Dan Liu, Shunyu Yao, Feiyu Xiong, Zhiyu Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Could ChatGPT get an Engineering Degree? Evaluating Higher Education Vulnerability to AI Assistants</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11841</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11841v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: AI assistants are being increasingly used by students enrolled in higher education institutions. While these tools provide opportunities for improved teaching and education, they also pose significant challenges for assessment and learning outcomes. We conceptualize these challenges through the lens of vulnerability, the potential for university assessments and learning outcomes to be impacted by student use of generative AI. We investigate the potential scale of this vulnerability by measuring the degree to which AI assistants can complete assessment questions in standard university-level STEM courses. Specifically, we compile a novel dataset of textual assessment questions from 50 courses at EPFL and evaluate whether two AI assistants, GPT-3.5 and GPT-4 can adequately answer these questions. We use eight prompting strategies to produce responses and find that GPT-4 answers an average of 65.8% of questions correctly, and can even produce the correct answer across at least one prompting strategy for 85.1% of questions. When grouping courses in our dataset by degree program, these systems already pass non-project assessments of large numbers of core courses in various degree programs, posing risks to higher education accreditation that will be amplified as these models improve. Our results call for revising program-level assessment design in higher education in light of advances in generative AI.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11841v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Beatriz Borges, Negar Foroutan, Deniz Bayazit, Anna Sotnikova, Syrielle Montariol, Tanya Nazaretzky, Mohammadreza Banaei, Alireza Sakhaeirad, Philippe Servant, Seyed Parsa Neshaei, Jibril Frej, Angelika Romanou, Gail Weiss, Sepideh Mamooler, Zeming Chen, Simin Fan, Silin Gao, Mete Ismayilzada, Debjit Paul, Alexandre Sch\"opfer, Andrej Janchevski, Anja Tiede, Clarence Linden, Emanuele Troiani, Francesco Salvi, Freya Behrens, Giacomo Orsi, Giovanni Piccioli, Hadrien Sevel, Louis Coulon, Manuela Pineros-Rodriguez, Marin Bonnassies, Pierre Hellich, Puck van Gerwen, Sankalp Gambhir, Solal Pirelli, Thomas Blanchard, Timoth\'ee Callens, Toni Abi Aoun, Yannick Calvino Alonso, Yuri Cho, Alberto Chiappa, Antonio Sclocchi, \'Etienne Bruno, Florian Hofhammer, Gabriel Pescia, Geovani Rizk, Leello Dadi, Lucas Stoffl, Manoel Horta Ribeiro, Matthieu Bovel, Yueyang Pan, Aleksandra Radenovic, Alexandre Alahi, Alexander Mathis, Anne-Florence Bitbol, Boi Faltings, C\'ecile H\'ebert, Devis Tuia, Fran\c{c}ois Mar\'echal, George Candea, Giuseppe Carleo, Jean-C\'edric Chappelier, Nicolas Flammarion, Jean-Marie F\"urbringer, Jean-Philippe Pellet, Karl Aberer, Lenka Zdeborov\'a, Marcel Salath\'e, Martin Jaggi, Martin Rajman, Mathias Payer, Matthieu Wyart, Michael Gastpar, Michele Ceriotti, Ola Svensson, Olivier L\'ev\^eque, Paolo Ienne, Rachid Guerraoui, Robert West, Sanidhya Kashyap, Valerio Piazza, Viesturs Simanis, Viktor Kuncak, Volkan Cevher, Philippe Schwaller, Sacha Friedli, Patrick Jermann, Tanja Kaser, Antoine Bosselut</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAGE-RT: Synthetic Alignment data Generation for Safety Evaluation and Red Teaming</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11851</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11851v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We introduce Synthetic Alignment data Generation for Safety Evaluation and Red Teaming (SAGE-RT or SAGE) a novel pipeline for generating synthetic alignment and red-teaming data. Existing methods fall short in creating nuanced and diverse datasets, providing necessary control over the data generation and validation processes, or require large amount of manually generated seed data. SAGE addresses these limitations by using a detailed taxonomy to produce safety-alignment and red-teaming data across a wide range of topics. We generated 51,000 diverse and in-depth prompt-response pairs, encompassing over 1,500 topics of harmfulness and covering variations of the most frequent types of jailbreaking prompts faced by large language models (LLMs). We show that the red-teaming data generated through SAGE jailbreaks state-of-the-art LLMs in more than 27 out of 32 sub-categories, and in more than 58 out of 279 leaf-categories (sub-sub categories). The attack success rate for GPT-4o, GPT-3.5-turbo is 100% over the sub-categories of harmfulness. Our approach avoids the pitfalls of synthetic safety-training data generation such as mode collapse and lack of nuance in the generation pipeline by ensuring a detailed coverage of harmful topics using iterative expansion of the topics and conditioning the outputs on the generated raw-text. This method can be used to generate red-teaming and alignment data for LLM Safety completely synthetically to make LLMs safer or for red-teaming the models over a diverse range of topics.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11851v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Anurakt Kumar, Divyanshu Kumar, Jatan Loya, Nitin Aravind Birur, Tanay Baswa, Sahil Agarwal, Prashanth Harshangi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling Text Generation in LLMs: A Stochastic Differential Equation Approach</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11863</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11863v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This paper explores the application of Stochastic Differential Equations (SDE) to interpret the text generation process of Large Language Models (LLMs) such as GPT-4. Text generation in LLMs is modeled as a stochastic process where each step depends on previously generated content and model parameters, sampling the next word from a vocabulary distribution. We represent this generation process using SDE to capture both deterministic trends and stochastic perturbations. The drift term describes the deterministic trends in the generation process, while the diffusion term captures the stochastic variations. We fit these functions using neural networks and validate the model on real-world text corpora. Through numerical simulations and comprehensive analyses, including drift and diffusion analysis, stochastic process property evaluation, and phase space exploration, we provide deep insights into the dynamics of text generation. This approach not only enhances the understanding of the inner workings of LLMs but also offers a novel mathematical perspective on language generation, which is crucial for diagnosing, optimizing, and controlling the quality of generated text.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11863v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yukun Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characterizing Online Toxicity During the 2022 Mpox Outbreak: A Computational Analysis of Topical and Network Dynamics</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11962</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11962v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Background: Online toxicity, encompassing behaviors such as harassment, bullying, hate speech, and the dissemination of misinformation, has become a pressing social concern in the digital age. The 2022 Mpox outbreak, initially termed "Monkeypox" but subsequently renamed to mitigate associated stigmas and societal concerns, serves as a poignant backdrop to this issue. Objective: In this research, we undertake a comprehensive analysis of the toxic online discourse surrounding the 2022 Mpox outbreak. Our objective is to dissect its origins, characterize its nature and content, trace its dissemination patterns, and assess its broader societal implications, with the goal of providing insights that can inform strategies to mitigate such toxicity in future crises. Methods: We collected more than 1.6 million unique tweets and analyzed them from five dimensions, including context, extent, content, speaker, and intent. Utilizing BERT-based topic modeling and social network community clustering, we delineated the toxic dynamics on Twitter. Results: We identified five high-level topic categories in the toxic online discourse on Twitter, including disease (46.6%), health policy and healthcare (19.3%), homophobia (23.9%), politics (6.0%), and racism (4.1%). Through the toxicity diffusion networks of mentions, retweets, and the top users, we found that retweets of toxic content were widespread, while influential users rarely engaged with or countered this toxicity through retweets. Conclusions: By tracking topical dynamics, we can track the changing popularity of toxic content online, providing a better understanding of societal challenges. Network dynamics spotlight key social media influencers and their intents, indicating that addressing these central figures in toxic discourse can enhance crisis communication and inform policy-making.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11962v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lizhou Fan, Lingyao Li, Libby Hemphill</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Limitations in Employing Natural Language Supervision for Sensor-Based Human Activity Recognition -- And Ways to Overcome Them</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12023</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12023v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Cross-modal contrastive pre-training between natural language and other modalities, e.g., vision and audio, has demonstrated astonishing performance and effectiveness across a diverse variety of tasks and domains. In this paper, we investigate whether such natural language supervision can be used for wearable sensor based Human Activity Recognition (HAR), and discover that-surprisingly-it performs substantially worse than standard end-to-end training and self-supervision. We identify the primary causes for this as: sensor heterogeneity and the lack of rich, diverse text descriptions of activities. To mitigate their impact, we also develop strategies and assess their effectiveness through an extensive experimental evaluation. These strategies lead to significant increases in activity recognition, bringing performance closer to supervised and self-supervised training, while also enabling the recognition of unseen activities and cross modal retrieval of videos. Overall, our work paves the way for better sensor-language learning, ultimately leading to the development of foundational models for HAR using wearables.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12023v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Harish Haresamudram, Apoorva Beedu, Mashfiqui Rabbi, Sankalita Saha, Irfan Essa, Thomas Ploetz</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let Community Rules Be Reflected in Online Content Moderation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12035</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12035v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Content moderation is a widely used strategy to prevent the dissemination of irregular information on social media platforms. Despite extensive research on developing automated models to support decision-making in content moderation, there remains a notable scarcity of studies that integrate the rules of online communities into content moderation. This study addresses this gap by proposing a community rule-based content moderation framework that directly integrates community rules into the moderation of user-generated content. Our experiment results with datasets collected from two domains demonstrate the superior performance of models based on the framework to baseline models across all evaluation metrics. In particular, incorporating community rules substantially enhances model performance in content moderation. The findings of this research have significant research and practical implications for improving the effectiveness and generalizability of content moderation models in online communities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12035v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wangjiaxuan Xin, Kanlun Wang, Zhe Fu, Lina Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reasoning and Tools for Human-Level Forecasting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12036</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12036v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Language models (LMs) trained on web-scale datasets are largely successful due to their ability to memorize large amounts of training data, even if only present in a few examples. These capabilities are often desirable in evaluation on tasks such as question answering but raise questions about whether these models can exhibit genuine reasoning or succeed only at mimicking patterns from the training data. This distinction is particularly salient in forecasting tasks, where the answer is not present in the training data, and the model must reason to make logical deductions. We present Reasoning and Tools for Forecasting (RTF), a framework of reasoning-and-acting (ReAct) agents that can dynamically retrieve updated information and run numerical simulation with equipped tools. We evaluate our model with questions from competitive forecasting platforms and demonstrate that our method is competitive with and can outperform human predictions. This suggests that LMs, with the right tools, can indeed think and adapt like humans, offering valuable insights for real-world decision-making.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12036v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Elvis Hsieh, Preston Fu, Jonathan Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extraction of Research Objectives, Machine Learning Model Names, and Dataset Names from Academic Papers and Analysis of Their Interrelationships Using LLM and Network Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12097</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12097v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Machine learning is widely utilized across various industries. Identifying the appropriate machine learning models and datasets for specific tasks is crucial for the effective industrial application of machine learning. However, this requires expertise in both machine learning and the relevant domain, leading to a high learning cost. Therefore, research focused on extracting combinations of tasks, machine learning models, and datasets from academic papers is critically important, as it can facilitate the automatic recommendation of suitable methods. Conventional information extraction methods from academic papers have been limited to identifying machine learning models and other entities as named entities. To address this issue, this study proposes a methodology extracting tasks, machine learning methods, and dataset names from scientific papers and analyzing the relationships between these information by using LLM, embedding model, and network clustering. The proposed method's expression extraction performance, when using Llama3, achieves an F-score exceeding 0.8 across various categories, confirming its practical utility. Benchmarking results on financial domain papers have demonstrated the effectiveness of this method, providing insights into the use of the latest datasets, including those related to ESG (Environmental, Social, and Governance) data.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12097v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>S. Nishio, H. Nonaka, N. Tsuchiya, A. Migita, Y. Banno, T. Hayashi, H. Sakaji, T. Sakumoto, K. Watabe</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RoVRM: A Robust Visual Reward Model Optimized via Auxiliary Textual Preference Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12109</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12109v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large vision-language models (LVLMs) often fail to align with human preferences, leading to issues like generating misleading content without proper visual context (also known as hallucination). A promising solution to this problem is using human-preference alignment techniques, such as best-of-n sampling and reinforcement learning. However, these techniques face the difficulty arising from the scarcity of visual preference data, which is required to train a visual reward model (VRM). In this work, we continue the line of research. We present a Robust Visual Reward Model (RoVRM) which improves human-preference alignment for LVLMs. RoVRM leverages auxiliary textual preference data through a three-phase progressive training and optimal transport-based preference data selection to effectively mitigate the scarcity of visual preference data. We experiment with RoVRM on the commonly used vision-language tasks based on the LLaVA-1.5-7B and -13B models. Experimental results demonstrate that RoVRM consistently outperforms traditional VRMs. Furthermore, our three-phase progressive training and preference data selection approaches can yield consistent performance gains over ranking-based alignment techniques, such as direct preference optimization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12109v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chenglong Wang, Yang Gan, Yifu Huo, Yongyu Mu, Murun Yang, Qiaozhi He, Tong Xiao, Chunliang Zhang, Tongran Liu, Quan Du, Di Yang, Jingbo Zhu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Tighter Complexity Analysis of SparseGPT</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12151</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12151v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In this work, we improved the analysis of the running time of SparseGPT [Frantar, Alistarh ICML 2023] from $O(d^{3})$ to $O(d^{\omega} + d^{2+a+o(1)} + d^{1+\omega(1,1,a)-a})$ for any $a \in [0, 1]$, where $\omega$ is the exponent of matrix multiplication. In particular, for the current $\omega \approx 2.371$ [Alman, Duan, Williams, Xu, Xu, Zhou 2024], our running times boil down to $O(d^{2.53})$. This running time is due to the analysis of the lazy update behavior in iterative maintenance problems, such as [Deng, Song, Weinstein 2022, Brand, Song, Zhou ICML 2024].</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12151v1</guid>
      <category>cs.DS</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoyu Li, Yingyu Liang, Zhenmei Shi, Zhao Song</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Search-Based LLMs for Code Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12159</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12159v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The code written by developers usually suffers from efficiency problems and contain various performance bugs. These inefficiencies necessitate the research of automated refactoring methods for code optimization. Early research in code optimization employs rule-based methods and focuses on specific inefficiency issues, which are labor-intensive and suffer from the low coverage issue. Recent work regards the task as a sequence generation problem, and resorts to deep learning (DL) techniques such as large language models (LLMs). These methods typically prompt LLMs to directly generate optimized code. Although these methods show state-of-the-art performance, such one-step generation paradigm is hard to achieve an optimal solution. First, complex optimization methods such as combinatorial ones are hard to be captured by LLMs. Second, the one-step generation paradigm poses challenge in precisely infusing the knowledge required for effective code optimization within LLMs, resulting in under-optimized code.To address these problems, we propose to model this task from the search perspective, and propose a search-based LLMs framework named SBLLM that enables iterative refinement and discovery of improved optimization methods. SBLLM synergistically integrate LLMs with evolutionary search and consists of three key components: 1) an execution-based representative sample selection part that evaluates the fitness of each existing optimized code and prioritizes promising ones to pilot the generation of improved code; 2) an adaptive optimization pattern retrieval part that infuses targeted optimization patterns into the model for guiding LLMs towards rectifying and progressively enhancing their optimization methods; and 3) a genetic operator-inspired chain-of-thought prompting part that aids LLMs in combining different optimization methods and generating improved optimization methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12159v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shuzheng Gao, Cuiyun Gao, Wenchao Gu, Michael Lyu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Language Models Are Self-Taught Reasoners: Enhancing LLM Applications via Tailored Problem-Solving Demonstrations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12315</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12315v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Guiding large language models with a selected set of human-authored demonstrations is a common practice for improving LLM applications. However, human effort can be costly, especially in specialized domains (e.g., clinical diagnosis), and does not guarantee optimal performance due to the potential discrepancy of target skills between selected demonstrations and real test instances. Motivated by these, this paper explores the automatic creation of customized demonstrations, whose target skills align with the given target instance. We present SELF-TAUGHT, a problem-solving framework, which facilitates demonstrations that are "tailored" to the target problem and "filtered" for better quality (i.e., correctness) in a zero-shot manner. In 15 tasks of multiple-choice questions of diverse domains and the diagnosis of Alzheimer's disease (AD) with real-world patients, SELF-TAUGHT achieves superior performance to strong baselines (e.g., Few-shot CoT, Plan-and-Solve, Auto-CoT). We conduct comprehensive analyses on SELF-TAUGHT, including its generalizability to existing prompting methods and different LLMs, the quality of its intermediate generation, and more.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12315v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kai Tzu-iunn Ong, Taeyoon Kwon, Jinyoung Yeo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comparative Analysis of Faithfulness Metrics and Humans in Citation Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12398</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12398v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) often generate content with unsupported or unverifiable content, known as "hallucinations." To address this, retrieval-augmented LLMs are employed to include citations in their content, grounding the content in verifiable sources. Despite such developments, manually assessing how well a citation supports the associated statement remains a major challenge. Previous studies tackle this challenge by leveraging faithfulness metrics to estimate citation support automatically. However, they limit this citation support estimation to a binary classification scenario, neglecting fine-grained citation support in practical scenarios. To investigate the effectiveness of faithfulness metrics in fine-grained scenarios, we propose a comparative evaluation framework that assesses the metric effectiveness in distinguishing citations between three-category support levels: full, partial, and no support. Our framework employs correlation analysis, classification evaluation, and retrieval evaluation to measure the alignment between metric scores and human judgments comprehensively. Our results indicate no single metric consistently excels across all evaluations, highlighting the complexity of accurately evaluating fine-grained support levels. Particularly, we find that the best-performing metrics struggle to distinguish partial support from full or no support. Based on these findings, we provide practical recommendations for developing more effective metrics.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12398v1</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weijia Zhang, Mohammad Aliannejadi, Jiahuan Pei, Yifei Yuan, Jia-Hong Huang, Evangelos Kanoulas</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vintern-1B: An Efficient Multimodal Large Language Model for Vietnamese</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12480</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12480v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In this report, we introduce Vintern-1B, a reliable 1-billion-parameters multimodal large language model (MLLM) for Vietnamese language tasks. By integrating the Qwen2-0.5B-Instruct language model with the InternViT-300M-448px visual model, Vintern-1B is optimized for a range of applications, including optical character recognition (OCR), document extraction, and general question-answering in Vietnamese context. The model is fine-tuned on an extensive dataset of over 3 million image-question-answer pairs, achieving robust performance and reliable results across multiple Vietnamese language benchmarks like OpenViVQA and ViTextVQA. Vintern-1B is small enough to fit into various on-device applications easily. Additionally, we have open-sourced several Vietnamese vision question answering (VQA) datasets for text and diagrams, created with Gemini 1.5 Flash. Our models are available at: https://huggingface.co/5CD-AI/Vintern-1B-v2.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12480v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Khang T. Doan, Bao G. Huynh, Dung T. Hoang, Thuc D. Pham, Nhat H. Pham, Quan T. M. Nguyen, Bang Q. Vo, Suong N. Hoang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MuMA-ToM: Multi-modal Multi-Agent Theory of Mind</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12574</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12574v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Understanding people's social interactions in complex real-world scenarios often relies on intricate mental reasoning. To truly understand how and why people interact with one another, we must infer the underlying mental states that give rise to the social interactions, i.e., Theory of Mind reasoning in multi-agent interactions. Additionally, social interactions are often multi-modal -- we can watch people's actions, hear their conversations, and/or read about their past behaviors. For AI systems to successfully and safely interact with people in real-world environments, they also need to understand people's mental states as well as their inferences about each other's mental states based on multi-modal information about their interactions. For this, we introduce MuMA-ToM, a Multi-modal Multi-Agent Theory of Mind benchmark. MuMA-ToM is the first multi-modal Theory of Mind benchmark that evaluates mental reasoning in embodied multi-agent interactions. In MuMA-ToM, we provide video and text descriptions of people's multi-modal behavior in realistic household environments. Based on the context, we then ask questions about people's goals, beliefs, and beliefs about others' goals. We validated MuMA-ToM in a human experiment and provided a human baseline. We also proposed a novel multi-modal, multi-agent ToM model, LIMP (Language model-based Inverse Multi-agent Planning). Our experimental results show that LIMP significantly outperforms state-of-the-art methods, including large multi-modal models (e.g., GPT-4o, Gemini-1.5 Pro) and a recent multi-modal ToM model, BIP-ALM.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12574v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haojun Shi, Suyu Ye, Xinyu Fang, Chuanyang Jin, Layla Isik, Yen-Ling Kuo, Tianmin Shu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Topics as Entity Clusters: Entity-based Topics from Large Language Models and Graph Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2301.02458</link>
      <description>arXiv:2301.02458v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Topic models aim to reveal latent structures within a corpus of text, typically through the use of term-frequency statistics over bag-of-words representations from documents. In recent years, conceptual entities -- interpretable, language-independent features linked to external knowledge resources -- have been used in place of word-level tokens, as words typically require extensive language processing with a minimal assurance of interpretability. However, current literature is limited when it comes to exploring purely entity-driven neural topic modeling. For instance, despite the advantages of using entities for eliciting thematic structure, it is unclear whether current techniques are compatible with these sparsely organised, information-dense conceptual units. In this work, we explore entity-based neural topic modeling and propose a novel topic clustering approach using bimodal vector representations of entities. Concretely, we extract these latent representations from large language models and graph neural networks trained on a knowledge base of symbolic relations, in order to derive the most salient aspects of these conceptual units. Analysis of coherency metrics confirms that our approach is better suited to working with entities in comparison to state-of-the-art models, particularly when using graph-based embeddings trained on a knowledge base.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2301.02458v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Manuel V. Loureiro, Steven Derby, Tri Kurniawan Wijaya</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can we trust the evaluation on ChatGPT?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2303.12767</link>
      <description>arXiv:2303.12767v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: ChatGPT, the first large language model (LLM) with mass adoption, has demonstrated remarkable performance in numerous natural language tasks. Despite its evident usefulness, evaluating ChatGPT's performance in diverse problem domains remains challenging due to the closed nature of the model and its continuous updates via Reinforcement Learning from Human Feedback (RLHF). We highlight the issue of data contamination in ChatGPT evaluations, with a case study of the task of stance detection. We discuss the challenge of preventing data contamination and ensuring fair model evaluation in the age of closed and continuously trained models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2303.12767v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.18653/v1/2023.trustnlp-1.5</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Proceedings of the 3rd Workshop on Trustworthy Natural Language Processing (TrustNLP 2023) (July 2023) 47-54</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Rachith Aiyappa, Jisun An, Haewoon Kwak, Yong-Yeol Ahn</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPICED: News Similarity Detection Dataset with Multiple Topics and Complexity Levels</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2309.13080</link>
      <description>arXiv:2309.13080v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The proliferation of news media outlets has increased the demand for intelligent systems capable of detecting redundant information in news articles in order to enhance user experience. However, the heterogeneous nature of news can lead to spurious findings in these systems: Simple heuristics such as whether a pair of news are both about politics can provide strong but deceptive downstream performance. Segmenting news similarity datasets into topics improves the training of these models by forcing them to learn how to distinguish salient characteristics under more narrow domains. However, this requires the existence of topic-specific datasets, which are currently lacking. In this article, we propose a novel dataset of similar news, SPICED, which includes seven topics: Crime &amp; Law, Culture &amp; Entertainment, Disasters &amp; Accidents, Economy &amp; Business, Politics &amp; Conflicts, Science &amp; Technology, and Sports. Futhermore, we present four different levels of complexity, specifically designed for news similarity detection task. We benchmarked the created datasets using MinHash, BERT, SBERT, and SimCSE models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2309.13080v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Elena Shushkevich, Long Mai, Manuel V. Loureiro, Steven Derby, Tri Kurniawan Wijaya</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KLoB: a Benchmark for Assessing Knowledge Locating Methods in Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2309.16535</link>
      <description>arXiv:2309.16535v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recently, Locate-Then-Edit paradigm has emerged as one of the main approaches in changing factual knowledge stored in the Language models. However, there is a lack of research on whether present locating methods can pinpoint the exact parameters embedding the desired knowledge. Moreover, although many researchers have questioned the validity of locality hypothesis of factual knowledge, no method is provided to test the a hypothesis for more in-depth discussion and research. Therefore, we introduce KLoB, a benchmark examining three essential properties that a reliable knowledge locating method should satisfy. KLoB can serve as a benchmark for evaluating existing locating methods in language models, and can contributes a method to reassessing the validity of locality hypothesis of factual knowledge. KLoB is publicly available at an anonymous GitHub: \url{https://github.com/anon6662/KLoB}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2309.16535v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yiming Ju, Xingrun Xing, Zhixiong Zeng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Early Detection of Hallucinations in Factual Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.14183</link>
      <description>arXiv:2312.14183v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: While large language models (LLMs) have taken great strides towards helping humans with a plethora of tasks, hallucinations remain a major impediment towards gaining user trust. The fluency and coherence of model generations even when hallucinating makes detection a difficult task. In this work, we explore if the artifacts associated with the model generations can provide hints that the generation will contain hallucinations. Specifically, we probe LLMs at 1) the inputs via Integrated Gradients based token attribution, 2) the outputs via the Softmax probabilities, and 3) the internal state via self-attention and fully-connected layer activations for signs of hallucinations on open-ended question answering tasks. Our results show that the distributions of these artifacts tend to differ between hallucinated and non-hallucinated generations. Building on this insight, we train binary classifiers that use these artifacts as input features to classify model generations into hallucinations and non-hallucinations. These hallucination classifiers achieve up to $0.80$ AUROC. We also show that tokens preceding a hallucination can already predict the subsequent hallucination even before it occurs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2312.14183v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3637528.3671796</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Ben Snyder, Marius Moisescu, Muhammad Bilal Zafar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generalizing Visual Question Answering from Synthetic to Human-Written Questions via a Chain of QA with a Large Language Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.06400</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.06400v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Visual question answering (VQA) is a task where an image is given, and a series of questions are asked about the image. To build an efficient VQA algorithm, a large amount of QA data is required which is very expensive. Generating synthetic QA pairs based on templates is a practical way to obtain data. However, VQA models trained on those data do not perform well on complex, human-written questions. To address this issue, we propose a new method called {\it chain of QA for human-written questions} (CoQAH). CoQAH utilizes a sequence of QA interactions between a large language model and a VQA model trained on synthetic data to reason and derive logical answers for human-written questions. We tested the effectiveness of CoQAH on two types of human-written VQA datasets for 3D-rendered and chest X-ray images and found that it achieved state-of-the-art accuracy in both types of data. Notably, CoQAH outperformed general vision-language models, VQA models, and medical foundation models with no finetuning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.06400v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Taehee Kim, Yeongjae Cho, Heejun Shin, Yohan Jo, Dongmyung Shin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Curious Case of Nonverbal Abstract Reasoning with Multi-Modal Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12117</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.12117v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: While large language models (LLMs) are still being adopted to new domains and utilized in novel applications, we are experiencing an influx of the new generation of foundation models, namely multi-modal large language models (MLLMs). These models integrate verbal and visual information, opening new possibilities to demonstrate more complex reasoning abilities at the intersection of the two modalities. However, despite the revolutionizing prospect of MLLMs, our understanding of their reasoning abilities is limited. In this study, we assess the nonverbal abstract reasoning abilities of open-source and closed-source MLLMs using variations of Raven's Progressive Matrices. Our experiments reveal the challenging nature of such problems for MLLMs while showcasing the immense gap between open-source and closed-source models. We also uncover critical shortcomings of visual and textual perceptions, subjecting the models to low-performance ceilings. Finally, to improve MLLMs' performance, we experiment with different methods, such as Chain-of-Thought prompting, leading to a significant (up to 100%) boost in performance. Our code and datasets are available at https://github.com/usc-isi-i2/isi-mmlm-rpm.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.12117v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kian Ahrabian, Zhivar Sourati, Kexuan Sun, Jiarui Zhang, Yifan Jiang, Fred Morstatter, Jay Pujara</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dependency Annotation of Ottoman Turkish with Multilingual BERT</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.14743</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.14743v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This study introduces a pretrained large language model-based annotation methodology for the first de dency treebank in Ottoman Turkish. Our experimental results show that, iteratively, i) pseudo-annotating data using a multilingual BERT-based parsing model, ii) manually correcting the pseudo-annotations, and iii) fine-tuning the parsing model with the corrected annotations, we speed up and simplify the challenging dependency annotation process. The resulting treebank, that will be a part of the Universal Dependencies (UD) project, will facilitate automated analysis of Ottoman Turkish documents, unlocking the linguistic richness embedded in this historical heritage.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.14743v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>\c{S}aziye Bet\"ul \"Ozate\c{s}, Tar{\i}k T{\i}ra\c{s}, Efe Gen\c{c}, and Esma Bilgin Ta\c{s}demir. 2024. Dependency Annotation of Ottoman Turkish with Multilingual BERT. LAW-XVIII, pages 188-196, St. Julians, Malta</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>\c{S}aziye Bet\"ul \"Ozate\c{s}, Tar{\i}k Emre T{\i}ra\c{s}, Efe Eren Gen\c{c}, Esma Fat{\i}ma Bilgin Ta\c{s}demir</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM2Vec: Large Language Models Are Secretly Powerful Text Encoders</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.05961</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.05961v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large decoder-only language models (LLMs) are the state-of-the-art models on most of today's NLP tasks and benchmarks. Yet, the community is only slowly adopting these models for text embedding tasks, which require rich contextualized representations. In this work, we introduce LLM2Vec, a simple unsupervised approach that can transform any decoder-only LLM into a strong text encoder. LLM2Vec consists of three simple steps: 1) enabling bidirectional attention, 2) masked next token prediction, and 3) unsupervised contrastive learning. We demonstrate the effectiveness of LLM2Vec by applying it to 4 popular LLMs ranging from 1.3B to 8B parameters and evaluate the transformed models on English word- and sequence-level tasks. We outperform encoder-only models by a large margin on word-level tasks and reach a new unsupervised state-of-the-art performance on the Massive Text Embeddings Benchmark (MTEB). Moreover, when combining LLM2Vec with supervised contrastive learning, we achieve state-of-the-art performance on MTEB among models that train only on publicly available data (as of May 24, 2024). Our strong empirical results and extensive analysis demonstrate that LLMs can be effectively transformed into universal text encoders in a parameter-efficient manner without the need for expensive adaptation or synthetic GPT-4 generated data.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.05961v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Parishad BehnamGhader, Vaibhav Adlakha, Marius Mosbach, Dzmitry Bahdanau, Nicolas Chapados, Siva Reddy</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering Latent Arguments in Social Media Messaging by Employing LLMs-in-the-Loop Strategy</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.10259</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.10259v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The widespread use of social media has led to a surge in popularity for automated methods of analyzing public opinion. Supervised methods are adept at text categorization, yet the dynamic nature of social media discussions poses a continual challenge for these techniques due to the constant shifting of the focus. On the other hand, traditional unsupervised methods for extracting themes from public discourse, such as topic modeling, often reveal overarching patterns that might not capture specific nuances. Consequently, a significant portion of research into social media discourse still depends on labor-intensive manual coding techniques and a human-in-the-loop approach, which are both time-consuming and costly. In this work, we study the problem of discovering arguments associated with a specific theme. We propose a generic LLMs-in-the-Loop strategy that leverages the advanced capabilities of Large Language Models (LLMs) to extract latent arguments from social media messaging. To demonstrate our approach, we apply our framework to contentious topics. We use two publicly available datasets: (1) the climate campaigns dataset of 14k Facebook ads with 25 themes and (2) the COVID-19 vaccine campaigns dataset of 9k Facebook ads with 14 themes. Additionally, we design a downstream task as stance prediction by leveraging talking points in climate debates. Furthermore, we analyze demographic targeting and the adaptation of messaging based on real-world events.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.10259v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tunazzina Islam, Dan Goldwasser</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SUBLLM: A Novel Efficient Architecture with Token Sequence Subsampling for LLM</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.06571</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.06571v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: While Large Language Models (LLMs) have achieved remarkable success in various fields, the efficiency of training and inference remains a major challenge. To address this issue, we propose SUBLLM, short for Subsampling-Upsampling-Bypass Large Language Model, an innovative architecture that extends the core decoder-only framework by incorporating subsampling, upsampling, and bypass modules. The subsampling modules are responsible for shortening the sequence, while the upsampling modules restore the sequence length, and the bypass modules enhance convergence. In comparison to LLaMA, the proposed SUBLLM exhibits significant enhancements in both training and inference speeds as well as memory usage, while maintaining competitive few-shot performance. During training, SUBLLM increases speeds by 26% and cuts memory by 10GB per GPU. In inference, it boosts speeds by up to 37% and reduces memory by 1GB per GPU. The training and inference speeds can be enhanced by 34% and 52% respectively when the context window is expanded to 8192. Our code is available at https://github.com/XiaoMi/subllm.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.06571v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Quandong Wang, Yuxuan Yuan, Xiaoyu Yang, Ruike Zhang, Kang Zhao, Wei Liu, Jian Luan, Daniel Povey, Bin Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Reference Policies in Direct Preference Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.13709</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.13709v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Direct Preference Optimization (DPO) has become a widely used training method for the instruction fine-tuning of large language models (LLMs). In this work, we explore an under-investigated aspect of DPO - its dependency on the reference model or policy. Such reference policies, typically instantiated as the model to be further fine-tuned, are important since they can impose an upper limit on DPO's effectiveness. Therefore, we address three related research questions in this work. First, we explore the optimal strength of the KL divergence constraint in DPO, which penalizes deviations from the reference policy, and find that DPO is sensitive to this strength. Next, we examine the necessity of the KL-constraint from the reference policies in DPO by providing both theoretical and empirical comparisons between DPO and related learning objectives, demonstrating DPO's superiority in this controlled setting. Additionally, we investigate whether DPO benefits from stronger reference policies, finding that a stronger reference policy can lead to improved performance, but only when it is similar to the model being fine-tuned. Our findings highlight the confounding role of reference policies in DPO and offer insights for best practices, while also identifying open research questions for future studies.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.13709v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yixin Liu, Pengfei Liu, Arman Cohan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Language Models Might Not Care What You Are Saying: Prompt Format Beats Descriptions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08780</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08780v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: With the help of in-context learning (ICL), large language models (LLMs) have achieved impressive performance across various tasks. However, the function of descriptive instructions during ICL remains under-explored. In this work, we propose an ensemble prompt framework to describe the selection criteria of multiple in-context examples, and preliminary experiments on machine translation (MT) across six translation directions confirm that this framework boosts ICL perfromance. But to our surprise, LLMs might not necessarily care what the descriptions actually say, and the performance gain is primarily caused by the ensemble format, since the framework could lead to improvement even with random descriptive nouns. We further apply this new ensemble prompt on a range of commonsense, math, logical reasoning and hallucination tasks with three LLMs and achieve promising results, suggesting again that designing a proper prompt format would be much more effective and efficient than paying effort into specific descriptions. Our code will be publicly available once this paper is published.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08780v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chenming Tang, Zhixiang Wang, Yunfang Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vaccine: Perturbation-aware Alignment for Large Language Models against Harmful Fine-tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.01109</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.01109v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The new paradigm of finetuning-as-a-service introduces a new attack surface for Large Language Models (LLMs): a few harmful data uploaded by users can easily trick the finetuning to produce an alignment-broken model. We conduct an empirical analysis and uncover a \textit{harmful embedding drift} phenomenon, showing a probable cause of the alignment-broken effect. Inspired by our findings, we propose Vaccine, a perturbation-aware alignment technique to mitigate the security risk of users finetuning. The core idea of Vaccine is to produce invariant hidden embeddings by progressively adding crafted perturbation to them in the alignment phase. This enables the embeddings to withstand harmful perturbation from un-sanitized user data in the finetuning phase. Our results on open source mainstream LLMs (e.g., Llama2, Opt, Vicuna) demonstrate that Vaccine can boost the robustness of alignment against harmful prompts induced embedding drift while reserving reasoning ability towards benign prompts. Our code is available at \url{https://github.com/git-disl/Vaccine}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.01109v4</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tiansheng Huang, Sihao Hu, Ling Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clarify: Improving Model Robustness With Natural Language Corrections</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03715</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.03715v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The standard way to teach models is by feeding them lots of data. However, this approach often teaches models incorrect ideas because they pick up on misleading signals in the data. To prevent such misconceptions, we must necessarily provide additional information beyond the training data. Prior methods incorporate additional instance-level supervision, such as labels for misleading features or additional labels for debiased data. However, such strategies require a large amount of labeler effort. We hypothesize that people are good at providing textual feedback at the concept level, a capability that existing teaching frameworks do not leverage. We propose Clarify, a novel interface and method for interactively correcting model misconceptions. Through Clarify, users need only provide a short text description of a model's consistent failure patterns. Then, in an entirely automated way, we use such descriptions to improve the training process. Clarify is the first end-to-end system for user model correction. Our user studies show that non-expert users can successfully describe model misconceptions via Clarify, leading to increased worst-case performance in two datasets. We additionally conduct a case study on a large-scale image dataset, ImageNet, using Clarify to find and rectify 31 novel hard subpopulations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.03715v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3654777.3676362</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Yoonho Lee, Michelle S. Lam, Helena Vasconcelos, Michael S. Bernstein, Chelsea Finn</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fight Back Against Jailbreaking via Prompt Adversarial Tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.06255</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.06255v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: While Large Language Models (LLMs) have achieved tremendous success in various applications, they are also susceptible to jailbreak attacks. Several primary defense strategies have been proposed to protect LLMs from producing harmful information, mostly with a particular focus on harmful content filtering or heuristical defensive prompt designs. However, how to achieve intrinsic robustness through the prompts remains an open problem. In this paper, motivated by adversarial training paradigms for achieving reliable robustness, we propose an approach named Prompt Adversarial Tuning (PAT) that trains a prompt control attached to the user prompt as a guard prefix. To achieve our defense goal whilst maintaining natural performance, we optimize the control prompt with both adversarial and benign prompts. Comprehensive experiments show that our method is effective against both grey-box and black-box attacks, reducing the success rate of advanced attacks to nearly 0 while maintaining the model's utility on the benign task. The proposed defense strategy incurs only negligible computational overhead, charting a new perspective for future explorations in LLM security. Our code is available at https://github.com/rain152/PAT.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.06255v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yichuan Mo, Yuji Wang, Zeming Wei, Yisen Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI-Augmented Predictions: LLM Assistants Improve Human Forecasting Accuracy</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.07862</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.07862v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) match and sometimes exceeding human performance in many domains. This study explores the potential of LLMs to augment human judgement in a forecasting task. We evaluate the effect on human forecasters of two LLM assistants: one designed to provide high-quality ("superforecasting") advice, and the other designed to be overconfident and base-rate neglecting, thus providing noisy forecasting advice. We compare participants using these assistants to a control group that received a less advanced model that did not provide numerical predictions or engaged in explicit discussion of predictions. Participants (N = 991) answered a set of six forecasting questions and had the option to consult their assigned LLM assistant throughout. Our preregistered analyses show that interacting with each of our frontier LLM assistants significantly enhances prediction accuracy by between 24 percent and 28 percent compared to the control group. Exploratory analyses showed a pronounced outlier effect in one forecasting item, without which we find that the superforecasting assistant increased accuracy by 41 percent, compared with 29 percent for the noisy assistant. We further examine whether LLM forecasting augmentation disproportionately benefits less skilled forecasters, degrades the wisdom-of-the-crowd by reducing prediction diversity, or varies in effectiveness with question difficulty. Our data do not consistently support these hypotheses. Our results suggest that access to a frontier LLM assistant, even a noisy one, can be a helpful decision aid in cognitively demanding tasks compared to a less powerful model that does not provide specific forecasting advice. However, the effects of outliers suggest that further research into the robustness of this pattern is needed.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.07862v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Philipp Schoenegger, Peter S. Park, Ezra Karger, Sean Trott, Philip E. Tetlock</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Language Agents as Optimizable Graphs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16823</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.16823v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Various human-designed prompt engineering techniques have been proposed to improve problem solvers based on Large Language Models (LLMs), yielding many disparate code bases. We unify these approaches by describing LLM-based agents as computational graphs. The nodes implement functions to process multimodal data or query LLMs, and the edges describe the information flow between operations. Graphs can be recursively combined into larger composite graphs representing hierarchies of inter-agent collaboration (where edges connect operations of different agents). Our novel automatic graph optimizers (1) refine node-level LLM prompts (node optimization) and (2) improve agent orchestration by changing graph connectivity (edge optimization). Experiments demonstrate that our framework can be used to efficiently develop, integrate, and automatically improve various LLM agents. The code can be found at https://github.com/metauto-ai/gptswarm.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.16823v3</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mingchen Zhuge, Wenyi Wang, Louis Kirsch, Francesco Faccio, Dmitrii Khizbullin, J\"urgen Schmidhuber</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Study of Backdoors in Instruction Fine-tuned Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07778</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.07778v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Backdoor data poisoning, inserted within instruction examples used to fine-tune a foundation Large Language Model (LLM) for downstream tasks (\textit{e.g.,} sentiment prediction), is a serious security concern due to the evasive nature of such attacks. The poisoning is usually in the form of a (seemingly innocuous) trigger word or phrase inserted into a very small fraction of the fine-tuning samples from a target class. Such backdoor attacks can: alter response sentiment, violate censorship, over-refuse (invoke censorship for legitimate queries), inject false content, or trigger nonsense responses (hallucinations). In this work we investigate the efficacy of instruction fine-tuning backdoor attacks as attack "hyperparameters" are varied under a variety of scenarios, considering: the trigger location in the poisoned examples; robustness to change in the trigger location, partial triggers, and synonym substitutions at test time; attack transfer from one (fine-tuning) domain to a related test domain; and clean-label vs. dirty-label poisoning. Based on our observations, we propose and evaluate two defenses against these attacks: i) a \textit{during-fine-tuning defense} based on word-frequency counts that assumes the (possibly poisoned) fine-tuning dataset is available and identifies the backdoor trigger tokens; and ii) a \textit{post-fine-tuning defense} based on downstream clean fine-tuning of the backdoored LLM with a small defense dataset. Finally, we provide a brief survey of related work on backdoor attacks and defenses.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.07778v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jayaram Raghuram, George Kesidis, David J. Miller</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Oscars of AI Theater: A Survey on Role-Playing with Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.11484</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.11484v5 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: This survey explores the burgeoning field of role-playing with language models, focusing on their development from early persona-based models to advanced character-driven simulations facilitated by Large Language Models (LLMs). Initially confined to simple persona consistency due to limited model capabilities, role-playing tasks have now expanded to embrace complex character portrayals involving character consistency, behavioral alignment, and overall attractiveness. We provide a comprehensive taxonomy of the critical components in designing these systems, including data, models and alignment, agent architecture and evaluation. This survey not only outlines the current methodologies and challenges, such as managing dynamic personal profiles and achieving high-level persona consistency but also suggests avenues for future research in improving the depth and realism of role-playing applications. The goal is to guide future research by offering a structured overview of current methodologies and identifying potential areas for improvement. Related resources and papers are available at https://github.com/nuochenpku/Awesome-Role-Play-Papers.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.11484v5</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nuo Chen, Yan Wang, Yang Deng, Jia Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Relationship between Prompts and Response Uncertainty in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.14845</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.14845v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are widely used in decision-making, but their reliability, especially in critical tasks like healthcare, is not well-established. Therefore, understanding how LLMs reason and make decisions is crucial for their safe deployment. This paper investigates how the uncertainty of responses generated by LLMs relates to the information provided in the input prompt. Leveraging the insight that LLMs learn to infer latent concepts during pretraining, we propose a prompt-response concept model that explains how LLMs generate responses and helps understand the relationship between prompts and response uncertainty. We show that the uncertainty decreases as the prompt's informativeness increases, similar to epistemic uncertainty. Our detailed experimental results on real datasets validate our proposed model.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.14845v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ze Yu Zhang, Arun Verma, Finale Doshi-Velez, Bryan Kian Hsiang Low</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Latent Adversarial Training Improves Robustness to Persistent Harmful Behaviors in LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.15549</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.15549v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) can often be made to behave in undesirable ways that they are explicitly fine-tuned not to. For example, the LLM red-teaming literature has produced a wide variety of 'jailbreaking' techniques to elicit harmful text from models that were fine-tuned to be harmless. Recent work on red-teaming, model editing, and interpretability suggests that this challenge stems from how (adversarial) fine-tuning largely serves to suppress rather than remove undesirable capabilities from LLMs. Prior work has introduced latent adversarial training (LAT) as a way to improve robustness to broad classes of failures. These prior works have considered untargeted latent space attacks where the adversary perturbs latent activations to maximize loss on examples of desirable behavior. Untargeted LAT can provide a generic type of robustness but does not leverage information about specific failure modes. Here, we experiment with targeted LAT where the adversary seeks to minimize loss on a specific competing task. We find that it can augment a wide variety of state-of-the-art methods. First, we use targeted LAT to improve robustness to jailbreaks, outperforming a strong R2D2 baseline with orders of magnitude less compute. Second, we use it to more effectively remove backdoors with no knowledge of the trigger. Finally, we use it to more effectively unlearn knowledge for specific undesirable tasks in a way that is also more robust to re-learning. Overall, our results suggest that targeted LAT can be an effective tool for defending against harmful behaviors from LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.15549v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Abhay Sheshadri, Aidan Ewart, Phillip Guo, Aengus Lynch, Cindy Wu, Vivek Hebbar, Henry Sleight, Asa Cooper Stickland, Ethan Perez, Dylan Hadfield-Menell, Stephen Casper</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lighthouse: A User-Friendly Library for Reproducible Video Moment Retrieval and Highlight Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02901</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.02901v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We propose Lighthouse, a user-friendly library for reproducible video moment retrieval and highlight detection (MR-HD). Although researchers proposed various MR-HD approaches, the research community holds two main issues. The first is a lack of comprehensive and reproducible experiments across various methods, datasets, and video-text features. This is because no unified training and evaluation codebase covers multiple settings. The second is user-unfriendly design. Because previous works use different libraries, researchers set up individual environments. In addition, most works release only the training codes, requiring users to implement the whole inference process of MR-HD. Lighthouse addresses these issues by implementing a unified reproducible codebase that includes six models, three features, and five datasets. In addition, it provides an inference API and web demo to make these methods easily accessible for researchers and developers. Our experiments demonstrate that Lighthouse generally reproduces the reported scores in the reference papers. The code is available at https://github.com/line/lighthouse.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.02901v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Taichi Nishimura, Shota Nakada, Hokuto Munakata, Tatsuya Komatsu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prefix Guidance: A Steering Wheel for Large Language Models to Defend Against Jailbreak Attacks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08924</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08924v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In recent years, the rapid development of large language models (LLMs) has achieved remarkable performance across various tasks. However, research indicates that LLMs are vulnerable to jailbreak attacks, where adversaries can induce the generation of harmful content through meticulously crafted prompts. This vulnerability poses significant challenges to the secure use and promotion of LLMs. Existing defense methods offer protection from different perspectives but often suffer from insufficient effectiveness or a significant impact on the model's capabilities. In this paper, we propose a plug-and-play and easy-to-deploy jailbreak defense framework, namely Prefix Guidance (PG), which guides the model to identify harmful prompts by directly setting the first few tokens of the model's output. This approach combines the model's inherent security capabilities with an external classifier to defend against jailbreak attacks. We demonstrate the effectiveness of PG across three models and five attack methods. Compared to baselines, our approach is generally more effective on average. Additionally, results on the Just-Eval benchmark further confirm PG's superiority to preserve the model's performance. our code is available at https://github.com/weiyezhimeng/Prefix-Guidance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08924v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiawei Zhao, Kejiang Chen, Xiaojian Yuan, Weiming Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Lazy to Prolific: Tackling Missing Labels in Open Vocabulary Extreme Classification by Positive-Unlabeled Sequence Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08981</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08981v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Open-vocabulary Extreme Multi-label Classification (OXMC) extends traditional XMC by allowing prediction beyond an extremely large, predefined label set (typically $10^3$ to $10^{12}$ labels), addressing the dynamic nature of real-world labeling tasks. However, self-selection bias in data annotation leads to significant missing labels in both training and test data, particularly for less popular inputs. This creates two critical challenges: generation models learn to be "lazy'" by under-generating labels, and evaluation becomes unreliable due to insufficient annotation in the test set. In this work, we introduce Positive-Unlabeled Sequence Learning (PUSL), which reframes OXMC as an infinite keyphrase generation task, addressing the generation model's laziness. Additionally, we propose to adopt a suite of evaluation metrics, F1@$\mathcal{O}$ and newly proposed B@$k$, to reliably assess OXMC models with incomplete ground truths. In a highly imbalanced e-commerce dataset with substantial missing labels, PUSL generates 30% more unique labels, and 72% of its predictions align with actual user queries. On the less skewed EURLex-4.3k dataset, PUSL demonstrates superior F1 scores, especially as label counts increase from 15 to 30. Our approach effectively tackles both the modeling and evaluation challenges in OXMC with missing labels.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08981v2</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ranran Haoran Zhang, Bensu U\c{c}ar, Soumik Dey, Hansi Wu, Binbin Li, Rui Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mistral-SPLADE: LLMs for better Learned Sparse Retrieval</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11119</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11119v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Learned Sparse Retrievers (LSR) have evolved into an effective retrieval strategy that can bridge the gap between traditional keyword-based sparse retrievers and embedding-based dense retrievers. At its core, learned sparse retrievers try to learn the most important semantic keyword expansions from a query and/or document which can facilitate better retrieval with overlapping keyword expansions. LSR like SPLADE has typically been using encoder only models with MLM (masked language modeling) style objective in conjunction with known ways of retrieval performance improvement such as hard negative mining, distillation, etc. In this work, we propose to use decoder-only model for learning semantic keyword expansion. We posit, decoder only models that have seen much higher magnitudes of data are better equipped to learn keyword expansions needed for improved retrieval. We use Mistral as the backbone to develop our Learned Sparse Retriever similar to SPLADE and train it on a subset of sentence-transformer data which is often used for training text embedding models. Our experiments support the hypothesis that a sparse retrieval model based on decoder only large language model (LLM) surpasses the performance of existing LSR systems, including SPLADE and all its variants. The LLM based model (Echo-Mistral-SPLADE) now stands as a state-of-the-art learned sparse retrieval model on the BEIR text retrieval benchmark.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11119v2</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Meet Doshi, Vishwajeet Kumar, Rudra Murthy, Vignesh P, Jaydeep Sen</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
