<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL</link>
    <description>cs.CL updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 04:00:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Sunday</day>
      <day>Saturday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>Retrieval-Augmented Generation Meets Data-Driven Tabula Rasa Approach for Temporal Knowledge Graph Forecasting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13273</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13273v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Pre-trained large language models (PLLMs) like OpenAI ChatGPT and Google Gemini face challenges such as inaccurate factual recall, hallucinations, biases, and future data leakage for temporal Knowledge Graph (tKG) forecasting. To address these issues, we introduce sLA-tKGF (small-scale language assistant for tKG forecasting), which utilizes Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) aided, custom-trained small-scale language models through a tabula rasa approach from scratch for effective tKG forecasting. Our framework constructs knowledge-infused prompts with relevant historical data from tKGs, web search results, and PLLMs-generated textual descriptions to understand historical entity relationships prior to the target time. It leverages these external knowledge-infused prompts for deeper understanding and reasoning of context-specific semantic and temporal information to zero-shot prompt small-scale language models for more accurate predictions of future events within tKGs. It reduces hallucinations and mitigates distributional shift challenges through comprehending changing trends over time. As a result, it enables more accurate and contextually grounded forecasts of future events while minimizing computational demands. Rigorous empirical studies demonstrate our framework robustness, scalability, and state-of-the-art (SOTA) performance on benchmark datasets with interpretable and trustworthy tKG forecasting.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13273v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Geethan Sannidhi, Sagar Srinivas Sakhinana, Venkataramana Runkana</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Question answering system of bridge design specification based on large language model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13282</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13282v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper constructs question answering system for bridge design specification based on large language model. Three implementation schemes are tried: full fine-tuning of the Bert pretrained model, parameter-efficient fine-tuning of the Bert pretrained model, and self-built language model from scratch. Through the self-built question and answer task dataset, based on the tensorflow and keras deep learning platform framework, the model is constructed and trained to predict the start position and end position of the answer in the bridge design specification given by the user. The experimental results show that full fine-tuning of the Bert pretrained model achieves 100% accuracy in the training-dataset, validation-dataset and test-dataset, and the system can extract the answers from the bridge design specification given by the user to answer various questions of the user; While parameter-efficient fine-tuning of the Bert pretrained model and self-built language model from scratch perform well in the training-dataset, their generalization ability in the test-dataset needs to be improved. The research of this paper provides a useful reference for the development of question answering system in professional field.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13282v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Leye Zhang, Xiangxiang Tian, Hongjun Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Power Scheduler: A Batch Size and Token Number Agnostic Learning Rate Scheduler</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13359</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13359v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Finding the optimal learning rate for language model pretraining is a challenging task. This is not only because there is a complicated correlation between learning rate, batch size, number of training tokens, model size, and other hyperparameters but also because it is prohibitively expensive to perform a hyperparameter search for large language models with Billions or Trillions of parameters. Recent studies propose using small proxy models and small corpus to perform hyperparameter searches and transposing the optimal parameters to large models and large corpus. While the zero-shot transferability is theoretically and empirically proven for model size related hyperparameters, like depth and width, the zero-shot transfer from small corpus to large corpus is underexplored. In this paper, we study the correlation between optimal learning rate, batch size, and number of training tokens for the recently proposed WSD scheduler. After thousands of small experiments, we found a power-law relationship between variables and demonstrated its transferability across model sizes. Based on the observation, we propose a new learning rate scheduler, Power scheduler, that is agnostic about the number of training tokens and batch size. The experiment shows that combining the Power scheduler with Maximum Update Parameterization (muP) can consistently achieve impressive performance with one set of hyperparameters regardless of the number of training tokens, batch size, model size, and even model architecture. Our 3B dense and MoE models trained with the Power scheduler achieve comparable performance as state-of-the-art small language models. We open-source these pretrained models at https://ibm.biz/BdKhLa.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13359v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yikang Shen, Matthew Stallone, Mayank Mishra, Gaoyuan Zhang, Shawn Tan, Aditya Prasad, Adriana Meza Soria, David D. Cox, Rameswar Panda</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CodeRefine: A Pipeline for Enhancing LLM-Generated Code Implementations of Research Papers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13366</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13366v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper presents CodeRefine, a novel framework for automatically transforming research paper methodologies into functional code using Large Language Models (LLMs). Our multi-step approach first extracts and summarizes key text chunks from papers, analyzes their code relevance, and creates a knowledge graph using a predefined ontology. Code is then generated from this structured representation and enhanced through a proposed retrospective retrieval-augmented generation approach. CodeRefine addresses the challenge of bridging theoretical research and practical implementation, offering a more accurate alternative to LLM zero-shot prompting. Evaluations on diverse scientific papers demonstrate CodeRefine's ability to improve code implementation from the paper, potentially accelerating the adoption of cutting-edge algorithms in real-world applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13366v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ekaterina Trofimova, Emil Sataev, Abhijit Singh Jowhari</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Multi-Head Convolutional Encoders with Cross-Attention for Improved SPARQL Query Translation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13432</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13432v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The main task of the KGQA system (Knowledge Graph Question Answering) is to convert user input questions into query syntax (such as SPARQL). With the rise of modern popular encoders and decoders like Transformer and ConvS2S, many scholars have shifted the research direction of SPARQL generation to the Neural Machine Translation (NMT) architecture or the generative AI field of Text-to-SPARQL. In NMT-based QA systems, the system treats knowledge base query syntax as a language. It uses NMT-based translation models to translate natural language questions into query syntax. Scholars use popular architectures equipped with cross-attention, such as Transformer, ConvS2S, and BiLSTM, to train translation models for query syntax. To achieve better query results, this paper improved the ConvS2S encoder and added multi-head attention from the Transformer, proposing a Multi-Head Conv encoder (MHC encoder) based on the n-gram language model. The principle is to use convolutional layers to capture local hidden features in the input sequence with different receptive fields, using multi-head attention to calculate dependencies between them. Ultimately, we found that the translation model based on the Multi-Head Conv encoder achieved better performance than other encoders, obtaining 76.52\% and 83.37\% BLEU-1 (BiLingual Evaluation Understudy) on the QALD-9 and LC-QuAD-1.0 datasets, respectively. Additionally, in the end-to-end system experiments on the QALD-9 and LC-QuAD-1.0 datasets, we achieved leading results over other KGQA systems, with Macro F1-measures reaching 52\% and 66\%, respectively. Moreover, the experimental results show that with limited computational resources, if one possesses an excellent encoder-decoder architecture and cross-attention, experts and scholars can achieve outstanding performance equivalent to large pre-trained models using only general embeddings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13432v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yi-Hui Chen, Eric Jui-Lin Lu, Kwan-Ho Cheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge-Aware Conversation Derailment Forecasting Using Graph Convolutional Networks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13440</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13440v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Online conversations are particularly susceptible to derailment, which can manifest itself in the form of toxic communication patterns including disrespectful comments and abuse. Forecasting conversation derailment predicts signs of derailment in advance enabling proactive moderation of conversations. State-of-the-art approaches to conversation derailment forecasting sequentially encode conversations and use graph neural networks to model dialogue user dynamics. However, existing graph models are not able to capture complex conversational characteristics such as context propagation and emotional shifts. The use of common sense knowledge enables a model to capture such characteristics, thus improving performance. Following this approach, here we derive commonsense statements from a knowledge base of dialogue contextual information to enrich a graph neural network classification architecture. We fuse the multi-source information on utterance into capsules, which are used by a transformer-based forecaster to predict conversation derailment. Our model captures conversation dynamics and context propagation, outperforming the state-of-the-art models on the CGA and CMV benchmark datasets</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13440v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Enas Altarawneh, Ameeta Agrawal, Michael Jenkin, Manos Papagelis</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Make Every Penny Count: Difficulty-Adaptive Self-Consistency for Cost-Efficient Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13457</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13457v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Self-consistency (SC), a widely used decoding strategy for chain-of-thought reasoning, shows significant gains across various multi-step reasoning tasks but comes with a high cost due to multiple sampling with the preset size. Its variants, Adaptive self-consistency (ASC) and Early-stopping self-consistency (ESC), dynamically adjust the number of samples based on the posterior distribution of a set of pre-samples, reducing the cost of SC with minimal impact on performance. Both methods, however, do not exploit the prior information about question difficulty. It often results in unnecessary repeated sampling for easy questions that could be accurately answered with just one attempt, wasting resources. To tackle this problem, we propose Difficulty-Adaptive Self-Consistency (DSC), which leverages the difficulty information from both prior and posterior perspectives to adaptively allocate inference resources, further reducing the cost of SC. To demonstrate the effectiveness of DSC, we conduct extensive experiments on three popular categories of reasoning tasks: arithmetic, commonsense and symbolic reasoning on six benchmarks. The empirical results show that DSC consistently surpasses the strong baseline ASC and ESC in terms of costs by a significant margin, while attaining comparable performances.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13457v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xinglin Wang, Shaoxiong Feng, Yiwei Li, Peiwen Yuan, Yueqi Zhang, Boyuan Pan, Heda Wang, Yao Hu, Kan Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Antiwork: A RoBERTa-Based System for Work-Related Stress Identification and Leading Factor Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13473</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13473v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Harsh working environments and work-related stress have been known to contribute to mental health problems such as anxiety, depression, and suicidal ideation. As such, it is paramount to create solutions that can both detect employee unhappiness and find the root cause of the problem. While prior works have examined causes of mental health using machine learning, they typically focus on general mental health analysis, with few of them focusing on explainable solutions or looking at the workplace-specific setting. r/antiwork is a subreddit for the antiwork movement, which is the desire to stop working altogether. Using this subreddit as a proxy for work environment dissatisfaction, we create a new dataset for antiwork sentiment detection and subsequently train a model that highlights the words with antiwork sentiments. Following this, we performed a qualitative and quantitative analysis to uncover some of the key insights into the mindset of individuals who identify with the antiwork movement and how their working environments influenced them. We find that working environments that do not give employees authority or responsibility, frustrating recruiting experiences, and unfair compensation, are some of the leading causes of the antiwork sentiment, resulting in a lack of self-confidence and motivation among their employees.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13473v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tao Lu, Muzhe Wu, Xinyi Lu, Siyuan Xu, Shuyu Zhan, Anuj Tambwekar, Emily Mower Provost</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utilizing Large Language Models for Named Entity Recognition in Traditional Chinese Medicine against COVID-19 Literature: Comparative Study</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13501</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13501v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Objective: To explore and compare the performance of ChatGPT and other state-of-the-art LLMs on domain-specific NER tasks covering different entity types and domains in TCM against COVID-19 literature. Methods: We established a dataset of 389 articles on TCM against COVID-19, and manually annotated 48 of them with 6 types of entities belonging to 3 domains as the ground truth, against which the NER performance of LLMs can be assessed. We then performed NER tasks for the 6 entity types using ChatGPT (GPT-3.5 and GPT-4) and 4 state-of-the-art BERT-based question-answering (QA) models (RoBERTa, MiniLM, PubMedBERT and SciBERT) without prior training on the specific task. A domain fine-tuned model (GSAP-NER) was also applied for a comprehensive comparison. Results: The overall performance of LLMs varied significantly in exact match and fuzzy match. In the fuzzy match, ChatGPT surpassed BERT-based QA models in 5 out of 6 tasks, while in exact match, BERT-based QA models outperformed ChatGPT in 5 out of 6 tasks but with a smaller F-1 difference. GPT-4 showed a significant advantage over other models in fuzzy match, especially on the entity type of TCM formula and the Chinese patent drug (TFD) and ingredient (IG). Although GPT-4 outperformed BERT-based models on entity type of herb, target, and research method, none of the F-1 scores exceeded 0.5. GSAP-NER, outperformed GPT-4 in terms of F-1 by a slight margin on RM. ChatGPT achieved considerably higher recalls than precisions, particularly in the fuzzy match. Conclusions: The NER performance of LLMs is highly dependent on the entity type, and their performance varies across application scenarios. ChatGPT could be a good choice for scenarios where high recall is favored. However, for knowledge acquisition in rigorous scenarios, neither ChatGPT nor BERT-based QA models are off-the-shelf tools for professional practitioners.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13501v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xu Tong, Nina Smirnova, Sharmila Upadhyaya, Ran Yu, Jack H. Culbert, Chao Sun, Wolfgang Otto, Philipp Mayr</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Preference Optimization via Token-Level Reward Function Estimation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13518</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13518v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent advancements in large language model alignment leverage token-level supervisions to perform fine-grained preference optimization. However, existing token-level alignment methods either optimize on all available tokens, which can be noisy and inefficient, or perform selective training with complex and expensive key token selection strategies. In this work, we propose Selective Preference Optimization (SePO), a novel selective alignment strategy that centers on efficient key token selection. SePO proposes the first token selection method based on Direct Preference Optimization (DPO), which trains an oracle model to estimate a token-level reward function on the target data. This method applies to any existing alignment datasets with response-level annotations and enables cost-efficient token selection with small-scale oracle models and training data. The estimated reward function is then utilized to score all tokens within the target dataset, where only the key tokens are selected to supervise the target policy model with a reference model-free contrastive objective function. Extensive experiments on three public evaluation benchmarks show that SePO significantly outperforms competitive baseline methods by only optimizing 30% key tokens on the target dataset. SePO applications on weak-to-strong generalization show that weak oracle models effectively supervise strong policy models with up to 16.8x more parameters. SePO also effectively selects key tokens from out-of-distribution data to enhance strong policy models and alleviate the over-optimization problem.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13518v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kailai Yang, Zhiwei Liu, Qianqian Xie, Jimin Huang, Erxue Min, Sophia Ananiadou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HRGraph: Leveraging LLMs for HR Data Knowledge Graphs with Information Propagation-based Job Recommendation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13521</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13521v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Knowledge Graphs (KGs) serving as semantic networks, prove highly effective in managing complex interconnected data in different domains, by offering a unified, contextualized, and structured representation with flexibility that allows for easy adaptation to evolving knowledge. Processing complex Human Resources (HR) data, KGs can help in different HR functions like recruitment, job matching, identifying learning gaps, and enhancing employee retention. Despite their potential, limited efforts have been made to implement practical HR knowledge graphs. This study addresses this gap by presenting a framework for effectively developing HR knowledge graphs from documents using Large Language Models. The resulting KG can be used for a variety of downstream tasks, including job matching, identifying employee skill gaps, and many more. In this work, we showcase instances where HR KGs prove instrumental in precise job matching, yielding advantages for both employers and employees. Empirical evidence from experiments with information propagation in KGs and Graph Neural Nets, along with case studies underscores the effectiveness of KGs in tasks such as job and employee recommendations and job area classification. Code and data are available at : https://github.com/azminewasi/HRGraph</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13521v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.IT</category>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <category>math.IT</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Proceedings of the 1st Workshop on Knowledge Graphs and Large Language Models (KaLLM 2024), Association for Computational Linguistics 2024</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Azmine Toushik Wasi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pandora's Box or Aladdin's Lamp: A Comprehensive Analysis Revealing the Role of RAG Noise in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13533</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13533v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) has emerged as a crucial method for addressing hallucinations in large language models (LLMs). While recent research has extended RAG models to complex noisy scenarios, these explorations often confine themselves to limited noise types and presuppose that noise is inherently detrimental to LLMs, potentially deviating from real-world retrieval environments and restricting practical applicability. In this paper, we define seven distinct noise types from a linguistic perspective and establish a Noise RAG Benchmark (NoiserBench), a comprehensive evaluation framework encompassing multiple datasets and reasoning tasks. Through empirical evaluation of eight representative LLMs with diverse architectures and scales, we reveal that these noises can be further categorized into two practical groups: noise that is beneficial to LLMs (aka beneficial noise) and noise that is harmful to LLMs (aka harmful noise). While harmful noise generally impairs performance, beneficial noise may enhance several aspects of model capabilities and overall performance. Our analysis offers insights for developing more robust, adaptable RAG solutions and mitigating hallucinations across diverse retrieval scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13533v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jinyang Wu, Feihu Che, Chuyuan Zhang, Jianhua Tao, Shuai Zhang, Pengpeng Shao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cultural Adaptation of Menus: A Fine-Grained Approach</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13534</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13534v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Machine Translation of Culture-Specific Items (CSIs) poses significant challenges. Recent work on CSI translation has shown some success using Large Language Models (LLMs) to adapt to different languages and cultures; however, a deeper analysis is needed to examine the benefits and pitfalls of each method. In this paper, we introduce the ChineseMenuCSI dataset, the largest for Chinese-English menu corpora, annotated with CSI vs Non-CSI labels and a fine-grained test set. We define three levels of CSI figurativeness for a more nuanced analysis and develop a novel methodology for automatic CSI identification, which outperforms GPT-based prompts in most categories. Importantly, we are the first to integrate human translation theories into LLM-driven translation processes, significantly improving translation accuracy, with COMET scores increasing by up to 7 points.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13534v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhonghe Zhang, Xiaoyu He, Vivek Iyer, Alexandra Birch</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IQA-EVAL: Automatic Evaluation of Human-Model Interactive Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13545</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13545v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: To evaluate Large Language Models (LLMs) for question answering (QA), traditional methods typically focus on directly assessing the immediate responses generated by the models based on the given question and context. In the common use case of humans seeking AI assistant's help in finding information, these non-interactive evaluations do not account for the dynamic nature of human-model conversations, and interaction-aware evaluations have shown that accurate QA models are preferred by humans (Lee et al., 2023). Recent works in human-computer interaction (HCI) have employed human evaluators to conduct interactions and evaluations, but they are often prohibitively expensive and time-consuming to scale. In this work, we introduce an automatic evaluation framework IQA-EVAL to Interactive Question Answering Evaluation. More specifically, we introduce LLM-based Evaluation Agent (LEA) that can: (1) simulate human behaviors to generate interactions with IQA models; (2) automatically evaluate the generated interactions. Moreover, we propose assigning personas to LEAs to better simulate groups of real human evaluators. We show that: (1) our evaluation framework with GPT-4 (or Claude) as the backbone model achieves a high correlation with human evaluations on the IQA task; (2) assigning personas to LEA to better represent the crowd further significantly improves correlations. Finally, we use our automatic metric to evaluate five recent representative LLMs with over 1000 questions from complex and ambiguous question answering tasks, which comes with a substantial cost of $5k if evaluated by humans.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13545v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ruosen Li, Barry Wang, Ruochen Li, Xinya Du</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FLEURS-ASL: Including American Sign Language in Massively Multilingual Multitask Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13585</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13585v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Sign language translation has historically been peripheral to mainstream machine translation research. In order to help converge the fields, we introduce FLEURS-ASL, an extension of the multiway parallel benchmarks FLORES (for text) and FLEURS (for speech) to support their first sign language (as video), American Sign Language, translated by 5 Certified Deaf Interpreters. FLEURS-ASL can be used to evaluate a variety of tasks -- primarily sentence- and discourse-level translation -- between ASL and 200 other languages as text, or 102 languages as speech. We provide baselines for tasks from ASL to English text using a unified modeling approach that incorporates timestamp tokens and previous text tokens in a 34-second context window, trained on random video clips from YouTube-ASL. This model meets or exceeds the performance of phrase-level baselines while supporting a multitude of new tasks. We also use FLEURS-ASL to show that multimodal frontier models have virtually no understanding of ASL, underscoring the importance of including sign languages in standard evaluation suites.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13585v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Garrett Tanzer</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Balancing Diversity and Risk in LLM Sampling: How to Select Your Method and Parameter for Open-Ended Text Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13586</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13586v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Sampling-based decoding strategies have been widely adopted for Large Language Models (LLMs) in numerous applications, which target a balance between diversity and quality via temperature tuning and tail truncation (e.g., top-k and top-p sampling). Considering the high dynamic range of the candidate next-token given different prefixes, recent studies propose to adaptively truncate the tail of LLM's predicted distribution. Although improved results haven been reported with these methods on open-ended text generation tasks, the results are highly dependent on the curated truncation parameters and exemplar text. In this paper, we propose a systematic way to estimate the intrinsic capacity of a truncation sampling method by considering the trade-off between diversity and risk at each decoding step, based on our collected prefix tree which preserves the context of a full sentence. Our work provides a comprehensive comparison between existing truncation sampling methods, as well as their recommended parameters as a guideline for users.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13586v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuxuan Zhou, Margret Keuper, Mario Fritz</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No Dataset Needed for Downstream Knowledge Benchmarking: Response Dispersion Inversely Correlates with Accuracy on Domain-specific QA</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13624</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13624v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This research seeks to obviate the need for creating QA datasets and grading (chatbot) LLM responses when comparing LLMs' knowledge in specific topic domains. This is done in an entirely end-user centric way without need for access to any inner workings of the LLM, so long as it can be prompted and given a random seed to create different generations to the same prompt. The paper does this by, for a given topic domain, defining the "response dispersion" of an LLM by repeatedly asking an LLM the same opinion question about that topic domain. Namely, the response dispersion is the count of singular values needed to explain 95% of the variance in the embedding matrix of the LLM's responses. It is found that the response dispersion is inversely correlated with accuracy on relevant QA evaluations (average spearman rank correlation stronger than -.59). A use-case analysis shows that when comparing two different LLMs on the same topic domain, comparing their response dispersion is a suitable replacement for comparing their QA accuracy between 74% and 89% of the time, the range depending on certain reasonable accuracy-difference tolerances that may be acceptable to an end-user in exchange for the labor being saved using response dispersion instead of QA accuracy for comparison. Two response embeddings are studied for creating the embedding matrix in this study, one is from OpenAI's APIs and one is a novel embedding, here named reference sentence similarity embeddings, that can be computed locally and performs very nearly as well in calculating response dispersion. Also in this research, a pre-existing dataset called the IRC-Wiki Trivia dataset, originally developed for trivia games, has been re-purposed, curated, and the curation, called IRC-WikiTriviaQA, is made available for the purpose of this research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13624v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Robert L Simione II</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Narratives at Conflict: Computational Analysis of News Framing in Multilingual Disinformation Campaigns</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13651</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13651v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Any report frames issues to favor a particular interpretation by highlighting or excluding certain aspects of a story. Despite the widespread use of framing in disinformation, framing properties and detection methods remain underexplored outside the English-speaking world. We explore how multilingual framing of the same issue differs systematically. We use eight years of Russia-backed disinformation campaigns, spanning 8k news articles in 4 languages targeting 15 countries. We find that disinformation campaigns consistently and intentionally favor specific framing, depending on the target language of the audience. We further discover how Russian-language articles consistently highlight selected frames depending on the region of the media coverage. We find that the two most prominent models for automatic frame analysis underperform and show high disagreement, highlighting the need for further research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13651v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Antonina Sinelnik, Dirk Hovy</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Symbolic Working Memory Enhances Language Models for Complex Rule Application</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13654</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13654v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have shown remarkable reasoning performance but struggle with multi-step deductive reasoning involving a series of rule application steps, especially when rules are presented non-sequentially. Our preliminary analysis shows that while LLMs excel in single-step rule application, their performance drops significantly in multi-step scenarios due to the challenge in rule grounding. It requires anchoring the applicable rule and supporting facts at each step, amidst multiple input rules, facts, and inferred facts. To address this, we propose augmenting LLMs with external working memory and introduce a neurosymbolic framework for rule application. The memory stores facts and rules in both natural language and symbolic forms, enabling precise tracking. Utilizing this memory, our framework iteratively performs symbolic rule grounding and LLM-based rule implementation. The former matches predicates and variables of symbolic rules and facts to ground applicable rules at each step. Experiments indicate our framework's effectiveness in rule application and its robustness across various steps and settings~\footnote{Code and data are available at \url{https://github.com/SiyuanWangw/RuleApplication}.}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13654v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Siyuan Wang, Zhongyu Wei, Yejin Choi, Xiang Ren</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A layer-wise analysis of Mandarin and English suprasegmentals in SSL speech models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13678</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13678v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This study asks how self-supervised speech models represent suprasegmental categories like Mandarin lexical tone, English lexical stress, and English phrasal accents. Through a series of probing tasks, we make layer-wise comparisons of English and Mandarin 12 layer monolingual models. Our findings suggest that 1) English and Mandarin wav2vec 2.0 models learn contextual representations of abstract suprasegmental categories which are strongest in the middle third of the network. 2) Models are better at representing features that exist in the language of their training data, and this difference is driven by enriched context in transformer blocks, not local acoustic representation. 3) Fine-tuned wav2vec 2.0 improves performance in later layers compared to pre-trained models mainly for lexically contrastive features like tone and stress, 4) HuBERT and WavLM learn similar representations to wav2vec 2.0, differing mainly in later layer performance. Our results extend previous understanding of how models represent suprasegmentals and offer new insights into the language-specificity and contextual nature of these representations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13678v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ant\'on de la Fuente, Dan Jurafsky</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DHP Benchmark: Are LLMs Good NLG Evaluators?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13704</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13704v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) are increasingly serving as evaluators in Natural Language Generation (NLG) tasks. However, the capabilities of LLMs in scoring NLG quality remain inadequately explored. Current studies depend on human assessments and simple metrics that fail to capture the discernment of LLMs across diverse NLG tasks. To address this gap, we propose the Discernment of Hierarchical Perturbation (DHP) benchmarking framework, which provides quantitative discernment scores for LLMs utilizing hierarchically perturbed text data and statistical tests to measure the NLG evaluation capabilities of LLMs systematically. We have re-established six evaluation datasets for this benchmark, covering four NLG tasks: Summarization, Story Completion, Question Answering, and Translation. Our comprehensive benchmarking of five major LLM series provides critical insight into their strengths and limitations as NLG evaluators.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13704v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yicheng Wang, Jiayi Yuan, Yu-Neng Chuang, Zhuoer Wang, Yingchi Liu, Mark Cusick, Param Kulkarni, Zhengping Ji, Yasser Ibrahim, Xia Hu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cross-Modal Denoising: A Novel Training Paradigm for Enhancing Speech-Image Retrieval</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13705</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13705v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The success of speech-image retrieval relies on establishing an effective alignment between speech and image. Existing methods often model cross-modal interaction through simple cosine similarity of the global feature of each modality, which fall short in capturing fine-grained details within modalities. To address this issue, we introduce an effective framework and a novel learning task named cross-modal denoising (CMD) to enhance cross-modal interaction to achieve finer-level cross-modal alignment. Specifically, CMD is a denoising task designed to reconstruct semantic features from noisy features within one modality by interacting features from another modality. Notably, CMD operates exclusively during model training and can be removed during inference without adding extra inference time. The experimental results demonstrate that our framework outperforms the state-of-the-art method by 2.0% in mean R@1 on the Flickr8k dataset and by 1.7% in mean R@1 on the SpokenCOCO dataset for the speech-image retrieval tasks, respectively. These experimental results validate the efficiency and effectiveness of our framework.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13705v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lifeng Zhou, Yuke Li, Rui Deng, Yuting Yang, Haoqi Zhu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poor-Supervised Evaluation for SuperLLM via Mutual Consistency</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13738</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13738v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The guidance from capability evaluations has greatly propelled the progress of both human society and Artificial Intelligence. However, as LLMs evolve, it becomes challenging to construct evaluation benchmarks for them with accurate labels on hard tasks that approach the boundaries of human capabilities. To credibly conduct evaluation without accurate labels (denoted as poor-supervised evaluation), we propose the PoEM framework. We first prove that the capability of a model can be equivalently assessed by the consistency between it and certain reference model, when their prediction distributions are independent and the sample size is infinite. To alleviate the insufficiencies of the conditions in reality, we further introduce an algorithm that treats humans (when available) and the models under evaluation as reference models, alternately conducting model weights calibration and filtering during E-step and M-step. Comprehensive experiments across 3 types of tasks with 16 mainstream LLMs have shown that PoEM under poor supervision can achieve an average of 0.98 Pearson correlation coefficient with supervised evaluation results, demonstrating good effectiveness, efficiency and generalizability. More generally, PoEM has advanced the evaluation paradigm evolution from human-centric to human&amp;model-centric by treating both of them as reference models, mitigating the limitations of human evaluation in the era of LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13738v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Peiwen Yuan, Shaoxiong Feng, Yiwei Li, Xinglin Wang, Boyuan Pan, Heda Wang, Yao Hu, Kan Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DOCE: Finding the Sweet Spot for Execution-Based Code Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13745</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13745v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recently, a diverse set of decoding and reranking procedures have been shown effective for LLM-based code generation. However, a comprehensive framework that links and experimentally compares these methods is missing. We address this by proposing Decoding Objectives for Code Execution, a comprehensive framework that includes candidate generation, $n$-best reranking, minimum Bayes risk (MBR) decoding, and self-debugging as the core components. We then study the contributions of these components through execution-based evaluation metrics. Our findings highlight the importance of execution-based methods and the difference gap between execution-based and execution-free methods. Furthermore, we assess the impact of filtering based on trial unit tests, a simple and effective strategy that has been often overlooked in prior works. We also propose self-debugging on multiple candidates, obtaining state-of-the-art performance on reranking for code generation. We expect our framework to provide a solid guideline for future research on code generation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13745v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.PL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haau-Sing Li, Patrick Fernandes, Iryna Gurevych, Andr\'e F. T. Martins</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Reliable Medical Question Answering: Techniques and Challenges in Mitigating Hallucinations in Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13808</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13808v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The rapid advancement of large language models (LLMs) has significantly impacted various domains, including healthcare and biomedicine. However, the phenomenon of hallucination, where LLMs generate outputs that deviate from factual accuracy or context, poses a critical challenge, especially in high-stakes domains. This paper conducts a scoping study of existing techniques for mitigating hallucinations in knowledge-based task in general and especially for medical domains. Key methods covered in the paper include Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG)-based techniques, iterative feedback loops, supervised fine-tuning, and prompt engineering. These techniques, while promising in general contexts, require further adaptation and optimization for the medical domain due to its unique demands for up-to-date, specialized knowledge and strict adherence to medical guidelines. Addressing these challenges is crucial for developing trustworthy AI systems that enhance clinical decision-making and patient safety as well as accuracy of biomedical scientific research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13808v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Duy Khoa Pham, Bao Quoc Vo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting the Exit from Nuclear Energy in Germany with NLP</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13810</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13810v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Annotation of political discourse is resource-intensive, but recent developments in NLP promise to automate complex annotation tasks. Fine-tuned transformer-based models outperform human annotators in some annotation tasks, but they require large manually annotated training datasets. In our contribution, we explore to which degree a manually annotated dataset can be automatically replicated with today's NLP methods, using unsupervised machine learning and zero- and few-shot learning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13810v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sebastian Haunss, Andr\'e Blessing</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guardians of the Machine Translation Meta-Evaluation: Sentinel Metrics Fall In!</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13831</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13831v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Annually, at the Conference of Machine Translation (WMT), the Metrics Shared Task organizers conduct the meta-evaluation of Machine Translation (MT) metrics, ranking them according to their correlation with human judgments. Their results guide researchers toward enhancing the next generation of metrics and MT systems. With the recent introduction of neural metrics, the field has witnessed notable advancements. Nevertheless, the inherent opacity of these metrics has posed substantial challenges to the meta-evaluation process. This work highlights two issues with the meta-evaluation framework currently employed in WMT, and assesses their impact on the metrics rankings. To do this, we introduce the concept of sentinel metrics, which are designed explicitly to scrutinize the meta-evaluation process's accuracy, robustness, and fairness. By employing sentinel metrics, we aim to validate our findings, and shed light on and monitor the potential biases or inconsistencies in the rankings. We discover that the present meta-evaluation framework favors two categories of metrics: i) those explicitly trained to mimic human quality assessments, and ii) continuous metrics. Finally, we raise concerns regarding the evaluation capabilities of state-of-the-art metrics, emphasizing that they might be basing their assessments on spurious correlations found in their training data.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13831v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Stefano Perrella, Lorenzo Proietti, Alessandro Scir\`e, Edoardo Barba, Roberto Navigli</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biomedical Large Languages Models Seem not to be Superior to Generalist Models on Unseen Medical Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13833</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13833v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have shown potential in biomedical applications, leading to efforts to fine-tune them on domain-specific data. However, the effectiveness of this approach remains unclear. This study evaluates the performance of biomedically fine-tuned LLMs against their general-purpose counterparts on a variety of clinical tasks. We evaluated their performance on clinical case challenges from the New England Journal of Medicine (NEJM) and the Journal of the American Medical Association (JAMA) and on several clinical tasks (e.g., information extraction, document summarization, and clinical coding). Using benchmarks specifically chosen to be likely outside the fine-tuning datasets of biomedical models, we found that biomedical LLMs mostly perform inferior to their general-purpose counterparts, especially on tasks not focused on medical knowledge. While larger models showed similar performance on case tasks (e.g., OpenBioLLM-70B: 66.4% vs. Llama-3-70B-Instruct: 65% on JAMA cases), smaller biomedical models showed more pronounced underperformance (e.g., OpenBioLLM-8B: 30% vs. Llama-3-8B-Instruct: 64.3% on NEJM cases). Similar trends were observed across the CLUE (Clinical Language Understanding Evaluation) benchmark tasks, with general-purpose models often performing better on text generation, question answering, and coding tasks. Our results suggest that fine-tuning LLMs to biomedical data may not provide the expected benefits and may potentially lead to reduced performance, challenging prevailing assumptions about domain-specific adaptation of LLMs and highlighting the need for more rigorous evaluation frameworks in healthcare AI. Alternative approaches, such as retrieval-augmented generation, may be more effective in enhancing the biomedical capabilities of LLMs without compromising their general knowledge.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13833v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Felix J. Dorfner, Amin Dada, Felix Busch, Marcus R. Makowski, Tianyu Han, Daniel Truhn, Jens Kleesiek, Madhumita Sushil, Jacqueline Lammert, Lisa C. Adams, Keno K. Bressem</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge-Aware Reasoning over Multimodal Semi-structured Tables</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13860</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13860v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Existing datasets for tabular question answering typically focus exclusively on text within cells. However, real-world data is inherently multimodal, often blending images such as symbols, faces, icons, patterns, and charts with textual content in tables. With the evolution of AI models capable of multimodal reasoning, it is pertinent to assess their efficacy in handling such structured data. This study investigates whether current AI models can perform knowledge-aware reasoning on multimodal structured data. We explore their ability to reason on tables that integrate both images and text, introducing MMTabQA, a new dataset designed for this purpose. Our experiments highlight substantial challenges for current AI models in effectively integrating and interpreting multiple text and image inputs, understanding visual context, and comparing visual content across images. These findings establish our dataset as a robust benchmark for advancing AI's comprehension and capabilities in analyzing multimodal structured data.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13860v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Suyash Vardhan Mathur, Jainit Sushil Bafna, Kunal Kartik, Harshita Khandelwal, Manish Shrivastava, Vivek Gupta, Mohit Bansal, Dan Roth</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CodeGraph: Enhancing Graph Reasoning of LLMs with Code</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13863</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13863v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: With the increasing popularity of large language models (LLMs), reasoning on basic graph algorithm problems is an essential intermediate step in assessing their abilities to process and infer complex graph reasoning tasks. Existing methods usually convert graph-structured data to textual descriptions and then use LLMs for reasoning and computation. However, LLMs often produce computation errors on arithmetic parts in basic graph algorithm problems, such as counting number of edges. In addition, they struggle to control or understand the output of the reasoning process, raising concerns about whether LLMs are simply guessing. In this paper, we introduce CodeGraph, a method that encodes graph problem solutions as code. The methods solve new graph problems by learning from exemplars, generating programs, and executing them via a program interpreter. Using the few-shot setting, we evaluate CodeGraph with the base LLM being GPT-3.5 Turbo, Llama3-70B Instruct, Mixtral-8x22B Instruct, and Mixtral-8x7B Instruct. Experimental results on six tasks with six graph encoding methods in the GraphQA dataset demonstrate that CodeGraph can boost performance on graph reasoning tasks inside LLMs by 1.3% to 58.6%, depending on the task. Compared to the existing methods, CodeGraph demonstrates strong performance on arithmetic problems in graph tasks and offers a more controllable and interpretable approach to the reasoning process.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13863v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qiaolong Cai, Zhaowei Wang, Shizhe Diao, James Kwok, Yangqiu Song</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM with Relation Classifier for Document-Level Relation Extraction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13889</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13889v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) create a new paradigm for natural language processing. Despite their advancement, LLM-based methods still lag behind traditional approaches in document-level relation extraction (DocRE), a critical task for understanding complex entity relations. This paper investigates the causes of this performance gap, identifying the dispersion of attention by LLMs due to entity pairs without relations as a primary factor. We then introduce a novel classifier-LLM approach to DocRE. The proposed approach begins with a classifier specifically designed to select entity pair candidates exhibiting potential relations and thereby feeds them to LLM for the final relation extraction. This method ensures that during inference, the LLM's focus is directed primarily at entity pairs with relations. Experiments on DocRE benchmarks reveal that our method significantly outperforms recent LLM-based DocRE models and achieves competitive performance with several leading traditional DocRE models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13889v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xingzuo Li, Kehai Chen, Yunfei Long, Min Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SpeechCaps: Advancing Instruction-Based Universal Speech Models with Multi-Talker Speaking Style Captioning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13891</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13891v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Instruction-based speech processing is becoming popular. Studies show that training with multiple tasks boosts performance, but collecting diverse, large-scale tasks and datasets is expensive. Thus, it is highly desirable to design a fundamental task that benefits other downstream tasks. This paper introduces a multi-talker speaking style captioning task to enhance the understanding of speaker and prosodic information. We used large language models to generate descriptions for multi-talker speech. Then, we trained our model with pre-training on this captioning task followed by instruction tuning. Evaluation on Dynamic-SUPERB shows our model outperforming the baseline pre-trained only on single-talker tasks, particularly in speaker and emotion recognition. Additionally, tests on a multi-talker QA task reveal that current models struggle with attributes such as gender, pitch, and speaking rate. The code and dataset are available at https://github.com/cyhuang-tw/speechcaps.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13891v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chien-yu Huang, Min-Han Shih, Ke-Han Lu, Chi-Yuan Hsiao, Hung-yi Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLMs are Superior Feedback Providers: Bootstrapping Reasoning for Lie Detection with Self-Generated Feedback</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13915</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13915v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) excel at generating human-like dialogues and comprehending text. However, understanding the subtleties of complex exchanges in language remains a challenge. We propose a bootstrapping framework that leverages self-generated feedback to enhance LLM reasoning capabilities for lie detection. The framework consists of three stages: suggestion, feedback collection, and modification. In the suggestion stage, a cost-effective language model generates initial predictions based on game state and dialogue. The feedback-collection stage involves a language model providing feedback on these predictions. In the modification stage, a more advanced language model refines the initial predictions using the auto-generated feedback. We investigate the application of the proposed framework for detecting betrayal and deception in Diplomacy games, and compare it with feedback from professional human players. The LLM-generated feedback exhibits superior quality and significantly enhances the performance of the model. Our approach achieves a 39% improvement over the zero-shot baseline in lying-F1 without the need for any training data, rivaling state-of-the-art supervised learning results.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13915v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tanushree Banerjee, Richard Zhu, Runzhe Yang, Karthik Narasimhan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MobileQuant: Mobile-friendly Quantization for On-device Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13933</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13933v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have revolutionized language processing, delivering outstanding results across multiple applications. However, deploying LLMs on edge devices poses several challenges with respect to memory, energy, and compute costs, limiting their widespread use in devices such as mobile phones. A promising solution is to reduce the number of bits used to represent weights and activations. While existing works have found partial success at quantizing LLMs to lower bitwidths, e.g. 4-bit weights, quantizing activations beyond 16 bits often leads to large computational overheads due to poor on-device quantization support, or a considerable accuracy drop. Yet, 8-bit activations are very attractive for on-device deployment as they would enable LLMs to fully exploit mobile-friendly hardware, e.g. Neural Processing Units (NPUs). In this work, we make a first attempt to facilitate the on-device deployment of LLMs using integer-only quantization. We first investigate the limitations of existing quantization methods for on-device deployment, with a special focus on activation quantization. We then address these limitations by introducing a simple post-training quantization method, named MobileQuant, that extends previous weight equivalent transformation works by jointly optimizing the weight transformation and activation range parameters in an end-to-end manner. MobileQuant demonstrates superior capabilities over existing methods by 1) achieving near-lossless quantization on a wide range of LLM benchmarks, 2) reducing latency and energy consumption by 20\%-50\% compared to current on-device quantization strategies, 3) requiring limited compute budget, 4) being compatible with mobile-friendly compute units, e.g. NPU.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13933v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fuwen Tan, Royson Lee, {\L}ukasz Dudziak, Shell Xu Hu, Sourav Bhattacharya, Timothy Hospedales, Georgios Tzimiropoulos, Brais Martinez</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoT Rerailer: Enhancing the Reliability of Large Language Models in Complex Reasoning Tasks through Error Detection and Correction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13940</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13940v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Chain-of-Thought (CoT) prompting enhances Large Language Models (LLMs) complex reasoning abilities by generating intermediate steps. However, these steps can introduce hallucinations and accumulate errors. We propose the CoT Rerailer to address these challenges, employing self-consistency and multi-agent debate systems to identify and rectify errors in the reasoning process. The CoT Rerailer first selects the most logically correct Reasoning Path (RP) using consistency checks and critical evaluation by automated agents. It then engages a multi-agent debate system to propose and validate corrections to ensure the generation of an error-free intermediate logical path. The corrected steps are then used to generate a revised reasoning chain to further reduce hallucinations and enhance answer quality. We demonstrate the effectiveness of our approach across diverse question-answering datasets in various knowledge domains. The CoT Rerailer enhances the reliability of LLM-generated reasoning, contributing to more trustworthy AI driven decision-making processes.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13940v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Guangya Wan, Yuqi Wu, Jie Chen, Sheng Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bidirectional Awareness Induction in Autoregressive Seq2Seq Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13959</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13959v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Autoregressive Sequence-To-Sequence models are the foundation of many Deep Learning achievements in major research fields such as Vision and Natural Language Processing. Despite that, they still present significant limitations. For instance, when errors occur in the early steps of the prediction, the whole output is severely affected. Such reliance on previously predicted tokens and the inherent computational unfriendliness of sequential algorithms, motivated researchers to explore different architectures and methods in the search for bidirectional approaches. In this work, we introduce the Bidirectional Awareness Induction (BAI), a training method that leverages a subset of elements in the network, the Pivots, to perform bidirectional learning without breaking the autoregressive constraints. To showcase its flexibility, we apply the method to three architectures, the Transformer, ExpansionNet v2 and GPT, then perform experiments over three tasks. Experimental results showcase BAI's effectiveness on all selected tasks and architectures. In particular, we observed an increase of up to 2.4 CIDEr in Image-Captioning, 4.96 BLEU in Neural Machine Translation, and 1.16 ROUGE in Text Summarization compared to the respective baselines. Notably, BAI not only has a positive impact on models trained from scratch but on pre-trained models as well. Such an aspect, combined with the absence of architectural requirements synergizes well with the current trend of LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13959v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jia Cheng Hu, Roberto Cavicchioli, Alessandro Capotondi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reducing the Cost: Cross-Prompt Pre-Finetuning for Short Answer Scoring</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13966</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13966v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Automated Short Answer Scoring (SAS) is the task of automatically scoring a given input to a prompt based on rubrics and reference answers. Although SAS is useful in real-world applications, both rubrics and reference answers differ between prompts, thus requiring a need to acquire new data and train a model for each new prompt. Such requirements are costly, especially for schools and online courses where resources are limited and only a few prompts are used. In this work, we attempt to reduce this cost through a two-phase approach: train a model on existing rubrics and answers with gold score signals and finetune it on a new prompt. Specifically, given that scoring rubrics and reference answers differ for each prompt, we utilize key phrases, or representative expressions that the answer should contain to increase scores, and train a SAS model to learn the relationship between key phrases and answers using already annotated prompts (i.e., cross-prompts). Our experimental results show that finetuning on existing cross-prompt data with key phrases significantly improves scoring accuracy, especially when the training data is limited. Finally, our extensive analysis shows that it is crucial to design the model so that it can learn the task's general property.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13966v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1007/978-3-031-36272-9_7</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>AIED 2023. Lecture Notes in Computer Science(), vol 13916.pp.78-89. Springer</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Hiroaki Funayama, Yuya Asazuma, Yuichiroh Matsubayashi, Tomoya Mizumoto, Kentaro Inui</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TF-Attack: Transferable and Fast Adversarial Attacks on Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13985</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13985v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: With the great advancements in large language models (LLMs), adversarial attacks against LLMs have recently attracted increasing attention. We found that pre-existing adversarial attack methodologies exhibit limited transferability and are notably inefficient, particularly when applied to LLMs. In this paper, we analyze the core mechanisms of previous predominant adversarial attack methods, revealing that 1) the distributions of importance score differ markedly among victim models, restricting the transferability; 2) the sequential attack processes induces substantial time overheads. Based on the above two insights, we introduce a new scheme, named TF-Attack, for Transferable and Fast adversarial attacks on LLMs. TF-Attack employs an external LLM as a third-party overseer rather than the victim model to identify critical units within sentences. Moreover, TF-Attack introduces the concept of Importance Level, which allows for parallel substitutions of attacks. We conduct extensive experiments on 6 widely adopted benchmarks, evaluating the proposed method through both automatic and human metrics. Results show that our method consistently surpasses previous methods in transferability and delivers significant speed improvements, up to 20 times faster than earlier attack strategies.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13985v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zelin Li, Kehai Chen, Xuefeng Bai, Lemao Liu, Mingming Yang, Yang Xiang, Min Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Focused Large Language Models are Stable Many-Shot Learners</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13987</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13987v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In-Context Learning (ICL) enables large language models (LLMs) to achieve rapid task adaptation by learning from demonstrations. With the increase in available context length of LLMs, recent experiments have shown that the performance of ICL does not necessarily scale well in many-shot (demonstration) settings. We theoretically and experimentally confirm that the reason lies in more demonstrations dispersing the model attention from the query, hindering its understanding of key content. Inspired by how humans learn from examples, we propose a training-free method FocusICL, which conducts triviality filtering to avoid attention being diverted by unimportant contents at token-level and operates hierarchical attention to further ensure sufficient attention towards current query at demonstration-level. We also design an efficient hyperparameter searching strategy for FocusICL based on model perplexity of demonstrations. Comprehensive experiments validate that FocusICL achieves an average performance improvement of 5.2% over vanilla ICL and scales well with many-shot demonstrations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13987v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Peiwen Yuan, Shaoxiong Feng, Yiwei Li, Xinglin Wang, Yueqi Zhang, Chuyi Tan, Boyuan Pan, Heda Wang, Yao Hu, Kan Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Empowering Low-Resource Language ASR via Large-Scale Pseudo Labeling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14026</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14026v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this study, we tackle the challenge of limited labeled data for low-resource languages in ASR, focusing on Hindi. Specifically, we explore pseudo-labeling, by proposing a generic framework combining multiple ideas from existing works. Our framework integrates multiple base models for transcription and evaluators for assessing audio-transcript pairs, resulting in robust pseudo-labeling for low resource languages. We validate our approach with a new benchmark, IndicYT, comprising diverse YouTube audio files from multiple content categories. Our findings show that augmenting pseudo labeled data from YouTube with existing training data leads to significant performance improvements on IndicYT, without affecting performance on out-of-domain benchmarks, demonstrating the efficacy of pseudo-labeled data in enhancing ASR capabilities for low-resource languages. The benchmark, code and models developed as a part of this work will be made publicly available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14026v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kaushal Santosh Bhogale, Deovrat Mehendale, Niharika Parasa, Sathish Kumar Reddy G, Tahir Javed, Pratyush Kumar, Mitesh M. Khapra</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Depression Diagnosis with Chain-of-Thought Prompting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14053</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14053v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: When using AI to detect signs of depressive disorder, AI models habitually draw preemptive conclusions. We theorize that using chain-of-thought (CoT) prompting to evaluate Patient Health Questionnaire-8 (PHQ-8) scores will improve the accuracy of the scores determined by AI models. In our findings, when the models reasoned with CoT, the estimated PHQ-8 scores were consistently closer on average to the accepted true scores reported by each participant compared to when not using CoT. Our goal is to expand upon AI models' understanding of the intricacies of human conversation, allowing them to more effectively assess a patient's feelings and tone, therefore being able to more accurately discern mental disorder symptoms; ultimately, we hope to augment AI models' abilities, so that they can be widely accessible and used in the medical field.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14053v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Elysia Shi, Adithri Manda, London Chowdhury, Runeema Arun, Kevin Zhu, Michael Lam</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contrastive Learning Subspace for Text Clustering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14119</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14119v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Contrastive learning has been frequently investigated to learn effective representations for text clustering tasks. While existing contrastive learning-based text clustering methods only focus on modeling instance-wise semantic similarity relationships, they ignore contextual information and underlying relationships among all instances that needs to be clustered. In this paper, we propose a novel text clustering approach called Subspace Contrastive Learning (SCL) which models cluster-wise relationships among instances. Specifically, the proposed SCL consists of two main modules: (1) a self-expressive module that constructs virtual positive samples and (2) a contrastive learning module that further learns a discriminative subspace to capture task-specific cluster-wise relationships among texts. Experimental results show that the proposed SCL method not only has achieved superior results on multiple task clustering datasets but also has less complexity in positive sample construction.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14119v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qian Yong, Chen Chen, Xiabing Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Faceted Evaluation of Modeling Languages for Augmented Reality Applications -- The Case of ARWFML</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14137</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14137v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The evaluation of modeling languages for augmented reality applications poses particular challenges due to the three-dimensional environment they target. The previously introduced Augmented Reality Workflow Modeling Language (ARWFML) enables the model-based creation of augmented reality scenarios without programming knowledge. Building upon the first design cycle of the language's specification, this paper presents two further design iterations for refining the language based on multi-faceted evaluations. These include a comparative evaluation of implementation options and workflow capabilities, the introduction of a 3D notation, and the development of a new 3D modeling environment. On this basis, a comprehensibility study of the language was conducted. Thereby, we show how modeling languages for augmented reality can be evolved towards a maturity level suitable for empirical evaluations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14137v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.ET</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fabian Muff, Hans-Georg Fill</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crowd-Calibrator: Can Annotator Disagreement Inform Calibration in Subjective Tasks?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14141</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14141v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Subjective tasks in NLP have been mostly relegated to objective standards, where the gold label is decided by taking the majority vote. This obfuscates annotator disagreement and the inherent uncertainty of the label. We argue that subjectivity should factor into model decisions and play a direct role via calibration under a selective prediction setting. Specifically, instead of calibrating confidence purely from the model's perspective, we calibrate models for subjective tasks based on crowd worker agreement. Our method, Crowd-Calibrator, models the distance between the distribution of crowd worker labels and the model's own distribution over labels to inform whether the model should abstain from a decision. On two highly subjective tasks, hate speech detection and natural language inference, our experiments show Crowd-Calibrator either outperforms or achieves competitive performance with existing selective prediction baselines. Our findings highlight the value of bringing human decision-making into model predictions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14141v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Urja Khurana, Eric Nalisnick, Antske Fokkens, Swabha Swayamdipta</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the effect of Mental Models in User Interaction with an Adaptive Dialog Agent</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14154</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14154v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Mental models play an important role in whether user interaction with intelligent systems, such as dialog systems is successful or not. Adaptive dialog systems present the opportunity to align a dialog agent's behavior with heterogeneous user expectations. However, there has been little research into what mental models users form when interacting with a task-oriented dialog system, how these models affect users' interactions, or what role system adaptation can play in this process, making it challenging to avoid damage to human-AI partnership. In this work, we collect a new publicly available dataset for exploring user mental models about information seeking dialog systems. We demonstrate that users have a variety of conflicting mental models about such systems, the validity of which directly impacts the success of their interactions and perceived usability of system. Furthermore, we show that adapting a dialog agent's behavior to better align with users' mental models, even when done implicitly, can improve perceived usability, dialog efficiency, and success. To this end, we argue that implicit adaptation can be a valid strategy for task-oriented dialog systems, so long as developers first have a solid understanding of users' mental models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14154v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lindsey Vanderlyn, Dirk V\"ath, Ngoc Thang Vu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DSTI at LLMs4OL 2024 Task A: Intrinsic versus extrinsic knowledge for type classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14236</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14236v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We introduce semantic towers, an extrinsic knowledge representation method, and compare it to intrinsic knowledge in large language models for ontology learning. Our experiments show a trade-off between performance and semantic grounding for extrinsic knowledge compared to a fine-tuned model intrinsic knowledge. We report our findings on the Large Language Models for Ontology Learning (LLMs4OL) 2024 challenge.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14236v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hanna Abi Akl</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-supervised Speech Representations Still Struggle with African American Vernacular English</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14262</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14262v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Underperformance of ASR systems for speakers of African American Vernacular English (AAVE) and other marginalized language varieties is a well-documented phenomenon, and one that reinforces the stigmatization of these varieties. We investigate whether or not the recent wave of Self-Supervised Learning (SSL) speech models can close the gap in ASR performance between AAVE and Mainstream American English (MAE). We evaluate four SSL models (wav2vec 2.0, HuBERT, WavLM, and XLS-R) on zero-shot Automatic Speech Recognition (ASR) for these two varieties and find that these models perpetuate the bias in performance against AAVE. Additionally, the models have higher word error rates on utterances with more phonological and morphosyntactic features of AAVE. Despite the success of SSL speech models in improving ASR for low resource varieties, SSL pre-training alone may not bridge the gap between AAVE and MAE. Our code is publicly available at https://github.com/cmu-llab/s3m-aave.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14262v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kalvin Chang, Yi-Hui Chou, Jiatong Shi, Hsuan-Ming Chen, Nicole Holliday, Odette Scharenborg, David R. Mortensen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predictability and Causality in Spanish and English Natural Language Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14283</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14283v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In recent years, the field of Natural Language Generation (NLG) has been boosted by the recent advances in deep learning technologies. Nonetheless, these new data-intensive methods introduce language-dependent disparities in NLG as the main training data sets are in English. Also, most neural NLG systems use decoder-only (causal) transformer language models, which work well for English, but were not designed with other languages in mind. In this work we depart from the hypothesis that they may introduce generation bias in target languages with less rigid word ordering, subject omission, or different attachment preferences for relative clauses, so that for these target languages other language generation strategies may be more desirable. This paper first compares causal and non-causal language modeling for English and Spanish, two languages with different grammatical structures and over 1.5 billion and 0.5 billion speakers, respectively. For this purpose, we define a novel metric of average causal and non-causal context-conditioned entropy of the grammatical category distribution for both languages as an information-theoretic a priori approach. The evaluation of natural text sources (such as training data) in both languages reveals lower average non-causal conditional entropy in Spanish and lower causal conditional entropy in English. According to this experiment, Spanish is more predictable than English given a non-causal context. Then, by applying a conditional relative entropy metric to text generation experiments, we obtain as insights that the best performance is respectively achieved with causal NLG in English, and with non-causal NLG in Spanish. These insights support further research in NLG in Spanish using bidirectional transformer language models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14283v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1109/ACCESS.2024.3420710</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Busto-Casti\~neira, A., Casta\~no, F. J. G., Garc\'ia-M\'endez, S., &amp; De Arriba-P\'erez, F. (2024). Predictability and Causality in Spanish and English Natural Language Generation. IEEE Access</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Andrea Busto-Casti\~neira, Francisco J. Gonz\'alez-Casta\~no, Silvia Garc\'ia-M\'endez, Francisco de Arriba-P\'erez</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM-3D Print: Large Language Models To Monitor and Control 3D Printing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14307</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14307v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Industry 4.0 has revolutionized manufacturing by driving digitalization and shifting the paradigm toward additive manufacturing (AM). Fused Deposition Modeling (FDM), a key AM technology, enables the creation of highly customized, cost-effective products with minimal material waste through layer-by-layer extrusion, posing a significant challenge to traditional subtractive methods. However, the susceptibility of material extrusion techniques to errors often requires expert intervention to detect and mitigate defects that can severely compromise product quality. While automated error detection and machine learning models exist, their generalizability across diverse 3D printer setups, firmware, and sensors is limited, and deep learning methods require extensive labeled datasets, hindering scalability and adaptability. To address these challenges, we present a process monitoring and control framework that leverages pre-trained Large Language Models (LLMs) alongside 3D printers to detect and address printing defects. The LLM evaluates print quality by analyzing images captured after each layer or print segment, identifying failure modes and querying the printer for relevant parameters. It then generates and executes a corrective action plan. We validated the effectiveness of the proposed framework in identifying defects by comparing it against a control group of engineers with diverse AM expertise. Our evaluation demonstrated that LLM-based agents not only accurately identify common 3D printing errors, such as inconsistent extrusion, stringing, warping, and layer adhesion, but also effectively determine the parameters causing these failures and autonomously correct them without any need for human intervention.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14307v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yayati Jadhav, Peter Pak, Amir Barati Farimani</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Claim Verification in the Age of Large Language Models: A Survey</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14317</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14317v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The large and ever-increasing amount of data available on the Internet coupled with the laborious task of manual claim and fact verification has sparked the interest in the development of automated claim verification systems. Several deep learning and transformer-based models have been proposed for this task over the years. With the introduction of Large Language Models (LLMs) and their superior performance in several NLP tasks, we have seen a surge of LLM-based approaches to claim verification along with the use of novel methods such as Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG). In this survey, we present a comprehensive account of recent claim verification frameworks using LLMs. We describe the different components of the claim verification pipeline used in these frameworks in detail including common approaches to retrieval, prompting, and fine-tuning. Finally, we describe publicly available English datasets created for this task.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14317v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alphaeus Dmonte, Roland Oruche, Marcos Zampieri, Prasad Calyam, Isabelle Augenstein</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing Contamination in Large Language Models: Introducing the LogProber method</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14352</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14352v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In machine learning, contamination refers to situations where testing data leak into the training set. The issue is particularly relevant for the evaluation of the performance of Large Language Models (LLMs), which are generally trained on gargantuan, and generally opaque, corpora of text scraped from the world wide web. Developing tools to detect contamination is therefore crucial to be able to fairly and properly track the evolution of the performance of LLMs. Most recent works in the field are not tailored to quantify contamination on short sequences of text like we find in psychology questionnaires. In the present paper we introduce LogProber, a novel, efficient, algorithm that we show able to detect contamination using token probability in given sentences. In the second part we investigate the limitations of the method and discuss how different training methods can contaminate models without leaving traces in the token probabilities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14352v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nicolas Yax, Pierre-Yves Oudeyer, Stefano Palminteri</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Probing Causality Manipulation of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14380</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14380v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have shown various ability on natural language processing, including problems about causality. It is not intuitive for LLMs to command causality, since pretrained models usually work on statistical associations, and do not focus on causes and effects in sentences. So that probing internal manipulation of causality is necessary for LLMs. This paper proposes a novel approach to probe causality manipulation hierarchically, by providing different shortcuts to models and observe behaviors. We exploit retrieval augmented generation (RAG) and in-context learning (ICL) for models on a designed causality classification task. We conduct experiments on mainstream LLMs, including GPT-4 and some smaller and domain-specific models. Our results suggest that LLMs can detect entities related to causality and recognize direct causal relationships. However, LLMs lack specialized cognition for causality, merely treating them as part of the global semantic of the sentence.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14380v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chenyang Zhang, Haibo Tong, Bin Zhang, Dongyu Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Language-specific Calibration for Pruning Multilingual Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14398</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14398v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent advances in large language model (LLM) pruning have shown state-of-the-art compression results in post-training and retraining-free settings while maintaining high predictive performance. However, such research mainly considers calibrating pruning using English text, despite the multilingual nature of modern LLMs and their frequent uses in non-English languages. In this paper, we set out to explore effective strategies for calibrating the pruning of multilingual language models. We present the first comprehensive empirical study, comparing different calibration languages for pruning multilingual models across diverse tasks, models, and state-of-the-art pruning techniques. Our results present practical suggestions, for example, calibrating in the target language can efficiently yield lower perplexity, but does not necessarily benefit downstream tasks. Our further analysis experiments unveil that calibration in the target language mainly contributes to preserving language-specific features related to fluency and coherence, but might not contribute to capturing language-agnostic features such as language understanding and reasoning. Last, we provide practical recommendations for future practitioners.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14398v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Simon Kurz, Zhixue Zhao, Jian-Jia Chen, Lucie Flek</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MEDSAGE: Enhancing Robustness of Medical Dialogue Summarization to ASR Errors with LLM-generated Synthetic Dialogues</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14418</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14418v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Automatic Speech Recognition (ASR) systems are pivotal in transcribing speech into text, yet the errors they introduce can significantly degrade the performance of downstream tasks like summarization. This issue is particularly pronounced in clinical dialogue summarization, a low-resource domain where supervised data for fine-tuning is scarce, necessitating the use of ASR models as black-box solutions. Employing conventional data augmentation for enhancing the noise robustness of summarization models is not feasible either due to the unavailability of sufficient medical dialogue audio recordings and corresponding ASR transcripts. To address this challenge, we propose MEDSAGE, an approach for generating synthetic samples for data augmentation using Large Language Models (LLMs). Specifically, we leverage the in-context learning capabilities of LLMs and instruct them to generate ASR-like errors based on a few available medical dialogue examples with audio recordings. Experimental results show that LLMs can effectively model ASR noise, and incorporating this noisy data into the training process significantly improves the robustness and accuracy of medical dialogue summarization systems. This approach addresses the challenges of noisy ASR outputs in critical applications, offering a robust solution to enhance the reliability of clinical dialogue summarization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14418v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kuluhan Binici, Abhinav Ramesh Kashyap, Viktor Schlegel, Andy T. Liu, Vijay Prakash Dwivedi, Thanh-Tung Nguyen, Xiaoxue Gao, Nancy F. Chen, Stefan Winkler</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Large Language Models on Spatial Tasks: A Multi-Task Benchmarking Study</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14438</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14438v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The advent of large language models such as ChatGPT, Gemini, and others has underscored the importance of evaluating their diverse capabilities, ranging from natural language understanding to code generation. However, their performance on spatial tasks has not been comprehensively assessed. This study addresses this gap by introducing a novel multi-task spatial evaluation dataset, designed to systematically explore and compare the performance of several advanced models on spatial tasks. The dataset encompasses twelve distinct task types, including spatial understanding and path planning, each with verified, accurate answers. We evaluated multiple models, including OpenAI's gpt-3.5-turbo, gpt-4o, and ZhipuAI's glm-4, through a two-phase testing approach. Initially, we conducted zero-shot testing, followed by categorizing the dataset by difficulty and performing prompt tuning tests. Results indicate that gpt-4o achieved the highest overall accuracy in the first phase, with an average of 71.3%. Although moonshot-v1-8k slightly underperformed overall, it surpassed gpt-4o in place name recognition tasks. The study also highlights the impact of prompt strategies on model performance in specific tasks. For example, the Chain-of-Thought (COT) strategy increased gpt-4o's accuracy in path planning from 12.4% to 87.5%, while a one-shot strategy enhanced moonshot-v1-8k's accuracy in mapping tasks from 10.1% to 76.3%.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14438v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Liuchang Xu Shuo Zhao, Qingming Lin, Luyao Chen, Qianqian Luo, Sensen Wu, Xinyue Ye, Hailin Feng, Zhenhong Du</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explicit Inductive Inference using Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14467</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14467v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) are reported to hold undesirable attestation bias on inference tasks: when asked to predict if a premise P entails a hypothesis H, instead of considering H's conditional truthfulness entailed by P, LLMs tend to use the out-of-context truth label of H as a fragile proxy. In this paper, we propose a pipeline that exploits this bias to do explicit inductive inference. Our pipeline uses an LLM to transform a premise into a set of attested alternatives, and then aggregate answers of the derived new entailment inquiries to support the original inference prediction. On a directional predicate entailment benchmark, we demonstrate that by applying this simple pipeline, we can improve the overall performance of LLMs on inference and substantially alleviate the impact of their attestation bias.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14467v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tianyang Liu, Tianyi Li, Liang Cheng, Mark Steedman</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Step-by-Step Unmasking for Parameter-Efficient Fine-tuning of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14470</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14470v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Fine-tuning large language models (LLMs) on downstream tasks requires substantial computational resources. A class of parameter-efficient fine-tuning (PEFT) aims to mitigate these computational challenges by selectively fine-tuning only a small fraction of the model parameters. Although computationally efficient, these techniques often fail to match the performance of fully fine-tuned models, primarily due to inherent biases introduced during parameter selection. Traditional selective PEFT techniques use a fixed set of parameters based on a predefined budget (a process also known as unmasking), failing to capture parameter importance dynamically and often ending up exceeding the budget. We introduce $\text{ID}^3$, a novel selective PEFT method that calculates parameter importance continually and dynamically unmasks parameters by balancing exploration and exploitation in parameter selection. Our empirical study on 15 tasks spanning natural language understanding and generative tasks demonstrates the effectiveness of our method compared to fixed-masking-based PEFT techniques. We analytically show that $\text{ID}^3$ reduces the number of gradient updates by a factor of two, enhancing computational efficiency. $\text{ID}^3$ is robust to random initialization of neurons and, therefore, can be seamlessly integrated into existing additive and reparametrization-based PEFT modules such as adapters and LoRA for dynamic sparsification.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14470v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aradhye Agarwal, Suhas K Ramesh, Ayan Sengupta, Tanmoy Chakraborty</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Bias and Prediction Metrics to Characterise the Fairness of Machine Learning for Equity-Centered Public Health Decision-Making: A Narrative Review</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13295</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13295v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Background: The rapid advancement of Machine Learning (ML) represents novel opportunities to enhance public health research, surveillance, and decision-making. However, there is a lack of comprehensive understanding of algorithmic bias -- systematic errors in predicted population health outcomes -- resulting from the public health application of ML. The objective of this narrative review is to explore the types of bias generated by ML and quantitative metrics to assess these biases.
  Methods: We performed search on PubMed, MEDLINE, IEEE (Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers), ACM (Association for Computing Machinery) Digital Library, Science Direct, and Springer Nature. We used keywords to identify studies describing types of bias and metrics to measure these in the domain of ML and public and population health published in English between 2008 and 2023, inclusive.
  Results: A total of 72 articles met the inclusion criteria. Our review identified the commonly described types of bias and quantitative metrics to assess these biases from an equity perspective.
  Conclusion: The review will help formalize the evaluation framework for ML on public health from an equity perspective.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13295v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shaina Raza, Arash Shaban-Nejad, Elham Dolatabadi, Hiroshi Mamiya</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Guide to Fine-Tuning LLMs from Basics to Breakthroughs: An Exhaustive Review of Technologies, Research, Best Practices, Applied Research Challenges and Opportunities</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13296</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13296v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This report examines the fine-tuning of Large Language Models (LLMs), integrating theoretical insights with practical applications. It outlines the historical evolution of LLMs from traditional Natural Language Processing (NLP) models to their pivotal role in AI. A comparison of fine-tuning methodologies, including supervised, unsupervised, and instruction-based approaches, highlights their applicability to different tasks. The report introduces a structured seven-stage pipeline for fine-tuning LLMs, spanning data preparation, model initialization, hyperparameter tuning, and model deployment. Emphasis is placed on managing imbalanced datasets and optimization techniques. Parameter-efficient methods like Low-Rank Adaptation (LoRA) and Half Fine-Tuning are explored for balancing computational efficiency with performance. Advanced techniques such as memory fine-tuning, Mixture of Experts (MoE), and Mixture of Agents (MoA) are discussed for leveraging specialized networks and multi-agent collaboration. The report also examines novel approaches like Proximal Policy Optimization (PPO) and Direct Preference Optimization (DPO), which align LLMs with human preferences, alongside pruning and routing optimizations to improve efficiency. Further sections cover validation frameworks, post-deployment monitoring, and inference optimization, with attention to deploying LLMs on distributed and cloud-based platforms. Emerging areas such as multimodal LLMs, fine-tuning for audio and speech, and challenges related to scalability, privacy, and accountability are also addressed. This report offers actionable insights for researchers and practitioners navigating LLM fine-tuning in an evolving landscape.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13296v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Venkatesh Balavadhani Parthasarathy, Ahtsham Zafar, Aafaq Khan, Arsalan Shahid</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LalaEval: A Holistic Human Evaluation Framework for Domain-Specific Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13338</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13338v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This paper introduces LalaEval, a holistic framework designed for the human evaluation of domain-specific large language models (LLMs). LalaEval proposes a comprehensive suite of end-to-end protocols that cover five main components including domain specification, criteria establishment, benchmark dataset creation, construction of evaluation rubrics, and thorough analysis and interpretation of evaluation outcomes. This initiative aims to fill a crucial research gap by providing a systematic methodology for conducting standardized human evaluations within specific domains, a practice that, despite its widespread application, lacks substantial coverage in the literature and human evaluation are often criticized to be less reliable due to subjective factors, so standardized procedures adapted to the nuanced requirements of specific domains or even individual organizations are in great need. Furthermore, the paper demonstrates the framework's application within the logistics industry, presenting domain-specific evaluation benchmarks, datasets, and a comparative analysis of LLMs for the logistics domain use, highlighting the framework's capacity to elucidate performance differences and guide model selection and development for domain-specific LLMs. Through real-world deployment, the paper underscores the framework's effectiveness in advancing the field of domain-specific LLM evaluation, thereby contributing significantly to the ongoing discussion on LLMs' practical utility and performance in domain-specific applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13338v1</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chongyan Sun, Ken Lin, Shiwei Wang, Hulong Wu, Chengfei Fu, Zhen Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DrugAgent: Explainable Drug Repurposing Agent with Large Language Model-based Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13378</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13378v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Drug repurposing offers a promising avenue for accelerating drug development by identifying new therapeutic potentials of existing drugs. In this paper, we propose a multi-agent framework to enhance the drug repurposing process using state-of-the-art machine learning techniques and knowledge integration. Our framework comprises several specialized agents: an AI Agent trains robust drug-target interaction (DTI) models; a Knowledge Graph Agent utilizes the drug-gene interaction database (DGIdb), DrugBank, Comparative Toxicogenomics Database (CTD), and Search Tool for Interactions of Chemicals (STITCH) to systematically extract DTIs; and a Search Agent interacts with biomedical literature to annotate and verify computational predictions. By integrating outputs from these agents, our system effectively harnesses diverse data sources, including external databases, to propose viable repurposing candidates. Preliminary results demonstrate the potential of our approach in not only predicting drug-disease interactions but also in reducing the time and cost associated with traditional drug discovery methods. This paper highlights the scalability of multi-agent systems in biomedical research and their role in driving innovation in drug repurposing. Our approach not only outperforms existing methods in predicting drug repurposing potential but also provides interpretable results, paving the way for more efficient and cost-effective drug discovery processes.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13378v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>q-bio.QM</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yoshitaka Inoue, Tianci Song, Tianfan Fu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Law of Next-Token Prediction in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13442</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13442v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have been widely employed across various application domains, yet their black-box nature poses significant challenges to understanding how these models process input data internally to make predictions. In this paper, we introduce a precise and quantitative law that governs the learning of contextualized token embeddings through intermediate layers in pre-trained LLMs for next-token prediction. Our findings reveal that each layer contributes equally to enhancing prediction accuracy, from the lowest to the highest layer -- a universal phenomenon observed across a diverse array of open-source LLMs, built on architectures such as Transformer, RWKV, and Mamba. We demonstrate that this law offers new perspectives and insights to inform and guide practices in LLM development and applications, including model scaling, pre-training tasks, and information flow. Overall, our law enables more fine-grained approaches to the design, training, and interpretation of LLMs through scrutinizing their internal data processing mechanisms.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13442v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hangfeng He, Weijie J. Su</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ancient but Digitized: Developing Handwritten Optical Character Recognition for East Syriac Script Through Creating KHAMIS Dataset</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13631</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13631v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Many languages have vast amounts of handwritten texts, such as ancient scripts about folktale stories and historical narratives or contemporary documents and letters. Digitization of those texts has various applications, such as daily tasks, cultural studies, and historical research. Syriac is an ancient, endangered, and low-resourced language that has not received the attention it requires and deserves. This paper reports on a research project aimed at developing a optical character recognition (OCR) model based on the handwritten Syriac texts as a starting point to build more digital services for this endangered language. A dataset was created, KHAMIS (inspired by the East Syriac poet, Khamis bar Qardahe), which consists of handwritten sentences in the East Syriac script. We used it to fine-tune the Tesseract-OCR engine's pretrained Syriac model on handwritten data. The data was collected from volunteers capable of reading and writing in the language to create KHAMIS. KHAMIS currently consists of 624 handwritten Syriac sentences collected from 31 university students and one professor, and it will be partially available online and the whole dataset available in the near future for development and research purposes. As a result, the handwritten OCR model was able to achieve a character error rate of 1.097-1.610% and 8.963-10.490% on both training and evaluation sets, respectively, and both a character error rate of 18.89-19.71% and a word error rate of 62.83-65.42% when evaluated on the test set, which is twice as better than the default Syriac model of Tesseract.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13631v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ameer Majeed, Hossein Hassani</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GPT-4 Emulates Average-Human Emotional Cognition from a Third-Person Perspective</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13718</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13718v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This paper extends recent investigations on the emotional reasoning abilities of Large Language Models (LLMs). Current research on LLMs has not directly evaluated the distinction between how LLMs predict the self-attribution of emotions and the perception of others' emotions. We first look at carefully crafted emotion-evoking stimuli, originally designed to find patterns of brain neural activity representing fine-grained inferred emotional attributions of others. We show that GPT-4 is especially accurate in reasoning about such stimuli. This suggests LLMs agree with humans' attributions of others' emotions in stereotypical scenarios remarkably more than self-attributions of emotions in idiosyncratic situations. To further explore this, our second study utilizes a dataset containing annotations from both the author and a third-person perspective. We find that GPT-4's interpretations align more closely with human judgments about the emotions of others than with self-assessments. Notably, conventional computational models of emotion primarily rely on self-reported ground truth as the gold standard. However, an average observer's standpoint, which LLMs appear to have adopted, might be more relevant for many downstream applications, at least in the absence of individual information and adequate safety considerations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13718v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ala N. Tak, Jonathan Gratch</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Literary and Colloquial Tamil Dialect Identification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13739</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13739v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Culture and language evolve together. The old literary form of Tamil is used commonly for writing and the contemporary colloquial Tamil is used for speaking. Human-computer interaction applications require Colloquial Tamil (CT) to make it more accessible and easy for the everyday user and, it requires Literary Tamil (LT) when information is needed in a formal written format. Continuing the use of LT alongside CT in computer aided language learning applications will both preserve LT, and provide ease of use via CT, at the same time. Hence there is a need for the conversion between LT and CT dialects, which demands as a first step, dialect identification. Dialect Identification (DID) of LT and CT is an unexplored area of research. In the current work, keeping the nuances of both these dialects in mind, five methods are explored which include two implicit methods - Gaussian Mixture Model (GMM) and Convolutional Neural Network (CNN); two explicit methods - Parallel Phone Recognition (PPR) and Parallel Large Vocabulary Continuous Speech Recognition (P-LVCSR); two versions of the proposed explicit Unified Phone Recognition method (UPR-1 and UPR-2). These methods vary based on: the need for annotated data, the size of the unit, the way in which modelling is carried out, and the way in which the final decision is made. Even though the average duration of the test utterances is less - 4.9s for LT and 2.5s for CT - the systems performed well, offering the following identification accuracies: 87.72% (GMM), 93.97% (CNN), 89.24% (PPR), 94.21% (P-LVCSR), 88.57% (UPR-1), 93.53% (UPR-1 with P-LVCSR), 94.55% (UPR-2), and 95.61% (UPR-2 with P-LVCSR).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13739v1</guid>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1007/s00034-022-01971-2</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Circuits Syst Signal Process 41, 4004-4027 (2022)</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>M. Nanmalar, P. Vijayalakshmi, T. Nagarajan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LowCLIP: Adapting the CLIP Model Architecture for Low-Resource Languages in Multimodal Image Retrieval Task</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13909</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13909v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This research explores the development of multimodal vision-language models for image retrieval in low-resource languages, specifically Azerbaijani. Existing vision-language models primarily support high-resource languages, and fine-tuning them remains computationally demanding. To address challenges in vision-language retrieval for low-resource languages, we integrated the CLIP model architecture and employed several techniques to balance computational efficiency with performance. These techniques include synthetic data generation through machine translation, image augmentation, and further training the attention mechanisms of transformer-based models with domain-specific data. We integrated Multilingual BERT as a text encoder with image encoders like ResNet50, EfficientNet0, Vision Transformer (ViT), and Tiny Swin Transformer. Our study found that models like EfficientNet0 and Tiny Swin Transformer perform best on the datasets they were trained on, such as COCO, Flickr30k, and Flickr8k. Augmentation techniques boosted EfficientNet0 MAP on Flickr30k from 0.84 to 0.87 and ResNet50 MAP on MSCOCO from 0.70 to 0.80, contributing to a new state of the art in vision-language retrieval. We share our configurations and results to support further research. Code and pre-trained models are available at https://github.com/aliasgerovs/azclip.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13909v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ali Asgarov, Samir Rustamov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prediction of COPD Using Machine Learning, Clinical Summary Notes, and Vital Signs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13958</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13958v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) is a chronic inflammatory lung disease that causes obstructed airflow from the lungs. In the United States, more than 15.7 million Americans have been diagnosed with COPD, with 96% of individuals living with at least one other chronic health condition. It is the 4th leading cause of death in the country. Over 2.2 million patients are admitted to hospitals annually due to COPD exacerbations. Monitoring and predicting patient exacerbations on-time could save their life. This paper presents two different predictive models to predict COPD exacerbation using AI and natural language processing (NLP) approaches. These models use respiration summary notes, symptoms, and vital signs. To train and test these models, data records containing physiologic signals and vital signs time series were used. These records were captured from patient monitors and comprehensive clinical data obtained from hospital medical information systems for tens of thousands of Intensive Care Unit (ICU) patients. We achieved an area under the Receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve of 0.82 in detection and prediction of COPD exacerbation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13958v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Negar Orangi-Fard</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AgentMove: Predicting Human Mobility Anywhere Using Large Language Model based Agentic Framework</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13986</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13986v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Human mobility prediction plays a crucial role in various real-world applications. Although deep learning based models have shown promising results over the past decade, their reliance on extensive private mobility data for training and their inability to perform zero-shot predictions, have hindered further advancements. Recently, attempts have been made to apply large language models (LLMs) to mobility prediction task. However, their performance has been constrained by the absence of a systematic design of workflow. They directly generate the final output using LLMs, which limits the potential of LLMs to uncover complex mobility patterns and underestimates their extensive reserve of global geospatial knowledge. In this paper, we introduce AgentMove, a systematic agentic prediction framework to achieve generalized mobility prediction for any cities worldwide. In AgentMove, we first decompose the mobility prediction task into three sub-tasks and then design corresponding modules to complete these subtasks, including spatial-temporal memory for individual mobility pattern mining, world knowledge generator for modeling the effects of urban structure and collective knowledge extractor for capturing the shared patterns among population. Finally, we combine the results of three modules and conduct a reasoning step to generate the final predictions. Extensive experiments on mobility data from two sources in 12 cities demonstrate that AgentMove outperforms the best baseline more than 8% in various metrics and it shows robust predictions with various LLMs as base and also less geographical bias across cities. Codes and data can be found in https://github.com/tsinghua-fib-lab/AgentMove.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13986v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jie Feng, Yuwei Du, Jie Zhao, Yong Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SurGen: Text-Guided Diffusion Model for Surgical Video Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14028</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14028v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Diffusion-based video generation models have made significant strides, producing outputs with improved visual fidelity, temporal coherence, and user control. These advancements hold great promise for improving surgical education by enabling more realistic, diverse, and interactive simulation environments. In this study, we introduce SurGen, a text-guided diffusion model tailored for surgical video synthesis, producing the highest resolution and longest duration videos among existing surgical video generation models. We validate the visual and temporal quality of the outputs using standard image and video generation metrics. Additionally, we assess their alignment to the corresponding text prompts through a deep learning classifier trained on surgical data. Our results demonstrate the potential of diffusion models to serve as valuable educational tools for surgical trainees.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14028v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Joseph Cho, Samuel Schmidgall, Cyril Zakka, Mrudang Mathur, Rohan Shad, William Hiesinger</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explaining Vision-Language Similarities in Dual Encoders with Feature-Pair Attributions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14153</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14153v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Dual encoder architectures like CLIP models map two types of inputs into a shared embedding space and learn similarities between them. However, it is not understood how such models compare two inputs. Here, we address this research gap with two contributions. First, we derive a method to attribute predictions of any differentiable dual encoder onto feature-pair interactions between its inputs. Second, we apply our method to CLIP-type models and show that they learn fine-grained correspondences between parts of captions and regions in images. They match objects across input modes and also account for mismatches. However, this visual-linguistic grounding ability heavily varies between object classes, depends on the training data distribution, and largely improves after in-domain training. Using our method we can identify knowledge gaps about specific object classes in individual models and can monitor their improvement upon fine-tuning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14153v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lucas M\"oller, Pascal Tilli, Ngoc Thang Vu, Sebastian Pad\'o</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epidemic Information Extraction for Event-Based Surveillance using Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14277</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14277v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This paper presents a novel approach to epidemic surveillance, leveraging the power of Artificial Intelligence and Large Language Models (LLMs) for effective interpretation of unstructured big data sources, like the popular ProMED and WHO Disease Outbreak News. We explore several LLMs, evaluating their capabilities in extracting valuable epidemic information. We further enhance the capabilities of the LLMs using in-context learning, and test the performance of an ensemble model incorporating multiple open-source LLMs. The findings indicate that LLMs can significantly enhance the accuracy and timeliness of epidemic modelling and forecasting, offering a promising tool for managing future pandemic events.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14277v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CE</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1007/978-981-97-4581-4_17</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Lecture Notes in Networks and Systems, 2024, vol 1011, pages 241-252. Springer, Singapore</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Sergio Consoli, Peter Markov, Nikolaos I. Stilianakis, Lorenzo Bertolini, Antonio Puertas Gallardo, Mario Ceresa</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Foundation Models for Music: A Survey</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14340</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14340v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In recent years, foundation models (FMs) such as large language models (LLMs) and latent diffusion models (LDMs) have profoundly impacted diverse sectors, including music. This comprehensive review examines state-of-the-art (SOTA) pre-trained models and foundation models in music, spanning from representation learning, generative learning and multimodal learning. We first contextualise the significance of music in various industries and trace the evolution of AI in music. By delineating the modalities targeted by foundation models, we discover many of the music representations are underexplored in FM development. Then, emphasis is placed on the lack of versatility of previous methods on diverse music applications, along with the potential of FMs in music understanding, generation and medical application. By comprehensively exploring the details of the model pre-training paradigm, architectural choices, tokenisation, finetuning methodologies and controllability, we emphasise the important topics that should have been well explored, like instruction tuning and in-context learning, scaling law and emergent ability, as well as long-sequence modelling etc. A dedicated section presents insights into music agents, accompanied by a thorough analysis of datasets and evaluations essential for pre-training and downstream tasks. Finally, by underscoring the vital importance of ethical considerations, we advocate that following research on FM for music should focus more on such issues as interpretability, transparency, human responsibility, and copyright issues. The paper offers insights into future challenges and trends on FMs for music, aiming to shape the trajectory of human-AI collaboration in the music realm.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14340v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yinghao Ma, Anders {\O}land, Anton Ragni, Bleiz MacSen Del Sette, Charalampos Saitis, Chris Donahue, Chenghua Lin, Christos Plachouras, Emmanouil Benetos, Elio Quinton, Elona Shatri, Fabio Morreale, Ge Zhang, Gy\"orgy Fazekas, Gus Xia, Huan Zhang, Ilaria Manco, Jiawen Huang, Julien Guinot, Liwei Lin, Luca Marinelli, Max W. Y. Lam, Megha Sharma, Qiuqiang Kong, Roger B. Dannenberg, Ruibin Yuan, Shangda Wu, Shih-Lun Wu, Shuqi Dai, Shun Lei, Shiyin Kang, Simon Dixon, Wenhu Chen, Wehhao Huang, Xingjian Du, Xingwei Qu, Xu Tan, Yizhi Li, Zeyue Tian, Zhiyong Wu, Zhizheng Wu, Ziyang Ma, Ziyu Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SWE-bench-java: A GitHub Issue Resolving Benchmark for Java</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14354</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14354v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: GitHub issue resolving is a critical task in software engineering, recently gaining significant attention in both industry and academia. Within this task, SWE-bench has been released to evaluate issue resolving capabilities of large language models (LLMs), but has so far only focused on Python version. However, supporting more programming languages is also important, as there is a strong demand in industry. As a first step toward multilingual support, we have developed a Java version of SWE-bench, called SWE-bench-java. We have publicly released the dataset, along with the corresponding Docker-based evaluation environment and leaderboard, which will be continuously maintained and updated in the coming months. To verify the reliability of SWE-bench-java, we implement a classic method SWE-agent and test several powerful LLMs on it. As is well known, developing a high-quality multi-lingual benchmark is time-consuming and labor-intensive, so we welcome contributions through pull requests or collaboration to accelerate its iteration and refinement, paving the way for fully automated programming.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14354v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Daoguang Zan, Zhirong Huang, Ailun Yu, Shaoxin Lin, Yifan Shi, Wei Liu, Dong Chen, Zongshuai Qi, Hao Yu, Lei Yu, Dezhi Ran, Muhan Zeng, Bo Shen, Pan Bian, Guangtai Liang, Bei Guan, Pengjie Huang, Tao Xie, Yongji Wang, Qianxiang Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering Knowledge Gaps in Radiology Report Generation Models through Knowledge Graphs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14397</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14397v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recent advancements in artificial intelligence have significantly improved the automatic generation of radiology reports. However, existing evaluation methods fail to reveal the models' understanding of radiological images and their capacity to achieve human-level granularity in descriptions. To bridge this gap, we introduce a system, named ReXKG, which extracts structured information from processed reports to construct a comprehensive radiology knowledge graph. We then propose three metrics to evaluate the similarity of nodes (ReXKG-NSC), distribution of edges (ReXKG-AMS), and coverage of subgraphs (ReXKG-SCS) across various knowledge graphs. We conduct an in-depth comparative analysis of AI-generated and human-written radiology reports, assessing the performance of both specialist and generalist models. Our study provides a deeper understanding of the capabilities and limitations of current AI models in radiology report generation, offering valuable insights for improving model performance and clinical applicability.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14397v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoman Zhang, Juli\'an N. Acosta, Hong-Yu Zhou, Pranav Rajpurkar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHARTOM: A Visual Theory-of-Mind Benchmark for Multimodal Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14419</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14419v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We introduce CHARTOM, a visual theory-of-mind benchmark for multimodal large language models. CHARTOM consists of specially designed data visualizing charts. Given a chart, a language model needs to not only correctly comprehend the chart (the FACT question) but also judge if the chart will be misleading to a human reader (the MIND question). Both questions have significant societal benefits. We detail the construction of the CHARTOM benchmark including its calibration on human performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14419v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shubham Bharti, Shiyun Cheng, Jihyun Rho, Martina Rao, Xiaojin Zhu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Practitioner's Guide to Continual Multimodal Pretraining</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14471</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14471v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Multimodal foundation models serve numerous applications at the intersection of vision and language. Still, despite being pretrained on extensive data, they become outdated over time. To keep models updated, research into continual pretraining mainly explores scenarios with either (1) infrequent, indiscriminate updates on large-scale new data, or (2) frequent, sample-level updates. However, practical model deployment often operates in the gap between these two limit cases, as real-world applications often demand adaptation to specific subdomains, tasks or concepts -- spread over the entire, varying life cycle of a model. In this work, we complement current perspectives on continual pretraining through a research test bed as well as provide comprehensive guidance for effective continual model updates in such scenarios. We first introduce FoMo-in-Flux, a continual multimodal pretraining benchmark with realistic compute constraints and practical deployment requirements, constructed over 63 datasets with diverse visual and semantic coverage. Using FoMo-in-Flux, we explore the complex landscape of practical continual pretraining through multiple perspectives: (1) A data-centric investigation of data mixtures and stream orderings that emulate real-world deployment situations, (2) a method-centric investigation ranging from simple fine-tuning and traditional continual learning strategies to parameter-efficient updates and model merging, (3) meta learning rate schedules and mechanistic design choices, and (4) the influence of model and compute scaling. Together, our insights provide a practitioner's guide to continual multimodal pretraining for real-world deployment. Our benchmark and code is here: https://github.com/ExplainableML/fomo_in_flux.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14471v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Karsten Roth, Vishaal Udandarao, Sebastian Dziadzio, Ameya Prabhu, Mehdi Cherti, Oriol Vinyals, Olivier H\'enaff, Samuel Albanie, Matthias Bethge, Zeynep Akata</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Zero to Hero: Harnessing Transformers for Biomedical Named Entity Recognition in Zero- and Few-shot Contexts</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2305.04928</link>
      <description>arXiv:2305.04928v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Supervised named entity recognition (NER) in the biomedical domain depends on large sets of annotated texts with the given named entities. The creation of such datasets can be time-consuming and expensive, while extraction of new entities requires additional annotation tasks and retraining the model. To address these challenges, this paper proposes a method for zero- and few-shot NER in the biomedical domain. The method is based on transforming the task of multi-class token classification into binary token classification and pre-training on a large amount of datasets and biomedical entities, which allow the model to learn semantic relations between the given and potentially novel named entity labels. We have achieved average F1 scores of 35.44% for zero-shot NER, 50.10% for one-shot NER, 69.94% for 10-shot NER, and 79.51% for 100-shot NER on 9 diverse evaluated biomedical entities with fine-tuned PubMedBERT-based model. The results demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed method for recognizing new biomedical entities with no or limited number of examples, outperforming previous transformer-based methods, and being comparable to GPT3-based models using models with over 1000 times fewer parameters. We make models and developed code publicly available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2305.04928v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1016/j.artmed.2024.102970</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Milo\v{s} Ko\v{s}prdi\'c, Nikola Prodanovi\'c, Adela Ljaji\'c, Bojana Ba\v{s}aragin, Nikola Milo\v{s}evi\'c</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Scale: The Diversity Coefficient as a Data Quality Metric for Variability in Natural Language Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2306.13840</link>
      <description>arXiv:2306.13840v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Current trends in pre-training Large Language Models (LLMs) primarily focus on the scaling of model and dataset size. While the quality of pre-training data is considered an important factor for training powerful LLMs, it remains a nebulous concept that has not been rigorously characterized. To this end, we propose a formalization of one key aspect of data quality -- measuring the variability of natural language data -- specifically via a measure we call the diversity coefficient. Our empirical analysis shows that the proposed diversity coefficient aligns with the intuitive properties of diversity and variability, e.g., it increases as the number of latent concepts increases. Then, we measure the diversity coefficient of publicly available pre-training datasets and demonstrate that their formal diversity is high compared to theoretical lower and upper bounds. Finally, we conduct a comprehensive set of controlled interventional experiments with GPT-2 and LLaMAv2 that demonstrate the diversity coefficient of pre-training data characterizes useful aspects of downstream model evaluation performance -- totaling 44 models of various sizes (51M to 7B parameters). We conclude that our formal notion of diversity is an important aspect of data quality that captures variability and causally leads to improved evaluation performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2306.13840v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.NE</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Published as workshop paper in the Data-centric Machine Learning Research (DMLR) Workshop, ICLR 2024</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Brando Miranda, Alycia Lee, Sudharsan Sundar, Allison Casasola, Sanmi Koyejo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lyra: Orchestrating Dual Correction in Automated Theorem Proving</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2309.15806</link>
      <description>arXiv:2309.15806v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) present an intriguing avenue for exploration in the field of formal theorem proving. Nevertheless, their full potential, particularly concerning the mitigation of hallucinations and refinement through prover error messages, remains an area that has yet to be thoroughly investigated. To enhance the effectiveness of LLMs in the field, we introduce the Lyra, a new framework that employs two distinct correction mechanisms: Tool Correction (TC) and Conjecture Correction (CC). To implement Tool Correction in the post-processing of formal proofs, we leverage prior knowledge to utilize predefined prover tools (e.g., Sledgehammer) for guiding the replacement of incorrect tools. Tool Correction significantly contributes to mitigating hallucinations, thereby improving the overall accuracy of the proof. In addition, we introduce Conjecture Correction, an error feedback mechanism designed to interact with prover to refine formal proof conjectures with prover error messages. Compared to the previous refinement framework, the proposed Conjecture Correction refines generation with instruction but does not collect paired (generation, error &amp; refinement) prompts. Our method has achieved state-of-the-art (SOTA) performance on both miniF2F validation (48.0% -&gt; 55.3%) and test (45.5% -&gt; 51.2%). We also present 3 IMO problems solved by Lyra. We believe Tool Correction (post-process for hallucination mitigation) and Conjecture Correction (subgoal adjustment from interaction with environment) could provide a promising avenue for future research in this field.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2309.15806v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chuanyang Zheng, Haiming Wang, Enze Xie, Zhengying Liu, Jiankai Sun, Huajian Xin, Jianhao Shen, Zhenguo Li, Yu Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KLoB: a Benchmark for Assessing Knowledge Locating Methods in Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2309.16535</link>
      <description>arXiv:2309.16535v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recently, Locate-Then-Edit paradigm has emerged as one of the main approaches in changing factual knowledge stored in the Language models. However, there is a lack of research on whether present locating methods can pinpoint the exact parameters embedding the desired knowledge. Moreover, although many researchers have questioned the validity of locality hypothesis of factual knowledge, no method is provided to test the a hypothesis for more in-depth discussion and research. Therefore, we introduce KLoB, a benchmark examining three essential properties that a reliable knowledge locating method should satisfy. KLoB can serve as a benchmark for evaluating existing locating methods in language models, and can contributes a method to reassessing the validity of locality hypothesis of factual knowledge. KLoB is publicly available at an anonymous GitHub: \url{https://github.com/anon6662/KLoB}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2309.16535v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yiming Ju, Xingrun Xing, Zhixiong Zeng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reformulating Domain Adaptation of Large Language Models as Adapt-Retrieve-Revise: A Case Study on Chinese Legal Domain</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.03328</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.03328v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: While large language models (LLMs) like GPT-4 have recently demonstrated astonishing zero-shot capabilities in general domain tasks, they often generate content with hallucinations in specific domains such as Chinese law, hindering their application in these areas. This is typically due to the absence of training data that encompasses such a specific domain, preventing GPT-4 from acquiring in-domain knowledge. A pressing challenge is that it's not plausible to continue training LLMs of such scale on in-domain data.
  This paper introduces a simple and effective domain adaptation framework for GPT-4 by reformulating generation as an \textbf{adapt-retrieve-revise} process. The initial step is to \textbf{adapt} an affordable 7B LLM to the target domain by continuing learning on in-domain data. When solving a task, we leverage the adapted LLM to generate a draft answer given a task query. Then, the draft answer will be used to \textbf{retrieve} supporting evidence candidates from an external in-domain knowledge base. Finally, the draft answer and retrieved evidence are concatenated into a whole prompt to let GPT-4 assess the evidence and \textbf{revise} the draft answer to generate the final answer.
  Our proposal combines the advantages of the efficiency of adapting a smaller 7B model with the evidence-assessing capability of GPT-4 and effectively prevents GPT-4 from generating hallucinatory content. In the zero-shot setting of four Chinese legal tasks, our method improves accuracy by 33.3\% compared to the direct generation by GPT-4. When compared to two stronger retrieval-based baselines, our method outperforms them by 15.4\% and 23.9\%. Our code will be released</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.03328v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhen wan, Yating Zhang, Yexiang Wang, Fei Cheng, Sadao Kurohashi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Put Your Money Where Your Mouth Is: Evaluating Strategic Planning and Execution of LLM Agents in an Auction Arena</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.05746</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.05746v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advancements in Large Language Models (LLMs) showcase advanced reasoning, yet NLP evaluations often depend on static benchmarks. Evaluating this necessitates environments that test strategic reasoning in dynamic, competitive scenarios requiring long-term planning. We introduce AucArena, a novel evaluation suite that simulates auctions, a setting chosen for being highly unpredictable and involving many skills related to resource and risk management, while also being easy to evaluate. We conduct controlled experiments using state-of-the-art LLMs to power bidding agents to benchmark their planning and execution skills. Our research demonstrates that LLMs, such as GPT-4, possess key skills for auction participation, such as budget management and goal adherence, which improve with adaptive strategies. This highlights LLMs' potential in modeling complex social interactions in competitive contexts. However, variability in LLM performance and occasional outperformance by simpler methods indicate opportunities for further advancements in LLM design and the value of our simulation environment for ongoing testing and refinement.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.05746v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiangjie Chen, Siyu Yuan, Rong Ye, Bodhisattwa Prasad Majumder, Kyle Richardson</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lemur: Harmonizing Natural Language and Code for Language Agents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.06830</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.06830v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We introduce Lemur and Lemur-Chat, openly accessible language models optimized for both natural language and coding capabilities to serve as the backbone of versatile language agents. The evolution from language chat models to functional language agents demands that models not only master human interaction, reasoning, and planning but also ensure grounding in the relevant environments. This calls for a harmonious blend of language and coding capabilities in the models. Lemur and Lemur-Chat are proposed to address this necessity, demonstrating balanced proficiencies in both domains, unlike existing open-source models that tend to specialize in either. Through meticulous pre-training using a code-intensive corpus and instruction fine-tuning on text and code data, our models achieve state-of-the-art averaged performance across diverse text and coding benchmarks among open-source models. Comprehensive experiments demonstrate Lemur's superiority over existing open-source models and its proficiency across various agent tasks involving human communication, tool usage, and interaction under fully- and partially- observable environments. The harmonization between natural and programming languages enables Lemur-Chat to significantly narrow the gap with proprietary models on agent abilities, providing key insights into developing advanced open-source agents adept at reasoning, planning, and operating seamlessly across environments. https://github.com/OpenLemur/Lemur</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.06830v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yiheng Xu, Hongjin Su, Chen Xing, Boyu Mi, Qian Liu, Weijia Shi, Binyuan Hui, Fan Zhou, Yitao Liu, Tianbao Xie, Zhoujun Cheng, Siheng Zhao, Lingpeng Kong, Bailin Wang, Caiming Xiong, Tao Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehensive Evaluation of GPT-4V on Knowledge-Intensive Visual Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.07536</link>
      <description>arXiv:2311.07536v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The emergence of multimodal large models (MLMs) has significantly advanced the field of visual understanding, offering remarkable capabilities in the realm of visual question answering (VQA). Yet, the true challenge lies in the domain of knowledge-intensive VQA tasks, which necessitate not just recognition of visual elements, but also a deep comprehension of the visual information in conjunction with a vast repository of learned knowledge. To uncover such capabilities of MLMs, particularly the newly introduced GPT-4V and Gemini, we provide an in-depth evaluation from three perspectives: 1) Commonsense Knowledge, which assesses how well models can understand visual cues and connect to general knowledge; 2) Fine-grained World Knowledge, which tests the model's skill in reasoning out specific knowledge from images, showcasing their proficiency across various specialized fields; 3) Comprehensive Knowledge with Decision-making Rationales, which examines model's capability to provide logical explanations for its inference, facilitating a deeper analysis from the interpretability perspective. Additionally, we utilize a visual knowledge-enhanced training strategy and multimodal retrieval-augmented generation approach to enhance MLMs, highlighting the future need for advancements in this research direction. Extensive experiments indicate that: a) GPT-4V demonstrates enhanced explanation generation when using composite images as few-shots; b) GPT-4V and other MLMs produce severe hallucinations when dealing with world knowledge; c) Visual knowledge enhanced training and prompting technicals present potential to improve performance. Codes: https://github.com/HITsz-TMG/Cognitive-Visual-Language-Mapper</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2311.07536v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yunxin Li, Longyue Wang, Baotian Hu, Xinyu Chen, Wanqi Zhong, Chenyang Lyu, Wei Wang, Min Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AlignBench: Benchmarking Chinese Alignment of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.18743</link>
      <description>arXiv:2311.18743v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Alignment has become a critical step for instruction-tuned Large Language Models (LLMs) to become helpful assistants. However, the effective evaluation of alignment for emerging Chinese LLMs is still largely unexplored. To fill in this gap, we introduce AlignBench, a comprehensive multi-dimensional benchmark for evaluating LLMs' alignment in Chinese. We design a human-in-the-loop data curation pipeline, containing eight main categories, 683 real-scenario rooted queries and corresponding human verified references. To ensure the correctness of references, each knowledge-intensive query is accompanied with evidences collected from reliable web sources (including URLs and quotations) by our annotators. For automatic evaluation, our benchmark employs a rule-calibrated multi-dimensional LLM-as-Judge~\cite{zheng2023judging} approach with Chain-of-Thought to generate explanations and final ratings, ensuring high reliability and interpretability. All evaluation code, data, and LLM generations are available at \url{https://github.com/THUDM/AlignBench}. Since its release, AlignBench has been adopted by top (Chinese) LLMs for evaluating their alignment capabilities in Chinese, including ChatGLM, Qwen, DeepSeek, Yi, Baichuan, and Abab.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2311.18743v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiao Liu, Xuanyu Lei, Shengyuan Wang, Yue Huang, Zhuoer Feng, Bosi Wen, Jiale Cheng, Pei Ke, Yifan Xu, Weng Lam Tam, Xiaohan Zhang, Lichao Sun, Xiaotao Gu, Hongning Wang, Jing Zhang, Minlie Huang, Yuxiao Dong, Jie Tang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TrustLLM: Trustworthiness in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05561</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.05561v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs), exemplified by ChatGPT, have gained considerable attention for their excellent natural language processing capabilities. Nonetheless, these LLMs present many challenges, particularly in the realm of trustworthiness. Therefore, ensuring the trustworthiness of LLMs emerges as an important topic. This paper introduces TrustLLM, a comprehensive study of trustworthiness in LLMs, including principles for different dimensions of trustworthiness, established benchmark, evaluation, and analysis of trustworthiness for mainstream LLMs, and discussion of open challenges and future directions. Specifically, we first propose a set of principles for trustworthy LLMs that span eight different dimensions. Based on these principles, we further establish a benchmark across six dimensions including truthfulness, safety, fairness, robustness, privacy, and machine ethics. We then present a study evaluating 16 mainstream LLMs in TrustLLM, consisting of over 30 datasets. Our findings firstly show that in general trustworthiness and utility (i.e., functional effectiveness) are positively related. Secondly, our observations reveal that proprietary LLMs generally outperform most open-source counterparts in terms of trustworthiness, raising concerns about the potential risks of widely accessible open-source LLMs. However, a few open-source LLMs come very close to proprietary ones. Thirdly, it is important to note that some LLMs may be overly calibrated towards exhibiting trustworthiness, to the extent that they compromise their utility by mistakenly treating benign prompts as harmful and consequently not responding. Finally, we emphasize the importance of ensuring transparency not only in the models themselves but also in the technologies that underpin trustworthiness. Knowing the specific trustworthy technologies that have been employed is crucial for analyzing their effectiveness.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.05561v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yue Huang, Lichao Sun, Haoran Wang, Siyuan Wu, Qihui Zhang, Yuan Li, Chujie Gao, Yixin Huang, Wenhan Lyu, Yixuan Zhang, Xiner Li, Zhengliang Liu, Yixin Liu, Yijue Wang, Zhikun Zhang, Bertie Vidgen, Bhavya Kailkhura, Caiming Xiong, Chaowei Xiao, Chunyuan Li, Eric Xing, Furong Huang, Hao Liu, Heng Ji, Hongyi Wang, Huan Zhang, Huaxiu Yao, Manolis Kellis, Marinka Zitnik, Meng Jiang, Mohit Bansal, James Zou, Jian Pei, Jian Liu, Jianfeng Gao, Jiawei Han, Jieyu Zhao, Jiliang Tang, Jindong Wang, Joaquin Vanschoren, John Mitchell, Kai Shu, Kaidi Xu, Kai-Wei Chang, Lifang He, Lifu Huang, Michael Backes, Neil Zhenqiang Gong, Philip S. Yu, Pin-Yu Chen, Quanquan Gu, Ran Xu, Rex Ying, Shuiwang Ji, Suman Jana, Tianlong Chen, Tianming Liu, Tianyi Zhou, William Wang, Xiang Li, Xiangliang Zhang, Xiao Wang, Xing Xie, Xun Chen, Xuyu Wang, Yan Liu, Yanfang Ye, Yinzhi Cao, Yong Chen, Yue Zhao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SpeechDPR: End-to-End Spoken Passage Retrieval for Open-Domain Spoken Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.13463</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.13463v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Spoken Question Answering (SQA) is essential for machines to reply to user's question by finding the answer span within a given spoken passage. SQA has been previously achieved without ASR to avoid recognition errors and Out-of-Vocabulary (OOV) problems. However, the real-world problem of Open-domain SQA (openSQA), in which the machine needs to first retrieve passages that possibly contain the answer from a spoken archive in addition, was never considered. This paper proposes the first known end-to-end framework, Speech Dense Passage Retriever (SpeechDPR), for the retrieval component of the openSQA problem. SpeechDPR learns a sentence-level semantic representation by distilling knowledge from the cascading model of unsupervised ASR (UASR) and text dense retriever (TDR). No manually transcribed speech data is needed. Initial experiments showed performance comparable to the cascading model of UASR and TDR, and significantly better when UASR was poor, verifying this approach is more robust to speech recognition errors.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.13463v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chyi-Jiunn Lin, Guan-Ting Lin, Yung-Sung Chuang, Wei-Lun Wu, Shang-Wen Li, Abdelrahman Mohamed, Hung-yi Lee, Lin-shan Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergy-of-Thoughts: Eliciting Efficient Reasoning in Hybrid Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.02563</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.02563v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have shown impressive emergent abilities in a wide range of tasks, but the associated expensive API cost greatly limits the real application. Previous works like chain-of-thought (CoT) and tree-of-thoughts (ToT) have predominately focused on enhancing accuracy, but overlook the rapidly increasing API cost, which could be particularly problematic for open-ended real-world tasks with huge solution spaces. Motivated by the dual process theory of human cognition, we propose "Synergy of Thoughts"(SoT) to unleash the synergistic potential of hybrid LLMs with different scales for efficient reasoning. By default, SoT uses smaller-scale language models to generate multiple low-cost intuitive thoughts, which resembles the parallel intuitions produced by System 1. We then design a confidence evaluator where the intuitive thoughts are cross-evaluated and introduce a controllable threshold mechanism to decide their mutual conflict. If these intuitive thoughts exhibit conflicts, SoT will invoke the reflective reasoning of scaled-up language models to emulate the intervention of System 2, which will override the intuitive thoughts and rectify the reasoning results. This framework is model-agnostic and training-free, which can be flexibly implemented with various off-the-shelf LLMs. Experiments on six representative reasoning tasks show that SoT substantially reduces the API cost by 38.3%-75.1%, and simultaneously achieves state-of-the-art reasoning accuracy and solution diversity. Notably, the average token cost reduction on open-ended tasks reaches up to 69.1%.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.02563v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yu Shang, Yu Li, Fengli Xu, Yong Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLMs Meet Long Video: Advancing Long Video Question Answering with An Interactive Visual Adapter in LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.13546</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.13546v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Long video understanding is a significant and ongoing challenge in the intersection of multimedia and artificial intelligence. Employing large language models (LLMs) for comprehending video becomes an emerging and promising method. However, this approach incurs high computational costs due to the extensive array of video tokens, experiences reduced visual clarity as a consequence of token aggregation, and confronts challenges arising from irrelevant visual tokens while answering video-related questions. To alleviate these issues, we present an Interactive Visual Adapter (IVA) within LLMs, designed to enhance interaction with fine-grained visual elements. Specifically, we first transform long videos into temporal video tokens via leveraging a visual encoder alongside a pretrained causal transformer, then feed them into LLMs with the video instructions. Subsequently, we integrated IVA, which contains a lightweight temporal frame selector and a spatial feature interactor, within the internal blocks of LLMs to capture instruction-aware and fine-grained visual signals. Consequently, the proposed video-LLM facilitates a comprehensive understanding of long video content through appropriate long video modeling and precise visual interactions. We conducted extensive experiments on nine video understanding benchmarks and experimental results show that our interactive visual adapter significantly improves the performance of video LLMs on long video QA tasks. Ablation studies further verify the effectiveness of IVA in understanding long and short video.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.13546v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yunxin Li, Xinyu Chen, Baotain Hu, Min Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Dataset and Benchmark for Hospital Course Summarization with Adapted Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.05720</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.05720v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Brief hospital course (BHC) summaries are clinical documents that summarize a patient's hospital stay. While large language models (LLMs) depict remarkable capabilities in automating real-world tasks, their capabilities for healthcare applications such as synthesizing BHCs from clinical notes have not been shown. We introduce a novel pre-processed dataset, the MIMIC-IV-BHC, encapsulating clinical note and brief hospital course (BHC) pairs to adapt LLMs for BHC synthesis. Furthermore, we introduce a benchmark of the summarization performance of two general-purpose LLMs and three healthcare-adapted LLMs.
  Using clinical notes as input, we apply prompting-based (using in-context learning) and fine-tuning-based adaptation strategies to three open-source LLMs (Clinical-T5-Large, Llama2-13B, FLAN-UL2) and two proprietary LLMs (GPT-3.5, GPT-4). We evaluate these LLMs across multiple context-length inputs using natural language similarity metrics. We further conduct a clinical study with five clinicians, comparing clinician-written and LLM-generated BHCs across 30 samples, focusing on their potential to enhance clinical decision-making through improved summary quality. We observe that the Llama2-13B fine-tuned LLM outperforms other domain-adapted models given quantitative evaluation metrics of BLEU and BERT-Score. GPT-4 with in-context learning shows more robustness to increasing context lengths of clinical note inputs than fine-tuned Llama2-13B. Despite comparable quantitative metrics, the reader study depicts a significant preference for summaries generated by GPT-4 with in-context learning compared to both Llama2-13B fine-tuned summaries and the original summaries, highlighting the need for qualitative clinical evaluation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.05720v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Asad Aali, Dave Van Veen, Yamin Ishraq Arefeen, Jason Hom, Christian Bluethgen, Eduardo Pontes Reis, Sergios Gatidis, Namuun Clifford, Joseph Daws, Arash S. Tehrani, Jangwon Kim, Akshay S. Chaudhari</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-discrimination Criteria for Generative Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.08564</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.08564v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Generative AI, such as large language models, has undergone rapid development within recent years. As these models become increasingly available to the public, concerns arise about perpetuating and amplifying harmful biases in applications. Gender stereotypes can be harmful and limiting for the individuals they target, whether they consist of misrepresentation or discrimination. Recognizing gender bias as a pervasive societal construct, this paper studies how to uncover and quantify the presence of gender biases in generative language models. In particular, we derive generative AI analogues of three well-known non-discrimination criteria from classification, namely independence, separation and sufficiency. To demonstrate these criteria in action, we design prompts for each of the criteria with a focus on occupational gender stereotype, specifically utilizing the medical test to introduce the ground truth in the generative AI context. Our results address the presence of occupational gender bias within such conversational language models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.08564v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sara Sterlie, Nina Weng, Aasa Feragen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>StateFlow: Enhancing LLM Task-Solving through State-Driven Workflows</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.11322</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.11322v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: It is a notable trend to use Large Language Models (LLMs) to tackle complex tasks, e.g., tasks that require a sequence of actions and dynamic interaction with tools and external environments. In this paper, we propose StateFlow, a novel LLM-based task-solving paradigm that conceptualizes complex task-solving processes as state machines. In StateFlow, we distinguish between "process grounding" (via state and state transitions) and "sub-task solving" (through actions within a state), enhancing control and interpretability of the task-solving procedure. A state represents the status of a running process. The transitions between states are controlled by heuristic rules or decisions made by the LLM, allowing for a dynamic and adaptive progression. Upon entering a state, a series of actions is executed, involving not only calling LLMs guided by different prompts, but also the utilization of external tools as needed. Our results show that StateFlow significantly enhances LLMs' efficiency. For instance, StateFlow achieves 13% and 28% higher success rates compared to ReAct in InterCode SQL and ALFWorld benchmark, with 5x and 3x less cost respectively. We also show that StateFlow can be combined with iterative refining methods like Reflexion to further improve performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.11322v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yiran Wu, Tianwei Yue, Shaokun Zhang, Chi Wang, Qingyun Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revenge of the Fallen? Recurrent Models Match Transformers at Predicting Human Language Comprehension Metrics</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.19178</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.19178v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Transformers have generally supplanted recurrent neural networks as the dominant architecture for both natural language processing tasks and for modelling the effect of predictability on online human language comprehension. However, two recently developed recurrent model architectures, RWKV and Mamba, appear to perform natural language tasks comparably to or better than transformers of equivalent scale. In this paper, we show that contemporary recurrent models are now also able to match - and in some cases, exceed - the performance of comparably sized transformers at modeling online human language comprehension. This suggests that transformer language models are not uniquely suited to this task, and opens up new directions for debates about the extent to which architectural features of language models make them better or worse models of human language comprehension.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.19178v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>James A. Michaelov, Catherine Arnett, Benjamin K. Bergen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>QFMTS: Generating Query-Focused Summaries over Multi-Table Inputs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.05109</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.05109v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Table summarization is a crucial task aimed at condensing information from tabular data into concise and comprehensible textual summaries. However, existing approaches often fall short of adequately meeting users' information and quality requirements and tend to overlook the complexities of real-world queries. In this paper, we propose a novel method to address these limitations by introducing query-focused multi-table summarization. Our approach, which comprises a table serialization module, a summarization controller, and a large language model (LLM), utilizes textual queries and multiple tables to generate query-dependent table summaries tailored to users' information needs. To facilitate research in this area, we present a comprehensive dataset specifically tailored for this task, consisting of 4909 query-summary pairs, each associated with multiple tables. Through extensive experiments using our curated dataset, we demonstrate the effectiveness of our proposed method compared to baseline approaches. Our findings offer insights into the challenges of complex table reasoning for precise summarization, contributing to the advancement of research in query-focused multi-table summarization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.05109v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weijia Zhang, Vaishali Pal, Jia-Hong Huang, Evangelos Kanoulas, Maarten de Rijke</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Language Models as Carriers of Hidden Messages</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.02481</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.02481v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: With the help of simple fine-tuning, one can artificially embed hidden text into large language models (LLMs). This text is revealed only when triggered by a specific query to the LLM. Two primary applications are LLM fingerprinting and steganography. In the context of LLM fingerprinting, a unique text identifier (fingerprint) is embedded within the model to verify licensing compliance. In the context of steganography, the LLM serves as a carrier for hidden messages that can be disclosed through a chosen trigger question.
  Our work demonstrates that embedding hidden text in the LLM via fine-tuning, though seemingly secure due to the vast number of potential triggers (any sequence of characters or tokens could serve as a trigger), is susceptible to extraction through analysis of the LLM's output decoding process. We propose an extraction attack called Unconditional Token Forcing (UTF). It is premised on the hypothesis that iteratively feeding each token from the LLM's vocabulary into the model should reveal output sequences with abnormally high token probabilities, indicating potential hidden text candidates. We also present a defense method to hide text in such a way that it is resistant to both UTF and attacks based on sampling decoding methods, which we named Unconditional Token Forcing Confusion (UTFC). To the best of our knowledge, there is no attack method that can extract text hidden with UTFC. UTFC has both benign applications (improving LLM fingerprinting) and malign applications (using LLMs to create covert communication channels).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.02481v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jakub Hoscilowicz, Pawel Popiolek, Jan Rudkowski, Jedrzej Bieniasz, Artur Janicki</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chaos with Keywords: Exposing Large Language Models Sycophantic Hallucination to Misleading Keywords and Evaluating Defense Strategies</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.03827</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.03827v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This study explores the sycophantic tendencies of Large Language Models (LLMs), where these models tend to provide answers that match what users want to hear, even if they are not entirely correct. The motivation behind this exploration stems from the common behavior observed in individuals searching the internet for facts with partial or misleading knowledge. Similar to using web search engines, users may recall fragments of misleading keywords and submit them to an LLM, hoping for a comprehensive response. Our empirical analysis of several LLMs shows the potential danger of these models amplifying misinformation when presented with misleading keywords. Additionally, we thoroughly assess four existing hallucination mitigation strategies to reduce LLMs sycophantic behavior. Our experiments demonstrate the effectiveness of these strategies for generating factually correct statements. Furthermore, our analyses delve into knowledge-probing experiments on factual keywords and different categories of sycophancy mitigation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.03827v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aswin RRV, Nemika Tyagi, Md Nayem Uddin, Neeraj Varshney, Chitta Baral</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling language contact with the Iterated Learning Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.06878</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.06878v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Contact between languages has the potential to transmit vocabulary and other language features; however, this does not always happen. Here, an iterated learning model is used to examine, in a simple way, the resistance of languages to change during language contact. Iterated learning models are agent-based models of language change, they demonstrate that languages that are expressive and compositional arise spontaneously as a consequence of a language transmission bottleneck. A recently introduced type of iterated learning model, the Semi-Supervised ILM is used to simulate language contact. These simulations do not include many of the complex factors involved in language contact and do not model a population of speakers; nonetheless the model demonstrates that the dynamics which lead languages in the model to spontaneously become expressive and compositional, also cause a language to maintain its core traits even after mixing with another language.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.06878v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Seth Bullock, Conor Houghton</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Language Models for Emotion Analysis: Insights from Cognitive Science</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10265</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10265v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We propose leveraging cognitive science research on emotions and communication to improve language models for emotion analysis. First, we present the main emotion theories in psychology and cognitive science. Then, we introduce the main methods of emotion annotation in natural language processing and their connections to psychological theories. We also present the two main types of analyses of emotional communication in cognitive pragmatics. Finally, based on the cognitive science research presented, we propose directions for improving language models for emotion analysis. We suggest that these research efforts pave the way for constructing new annotation schemes, methods, and a possible benchmark for emotional understanding, considering different facets of human emotion and communication.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10265v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Proceedings of the Workshop on Cognitive Modeling and Computational Linguistics, Association for Computational Linguistics, Aug 2024, Bangkok, Thailand. pp.264-277</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Constant Bonard (UNIBE), Gustave Cortal (LMF, LISN)</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BlockPruner: Fine-grained Pruning for Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10594</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10594v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: With the rapid growth in the size and complexity of large language models (LLMs), the costs associated with their training and inference have escalated significantly. Research indicates that certain layers in LLMs harbor substantial redundancy, and pruning these layers has minimal impact on the overall performance. While various layer pruning methods have been developed based on this insight, they generally overlook the finer-grained redundancies within the layers themselves. In this paper, we delve deeper into the architecture of LLMs and demonstrate that finer-grained pruning can be achieved by targeting redundancies in multi-head attention (MHA) and multi-layer perceptron (MLP) blocks. We propose a novel, training-free structured pruning approach called BlockPruner. Unlike existing layer pruning methods, BlockPruner segments each Transformer layer into MHA and MLP blocks. It then assesses the importance of these blocks using perplexity measures and applies a heuristic search for iterative pruning. We applied BlockPruner to LLMs of various sizes and architectures and validated its performance across a wide range of downstream tasks. Experimental results show that BlockPruner achieves more granular and effective pruning compared to state-of-the-art baselines.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10594v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Longguang Zhong, Fanqi Wan, Ruijun Chen, Xiaojun Quan, Liangzhi Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehensive Survey of Scientific Large Language Models and Their Applications in Scientific Discovery</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10833</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10833v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In many scientific fields, large language models (LLMs) have revolutionized the way text and other modalities of data (e.g., molecules and proteins) are handled, achieving superior performance in various applications and augmenting the scientific discovery process. Nevertheless, previous surveys on scientific LLMs often concentrate on one or two fields or a single modality. In this paper, we aim to provide a more holistic view of the research landscape by unveiling cross-field and cross-modal connections between scientific LLMs regarding their architectures and pre-training techniques. To this end, we comprehensively survey over 250 scientific LLMs, discuss their commonalities and differences, as well as summarize pre-training datasets and evaluation tasks for each field and modality. Moreover, we investigate how LLMs have been deployed to benefit scientific discovery. Resources related to this survey are available at https://github.com/yuzhimanhua/Awesome-Scientific-Language-Models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10833v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yu Zhang, Xiusi Chen, Bowen Jin, Sheng Wang, Shuiwang Ji, Wei Wang, Jiawei Han</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HyperLoader: Integrating Hypernetwork-Based LoRA and Adapter Layers into Multi-Task Transformers for Sequence Labelling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.01411</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.01411v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We present HyperLoader, a simple approach that combines different parameter-efficient fine-tuning methods in a multi-task setting. To achieve this goal, our model uses a hypernetwork to generate the weights of these modules based on the task, the transformer layer, and its position within this layer. Our method combines the benefits of multi-task learning by capturing the structure of all tasks while reducing the task interference problem by encapsulating the task-specific knowledge in the generated weights and the benefits of combining different parameter-efficient methods to outperform full-fine tuning. We provide empirical evidence that HyperLoader outperforms previous approaches in most datasets and obtains the best average performance across tasks in high-resource and low-resource scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.01411v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jesus-German Ortiz-Barajas, Helena Gomez-Adorno, Thamar Solorio</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Question-Analysis Prompting Improves LLM Performance in Reasoning Tasks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.03624</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.03624v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Although LLMs have the potential to transform many fields, they still underperform humans in reasoning tasks. Existing methods induce the model to produce step-by-step calculations, but this research explores the question: Does making the LLM analyze the question improve its performance? We propose a novel prompting strategy called Question Analysis Prompting (QAP), in which the model is prompted to explain the question in $n$ words before solving. The value of $n$ influences the length of response generated by the model. QAP is evaluated on GPT 3.5 Turbo and GPT 4 Turbo on arithmetic datasets GSM8K, AQuA, and SAT and commonsense dataset StrategyQA. QAP is compared with other state-of-the-art prompts including Chain-of-Thought (CoT), Plan and Solve Prompting (PS+) and Take A Deep Breath (TADB). QAP outperforms all state-of-the-art prompts on AQuA and SAT datasets on both GPT3.5 and GPT4. QAP consistently ranks among the top-2 prompts on 75\% of the tests. A key factor of QAP performance can be attributed to response length, where detailed responses are beneficial when answering harder questions, but can negatively affect easy questions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.03624v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dharunish Yugeswardeenoo, Kevin Zhu, Sean O'Brien</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>M5 -- A Diverse Benchmark to Assess the Performance of Large Multimodal Models Across Multilingual and Multicultural Vision-Language Tasks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.03791</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.03791v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Since the release of ChatGPT, the field of Natural Language Processing has experienced rapid advancements, particularly in Large Language Models (LLMs) and their multimodal counterparts, Large Multimodal Models (LMMs). Despite their impressive capabilities, LLMs often exhibit significant performance disparities across different languages and cultural contexts, as demonstrated by various text-only benchmarks. However, current research lacks such benchmarks for multimodal visio-linguistic settings. This work fills this gap by introducing M5, the first comprehensive benchmark designed to evaluate LMMs on diverse vision-language tasks within a multilingual and multicultural context. M5 includes eight datasets covering five tasks and $41$ languages, with a focus on underrepresented languages and culturally diverse images. Furthermore, we introduce two novel datasets, M5-VGR and M5-VLOD, including a new Visio-Linguistic Outlier Detection task, in which all evaluated open-source models fail to significantly surpass the random baseline. Through extensive evaluation and analyses, we highlight substantial task-agnostic performance disparities between high- and low-resource languages. Moreover, we show that larger models do not necessarily outperform smaller ones in a multilingual setting.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.03791v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Florian Schneider, Sunayana Sitaram</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Multi-Agent Framework with Trajectory Learning for Knowledge-Intensive Tasks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.09893</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.09893v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advancements in Large Language Models (LLMs) have led to significant breakthroughs in various natural language processing tasks. However, generating factually consistent responses in knowledge-intensive scenarios remains a challenge due to issues such as hallucination, difficulty in acquiring long-tailed knowledge, and limited memory expansion. This paper introduces SMART, a novel multi-agent framework that leverages external knowledge to enhance the interpretability and factual consistency of LLM-generated responses. SMART comprises four specialized agents, each performing a specific sub-trajectory action to navigate complex knowledge-intensive tasks. We propose a multi-agent co-training paradigm, Long-Short Trajectory Learning, which ensures synergistic collaboration among agents while maintaining fine-grained execution by each agent. Extensive experiments on five knowledge-intensive tasks demonstrate SMART's superior performance compared to widely adopted knowledge internalization and knowledge enhancement methods. Our framework can extend beyond knowledge-intensive tasks to more complex scenarios. Our code is available at https://github.com/yueshengbin/SMART.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.09893v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shengbin Yue, Siyuan Wang, Wei Chen, Xuanjing Huang, Zhongyu Wei</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crafting the Path: Robust Query Rewriting for Information Retrieval</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.12529</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.12529v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Query rewriting aims to generate a new query that can complement the original query to improve the information retrieval system. Recent studies on query rewriting, such as query2doc, query2expand and querey2cot, rely on the internal knowledge of Large Language Models (LLMs) to generate a relevant passage to add information to the query. Nevertheless, the efficacy of these methodologies may markedly decline in instances where the requisite knowledge is not encapsulated within the model's intrinsic parameters. In this paper, we propose a novel structured query rewriting method called Crafting the Path tailored for retrieval systems. Crafting the Path involves a three-step process that crafts query-related information necessary for finding the passages to be searched in each step. Specifically, the Crafting the Path begins with Query Concept Comprehension, proceeds to Query Type Identification, and finally conducts Expected Answer Extraction. Experimental results show that our method outperforms previous rewriting methods, especially in less familiar domains for LLMs. We demonstrate that our method is less dependent on the internal parameter knowledge of the model and generates queries with fewer factual inaccuracies. Furthermore, we observe that \name{} demonstrates superior performance in the retrieval-augmented generation scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.12529v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ingeol Baek, Jimin Lee, Joonho Yang, Hwanhee Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Sarcasm Detection A Step-by-Step Reasoning Process in Large Language Models?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.12725</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.12725v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Elaborating a series of intermediate reasoning steps significantly improves the ability of large language models (LLMs) to solve complex problems, as such steps would evoke LLMs to think sequentially. However, human sarcasm understanding is often considered an intuitive and holistic cognitive process, in which various linguistic, contextual, and emotional cues are integrated to form a comprehensive understanding, in a way that does not necessarily follow a step-by-step fashion. To verify the validity of this argument, we introduce a new prompting framework (called SarcasmCue) containing four sub-methods, viz. chain of contradiction (CoC), graph of cues (GoC), bagging of cues (BoC) and tensor of cues (ToC), which elicits LLMs to detect human sarcasm by considering sequential and non-sequential prompting methods. Through a comprehensive empirical comparison on four benchmarks, we highlight three key findings: (1) CoC and GoC show superior performance with more advanced models like GPT-4 and Claude 3.5, with an improvement of 3.5%. (2) ToC significantly outperforms other methods when smaller LLMs are evaluated, boosting the F1 score by 29.7% over the best baseline. (3) Our proposed framework consistently pushes the state-of-the-art (i.e., ToT) by 4.2%, 2.0%, 29.7%, and 58.2% in F1 scores across four datasets. This demonstrates the effectiveness and stability of the proposed framework.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.12725v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ben Yao, Yazhou Zhang, Qiuchi Li, Jing Qin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pruning Large Language Models with Semi-Structural Adaptive Sparse Training</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.20584</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.20584v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The tremendous success of Large Language Models (LLMs) across various complex tasks relies heavily on their substantial scale, which raises challenges during model deployment due to their large memory consumption. Recently, numerous studies have attempted to compress LLMs using one-shot pruning methods. However, these methods often experience considerable performance degradation on complex language understanding tasks, calling into question the feasibility of pruning in LLMs. To address this issue, we propose a pruning pipeline for semi-structured sparse models via retraining, termed Adaptive Sparse Trainer (AST). Unlike previous one-shot pruning methods, AST incrementally transforms dense models into sparse ones by applying decay to masked weights while allowing the model to adaptively select masks throughout the training process. Furthermore, we observe that using distillation with a dense model as the teacher can prevent the sparse model from falling into local optima and accelerate convergence. In addition, we incorporate extra well-initialized parameters to further enhance model performance with minimal increase in memory footprint. AST can significantly enhance model performance, approaching the level of dense models. When applied to the LLaMA2-7B model, AST reduces the zero-shot accuracy gap between dense and semi-structured sparse models to 1.12% across multiple zero-shot tasks, utilizing less than 0.4% of the pretraining tokens. Our work demonstrates the feasibility of deploying semi-structured sparse large language models and introduces a novel method for achieving highly compressed models when combined with existing quantization techniques.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.20584v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weiyu Huang, Yuezhou Hu, Guohao Jian, Jun Zhu, Jianfei Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CARE: A Clue-guided Assistant for CSRs to Read User Manuals</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03633</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03633v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: It is time-saving to build a reading assistant for customer service representations (CSRs) when reading user manuals, especially information-rich ones. Current solutions don't fit the online custom service scenarios well due to the lack of attention to user questions and possible responses. Hence, we propose to develop a time-saving and careful reading assistant for CSRs, named CARE. It can help the CSRs quickly find proper responses from the user manuals via explicit clue chains. Specifically, each of the clue chains is formed by inferring over the user manuals, starting from the question clue aligned with the user question and ending at a possible response. To overcome the shortage of supervised data, we adopt the self-supervised strategy for model learning. The offline experiment shows that CARE is efficient in automatically inferring accurate responses from the user manual. The online experiment further demonstrates the superiority of CARE to reduce CSRs' reading burden and keep high service quality, in particular with &gt;35% decrease in time spent and keeping a &gt;0.75 ICC score.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03633v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weihong Du, Jia Liu, Zujie Wen, Dingnan Jin, Hongru Liang, Wenqiang Lei</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XMainframe: A Large Language Model for Mainframe Modernization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.04660</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.04660v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Mainframe operating systems, despite their inception in the 1940s, continue to support critical sectors like finance and government. However, these systems are often viewed as outdated, requiring extensive maintenance and modernization. Addressing this challenge necessitates innovative tools that can understand and interact with legacy codebases. To this end, we introduce XMainframe, a state-of-the-art large language model (LLM) specifically designed with knowledge of mainframe legacy systems and COBOL codebases. Our solution involves the creation of an extensive data collection pipeline to produce high-quality training datasets, enhancing XMainframe's performance in this specialized domain. Additionally, we present MainframeBench, a comprehensive benchmark for assessing mainframe knowledge, including multiple-choice questions, question answering, and COBOL code summarization. Our empirical evaluations demonstrate that XMainframe consistently outperforms existing state-of-the-art LLMs across these tasks. Specifically, XMainframe achieves 30% higher accuracy than DeepSeek-Coder on multiple-choice questions, doubles the BLEU score of Mixtral-Instruct 8x7B on question answering, and scores six times higher than GPT-3.5 on COBOL summarization. Our work highlights the potential of XMainframe to drive significant advancements in managing and modernizing legacy systems, thereby enhancing productivity and saving time for software developers.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.04660v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Anh T. V. Dau, Hieu Trung Dao, Anh Tuan Nguyen, Hieu Trung Tran, Phong X. Nguyen, Nghi D. Q. Bui</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>reCSE: Portable Reshaping Features for Sentence Embedding in Self-supervised Contrastive Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.04975</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.04975v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We propose reCSE, a self supervised contrastive learning sentence representation framework based on feature reshaping. This framework is different from the current advanced models that use discrete data augmentation methods, but instead reshapes the input features of the original sentence, aggregates the global information of each token in the sentence, and alleviates the common problems of representation polarity and GPU memory consumption linear increase in current advanced models. In addition, our reCSE has achieved competitive performance in semantic similarity tasks. And the experiment proves that our proposed feature reshaping method has strong universality, which can be transplanted to other self supervised contrastive learning frameworks and enhance their representation ability, even achieving state-of-the-art performance. Our code is available at https://github.com/heavenhellchen/reCSE.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.04975v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fufangchen Zhao, Jian Gao, Danfeng Yan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Hybrid RAG System with Comprehensive Enhancement on Complex Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05141</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05141v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) is a framework enabling large language models (LLMs) to enhance their accuracy and reduce hallucinations by integrating external knowledge bases. In this paper, we introduce a hybrid RAG system enhanced through a comprehensive suite of optimizations that significantly improve retrieval quality, augment reasoning capabilities, and refine numerical computation ability. We refined the text chunks and tables in web pages, added attribute predictors to reduce hallucinations, conducted LLM Knowledge Extractor and Knowledge Graph Extractor, and finally built a reasoning strategy with all the references. We evaluated our system on the CRAG dataset through the Meta CRAG KDD Cup 2024 Competition. Both the local and online evaluations demonstrate that our system significantly enhances complex reasoning capabilities. In local evaluations, we have significantly improved accuracy and reduced error rates compared to the baseline model, achieving a notable increase in scores. In the meanwhile, we have attained outstanding results in online assessments, demonstrating the performance and generalization capabilities of the proposed system. The source code for our system is released in \url{https://gitlab.aicrowd.com/shizueyy/crag-new}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05141v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ye Yuan, Chengwu Liu, Jingyang Yuan, Gongbo Sun, Siqi Li, Ming Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Fellowship of the LLMs: Multi-Agent Workflows for Synthetic Preference Optimization Dataset Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08688</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08688v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper presents synthetic Preference Optimization (PO) datasets generated using multi-agent workflows and evaluates the effectiveness and potential of these workflows in the dataset generation process. PO dataset generation requires two modules: (1) response evaluation, and (2) response generation. In the response evaluation module, the responses from Large Language Models (LLMs) are evaluated and ranked - a task typically carried out by human annotators that we automate using LLMs. We assess the response evaluation module in a 2 step process. In step 1, we assess LLMs as evaluators using three distinct prompting strategies. In step 2, we apply the winning prompting strategy to compare the performance of LLM-as-a-Judge, LLMs-as-a-Jury, and LLM Debate. In each step, we use inter-rater agreement using Cohen's Kappa between human annotators and LLMs. For the response generation module, we compare different configurations for the LLM Feedback Loop using the identified LLM evaluator configuration. We use the win rate (the fraction of times a generation framework is selected as the best by an LLM evaluator) to determine the best multi-agent configuration for generation. After identifying the best configurations for both modules, we use models from the GPT, Gemma, and Llama families to generate our PO datasets using the above pipeline. We generate two types of PO datasets, one to improve the generation capabilities of individual LLM and the other to improve the multi-agent workflow. Our evaluation shows that GPT-4o-as-a-Judge is more consistent across datasets when the candidate responses do not include responses from the GPT family. Additionally, we find that the LLM Feedback Loop, with Llama as the generator and Gemma as the reviewer, achieves a notable 71.8% and 73.8% win rate over single-agent Llama and Gemma, respectively.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08688v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Samee Arif, Sualeha Farid, Abdul Hameed Azeemi, Awais Athar, Agha Ali Raza</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Docling Technical Report</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09869</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.09869v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This technical report introduces Docling, an easy to use, self-contained, MIT-licensed open-source package for PDF document conversion. It is powered by state-of-the-art specialized AI models for layout analysis (DocLayNet) and table structure recognition (TableFormer), and runs efficiently on commodity hardware in a small resource budget. The code interface allows for easy extensibility and addition of new features and models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.09869v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Christoph Auer, Maksym Lysak, Ahmed Nassar, Michele Dolfi, Nikolaos Livathinos, Panos Vagenas, Cesar Berrospi Ramis, Matteo Omenetti, Fabian Lindlbauer, Kasper Dinkla, Valery Weber, Lucas Morin, Ingmar Meijer, Viktor Kuropiatnyk, Peter W. J. Staar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BEYOND DIALOGUE: A Profile-Dialogue Alignment Framework Towards General Role-Playing Language Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.10903</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.10903v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The rapid advancement of large language models (LLMs) has revolutionized role-playing, enabling the development of general role-playing models. However, current role-playing training has two significant issues: (I) Using a predefined role profile to prompt dialogue training for specific scenarios usually leads to inconsistencies and even conflicts between the dialogue and the profile, resulting in training biases. (II) The model learns to imitate the role based solely on the profile, neglecting profile-dialogue alignment at the sentence level. In this work, we propose a simple yet effective framework called BEYOND DIALOGUE, designed to overcome these hurdles. This framework innovatively introduces "beyond dialogue" tasks to align dialogue with profile traits based on each specific scenario, thereby eliminating biases during training. Furthermore, by adopting an innovative prompting mechanism that generates reasoning outcomes for training, the framework allows the model to achieve fine-grained alignment between profile and dialogue at the sentence level. The aforementioned methods are fully automated and low-cost. Additionally, the integration of automated dialogue and objective evaluation methods forms a comprehensive framework, paving the way for general role-playing. Experimental results demonstrate that our model excels in adhering to and reflecting various dimensions of role profiles, outperforming most proprietary general and specialized role-playing baselines. All code and datasets are available at https://github.com/yuyouyu32/BeyondDialogue.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.10903v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yeyong Yu, Rusheng Yu, Haojie Wei, Zhanqiu Zhang, Quan Qian</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LBC: Language-Based-Classifier for Out-Of-Variable Generalization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.10923</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.10923v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have great success in natural language processing tasks such as response generation. However, their use in tabular data has been limited due to their inferior performance compared to traditional machine learning models (TMLs) such as XGBoost. We find that the pre-trained knowledge of LLMs enables them to interpret new variables that appear in a test without additional training, a capability central to the concept of Out-of-Variable (OOV). From the findings, we propose a Language-Based-Classifier (LBC), a classifier that maximizes the benefits of LLMs to outperform TMLs on OOV tasks. LBC employs three key methodological strategies: 1) Categorical changes to adjust data to better fit the model's understanding, 2) Advanced order and indicator to enhance data representation to the model, and 3) Using verbalizer to map logit scores to classes during inference to generate model predictions. These strategies, combined with the pre-trained knowledge of LBC, emphasize the model's ability to effectively handle OOV tasks. We empirically and theoretically validate the superiority of LBC. LBC is the first study to apply an LLM-based model to OOV tasks. The source code is at https://github.com/sksmssh/LBCforOOVGen</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.10923v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kangjun Noh, Baekryun Seong, Hoyoon Byun, Youngjun Choi, Sungjin Song, Kyungwoo Song</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SarcasmBench: Towards Evaluating Large Language Models on Sarcasm Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11319</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11319v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In the era of large language models (LLMs), the task of ``System I''~-~the fast, unconscious, and intuitive tasks, e.g., sentiment analysis, text classification, etc., have been argued to be successfully solved. However, sarcasm, as a subtle linguistic phenomenon, often employs rhetorical devices like hyperbole and figuration to convey true sentiments and intentions, involving a higher level of abstraction than sentiment analysis. There is growing concern that the argument about LLMs' success may not be fully tenable when considering sarcasm understanding. To address this question, we select eleven SOTA LLMs and eight SOTA pre-trained language models (PLMs) and present comprehensive evaluations on six widely used benchmark datasets through different prompting approaches, i.e., zero-shot input/output (IO) prompting, few-shot IO prompting, chain of thought (CoT) prompting. Our results highlight three key findings: (1) current LLMs underperform supervised PLMs based sarcasm detection baselines across six sarcasm benchmarks. This suggests that significant efforts are still required to improve LLMs' understanding of human sarcasm. (2) GPT-4 consistently and significantly outperforms other LLMs across various prompting methods, with an average improvement of 14.0\%$\uparrow$. Claude 3 and ChatGPT demonstrate the next best performance after GPT-4. (3) Few-shot IO prompting method outperforms the other two methods: zero-shot IO and few-shot CoT. The reason is that sarcasm detection, being a holistic, intuitive, and non-rational cognitive process, is argued not to adhere to step-by-step logical reasoning, making CoT less effective in understanding sarcasm compared to its effectiveness in mathematical reasoning tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11319v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yazhou Zhang, Chunwang Zou, Zheng Lian, Prayag Tiwari, Jing Qin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM Pruning and Distillation in Practice: The Minitron Approach</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11796</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11796v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We present a comprehensive report on compressing the Llama 3.1 8B and Mistral NeMo 12B models to 4B and 8B parameters, respectively, using pruning and distillation. We explore two distinct pruning strategies: (1) depth pruning and (2) joint hidden/attention/MLP (width) pruning, and evaluate the results on common benchmarks from the LM Evaluation Harness. The models are then aligned with NeMo Aligner and tested in instruct-tuned versions. This approach produces a compelling 4B model from Llama 3.1 8B and a state-of-the-art Mistral-NeMo-Minitron-8B (MN-Minitron-8B for brevity) model from Mistral NeMo 12B. We found that with no access to the original data, it is beneficial to slightly fine-tune teacher models on the distillation dataset. We open-source our base model weights on Hugging Face with a permissive license.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11796v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sharath Turuvekere Sreenivas, Saurav Muralidharan, Raviraj Joshi, Marcin Chochowski, Mostofa Patwary, Mohammad Shoeybi, Bryan Catanzaro, Jan Kautz, Pavlo Molchanov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>uMedSum: A Unified Framework for Advancing Medical Abstractive Summarization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12095</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12095v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Medical abstractive summarization faces the challenge of balancing faithfulness and informativeness. Current methods often sacrifice key information for faithfulness or introduce confabulations when prioritizing informativeness. While recent advancements in techniques like in-context learning (ICL) and fine-tuning have improved medical summarization, they often overlook crucial aspects such as faithfulness and informativeness without considering advanced methods like model reasoning and self-improvement. Moreover, the field lacks a unified benchmark, hindering systematic evaluation due to varied metrics and datasets. This paper addresses these gaps by presenting a comprehensive benchmark of six advanced abstractive summarization methods across three diverse datasets using five standardized metrics. Building on these findings, we propose uMedSum, a modular hybrid summarization framework that introduces novel approaches for sequential confabulation removal followed by key missing information addition, ensuring both faithfulness and informativeness. Our work improves upon previous GPT-4-based state-of-the-art (SOTA) medical summarization methods, significantly outperforming them in both quantitative metrics and qualitative domain expert evaluations. Notably, we achieve an average relative performance improvement of 11.8% in reference-free metrics over the previous SOTA. Doctors prefer uMedSum's summaries 6 times more than previous SOTA in difficult cases where there are chances of confabulations or missing information. These results highlight uMedSum's effectiveness and generalizability across various datasets and metrics, marking a significant advancement in medical summarization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12095v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aishik Nagar, Yutong Liu, Andy T. Liu, Viktor Schlegel, Vijay Prakash Dwivedi, Arun-Kumar Kaliya-Perumal, Guna Pratheep Kalanchiam, Yili Tang, Robby T. Tan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MaVEn: An Effective Multi-granularity Hybrid Visual Encoding Framework for Multimodal Large Language Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12321</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12321v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper presents MaVEn, an innovative Multi-granularity Visual Encoding framework designed to enhance the capabilities of Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) in multi-image reasoning. Current MLLMs primarily focus on single-image visual understanding, limiting their ability to interpret and integrate information across multiple images. MaVEn addresses this limitation by combining discrete visual symbol sequences, which abstract coarse-grained semantic concepts, with traditional continuous representation sequences that model fine-grained features. This dual approach bridges the semantic gap between visual and textual data, thereby improving the model's ability to process and interpret information from multiple images effectively. Additionally, we design a dynamic reduction mechanism by for long-sequence continuous features to enhance multi-image processing efficiency. Experimental results demonstrate that MaVEn significantly enhances MLLMs' understanding in complex multi-image scenarios, while also improving performance in single-image contexts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12321v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chaoya Jiang, Jia Hongrui, Haiyang Xu, Wei Ye, Mengfan Dong, Ming Yan, Ji Zhang, Fei Huang, Shikun Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unboxing Engagement in YouTube Influencer Videos: An Attention-Based Approach</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2012.12311</link>
      <description>arXiv:2012.12311v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Influencer marketing videos have surged in popularity, yet significant gaps remain in understanding the relationship between video features and engagement. This challenge is intensified by the complexities of interpreting unstructured data. While deep learning models effectively leverage unstructured data to predict business outcomes, they often function as black boxes with limited interpretability, particularly when human validation is hindered by the absence of a known ground truth. To address this issue, the authors develop an "interpretable deep learning framework" that not only makes good out-of-sample predictions using unstructured data but also provides insights into the captured relationships. Inspired by visual attention in print advertising, the interpretation approach uses measures of model attention to video features, eliminating spurious associations through a two-step process and shortlisting relationships for formal causal testing. This method is applicable across well-known attention mechanisms - additive attention, scaled dot-product attention, and gradient-based attention - when analyzing text, audio, or video image data. Validated using simulations, this approach outperforms benchmark feature selection methods. This framework is applied to YouTube influencer videos, linking video features to measures of shallow and deep engagement developed based on the dual-system framework of thinking. The findings guide influencers and brands in prioritizing video features associated with deep engagement.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2012.12311v4</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Prashant Rajaram, Puneet Manchanda</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monkey: Image Resolution and Text Label Are Important Things for Large Multi-modal Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.06607</link>
      <description>arXiv:2311.06607v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large Multimodal Models (LMMs) have shown promise in vision-language tasks but struggle with high-resolution input and detailed scene understanding. Addressing these challenges, we introduce Monkey to enhance LMM capabilities. Firstly, Monkey processes input images by dividing them into uniform patches, each matching the size (e.g., 448x448) used in the original training of the well-trained vision encoder. Equipped with individual adapter for each patch, Monkey can handle higher resolutions up to 1344x896 pixels, enabling the detailed capture of complex visual information. Secondly, it employs a multi-level description generation method, enriching the context for scene-object associations. This two-part strategy ensures more effective learning from generated data: the higher resolution allows for a more detailed capture of visuals, which in turn enhances the effectiveness of comprehensive descriptions. Extensive ablative results validate the effectiveness of our designs. Additionally, experiments on 18 datasets further demonstrate that Monkey surpasses existing LMMs in many tasks like Image Captioning and various Visual Question Answering formats. Specially, in qualitative tests focused on dense text question answering, Monkey has exhibited encouraging results compared with GPT4V. Code is available at https://github.com/Yuliang-Liu/Monkey.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2311.06607v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhang Li, Biao Yang, Qiang Liu, Zhiyin Ma, Shuo Zhang, Jingxu Yang, Yabo Sun, Yuliang Liu, Xiang Bai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Big Tech influence over AI research revisited: memetic analysis of attribution of ideas to affiliation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12881</link>
      <description>arXiv:2312.12881v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: There exists a growing discourse around the domination of Big Tech on the landscape of artificial intelligence (AI) research, yet our comprehension of this phenomenon remains cursory. This paper aims to broaden and deepen our understanding of Big Tech's reach and power within AI research. It highlights the dominance not merely in terms of sheer publication volume but rather in the propagation of new ideas or memes. Current studies often oversimplify the concept of influence to the share of affiliations in academic papers, typically sourced from limited databases such as arXiv or specific academic conferences.
  The main goal of this paper is to unravel the specific nuances of such influence, determining which AI ideas are predominantly driven by Big Tech entities. By employing network and memetic analysis on AI-oriented paper abstracts and their citation network, we are able to grasp a deeper insight into this phenomenon. By utilizing two databases: OpenAlex and S2ORC, we are able to perform such analysis on a much bigger scale than previous attempts.
  Our findings suggest that while Big Tech-affiliated papers are disproportionately more cited in some areas, the most cited papers are those affiliated with both Big Tech and Academia. Focusing on the most contagious memes, their attribution to specific affiliation groups (Big Tech, Academia, mixed affiliation) seems equally distributed between those three groups. This suggests that the notion of Big Tech domination over AI research is oversimplified in the discourse.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2312.12881v2</guid>
      <category>physics.soc-ph</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1016/j.joi.2024.101572</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Journal of Informetrics 18(4), 101572 (2024)</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Stanis{\l}aw Gizi\'nski, Paulina Kaczy\'nska, Hubert Ruczy\'nski, Emilia Wi\'snios, Bartosz Pieli\'nski, Przemys{\l}aw Biecek, Julian Sienkiewicz</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning a Decision Tree Algorithm with Transformers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03774</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.03774v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Decision trees are renowned for their ability to achieve high predictive performance while remaining interpretable, especially on tabular data. Traditionally, they are constructed through recursive algorithms, where they partition the data at every node in a tree. However, identifying a good partition is challenging, as decision trees optimized for local segments may not yield global generalization. To address this, we introduce MetaTree, a transformer-based model trained via meta-learning to directly produce strong decision trees. Specifically, we fit both greedy decision trees and globally optimized decision trees on a large number of datasets, and train MetaTree to produce only the trees that achieve strong generalization performance. This training enables MetaTree to emulate these algorithms and intelligently adapt its strategy according to the context, thereby achieving superior generalization performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.03774v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yufan Zhuang, Liyuan Liu, Chandan Singh, Jingbo Shang, Jianfeng Gao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hypothesis Generation with Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.04326</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.04326v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Effective generation of novel hypotheses is instrumental to scientific progress. So far, researchers have been the main powerhouse behind hypothesis generation by painstaking data analysis and thinking (also known as the Eureka moment). In this paper, we examine the potential of large language models (LLMs) to generate hypotheses. We focus on hypothesis generation based on data (i.e., labeled examples). To enable LLMs to handle arbitrarily long contexts, we generate initial hypotheses from a small number of examples and then update them iteratively to improve the quality of hypotheses. Inspired by multi-armed bandits, we design a reward function to inform the exploitation-exploration tradeoff in the update process. Our algorithm is able to generate hypotheses that enable much better predictive performance than few-shot prompting in classification tasks, improving accuracy by 31.7% on a synthetic dataset and by 13.9%, 3.3% and, 24.9% on three real-world datasets. We also outperform supervised learning by 12.8% and 11.2% on two challenging real-world datasets. Furthermore, we find that the generated hypotheses not only corroborate human-verified theories but also uncover new insights for the tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.04326v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yangqiaoyu Zhou, Haokun Liu, Tejes Srivastava, Hongyuan Mei, Chenhao Tan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Re-Thinking Inverse Graphics With Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15228</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15228v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Inverse graphics -- the task of inverting an image into physical variables that, when rendered, enable reproduction of the observed scene -- is a fundamental challenge in computer vision and graphics. Successfully disentangling an image into its constituent elements, such as the shape, color, and material properties of the objects of the 3D scene that produced it, requires a comprehensive understanding of the environment. This complexity limits the ability of existing carefully engineered approaches to generalize across domains. Inspired by the zero-shot ability of large language models (LLMs) to generalize to novel contexts, we investigate the possibility of leveraging the broad world knowledge encoded in such models to solve inverse-graphics problems. To this end, we propose the Inverse-Graphics Large Language Model (IG-LLM), an inverse-graphics framework centered around an LLM, that autoregressively decodes a visual embedding into a structured, compositional 3D-scene representation. We incorporate a frozen pre-trained visual encoder and a continuous numeric head to enable end-to-end training. Through our investigation, we demonstrate the potential of LLMs to facilitate inverse graphics through next-token prediction, without the application of image-space supervision. Our analysis enables new possibilities for precise spatial reasoning about images that exploit the visual knowledge of LLMs. We release our code and data at https://ig-llm.is.tue.mpg.de/ to ensure the reproducibility of our investigation and to facilitate future research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15228v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Peter Kulits, Haiwen Feng, Weiyang Liu, Victoria Abrevaya, Michael J. Black</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Pruning of Pre-trained Language Models via Neural Architecture Search</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02267</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02267v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Pre-trained language models (PLM), for example BERT or RoBERTa, mark the state-of-the-art for natural language understanding task when fine-tuned on labeled data. However, their large size poses challenges in deploying them for inference in real-world applications, due to significant GPU memory requirements and high inference latency. This paper explores neural architecture search (NAS) for structural pruning to find sub-parts of the fine-tuned network that optimally trade-off efficiency, for example in terms of model size or latency, and generalization performance. We also show how we can utilize more recently developed two-stage weight-sharing NAS approaches in this setting to accelerate the search process. Unlike traditional pruning methods with fixed thresholds, we propose to adopt a multi-objective approach that identifies the Pareto optimal set of sub-networks, allowing for a more flexible and automated compression process.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02267v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aaron Klein, Jacek Golebiowski, Xingchen Ma, Valerio Perrone, Cedric Archambeau</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CALRec: Contrastive Alignment of Generative LLMs for Sequential Recommendation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02429</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02429v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Traditional recommender systems such as matrix factorization methods have primarily focused on learning a shared dense embedding space to represent both items and user preferences. Subsequently, sequence models such as RNN, GRUs, and, recently, Transformers have emerged and excelled in the task of sequential recommendation. This task requires understanding the sequential structure present in users' historical interactions to predict the next item they may like. Building upon the success of Large Language Models (LLMs) in a variety of tasks, researchers have recently explored using LLMs that are pretrained on vast corpora of text for sequential recommendation. To use LLMs for sequential recommendation, both the history of user interactions and the model's prediction of the next item are expressed in text form. We propose CALRec, a two-stage LLM finetuning framework that finetunes a pretrained LLM in a two-tower fashion using a mixture of two contrastive losses and a language modeling loss: the LLM is first finetuned on a data mixture from multiple domains followed by another round of target domain finetuning. Our model significantly outperforms many state-of-the-art baselines (+37% in Recall@1 and +24% in NDCG@10) and our systematic ablation studies reveal that (i) both stages of finetuning are crucial, and, when combined, we achieve improved performance, and (ii) contrastive alignment is effective among the target domains explored in our experiments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02429v2</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.48550/arXiv.2405.02429</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Yaoyiran Li, Xiang Zhai, Moustafa Alzantot, Keyi Yu, Ivan Vuli\'c, Anna Korhonen, Mohamed Hammad</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Text to Pixel: Advancing Long-Context Understanding in MLLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.14213</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.14213v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The rapid progress in Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) has significantly advanced their ability to process and understand complex visual and textual information. However, the integration of multiple images and extensive textual contexts remains a challenge due to the inherent limitation of the models' capacity to handle long input sequences efficiently. In this paper, we introduce SEEKER, a multimodal large language model designed to tackle this issue. SEEKER aims to optimize the compact encoding of long text by compressing the text sequence into the visual pixel space via images, enabling the model to handle long text within a fixed token-length budget efficiently. Our empirical experiments on six long-context multimodal tasks demonstrate that SEEKER can leverage fewer image tokens to convey the same amount of textual information compared with the OCR-based approach, and is more efficient in understanding long-form multimodal input and generating long-form textual output, outperforming all existing proprietary and open-source MLLMs by large margins.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.14213v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yujie Lu, Xiujun Li, Tsu-Jui Fu, Miguel Eckstein, William Yang Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LoQT: Low Rank Adapters for Quantized Training</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.16528</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.16528v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Training of large neural networks requires significant computational resources. Despite advances using low-rank adapters and quantization, pretraining of models such as LLMs on consumer hardware has not been possible without model sharding, offloading during training, or per-layer gradient updates. To address these limitations, we propose LoQT, a method for efficiently training quantized models. LoQT uses gradient-based tensor factorization to initialize low-rank trainable weight matrices that are periodically merged into quantized full-rank weight matrices. Our approach is suitable for both pretraining and fine-tuning of models, which we demonstrate experimentally for language modeling and downstream task adaptation. We find that LoQT enables efficient training of models up to 7B parameters on a consumer-grade 24GB GPU. We also demonstrate the feasibility of training a 13B parameter model using per-layer gradient updates on the same hardware.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.16528v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sebastian Loeschcke, Mads Toftrup, Michael J. Kastoryano, Serge Belongie, V\'esteinn Sn{\ae}bjarnarson</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remastering Divide and Remaster: A Cinematic Audio Source Separation Dataset with Multilingual Support</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.07275</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.07275v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Cinematic audio source separation (CASS), as a problem of extracting the dialogue, music, and effects stems from their mixture, is a relatively new subtask of audio source separation. To date, only one publicly available dataset exists for CASS, that is, the Divide and Remaster (DnR) dataset, which is currently at version 2. While DnR v2 has been an incredibly useful resource for CASS, several areas of improvement have been identified, particularly through its use in the 2023 Sound Demixing Challenge. In this work, we develop version 3 of the DnR dataset, addressing issues relating to vocal content in non-dialogue stems, loudness distributions, mastering process, and linguistic diversity. In particular, the dialogue stem of DnR v3 includes speech content from more than 30 languages from multiple families including but not limited to the Germanic, Romance, Indo-Aryan, Dravidian, Malayo-Polynesian, and Bantu families. Benchmark results using the Bandit model indicated that training on multilingual data yields significant generalizability to the model even in languages with low data availability. Even in languages with high data availability, the multilingual model often performs on par or better than dedicated models trained on monolingual CASS datasets. Dataset and model implementation will be made available at https://github.com/kwatcharasupat/source-separation-landing.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.07275v2</guid>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Karn N. Watcharasupat, Chih-Wei Wu, Iroro Orife</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Empowering Whisper as a Joint Multi-Talker and Target-Talker Speech Recognition System</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.09817</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.09817v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Multi-talker speech recognition and target-talker speech recognition, both involve transcription in multi-talker contexts, remain significant challenges. However, existing methods rarely attempt to simultaneously address both tasks. In this study, we propose a pioneering approach to empower Whisper, which is a speech foundation model, to tackle joint multi-talker and target-talker speech recognition tasks. Specifically, (i) we freeze Whisper and plug a Sidecar separator into its encoder to separate mixed embedding for multiple talkers; (ii) a Target Talker Identifier is introduced to identify the embedding flow of the target talker on the fly, requiring only three-second enrollment speech as a cue; (iii) soft prompt tuning for decoder is explored for better task adaptation. Our method outperforms previous methods on two- and three-talker LibriMix and LibriSpeechMix datasets for both tasks, and delivers acceptable zero-shot performance on multi-talker ASR on AishellMix Mandarin dataset.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.09817v2</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lingwei Meng, Jiawen Kang, Yuejiao Wang, Zengrui Jin, Xixin Wu, Xunying Liu, Helen Meng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anchored Preference Optimization and Contrastive Revisions: Addressing Underspecification in Alignment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06266</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06266v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) are often aligned using contrastive alignment objectives and preference pair datasets. The interaction between model, paired data, and objective makes alignment a complicated procedure, sometimes producing subpar results. We study this and find that (i) preference data gives a better learning signal when the underlying responses are contrastive, and (ii) alignment objectives lead to better performance when they specify more control over the model during training. Based on these insights, we introduce Contrastive Learning from AI Revisions (CLAIR), a data-creation method which leads to more contrastive preference pairs, and Anchored Preference Optimization (APO), a controllable and more stable alignment objective. We align Llama-3-8B-Instruct using various comparable datasets and alignment objectives and measure MixEval-Hard scores, which correlate highly with human judgments. The CLAIR preferences lead to the strongest performance out of all datasets, and APO consistently outperforms less controllable objectives. Our best model, trained on 32K CLAIR preferences with APO, improves Llama-3-8B-Instruct by 7.65%, closing the gap with GPT4-turbo by 45%. Our code is available at https://github.com/ContextualAI/CLAIR_and_APO.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06266v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Karel D'Oosterlinck, Winnie Xu, Chris Develder, Thomas Demeester, Amanpreet Singh, Christopher Potts, Douwe Kiela, Shikib Mehri</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unc-TTP: A Method for Classifying LLM Uncertainty to Improve In-Context Example Selection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09172</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.09172v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Nowadays, Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated exceptional performance across various downstream tasks. However, it is challenging for users to discern whether the responses are generated with certainty or are fabricated to meet user expectations. Estimating the uncertainty of LLMs is particularly challenging due to their vast scale and the lack of white-box access. In this work, we propose a novel Uncertainty Tripartite Testing Paradigm (Unc-TTP) to classify LLM uncertainty, via evaluating the consistency of LLM outputs when incorporating label interference into the sampling-based approach. Based on Unc-TTP outputs, we aggregate instances into certain and uncertain categories. Further, we conduct a detailed analysis of the uncertainty properties of LLMs and show Unc-TTP's superiority over the existing sampling-based methods. In addition, we leverage the obtained uncertainty information to guide in-context example selection, demonstrating that Unc-TTP obviously outperforms retrieval-based and sampling-based approaches in selecting more informative examples. Our work paves a new way to classify the uncertainty of both open- and closed-source LLMs, and introduces a practical approach to exploit this uncertainty to improve LLMs performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.09172v3</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hsiu-Yuan Huang, Zichen Wu, Yutong Yang, Junzhao Zhang, Yunfang Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracing Privacy Leakage of Language Models to Training Data via Adjusted Influence Functions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.10468</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.10468v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The responses generated by Large Language Models (LLMs) can include sensitive information from individuals and organizations, leading to potential privacy leakage. This work implements Influence Functions (IFs) to trace privacy leakage back to the training data, thereby mitigating privacy concerns of Language Models (LMs). However, we notice that current IFs struggle to accurately estimate the influence of tokens with large gradient norms, potentially overestimating their influence. When tracing the most influential samples, this leads to frequently tracing back to samples with large gradient norm tokens, overshadowing the actual most influential samples even if their influences are well estimated. To address this issue, we propose Heuristically Adjusted IF (HAIF), which reduces the weight of tokens with large gradient norms, thereby significantly improving the accuracy of tracing the most influential samples. To establish easily obtained groundtruth for tracing privacy leakage, we construct two datasets, PII-E and PII-CR, representing two distinct scenarios: one with identical text in the model outputs and pre-training data, and the other where models leverage their reasoning abilities to generate text divergent from pre-training data. HAIF significantly improves tracing accuracy, enhancing it by 20.96% to 73.71% on the PII-E dataset and 3.21% to 45.93% on the PII-CR dataset, compared to the best SOTA IFs against various GPT-2 and QWen-1.5 models. HAIF also outperforms SOTA IFs on real-world pretraining data CLUECorpus2020, demonstrating strong robustness regardless prompt and response lengths.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.10468v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jinxin Liu, Zao Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MuMA-ToM: Multi-modal Multi-Agent Theory of Mind</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12574</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12574v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Understanding people's social interactions in complex real-world scenarios often relies on intricate mental reasoning. To truly understand how and why people interact with one another, we must infer the underlying mental states that give rise to the social interactions, i.e., Theory of Mind reasoning in multi-agent interactions. Additionally, social interactions are often multi-modal -- we can watch people's actions, hear their conversations, and/or read about their past behaviors. For AI systems to successfully and safely interact with people in real-world environments, they also need to understand people's mental states as well as their inferences about each other's mental states based on multi-modal information about their interactions. For this, we introduce MuMA-ToM, a Multi-modal Multi-Agent Theory of Mind benchmark. MuMA-ToM is the first multi-modal Theory of Mind benchmark that evaluates mental reasoning in embodied multi-agent interactions. In MuMA-ToM, we provide video and text descriptions of people's multi-modal behavior in realistic household environments. Based on the context, we then ask questions about people's goals, beliefs, and beliefs about others' goals. We validated MuMA-ToM in a human experiment and provided a human baseline. We also proposed a novel multi-modal, multi-agent ToM model, LIMP (Language model-based Inverse Multi-agent Planning). Our experimental results show that LIMP significantly outperforms state-of-the-art methods, including large multi-modal models (e.g., GPT-4o, Gemini-1.5 Pro) and a recent multi-modal ToM model, BIP-ALM.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12574v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haojun Shi, Suyu Ye, Xinyu Fang, Chuanyang Jin, Leyla Isik, Yen-Ling Kuo, Tianmin Shu</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
