<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL</link>
    <description>cs.CL updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 19:06:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Saturday</day>
      <day>Sunday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>XC-Cache: Cross-Attending to Cached Context for Efficient LLM Inference</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15420</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15420v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In-context learning (ICL) approaches typically leverage prompting to condition decoder-only language model generation on reference information. Just-in-time processing of a context is inefficient due to the quadratic cost of self-attention operations, and caching is desirable. However, caching transformer states can easily require almost as much space as the model parameters. When the right context isn't known in advance, caching ICL can be challenging. This work addresses these limitations by introducing models that, inspired by the encoder-decoder architecture, use cross-attention to condition generation on reference text without the prompt. More precisely, we leverage pre-trained decoder-only models and only train a small number of added layers. We use Question-Answering (QA) as a testbed to evaluate the ability of our models to perform conditional generation and observe that they outperform ICL, are comparable to fine-tuned prompted LLMs, and drastically reduce the space footprint relative to standard KV caching by two orders of magnitude.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15420v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jo\~ao Monteiro, \'Etienne Marcotte, Pierre-Andr\'e No\"el, Valentina Zantedeschi, David V\'azquez, Nicolas Chapados, Christopher Pal, Perouz Taslakian</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Language Models Spot Phishing Emails with Surprising Accuracy: A Comparative Analysis of Performance</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15485</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15485v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Phishing, a prevalent cybercrime tactic for decades, remains a significant threat in today's digital world. By leveraging clever social engineering elements and modern technology, cybercrime targets many individuals, businesses, and organizations to exploit trust and security. These cyber-attackers are often disguised in many trustworthy forms to appear as legitimate sources. By cleverly using psychological elements like urgency, fear, social proof, and other manipulative strategies, phishers can lure individuals into revealing sensitive and personalized information. Building on this pervasive issue within modern technology, this paper aims to analyze the effectiveness of 15 Large Language Models (LLMs) in detecting phishing attempts, specifically focusing on a randomized set of "419 Scam" emails. The objective is to determine which LLMs can accurately detect phishing emails by analyzing a text file containing email metadata based on predefined criteria. The experiment concluded that the following models, ChatGPT 3.5, GPT-3.5-Turbo-Instruct, and ChatGPT, were the most effective in detecting phishing emails.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15485v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Het Patel, Umair Rehman, Farkhund Iqbal</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IryoNLP at MEDIQA-CORR 2024: Tackling the Medical Error Detection &amp; Correction Task On the Shoulders of Medical Agents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15488</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15488v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In natural language processing applied to the clinical domain, utilizing large language models has emerged as a promising avenue for error detection and correction on clinical notes, a knowledge-intensive task for which annotated data is scarce. This paper presents MedReAct'N'MedReFlex, which leverages a suite of four LLM-based medical agents. The MedReAct agent initiates the process by observing, analyzing, and taking action, generating trajectories to guide the search to target a potential error in the clinical notes. Subsequently, the MedEval agent employs five evaluators to assess the targeted error and the proposed correction. In cases where MedReAct's actions prove insufficient, the MedReFlex agent intervenes, engaging in reflective analysis and proposing alternative strategies. Finally, the MedFinalParser agent formats the final output, preserving the original style while ensuring the integrity of the error correction process. One core component of our method is our RAG pipeline based on our ClinicalCorp corpora. Among other well-known sources containing clinical guidelines and information, we preprocess and release the open-source MedWiki dataset for clinical RAG application. Our results demonstrate the central role of our RAG approach with ClinicalCorp leveraged through the MedReAct'N'MedReFlex framework. It achieved the ninth rank on the MEDIQA-CORR 2024 final leaderboard.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15488v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jean-Philippe Corbeil</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Killkan: The Automatic Speech Recognition Dataset for Kichwa with Morphosyntactic Information</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15501</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15501v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper presents Killkan, the first dataset for automatic speech recognition (ASR) in the Kichwa language, an indigenous language of Ecuador. Kichwa is an extremely low-resource endangered language, and there have been no resources before Killkan for Kichwa to be incorporated in applications of natural language processing. The dataset contains approximately 4 hours of audio with transcription, translation into Spanish, and morphosyntactic annotation in the format of Universal Dependencies. The audio data was retrieved from a publicly available radio program in Kichwa. This paper also provides corpus-linguistic analyses of the dataset with a special focus on the agglutinative morphology of Kichwa and frequent code-switching with Spanish. The experiments show that the dataset makes it possible to develop the first ASR system for Kichwa with reliable quality despite its small dataset size. This dataset, the ASR model, and the code used to develop them will be publicly available. Thus, our study positively showcases resource building and its applications for low-resource languages and their community.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15501v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chihiro Taguchi, Jefferson Saransig, Dayana Vel\'asquez, David Chiang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ToM-LM: Delegating Theory Of Mind Reasoning to External Symbolic Executors in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15515</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15515v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Theory of Mind (ToM) refers to the ability of individuals to attribute mental states to others. While Large Language Models (LLMs) have shown some promise with ToM ability, they still struggle with complex ToM reasoning. Our approach leverages an external symbolic executor, specifically the SMCDEL model checker, and fine-tuning to improve the ToM reasoning ability of LLMs. In our approach, an LLM is first fine-tuned through pairs of natural language and symbolic formulation representation of ToM problems and is then instructed to generate the symbolic formulation with a one-shot in-context example. The generated symbolic formulation is then executed by the SMCDEL model checker to perform transparent and verifiable ToM reasoning and give the final result. We demonstrate that our approach, ToM-LM, shows a significant improvement over all the constructed baselines. Our study proposes a novel view about externalizing a particular component of ToM reasoning, mainly reasoning about beliefs, and suggests generalizing it to other aspects of ToM reasoning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15515v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weizhi Tang, Vaishak Belle</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Systematic Evaluation of Logical Reasoning Ability of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15522</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15522v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recently developed large language models (LLMs) have been shown to perform remarkably well on a wide range of language understanding tasks. But, can they really "reason" over the natural language? This question has been receiving significant research attention and many reasoning skills such as commonsense, numerical, and qualitative have been studied. However, the crucial skill pertaining to 'logical reasoning' has remained underexplored. Existing work investigating this reasoning ability of LLMs has focused only on a couple of inference rules (such as modus ponens and modus tollens) of propositional and first-order logic. Addressing the above limitation, we comprehensively evaluate the logical reasoning ability of LLMs on 25 different reasoning patterns spanning over propositional, first-order, and non-monotonic logics. To enable systematic evaluation, we introduce LogicBench, a natural language question-answering dataset focusing on the use of a single inference rule. We conduct detailed analysis with a range of LLMs such as GPT-4, ChatGPT, Gemini, Llama-2, and Mistral using chain-of-thought prompting. Experimental results show that existing LLMs do not fare well on LogicBench; especially, they struggle with instances involving complex reasoning and negations. Furthermore, they sometimes overlook contextual information necessary for reasoning to arrive at the correct conclusion. We believe that our work and findings facilitate future research for evaluating and enhancing the logical reasoning ability of LLMs. Data and code are available at https://github.com/Mihir3009/LogicBench.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15522v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mihir Parmar, Nisarg Patel, Neeraj Varshney, Mutsumi Nakamura, Man Luo, Santosh Mashetty, Arindam Mitra, Chitta Baral</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PRISM: Patient Records Interpretation for Semantic Clinical Trial Matching using Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15549</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15549v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Clinical trial matching is the task of identifying trials for which patients may be potentially eligible. Typically, this task is labor-intensive and requires detailed verification of patient electronic health records (EHRs) against the stringent inclusion and exclusion criteria of clinical trials. This process is manual, time-intensive, and challenging to scale up, resulting in many patients missing out on potential therapeutic options. Recent advancements in Large Language Models (LLMs) have made automating patient-trial matching possible, as shown in multiple concurrent research studies. However, the current approaches are confined to constrained, often synthetic datasets that do not adequately mirror the complexities encountered in real-world medical data. In this study, we present the first, end-to-end large-scale empirical evaluation of clinical trial matching using real-world EHRs. Our study showcases the capability of LLMs to accurately match patients with appropriate clinical trials. We perform experiments with proprietary LLMs, including GPT-4 and GPT-3.5, as well as our custom fine-tuned model called OncoLLM and show that OncoLLM, despite its significantly smaller size, not only outperforms GPT-3.5 but also matches the performance of qualified medical doctors. All experiments were carried out on real-world EHRs that include clinical notes and available clinical trials from a single cancer center in the United States.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15549v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shashi Kant Gupta, Aditya Basu, Mauro Nievas, Jerrin Thomas, Nathan Wolfrath, Adhitya Ramamurthi, Bradley Taylor, Anai N. Kothari, Therica M. Miller, Sorena Nadaf-Rahrov, Yanshan Wang, Hrituraj Singh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CASPR: Automated Evaluation Metric for Contrastive Summarization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15565</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15565v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Summarizing comparative opinions about entities (e.g., hotels, phones) from a set of source reviews, often referred to as contrastive summarization, can considerably aid users in decision making. However, reliably measuring the contrastiveness of the output summaries without relying on human evaluations remains an open problem. Prior work has proposed token-overlap based metrics, Distinctiveness Score, to measure contrast which does not take into account the sensitivity to meaning-preserving lexical variations. In this work, we propose an automated evaluation metric CASPR to better measure contrast between a pair of summaries. Our metric is based on a simple and light-weight method that leverages natural language inference (NLI) task to measure contrast by segmenting reviews into single-claim sentences and carefully aggregating NLI scores between them to come up with a summary-level score. We compare CASPR with Distinctiveness Score and a simple yet powerful baseline based on BERTScore. Our results on a prior dataset CoCoTRIP demonstrate that CASPR can more reliably capture the contrastiveness of the summary pairs compared to the baselines.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15565v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nirupan Ananthamurugan, Dat Duong, Philip George, Ankita Gupta, Sandeep Tata, Beliz Gunel</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retrieval Head Mechanistically Explains Long-Context Factuality</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15574</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15574v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Despite the recent progress in long-context language models, it remains elusive how transformer-based models exhibit the capability to retrieve relevant information from arbitrary locations within the long context. This paper aims to address this question. Our systematic investigation across a wide spectrum of models reveals that a special type of attention heads are largely responsible for retrieving information, which we dub retrieval heads. We identify intriguing properties of retrieval heads:(1) universal: all the explored models with long-context capability have a set of retrieval heads; (2) sparse: only a small portion (less than 5\%) of the attention heads are retrieval. (3) intrinsic: retrieval heads already exist in models pretrained with short context. When extending the context length by continual pretraining, it is still the same set of heads that perform information retrieval. (4) dynamically activated: take Llama-2 7B for example, 12 retrieval heads always attend to the required information no matter how the context is changed. The rest of the retrieval heads are activated in different contexts. (5) causal: completely pruning retrieval heads leads to failure in retrieving relevant information and results in hallucination, while pruning random non-retrieval heads does not affect the model's retrieval ability. We further show that retrieval heads strongly influence chain-of-thought (CoT) reasoning, where the model needs to frequently refer back the question and previously-generated context. Conversely, tasks where the model directly generates the answer using its intrinsic knowledge are less impacted by masking out retrieval heads. These observations collectively explain which internal part of the model seeks information from the input tokens. We believe our insights will foster future research on reducing hallucination, improving reasoning, and compressing the KV cache.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15574v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenhao Wu, Yizhong Wang, Guangxuan Xiao, Hao Peng, Yao Fu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Foundational Large Language Models Assist with Conducting Pharmaceuticals Manufacturing Investigations?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15578</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15578v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: General purpose Large Language Models (LLM) such as the Generative Pretrained Transformer (GPT) and Large Language Model Meta AI (LLaMA) have attracted much attention in recent years. There is strong evidence that these models can perform remarkably well in various natural language processing tasks. However, how to leverage them to approach domain-specific use cases and drive value remains an open question. In this work, we focus on a specific use case, pharmaceutical manufacturing investigations, and propose that leveraging historical records of manufacturing incidents and deviations in an organization can be beneficial for addressing and closing new cases, or de-risking new manufacturing campaigns. Using a small but diverse dataset of real manufacturing deviations selected from different product lines, we evaluate and quantify the power of three general purpose LLMs (GPT-3.5, GPT-4, and Claude-2) in performing tasks related to the above goal. In particular, (1) the ability of LLMs in automating the process of extracting specific information such as root cause of a case from unstructured data, as well as (2) the possibility of identifying similar or related deviations by performing semantic search on the database of historical records are examined. While our results point to the high accuracy of GPT-4 and Claude-2 in the information extraction task, we discuss cases of complex interplay between the apparent reasoning and hallucination behavior of LLMs as a risk factor. Furthermore, we show that semantic search on vector embedding of deviation descriptions can be used to identify similar records, such as those with a similar type of defect, with a high level of accuracy. We discuss further improvements to enhance the accuracy of similar record identification.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15578v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hossein Salami (Digital Services, MMD, Merck &amp; Co., Inc., Rahway, NJ, USA), Brandye Smith-Goettler (Digital Services, MMD, Merck &amp; Co., Inc., West Point, PA, USA), Vijay Yadav (Digital Services, MMD, Merck &amp; Co., Inc., West Point, PA, USA)</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minimal Evidence Group Identification for Claim Verification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15588</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15588v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Claim verification in real-world settings (e.g. against a large collection of candidate evidences retrieved from the web) typically requires identifying and aggregating a complete set of evidence pieces that collectively provide full support to the claim. The problem becomes particularly challenging when there exists distinct sets of evidence that could be used to verify the claim from different perspectives. In this paper, we formally define and study the problem of identifying such minimal evidence groups (MEGs) for claim verification. We show that MEG identification can be reduced from Set Cover problem, based on entailment inference of whether a given evidence group provides full/partial support to a claim. Our proposed approach achieves 18.4% and 34.8% absolute improvements on the WiCE and SciFact datasets over LLM prompting. Finally, we demonstrate the benefits of MEGs in downstream applications such as claim generation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15588v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiangci Li, Sihao Chen, Rajvi Kapadia, Jessica Ouyang, Fan Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid LLM/Rule-based Approaches to Business Insights Generation from Structured Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15604</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15604v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In the field of business data analysis, the ability to extract actionable insights from vast and varied datasets is essential for informed decision-making and maintaining a competitive edge. Traditional rule-based systems, while reliable, often fall short when faced with the complexity and dynamism of modern business data. Conversely, Artificial Intelligence (AI) models, particularly Large Language Models (LLMs), offer significant potential in pattern recognition and predictive analytics but can lack the precision necessary for specific business applications. This paper explores the efficacy of hybrid approaches that integrate the robustness of rule-based systems with the adaptive power of LLMs in generating actionable business insights.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15604v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aliaksei Vertsel, Mikhail Rumiantsau</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CodeIP: A Grammar-Guided Multi-Bit Watermark for Large Language Models of Code</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15639</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15639v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: As Large Language Models (LLMs) are increasingly used to automate code generation, it is often desired to know if the code is AI-generated and by which model, especially for purposes like protecting intellectual property (IP) in industry and preventing academic misconduct in education. Incorporating watermarks into machine-generated content is one way to provide code provenance, but existing solutions are restricted to a single bit or lack flexibility. We present CodeIP, a new watermarking technique for LLM-based code generation. CodeIP enables the insertion of multi-bit information while preserving the semantics of the generated code, improving the strength and diversity of the inerseted watermark. This is achieved by training a type predictor to predict the subsequent grammar type of the next token to enhance the syntactical and semantic correctness of the generated code. Experiments on a real-world dataset across five programming languages showcase the effectiveness of CodeIP.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15639v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Batu Guan, Yao Wan, Zhangqian Bi, Zheng Wang, Hongyu Zhang, Yulei Sui, Pan Zhou, Lichao Sun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Return of EM: Entity-driven Answer Set Expansion for QA Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15650</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15650v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recently, directly using large language models (LLMs) has been shown to be the most reliable method to evaluate QA models. However, it suffers from limited interpretability, high cost, and environmental harm. To address these, we propose to use soft EM with entity-driven answer set expansion. Our approach expands the gold answer set to include diverse surface forms, based on the observation that the surface forms often follow particular patterns depending on the entity type. The experimental results show that our method outperforms traditional evaluation methods by a large margin. Moreover, the reliability of our evaluation method is comparable to that of LLM-based ones, while offering the benefits of high interpretability and reduced environmental harm.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15650v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dongryeol Lee, Minwoo Lee, Kyungmin Min, Joonsuk Park, Kyomin Jung</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KS-LLM: Knowledge Selection of Large Language Models with Evidence Document for Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15660</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15660v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) suffer from the hallucination problem and face significant challenges when applied to knowledge-intensive tasks. A promising approach is to leverage evidence documents as extra supporting knowledge, which can be obtained through retrieval or generation. However, existing methods directly leverage the entire contents of the evidence document, which may introduce noise information and impair the performance of large language models. To tackle this problem, we propose a novel Knowledge Selection of Large Language Models (KS-LLM) method, aiming to identify valuable information from evidence documents. The KS-LLM approach utilizes triples to effectively select knowledge snippets from evidence documents that are beneficial to answering questions. Specifically, we first generate triples based on the input question, then select the evidence sentences most similar to triples from the evidence document, and finally combine the evidence sentences and triples to assist large language models in generating answers. Experimental comparisons on several question answering datasets, such as TriviaQA, WebQ, and NQ, demonstrate that the proposed method surpasses the baselines and achieves the best results.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15660v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xinxin Zheng, Feihu Che, Jinyang Wu, Shuai Zhang, Shuai Nie, Kang Liu, Jianhua Tao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Promise and Challenges of Using LLMs to Accelerate the Screening Process of Systematic Reviews</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15667</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15667v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Systematic review (SR) is a popular research method in software engineering (SE). However, conducting an SR takes an average of 67 weeks. Thus, automating any step of the SR process could reduce the effort associated with SRs. Our objective is to investigate if Large Language Models (LLMs) can accelerate title-abstract screening by simplifying abstracts for human screeners, and automating title-abstract screening. We performed an experiment where humans screened titles and abstracts for 20 papers with both original and simplified abstracts from a prior SR. The experiment with human screeners was reproduced with GPT-3.5 and GPT-4 LLMs to perform the same screening tasks. We also studied if different prompting techniques (Zero-shot (ZS), One-shot (OS), Few-shot (FS), and Few-shot with Chain-of-Thought (FS-CoT)) improve the screening performance of LLMs. Lastly, we studied if redesigning the prompt used in the LLM reproduction of screening leads to improved performance. Text simplification did not increase the screeners' screening performance, but reduced the time used in screening. Screeners' scientific literacy skills and researcher status predict screening performance. Some LLM and prompt combinations perform as well as human screeners in the screening tasks. Our results indicate that the GPT-4 LLM is better than its predecessor, GPT-3.5. Additionally, Few-shot and One-shot prompting outperforms Zero-shot prompting. Using LLMs for text simplification in the screening process does not significantly improve human performance. Using LLMs to automate title-abstract screening seems promising, but current LLMs are not significantly more accurate than human screeners. To recommend the use of LLMs in the screening process of SRs, more research is needed. We recommend future SR studies publish replication packages with screening data to enable more conclusive experimenting with LLM screening.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15667v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aleksi Huotala, Miikka Kuutila, Paul Ralph, Mika M\"antyl\"a</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Chain-of-Thought: A Survey of Chain-of-X Paradigms for LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15676</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15676v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Chain-of-Thought (CoT) has been a widely adopted prompting method, eliciting impressive reasoning abilities of Large Language Models (LLMs). Inspired by the sequential thought structure of CoT, a number of Chain-of-X (CoX) methods have been developed to address various challenges across diverse domains and tasks involving LLMs. In this paper, we provide a comprehensive survey of Chain-of-X methods for LLMs in different contexts. Specifically, we categorize them by taxonomies of nodes, i.e., the X in CoX, and application tasks. We also discuss the findings and implications of existing CoX methods, as well as potential future directions. Our survey aims to serve as a detailed and up-to-date resource for researchers seeking to apply the idea of CoT to broader scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15676v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yu Xia, Rui Wang, Xu Liu, Mingyan Li, Tong Yu, Xiang Chen, Julian McAuley, Shuai Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neural Proto-Language Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15690</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15690v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Proto-form reconstruction has been a painstaking process for linguists. Recently, computational models such as RNN and Transformers have been proposed to automate this process. We take three different approaches to improve upon previous methods, including data augmentation to recover missing reflexes, adding a VAE structure to the Transformer model for proto-to-language prediction, and using a neural machine translation model for the reconstruction task. We find that with the additional VAE structure, the Transformer model has a better performance on the WikiHan dataset, and the data augmentation step stabilizes the training.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15690v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chenxuan Cui, Ying Chen, Qinxin Wang, David R. Mortensen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nyonic Technical Report</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15702</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15702v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This report details the development and key achievements of our latest language model designed for custom large language models. The advancements introduced include a novel Online Data Scheduler that supports flexible training data adjustments and curriculum learning. The model's architecture is fortified with state-of-the-art techniques such as Rotary Positional Embeddings, QK-LayerNorm, and a specially crafted multilingual tokenizer to enhance stability and performance. Moreover, our robust training framework incorporates advanced monitoring and rapid recovery features to ensure optimal efficiency. Our Wonton 7B model has demonstrated competitive performance on a range of multilingual and English benchmarks. Future developments will prioritize narrowing the performance gap with more extensively trained models, thereby enhancing the model's real-world efficacy and adaptability.GitHub: \url{https://github.com/nyonicai/nyonic-public}</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15702v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junfeng Tian, Rui Wang, Cong Li, Yudong Zhou, Jun Liu, Jun Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Annotator-Centric Active Learning for Subjective NLP Tasks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15720</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15720v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: To accurately capture the variability in human judgments for subjective NLP tasks, incorporating a wide range of perspectives in the annotation process is crucial. Active Learning (AL) addresses the high costs of collecting human annotations by strategically annotating the most informative samples. We introduce Annotator-Centric Active Learning (ACAL), which incorporates an annotator selection strategy following data sampling. Our objective is two-fold: (1) to efficiently approximate the full diversity of human judgments, and to assess model performance using annotator-centric metrics, which emphasize minority perspectives over a majority. We experiment with multiple annotator selection strategies across seven subjective NLP tasks, employing both traditional and novel, human-centered evaluation metrics. Our findings indicate that ACAL improves data efficiency and excels in annotator-centric performance evaluations. However, its success depends on the availability of a sufficiently large and diverse pool of annotators to sample from.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15720v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Michiel van der Meer, Neele Falk, Pradeep K. Murukannaiah, Enrico Liscio</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No Train but Gain: Language Arithmetic for training-free Language Adapters enhancement</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15737</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15737v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Modular deep learning is the state-of-the-art solution for lifting the curse of multilinguality, preventing the impact of negative interference and enabling cross-lingual performance in Multilingual Pre-trained Language Models. However, a trade-off of this approach is the reduction in positive transfer learning from closely related languages. In response, we introduce a novel method called language arithmetic, which enables training-free post-processing to address this limitation. Inspired by the task arithmetic framework, we apply learning via addition to the language adapters, transitioning the framework from a multi-task to a multilingual setup. The effectiveness of the proposed solution is demonstrated on three downstream tasks in a MAD-X-based set of cross-lingual schemes, acting as a post-processing procedure. Language arithmetic consistently improves the baselines with significant gains in the most challenging cases of zero-shot and low-resource applications. Our code and models are available at https://github.com/mklimasz/language-arithmetic .</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15737v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mateusz Klimaszewski, Piotr Andruszkiewicz, Alexandra Birch</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let's Think Dot by Dot: Hidden Computation in Transformer Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15758</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15758v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Chain-of-thought responses from language models improve performance across most benchmarks. However, it remains unclear to what extent these performance gains can be attributed to human-like task decomposition or simply the greater computation that additional tokens allow. We show that transformers can use meaningless filler tokens (e.g., '......') in place of a chain of thought to solve two hard algorithmic tasks they could not solve when responding without intermediate tokens. However, we find empirically that learning to use filler tokens is difficult and requires specific, dense supervision to converge. We also provide a theoretical characterization of the class of problems where filler tokens are useful in terms of the quantifier depth of a first-order formula. For problems satisfying this characterization, chain-of-thought tokens need not provide information about the intermediate computational steps involved in multi-token computations. In summary, our results show that additional tokens can provide computational benefits independent of token choice. The fact that intermediate tokens can act as filler tokens raises concerns about large language models engaging in unauditable, hidden computations that are increasingly detached from the observed chain-of-thought tokens.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15758v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jacob Pfau, William Merrill, Samuel R. Bowman</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehensive Survey on Evaluating Large Language Model Applications in the Medical Industry</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15777</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15777v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Since the inception of the Transformer architecture in 2017, Large Language Models (LLMs) such as GPT and BERT have evolved significantly, impacting various industries with their advanced capabilities in language understanding and generation. These models have shown potential to transform the medical field, highlighting the necessity for specialized evaluation frameworks to ensure their effective and ethical deployment. This comprehensive survey delineates the extensive application and requisite evaluation of LLMs within healthcare, emphasizing the critical need for empirical validation to fully exploit their capabilities in enhancing healthcare outcomes.
  Our survey is structured to provide an in-depth analysis of LLM applications across clinical settings, medical text data processing, research, education, and public health awareness. We begin by exploring the roles of LLMs in different medical applications, detailing how they are evaluated based on their performance in tasks such as clinical application, medical text data processing, information retrieval, data analysis, medical scientific writing, educational content generation etc. The subsequent sections delve into the methodologies employed in these evaluations, discussing the benchmarks and metrics used to assess the models' effectiveness, accuracy, and ethical alignment.
  Through this survey, we aim to equip healthcare professionals, researchers, and policymakers with a comprehensive understanding of the potential strengths and limitations of LLMs in medical applications. By providing detailed insights into the evaluation processes and the challenges faced in integrating LLMs into healthcare, this survey seeks to guide the responsible development and deployment of these powerful models, ensuring they are harnessed to their full potential while maintaining stringent ethical standards.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15777v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yining Huang, Keke Tang, Meilian Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Subgraph for All: Efficient Reasoning on Opening Subgraphs for Inductive Knowledge Graph Completion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15807</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15807v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Knowledge Graph Completion (KGC) has garnered massive research interest recently, and most existing methods are designed following a transductive setting where all entities are observed during training. Despite the great progress on the transductive KGC, these methods struggle to conduct reasoning on emerging KGs involving unseen entities. Thus, inductive KGC, which aims to deduce missing links among unseen entities, has become a new trend. Many existing studies transform inductive KGC as a graph classification problem by extracting enclosing subgraphs surrounding each candidate triple. Unfortunately, they still face certain challenges, such as the expensive time consumption caused by the repeat extraction of enclosing subgraphs, and the deficiency of entity-independent feature learning. To address these issues, we propose a global-local anchor representation (GLAR) learning method for inductive KGC. Unlike previous methods that utilize enclosing subgraphs, we extract a shared opening subgraph for all candidates and perform reasoning on it, enabling the model to perform reasoning more efficiently. Moreover, we design some transferable global and local anchors to learn rich entity-independent features for emerging entities. Finally, a global-local graph reasoning model is applied on the opening subgraph to rank all candidates. Extensive experiments show that our GLAR outperforms most existing state-of-the-art methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15807v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhiwen Xie, Yi Zhang, Guangyou Zhou, Jin Liu, Xinhui Tu, Jimmy Xiangji Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring LLM Prompting Strategies for Joint Essay Scoring and Feedback Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15845</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15845v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Individual feedback can help students improve their essay writing skills. However, the manual effort required to provide such feedback limits individualization in practice. Automatically-generated essay feedback may serve as an alternative to guide students at their own pace, convenience, and desired frequency. Large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated strong performance in generating coherent and contextually relevant text. Yet, their ability to provide helpful essay feedback is unclear. This work explores several prompting strategies for LLM-based zero-shot and few-shot generation of essay feedback. Inspired by Chain-of-Thought prompting, we study how and to what extent automated essay scoring (AES) can benefit the quality of generated feedback. We evaluate both the AES performance that LLMs can achieve with prompting only and the helpfulness of the generated essay feedback. Our results suggest that tackling AES and feedback generation jointly improves AES performance. However, while our manual evaluation emphasizes the quality of the generated essay feedback, the impact of essay scoring on the generated feedback remains low ultimately.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15845v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Maja Stahl, Leon Biermann, Andreas Nehring, Henning Wachsmuth</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Complex to Simple: Enhancing Multi-Constraint Complex Instruction Following Ability of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15846</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15846v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: It is imperative for Large language models (LLMs) to follow instructions with elaborate requirements (i.e. Complex Instructions Following). Yet, it remains under-explored how to enhance the ability of LLMs to follow complex instructions with multiple constraints. To bridge the gap, we initially study what training data is effective in enhancing complex constraints following abilities. We found that training LLMs with instructions containing multiple constraints enhances their understanding of complex instructions, especially those with lower complexity levels. The improvement can even generalize to compositions of out-of-domain constraints. Additionally, we further propose methods addressing how to obtain and utilize the effective training data. Finally, we conduct extensive experiments to prove the effectiveness of our methods in terms of overall performance, training efficiency, and generalization abilities under four settings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15846v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qianyu He, Jie Zeng, Qianxi He, Jiaqing Liang, Yanghua Xiao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Detecting Conceptual Abstraction in LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15848</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15848v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present a novel approach to detecting noun abstraction within a large language model (LLM). Starting from a psychologically motivated set of noun pairs in taxonomic relationships, we instantiate surface patterns indicating hypernymy and analyze the attention matrices produced by BERT. We compare the results to two sets of counterfactuals and show that we can detect hypernymy in the abstraction mechanism, which cannot solely be related to the distributional similarity of noun pairs. Our findings are a first step towards the explainability of conceptual abstraction in LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15848v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Michaela Regneri, Alhassan Abdelhalim, S\"oren Laue</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Unsupervised Constrained Text Generation based on Perturbed Masking</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15877</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15877v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Unsupervised constrained text generation aims to generate text under a given set of constraints without any supervised data. Current state-of-the-art methods stochastically sample edit positions and actions, which may cause unnecessary search steps. In this paper, we propose PMCTG to improve effectiveness by searching for the best edit position and action in each step. Specifically, PMCTG extends perturbed masking technique to effectively search for the most incongruent token to edit. Then it introduces four multi-aspect scoring functions to select edit action to further reduce search difficulty. Since PMCTG does not require supervised data, it could be applied to different generation tasks. We show that under the unsupervised setting, PMCTG achieves new state-of-the-art results in two representative tasks, namely keywords-to-sentence generation and paraphrasing.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15877v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yingwen Fu, Wenjie Ou, Zhou Yu, Yue Lin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing The Potential Of Mid-Sized Language Models For Clinical QA</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15894</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15894v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models, such as GPT-4 and Med-PaLM, have shown impressive performance on clinical tasks; however, they require access to compute, are closed-source, and cannot be deployed on device. Mid-size models such as BioGPT-large, BioMedLM, LLaMA 2, and Mistral 7B avoid these drawbacks, but their capacity for clinical tasks has been understudied. To help assess their potential for clinical use and help researchers decide which model they should use, we compare their performance on two clinical question-answering (QA) tasks: MedQA and consumer query answering. We find that Mistral 7B is the best performing model, winning on all benchmarks and outperforming models trained specifically for the biomedical domain. While Mistral 7B's MedQA score of 63.0% approaches the original Med-PaLM, and it often can produce plausible responses to consumer health queries, room for improvement still exists. This study provides the first head-to-head assessment of open source mid-sized models on clinical tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15894v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Elliot Bolton, Betty Xiong, Vijaytha Muralidharan, Joel Schamroth, Vivek Muralidharan, Christopher D. Manning, Roxana Daneshjou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generalization Measures for Zero-Shot Cross-Lingual Transfer</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15928</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15928v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: A model's capacity to generalize its knowledge to interpret unseen inputs with different characteristics is crucial to build robust and reliable machine learning systems. Language model evaluation tasks lack information metrics about model generalization and their applicability in a new setting is measured using task and language-specific downstream performance, which is often lacking in many languages and tasks. In this paper, we explore a set of efficient and reliable measures that could aid in computing more information related to the generalization capability of language models in cross-lingual zero-shot settings. In addition to traditional measures such as variance in parameters after training and distance from initialization, we also measure the effectiveness of sharpness in loss landscape in capturing the success in cross-lingual transfer and propose a novel and stable algorithm to reliably compute the sharpness of a model optimum that correlates to generalization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15928v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Saksham Bassi, Duygu Ataman, Kyunghyun Cho</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sequence can Secretly Tell You What to Discard</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15949</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15949v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs), despite their impressive performance on a wide range of tasks, require significant GPU memory and consume substantial computational resources. In addition to model weights, the memory occupied by KV cache increases linearly with sequence length, becoming a main bottleneck for inference. In this paper, we introduce a novel approach for optimizing the KV cache which significantly reduces its memory footprint. Through a comprehensive investigation, we find that on LLaMA2 series models, (i) the similarity between adjacent tokens' query vectors is remarkably high, and (ii) current query's attention calculation can rely solely on the attention information of a small portion of the preceding queries. Based on these observations, we propose CORM, a KV cache eviction policy that dynamically retains important key-value pairs for inference without finetuning the model. We validate that CORM reduces the inference memory usage of KV cache by up to 70% without noticeable performance degradation across six tasks in LongBench.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15949v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jincheng Dai, Zhuowei Huang, Haiyun Jiang, Chen Chen, Deng Cai, Wei Bi, Shuming Shi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The PRISM Alignment Project: What Participatory, Representative and Individualised Human Feedback Reveals About the Subjective and Multicultural Alignment of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.16019</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.16019v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Human feedback plays a central role in the alignment of Large Language Models (LLMs). However, open questions remain about the methods (how), domains (where), people (who) and objectives (to what end) of human feedback collection. To navigate these questions, we introduce PRISM, a new dataset which maps the sociodemographics and stated preferences of 1,500 diverse participants from 75 countries, to their contextual preferences and fine-grained feedback in 8,011 live conversations with 21 LLMs. PRISM contributes (i) wide geographic and demographic participation in human feedback data; (ii) two census-representative samples for understanding collective welfare (UK and US); and (iii) individualised feedback where every rating is linked to a detailed participant profile, thus permitting exploration of personalisation and attribution of sample artefacts. We focus on collecting conversations that centre subjective and multicultural perspectives on value-laden and controversial topics, where we expect the most interpersonal and cross-cultural disagreement. We demonstrate the usefulness of PRISM via three case studies of dialogue diversity, preference diversity, and welfare outcomes, showing that it matters which humans set alignment norms. As well as offering a rich community resource, we advocate for broader participation in AI development and a more inclusive approach to technology design.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.16019v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hannah Rose Kirk, Alexander Whitefield, Paul R\"ottger, Andrew Bean, Katerina Margatina, Juan Ciro, Rafael Mosquera, Max Bartolo, Adina Williams, He He, Bertie Vidgen, Scott A. Hale</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Universal Adversarial Triggers Are Not Universal</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.16020</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.16020v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent work has developed optimization procedures to find token sequences, called adversarial triggers, which can elicit unsafe responses from aligned language models. These triggers are believed to be universally transferable, i.e., a trigger optimized on one model can jailbreak other models. In this paper, we concretely show that such adversarial triggers are not universal. We extensively investigate trigger transfer amongst 13 open models and observe inconsistent transfer. Our experiments further reveal a significant difference in robustness to adversarial triggers between models Aligned by Preference Optimization (APO) and models Aligned by Fine-Tuning (AFT). We find that APO models are extremely hard to jailbreak even when the trigger is optimized directly on the model. On the other hand, while AFT models may appear safe on the surface, exhibiting refusals to a range of unsafe instructions, we show that they are highly susceptible to adversarial triggers. Lastly, we observe that most triggers optimized on AFT models also generalize to new unsafe instructions from five diverse domains, further emphasizing their vulnerability. Overall, our work highlights the need for more comprehensive safety evaluations for aligned language models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.16020v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nicholas Meade, Arkil Patel, Siva Reddy</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Large Language Models to Enrich the Documentation of Datasets for Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15320</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15320v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recent regulatory initiatives like the European AI Act and relevant voices in the Machine Learning (ML) community stress the need to describe datasets along several key dimensions for trustworthy AI, such as the provenance processes and social concerns. However, this information is typically presented as unstructured text in accompanying documentation, hampering their automated analysis and processing. In this work, we explore using large language models (LLM) and a set of prompting strategies to automatically extract these dimensions from documents and enrich the dataset description with them. Our approach could aid data publishers and practitioners in creating machine-readable documentation to improve the discoverability of their datasets, assess their compliance with current AI regulations, and improve the overall quality of ML models trained on them.
  In this paper, we evaluate the approach on 12 scientific dataset papers published in two scientific journals (Nature's Scientific Data and Elsevier's Data in Brief) using two different LLMs (GPT3.5 and Flan-UL2). Results show good accuracy with our prompt extraction strategies. Concrete results vary depending on the dimensions, but overall, GPT3.5 shows slightly better accuracy (81,21%) than FLAN-UL2 (69,13%) although it is more prone to hallucinations. We have released an open-source tool implementing our approach and a replication package, including the experiments' code and results, in an open-source repository.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15320v1</guid>
      <category>cs.DL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Joan Giner-Miguelez, Abel G\'omez, Jordi Cabot</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wiki-LLaVA: Hierarchical Retrieval-Augmented Generation for Multimodal LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15406</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15406v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Multimodal LLMs are the natural evolution of LLMs, and enlarge their capabilities so as to work beyond the pure textual modality. As research is being carried out to design novel architectures and vision-and-language adapters, in this paper we concentrate on endowing such models with the capability of answering questions that require external knowledge. Our approach, termed Wiki-LLaVA, aims at integrating an external knowledge source of multimodal documents, which is accessed through a hierarchical retrieval pipeline. Relevant passages, using this approach, are retrieved from the external knowledge source and employed as additional context for the LLM, augmenting the effectiveness and precision of generated dialogues. We conduct extensive experiments on datasets tailored for visual question answering with external data and demonstrate the appropriateness of our approach.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15406v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Davide Caffagni, Federico Cocchi, Nicholas Moratelli, Sara Sarto, Marcella Cornia, Lorenzo Baraldi, Rita Cucchiara</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GeoLLM-Engine: A Realistic Environment for Building Geospatial Copilots</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15500</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15500v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Geospatial Copilots unlock unprecedented potential for performing Earth Observation (EO) applications through natural language instructions. However, existing agents rely on overly simplified single tasks and template-based prompts, creating a disconnect with real-world scenarios. In this work, we present GeoLLM-Engine, an environment for tool-augmented agents with intricate tasks routinely executed by analysts on remote sensing platforms. We enrich our environment with geospatial API tools, dynamic maps/UIs, and external multimodal knowledge bases to properly gauge an agent's proficiency in interpreting realistic high-level natural language commands and its functional correctness in task completions. By alleviating overheads typically associated with human-in-the-loop benchmark curation, we harness our massively parallel engine across 100 GPT-4-Turbo nodes, scaling to over half a million diverse multi-tool tasks and across 1.1 million satellite images. By moving beyond traditional single-task image-caption paradigms, we investigate state-of-the-art agents and prompting techniques against long-horizon prompts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15500v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Simranjit Singh, Michael Fore, Dimitrios Stamoulis</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BattleAgent: Multi-modal Dynamic Emulation on Historical Battles to Complement Historical Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15532</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15532v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This paper presents BattleAgent, an emulation system that combines the Large Vision-Language Model and Multi-agent System. This novel system aims to simulate complex dynamic interactions among multiple agents, as well as between agents and their environments, over a period of time. It emulates both the decision-making processes of leaders and the viewpoints of ordinary participants, such as soldiers. The emulation showcases the current capabilities of agents, featuring fine-grained multi-modal interactions between agents and landscapes. It develops customizable agent structures to meet specific situational requirements, for example, a variety of battle-related activities like scouting and trench digging. These components collaborate to recreate historical events in a lively and comprehensive manner while offering insights into the thoughts and feelings of individuals from diverse viewpoints. The technological foundations of BattleAgent establish detailed and immersive settings for historical battles, enabling individual agents to partake in, observe, and dynamically respond to evolving battle scenarios. This methodology holds the potential to substantially deepen our understanding of historical events, particularly through individual accounts. Such initiatives can also aid historical research, as conventional historical narratives often lack documentation and prioritize the perspectives of decision-makers, thereby overlooking the experiences of ordinary individuals. BattelAgent illustrates AI's potential to revitalize the human aspect in crucial social events, thereby fostering a more nuanced collective understanding and driving the progressive development of human society.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15532v1</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shuhang Lin, Wenyue Hua, Lingyao Li, Che-Jui Chang, Lizhou Fan, Jianchao Ji, Hang Hua, Mingyu Jin, Jiebo Luo, Yongfeng Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DreamCraft: Text-Guided Generation of Functional 3D Environments in Minecraft</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15538</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15538v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Procedural Content Generation (PCG) algorithms enable the automatic generation of complex and diverse artifacts. However, they don't provide high-level control over the generated content and typically require domain expertise. In contrast, text-to-3D methods allow users to specify desired characteristics in natural language, offering a high amount of flexibility and expressivity. But unlike PCG, such approaches cannot guarantee functionality, which is crucial for certain applications like game design. In this paper, we present a method for generating functional 3D artifacts from free-form text prompts in the open-world game Minecraft. Our method, DreamCraft, trains quantized Neural Radiance Fields (NeRFs) to represent artifacts that, when viewed in-game, match given text descriptions. We find that DreamCraft produces more aligned in-game artifacts than a baseline that post-processes the output of an unconstrained NeRF. Thanks to the quantized representation of the environment, functional constraints can be integrated using specialized loss terms. We show how this can be leveraged to generate 3D structures that match a target distribution or obey certain adjacency rules over the block types. DreamCraft inherits a high degree of expressivity and controllability from the NeRF, while still being able to incorporate functional constraints through domain-specific objectives.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15538v1</guid>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sam Earle, Filippos Kokkinos, Yuhe Nie, Julian Togelius, Roberta Raileanu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ImplicitAVE: An Open-Source Dataset and Multimodal LLMs Benchmark for Implicit Attribute Value Extraction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15592</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15592v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Existing datasets for attribute value extraction (AVE) predominantly focus on explicit attribute values while neglecting the implicit ones, lack product images, are often not publicly available, and lack an in-depth human inspection across diverse domains. To address these limitations, we present ImplicitAVE, the first, publicly available multimodal dataset for implicit attribute value extraction. ImplicitAVE, sourced from the MAVE dataset, is carefully curated and expanded to include implicit AVE and multimodality, resulting in a refined dataset of 68k training and 1.6k testing data across five domains. We also explore the application of multimodal large language models (MLLMs) to implicit AVE, establishing a comprehensive benchmark for MLLMs on the ImplicitAVE dataset. Six recent MLLMs with eleven variants are evaluated across diverse settings, revealing that implicit value extraction remains a challenging task for MLLMs. The contributions of this work include the development and release of ImplicitAVE, and the exploration and benchmarking of various MLLMs for implicit AVE, providing valuable insights and potential future research directions. Dataset and code are available at https://github.com/HenryPengZou/ImplicitAVE</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15592v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Henry Peng Zou, Vinay Samuel, Yue Zhou, Weizhi Zhang, Liancheng Fang, Zihe Song, Philip S. Yu, Cornelia Caragea</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CatLIP: CLIP-level Visual Recognition Accuracy with 2.7x Faster Pre-training on Web-scale Image-Text Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15653</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15653v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Contrastive learning has emerged as a transformative method for learning effective visual representations through the alignment of image and text embeddings. However, pairwise similarity computation in contrastive loss between image and text pairs poses computational challenges. This paper presents a novel weakly supervised pre-training of vision models on web-scale image-text data. The proposed method reframes pre-training on image-text data as a classification task. Consequently, it eliminates the need for pairwise similarity computations in contrastive loss, achieving a remarkable $2.7\times$ acceleration in training speed compared to contrastive learning on web-scale data. Through extensive experiments spanning diverse vision tasks, including detection and segmentation, we demonstrate that the proposed method maintains high representation quality. Our source code along with pre-trained model weights and training recipes is available at \url{https://github.com/apple/corenet}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15653v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sachin Mehta, Maxwell Horton, Fartash Faghri, Mohammad Hossein Sekhavat, Mahyar Najibi, Mehrdad Farajtabar, Oncel Tuzel, Mohammad Rastegari</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChEX: Interactive Localization and Region Description in Chest X-rays</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15770</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15770v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Report generation models offer fine-grained textual interpretations of medical images like chest X-rays, yet they often lack interactivity (i.e. the ability to steer the generation process through user queries) and localized interpretability (i.e. visually grounding their predictions), which we deem essential for future adoption in clinical practice. While there have been efforts to tackle these issues, they are either limited in their interactivity by not supporting textual queries or fail to also offer localized interpretability. Therefore, we propose a novel multitask architecture and training paradigm integrating textual prompts and bounding boxes for diverse aspects like anatomical regions and pathologies. We call this approach the Chest X-Ray Explainer (ChEX). Evaluations across a heterogeneous set of 9 chest X-ray tasks, including localized image interpretation and report generation, showcase its competitiveness with SOTA models while additional analysis demonstrates ChEX's interactive capabilities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15770v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Philip M\"uller, Georgios Kaissis, Daniel Rueckert</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BASS: Batched Attention-optimized Speculative Sampling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15778</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15778v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Speculative decoding has emerged as a powerful method to improve latency and throughput in hosting large language models. However, most existing implementations focus on generating a single sequence. Real-world generative AI applications often require multiple responses and how to perform speculative decoding in a batched setting while preserving its latency benefits poses non-trivial challenges. This paper describes a system of batched speculative decoding that sets a new state of the art in multi-sequence generation latency and that demonstrates superior GPU utilization as well as quality of generations within a time budget. For example, for a 7.8B-size model on a single A100 GPU and with a batch size of 8, each sequence is generated at an average speed of 5.8ms per token, the overall throughput being 1.1K tokens per second. These results represent state-of-the-art latency and a 2.15X speed-up over optimized regular decoding. Within a time budget that regular decoding does not finish, our system is able to generate sequences with HumanEval Pass@First of 43% and Pass@All of 61%, far exceeding what's feasible with single-sequence speculative decoding. Our peak GPU utilization during decoding reaches as high as 15.8%, more than 3X the highest of that of regular decoding and around 10X of single-sequence speculative decoding.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15778v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haifeng Qian, Sujan Kumar Gonugondla, Sungsoo Ha, Mingyue Shang, Sanjay Krishna Gouda, Ramesh Nallapati, Sudipta Sengupta, Xiaofei Ma, Anoop Deoras</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KGValidator: A Framework for Automatic Validation of Knowledge Graph Construction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15923</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15923v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This study explores the use of Large Language Models (LLMs) for automatic evaluation of knowledge graph (KG) completion models. Historically, validating information in KGs has been a challenging task, requiring large-scale human annotation at prohibitive cost. With the emergence of general-purpose generative AI and LLMs, it is now plausible that human-in-the-loop validation could be replaced by a generative agent. We introduce a framework for consistency and validation when using generative models to validate knowledge graphs. Our framework is based upon recent open-source developments for structural and semantic validation of LLM outputs, and upon flexible approaches to fact checking and verification, supported by the capacity to reference external knowledge sources of any kind. The design is easy to adapt and extend, and can be used to verify any kind of graph-structured data through a combination of model-intrinsic knowledge, user-supplied context, and agents capable of external knowledge retrieval.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15923v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jack Boylan, Shashank Mangla, Dominic Thorn, Demian Gholipour Ghalandari, Parsa Ghaffari, Chris Hokamp</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside the echo chamber: Linguistic underpinnings of misinformation on Twitter</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15925</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15925v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Social media users drive the spread of misinformation online by sharing posts that include erroneous information or commenting on controversial topics with unsubstantiated arguments often in earnest. Work on echo chambers has suggested that users' perspectives are reinforced through repeated interactions with like-minded peers, promoted by homophily and bias in information diffusion. Building on long-standing interest in the social bases of language and linguistic underpinnings of social behavior, this work explores how conversations around misinformation are mediated through language use. We compare a number of linguistic measures, e.g., in-/out-group cues, readability, and discourse connectives, within and across topics of conversation and user communities. Our findings reveal increased presence of group identity signals and processing fluency within echo chambers during discussions of misinformation. We discuss the specific character of these broader trends across topics and examine contextual influences.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15925v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xinyu Wang, Jiayi Li, Sarah Rajtmajer</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncertainty Estimation and Quantification for LLMs: A Simple Supervised Approach</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15993</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15993v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are highly capable of many tasks but they can sometimes generate unreliable or inaccurate outputs. To tackle this issue, this paper studies the problem of uncertainty estimation and calibration for LLMs. We begin by formulating the uncertainty estimation problem for LLMs and then propose a supervised approach that takes advantage of the labeled datasets and estimates the uncertainty of the LLMs' responses. Based on the formulation, we illustrate the difference between the uncertainty estimation for LLMs and that for standard ML models and explain why the hidden activations of the LLMs contain uncertainty information. Our designed approach effectively demonstrates the benefits of utilizing hidden activations for enhanced uncertainty estimation across various tasks and shows robust transferability in out-of-distribution settings. Moreover, we distinguish the uncertainty estimation task from the uncertainty calibration task and show that a better uncertainty estimation mode leads to a better calibration performance. In practice, our method is easy to implement and is adaptable to different levels of model transparency including black box, grey box, and white box, each demonstrating strong performance based on the accessibility of the LLM's internal mechanisms.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15993v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Linyu Liu, Yu Pan, Xiaocheng Li, Guanting Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MoDE: CLIP Data Experts via Clustering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.16030</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.16030v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The success of contrastive language-image pretraining (CLIP) relies on the supervision from the pairing between images and captions, which tends to be noisy in web-crawled data. We present Mixture of Data Experts (MoDE) and learn a system of CLIP data experts via clustering. Each data expert is trained on one data cluster, being less sensitive to false negative noises in other clusters. At inference time, we ensemble their outputs by applying weights determined through the correlation between task metadata and cluster conditions. To estimate the correlation precisely, the samples in one cluster should be semantically similar, but the number of data experts should still be reasonable for training and inference. As such, we consider the ontology in human language and propose to use fine-grained cluster centers to represent each data expert at a coarse-grained level. Experimental studies show that four CLIP data experts on ViT-B/16 outperform the ViT-L/14 by OpenAI CLIP and OpenCLIP on zero-shot image classification but with less ($&lt;$35\%) training cost. Meanwhile, MoDE can train all data expert asynchronously and can flexibly include new data experts. The code is available at https://github.com/facebookresearch/MetaCLIP/tree/main/mode.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.16030v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiawei Ma, Po-Yao Huang, Saining Xie, Shang-Wen Li, Luke Zettlemoyer, Shih-Fu Chang, Wen-Tau Yih, Hu Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cantor: Inspiring Multimodal Chain-of-Thought of MLLM</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.16033</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.16033v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: With the advent of large language models(LLMs) enhanced by the chain-of-thought(CoT) methodology, visual reasoning problem is usually decomposed into manageable sub-tasks and tackled sequentially with various external tools. However, such a paradigm faces the challenge of the potential "determining hallucinations" in decision-making due to insufficient visual information and the limitation of low-level perception tools that fail to provide abstract summaries necessary for comprehensive reasoning. We argue that converging visual context acquisition and logical reasoning is pivotal for tackling visual reasoning tasks. This paper delves into the realm of multimodal CoT to solve intricate visual reasoning tasks with multimodal large language models(MLLMs) and their cognitive capability. To this end, we propose an innovative multimodal CoT framework, termed Cantor, characterized by a perception-decision architecture. Cantor first acts as a decision generator and integrates visual inputs to analyze the image and problem, ensuring a closer alignment with the actual context. Furthermore, Cantor leverages the advanced cognitive functions of MLLMs to perform as multifaceted experts for deriving higher-level information, enhancing the CoT generation process. Our extensive experiments demonstrate the efficacy of the proposed framework, showing significant improvements in multimodal CoT performance across two complex visual reasoning datasets, without necessitating fine-tuning or ground-truth rationales. Project Page: https://ggg0919.github.io/cantor/ .</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.16033v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Timin Gao, Peixian Chen, Mengdan Zhang, Chaoyou Fu, Yunhang Shen, Yan Zhang, Shengchuan Zhang, Xiawu Zheng, Xing Sun, Liujuan Cao, Rongrong Ji</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When does MAML Work the Best? An Empirical Study on Model-Agnostic Meta-Learning in NLP Applications</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2005.11700</link>
      <description>arXiv:2005.11700v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Model-Agnostic Meta-Learning (MAML), a model-agnostic meta-learning method, is successfully employed in NLP applications including few-shot text classification and multi-domain low-resource language generation. Many impacting factors, including data quantity, similarity among tasks, and the balance between general language model and task-specific adaptation, can affect the performance of MAML in NLP, but few works have thoroughly studied them. In this paper, we conduct an empirical study to investigate these impacting factors and conclude when MAML works the best based on the experimental results.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2005.11700v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zequn Liu, Ruiyi Zhang, Yiping Song, Wei Ju, Ming Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICDM 2020 Knowledge Graph Contest: Consumer Event-Cause Extraction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2110.15722</link>
      <description>arXiv:2110.15722v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Consumer Event-Cause Extraction, the task aimed at extracting the potential causes behind certain events in the text, has gained much attention in recent years due to its wide applications. The ICDM 2020 conference sets up an evaluation competition that aims to extract events and the causes of the extracted events with a specified subject (a brand or product). In this task, we mainly focus on how to construct an end-to-end model, and extract multiple event types and event-causes simultaneously. To this end, we introduce a fresh perspective to revisit the relational event-cause extraction task and propose a novel sequence tagging framework, instead of extracting event types and events-causes separately. Experiments show our framework outperforms baseline methods even when its encoder module uses an initialized pre-trained BERT encoder, showing the power of the new tagging framework. In this competition, our team achieved 1st place in the first stage leaderboard, and 3rd place in the final stage leaderboard.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2110.15722v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Congqing He, Jie Zhang, Xiangyu Zhu, Huan Liu, Yukun Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Noise-Robust De-Duplication at Scale</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2210.04261</link>
      <description>arXiv:2210.04261v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Identifying near duplicates within large, noisy text corpora has a myriad of applications that range from de-duplicating training datasets, reducing privacy risk, and evaluating test set leakage, to identifying reproduced news articles and literature within large corpora. Across these diverse applications, the overwhelming majority of work relies on N-grams. Limited efforts have been made to evaluate how well N-gram methods perform, in part because it is unclear how one could create an unbiased evaluation dataset for a massive corpus. This study uses the unique timeliness of historical news wires to create a 27,210 document dataset, with 122,876 positive duplicate pairs, for studying noise-robust de-duplication. The time-sensitivity of news makes comprehensive hand labelling feasible - despite the massive overall size of the corpus - as duplicates occur within a narrow date range. The study then develops and evaluates a range of de-duplication methods: hashing and N-gram overlap (which predominate in the literature), a contrastively trained bi-encoder, and a re-rank style approach combining a bi- and cross-encoder. The neural approaches significantly outperform hashing and N-gram overlap. We show that the bi-encoder scales well, de-duplicating a 10 million article corpus on a single GPU card in a matter of hours. We also apply our pre-trained model to the RealNews and patent portions of C4 (Colossal Clean Crawled Corpus), illustrating that a neural approach can identify many near duplicates missed by hashing, in the presence of various types of noise. The public release of our NEWS-COPY de-duplication dataset, codebase, and the pre-trained models will facilitate further research and applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2210.04261v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Emily Silcock, Luca D'Amico-Wong, Jinglin Yang, Melissa Dell</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Open-World Lottery Ticket Hypothesis for OOD Intent Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2210.07071</link>
      <description>arXiv:2210.07071v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Most existing methods of Out-of-Domain (OOD) intent classification rely on extensive auxiliary OOD corpora or specific training paradigms. However, they are underdeveloped in the underlying principle that the models should have differentiated confidence in In- and Out-of-domain intent. In this work, we shed light on the fundamental cause of model overconfidence on OOD and demonstrate that calibrated subnetworks can be uncovered by pruning the overparameterized model. Calibrated confidence provided by the subnetwork can better distinguish In- and Out-of-domain, which can be a benefit for almost all post hoc methods. In addition to bringing fundamental insights, we also extend the Lottery Ticket Hypothesis to open-world scenarios. We conduct extensive experiments on four real-world datasets to demonstrate our approach can establish consistent improvements compared with a suite of competitive baselines.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2210.07071v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yunhua Zhou, Pengyu Wang, Peiju Liu, Yuxin Wang, Xipeng Qiu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWQ: Activation-aware Weight Quantization for LLM Compression and Acceleration</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2306.00978</link>
      <description>arXiv:2306.00978v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have fundamentally transformed the capabilities of numerous applications, from natural language processing to more intricate domain-specific tasks in robotics and autonomous driving. Moreover, the importance of on-device LLMs has grown significantly in the recent years. Running LLMs on edge devices not only promises reduced latency and improved user experience but also aligns with the increasing need for user privacy, as data processing can occur locally. However, the astronomical model sizes of modern LLMs and constraints of the edge devices, primarily in terms of memory size and bandwidth, pose significant deployment challenges. In this paper, we propose Activation-aware Weight Quantization (AWQ), a hardware-friendly approach for LLM low-bit weight-only quantization. Our method is based on the observation that weights are not equally important: protecting only 1% of salient weights can greatly reduce quantization error. We then propose to search for the optimal per-channel scaling that protects the salient weights by observing the activation, not weights. AWQ does not rely on any backpropagation or reconstruction, so it can well preserve LLMs' generalization ability on different domains and modalities, without overfitting to the calibration set. AWQ outperforms existing work on various language modeling and domain-specific benchmarks (coding and math). Thanks to better generalization, it achieves excellent quantization performance for instruction-tuned LMs and, for the first time, multi-modal LMs. Alongside AWQ, we implement TinyChat, an efficient and flexible inference framework tailored for on-device LLM/VLMs, offering more than 3x speedup over the Huggingface FP16 implementation on both desktop and mobile GPUs. It also democratizes the deployment of the 70B Llama-2 model on mobile GPUs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2306.00978v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ji Lin, Jiaming Tang, Haotian Tang, Shang Yang, Wei-Ming Chen, Wei-Chen Wang, Guangxuan Xiao, Xingyu Dang, Chuang Gan, Song Han</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emotionally Numb or Empathetic? Evaluating How LLMs Feel Using EmotionBench</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2308.03656</link>
      <description>arXiv:2308.03656v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Evaluating Large Language Models' (LLMs) anthropomorphic capabilities has become increasingly important in contemporary discourse. Utilizing the emotion appraisal theory from psychology, we propose to evaluate the empathy ability of LLMs, i.e., how their feelings change when presented with specific situations. After a careful and comprehensive survey, we collect a dataset containing over 400 situations that have proven effective in eliciting the eight emotions central to our study. Categorizing the situations into 36 factors, we conduct a human evaluation involving more than 1,200 subjects worldwide. With the human evaluation results as references, our evaluation includes five LLMs, covering both commercial and open-source models, including variations in model sizes, featuring the latest iterations, such as GPT-4 and LLaMA-2. We find that, despite several misalignments, LLMs can generally respond appropriately to certain situations. Nevertheless, they fall short in alignment with the emotional behaviors of human beings and cannot establish connections between similar situations. Our collected dataset of situations, the human evaluation results, and the code of our testing framework, dubbed EmotionBench, is made openly accessible via https://github.com/CUHK-ARISE/EmotionBench. We aspire to contribute to the advancement of LLMs regarding better alignment with the emotional behaviors of human beings, thereby enhancing their utility and applicability as intelligent assistants.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2308.03656v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jen-tse Huang, Man Ho Lam, Eric John Li, Shujie Ren, Wenxuan Wang, Wenxiang Jiao, Zhaopeng Tu, Michael R. Lyu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can LLM-Generated Misinformation Be Detected?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2309.13788</link>
      <description>arXiv:2309.13788v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The advent of Large Language Models (LLMs) has made a transformative impact. However, the potential that LLMs such as ChatGPT can be exploited to generate misinformation has posed a serious concern to online safety and public trust. A fundamental research question is: will LLM-generated misinformation cause more harm than human-written misinformation? We propose to tackle this question from the perspective of detection difficulty. We first build a taxonomy of LLM-generated misinformation. Then we categorize and validate the potential real-world methods for generating misinformation with LLMs. Then, through extensive empirical investigation, we discover that LLM-generated misinformation can be harder to detect for humans and detectors compared to human-written misinformation with the same semantics, which suggests it can have more deceptive styles and potentially cause more harm. We also discuss the implications of our discovery on combating misinformation in the age of LLMs and the countermeasures.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2309.13788v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Canyu Chen, Kai Shu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RoleLLM: Benchmarking, Eliciting, and Enhancing Role-Playing Abilities of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.00746</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.00746v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The advent of Large Language Models (LLMs) has paved the way for complex tasks such as role-playing, which enhances user interactions by enabling models to imitate various characters. However, the closed-source nature of state-of-the-art LLMs and their general-purpose training limit role-playing optimization. In this paper, we introduce RoleLLM, a framework to benchmark, elicit, and enhance role-playing abilities in LLMs. RoleLLM comprises four stages: (1) Role Profile Construction for 100 roles; (2) Context-Based Instruction Generation (Context-Instruct) for role-specific knowledge extraction; (3) Role Prompting using GPT (RoleGPT) for speaking style imitation; and (4) Role-Conditioned Instruction Tuning (RoCIT) for fine-tuning open-source models along with role customization. By Context-Instruct and RoleGPT, we create RoleBench, the first systematic and fine-grained character-level benchmark dataset for role-playing with 168,093 samples. Moreover, RoCIT on RoleBench yields RoleLLaMA (English) and RoleGLM (Chinese), significantly enhancing role-playing abilities and even achieving comparable results with RoleGPT (using GPT-4).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.00746v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zekun Moore Wang, Zhongyuan Peng, Haoran Que, Jiaheng Liu, Wangchunshu Zhou, Yuhan Wu, Hongcheng Guo, Ruitong Gan, Zehao Ni, Jian Yang, Man Zhang, Zhaoxiang Zhang, Wanli Ouyang, Ke Xu, Stephen W. Huang, Jie Fu, Junran Peng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DEFT: Data Efficient Fine-Tuning for Pre-Trained Language Models via Unsupervised Core-Set Selection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.16776</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.16776v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advances have led to the availability of many pre-trained language models (PLMs); however, a question that remains is how much data is truly needed to fine-tune PLMs for downstream tasks? In this work, we introduce DEFT-UCS, a data-efficient fine-tuning framework that leverages unsupervised core-set selection to identify a smaller, representative dataset that reduces the amount of data needed to fine-tune PLMs for downstream tasks. We examine the efficacy of DEFT-UCS in the context of text-editing LMs, and compare to the state-of-the art text-editing model, CoEDIT. Our results demonstrate that DEFT-UCS models are just as accurate as CoEDIT, across eight different datasets consisting of six different editing tasks, while finetuned on 70% less data.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.16776v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Devleena Das, Vivek Khetan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AfriMTE and AfriCOMET: Enhancing COMET to Embrace Under-resourced African Languages</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.09828</link>
      <description>arXiv:2311.09828v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Despite the recent progress on scaling multilingual machine translation (MT) to several under-resourced African languages, accurately measuring this progress remains challenging, since evaluation is often performed on n-gram matching metrics such as BLEU, which typically show a weaker correlation with human judgments. Learned metrics such as COMET have higher correlation; however, the lack of evaluation data with human ratings for under-resourced languages, complexity of annotation guidelines like Multidimensional Quality Metrics (MQM), and limited language coverage of multilingual encoders have hampered their applicability to African languages. In this paper, we address these challenges by creating high-quality human evaluation data with simplified MQM guidelines for error detection and direct assessment (DA) scoring for 13 typologically diverse African languages. Furthermore, we develop AfriCOMET: COMET evaluation metrics for African languages by leveraging DA data from well-resourced languages and an African-centric multilingual encoder (AfroXLM-R) to create the state-of-the-art MT evaluation metrics for African languages with respect to Spearman-rank correlation with human judgments (0.441).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2311.09828v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiayi Wang, David Ifeoluwa Adelani, Sweta Agrawal, Marek Masiak, Ricardo Rei, Eleftheria Briakou, Marine Carpuat, Xuanli He, Sofia Bourhim, Andiswa Bukula, Muhidin Mohamed, Temitayo Olatoye, Tosin Adewumi, Hamam Mokayed, Christine Mwase, Wangui Kimotho, Foutse Yuehgoh, Anuoluwapo Aremu, Jessica Ojo, Shamsuddeen Hassan Muhammad, Salomey Osei, Abdul-Hakeem Omotayo, Chiamaka Chukwuneke, Perez Ogayo, Oumaima Hourrane, Salma El Anigri, Lolwethu Ndolela, Thabiso Mangwana, Shafie Abdi Mohamed, Ayinde Hassan, Oluwabusayo Olufunke Awoyomi, Lama Alkhaled, Sana Al-Azzawi, Naome A. Etori, Millicent Ochieng, Clemencia Siro, Samuel Njoroge, Eric Muchiri, Wangari Kimotho, Lyse Naomi Wamba Momo, Daud Abolade, Simbiat Ajao, Iyanuoluwa Shode, Ricky Macharm, Ruqayya Nasir Iro, Saheed S. Abdullahi, Stephen E. Moore, Bernard Opoku, Zainab Akinjobi, Abeeb Afolabi, Nnaemeka Obiefuna, Onyekachi Raphael Ogbu, Sam Brian, Verrah Akinyi Otiende, Chinedu Emmanuel Mbonu, Sakayo Toadoum Sari, Yao Lu, Pontus Stenetorp</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DP-NMT: Scalable Differentially-Private Machine Translation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.14465</link>
      <description>arXiv:2311.14465v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Neural machine translation (NMT) is a widely popular text generation task, yet there is a considerable research gap in the development of privacy-preserving NMT models, despite significant data privacy concerns for NMT systems. Differentially private stochastic gradient descent (DP-SGD) is a popular method for training machine learning models with concrete privacy guarantees; however, the implementation specifics of training a model with DP-SGD are not always clarified in existing models, with differing software libraries used and code bases not always being public, leading to reproducibility issues. To tackle this, we introduce DP-NMT, an open-source framework for carrying out research on privacy-preserving NMT with DP-SGD, bringing together numerous models, datasets, and evaluation metrics in one systematic software package. Our goal is to provide a platform for researchers to advance the development of privacy-preserving NMT systems, keeping the specific details of the DP-SGD algorithm transparent and intuitive to implement. We run a set of experiments on datasets from both general and privacy-related domains to demonstrate our framework in use. We make our framework publicly available and welcome feedback from the community.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2311.14465v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Timour Igamberdiev, Doan Nam Long Vu, Felix K\"unnecke, Zhuo Yu, Jannik Holmer, Ivan Habernal</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLMCheckup: Conversational Examination of Large Language Models via Interpretability Tools and Self-Explanations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12576</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.12576v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Interpretability tools that offer explanations in the form of a dialogue have demonstrated their efficacy in enhancing users' understanding (Slack et al., 2023; Shen et al., 2023), as one-off explanations may fall short in providing sufficient information to the user. Current solutions for dialogue-based explanations, however, often require external tools and modules and are not easily transferable to tasks they were not designed for. With LLMCheckup, we present an easily accessible tool that allows users to chat with any state-of-the-art large language model (LLM) about its behavior. We enable LLMs to generate explanations and perform user intent recognition without fine-tuning, by connecting them with a broad spectrum of Explainable AI (XAI) methods, including white-box explainability tools such as feature attributions, and self-explanations (e.g., for rationale generation). LLM-based (self-)explanations are presented as an interactive dialogue that supports follow-up questions and generates suggestions. LLMCheckupprovides tutorials for operations available in the system, catering to individuals with varying levels of expertise in XAI and supporting multiple input modalities. We introduce a new parsing strategy that substantially enhances the user intent recognition accuracy of the LLM. Finally, we showcase LLMCheckup for the tasks of fact checking and commonsense question answering.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.12576v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qianli Wang, Tatiana Anikina, Nils Feldhus, Josef van Genabith, Leonhard Hennig, Sebastian M\"oller</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poro 34B and the Blessing of Multilinguality</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.01856</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.01856v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The pretraining of state-of-the-art large language models now requires trillions of words of text, which is orders of magnitude more than available for the vast majority of languages. While including text in more than one language is an obvious way to acquire more pretraining data, multilinguality is often seen as a curse, and most model training efforts continue to focus near-exclusively on individual large languages. We believe that multilinguality can be a blessing and that it should be possible to substantially improve over the capabilities of monolingual models for small languages through multilingual training. In this study, we introduce Poro 34B, a 34 billion parameter model trained for 1 trillion tokens of Finnish, English, and programming languages, and demonstrate that a multilingual training approach can produce a model that not only substantially advances over the capabilities of existing models for Finnish, but also excels in translation and is competitive in its class in generating English and programming languages. We release the model parameters, scripts, and data under open licenses at https://huggingface.co/LumiOpen/Poro-34B.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.01856v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Risto Luukkonen, Jonathan Burdge, Elaine Zosa, Aarne Talman, Ville Komulainen, V\"ain\"o Hatanp\"a\"a, Peter Sarlin, Sampo Pyysalo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAAS: Solving Ability Amplification Strategy for Enhanced Mathematical Reasoning in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03887</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03887v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This study presents a novel learning approach designed to enhance both mathematical reasoning and problem-solving abilities of Large Language Models (LLMs). We focus on integrating the Chain-of-Thought (CoT) and the Program-of-Thought (PoT) learning, hypothesizing that prioritizing the learning of mathematical reasoning ability is helpful for the amplification of problem-solving ability. Thus, the initial learning with CoT is essential for solving challenging mathematical problems. To this end, we propose a sequential learning approach, named SAAS (Solving Ability Amplification Strategy), which strategically transitions from CoT learning to PoT learning. Our empirical study, involving an extensive performance comparison using several benchmarks, demonstrates that our SAAS achieves state-of-the-art (SOTA) performance. The results underscore the effectiveness of our sequential learning approach, marking a significant advancement in the field of mathematical reasoning in LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03887v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hyeonwoo Kim, Gyoungjin Gim, Yungi Kim, Jihoo Kim, Byungju Kim, Wonseok Lee, Chanjun Park</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Better Synthetic Data by Retrieving and Transforming Existing Datasets</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.14361</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.14361v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Despite recent advances in large language models, building dependable and deployable NLP models typically requires abundant, high-quality training data. However, task-specific data is not available for many use cases, and manually curating task-specific data is labor-intensive. Recent work has studied prompt-driven synthetic data generation using large language models, but these generated datasets tend to lack complexity and diversity. To address these limitations, we introduce a method, DataTune, to make better use of existing, publicly available datasets to improve automatic dataset generation. DataTune performs dataset transformation, enabling the repurposing of publicly available datasets into a format that is directly aligned with the specific requirements of target tasks. On a diverse set of language-based tasks from the BIG-Bench benchmark, we find that finetuning language models via DataTune improves over a few-shot prompting baseline by 49% and improves over existing methods that use synthetic or retrieved training data by 34%. We find that dataset transformation significantly increases the diversity and difficulty of generated data on many tasks. We integrate DataTune into an open-source repository to make this method accessible to the community: https://github.com/neulab/prompt2model.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.14361v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Saumya Gandhi, Ritu Gala, Vijay Viswanathan, Tongshuang Wu, Graham Neubig</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Talk Too Much: Poisoning Large Language Models under Token Limit</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.14795</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.14795v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Mainstream poisoning attacks on large language models (LLMs) typically set a fixed trigger in the input instance and specific responses for triggered queries. However, the fixed trigger setting (e.g., unusual words) may be easily detected by human detection, limiting the effectiveness and practicality in real-world scenarios. To enhance the stealthiness of the trigger, we present a poisoning attack against LLMs that is triggered by a generation/output condition-token limitation, which is a commonly adopted strategy by users for reducing costs. The poisoned model performs normally for output without token limitation, while becomes harmful for output with limited tokens. To achieve this objective, we introduce BrieFool, an efficient attack framework. It leverages the characteristics of generation limitation by efficient instruction sampling and poisoning data generation, thereby influencing the behavior of LLMs under target conditions. Our experiments demonstrate that BrieFool is effective across safety domains and knowledge domains. For instance, with only 20 generated poisoning examples against GPT-3.5-turbo, BrieFool achieves a 100% Attack Success Rate (ASR) and a 9.28/10 average Harmfulness Score (HS) under token limitation conditions while maintaining the benign performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.14795v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiaming He, Wenbo Jiang, Guanyu Hou, Wenshu Fan, Rui Zhang, Hongwei Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Never Train from Scratch: Fair Comparison of Long-Sequence Models Requires Data-Driven Priors</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.02980</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.02980v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Modeling long-range dependencies across sequences is a longstanding goal in machine learning and has led to architectures, such as state space models, that dramatically outperform Transformers on long sequences. However, these impressive empirical gains have been by and large demonstrated on benchmarks (e.g. Long Range Arena), where models are randomly initialized and trained to predict a target label from an input sequence. In this work, we show that random initialization leads to gross overestimation of the differences between architectures and that pretraining with standard denoising objectives, using $\textit{only the downstream task data}$, leads to dramatic gains across multiple architectures and to very small gaps between Transformers and state space models (SSMs). In stark contrast to prior works, we find vanilla Transformers to match the performance of S4 on Long Range Arena when properly pretrained, and we improve the best reported results of SSMs on the PathX-256 task by 20 absolute points. Subsequently, we analyze the utility of previously-proposed structured parameterizations for SSMs and show they become mostly redundant in the presence of data-driven initialization obtained through pretraining. Our work shows that, when evaluating different architectures on supervised tasks, incorporation of data-driven priors via pretraining is essential for reliable performance estimation, and can be done efficiently.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.02980v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ido Amos, Jonathan Berant, Ankit Gupta</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Survey of Graph Meets Large Language Model: Progress and Future Directions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12399</link>
      <description>arXiv:2311.12399v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Graph plays a significant role in representing and analyzing complex relationships in real-world applications such as citation networks, social networks, and biological data. Recently, Large Language Models (LLMs), which have achieved tremendous success in various domains, have also been leveraged in graph-related tasks to surpass traditional Graph Neural Networks (GNNs) based methods and yield state-of-the-art performance. In this survey, we first present a comprehensive review and analysis of existing methods that integrate LLMs with graphs. First of all, we propose a new taxonomy, which organizes existing methods into three categories based on the role (i.e., enhancer, predictor, and alignment component) played by LLMs in graph-related tasks. Then we systematically survey the representative methods along the three categories of the taxonomy. Finally, we discuss the remaining limitations of existing studies and highlight promising avenues for future research. The relevant papers are summarized and will be consistently updated at: https://github.com/yhLeeee/Awesome-LLMs-in-Graph-tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2311.12399v4</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuhan Li, Zhixun Li, Peisong Wang, Jia Li, Xiangguo Sun, Hong Cheng, Jeffrey Xu Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Faster and Lighter LLMs: A Survey on Current Challenges and Way Forward</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.01799</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.01799v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Despite the impressive performance of LLMs, their widespread adoption faces challenges due to substantial computational and memory requirements during inference. Recent advancements in model compression and system-level optimization methods aim to enhance LLM inference. This survey offers an overview of these methods, emphasizing recent developments. Through experiments on LLaMA(/2)-7B, we evaluate various compression techniques, providing practical insights for efficient LLM deployment in a unified setting. The empirical analysis on LLaMA(/2)-7B highlights the effectiveness of these methods. Drawing from survey insights, we identify current limitations and discuss potential future directions to improve LLM inference efficiency. We release the codebase to reproduce the results presented in this paper at https://github.com/nyunAI/Faster-LLM-Survey</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.01799v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Arnav Chavan, Raghav Magazine, Shubham Kushwaha, M\'erouane Debbah, Deepak Gupta</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Language Models in Biomedical and Health Informatics: A Bibliometric Review</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.16303</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.16303v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have rapidly become important tools in Biomedical and Health Informatics (BHI), enabling new ways to analyze data, treat patients, and conduct research. This bibliometric review aims to provide a panoramic view of how LLMs have been used in BHI by examining research articles and collaboration networks from 2022 to 2023. It further explores how LLMs can improve Natural Language Processing (NLP) applications in various BHI areas like medical diagnosis, patient engagement, electronic health record management, and personalized medicine. To do this, our bibliometric review identifies key trends, maps out research networks, and highlights major developments in this fast-moving field. Lastly, it discusses the ethical concerns and practical challenges of using LLMs in BHI, such as data privacy and reliable medical recommendations. Looking ahead, we consider how LLMs could further transform biomedical research as well as healthcare delivery and patient outcomes. This bibliometric review serves as a resource for stakeholders in healthcare, including researchers, clinicians, and policymakers, to understand the current state and future potential of LLMs in BHI.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.16303v3</guid>
      <category>cs.DL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Huizi Yu, Lizhou Fan, Lingyao Li, Jiayan Zhou, Zihui Ma, Lu Xian, Wenyue Hua, Sijia He, Mingyu Jin, Yongfeng Zhang, Ashvin Gandhi, Xin Ma</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parameter Efficient Fine Tuning: A Comprehensive Analysis Across Applications</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.13506</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.13506v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The rise of deep learning has marked significant progress in fields such as computer vision, natural language processing, and medical imaging, primarily through the adaptation of pre-trained models for specific tasks. Traditional fine-tuning methods, involving adjustments to all parameters, face challenges due to high computational and memory demands. This has led to the development of Parameter Efficient Fine-Tuning (PEFT) techniques, which selectively update parameters to balance computational efficiency with performance. This review examines PEFT approaches, offering a detailed comparison of various strategies highlighting applications across different domains, including text generation, medical imaging, protein modeling, and speech synthesis. By assessing the effectiveness of PEFT methods in reducing computational load, speeding up training, and lowering memory usage, this paper contributes to making deep learning more accessible and adaptable, facilitating its wider application and encouraging innovation in model optimization. Ultimately, the paper aims to contribute towards insights into PEFT's evolving landscape, guiding researchers and practitioners in overcoming the limitations of conventional fine-tuning approaches.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.13506v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Charith Chandra Sai Balne, Sreyoshi Bhaduri, Tamoghna Roy, Vinija Jain, Aman Chadha</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FlashSpeech: Efficient Zero-Shot Speech Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.14700</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.14700v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Recent progress in large-scale zero-shot speech synthesis has been significantly advanced by language models and diffusion models. However, the generation process of both methods is slow and computationally intensive. Efficient speech synthesis using a lower computing budget to achieve quality on par with previous work remains a significant challenge. In this paper, we present FlashSpeech, a large-scale zero-shot speech synthesis system with approximately 5\% of the inference time compared with previous work. FlashSpeech is built on the latent consistency model and applies a novel adversarial consistency training approach that can train from scratch without the need for a pre-trained diffusion model as the teacher. Furthermore, a new prosody generator module enhances the diversity of prosody, making the rhythm of the speech sound more natural. The generation processes of FlashSpeech can be achieved efficiently with one or two sampling steps while maintaining high audio quality and high similarity to the audio prompt for zero-shot speech generation. Our experimental results demonstrate the superior performance of FlashSpeech. Notably, FlashSpeech can be about 20 times faster than other zero-shot speech synthesis systems while maintaining comparable performance in terms of voice quality and similarity. Furthermore, FlashSpeech demonstrates its versatility by efficiently performing tasks like voice conversion, speech editing, and diverse speech sampling. Audio samples can be found in https://flashspeech.github.io/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.14700v2</guid>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhen Ye, Zeqian Ju, Haohe Liu, Xu Tan, Jianyi Chen, Yiwen Lu, Peiwen Sun, Jiahao Pan, Weizhen Bian, Shulin He, Qifeng Liu, Yike Guo, Wei Xue</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
