<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL</link>
    <description>cs.CL updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 05:00:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Sunday</day>
      <day>Saturday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>Inductive Linguistic Reasoning with Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.17819</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.17819v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Evaluating large language models (LLMs) on their linguistic reasoning capabilities is an important task to understand the gaps in their skills that may surface during large-scale adoption. In this work, we investigate the abilities of such models to perform abstract multilingual reasoning through the lens of linguistic puzzles on extremely low-resource languages. As these translation tasks involve inductive and deductive reasoning from reference instances, we examine whether diverse auxiliary demonstrations can be automatically induced from seed exemplars, through analogical prompting. We employ a two-stage procedure, first generating analogical exemplars with a language model, and then applying them in-context along with provided target language exemplars. Our results on the modeLing dataset show that analogical prompting is effective in eliciting models' knowledge of language grammar similarities, boosting the performance of GPT-4o by as much as 8.1% and Llama-3.1-405B-Instruct by 5.9% over chain-of-thought approaches. These gains are attributable to the analogical demonstrations, both when self-generated as well as when produced by weaker multilingual models. Furthermore, we demonstrate that our method generalizes to other tasks present in Linguistics Olympiad competitions, achieving sizable improvements across all problem types and difficulty levels included in the LINGOLY dataset with GPT-4o. We also report several findings about interesting phenomena which drive linguistic reasoning performance, suggesting that such puzzles are a valuable benchmark for new reasoning methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.17819v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Raghav Ramji, Keshav Ramji</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Rosetta Paradox: Domain-Specific Performance Inversions in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.17821</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.17821v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: While large language models, such as GPT and BERT, have already demonstrated unprecedented skills in everything from natural language processing to domain-specific applications, there came an unexplored phenomenon we term the Rosetta Paradox. The Rosetta Paradox characterizes the counterintuitive performance inversions across domains of knowledge. This paradox captures how such LLMs can excel in highly specialized fields but do poorly on tasks which require general, everyday knowledge. This paper formalizes the definition of the Rosetta Paradox and introduces a panoramic analysis framework that includes both a Domain Specificity Index (DSI) and a Performance Inversion Metric (PIM) for consistent quantification of domain-specific behavior in LLMs.
  We adopt this paradox and conduct a series of investigations through extensive experiments across diverse models and knowledge domains, ranging from rich technical areas to common-sense reasoning. Our findings indicate that the Rosetta Paradox is likely not a mere artifact of data distribution but an intrinsic architectural and emergent property of deep neural networks. We present comparative analyses across different model architectures, sizes, and training methodologies that shed light into the peculiar ways this paradox manifests itself and challenge the standard evaluation metrics.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.17821v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Basab Jha, Ujjwal Puri</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Sentiment for Offensive Text Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.17825</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.17825v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this paper, we conduct experiment to analyze whether models can classify offensive texts better with the help of sentiment. We conduct this experiment on the SemEval 2019 task 6, OLID, dataset. First, we utilize pre-trained language models to predict the sentiment of each instance. Later we pick the model that achieved the best performance on the OLID test set, and train it on the augmented OLID set to analyze the performance. Results show that utilizing sentiment increases the overall performance of the model.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.17825v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Khondoker Ittehadul Islam</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Look Ahead Text Understanding and LLM Stitching</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.17836</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.17836v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper proposes a look ahead text understanding problem with look ahead section identification (LASI) as an example. This problem may appear in generative AI as well as human interactions, where we want to understand the direction of a developing text or conversation. We tackle the problem using transformer-based LLMs. We show that LASI is more challenging than classic section identification (SI). We argue that both bidirectional contextual information (e.g., BERT) and unidirectional predictive ability (e.g., GPT) will benefit the task. We propose two approaches to stitch together BERT and GPT. Experiments show that our approach outperforms the established models, especially when there is noise in the text (which is often the case for developing text in generative AI). Our paper sheds light on other look ahead text understanding tasks that are important to social media, such as look ahead sentiment classification, and points out the opportunities to leverage pre-trained LLMs through stitching.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.17836v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1609/icwsm.v18i1.31349</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Proceedings of the International AAAI Conference on Web and Social Media, 18(1), 751-760 (2024)</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Junlin Julian Jiang (Piedmont High School, Piedmont, CA, USA), Xin Li (College of Business, City University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China)</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the Capabilities of Large Language Models for Multi-label Emotion Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.17837</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.17837v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) show promising learning and reasoning abilities. Compared to other NLP tasks, multilingual and multi-label emotion evaluation tasks are under-explored in LLMs. In this paper, we present EthioEmo, a multi-label emotion classification dataset for four Ethiopian languages, namely, Amharic (amh), Afan Oromo (orm), Somali (som), and Tigrinya (tir). We perform extensive experiments with an additional English multi-label emotion dataset from SemEval 2018 Task 1. Our evaluation includes encoder-only, encoder-decoder, and decoder-only language models. We compare zero and few-shot approaches of LLMs to fine-tuning smaller language models. The results show that accurate multi-label emotion classification is still insufficient even for high-resource languages such as English, and there is a large gap between the performance of high-resource and low-resource languages. The results also show varying performance levels depending on the language and model type. EthioEmo is available publicly to further improve the understanding of emotions in language models and how people convey emotions through various languages.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.17837v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tadesse Destaw Belay, Israel Abebe Azime, Abinew Ali Ayele, Grigori Sidorov, Dietrich Klakow, Philipp Slusallek, Olga Kolesnikova, Seid Muhie Yimam</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Knowledge Distillation for LLMs with Response-Priming Prompting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.17846</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.17846v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated remarkable performance across a wide range of natural language processing (NLP) tasks. However, these models are often difficult to deploy due to significant computational requirements and resource constraints. Knowledge distillation (KD) is an effective technique for transferring the performance of larger LLMs to smaller models. Traditional KD methods primarily focus on the direct output of the teacher model, with little emphasis on the role of prompting during knowledge transfer. In this paper, we propose a set of novel response-priming prompting strategies applied in the knowledge distillation pipeline to enhance the performance of student models. Our approach fine-tunes a smaller Llama 3.1 8B Instruct model by distilling knowledge from a quantized Llama 3.1 405B Instruct teacher model. We apply LoRA optimization and evaluate on the GSM8K benchmark. Experimental results demonstrate that integrating reasoning-eliciting prompting into the proposed KD pipeline significantly improves student model performance, offering an efficient way to deploy powerful models in resource-constrained environments. We find that Ground Truth prompting results in a 55\% performance increase on GSM8K for a distilled Llama 3.1 8B Instruct compared to the same model distilled without prompting. A thorough investigation into the self-attention layers of the student models indicates that the more successful prompted models tend to exhibit certain positive behaviors inside their attention heads which can be tied to their increased accuracy. Our implementation can be found at https://github.com/alonso130r/knowledge-distillation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.17846v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Vijay Goyal, Mustafa Khan, Aprameya Tirupati, Harveer Saini, Michael Lam, Kevin Zhu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overview of the 2024 ALTA Shared Task: Detect Automatic AI-Generated Sentences for Human-AI Hybrid Articles</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.17848</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.17848v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The ALTA shared tasks have been running annually since 2010. In 2024, the purpose of the task is to detect machine-generated text in a hybrid setting where the text may contain portions of human text and portions machine-generated. In this paper, we present the task, the evaluation criteria, and the results of the systems participating in the shared task.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.17848v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Proceedings of the 22nd Annual Workshop of the Australasian Language Technology Association, 2024</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Diego Moll\'a, Qiongkai Xu, Zijie Zeng, Zhuang Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating and Enhancing LLMs for Multi-turn Text-to-SQL with Multiple Question Types</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.17867</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.17867v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent advancements in large language models (LLMs) have significantly advanced text-to-SQL systems. However, most LLM-based methods often narrowly focus on SQL generation, neglecting the complexities of real-world conversational queries. This oversight can lead to unreliable responses, particularly for ambiguous questions that cannot be directly addressed with SQL. To bridge this gap, we propose MMSQL, a comprehensive test suite designed to evaluate the question classification and SQL generation capabilities of LLMs by simulating real-world scenarios with diverse question types and multi-turn Q\&amp;A interactions. Using MMSQL, we assessed the performance of popular LLMs, including both open-source and closed-source models, and identified key factors impacting their performance in such scenarios. Moreover, we introduce an LLM-based multi-agent framework that employs specialized agents to identify question types and determine appropriate answering strategies. Our experiments demonstrate that this approach significantly enhances the model's ability to navigate the complexities of conversational dynamics, effectively handling the diverse and complex nature of user queries.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.17867v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ziming Guo, Chao Ma, Yinggang Sun, Tiancheng Zhao, Guangyao Wang, Hai Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joint Knowledge Editing for Information Enrichment and Probability Promotion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.17872</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.17872v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Knowledge stored in large language models requires timely updates to reflect the dynamic nature of real-world information. To update the knowledge, most knowledge editing methods focus on the low layers, since recent probes into the knowledge recall process reveal that the answer information is enriched in low layers. However, these probes only and could only reveal critical recall stages for the original answers, while the goal of editing is to rectify model's prediction for the target answers. This inconsistency indicates that both the probe approaches and the associated editing methods are deficient. To mitigate the inconsistency and identify critical editing regions, we propose a contrast-based probe approach, and locate two crucial stages where the model behavior diverges between the original and target answers: Information Enrichment in low layers and Probability Promotion in high layers. Building upon the insights, we develop the Joint knowledge Editing for information Enrichment and probability Promotion (JEEP) method, which jointly edits both the low and high layers to modify the two critical recall stages. Considering the mutual interference and growing forgetting due to dual modifications, JEEP is designed to ensure that updates to distinct regions share the same objectives and are complementary. We rigorously evaluate JEEP by editing up to thousands of facts on various models, i.e., GPT-J (6B) and LLaMA (7B), and addressing diverse editing objectives, i.e., adding factual and counterfactual knowledge. In all tested scenarios, JEEP achieves best performances, validating the effectiveness of the revealings of our probe approach and the designs of our editing method. Our code and data are available at https://github.com/Eric8932/JEEP.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.17872v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenhang Shi, Yiren Chen, Shuqing Bian, Xinyi Zhang, Zhe Zhao, Pengfei Hu, Wei Lu, Xiaoyong Du</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating LLM Reasoning in the Operations Research Domain with ORQA</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.17874</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.17874v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this paper, we introduce and apply Operations Research Question Answering (ORQA), a new benchmark designed to assess the generalization capabilities of Large Language Models (LLMs) in the specialized technical domain of Operations Research (OR). This benchmark evaluates whether LLMs can emulate the knowledge and reasoning skills of OR experts when confronted with diverse and complex optimization problems. The dataset, developed by OR experts, features real-world optimization problems that demand multistep reasoning to construct their mathematical models. Our evaluations of various open source LLMs, such as LLaMA 3.1, DeepSeek, and Mixtral, reveal their modest performance, highlighting a gap in their ability to generalize to specialized technical domains. This work contributes to the ongoing discourse on LLMs generalization capabilities, offering valuable insights for future research in this area. The dataset and evaluation code are publicly available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.17874v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mahdi Mostajabdaveh, Timothy T. Yu, Samarendra Chandan Bindu Dash, Rindranirina Ramamonjison, Jabo Serge Byusa, Giuseppe Carenini, Zirui Zhou, Yong Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Adaptation: Boosting In-Context Learning through Adaptive Prompting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.17891</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.17891v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated exceptional abilities across a broad range of language-related tasks, including generating solutions to complex reasoning problems. An effective technique to enhance LLM performance is in-context learning, which encourages a step-by-step reasoning process by including explanatory examples to guide the model's responses. However, selecting appropriate exemplars for the model poses a challenge, as each dataset demands a distinct set of exemplars to enable the LLM to learn effectively and perform well on the test set. Current studies often rely on uncertainty- or diversity-based selection strategies to select exemplars for annotation and to improve model learning. However, these studies typically employ a non-adaptive approach, selecting a set of exemplars all at once. We argue that this non-adaptive strategy may result in a set of exemplars with high redundancy in terms of the knowledge covered, ultimately reducing their overall informativeness. To address this limitation, we propose \textsc{Adaptive-Prompt}, a novel method that adaptively selects exemplars by leveraging model feedback from previously chosen exemplars. Experimental results show that \textsc{Adaptive-Prompt} significantly enhances LLM performance across a variety of reasoning tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.17891v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shuzhang Cai, Twumasi Mensah-Boateng, Xander Kuksov, Jing Yuan, Shaojie Tang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BenCzechMark : A Czech-centric Multitask and Multimetric Benchmark for Large Language Models with Duel Scoring Mechanism</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.17933</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.17933v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present BenCzechMark (BCM), the first comprehensive Czech language benchmark designed for large language models, offering diverse tasks, multiple task formats, and multiple evaluation metrics. Its scoring system is grounded in statistical significance theory and uses aggregation across tasks inspired by social preference theory. Our benchmark encompasses 50 challenging tasks, with corresponding test datasets, primarily in native Czech, with 11 newly collected ones. These tasks span 8 categories and cover diverse domains, including historical Czech news, essays from pupils or language learners, and spoken word.
  Furthermore, we collect and clean BUT-Large Czech Collection, the largest publicly available clean Czech language corpus, and use it for (i) contamination analysis, (ii) continuous pretraining of the first Czech-centric 7B language model, with Czech-specific tokenization. We use our model as a baseline for comparison with publicly available multilingual models. Lastly, we release and maintain a leaderboard, with existing 44 model submissions, where new model submissions can be made at https://huggingface.co/spaces/CZLC/BenCzechMark.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.17933v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Martin Fajcik, Martin Docekal, Jan Dolezal, Karel Ondrej, Karel Bene\v{s}, Jan Kapsa, Pavel Smrz, Alexander Polok, Michal Hradis, Zuzana Neverilova, Ales Horak, Radoslav Sabol, Michal Stefanik, Adam Jirkovsky, David Adamczyk, Petr Hyner, Jan Hula, Hynek Kydlicek</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IITR-CIOL@NLU of Devanagari Script Languages 2025: Multilingual Hate Speech Detection and Target Identification in Devanagari-Scripted Languages</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.17947</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.17947v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This work focuses on two subtasks related to hate speech detection and target identification in Devanagari-scripted languages, specifically Hindi, Marathi, Nepali, Bhojpuri, and Sanskrit. Subtask B involves detecting hate speech in online text, while Subtask C requires identifying the specific targets of hate speech, such as individuals, organizations, or communities. We propose the MultilingualRobertaClass model, a deep neural network built on the pretrained multilingual transformer model ia-multilingual-transliterated-roberta, optimized for classification tasks in multilingual and transliterated contexts. The model leverages contextualized embeddings to handle linguistic diversity, with a classifier head for binary classification. We received 88.40% accuracy in Subtask B and 66.11% accuracy in Subtask C, in the test set.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.17947v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Siddhant Gupta, Siddh Singhal, Azmine Toushik Wasi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Path-of-Thoughts: Extracting and Following Paths for Robust Relational Reasoning with Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.17963</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.17963v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) possess vast semantic knowledge but often struggle with complex reasoning tasks, particularly in relational reasoning problems such as kinship or spatial reasoning. In this paper, we present Path-of-Thoughts (PoT), a novel framework designed to tackle relation reasoning by decomposing the task into three key stages: graph extraction, path identification, and reasoning. Unlike previous approaches, PoT efficiently extracts a task-agnostic graph that identifies crucial entities, relations, and attributes within the problem context. Subsequently, PoT identifies relevant reasoning chains within the graph corresponding to the posed question, facilitating inference of potential answers. Experimental evaluations on four benchmark datasets, demanding long reasoning chains, demonstrate that PoT surpasses state-of-the-art baselines by a significant margin (maximum 21.3%) without necessitating fine-tuning or extensive LLM calls. Furthermore, as opposed to prior neuro-symbolic methods, PoT exhibits improved resilience against LLM errors by leveraging the compositional nature of graphs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.17963v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ge Zhang, Mohammad Ali Alomrani, Hongjian Gu, Jiaming Zhou, Yaochen Hu, Bin Wang, Qun Liu, Mark Coates, Yingxue Zhang, Jianye Hao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CARL-GT: Evaluating Causal Reasoning Capabilities of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.17970</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.17970v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Causal reasoning capabilities are essential for large language models (LLMs) in a wide range of applications, such as education and healthcare. But there is still a lack of benchmarks for a better understanding of such capabilities. Current LLM benchmarks are mainly based on conversational tasks, academic math tests, and coding tests. Such benchmarks evaluate LLMs in well-regularized settings, but they are limited in assessing the skills and abilities to solve real-world problems. In this work, we provide a benchmark, named by CARL-GT, which evaluates CAusal Reasoning capabilities of large Language models using Graphs and Tabular data. The benchmark has a diverse range of tasks for evaluating LLMs from causal graph reasoning, knowledge discovery, and decision-making aspects. In addition, effective zero-shot learning prompts are developed for the tasks. In our experiments, we leverage the benchmark for evaluating open-source LLMs and provide a detailed comparison of LLMs for causal reasoning abilities. We found that LLMs are still weak in casual reasoning, especially with tabular data to discover new insights. Furthermore, we investigate and discuss the relationships of different benchmark tasks by analyzing the performance of LLMs. The experimental results show that LLMs have different strength over different tasks and that their performance on tasks in different categories, i.e., causal graph reasoning, knowledge discovery, and decision-making, shows stronger correlation than tasks in the same category.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.17970v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>stat.ME</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ruibo Tu, Hedvig Kjellstr\"om, Gustav Eje Henter, Cheng Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correctness is not Faithfulness in RAG Attributions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18004</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18004v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Retrieving relevant context is a common approach to reduce hallucinations and enhance answer reliability. Explicitly citing source documents allows users to verify generated responses and increases trust. Prior work largely evaluates citation correctness - whether cited documents support the corresponding statements. But citation correctness alone is insufficient. To establish trust in attributed answers, we must examine both citation correctness and citation faithfulness. In this work, we first disentangle the notions of citation correctness and faithfulness, which have been applied inconsistently in previous studies. Faithfulness ensures that the model's reliance on cited documents is genuine, reflecting actual reference use rather than superficial alignment with prior beliefs, which we call post-rationalization. We design an experiment that reveals the prevalent issue of post-rationalization, which undermines reliable attribution and may result in misplaced trust. Our findings suggest that current attributed answers often lack citation faithfulness (up to 57 percent of the citations), highlighting the need to evaluate correctness and faithfulness for trustworthy attribution in language models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18004v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jonas Wallat, Maria Heuss, Maarten de Rijke, Avishek Anand</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>StructTest: Benchmarking LLMs' Reasoning through Compositional Structured Outputs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18011</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18011v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The rapid development of large language models (LLMs) necessitates robust, unbiased, and scalable methods for evaluating their capabilities. However, human annotations are expensive to scale, model-based evaluations are prone to biases in answer style, while target-answer-based benchmarks are vulnerable to data contamination and cheating. To address these limitations, we propose StructTest, a novel benchmark that evaluates LLMs on their ability to produce compositionally specified structured outputs as an unbiased, cheap-to-run and difficult-to-cheat measure. The evaluation is done deterministically by a rule-based evaluator, which can be easily extended to new tasks. By testing structured outputs across diverse task domains -- including Summarization, Code, HTML and Math -- we demonstrate that StructTest serves as a good proxy for general reasoning abilities, as producing structured outputs often requires internal logical reasoning. We believe that StructTest offers a critical, complementary approach to objective and robust model evaluation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18011v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hailin Chen, Fangkai Jiao, Mathieu Ravaut, Nawshad Farruque, Xuan Phi Nguyen, Chengwei Qin, Manan Dey, Bosheng Ding, Caiming Xiong, Shafiq Joty, Yingbo Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Same Company, Same Signal: The Role of Identity in Earnings Call Transcripts</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18029</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18029v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Post-earnings volatility prediction is critical for investors, with previous works often leveraging earnings call transcripts under the assumption that their rich semantics contribute significantly. To further investigate how transcripts impact volatility, we introduce DEC, a dataset featuring accurate volatility calculations enabled by the previously overlooked beforeAfterMarket attribute and dense ticker coverage. Unlike established benchmarks, where each ticker has only around two earnings, DEC provides 20 earnings records per ticker. Using DEC, we reveal that post-earnings volatility undergoes significant shifts, with each ticker displaying a distinct volatility distribution. To leverage historical post-earnings volatility and capture ticker-specific patterns, we propose two training-free baselines: Post-earnings Volatility (PEV) and Same-ticker Post-earnings Volatility (STPEV). These baselines surpass all transcripts-based models on DEC as well as on established benchmarks. Additionally, we demonstrate that current transcript representations predominantly capture ticker identity rather than offering financially meaningful insights specific to each earnings. This is evidenced by two key observations: earnings representations from the same ticker exhibit significantly higher similarity compared to those from different tickers, and predictions from transcript-based models show strong correlations with prior post-earnings volatility.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18029v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ding Yu, Zhuo Liu, Hangfeng He</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explainability in Neural Networks for Natural Language Processing Tasks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18036</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18036v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Neural networks are widely regarded as black-box models, creating significant challenges in understanding their inner workings, especially in natural language processing (NLP) applications. To address this opacity, model explanation techniques like Local Interpretable Model-Agnostic Explanations (LIME) have emerged as essential tools for providing insights into the behavior of these complex systems. This study leverages LIME to interpret a multi-layer perceptron (MLP) neural network trained on a text classification task. By analyzing the contribution of individual features to model predictions, the LIME approach enhances interpretability and supports informed decision-making. Despite its effectiveness in offering localized explanations, LIME has limitations in capturing global patterns and feature interactions. This research highlights the strengths and shortcomings of LIME and proposes directions for future work to achieve more comprehensive interpretability in neural NLP models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18036v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Melkamu Mersha, Mingiziem Bitewa, Tsion Abay, Jugal Kalita</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aligning AI Research with the Needs of Clinical Coding Workflows: Eight Recommendations Based on US Data Analysis and Critical Review</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18043</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18043v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Clinical coding is crucial for healthcare billing and data analysis. Manual clinical coding is labour-intensive and error-prone, which has motivated research towards full automation of the process. However, our analysis, based on US English electronic health records and automated coding research using these records, shows that widely used evaluation methods are not aligned with real clinical contexts. For example, evaluations that focus on the top 50 most common codes are an oversimplification, as there are thousands of codes used in practice. This position paper aims to align AI coding research more closely with practical challenges of clinical coding. Based on our analysis, we offer eight specific recommendations, suggesting ways to improve current evaluation methods. Additionally, we propose new AI-based methods beyond automated coding, suggesting alternative approaches to assist clinical coders in their workflows.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18043v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yidong Gan, Maciej Rybinski, Ben Hachey, Jonathan K. Kummerfeld</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Factuality or Fiction? Benchmarking Modern LLMs on Ambiguous QA with Citations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18051</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18051v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Benchmarking modern large language models (LLMs) on complex and realistic tasks is critical to advancing their development. In this work, we evaluate the factual accuracy and citation performance of state-of-the-art LLMs on the task of Question Answering (QA) in ambiguous settings with source citations. Using three recently published datasets-DisentQA-DupliCite, DisentQA-ParaCite, and AmbigQA-Cite-featuring a range of real-world ambiguities, we analyze the performance of two leading LLMs, GPT-4o-mini and Claude-3.5. Our results show that larger, recent models consistently predict at least one correct answer in ambiguous contexts but fail to handle cases with multiple valid answers. Additionally, all models perform equally poorly in citation generation, with citation accuracy consistently at 0. However, introducing conflict-aware prompting leads to large improvements, enabling models to better address multiple valid answers and improve citation accuracy, while maintaining their ability to predict correct answers. These findings highlight the challenges and opportunities in developing LLMs that can handle ambiguity and provide reliable source citations. Our benchmarking study provides critical insights and sets a foundation for future improvements in trustworthy and interpretable QA systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18051v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Maya Patel, Aditi Anand</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neuron Empirical Gradient: Connecting Neurons' Linear Controllability and Representational Capacity</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18053</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18053v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Although neurons in the feed-forward layers of pre-trained language models (PLMs) can store factual knowledge, most prior analyses remain qualitative, leaving the quantitative relationship among knowledge representation, neuron activations, and model output poorly understood. In this study, by performing neuron-wise interventions using factual probing datasets, we first reveal the linear relationship between neuron activations and output token probabilities. We refer to the gradient of this linear relationship as ``neuron empirical gradients.'' and propose NeurGrad, an efficient method for their calculation to facilitate quantitative neuron analysis. We next investigate whether neuron empirical gradients in PLMs encode general task knowledge by probing skill neurons. To this end, we introduce MCEval8k, a multi-choice knowledge evaluation benchmark spanning six genres and 22 tasks. Our experiments confirm that neuron empirical gradients effectively capture knowledge, while skill neurons exhibit efficiency, generality, inclusivity, and interdependency. These findings link knowledge to PLM outputs via neuron empirical gradients, shedding light on how PLMs store knowledge. The code and dataset are released.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18053v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xin Zhao, Zehui Jiang, Naoki Yoshinaga</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Factuality with Explicit Working Memory</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18069</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18069v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models can generate factually inaccurate content, a problem known as hallucination. Recent works have built upon retrieved-augmented generation to improve factuality through iterative prompting but these methods are limited by the traditional RAG design. To address these challenges, we introduce EWE (Explicit Working Memory), a novel approach that enhances factuality in long-form text generation by integrating a working memory that receives real-time feedback from external resources. The memory is refreshed based on online fact-checking and retrieval feedback, allowing EWE to rectify false claims during the generation process and ensure more accurate and reliable outputs. Our experiments demonstrate that Ewe outperforms strong baselines on four fact-seeking long-form generation datasets, increasing the factuality metric, VeriScore, by 2 to 10 points absolute without sacrificing the helpfulness of the responses. Further analysis reveals that the design of rules for memory updates, configurations of memory units, and the quality of the retrieval datastore are crucial factors for influencing model performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18069v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mingda Chen, Yang Li, Karthik Padthe, Rulin Shao, Alicia Sun, Luke Zettlemoyer, Gargi Gosh, Wen-tau Yih</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molly: Making Large Language Model Agents Solve Python Problem More Logically</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18093</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18093v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Applying large language models (LLMs) as teaching assists has attracted much attention as an integral part of intelligent education, particularly in computing courses. To reduce the gap between the LLMs and the computer programming education expert, fine-tuning and retrieval augmented generation (RAG) are the two mainstream methods in existing researches. However, fine-tuning for specific tasks is resource-intensive and may diminish the model`s generalization capabilities. RAG can perform well on reducing the illusion of LLMs, but the generation of irrelevant factual content during reasoning can cause significant confusion for learners. To address these problems, we introduce the Molly agent, focusing on solving the proposed problem encountered by learners when learning Python programming language. Our agent automatically parse the learners' questioning intent through a scenario-based interaction, enabling precise retrieval of relevant documents from the constructed knowledge base. At generation stage, the agent reflect on the generated responses to ensure that they not only align with factual content but also effectively answer the user's queries. Extensive experimentation on a constructed Chinese Python QA dataset shows the effectiveness of the Molly agent, indicating an enhancement in its performance for providing useful responses to Python questions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18093v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rui Xiao, Jiong Wang, Lu Han, Na Zong, Han Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Language Models Understand the Cognitive Tasks Given to Them? Investigations with the N-Back Paradigm</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18120</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18120v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Cognitive tasks originally developed for humans are now increasingly used to study language models. While applying these tasks is often straightforward, interpreting their results can be challenging. In particular, when a model underperforms, it's often unclear whether this results from a limitation in the cognitive ability being tested or a failure to understand the task itself. A recent study argued that GPT 3.5's declining performance on 2-back and 3-back tasks reflects a working memory capacity limit similar to humans. By analyzing a range of open-source language models of varying performance levels on these tasks, we show that the poor performance instead reflects a limitation in task comprehension and task set maintenance. In addition, we push the best performing model to higher n values and experiment with alternative prompting strategies, before analyzing model attentions. Our larger aim is to contribute to the ongoing conversation around refining methodologies for the cognitive evaluation of language models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18120v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoyang Hu, Richard L. Lewis</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LSAQ: Layer-Specific Adaptive Quantization for Large Language Model Deployment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18135</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18135v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: As large language models (LLMs) demonstrate exceptional performance across various domains, the deployment of these models on edge devices has emerged as a new trend. Quantization techniques, which reduce the size and memory footprint of LLMs, are effective for enabling deployment on resource-constrained edge devices. However, existing one-size-fits-all quantization methods often fail to dynamically adjust the memory consumption of LLMs based on specific hardware characteristics and usage scenarios. To address this limitation, we propose LSAQ (Layer-Specific Adaptive Quantization), a system for adaptive quantization and dynamic deployment of LLMs based on layer importance. LSAQ evaluates layer importance by constructing top-k token sets from the inputs and outputs of each layer and calculating their Jaccard coefficient. Using this evaluation, the system adaptively adjusts quantization strategies in real time according to the resource availability of edge devices, assigning different precision levels to layers of varying importance. This approach significantly reduces the storage requirements of LLMs while maintaining model performance, enabling efficient deployment across diverse hardware platforms and usage scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18135v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Binrui Zeng, Bin Ji, Xiaodong Liu, Jie Yu, Shasha Li, Jun Ma, Xiaopeng Li, Shangwen Wang, Xinran Hong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ensuring Consistency for In-Image Translation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18139</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18139v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The in-image machine translation task involves translating text embedded within images, with the translated results presented in image format. While this task has numerous applications in various scenarios such as film poster translation and everyday scene image translation, existing methods frequently neglect the aspect of consistency throughout this process. We propose the need to uphold two types of consistency in this task: translation consistency and image generation consistency. The former entails incorporating image information during translation, while the latter involves maintaining consistency between the style of the text-image and the original image, ensuring background integrity. To address these consistency requirements, we introduce a novel two-stage framework named HCIIT (High-Consistency In-Image Translation) which involves text-image translation using a multimodal multilingual large language model in the first stage and image backfilling with a diffusion model in the second stage. Chain of thought learning is utilized in the first stage to enhance the model's ability to leverage image information during translation. Subsequently, a diffusion model trained for style-consistent text-image generation ensures uniformity in text style within images and preserves background details. A dataset comprising 400,000 style-consistent pseudo text-image pairs is curated for model training. Results obtained on both curated test sets and authentic image test sets validate the effectiveness of our framework in ensuring consistency and producing high-quality translated images.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18139v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chengpeng Fu, Xiaocheng Feng, Yichong Huang, Wenshuai Huo, Baohang Li, Zhirui Zhang, Yunfei Lu, Dandan Tu, Duyu Tang, Hui Wang, Bing Qin, Ting Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoAM: Corpus of All-Type Multiword Expressions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18151</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18151v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Multiword expressions (MWEs) refer to idiomatic sequences of multiple words. MWE identification, i.e., detecting MWEs in text, can play a key role in downstream tasks such as machine translation. Existing datasets for MWE identification are inconsistently annotated, limited to a single type of MWE, or limited in size. To enable reliable and comprehensive evaluation, we created CoAM: Corpus of All-Type Multiword Expressions, a dataset of 1.3K sentences constructed through a multi-step process to enhance data quality consisting of human annotation, human review, and automated consistency checking. MWEs in CoAM are tagged with MWE types, such as Noun and Verb, to enable fine-grained error analysis. Annotations for CoAM were collected using a new interface created with our interface generator, which allows easy and flexible annotation of MWEs in any form, including discontinuous ones. Through experiments using CoAM, we find that a fine-tuned large language model outperforms the current state-of-the-art approach for MWE identification. Furthermore, analysis using our MWE type tagged data reveals that Verb MWEs are easier than Noun MWEs to identify across approaches.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18151v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yusuke Ide, Joshua Tanner, Adam Nohejl, Jacob Hoffman, Justin Vasselli, Hidetaka Kamigaito, Taro Watanabe</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Survey of Pseudonymization, Abstractive Summarization &amp; Spell Checker for Hindi and Marathi</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18163</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18163v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: India's vast linguistic diversity presents unique challenges and opportunities for technological advancement, especially in the realm of Natural Language Processing (NLP). While there has been significant progress in NLP applications for widely spoken languages, the regional languages of India, such as Marathi and Hindi, remain underserved. Research in the field of NLP for Indian regional languages is at a formative stage and holds immense significance. The paper aims to build a platform which enables the user to use various features like text anonymization, abstractive text summarization and spell checking in English, Hindi and Marathi language. The aim of these tools is to serve enterprise and consumer clients who predominantly use Indian Regional Languages.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18163v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rasika Ransing, Mohammed Amaan Dhamaskar, Ayush Rajpurohit, Amey Dhoke, Sanket Dalvi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Applicability of Zero-Shot Cross-Lingual Transfer Learning for Sentiment Classification in Distant Language Pairs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18188</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18188v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This research explores the applicability of cross-lingual transfer learning from English to Japanese and Indonesian using the XLM-R pre-trained model. The results are compared with several previous works, either by models using a similar zero-shot approach or a fully-supervised approach, to provide an overview of the zero-shot transfer learning approach's capability using XLM-R in comparison with existing models. Our models achieve the best result in one Japanese dataset and comparable results in other datasets in Japanese and Indonesian languages without being trained using the target language. Furthermore, the results suggest that it is possible to train a multi-lingual model, instead of one model for each language, and achieve promising results.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18188v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Andre Rusli, Makoto Shishido</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Analysis on Automated Metrics for Evaluating Japanese-English Chat Translation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18190</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18190v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper analyses how traditional baseline metrics, such as BLEU and TER, and neural-based methods, such as BERTScore and COMET, score several NMT models performance on chat translation and how these metrics perform when compared to human-annotated scores. The results show that for ranking NMT models in chat translations, all metrics seem consistent in deciding which model outperforms the others. This implies that traditional baseline metrics, which are faster and simpler to use, can still be helpful. On the other hand, when it comes to better correlation with human judgment, neural-based metrics outperform traditional metrics, with COMET achieving the highest correlation with the human-annotated score on a chat translation. However, we show that even the best metric struggles when scoring English translations from sentences with anaphoric zero-pronoun in Japanese.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18190v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Andre Rusli, Makoto Shishido</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robustness-aware Automatic Prompt Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18196</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18196v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The performance of Large Language Models (LLMs) is based on the quality of the prompts and the semantic and structural integrity information of the input data. However, current prompt generation methods primarily focus on generating prompts for clean input data, often overlooking the impact of perturbed inputs on prompt performance. To address this limitation, we propose BATprompt (By Adversarial Training prompt), a novel method for prompt generation designed to withstand input perturbations (such as typos in the input). Inspired by adversarial training techniques, BATprompt demonstrates strong performance on a variety of perturbed tasks through a two-step process: adversarial perturbation and iterative optimization on unperturbed input via LLM. Unlike conventional adversarial attack methods, BATprompt avoids reliance on real gradients or model parameters. Instead, it leverages the advanced reasoning, language understanding and self reflection capabilities of LLMs to simulate gradients, guiding the generation of adversarial perturbations and optimizing prompt performance. In our experiments, we evaluate BATprompt on multiple datasets across both language understanding and generation tasks. The results indicate that BATprompt outperforms existing prompt generation methods, delivering superior robustness and performance under diverse perturbation scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18196v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zeru Shi, Zhenting Wang, Yongye Su, Weidi Luo, Fan Yang, Yongfeng Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating Large Language Models for Code Vulnerability Detection: An Experimental Study</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18260</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18260v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Code vulnerability detection (CVD) is essential for addressing and preventing system security issues, playing a crucial role in ensuring software security. Previous learning-based vulnerability detection methods rely on either fine-tuning medium-size sequence models or training smaller neural networks from scratch. Recent advancements in large pre-trained language models (LLMs) have showcased remarkable capabilities in various code intelligence tasks including code understanding and generation. However, the effectiveness of LLMs in detecting code vulnerabilities is largely under-explored. This work aims to investigate the gap by fine-tuning LLMs for the CVD task, involving four widely-used open-source LLMs. We also implement other five previous graph-based or medium-size sequence models for comparison. Experiments are conducted on five commonly-used CVD datasets, including both the part of short samples and long samples. In addition, we conduct quantitative experiments to investigate the class imbalance issue and the model's performance on samples of different lengths, which are rarely studied in previous works. To better facilitate communities, we open-source all codes and resources of this study in https://github.com/SakiRinn/LLM4CVD and https://huggingface.co/datasets/xuefen/VulResource.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18260v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xuefeng Jiang, Lvhua Wu, Sheng Sun, Jia Li, Jingjing Xue, Yuwei Wang, Tingting Wu, Min Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GenAI Content Detection Task 2: AI vs. Human -- Academic Essay Authenticity Challenge</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18274</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18274v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper presents a comprehensive overview of the first edition of the Academic Essay Authenticity Challenge, organized as part of the GenAI Content Detection shared tasks collocated with COLING 2025. This challenge focuses on detecting machine-generated vs. human-authored essays for academic purposes. The task is defined as follows: "Given an essay, identify whether it is generated by a machine or authored by a human.'' The challenge involves two languages: English and Arabic. During the evaluation phase, 25 teams submitted systems for English and 21 teams for Arabic, reflecting substantial interest in the task. Finally, seven teams submitted system description papers. The majority of submissions utilized fine-tuned transformer-based models, with one team employing Large Language Models (LLMs) such as Llama 2 and Llama 3. This paper outlines the task formulation, details the dataset construction process, and explains the evaluation framework. Additionally, we present a summary of the approaches adopted by participating teams. Nearly all submitted systems outperformed the n-gram-based baseline, with the top-performing systems achieving F1 scores exceeding 0.98 for both languages, indicating significant progress in the detection of machine-generated text.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18274v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shammur Absar Chowdhury, Hind Almerekhi, Mucahid Kutlu, Kaan Efe Keles, Fatema Ahmad, Tasnim Mohiuddin, George Mikros, Firoj Alam</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>M-Ped: Multi-Prompt Ensemble Decoding for Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18299</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18299v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: With the widespread application of Large Language Models (LLMs) in the field of Natural Language Processing (NLP), enhancing their performance has become a research hotspot. This paper presents a novel multi-prompt ensemble decoding approach designed to bolster the generation quality of LLMs by leveraging the aggregation of outcomes from multiple prompts. Given a unique input $X$, we submit $n$ variations of prompts with $X$ to LLMs in batch mode to decode and derive probability distributions. For each token prediction, we calculate the ensemble probability by averaging the $n$ probability distributions within the batch, utilizing this aggregated probability to generate the token. This technique is dubbed Inner-Batch Ensemble. To facilitate efficient batch inference, we implement a Left-Padding strategy to maintain uniform input lengths across the n prompts. Through extensive experimentation on diverse NLP tasks, including machine translation, code generation, and text simplification, we demonstrate the efficacy of our method in enhancing LLM performance. The results show substantial improvements in BLEU scores, pass@$k$ rates, and LENS metrics over conventional methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18299v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiaxin Guo, Daimeng Wei, Yuanchang Luo, Shimin Tao, Hengchao Shang, Zongyao Li, Shaojun Li, Jinlong Yang, Zhanglin Wu, Zhiqiang Rao, Hao Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Agents Based on Large Language Models for Knowledge-based Visual Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18351</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18351v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have achieved impressive results in knowledge-based Visual Question Answering (VQA). However existing methods still have challenges: the inability to use external tools autonomously, and the inability to work in teams. Humans tend to know whether they need to use external tools when they encounter a new question, e.g., they tend to be able to give a direct answer to a familiar question, whereas they tend to use tools such as search engines when they encounter an unfamiliar question. In addition, humans also tend to collaborate and discuss with others to get better answers. Inspired by this, we propose the multi-agent voting framework. We design three LLM-based agents that simulate different levels of staff in a team, and assign the available tools according to the levels. Each agent provides the corresponding answer, and finally all the answers provided by the agents are voted to get the final answer. Experiments on OK-VQA and A-OKVQA show that our approach outperforms other baselines by 2.2 and 1.0, respectively.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18351v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhongjian Hu, Peng Yang, Bing Li, Zhenqi Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extracting triples from dialogues for conversational social agents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18364</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18364v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Obtaining an explicit understanding of communication within a Hybrid Intelligence collaboration is essential to create controllable and transparent agents. In this paper, we describe a number of Natural Language Understanding models that extract explicit symbolic triples from social conversation. Triple extraction has mostly been developed and tested for Knowledge Base Completion using Wikipedia text and data for training and testing. However, social conversation is very different as a genre in which interlocutors exchange information in sequences of utterances that involve statements, questions, and answers. Phenomena such as co-reference, ellipsis, coordination, and implicit and explicit negation or confirmation are more prominent in conversation than in Wikipedia text. We therefore describe an attempt to fill this gap by releasing data sets for training and testing triple extraction from social conversation. We also created five triple extraction models and tested them in our evaluation data. The highest precision is 51.14 for complete triples and 69.32 for triple elements when tested on single utterances. However, scores for conversational triples that span multiple turns are much lower, showing that extracting knowledge from true conversational data is much more challenging.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18364v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Piek Vossen, Selene B\'aez Santamar\'ia, Lenka Baj\v{c}eti\'c, Thomas Belluci</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Global AI Inclusivity: A Large-Scale Multilingual Terminology Dataset</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18367</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18367v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The field of machine translation has achieved significant advancements, yet domain-specific terminology translation, particularly in AI, remains challenging. We introduced GIST, a large-scale multilingual AI terminology dataset containing 5K terms extracted from top AI conference papers spanning 2000 to 2023. The terms were translated into Arabic, Chinese, French, Japanese, and Russian using a hybrid framework that combines LLMs for extraction with human expertise for translation. The dataset's quality was benchmarked against existing resources, demonstrating superior translation accuracy through crowdsourced evaluation. GIST was integrated into translation workflows using post-translation refinement methods that required no retraining, where LLM prompting consistently improved BLEU and COMET scores. A web demonstration on the ACL Anthology platform highlights its practical application, showcasing improved accessibility for non-English speakers. This work aims to address critical gaps in AI terminology resources and fosters global inclusivity and collaboration in AI research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18367v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiarui Liu, Iman Ouzzani, Wenkai Li, Lechen Zhang, Tianyue Ou, Houda Bouamor, Zhijing Jin, Mona Diab</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bidirectional Topic Matching: Quantifying Thematic Overlap Between Corpora Through Topic Modelling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18376</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18376v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This study introduces Bidirectional Topic Matching (BTM), a novel method for cross-corpus topic modeling that quantifies thematic overlap and divergence between corpora. BTM is a flexible framework that can incorporate various topic modeling approaches, including BERTopic, Top2Vec, and Latent Dirichlet Allocation (LDA). BTM employs a dual-model approach, training separate topic models for each corpus and applying them reciprocally to enable comprehensive cross-corpus comparisons. This methodology facilitates the identification of shared themes and unique topics, providing nuanced insights into thematic relationships. Validation against cosine similarity-based methods demonstrates the robustness of BTM, with strong agreement metrics and distinct advantages in handling outlier topics. A case study on climate news articles showcases BTM's utility, revealing significant thematic overlaps and distinctions between corpora focused on climate change and climate action. BTM's flexibility and precision make it a valuable tool for diverse applications, from political discourse analysis to interdisciplinary studies. By integrating shared and unique topic analyses, BTM offers a comprehensive framework for exploring thematic relationships, with potential extensions to multilingual and dynamic datasets. This work highlights BTM's methodological contributions and its capacity to advance discourse analysis across various domains.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18376v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Raven Adam, Marie Lisa Kogler</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChaI-TeA: A Benchmark for Evaluating Autocompletion of Interactions with LLM-based Chatbots</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18377</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18377v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The rise of LLMs has deflected a growing portion of human-computer interactions towards LLM-based chatbots. The remarkable abilities of these models allow users to interact using long, diverse natural language text covering a wide range of topics and styles. Phrasing these messages is a time and effort consuming task, calling for an autocomplete solution to assist users. We introduce the task of chatbot interaction autocomplete. We present ChaI-TeA: CHat InTEraction Autocomplete; An autcomplete evaluation framework for LLM-based chatbot interactions. The framework includes a formal definition of the task, coupled with suitable datasets and metrics. We use the framework to evaluate After formally defining the task along with suitable datasets and metrics, we test 9 models on the defined auto completion task, finding that while current off-the-shelf models perform fairly, there is still much room for improvement, mainly in ranking of the generated suggestions. We provide insights for practitioners working on this task and open new research directions for researchers in the field. We release our framework to serve as a foundation for future research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18377v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shani Goren, Oren Kalinsky, Tomer Stav, Yuri Rapoport, Yaron Fairstein, Ram Yazdy, Nachshon Cohen, Alexander Libov, Guy Kushilevitz</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multilingual Mathematical Reasoning: Advancing Open-Source LLMs in Hindi and English</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18415</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18415v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) excel in linguistic tasks but struggle with mathematical reasoning, particularly in non English languages like Hindi. This research aims to enhance the mathematical reasoning skills of smaller, resource efficient open-source LLMs in both Hindi and English. We evaluate models like OpenHathi 7B, LLaMA-2 7B, WizardMath 7B, Mistral 7B, LLeMMa 7B, MAmmoTH 7B, Gemini Pro, and GPT-4 using zero-shot, few-shot chain-of-thought (CoT) methods, and supervised fine-tuning. Our approach incorporates curriculum learning, progressively training models on increasingly difficult problems, a novel Decomposition Strategy to simplify complex arithmetic operations, and a Structured Solution Design that divides solutions into phases. Our experiments result in notable performance enhancements. WizardMath 7B exceeds Gemini's accuracy on English datasets by +6% and matches Gemini's performance on Hindi datasets. Adopting a bilingual approach that combines English and Hindi samples achieves results comparable to individual language models, demonstrating the capability to learn mathematical reasoning in both languages. This research highlights the potential for improving mathematical reasoning in open-source LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18415v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Avinash Anand, Kritarth Prasad, Chhavi Kirtani, Ashwin R Nair, Manvendra Kumar Nema, Raj Jaiswal, Rajiv Ratn Shah</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GeAR: Graph-enhanced Agent for Retrieval-augmented Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18431</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18431v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Retrieval-augmented generation systems rely on effective document retrieval capabilities. By design, conventional sparse or dense retrievers face challenges in multi-hop retrieval scenarios. In this paper, we present GeAR, which advances RAG performance through two key innovations: (i) graph expansion, which enhances any conventional base retriever, such as BM25, and (ii) an agent framework that incorporates graph expansion. Our evaluation demonstrates GeAR's superior retrieval performance on three multi-hop question answering datasets. Additionally, our system achieves state-of-the-art results with improvements exceeding 10% on the challenging MuSiQue dataset, while requiring fewer tokens and iterations compared to other multi-step retrieval systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18431v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhili Shen, Chenxin Diao, Pavlos Vougiouklis, Pascual Merita, Shriram Piramanayagam, Damien Graux, Dandan Tu, Zeren Jiang, Ruofei Lai, Yang Ren, Jeff Z. Pan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Potential of Multiple BERT Models for Bangla Question Answering in NCTB Textbooks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18440</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18440v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Evaluating text comprehension in educational settings is critical for understanding student performance and improving curricular effectiveness. This study investigates the capability of state-of-the-art language models-RoBERTa Base, Bangla-BERT, and BERT Base-in automatically assessing Bangla passage-based question-answering from the National Curriculum and Textbook Board (NCTB) textbooks for classes 6-10. A dataset of approximately 3,000 Bangla passage-based question-answering instances was compiled, and the models were evaluated using F1 Score and Exact Match (EM) metrics across various hyperparameter configurations. Our findings revealed that Bangla-BERT consistently outperformed the other models, achieving the highest F1 (0.75) and EM (0.53) scores, particularly with smaller batch sizes, the inclusion of stop words, and a moderate learning rate. In contrast, RoBERTa Base demonstrated the weakest performance, with the lowest F1 (0.19) and EM (0.27) scores under certain configurations. The results underscore the importance of fine-tuning hyperparameters for optimizing model performance and highlight the potential of machine learning models in evaluating text comprehension in educational contexts. However, limitations such as dataset size, spelling inconsistencies, and computational constraints emphasize the need for further research to enhance the robustness and applicability of these models. This study lays the groundwork for the future development of automated evaluation systems in educational institutions, providing critical insights into model performance in the context of Bangla text comprehension.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18440v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Abdullah Khondoker, Enam Ahmed Taufik, Md Iftekhar Islam Tashik, S M Ishtiak mahmud, Antara Firoz Parsa</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Large Language Model Good at Triple Set Prediction? An Empirical Study</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18443</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18443v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The core of the Knowledge Graph Completion (KGC) task is to predict and complete the missing relations or nodes in a KG. Common KGC tasks are mostly about inferring unknown elements with one or two elements being known in a triple. In comparison, the Triple Set Prediction (TSP) task is a more realistic knowledge graph completion task. It aims to predict all elements of unknown triples based on the information from known triples. In recent years, large language models (LLMs) have exhibited significant advancements in language comprehension, demonstrating considerable potential for KGC tasks. However, the potential of LLM on the TSP task has not yet to be investigated. Thus in this paper we proposed a new framework to explore the strengths and limitations of LLM in the TSP task. Specifically, the framework consists of LLM-based rule mining and LLM-based triple set prediction. The relation list of KG embedded within rich semantic information is first leveraged to prompt LLM in the generation of rules. This process is both efficient and independent of statistical information, making it easier to mine effective and realistic rules. For each subgraph, the specified rule is applied in conjunction with the relevant triples within that subgraph to guide the LLM in predicting the missing triples. Subsequently, the predictions from all subgraphs are consolidated to derive the complete set of predicted triples on KG. Finally, the method is evaluated on the relatively complete CFamily dataset. The experimental results indicate that when LLMs are required to adhere to a large amount of factual knowledge to predict missing triples, significant hallucinations occurs, leading to a noticeable decline in performance. To further explore the causes of this phenomenon, this paper presents a comprehensive analysis supported by a detailed case study.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18443v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuan Yuan, Yajing Xu, Wen Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Segment-Based Attention Masking for GPTs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18487</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18487v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Modern Language Models (LMs) owe much of their success to masked causal attention, the backbone of Generative Pre-Trained Transformer (GPT) models. Although GPTs can process the entire user prompt at once, the causal masking is applied to all input tokens step-by-step, mimicking the generation process. This imposes an unnecessary constraint during the initial "prefill" phase when the model processes the input prompt and generates the internal representations before producing any output tokens. In this work, attention is masked based on the known block structure at the prefill phase, followed by the conventional token-by-token autoregressive process after that. For example, in a typical chat prompt, the system prompt is treated as one block, and the user prompt as the next one. Each of these is treated as a unit for the purpose of masking, such that the first tokens in each block can access the subsequent tokens in a non-causal manner. Then, the model answer is generated in the conventional causal manner. This Segment-by-Segment scheme entails no additional computational overhead. When integrating it into models such as Llama and Qwen, state-of-the-art performance is consistently achieved.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18487v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shahar Katz, Liran Ringel, Yaniv Romano, Lior Wolf</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How "Real" is Your Real-Time Simultaneous Speech-to-Text Translation System?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18495</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18495v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Simultaneous speech-to-text translation (SimulST) translates source-language speech into target-language text concurrently with the speaker's speech, ensuring low latency for better user comprehension. Despite its intended application to unbounded speech, most research has focused on human pre-segmented speech, simplifying the task and overlooking significant challenges. This narrow focus, coupled with widespread terminological inconsistencies, is limiting the applicability of research outcomes to real-world applications, ultimately hindering progress in the field. Our extensive literature review of 110 papers not only reveals these critical issues in current research but also serves as the foundation for our key contributions. We 1) define the steps and core components of a SimulST system, proposing a standardized terminology and taxonomy; 2) conduct a thorough analysis of community trends, and 3) offer concrete recommendations and future directions to bridge the gaps in existing literature, from evaluation frameworks to system architectures, for advancing the field towards more realistic and effective SimulST solutions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18495v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sara Papi, Peter Polak, Ond\v{r}ej Bojar, Dominik Mach\'a\v{c}ek</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generating event descriptions under syntactic and semantic constraints</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18496</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18496v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: With the goal of supporting scalable lexical semantic annotation, analysis, and theorizing, we conduct a comprehensive evaluation of different methods for generating event descriptions under both syntactic constraints -- e.g. desired clause structure -- and semantic constraints -- e.g. desired verb sense. We compare three different methods -- (i) manual generation by experts; (ii) sampling from a corpus annotated for syntactic and semantic information; and (iii) sampling from a language model (LM) conditioned on syntactic and semantic information -- along three dimensions of the generated event descriptions: (a) naturalness, (b) typicality, and (c) distinctiveness. We find that all methods reliably produce natural, typical, and distinctive event descriptions, but that manual generation continues to produce event descriptions that are more natural, typical, and distinctive than the automated generation methods. We conclude that the automated methods we consider produce event descriptions of sufficient quality for use in downstream annotation and analysis insofar as the methods used for this annotation and analysis are robust to a small amount of degradation in the resulting event descriptions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18496v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Angela Cao, Faye Holt, Jonas Chan, Stephanie Richter, Lelia Glass, Aaron Steven White</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Think or Remember? Detecting and Directing LLMs Towards Memorization or Generalization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18497</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18497v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this paper, we explore the foundational mechanisms of memorization and generalization in Large Language Models (LLMs), inspired by the functional specialization observed in the human brain. Our investigation serves as a case study leveraging specially designed datasets and experimental-scale LLMs to lay the groundwork for understanding these behaviors. Specifically, we aim to first enable LLMs to exhibit both memorization and generalization by training with the designed dataset, then (a) examine whether LLMs exhibit neuron-level spatial differentiation for memorization and generalization, (b) predict these behaviors using model internal representations, and (c) steer the behaviors through inference-time interventions. Our findings reveal that neuron-wise differentiation of memorization and generalization is observable in LLMs, and targeted interventions can successfully direct their behavior.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18497v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yi-Fu Fu, Yu-Chieh Tu, Tzu-Ling Cheng, Cheng-Yu Lin, Yi-Ting Yang, Heng-Yi Liu, Keng-Te Liao, Da-Cheng Juan, Shou-De Lin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing Large Language Models for Knowledge Graph Question Answering via Adaptive Multi-Aspect Retrieval-Augmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18537</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18537v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) demonstrate remarkable capabilities, yet struggle with hallucination and outdated knowledge when tasked with complex knowledge reasoning, resulting in factually incorrect outputs. Previous studies have attempted to mitigate it by retrieving factual knowledge from large-scale knowledge graphs (KGs) to assist LLMs in logical reasoning and prediction of answers. However, this kind of approach often introduces noise and irrelevant data, especially in situations with extensive context from multiple knowledge aspects. In this way, LLM attention can be potentially mislead from question and relevant information. In our study, we introduce an Adaptive Multi-Aspect Retrieval-augmented over KGs (Amar) framework. This method retrieves knowledge including entities, relations, and subgraphs, and converts each piece of retrieved text into prompt embeddings. The Amar framework comprises two key sub-components: 1) a self-alignment module that aligns commonalities among entities, relations, and subgraphs to enhance retrieved text, thereby reducing noise interference; 2) a relevance gating module that employs a soft gate to learn the relevance score between question and multi-aspect retrieved data, to determine which information should be used to enhance LLMs' output, or even filtered altogether. Our method has achieved state-of-the-art performance on two common datasets, WebQSP and CWQ, showing a 1.9\% improvement in accuracy over its best competitor and a 6.6\% improvement in logical form generation over a method that directly uses retrieved text as context prompts. These results demonstrate the effectiveness of Amar in improving the reasoning of LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18537v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Derong Xu Xinhang Li, Ziheng Zhang, Zhenxi Lin, Zhihong Zhu, Zhi Zheng, Xian Wu, Xiangyu Zhao, Tong Xu, Enhong Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Token-Budget-Aware LLM Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18547</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18547v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Reasoning is critical for large language models (LLMs) to excel in a wide range of tasks. While methods like Chain-of-Thought (CoT) reasoning enhance LLM performance by decomposing problems into intermediate steps, they also incur significant overhead in token usage, leading to increased costs. We find that the reasoning process of current LLMs is unnecessarily lengthy and it can be compressed by including a reasonable token budget in the prompt, but the choice of token budget plays a crucial role in the actual compression effectiveness. We then propose a token-budget-aware LLM reasoning framework, which dynamically estimates token budgets for different problems based on reasoning complexity and uses the estimated token budgets to guide the reasoning process. Experiments show that our method effectively reduces token costs in CoT reasoning with only a slight performance reduction, offering a practical solution to balance efficiency and accuracy in LLM reasoning. Code: https://github.com/GeniusHTX/TALE.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18547v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tingxu Han, Chunrong Fang, Shiyu Zhao, Shiqing Ma, Zhenyu Chen, Zhenting Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Libra-Leaderboard: Towards Responsible AI through a Balanced Leaderboard of Safety and Capability</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18551</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18551v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: To address this gap, we introduce Libra-Leaderboard, a comprehensive framework designed to rank LLMs through a balanced evaluation of performance and safety. Combining a dynamic leaderboard with an interactive LLM arena, Libra-Leaderboard encourages the joint optimization of capability and safety. Unlike traditional approaches that average performance and safety metrics, Libra-Leaderboard uses a distance-to-optimal-score method to calculate the overall rankings. This approach incentivizes models to achieve a balance rather than excelling in one dimension at the expense of some other ones. In the first release, Libra-Leaderboard evaluates 26 mainstream LLMs from 14 leading organizations, identifying critical safety challenges even in state-of-the-art models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18551v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haonan Li, Xudong Han, Zenan Zhai, Honglin Mu, Hao Wang, Zhenxuan Zhang, Yilin Geng, Shom Lin, Renxi Wang, Artem Shelmanov, Xiangyu Qi, Yuxia Wang, Donghai Hong, Youliang Yuan, Meng Chen, Haoqin Tu, Fajri Koto, Tatsuki Kuribayashi, Cong Zeng, Rishabh Bhardwaj, Bingchen Zhao, Yawen Duan, Yi Liu, Emad A. Alghamdi, Yaodong Yang, Yinpeng Dong, Soujanya Poria, Pengfei Liu, Zhengzhong Liu, Xuguang Ren, Eduard Hovy, Iryna Gurevych, Preslav Nakov, Monojit Choudhury, Timothy Baldwin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distilling Fine-grained Sentiment Understanding from Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18552</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18552v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Fine-grained sentiment analysis (FSA) aims to extract and summarize user opinions from vast opinionated text. Recent studies demonstrate that large language models (LLMs) possess exceptional sentiment understanding capabilities. However, directly deploying LLMs for FSA applications incurs high inference costs. Therefore, this paper investigates the distillation of fine-grained sentiment understanding from LLMs into small language models (SLMs). We prompt LLMs to examine and interpret the sentiments of given reviews and then utilize the generated content to pretrain SLMs. Additionally, we develop a comprehensive FSA benchmark to evaluate both SLMs and LLMs. Extensive experiments on this benchmark reveal that: (1) distillation significantly enhances the performance of SLMs in FSA tasks, achieving a 6.00\% improvement in $F_1$-score, and the distilled model can outperform Llama-2-7b with only 220M parameters; (2) distillation equips SLMs with excellent zero-shot sentiment classification capabilities, enabling them to match or even exceed their teacher models. These results suggest that distillation from LLMs is a highly promising direction for FSA. We will release our code, data, and pretrained model weights at \url{https://github.com/HITSZ-HLT/FSA-Distillation}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18552v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yice Zhang, Guangyu Xie, Hongling Xu, Kaiheng Hou, Jianzhu Bao, Qianlong Wang, Shiwei Chen, Ruifeng Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zero-resource Speech Translation and Recognition with LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18566</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18566v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Despite recent advancements in speech processing, zero-resource speech translation (ST) and automatic speech recognition (ASR) remain challenging problems. In this work, we propose to leverage a multilingual Large Language Model (LLM) to perform ST and ASR in languages for which the model has never seen paired audio-text data. We achieve this by using a pre-trained multilingual speech encoder, a multilingual LLM, and a lightweight adaptation module that maps the audio representations to the token embedding space of the LLM. We perform several experiments both in ST and ASR to understand how to best train the model and what data has the most impact on performance in previously unseen languages. In ST, our best model is capable to achieve BLEU scores over 23 in CoVoST2 for two previously unseen languages, while in ASR, we achieve WERs of up to 28.2\%. We finally show that the performance of our system is bounded by the ability of the LLM to output text in the desired language.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18566v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Karel Mundnich, Xing Niu, Prashant Mathur, Srikanth Ronanki, Brady Houston, Veera Raghavendra Elluru, Nilaksh Das, Zejiang Hou, Goeric Huybrechts, Anshu Bhatia, Daniel Garcia-Romero, Kyu J. Han, Katrin Kirchhoff</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Embedding Priors in Prompt-Tuning for Improved Interpretability and Control</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18582</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18582v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Prompt-Tuning is an efficient method for adapting pre-trained language models to new tasks with minimal computational overhead by modifying prompt embeddings. In this work, we investigate how crucial the phenomenon of embedding collapse, frequently observed in Prompt-Tuning, is for the final performance of the model. To address this question, we designed embedding priors and compared them with posteriors of the converged Soft and Deep Prompt-Tuning methods. Our findings suggest that priors strongly affect the position of the tuned embeddings, and models can effectively work with embeddings from different parts of activation spaces, including completely new regions. As the final Prompt-Tuning capabilities are limited, we hypothesize that controllable Prompt-Tuning posteriors may serve as a good starting point for tasks such as chain-of-thought (COT) distillation. Our experiments also show that generated trajectories are not localized in the activation space of the models. However, there are distinct clusters of activations for distant tasks (e.g., NLP and arithmetic), while activations between NLP tasks (e.g., Question-Answering and MLM) lie in the same cluster. These observations raise questions about the importance of a single activation cluster for the generalization abilities of large language models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18582v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sergey Sedov, Sumanth Bharadwaj Hachalli Karanam, Venu Gopal Kadamba</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long-Form Speech Generation with Spoken Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18603</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18603v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We consider the generative modeling of speech over multiple minutes, a requirement for long-form multimedia generation and audio-native voice assistants. However, current spoken language models struggle to generate plausible speech past tens of seconds, from high temporal resolution of speech tokens causing loss of coherence, to architectural issues with long-sequence training or extrapolation, to memory costs at inference time. With these considerations we propose SpeechSSM, the first speech language model to learn from and sample long-form spoken audio (e.g., 16 minutes of read or extemporaneous speech) in a single decoding session without text intermediates, based on recent advances in linear-time sequence modeling. Furthermore, to address growing challenges in spoken language evaluation, especially in this new long-form setting, we propose: new embedding-based and LLM-judged metrics; quality measurements over length and time; and a new benchmark for long-form speech processing and generation, LibriSpeech-Long. Speech samples and the dataset are released at https://google.github.io/tacotron/publications/speechssm/</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18603v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Se Jin Park, Julian Salazar, Aren Jansen, Keisuke Kinoshita, Yong Man Ro, RJ Skerry-Ryan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Language Model Safety: A Holistic Survey</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.17686</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.17686v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The rapid development and deployment of large language models (LLMs) have introduced a new frontier in artificial intelligence, marked by unprecedented capabilities in natural language understanding and generation. However, the increasing integration of these models into critical applications raises substantial safety concerns, necessitating a thorough examination of their potential risks and associated mitigation strategies.
  This survey provides a comprehensive overview of the current landscape of LLM safety, covering four major categories: value misalignment, robustness to adversarial attacks, misuse, and autonomous AI risks. In addition to the comprehensive review of the mitigation methodologies and evaluation resources on these four aspects, we further explore four topics related to LLM safety: the safety implications of LLM agents, the role of interpretability in enhancing LLM safety, the technology roadmaps proposed and abided by a list of AI companies and institutes for LLM safety, and AI governance aimed at LLM safety with discussions on international cooperation, policy proposals, and prospective regulatory directions.
  Our findings underscore the necessity for a proactive, multifaceted approach to LLM safety, emphasizing the integration of technical solutions, ethical considerations, and robust governance frameworks. This survey is intended to serve as a foundational resource for academy researchers, industry practitioners, and policymakers, offering insights into the challenges and opportunities associated with the safe integration of LLMs into society. Ultimately, it seeks to contribute to the safe and beneficial development of LLMs, aligning with the overarching goal of harnessing AI for societal advancement and well-being. A curated list of related papers has been publicly available at https://github.com/tjunlp-lab/Awesome-LLM-Safety-Papers.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.17686v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dan Shi, Tianhao Shen, Yufei Huang, Zhigen Li, Yongqi Leng, Renren Jin, Chuang Liu, Xinwei Wu, Zishan Guo, Linhao Yu, Ling Shi, Bojian Jiang, Deyi Xiong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ensemble Machine Learning Model for Inner Speech Recognition: A Subject-Specific Investigation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.17824</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.17824v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Inner speech recognition has gained enormous interest in recent years due to its applications in rehabilitation, developing assistive technology, and cognitive assessment. However, since language and speech productions are a complex process, for which identifying speech components has remained a challenging task. Different approaches were taken previously to reach this goal, but new approaches remain to be explored. Also, a subject-oriented analysis is necessary to understand the underlying brain dynamics during inner speech production, which can bring novel methods to neurological research. A publicly available dataset, Thinking Out Loud Dataset, has been used to develop a Machine Learning (ML)-based technique to classify inner speech using 128-channel surface EEG signals. The dataset is collected on a Spanish cohort of ten subjects while uttering four words (Arriba, Abajo, Derecha, and Izquierda) by each participant. Statistical methods were employed to detect and remove motion artifacts from the Electroencephalography (EEG) signals. A large number (191 per channel) of time-, frequency- and time-frequency-domain features were extracted. Eight feature selection algorithms are explored, and the best feature selection technique is selected for subsequent evaluations. The performance of six ML algorithms is evaluated, and an ensemble model is proposed. Deep Learning (DL) models are also explored, and the results are compared with the classical ML approach. The proposed ensemble model, by stacking the five best logistic regression models, generated an overall accuracy of 81.13% and an F1 score of 81.12% in the classification of four inner speech words using surface EEG signals. The proposed framework with the proposed ensemble of classical ML models shows promise in the classification of inner speech using surface EEG signals.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.17824v1</guid>
      <category>eess.SP</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shahamat Mustavi Tasin, Muhammad E. H. Chowdhury, Shona Pedersen, Malek Chabbouh, Diala Bushnaq, Raghad Aljindi, Saidul Kabir, Anwarul Hasan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the Data Provenance Gap Across Text, Speech and Video</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.17847</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.17847v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Progress in AI is driven largely by the scale and quality of training data. Despite this, there is a deficit of empirical analysis examining the attributes of well-established datasets beyond text. In this work we conduct the largest and first-of-its-kind longitudinal audit across modalities--popular text, speech, and video datasets--from their detailed sourcing trends and use restrictions to their geographical and linguistic representation. Our manual analysis covers nearly 4000 public datasets between 1990-2024, spanning 608 languages, 798 sources, 659 organizations, and 67 countries. We find that multimodal machine learning applications have overwhelmingly turned to web-crawled, synthetic, and social media platforms, such as YouTube, for their training sets, eclipsing all other sources since 2019. Secondly, tracing the chain of dataset derivations we find that while less than 33% of datasets are restrictively licensed, over 80% of the source content in widely-used text, speech, and video datasets, carry non-commercial restrictions. Finally, counter to the rising number of languages and geographies represented in public AI training datasets, our audit demonstrates measures of relative geographical and multilingual representation have failed to significantly improve their coverage since 2013. We believe the breadth of our audit enables us to empirically examine trends in data sourcing, restrictions, and Western-centricity at an ecosystem-level, and that visibility into these questions are essential to progress in responsible AI. As a contribution to ongoing improvements in dataset transparency and responsible use, we release our entire multimodal audit, allowing practitioners to trace data provenance across text, speech, and video.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.17847v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shayne Longpre, Nikhil Singh, Manuel Cherep, Kushagra Tiwary, Joanna Materzynska, William Brannon, Robert Mahari, Manan Dey, Mohammed Hamdy, Nayan Saxena, Ahmad Mustafa Anis, Emad A. Alghamdi, Vu Minh Chien, Naana Obeng-Marnu, Da Yin, Kun Qian, Yizhi Li, Minnie Liang, An Dinh, Shrestha Mohanty, Deividas Mataciunas, Tobin South, Jianguo Zhang, Ariel N. Lee, Campbell S. Lund, Christopher Klamm, Damien Sileo, Diganta Misra, Enrico Shippole, Kevin Klyman, Lester JV Miranda, Niklas Muennighoff, Seonghyeon Ye, Seungone Kim, Vipul Gupta, Vivek Sharma, Xuhui Zhou, Caiming Xiong, Luis Villa, Stella Biderman, Alex Pentland, Sara Hooker, Jad Kabbara</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Multimodal Emotion Recognition System: Integrating Facial Expressions, Body Movement, Speech, and Spoken Language</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.17907</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.17907v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Traditional psychological evaluations rely heavily on human observation and interpretation, which are prone to subjectivity, bias, fatigue, and inconsistency. To address these limitations, this work presents a multimodal emotion recognition system that provides a standardised, objective, and data-driven tool to support evaluators, such as psychologists, psychiatrists, and clinicians. The system integrates recognition of facial expressions, speech, spoken language, and body movement analysis to capture subtle emotional cues that are often overlooked in human evaluations. By combining these modalities, the system provides more robust and comprehensive emotional state assessment, reducing the risk of mis- and overdiagnosis. Preliminary testing in a simulated real-world condition demonstrates the system's potential to provide reliable emotional insights to improve the diagnostic accuracy. This work highlights the promise of automated multimodal analysis as a valuable complement to traditional psychological evaluation practices, with applications in clinical and therapeutic settings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.17907v1</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kris Kraack</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VITRO: Vocabulary Inversion for Time-series Representation Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.17921</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.17921v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Although LLMs have demonstrated remarkable capabilities in processing and generating textual data, their pre-trained vocabularies are ill-suited for capturing the nuanced temporal dynamics and patterns inherent in time series. The discrete, symbolic nature of natural language tokens, which these vocabularies are designed to represent, does not align well with the continuous, numerical nature of time series data. To address this fundamental limitation, we propose VITRO. Our method adapts textual inversion optimization from the vision-language domain in order to learn a new time series per-dataset vocabulary that bridges the gap between the discrete, semantic nature of natural language and the continuous, numerical nature of time series data. We show that learnable time series-specific pseudo-word embeddings represent time series data better than existing general language model vocabularies, with VITRO-enhanced methods achieving state-of-the-art performance in long-term forecasting across most datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.17921v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Filippos Bellos, Nam H. Nguyen, Jason J. Corso</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Constraints on the Expressive Power of $\mathsf{RoPE}$-based Tensor Attention Transformers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18040</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18040v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Tensor Attention extends traditional attention mechanisms by capturing high-order correlations across multiple modalities, addressing the limitations of classical matrix-based attention. Meanwhile, Rotary Position Embedding ($\mathsf{RoPE}$) has shown superior performance in encoding positional information in long-context scenarios, significantly enhancing transformer models' expressiveness. Despite these empirical successes, the theoretical limitations of these technologies remain underexplored. In this study, we analyze the circuit complexity of Tensor Attention and $\mathsf{RoPE}$-based Tensor Attention, showing that with polynomial precision, constant-depth layers, and linear or sublinear hidden dimension, they cannot solve fixed membership problems or $(A_{F,r})^*$ closure problems, under the assumption that $\mathsf{TC}^0 \neq \mathsf{NC}^1$. These findings highlight a gap between the empirical performance and theoretical constraints of Tensor Attention and $\mathsf{RoPE}$-based Tensor Attention Transformers, offering insights that could guide the development of more theoretically grounded approaches to Transformer model design and scaling.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18040v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CC</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoyu Li, Yingyu Liang, Zhenmei Shi, Zhao Song, Mingda Wan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emoji Retrieval from Gibberish or Garbled Social Media Text: A Novel Methodology and A Case Study</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18046</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18046v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Emojis are widely used across social media platforms but are often lost in noisy or garbled text, posing challenges for data analysis and machine learning. Conventional preprocessing approaches recommend removing such text, risking the loss of emojis and their contextual meaning. This paper proposes a three-step reverse-engineering methodology to retrieve emojis from garbled text in social media posts. The methodology also identifies reasons for the generation of such text during social media data mining. To evaluate its effectiveness, the approach was applied to 509,248 Tweets about the Mpox outbreak, a dataset referenced in about 30 prior works that failed to retrieve emojis from garbled text. Our method retrieved 157,748 emojis from 76,914 Tweets. Improvements in text readability and coherence were demonstrated through metrics such as Flesch Reading Ease, Flesch-Kincaid Grade Level, Coleman-Liau Index, Automated Readability Index, Dale-Chall Readability Score, Text Standard, and Reading Time. Additionally, the frequency of individual emojis and their patterns of usage in these Tweets were analyzed, and the results are presented.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18046v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shuqi Cui, Nirmalya Thakur, Audrey Poon</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lla-VAP: LSTM Ensemble of Llama and VAP for Turn-Taking Prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18061</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18061v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Turn-taking prediction is the task of anticipating when the speaker in a conversation will yield their turn to another speaker to begin speaking. This project expands on existing strategies for turn-taking prediction by employing a multi-modal ensemble approach that integrates large language models (LLMs) and voice activity projection (VAP) models. By combining the linguistic capabilities of LLMs with the temporal precision of VAP models, we aim to improve the accuracy and efficiency of identifying TRPs in both scripted and unscripted conversational scenarios. Our methods are evaluated on the In-Conversation Corpus (ICC) and Coached Conversational Preference Elicitation (CCPE) datasets, highlighting the strengths and limitations of current models while proposing a potentially more robust framework for enhanced prediction.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18061v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hyunbae Jeon, Frederic Guintu, Rayvant Sahni</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MMFactory: A Universal Solution Search Engine for Vision-Language Tasks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18072</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18072v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: With advances in foundational and vision-language models, and effective fine-tuning techniques, a large number of both general and special-purpose models have been developed for a variety of visual tasks. Despite the flexibility and accessibility of these models, no single model is able to handle all tasks and/or applications that may be envisioned by potential users. Recent approaches, such as visual programming and multimodal LLMs with integrated tools aim to tackle complex visual tasks, by way of program synthesis. However, such approaches overlook user constraints (e.g., performance / computational needs), produce test-time sample-specific solutions that are difficult to deploy, and, sometimes, require low-level instructions that maybe beyond the abilities of a naive user. To address these limitations, we introduce MMFactory, a universal framework that includes model and metrics routing components, acting like a solution search engine across various available models. Based on a task description and few sample input-output pairs and (optionally) resource and/or performance constraints, MMFactory can suggest a diverse pool of programmatic solutions by instantiating and combining visio-lingual tools from its model repository. In addition to synthesizing these solutions, MMFactory also proposes metrics and benchmarks performance / resource characteristics, allowing users to pick a solution that meets their unique design constraints. From the technical perspective, we also introduced a committee-based solution proposer that leverages multi-agent LLM conversation to generate executable, diverse, universal, and robust solutions for the user. Experimental results show that MMFactory outperforms existing methods by delivering state-of-the-art solutions tailored to user problem specifications. Project page is available at https://davidhalladay.github.io/mmfactory_demo.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18072v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wan-Cyuan Fan, Tanzila Rahman, Leonid Sigal</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generating Traffic Scenarios via In-Context Learning to Learn Better Motion Planner</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18086</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18086v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Motion planning is a crucial component in autonomous driving. State-of-the-art motion planners are trained on meticulously curated datasets, which are not only expensive to annotate but also insufficient in capturing rarely seen critical scenarios. Failing to account for such scenarios poses a significant risk to motion planners and may lead to incidents during testing. An intuitive solution is to manually compose such scenarios by programming and executing a simulator (e.g., CARLA). However, this approach incurs substantial human costs. Motivated by this, we propose an inexpensive method for generating diverse critical traffic scenarios to train more robust motion planners. First, we represent traffic scenarios as scripts, which are then used by the simulator to generate traffic scenarios. Next, we develop a method that accepts user-specified text descriptions, which a Large Language Model (LLM) translates into scripts using in-context learning. The output scripts are sent to the simulator that produces the corresponding traffic scenarios. As our method can generate abundant safety-critical traffic scenarios, we use them as synthetic training data for motion planners. To demonstrate the value of generated scenarios, we train existing motion planners on our synthetic data, real-world datasets, and a combination of both. Our experiments show that motion planners trained with our data significantly outperform those trained solely on real-world data, showing the usefulness of our synthetic data and the effectiveness of our data generation method. Our source code is available at https://ezharjan.github.io/AutoSceneGen.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18086v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aizierjiang Aiersilan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AEIOU: A Unified Defense Framework against NSFW Prompts in Text-to-Image Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18123</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18123v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: As text-to-image (T2I) models continue to advance and gain widespread adoption, their associated safety issues are becoming increasingly prominent. Malicious users often exploit these models to generate Not-Safe-for-Work (NSFW) images using harmful or adversarial prompts, highlighting the critical need for robust safeguards to ensure the integrity and compliance of model outputs. Current internal safeguards frequently degrade image quality, while external detection methods often suffer from low accuracy and inefficiency.
  In this paper, we introduce AEIOU, a defense framework that is Adaptable, Efficient, Interpretable, Optimizable, and Unified against NSFW prompts in T2I models. AEIOU extracts NSFW features from the hidden states of the model's text encoder, utilizing the separable nature of these features to detect NSFW prompts. The detection process is efficient, requiring minimal inference time. AEIOU also offers real-time interpretation of results and supports optimization through data augmentation techniques. The framework is versatile, accommodating various T2I architectures. Our extensive experiments show that AEIOU significantly outperforms both commercial and open-source moderation tools, achieving over 95% accuracy across all datasets and improving efficiency by at least tenfold. It effectively counters adaptive attacks and excels in few-shot and multi-label scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18123v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yiming Wang, Jiahao Chen, Qingming Li, Xing Yang, Shouling Ji</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are We in the AI-Generated Text World Already? Quantifying and Monitoring AIGT on Social Media</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18148</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18148v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Social media platforms are experiencing a growing presence of AI-Generated Texts (AIGTs). However, the misuse of AIGTs could have profound implications for public opinion, such as spreading misinformation and manipulating narratives. Despite its importance, a systematic study to assess the prevalence of AIGTs on social media is still lacking. To address this gap, this paper aims to quantify, monitor, and analyze the AIGTs on online social media platforms. We first collect a dataset (SM-D) with around 2.4M posts from 3 major social media platforms: Medium, Quora, and Reddit. Then, we construct a diverse dataset (AIGTBench) to train and evaluate AIGT detectors. AIGTBench combines popular open-source datasets and our AIGT datasets generated from social media texts by 12 LLMs, serving as a benchmark for evaluating mainstream detectors. With this setup, we identify the best-performing detector (OSM-Det). We then apply OSM-Det to SM-D to track AIGTs over time and observe different trends of AI Attribution Rate (AAR) across social media platforms from January 2022 to October 2024. Specifically, Medium and Quora exhibit marked increases in AAR, rising from 1.77% to 37.03% and 2.06% to 38.95%, respectively. In contrast, Reddit shows slower growth, with AAR increasing from 1.31% to 2.45% over the same period. Our further analysis indicates that AIGTs differ from human-written texts across several dimensions, including linguistic patterns, topic distributions, engagement levels, and the follower distribution of authors. We envision our analysis and findings on AIGTs in social media can shed light on future research in this domain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18148v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhen Sun, Zongmin Zhang, Xinyue Shen, Ziyi Zhang, Yule Liu, Michael Backes, Yang Zhang, Xinlei He</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GeneSUM: Large Language Model-based Gene Summary Extraction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18154</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18154v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Emerging topics in biomedical research are continuously expanding, providing a wealth of information about genes and their function. This rapid proliferation of knowledge presents unprecedented opportunities for scientific discovery and formidable challenges for researchers striving to keep abreast of the latest advancements. One significant challenge is navigating the vast corpus of literature to extract vital gene-related information, a time-consuming and cumbersome task. To enhance the efficiency of this process, it is crucial to address several key challenges: (1) the overwhelming volume of literature, (2) the complexity of gene functions, and (3) the automated integration and generation. In response, we propose GeneSUM, a two-stage automated gene summary extractor utilizing a large language model (LLM). Our approach retrieves and eliminates redundancy of target gene literature and then fine-tunes the LLM to refine and streamline the summarization process. We conducted extensive experiments to validate the efficacy of our proposed framework. The results demonstrate that LLM significantly enhances the integration of gene-specific information, allowing more efficient decision-making in ongoing research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18154v1</guid>
      <category>q-bio.GN</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhijian Chen, Chuan Hu, Min Wu, Qingqing Long, Xuezhi Wang, Yuanchun Zhou, Meng Xiao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>scReader: Prompting Large Language Models to Interpret scRNA-seq Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18156</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18156v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated remarkable advancements, primarily due to their capabilities in modeling the hidden relationships within text sequences. This innovation presents a unique opportunity in the field of life sciences, where vast collections of single-cell omics data from multiple species provide a foundation for training foundational models. However, the challenge lies in the disparity of data scales across different species, hindering the development of a comprehensive model for interpreting genetic data across diverse organisms. In this study, we propose an innovative hybrid approach that integrates the general knowledge capabilities of LLMs with domain-specific representation models for single-cell omics data interpretation. We begin by focusing on genes as the fundamental unit of representation. Gene representations are initialized using functional descriptions, leveraging the strengths of mature language models such as LLaMA-2. By inputting single-cell gene-level expression data with prompts, we effectively model cellular representations based on the differential expression levels of genes across various species and cell types. In the experiments, we constructed developmental cells from humans and mice, specifically targeting cells that are challenging to annotate. We evaluated our methodology through basic tasks such as cell annotation and visualization analysis. The results demonstrate the efficacy of our approach compared to other methods using LLMs, highlighting significant improvements in accuracy and interoperability. Our hybrid approach enhances the representation of single-cell data and offers a robust framework for future research in cross-species genetic analysis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18156v1</guid>
      <category>q-bio.GN</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Cong Li, Qingqing Long, Yuanchun Zhou, Meng Xiao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VLABench: A Large-Scale Benchmark for Language-Conditioned Robotics Manipulation with Long-Horizon Reasoning Tasks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18194</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18194v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: General-purposed embodied agents are designed to understand the users' natural instructions or intentions and act precisely to complete universal tasks. Recently, methods based on foundation models especially Vision-Language-Action models (VLAs) have shown a substantial potential to solve language-conditioned manipulation (LCM) tasks well. However, existing benchmarks do not adequately meet the needs of VLAs and relative algorithms. To better define such general-purpose tasks in the context of LLMs and advance the research in VLAs, we present VLABench, an open-source benchmark for evaluating universal LCM task learning. VLABench provides 100 carefully designed categories of tasks, with strong randomization in each category of task and a total of 2000+ objects. VLABench stands out from previous benchmarks in four key aspects: 1) tasks requiring world knowledge and common sense transfer, 2) natural language instructions with implicit human intentions rather than templates, 3) long-horizon tasks demanding multi-step reasoning, and 4) evaluation of both action policies and language model capabilities. The benchmark assesses multiple competencies including understanding of mesh\&amp;texture, spatial relationship, semantic instruction, physical laws, knowledge transfer and reasoning, etc. To support the downstream finetuning, we provide high-quality training data collected via an automated framework incorporating heuristic skills and prior information. The experimental results indicate that both the current state-of-the-art pretrained VLAs and the workflow based on VLMs face challenges in our tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18194v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shiduo Zhang, Zhe Xu, Peiju Liu, Xiaopeng Yu, Yuan Li, Qinghui Gao, Zhaoye Fei, Zhangyue Yin, Zuxuan Wu, Yu-Gang Jiang, Xipeng Qiu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICM-Assistant: Instruction-tuning Multimodal Large Language Models for Rule-based Explainable Image Content Moderation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18216</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18216v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Controversial contents largely inundate the Internet, infringing various cultural norms and child protection standards. Traditional Image Content Moderation (ICM) models fall short in producing precise moderation decisions for diverse standards, while recent multimodal large language models (MLLMs), when adopted to general rule-based ICM, often produce classification and explanation results that are inconsistent with human moderators. Aiming at flexible, explainable, and accurate ICM, we design a novel rule-based dataset generation pipeline, decomposing concise human-defined rules and leveraging well-designed multi-stage prompts to enrich short explicit image annotations. Our ICM-Instruct dataset includes detailed moderation explanation and moderation Q-A pairs. Built upon it, we create our ICM-Assistant model in the framework of rule-based ICM, making it readily applicable in real practice. Our ICM-Assistant model demonstrates exceptional performance and flexibility. Specifically, it significantly outperforms existing approaches on various sources, improving both the moderation classification (36.8\% on average) and moderation explanation quality (26.6\% on average) consistently over existing MLLMs. Code/Data is available at https://github.com/zhaoyuzhi/ICM-Assistant.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18216v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mengyang Wu, Yuzhi Zhao, Jialun Cao, Mingjie Xu, Zhongming Jiang, Xuehui Wang, Qinbin Li, Guangneng Hu, Shengchao Qin, Chi-Wing Fu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DeepCRCEval: Revisiting the Evaluation of Code Review Comment Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18291</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18291v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Code review is a vital but demanding aspect of software development, generating significant interest in automating review comments. Traditional evaluation methods for these comments, primarily based on text similarity, face two major challenges: inconsistent reliability of human-authored comments in open-source projects and the weak correlation of text similarity with objectives like enhancing code quality and detecting defects.
  This study empirically analyzes benchmark comments using a novel set of criteria informed by prior research and developer interviews. We then similarly revisit the evaluation of existing methodologies. Our evaluation framework, DeepCRCEval, integrates human evaluators and Large Language Models (LLMs) for a comprehensive reassessment of current techniques based on the criteria set. Besides, we also introduce an innovative and efficient baseline, LLM-Reviewer, leveraging the few-shot learning capabilities of LLMs for a target-oriented comparison.
  Our research highlights the limitations of text similarity metrics, finding that less than 10% of benchmark comments are high quality for automation. In contrast, DeepCRCEval effectively distinguishes between high and low-quality comments, proving to be a more reliable evaluation mechanism. Incorporating LLM evaluators into DeepCRCEval significantly boosts efficiency, reducing time and cost by 88.78% and 90.32%, respectively. Furthermore, LLM-Reviewer demonstrates significant potential of focusing task real targets in comment generation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18291v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junyi Lu, Xiaojia Li, Zihan Hua, Lei Yu, Shiqi Cheng, Li Yang, Fengjun Zhang, Chun Zuo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LongDocURL: a Comprehensive Multimodal Long Document Benchmark Integrating Understanding, Reasoning, and Locating</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18424</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18424v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large vision language models (LVLMs) have improved the document understanding capabilities remarkably, enabling the handling of complex document elements, longer contexts, and a wider range of tasks. However, existing document understanding benchmarks have been limited to handling only a small number of pages and fail to provide a comprehensive analysis of layout elements locating. In this paper, we first define three primary task categories: Long Document Understanding, numerical Reasoning, and cross-element Locating, and then propose a comprehensive benchmark, LongDocURL, integrating above three primary tasks and comprising 20 sub-tasks categorized based on different primary tasks and answer evidences. Furthermore, we develop a semi-automated construction pipeline and collect 2,325 high-quality question-answering pairs, covering more than 33,000 pages of documents, significantly outperforming existing benchmarks. Subsequently, we conduct comprehensive evaluation experiments on both open-source and closed-source models across 26 different configurations, revealing critical performance gaps in this field.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18424v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chao Deng, Jiale Yuan, Pi Bu, Peijie Wang, Zhong-Zhi Li, Jian Xu, Xiao-Hui Li, Yuan Gao, Jun Song, Bo Zheng, Cheng-Lin Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explainable Multi-Modal Data Exploration in Natural Language via LLM Agent</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18428</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18428v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: International enterprises, organizations, or hospitals collect large amounts of multi-modal data stored in databases, text documents, images, and videos. While there has been recent progress in the separate fields of multi-modal data exploration as well as in database systems that automatically translate natural language questions to database query languages, the research challenge of querying database systems combined with other unstructured modalities such as images in natural language is widely unexplored.
  In this paper, we propose XMODE - a system that enables explainable, multi-modal data exploration in natural language. Our approach is based on the following research contributions: (1) Our system is inspired by a real-world use case that enables users to explore multi-modal information systems. (2) XMODE leverages a LLM-based agentic AI framework to decompose a natural language question into subtasks such as text-to-SQL generation and image analysis. (3) Experimental results on multi-modal datasets over relational data and images demonstrate that our system outperforms state-of-the-art multi-modal exploration systems, excelling not only in accuracy but also in various performance metrics such as query latency, API costs, planning efficiency, and explanation quality, thanks to the more effective utilization of the reasoning capabilities of LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18428v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Farhad Nooralahzadeh, Yi Zhang, Jonathan Furst, Kurt Stockinger</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characterizations of Language Generation With Breadth</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18530</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18530v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We study language generation in the limit, introduced by Kleinberg and Mullainathan [KM24], building on classical works of Gold [Gol67] and Angluin [Ang79]. [KM24] proposed an algorithm that generates strings from any countable language collection in the limit. While their algorithm eventually outputs strings from the target language $K$, it sacrifices breadth, i.e., the ability to generate all strings in $K$. A key open question in [KM24] is whether this trade-off between consistency and breadth is inherrent.
  Recent works proposed different notions of consistent generation with breadth. Kalavasis, Mehrotra, and Velegkas [KVM24] introduced three definitions: generation with exact breadth, approximate breadth, and unambiguous generation. Concurrently and independently, Charikar and Pabbaraju [CP24a] proposed exhaustive generation. Both works examined when generation with these notions of breadth is possible.
  Building on [CP24a, KVM24], we fully characterize language generation for these notions and their natural combinations. For exact breadth, we provide an unconditional lower bound, removing a technical condition from [KVM24] and extending the result of [CP24a] that holds for specific collections of languages. We show that generation with exact breadth is characterized by Angluin's condition for identification. We further introduce a weaker version of Angluin's condition that tightly characterizes both approximate breadth and exhaustive generation, proving their equivalence. Additionally, we show that unambiguous generation is also characterized by Angluin's condition as a special case of a broader result. Finally, we strengthen [KVM24] by giving unconditional lower bounds for stable generators, showing that Angluin's condition characterizes the previous breadth notions for stable generators. This shows a separation between stable and unstable generation with approximate breadth.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18530v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.DS</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alkis Kalavasis, Anay Mehrotra, Grigoris Velegkas</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Consistency Checks for Language Model Forecasters</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18544</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18544v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Forecasting is a task that is difficult to evaluate: the ground truth can only be known in the future. Recent work showing LLM forecasters rapidly approaching human-level performance begs the question: how can we benchmark and evaluate these forecasters instantaneously? Following the consistency check framework, we measure the performance of forecasters in terms of the consistency of their predictions on different logically-related questions. We propose a new, general consistency metric based on arbitrage: for example, if a forecasting AI illogically predicts that both the Democratic and Republican parties have 60% probability of winning the 2024 US presidential election, an arbitrageur can trade against the forecaster's predictions and make a profit. We build an automated evaluation system that generates a set of base questions, instantiates consistency checks from these questions, elicits the predictions of the forecaster, and measures the consistency of the predictions. We then build a standard, proper-scoring-rule forecasting benchmark, and show that our (instantaneous) consistency metrics correlate with LLM forecasters' ground truth Brier scores (which are only known in the future). We also release a consistency benchmark that resolves in 2028, providing a long-term evaluation tool for forecasting.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18544v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Daniel Paleka, Abhimanyu Pallavi Sudhir, Alejandro Alvarez, Vineeth Bhat, Adam Shen, Evan Wang, Florian Tram\`er</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Well Do LLMs Generate Code for Different Application Domains? Benchmark and Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18573</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18573v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recently, an increasing number of AI-driven programming assistants powered by code LLMs have been integrated into various real-world software development environments, significantly boosting developer productivity. However, existing code generation benchmarks primarily focus on general-purpose scenarios, leaving the code generation performance of LLMs for specific application domains largely unknown. In this paper, we introduce a new benchmark, MultiCodeBench, to fill this gap. MultiCodeBench comprises 2,400 programming tasks, covering 12 popular software development domains and 15 programming languages. Specifically, we perform in-depth research to identify these 12 application domains. Given that each domain may involve multiple technical frameworks, and that different frameworks present distinct challenges in the coding process, we categorize the commonly used frameworks and platforms within each domain. We then sample programming problems from GitHub repositories related to these subdomains. To ensure the quality of the tasks and mitigate data leakage issues, we invite annotators to rewrite the docstrings for each task in MultiCodeBench. Additionally, we build a static analysis-based dependency parsing tool to extract the dependencies in the ground truth for each task, enabling deeper performance analysis. Through extensive experiments on MultiCodeBench with eleven representative mainstream LLMs, we reveal the code generation performance of the LLMs across different application domains, providing practical insights for developers in downstream fields when selecting LLMs. Furthermore, we analyze the reasons behind the models' failures in completing software application development tasks, offering guidance for model developers to enhance domain-specific code generation capabilities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18573v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dewu Zheng, Yanlin Wang, Ensheng Shi, Hongyu Zhang, Zibin Zheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting Jailbreaking for Large Language Models: A Representation Engineering Perspective</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.06824</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.06824v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The recent surge in jailbreaking attacks has revealed significant vulnerabilities in Large Language Models (LLMs) when exposed to malicious inputs. While various defense strategies have been proposed to mitigate these threats, there has been limited research into the underlying mechanisms that make LLMs vulnerable to such attacks. In this study, we suggest that the self-safeguarding capability of LLMs is linked to specific activity patterns within their representation space. Although these patterns have little impact on the semantic content of the generated text, they play a crucial role in shaping LLM behavior under jailbreaking attacks. Our findings demonstrate that these patterns can be detected with just a few pairs of contrastive queries. Extensive experimentation shows that the robustness of LLMs against jailbreaking can be manipulated by weakening or strengthening these patterns. Further visual analysis provides additional evidence for our conclusions, providing new insights into the jailbreaking phenomenon. These findings highlight the importance of addressing the potential misuse of open-source LLMs within the community.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.06824v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tianlong Li, Zhenghua Wang, Wenhao Liu, Muling Wu, Shihan Dou, Changze Lv, Xiaohua Wang, Xiaoqing Zheng, Xuanjing Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AgentBoard: An Analytical Evaluation Board of Multi-turn LLM Agents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.13178</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.13178v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Evaluating Large Language Models (LLMs) as general-purpose agents is essential for understanding their capabilities and facilitating their integration into practical applications. However, the evaluation process presents substantial challenges. A primary obstacle is the benchmarking of agent performance across diverse scenarios within a unified framework, especially in maintaining partially-observable environments and ensuring multi-round interactions. Moreover, current evaluation frameworks mostly focus on the final success rate, revealing few insights during the process and failing to provide a deep understanding of the model abilities. To address these challenges, we introduce AgentBoard, a pioneering comprehensive benchmark and accompanied open-source evaluation framework tailored to analytical evaluation of LLM agents. AgentBoard offers a fine-grained progress rate metric that captures incremental advancements as well as a comprehensive evaluation toolkit that features easy assessment of agents for multi-faceted analysis. This not only sheds light on the capabilities and limitations of LLM agents but also propels the interpretability of their performance to the forefront. Ultimately, AgentBoard serves as a step towards demystifying agent behaviors and accelerating the development of stronger LLM agents.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.13178v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chang Ma, Junlei Zhang, Zhihao Zhu, Cheng Yang, Yujiu Yang, Yaohui Jin, Zhenzhong Lan, Lingpeng Kong, Junxian He</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Counting-Stars: A Multi-evidence, Position-aware, and Scalable Benchmark for Evaluating Long-Context Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.11802</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.11802v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Despite recent efforts to develop large language models with robust long-context capabilities, the lack of long-context benchmarks means that relatively little is known about their performance. To alleviate this gap, in this paper, we propose \textbf{Counting-Stars}, a multi-evidence, position-aware, and scalable benchmark designed to evaluate the multi-evidence retrieval capabilities of long-context LLMs. \textbf{Counting-Stars} comprises two counting-based multiple pieces of evidence retrieval sub-tasks: searching and reasoning. Using Counting-Stars, we conduct experiments to evaluate several long-context LLMs, including GPT-4 Turbo, Gemini 1.5 Pro, Claude3 Opus, GLM-4, and Moonshot-v1. Extensive experimental results demonstrate that Gemini 1.5 Pro achieves the best overall results, while GPT-4 Turbo exhibits the most stable performance across various tasks. Furthermore, our analysis of these LLMs, which have been extended to handle long-context scenarios, indicates that significant room for improvement remains as the length of the input context and the complexity of the tasks increase.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.11802v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mingyang Song, Mao Zheng, Xuan Luo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BEADs: Bias Evaluation Across Domains</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.04220</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.04220v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advancements in large language models (LLMs) have greatly enhanced natural language processing (NLP) applications. Nevertheless, these models often inherit biases from their training data. Despite the availability of various datasets for bias detection, most are limited to one or two NLP tasks (typically classification or evaluation) and lack comprehensive evaluations across a broader range of NLP tasks. To address this gap, we introduce the Bias Evaluations Across Domains BEADs dataset, designed to support a wide array of NLP tasks, including text classification, token classification, bias quantification, and benign language generation. A key focus of this paper is the gold label dataset that is annotated by GPT4 for scalabilty and verified by experts to ensure high reliability. BEADs provides data for both fine-tuning, including classification and language generation tasks, and for evaluating LLMs. Our findings indicate that BEADs effectively identifies numerous biases when fine-tuned on this dataset. It also reduces biases when used for fine-tuning language generation task, while preserving language quality. The results also reveal some prevalent demographic biases in LLMs when BEADs is used for evaluation in demographic task. We provide the BEADs dataset for detecting biases in various domains, and this dataset is readily usable for responsible AI development and application. The dataset can be accessed at https://huggingface.co/datasets/shainar/BEAD .</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.04220v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shaina Raza, Mizanur Rahman, Michael R. Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Attacks on LLM-based Code Completion Tools</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11006</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11006v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The rapid development of large language models (LLMs) has significantly advanced code completion capabilities, giving rise to a new generation of LLM-based Code Completion Tools (LCCTs). Unlike general-purpose LLMs, these tools possess unique workflows, integrating multiple information sources as input and prioritizing code suggestions over natural language interaction, which introduces distinct security challenges. Additionally, LCCTs often rely on proprietary code datasets for training, raising concerns about the potential exposure of sensitive data. This paper exploits these distinct characteristics of LCCTs to develop targeted attack methodologies on two critical security risks: jailbreaking and training data extraction attacks. Our experimental results expose significant vulnerabilities within LCCTs, including a 99.4% success rate in jailbreaking attacks on GitHub Copilot and a 46.3% success rate on Amazon Q. Furthermore, We successfully extracted sensitive user data from GitHub Copilot, including 54 real email addresses and 314 physical addresses associated with GitHub usernames. Our study also demonstrates that these code-based attack methods are effective against general-purpose LLMs, such as the GPT series, highlighting a broader security misalignment in the handling of code by modern LLMs. These findings underscore critical security challenges associated with LCCTs and suggest essential directions for strengthening their security frameworks. The example code and attack samples from our research are provided at https://github.com/Sensente/Security-Attacks-on-LCCTs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11006v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wen Cheng, Ke Sun, Xinyu Zhang, Wei Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SpikingSSMs: Learning Long Sequences with Sparse and Parallel Spiking State Space Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14909</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14909v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Known as low energy consumption networks, spiking neural networks (SNNs) have gained a lot of attention within the past decades. While SNNs are increasing competitive with artificial neural networks (ANNs) for vision tasks, they are rarely used for long sequence tasks, despite their intrinsic temporal dynamics. In this work, we develop spiking state space models (SpikingSSMs) for long sequence learning by leveraging on the sequence learning abilities of state space models (SSMs). Inspired by dendritic neuron structure, we hierarchically integrate neuronal dynamics with the original SSM block, meanwhile realizing sparse synaptic computation. Furthermore, to solve the conflict of event-driven neuronal dynamics with parallel computing, we propose a light-weight surrogate dynamic network which accurately predicts the after-reset membrane potential and compatible to learnable thresholds, enabling orders of acceleration in training speed compared with conventional iterative methods. On the long range arena benchmark task, SpikingSSM achieves competitive performance to state-of-the-art SSMs meanwhile realizing on average 90\% of network sparsity. On language modeling, our network significantly surpasses existing spiking large language models (spikingLLMs) on the WikiText-103 dataset with only a third of the model size, demonstrating its potential as backbone architecture for low computation cost LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14909v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.NE</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shuaijie Shen, Chao Wang, Renzhuo Huang, Yan Zhong, Qinghai Guo, Zhichao Lu, Jianguo Zhang, Luziwei Leng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM-GAN: Construct Generative Adversarial Network Through Large Language Models For Explainable Fake News Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.01787</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.01787v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Explainable fake news detection predicts the authenticity of news items with annotated explanations. Today, Large Language Models (LLMs) are known for their powerful natural language understanding and explanation generation abilities. However, presenting LLMs for explainable fake news detection remains two main challenges. Firstly, fake news appears reasonable and could easily mislead LLMs, leaving them unable to understand the complex news-faking process. Secondly, utilizing LLMs for this task would generate both correct and incorrect explanations, which necessitates abundant labor in the loop. In this paper, we propose LLM-GAN, a novel framework that utilizes prompting mechanisms to enable an LLM to become Generator and Detector and for realistic fake news generation and detection. Our results demonstrate LLM-GAN's effectiveness in both prediction performance and explanation quality. We further showcase the integration of LLM-GAN to a cloud-native AI platform to provide better fake news detection service in the cloud.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.01787v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yifeng Wang, Zhouhong Gu, Siwei Zhang, Suhang Zheng, Tao Wang, Tianyu Li, Hongwei Feng, Yanghua Xiao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TableRAG: Million-Token Table Understanding with Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.04739</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.04739v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advancements in language models (LMs) have notably enhanced their ability to reason with tabular data, primarily through program-aided mechanisms that manipulate and analyze tables. However, these methods often require the entire table as input, leading to scalability challenges due to the positional bias or context length constraints. In response to these challenges, we introduce TableRAG, a Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) framework specifically designed for LM-based table understanding. TableRAG leverages query expansion combined with schema and cell retrieval to pinpoint crucial information before providing it to the LMs. This enables more efficient data encoding and precise retrieval, significantly reducing prompt lengths and mitigating information loss. We have developed two new million-token benchmarks from the Arcade and BIRD-SQL datasets to thoroughly evaluate TableRAG's effectiveness at scale. Our results demonstrate that TableRAG's retrieval design achieves the highest retrieval quality, leading to the new state-of-the-art performance on large-scale table understanding.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.04739v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Si-An Chen, Lesly Miculicich, Julian Martin Eisenschlos, Zifeng Wang, Zilong Wang, Yanfei Chen, Yasuhisa Fujii, Hsuan-Tien Lin, Chen-Yu Lee, Tomas Pfister</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Listening to Patients: A Framework of Detecting and Mitigating Patient Misreport for Medical Dialogue Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.06094</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.06094v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Medical Dialogue Systems aim to provide automated healthcare support through patient-agent conversations. Previous efforts typically regard patients as ideal users -- one who accurately and consistently reports their health conditions. However, in reality, patients often misreport their symptoms, leading to discrepancies between their reports and actual health conditions. Overlooking patient misreport will affect the quality of healthcare consultations provided by MDS. To address this issue, we argue that MDS should ''listen to patients'' and tackle two key challenges: how to detect and mitigate patient misreport effectively. In this work, we propose PaMis, a framework of detecting and mitigating Patient Misreport for medical dialogue generation. PaMis first constructs dialogue entity graphs, then detects patient misreport based on graph entropy, and mitigates patient misreport by formulating clarifying questions. Experiments indicate that PaMis effectively enhances medical response generation, enabling models like GPT-4 to detect and mitigate patient misreports, and provide high-quality healthcare assistance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.06094v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lang Qin, Yao Zhang, Hongru Liang, Adam Jatowt, Zhenglu Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Omni-MATH: A Universal Olympiad Level Mathematic Benchmark For Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.07985</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.07985v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advancements in large language models (LLMs) have led to significant breakthroughs in mathematical reasoning capabilities. However, existing benchmarks like GSM8K or MATH are now being solved with high accuracy (e.g., OpenAI o1 achieves 94.8\% on MATH dataset), indicating their inadequacy for truly challenging these models. To bridge this gap, we propose a comprehensive and challenging benchmark specifically designed to assess LLMs' mathematical reasoning at the Olympiad level. Unlike existing Olympiad-related benchmarks, our dataset focuses exclusively on mathematics and comprises a vast collection of 4428 competition-level problems with rigorous human annotation. These problems are meticulously categorized into over 33 sub-domains and span more than 10 distinct difficulty levels, enabling a holistic assessment of model performance in Olympiad-mathematical reasoning. Furthermore, we conducted an in-depth analysis based on this benchmark. Our experimental results show that even the most advanced models, OpenAI o1-mini and OpenAI o1-preview, struggle with highly challenging Olympiad-level problems, with 60.54\% and 52.55\% accuracy, highlighting significant challenges in Olympiad-level mathematical reasoning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.07985v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bofei Gao, Feifan Song, Zhe Yang, Zefan Cai, Yibo Miao, Qingxiu Dong, Lei Li, Chenghao Ma, Liang Chen, Runxin Xu, Zhengyang Tang, Benyou Wang, Daoguang Zan, Shanghaoran Quan, Ge Zhang, Lei Sha, Yichang Zhang, Xuancheng Ren, Tianyu Liu, Baobao Chang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Navigating the Cultural Kaleidoscope: A Hitchhiker's Guide to Sensitivity in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.12880</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.12880v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: As LLMs are increasingly deployed in global applications, the importance of cultural sensitivity becomes paramount, ensuring that users from diverse backgrounds feel respected and understood. Cultural harm can arise when these models fail to align with specific cultural norms, resulting in misrepresentations or violations of cultural values. This work addresses the challenges of ensuring cultural sensitivity in LLMs, especially in small-parameter models that often lack the extensive training data needed to capture global cultural nuances. We present two key contributions: (1) A cultural harm test dataset, created to assess model outputs across different cultural contexts through scenarios that expose potential cultural insensitivities, and (2) A culturally aligned preference dataset, aimed at restoring cultural sensitivity through fine-tuning based on feedback from diverse annotators. These datasets facilitate the evaluation and enhancement of LLMs, ensuring their ethical and safe deployment across different cultural landscapes. Our results show that integrating culturally aligned feedback leads to a marked improvement in model behavior, significantly reducing the likelihood of generating culturally insensitive or harmful content. Ultimately, this work paves the way for more inclusive and respectful AI systems, fostering a future where LLMs can safely and ethically navigate the complexities of diverse cultural landscapes.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.12880v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Somnath Banerjee, Sayan Layek, Hari Shrawgi, Rajarshi Mandal, Avik Halder, Shanu Kumar, Sagnik Basu, Parag Agrawal, Rima Hazra, Animesh Mukherjee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the loss of context-awareness in general instruction fine-tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.02688</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.02688v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Pre-trained Large Language Models (LLMs) require post-training methods such as supervised fine-tuning (SFT) on instruction-response pairs to enable instruction following. However, this process can potentially harm existing capabilities learned during pre-training. In this paper, we investigate the loss of context awareness after SFT, where context awareness is defined as the ability to extract and understand information from user-provided context and respond accordingly. We are the first to identify and show that the loss of context awareness, as reflected by the performance drop in the Needle-in-a-Haystack test, occurs in instruction fine-tuned LLMs when the chat template is applied to input prompts. We identify that the performance decline is partially caused by an attention bias toward different roles learned during conversational instruction fine-tuning. We validate our hypothesis by visualizing changes in attention allocation after the chat template is applied and manually steering the attention heads. Based on these observations, we propose a metric to select context-dependent examples from general instruction fine-tuning datasets. We then apply conditional instruction fine-tuning with a context-dependency indicator, enabling the model to learn context awareness from these selected examples. Empirical experiments on four context-dependent downstream tasks and three pre-trained LLMs of different sizes show that our method effectively mitigates the loss of context awareness without compromising general instruction-following capabilities. Given our findings, we strongly advocate for careful benchmarking of context awareness after instruction fine-tuning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.02688v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yihan Wang, Andrew Bai, Nanyun Peng, Cho-Jui Hsieh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UniHR: Hierarchical Representation Learning for Unified Knowledge Graph Link Prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.07019</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.07019v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Beyond-triple fact representations including hyper-relational facts with auxiliary key-value pairs, temporal facts with additional timestamps, and nested facts implying relationships between facts, are gaining significant attention. However, existing link prediction models are usually designed for one specific type of facts, making it difficult to generalize to other fact representations. To overcome this limitation, we propose a Unified Hierarchical Representation learning framework (UniHR) for unified knowledge graph link prediction. It consists of a unified Hierarchical Data Representation (HiDR) module and a unified Hierarchical Structure Learning (HiSL) module as graph encoder. The HiDR module unifies hyper-relational KGs, temporal KGs, and nested factual KGs into triple-based representations. Then HiSL incorporates intra-fact and inter-fact message passing, focusing on enhancing the semantic information within individual facts and enriching the structural information between facts. Experimental results across 7 datasets from 3 types of KGs demonstrate that our UniHR outperforms baselines designed for one specific kind of KG, indicating strong generalization capability of HiDR form and the effectiveness of HiSL module. Code and data are available at https://github.com/Lza12a/UniHR.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.07019v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhiqiang Liu, Mingyang Chen, Yin Hua, Zhuo Chen, Ziqi Liu, Lei Liang, Huajun Chen, Wen Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM for Barcodes: Generating Diverse Synthetic Data for Identity Documents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.14962</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.14962v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Accurate barcode detection and decoding in Identity documents is crucial for applications like security, healthcare, and education, where reliable data extraction and verification are essential. However, building robust detection models is challenging due to the lack of diverse, realistic datasets an issue often tied to privacy concerns and the wide variety of document formats. Traditional tools like Faker rely on predefined templates, making them less effective for capturing the complexity of real-world identity documents. In this paper, we introduce a new approach to synthetic data generation that uses LLMs to create contextually rich and realistic data without relying on predefined field. Using the vast knowledge LLMs have about different documents and content, our method creates data that reflects the variety found in real identity documents. This data is then encoded into barcode and overlayed on templates for documents such as Driver's licenses, Insurance cards, Student IDs. Our approach simplifies the process of dataset creation, eliminating the need for extensive domain knowledge or predefined fields. Compared to traditional methods like Faker, data generated by LLM demonstrates greater diversity and contextual relevance, leading to improved performance in barcode detection models. This scalable, privacy-first solution is a big step forward in advancing machine learning for automated document processing and identity verification.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.14962v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hitesh Laxmichand Patel, Amit Agarwal, Bhargava Kumar, Karan Gupta, Priyaranjan Pattnayak</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TSCheater: Generating High-Quality Tibetan Adversarial Texts via Visual Similarity</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02371</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02371v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Language models based on deep neural networks are vulnerable to textual adversarial attacks. While rich-resource languages like English are receiving focused attention, Tibetan, a cross-border language, is gradually being studied due to its abundant ancient literature and critical language strategy. Currently, there are several Tibetan adversarial text generation methods, but they do not fully consider the textual features of Tibetan script and overestimate the quality of generated adversarial texts. To address this issue, we propose a novel Tibetan adversarial text generation method called TSCheater, which considers the characteristic of Tibetan encoding and the feature that visually similar syllables have similar semantics. This method can also be transferred to other abugidas, such as Devanagari script. We utilize a self-constructed Tibetan syllable visual similarity database called TSVSDB to generate substitution candidates and adopt a greedy algorithm-based scoring mechanism to determine substitution order. After that, we conduct the method on eight victim language models. Experimentally, TSCheater outperforms existing methods in attack effectiveness, perturbation magnitude, semantic similarity, visual similarity, and human acceptance. Finally, we construct the first Tibetan adversarial robustness evaluation benchmark called AdvTS, which is generated by existing methods and proofread by humans.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02371v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xi Cao, Quzong Gesang, Yuan Sun, Nuo Qun, Tashi Nyima</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steps are all you need: Rethinking STEM Education with Prompt Engineering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.05023</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.05023v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Few shot and Chain-of-Thought prompting have shown promise when applied to Physics Question Answering Tasks, but are limited by the lack of mathematical ability inherent to LLMs, and are prone to hallucination. By utilizing a Mixture of Experts (MoE) Model, along with analogical prompting, we are able to show improved model performance when compared to the baseline on standard LLMs. We also survey the limits of these prompting techniques and the effects they have on model performance. Additionally, we propose Analogical CoT prompting, a prompting technique designed to allow smaller, open source models to leverage Analogical prompting, something they have struggled with, possibly due to a lack of specialist training data.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.05023v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Krishnasai Addala, Kabir Dev Paul Baghel, Chhavi Kirtani, Avinash Anand, Rajiv Ratn Shah</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Graphs are all you need: Leveraging KGs in Physics Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.05453</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.05453v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This study explores the effectiveness of using knowledge graphs generated by large language models to decompose high school-level physics questions into sub-questions. We introduce a pipeline aimed at enhancing model response quality for Question Answering tasks. By employing LLMs to construct knowledge graphs that capture the internal logic of the questions, these graphs then guide the generation of subquestions. We hypothesize that this method yields sub-questions that are more logically consistent with the original questions compared to traditional decomposition techniques. Our results show that sub-questions derived from knowledge graphs exhibit significantly improved fidelity to the original question's logic. This approach not only enhances the learning experience by providing clearer and more contextually appropriate sub-questions but also highlights the potential of LLMs to transform educational methodologies. The findings indicate a promising direction for applying AI to improve the quality and effectiveness of educational content.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.05453v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Krishnasai Addala, Kabir Dev Paul Baghel, Dhruv Jain, Chhavi Kirtani, Avinash Anand, Rajiv Ratn Shah</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improvement in Sign Language Translation Using Text CTC Alignment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09014</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09014v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Current sign language translation (SLT) approaches often rely on gloss-based supervision with Connectionist Temporal Classification (CTC), limiting their ability to handle non-monotonic alignments between sign language video and spoken text. In this work, we propose a novel method combining joint CTC/Attention and transfer learning. The joint CTC/Attention introduces hierarchical encoding and integrates CTC with the attention mechanism during decoding, effectively managing both monotonic and non-monotonic alignments. Meanwhile, transfer learning helps bridge the modality gap between vision and language in SLT. Experimental results on two widely adopted benchmarks, RWTH-PHOENIX-Weather 2014 T and CSL-Daily, show that our method achieves results comparable to state-of-the-art and outperforms the pure-attention baseline. Additionally, this work opens a new door for future research into gloss-free SLT using text-based CTC alignment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09014v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sihan Tan, Taro Miyazaki, Nabeela Khan, Kazuhiro Nakadai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tokens, the oft-overlooked appetizer: Large language models, the distributional hypothesis, and meaning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10924</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10924v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Tokenization is a necessary component within the current architecture of many language models, including the transformer-based large language models (LLMs) of Generative AI, yet its impact on the model's cognition is often overlooked. We argue that LLMs demonstrate that the Distributional Hypothesis (DH) is sufficient for reasonably human-like language performance, and that the emergence of human-meaningful linguistic units among tokens motivates linguistically-informed interventions in existing, linguistically-agnostic tokenization techniques, particularly with respect to their roles as (1) semantic primitives and as (2) vehicles for conveying salient distributional patterns from human language to the model. We explore tokenizations from a BPE tokenizer; extant model vocabularies obtained from Hugging Face and tiktoken; and the information in exemplar token vectors as they move through the layers of a RoBERTa (large) model. Besides creating sub-optimal semantic building blocks and obscuring the model's access to the necessary distributional patterns, we describe how tokenization pretraining can be a backdoor for bias and other unwanted content, which current alignment practices may not remediate. Additionally, we relay evidence that the tokenization algorithm's objective function impacts the LLM's cognition, despite being meaningfully insulated from the main system intelligence.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10924v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Julia Witte Zimmerman, Denis Hudon, Kathryn Cramer, Alejandro J. Ruiz, Calla Beauregard, Ashley Fehr, Mikaela Irene Fudolig, Bradford Demarest, Yoshi Meke Bird, Milo Z. Trujillo, Christopher M. Danforth, Peter Sheridan Dodds</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MiMoTable: A Multi-scale Spreadsheet Benchmark with Meta Operations for Table Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.11711</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.11711v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Extensive research has been conducted to explore the capability of Large Language Models (LLMs) for table reasoning and has significantly improved the performance on existing benchmarks. However, tables and user questions in real-world applications are more complex and diverse, presenting an unignorable gap compared to the existing benchmarks. To fill the gap, we propose a \textbf{M}ult\textbf{i}-scale spreadsheet benchmark with \textbf{M}eta \textbf{o}perations for \textbf{Table} reasoning, named as MiMoTable. Specifically, MiMoTable incorporates two key features. First, the tables in MiMoTable are all spreadsheets used in real-world scenarios, which cover seven domains and contain different types. Second, we define a new criterion with six categories of meta operations for measuring the difficulty of each question in MiMoTable, simultaneously as a new perspective for measuring the difficulty of the existing benchmarks. Experimental results show that Claude-3.5-Sonnet achieves the best performance with 77.4\% accuracy, indicating that there is still significant room to improve for LLMs on MiMoTable. Furthermore, we grade the difficulty of existing benchmarks according to our new criteria. Experiments have shown that the performance of LLMs decreases as the difficulty of benchmarks increases, thereby proving the effectiveness of our proposed new criterion.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.11711v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zheng Li, Yang Du, Mao Zheng, Mingyang Song</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Zero-Shot Multilingual Aspect-Based Sentiment Analysis with Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.12564</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.12564v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Aspect-based sentiment analysis (ABSA), a sequence labeling task, has attracted increasing attention in multilingual contexts. While previous research has focused largely on fine-tuning or training models specifically for ABSA, we evaluate large language models (LLMs) under zero-shot conditions to explore their potential to tackle this challenge with minimal task-specific adaptation. We conduct a comprehensive empirical evaluation of a series of LLMs on multilingual ABSA tasks, investigating various prompting strategies, including vanilla zero-shot, chain-of-thought (CoT), self-improvement, self-debate, and self-consistency, across nine different models. Results indicate that while LLMs show promise in handling multilingual ABSA, they generally fall short of fine-tuned, task-specific models. Notably, simpler zero-shot prompts often outperform more complex strategies, especially in high-resource languages like English. These findings underscore the need for further refinement of LLM-based approaches to effectively address ABSA task across diverse languages.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.12564v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chengyan Wu, Bolei Ma, Zheyu Zhang, Ningyuan Deng, Yanqing He, Yun Xue</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memorization Over Reasoning? Exposing and Mitigating Verbatim Memorization in Large Language Models' Character Understanding Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.14368</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.14368v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recently, Large Language Models (LLMs) have shown impressive performance in character understanding tasks, such as analyzing the roles, personalities, and relationships of fictional characters. However, the extensive pre-training corpora used by LLMs raise concerns that they may rely on memorizing popular fictional works rather than genuinely understanding and reasoning about them. In this work, we argue that 'gist memory'-capturing essential meaning - should be the primary mechanism for character understanding tasks, as opposed to 'verbatim memory' - exact match of a string. We introduce a simple yet effective method to mitigate mechanized memorization in character understanding evaluations while preserving the essential implicit cues needed for comprehension and reasoning. Our approach reduces memorization-driven performance on popular fictional works from 96% accuracy to 72% and results in up to an 18% drop in accuracy across various character understanding tasks. These findings underscore the issue of data contamination in existing benchmarks, which often measure memorization rather than true character understanding.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.14368v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuxuan Jiang, Francis Ferraro</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing LLM-based Hatred and Toxicity Detection with Meta-Toxic Knowledge Graph</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.15268</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.15268v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The rapid growth of social media platforms has raised significant concerns regarding online content toxicity. When Large Language Models (LLMs) are used for toxicity detection, two key challenges emerge: 1) the absence of domain-specific toxic knowledge leads to false negatives; 2) the excessive sensitivity of LLMs to toxic speech results in false positives, limiting freedom of speech. To address these issues, we propose a novel method called MetaTox, leveraging graph search on a meta-toxic knowledge graph to enhance hatred and toxicity detection. First, we construct a comprehensive meta-toxic knowledge graph by utilizing LLMs to extract toxic information through a three-step pipeline, with toxic benchmark datasets serving as corpora. Second, we query the graph via retrieval and ranking processes to supplement accurate, relevant toxic knowledge. Extensive experiments and in-depth case studies across multiple datasets demonstrate that our MetaTox significantly decreases the false positive rate while boosting overall toxicity detection performance. Our code will be available soon.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.15268v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yibo Zhao, Jiapeng Zhu, Can Xu, Xiang Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Review of the Marathi Natural Language Processing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.15471</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.15471v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Marathi is one of the most widely used languages in the world. One might expect that the latest advances in NLP research in languages like English reach such a large community. However, NLP advancements in English didn't immediately reach Indian languages like Marathi. There were several reasons for this. They included diversity of scripts used, lack of (publicly available) resources like tokenization strategies, high quality datasets \&amp; benchmarks, and evaluation metrics. In addition to this, the morphologically rich nature of Marathi, made NLP tasks challenging. Advances in Neural Network (NN) based models and tools since the early 2000s helped improve this situation and make NLP research more accessible. In the past 10 years, significant efforts were made to improve language resources for all 22 scheduled languages of India. This paper presents a broad overview of evolution of NLP research in Indic languages with a focus on Marathi and state-of-the-art resources and tools available to the research community. It also provides an overview of tools \&amp; techniques associated with Marathi NLP tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.15471v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Asang Dani, Shailesh R Sathe</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XRAG: eXamining the Core -- Benchmarking Foundational Components in Advanced Retrieval-Augmented Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.15529</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.15529v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) synergizes the retrieval of pertinent data with the generative capabilities of Large Language Models (LLMs), ensuring that the generated output is not only contextually relevant but also accurate and current. We introduce XRAG, an open-source, modular codebase that facilitates exhaustive evaluation of the performance of foundational components of advanced RAG modules. These components are systematically categorized into four core phases: pre-retrieval, retrieval, post-retrieval, and generation. We systematically analyse them across reconfigured datasets, providing a comprehensive benchmark for their effectiveness. As the complexity of RAG systems continues to escalate, we underscore the critical need to identify potential failure points in RAG systems. We formulate a suite of experimental methodologies and diagnostic testing protocols to dissect the failure points inherent in RAG engineering. Subsequently, we proffer bespoke solutions aimed at bolstering the overall performance of these modules. Our work thoroughly evaluates the performance of advanced core components in RAG systems, providing insights into optimizations for prevalent failure points.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.15529v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qianren Mao, Yangyifei Luo, Jinlong Zhang, Hanwen Hao, Zhilong Cao, Xiaolong Wang, Xiao Guan, Zhenting Huang, Weifeng Jiang, Shuyu Guo, Zhentao Han, Qili Zhang, Siyuan Tao, Yujie Liu, Junnan Liu, Zhixing Tan, Jie Sun, Bo Li, Xudong Liu, Richong Zhang, Jianxin Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adapting Whisper for Code-Switching through Encoding Refining and Language-Aware Decoding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.16507</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.16507v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Code-switching (CS) automatic speech recognition (ASR) faces challenges due to the language confusion resulting from accents, auditory similarity, and seamless language switches. Adaptation on the pre-trained multi-lingual model has shown promising performance for CS-ASR. In this paper, we adapt Whisper, which is a large-scale multilingual pre-trained speech recognition model, to CS from both encoder and decoder parts. First, we propose an encoder refiner to enhance the encoder's capacity of intra-sentence swithching. Second, we propose using two sets of language-aware adapters with different language prompt embeddings to achieve language-specific decoding information in each decoder layer. Then, a fusion module is added to fuse the language-aware decoding. The experimental results using the SEAME dataset show that, compared with the baseline model, the proposed approach achieves a relative MER reduction of 4.1% and 7.2% on the dev_man and dev_sge test sets, respectively, surpassing state-of-the-art methods. Through experiments, we found that the proposed method significantly improves the performance on non-native language in CS speech, indicating that our approach enables Whisper to better distinguish between the two languages.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.16507v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>ICASSP 2025</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Jiahui Zhao, Hao Shi, Chenrui Cui, Tianrui Wang, Hexin Liu, Zhaoheng Ni, Lingxuan Ye, Longbiao Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>L3TC: Leveraging RWKV for Learned Lossless Low-Complexity Text Compression</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.16642</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.16642v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Learning-based probabilistic models can be combined with an entropy coder for data compression. However, due to the high complexity of learning-based models, their practical application as text compressors has been largely overlooked. To address this issue, our work focuses on a low-complexity design while maintaining compression performance. We introduce a novel Learned Lossless Low-complexity Text Compression method (L3TC). Specifically, we conduct extensive experiments demonstrating that RWKV models achieve the fastest decoding speed with a moderate compression ratio, making it the most suitable backbone for our method. Second, we propose an outlier-aware tokenizer that uses a limited vocabulary to cover frequent tokens while allowing outliers to bypass the prediction and encoding. Third, we propose a novel high-rank reparameterization strategy that enhances the learning capability during training without increasing complexity during inference. Experimental results validate that our method achieves 48% bit saving compared to gzip compressor. Besides, L3TC offers compression performance comparable to other learned compressors, with a 50x reduction in model parameters. More importantly, L3TC is the fastest among all learned compressors, providing real-time decoding speeds up to megabytes per second. Our code is available at https://github.com/alipay/L3TC-leveraging-rwkv-for-learned-lossless-low-complexity-text-compression.git.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.16642v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.IT</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <category>math.IT</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junxuan Zhang, Zhengxue Cheng, Yan Zhao, Shihao Wang, Dajiang Zhou, Guo Lu, Li Song</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sim911: Towards Effective and Equitable 9-1-1 Dispatcher Training with an LLM-Enabled Simulation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.16844</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.16844v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Emergency response services are vital for enhancing public safety by safeguarding the environment, property, and human lives. As frontline members of these services, 9-1-1 dispatchers have a direct impact on response times and the overall effectiveness of emergency operations. However, traditional dispatcher training methods, which rely on role-playing by experienced personnel, are labor-intensive, time-consuming, and often neglect the specific needs of underserved communities. To address these challenges, we introduce Sim911, the first training simulation for 9-1-1 dispatchers powered by Large Language Models (LLMs). Sim911 enhances training through three key technical innovations: (1) knowledge construction, which utilizes archived 9-1-1 call data to generate simulations that closely mirror real-world scenarios; (2) context-aware controlled generation, which employs dynamic prompts and vector bases to ensure that LLM behavior aligns with training objectives; and (3) validation with looped correction, which filters out low-quality responses and refines the system performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.16844v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zirong Chen, Elizabeth Chason, Noah Mladenovski, Erin Wilson, Kristin Mullen, Stephen Martini, Meiyi Ma</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RAGONITE: Iterative Retrieval on Induced Databases and Verbalized RDF for Conversational QA over KGs with RAG</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.17690</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.17690v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Conversational question answering (ConvQA) is a convenient means of searching over RDF knowledge graphs (KGs), where a prevalent approach is to translate natural language questions to SPARQL queries. However, SPARQL has certain shortcomings: (i) it is brittle for complex intents and conversational questions, and (ii) it is not suitable for more abstract needs. Instead, we propose a novel two-pronged system where we fuse: (i) SQL-query results over a database automatically derived from the KG, and (ii) text-search results over verbalizations of KG facts. Our pipeline supports iterative retrieval: when the results of any branch are found to be unsatisfactory, the system can automatically opt for further rounds. We put everything together in a retrieval augmented generation (RAG) setup, where an LLM generates a coherent response from accumulated search results. We demonstrate the superiority of our proposed system over several baselines on a knowledge graph of BMW automobiles.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.17690v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rishiraj Saha Roy, Chris Hinze, Joel Schlotthauer, Farzad Naderi, Viktor Hangya, Andreas Foltyn, Luzian Hahn, Fabian Kuech</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Models to Microtheories: Distilling a Model's Topical Knowledge for Grounded Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.17701</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.17701v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent reasoning methods (e.g., chain-of-thought, entailment reasoning) help users understand how language models (LMs) answer a single question, but they do little to reveal the LM's overall understanding, or "theory," about the question's topic, making it still hard to trust the model. Our goal is to materialize such theories - here called microtheories (a linguistic analog of logical microtheories) - as a set of sentences encapsulating an LM's core knowledge about a topic. These statements systematically work together to entail answers to a set of questions to both engender trust and improve performance. Our approach is to first populate a knowledge store with (model-generated) sentences that entail answers to training questions and then distill those down to a core microtheory that is concise, general, and non-redundant. We show that, when added to a general corpus (e.g., Wikipedia), microtheories can supply critical, topical information not necessarily present in the corpus, improving both a model's ability to ground its answers to verifiable knowledge (i.e., show how answers are systematically entailed by documents in the corpus, fully grounding up to +8% more answers), and the accuracy of those grounded answers (up to +8% absolute). We also show that, in a human evaluation in the medical domain, our distilled microtheories contain a significantly higher concentration of topically critical facts than the non-distilled knowledge store. Finally, we show we can quantify the coverage of a microtheory for a topic (characterized by a dataset) using a notion of $p$-relevance. Together, these suggest that microtheories are an efficient distillation of an LM's topic-relevant knowledge, that they can usefully augment existing corpora, and can provide both performance gains and an interpretable, verifiable window into the model's knowledge of a topic.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.17701v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nathaniel Weir, Bhavana Dalvi Mishra, Orion Weller, Oyvind Tafjord, Sam Hornstein, Alexander Sabol, Peter Jansen, Benjamin Van Durme, Peter Clark</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YuLan-Mini: An Open Data-efficient Language Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.17743</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.17743v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Effective pre-training of large language models (LLMs) has been challenging due to the immense resource demands and the complexity of the technical processes involved. This paper presents a detailed technical report on YuLan-Mini, a highly capable base model with 2.42B parameters that achieves top-tier performance among models of similar parameter scale. Our pre-training approach focuses on enhancing training efficacy through three key technical contributions: an elaborate data pipeline combines data cleaning with data schedule strategies, a robust optimization method to mitigate training instability, and an effective annealing approach that incorporates targeted data selection and long context training. Remarkably, YuLan-Mini, trained on 1.08T tokens, achieves performance comparable to industry-leading models that require significantly more data. To facilitate reproduction, we release the full details of the data composition for each training phase. Project details can be accessed at the following link: https://github.com/RUC-GSAI/YuLan-Mini.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.17743v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yiwen Hu, Huatong Song, Jia Deng, Jiapeng Wang, Jie Chen, Kun Zhou, Yutao Zhu, Jinhao Jiang, Zican Dong, Wayne Xin Zhao, Ji-Rong Wen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GPTEval: A Survey on Assessments of ChatGPT and GPT-4</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2308.12488</link>
      <description>arXiv:2308.12488v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The emergence of ChatGPT has generated much speculation in the press about its potential to disrupt social and economic systems. Its astonishing language ability has aroused strong curiosity among scholars about its performance in different domains. There have been many studies evaluating the ability of ChatGPT and GPT-4 in different tasks and disciplines. However, a comprehensive review summarizing the collective assessment findings is lacking. The objective of this survey is to thoroughly analyze prior assessments of ChatGPT and GPT-4, focusing on its language and reasoning abilities, scientific knowledge, and ethical considerations. Furthermore, an examination of the existing evaluation methods is conducted, offering several recommendations for future research in evaluating large language models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2308.12488v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Proceedings of the 2024 Joint International Conference on Computational Linguistics, Language Resources and Evaluation (2024) 7844-7866</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Rui Mao, Guanyi Chen, Xulang Zhang, Frank Guerin, Erik Cambria</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prompted Contextual Vectors for Spear-Phishing Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.08309</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.08309v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Spear-phishing attacks present a significant security challenge, with large language models (LLMs) escalating the threat by generating convincing emails and facilitating target reconnaissance. To address this, we propose a detection approach based on a novel document vectorization method that utilizes an ensemble of LLMs to create representation vectors. By prompting LLMs to reason and respond to human-crafted questions, we quantify the presence of common persuasion principles in the email's content, producing prompted contextual document vectors for a downstream supervised machine learning model. We evaluate our method using a unique dataset generated by a proprietary system that automates target reconnaissance and spear-phishing email creation. Our method achieves a 91\% F1 score in identifying LLM-generated spear-phishing emails, with the training set comprising only traditional phishing and benign emails. Key contributions include a novel document vectorization method utilizing LLM reasoning, a publicly available dataset of high-quality spear-phishing emails, and the demonstrated effectiveness of our method in detecting such emails. This methodology can be utilized for various document classification tasks, particularly in adversarial problem domains.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.08309v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Daniel Nahmias, Gal Engelberg, Dan Klein, Asaf Shabtai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SafeAligner: Safety Alignment against Jailbreak Attacks via Response Disparity Guidance</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.18118</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.18118v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: As the development of large language models (LLMs) rapidly advances, securing these models effectively without compromising their utility has become a pivotal area of research. However, current defense strategies against jailbreak attacks (i.e., efforts to bypass security protocols) often suffer from limited adaptability, restricted general capability, and high cost. To address these challenges, we introduce SafeAligner, a methodology implemented at the decoding stage to fortify defenses against jailbreak attacks. We begin by developing two specialized models: the Sentinel Model, which is trained to foster safety, and the Intruder Model, designed to generate riskier responses. SafeAligner leverages the disparity in security levels between the responses from these models to differentiate between harmful and beneficial tokens, effectively guiding the safety alignment by altering the output token distribution of the target model. Extensive experiments show that SafeAligner can increase the likelihood of beneficial tokens, while reducing the occurrence of harmful ones, thereby ensuring secure alignment with minimal loss to generality.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.18118v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Caishuang Huang, Wanxu Zhao, Rui Zheng, Huijie Lv, Wenyu Zhan, Shihan Dou, Sixian Li, Xiao Wang, Enyu Zhou, Junjie Ye, Yuming Yang, Tao Gui, Qi Zhang, Xuanjing Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Future Events as Backdoor Triggers: Investigating Temporal Vulnerabilities in LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.04108</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.04108v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Backdoors are hidden behaviors that are only triggered once an AI system has been deployed. Bad actors looking to create successful backdoors must design them to avoid activation during training and evaluation. Since data used in these stages often only contains information about events that have already occurred, a component of a simple backdoor trigger could be a model recognizing data that is in the future relative to when it was trained. Through prompting experiments and by probing internal activations, we show that current large language models (LLMs) can distinguish past from future events, with probes on model activations achieving 90% accuracy. We train models with backdoors triggered by a temporal distributional shift; they activate when the model is exposed to news headlines beyond their training cut-off dates. Fine-tuning on helpful, harmless and honest (HHH) data does not work well for removing simpler backdoor triggers but is effective on our backdoored models, although this distinction is smaller for the larger-scale model we tested. We also find that an activation-steering vector representing a model's internal representation of the date influences the rate of backdoor activation. We take these results as initial evidence that, at least for models at the modest scale we test, standard safety measures are enough to remove these backdoors.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.04108v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sara Price, Arjun Panickssery, Sam Bowman, Asa Cooper Stickland</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Horizon-Length Prediction: Advancing Fill-in-the-Middle Capabilities for Code Generation with Lookahead Planning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.03103</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.03103v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Fill-in-the-Middle (FIM) has become integral to code language models, enabling generation of missing code given both left and right contexts. However, the current FIM training paradigm, which reorders original training sequences and then performs regular next-token prediction (NTP), often leads to models struggling to generate content that aligns smoothly with the surrounding context. Crucially, while existing works rely on rule-based post-processing to circumvent this weakness, such methods are not practically usable in open-domain code completion tasks as they depend on restrictive, dataset-specific assumptions (e.g., generating the same number of lines as in the ground truth). Moreover, model performance on FIM tasks deteriorates significantly without these unrealistic assumptions.
  We hypothesize that NTP alone is insufficient for models to learn effective planning conditioned on the distant right context, a critical factor for successful code infilling. To overcome this, we propose Horizon-Length Prediction (HLP), a novel training objective that teaches models to predict the number of remaining middle tokens (i.e., horizon length) at each step. HLP advances FIM with lookahead planning, enabling models to inherently learn infilling boundaries for arbitrary left and right contexts without relying on dataset-specific post-processing. Our evaluation across different models and sizes shows that HLP significantly improves FIM performance by up to 24% relatively on diverse benchmarks, across file-level and repository-level, and without resorting to unrealistic post-processing methods. Furthermore, the enhanced planning capability gained through HLP boosts model performance on code reasoning. Importantly, HLP only incurs negligible training overhead and no additional inference cost, ensuring its practicality for real-world scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.03103v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yifeng Ding, Hantian Ding, Shiqi Wang, Qing Sun, Varun Kumar, Zijian Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Parameter Collision Hindering Continual Learning in LLMs?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.10179</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.10179v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) often suffer from catastrophic forgetting when learning multiple tasks sequentially, making continual learning (CL) essential for their dynamic deployment. Existing state-of-the-art (SOTA) methods, such as O-LoRA, typically focus on constructing orthogonality tasks to decouple parameter interdependence from various domains.In this paper, we reveal that building non-collision parameters is a more critical factor in addressing CL challenges. Our theoretical and experimental analyses demonstrate that non-collision parameters can provide better task orthogonality, which is a sufficient but unnecessary condition. Furthermore, knowledge from multiple domains will be preserved in non-collision parameter subspaces, making it more difficult to forget previously seen data. Leveraging this insight, we propose Non-collision Low-Rank Adaptation (N-LoRA), a simple yet effective approach leveraging low collision rates to enhance CL in LLMs. Experimental results on multiple CL benchmarks indicate that N-LoRA achieves superior performance (+2.9), higher task orthogonality (*4.1 times), and lower parameter collision (*58.1 times) than SOTA methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.10179v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shuo Yang, Kun-Peng Ning, Yu-Yang Liu, Jia-Yu Yao, Yong-Hong Tian, Yi-Bing Song, Li Yuan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Re-examining learning linear functions in context</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.11465</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.11465v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In-context learning (ICL) has emerged as a powerful paradigm for easily adapting Large Language Models (LLMs) to various tasks. However, our understanding of how ICL works remains limited. We explore a simple model of ICL in a controlled setup with synthetic training data to investigate ICL of univariate linear functions. We experiment with a range of GPT-2-like transformer models trained from scratch. Our findings challenge the prevailing narrative that transformers adopt algorithmic approaches like linear regression to learn a linear function in-context. These models fail to generalize beyond their training distribution, highlighting fundamental limitations in their capacity to infer abstract task structures. Our experiments lead us to propose a mathematically precise hypothesis of what the model might be learning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.11465v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Omar Naim, Guilhem Fouilh\'e, Nicholas Asher</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Facets of Language Generation in the Limit</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.15364</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.15364v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The recent work of Kleinberg &amp; Mullainathan [KM24] provides a concrete model for language generation in the limit: given a sequence of examples from an unknown target language, the goal is to generate new examples from the target language such that no incorrect examples are generated beyond some point. In sharp contrast to strong negative results for the closely related problem of language identification, they establish positive results for language generation in the limit for all countable collections of languages. Follow-up work by Raman &amp; Tewari [RT24] studies bounds on the number of distinct inputs required by an algorithm before correct language generation is achieved -- namely, whether this is a constant for all languages in the collection (uniform generation) or a language-dependent constant (non-uniform generation).
  We show that every countable language collection has a generator which has the stronger property of non-uniform generation in the limit. However, while the generation algorithm of [KM24] can be implemented using membership queries, we show that any algorithm cannot non-uniformly generate even for collections of just two languages, using only membership queries.
  We also formalize the tension between validity and breadth in the generation algorithm of [KM24] by introducing a definition of exhaustive generation, and show a strong negative result for exhaustive generation. Our result shows that a tradeoff between validity and breadth is inherent for generation in the limit. We also provide a precise characterization of the language collections for which exhaustive generation is possible. Finally, inspired by algorithms that can choose to obtain feedback, we consider a model of uniform generation with feedback, completely characterizing language collections for which such uniform generation with feedback is possible in terms of a complexity measure of the collection.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.15364v2</guid>
      <category>cs.DS</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Moses Charikar, Chirag Pabbaraju</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Subtopic-aware View Sampling and Temporal Aggregation for Long-form Document Matching</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.07573</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.07573v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Long-form document matching aims to judge the relevance between two documents and has been applied to various scenarios. Most existing works utilize hierarchical or long context models to process documents, which achieve coarse understanding but may ignore details. Some researchers construct a document view with similar sentences about aligned document subtopics to focus on detailed matching signals. However, a long document generally contains multiple subtopics. The matching signals are heterogeneous from multiple topics. Considering only the homologous aligned subtopics may not be representative enough and may cause biased modeling. In this paper, we introduce a new framework to model representative matching signals. First, we propose to capture various matching signals through subtopics of document pairs. Next, We construct multiple document views based on subtopics to cover heterogeneous and valuable details. However, existing spatial aggregation methods like attention, which integrate all these views simultaneously, are hard to integrate heterogeneous information. Instead, we propose temporal aggregation, which effectively integrates different views gradually as the training progresses. Experimental results show that our learning framework is effective on several document-matching tasks, including news duplication and legal case retrieval.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.07573v2</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Youchao Zhou, Heyan Huang, Zhijing Wu, Yuhang Liu, Xinglin Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can LLMs Obfuscate Code? A Systematic Analysis of Large Language Models into Assembly Code Obfuscation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.16135</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.16135v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Malware authors often employ code obfuscations to make their malware harder to detect. Existing tools for generating obfuscated code often require access to the original source code (e.g., C++ or Java), and adding new obfuscations is a non-trivial, labor-intensive process. In this study, we ask the following question: Can Large Language Models (LLMs) potentially generate a new obfuscated assembly code? If so, this poses a risk to anti-virus engines and potentially increases the flexibility of attackers to create new obfuscation patterns. We answer this in the affirmative by developing the MetamorphASM benchmark comprising MetamorphASM Dataset (MAD) along with three code obfuscation techniques: dead code, register substitution, and control flow change. The MetamorphASM systematically evaluates the ability of LLMs to generate and analyze obfuscated code using MAD, which contains 328,200 obfuscated assembly code samples. We release this dataset and analyze the success rate of various LLMs (e.g., GPT-3.5/4, GPT-4o-mini, Starcoder, CodeGemma, CodeLlama, CodeT5, and LLaMA 3.1) in generating obfuscated assembly code. The evaluation was performed using established information-theoretic metrics and manual human review to ensure correctness and provide the foundation for researchers to study and develop remediations to this risk. The source code can be found at the following GitHub link: https://github.com/mohammadi-ali/MetamorphASM.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.16135v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Seyedreza Mohseni, Seyedali Mohammadi, Deepa Tilwani, Yash Saxena, Gerald Ndawula, Sriram Vema, Edward Raff, Manas Gaur</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HashEvict: A Pre-Attention KV Cache Eviction Strategy using Locality-Sensitive Hashing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.16187</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.16187v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Transformer-based large language models (LLMs) use the key-value (KV) cache to significantly accelerate inference by storing the key and value embeddings of past tokens. However, this cache consumes significant GPU memory. In this work, we introduce HashEvict, an algorithm that uses locality-sensitive hashing (LSH) to compress the KV cache. HashEvict quickly locates tokens in the cache that are cosine dissimilar to the current query token. This is achieved by computing the Hamming distance between binarized Gaussian projections of the current token query and cached token keys, with a projection length much smaller than the embedding dimension. We maintain a lightweight binary structure in GPU memory to facilitate these calculations. Unlike existing compression strategies that compute attention to determine token retention, HashEvict makes these decisions pre-attention, thereby reducing computational costs. Additionally, HashEvict is dynamic - at every decoding step, the key and value of the current token replace the embeddings of a token expected to produce the lowest attention score. We demonstrate that HashEvict can compress the KV cache by 30%-70% while maintaining high performance across reasoning, multiple-choice, long-context retrieval and summarization tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.16187v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.DS</category>
      <category>cs.PF</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Minghui Liu, Tahseen Rabbani, Tony O'Halloran, Ananth Sankaralingam, Mary-Anne Hartley, Brian Gravelle, Furong Huang, Cornelia Ferm\"uller, Yiannis Aloimonos</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open-Vocabulary Mobile Manipulation Based on Double Relaxed Contrastive Learning with Dense Labeling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.16576</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.16576v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Growing labor shortages are increasing the demand for domestic service robots (DSRs) to assist in various settings. In this study, we develop a DSR that transports everyday objects to specified pieces of furniture based on open-vocabulary instructions. Our approach focuses on retrieving images of target objects and receptacles from pre-collected images of indoor environments. For example, given an instruction "Please get the right red towel hanging on the metal towel rack and put it in the white washing machine on the left," the DSR is expected to carry the red towel to the washing machine based on the retrieved images. This is challenging because the correct images should be retrieved from thousands of collected images, which may include many images of similar towels and appliances. To address this, we propose RelaX-Former, which learns diverse and robust representations from among positive, unlabeled positive, and negative samples. We evaluated RelaX-Former on a dataset containing real-world indoor images and human annotated instructions including complex referring expressions. The experimental results demonstrate that RelaX-Former outperformed existing baseline models across standard image retrieval metrics. Moreover, we performed physical experiments using a DSR to evaluate the performance of our approach in a zero-shot transfer setting. The experiments involved the DSR to carry objects to specific receptacles based on open-vocabulary instructions, achieving an overall success rate of 75%.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.16576v2</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Daichi Yashima, Ryosuke Korekata, Komei Sugiura</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>System-2 Mathematical Reasoning via Enriched Instruction Tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.16964</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.16964v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Solving complex mathematical problems via system-2 reasoning is a natural human skill, yet it remains a significant challenge for current large language models (LLMs). We identify the scarcity of deliberate multi-step reasoning data as a primary limiting factor. To this end, we introduce Enriched Instruction Tuning (EIT), a method that enriches existing human-annotated mathematical datasets by synergizing human and AI feedback to create fine-grained reasoning trajectories. These datasets are then used to fine-tune open-source LLMs, enhancing their mathematical reasoning abilities without reliance on any symbolic verification program. Concretely, EIT is composed of two critical steps: Enriching with Reasoning Plan (ERP) and Enriching with Reasoning Step (ERS). The former generates a high-level plan that breaks down complex instructions into a sequence of simpler objectives, while ERS fills in reasoning contexts often overlooked by human annotators, creating a smoother reasoning trajectory for LLM fine-tuning. Unlike existing CoT prompting methods that generate reasoning chains only depending on LLM's internal knowledge, our method leverages human-annotated initial answers as ``meta-knowledge'' to help LLMs generate more detailed and precise reasoning processes, leading to a more trustworthy LLM expert for complex mathematical problems. In experiments, EIT achieves an accuracy of 84.1% on GSM8K and 32.5% on MATH, surpassing state-of-the-art fine-tuning and prompting methods, and even matching the performance of tool-augmented methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.16964v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Huanqia Cai, Yijun Yang, Zhifeng Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
