<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CV updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CV</link>
    <description>cs.CV updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CV" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 04:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Saturday</day>
      <day>Sunday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>NeuroPapyri: A Deep Attention Embedding Network for Handwritten Papyri Retrieval</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07785</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07785v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The intersection of computer vision and machine learning has emerged as a promising avenue for advancing historical research, facilitating a more profound exploration of our past. However, the application of machine learning approaches in historical palaeography is often met with criticism due to their perceived ``black box'' nature. In response to this challenge, we introduce NeuroPapyri, an innovative deep learning-based model specifically designed for the analysis of images containing ancient Greek papyri. To address concerns related to transparency and interpretability, the model incorporates an attention mechanism. This attention mechanism not only enhances the model's performance but also provides a visual representation of the image regions that significantly contribute to the decision-making process. Specifically calibrated for processing images of papyrus documents with lines of handwritten text, the model utilizes individual attention maps to inform the presence or absence of specific characters in the input image. This paper presents the NeuroPapyri model, including its architecture and training methodology. Results from the evaluation demonstrate NeuroPapyri's efficacy in document retrieval, showcasing its potential to advance the analysis of historical manuscripts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07785v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.DL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Giuseppe De Gregorio, Simon Perrin, Rodrigo C. G. Pena, Isabelle Marthot-Santaniello, Harold Mouch\`ere</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cropper: Vision-Language Model for Image Cropping through In-Context Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07790</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07790v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The goal of image cropping is to identify visually appealing crops within an image. Conventional methods rely on specialized architectures trained on specific datasets, which struggle to be adapted to new requirements. Recent breakthroughs in large vision-language models (VLMs) have enabled visual in-context learning without explicit training. However, effective strategies for vision downstream tasks with VLMs remain largely unclear and underexplored. In this paper, we propose an effective approach to leverage VLMs for better image cropping. First, we propose an efficient prompt retrieval mechanism for image cropping to automate the selection of in-context examples. Second, we introduce an iterative refinement strategy to iteratively enhance the predicted crops. The proposed framework, named Cropper, is applicable to a wide range of cropping tasks, including free-form cropping, subject-aware cropping, and aspect ratio-aware cropping. Extensive experiments and a user study demonstrate that Cropper significantly outperforms state-of-the-art methods across several benchmarks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07790v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Seung Hyun Lee, Junjie Ke, Yinxiao Li, Junfeng He, Steven Hickson, Katie Datsenko, Sangpil Kim, Ming-Hsuan Yang, Irfan Essa, Feng Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Algebraic Representations for Faster Predictions in Convolutional Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07815</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07815v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Convolutional neural networks (CNNs) are a popular choice of model for tasks in computer vision. When CNNs are made with many layers, resulting in a deep neural network, skip connections may be added to create an easier gradient optimization problem while retaining model expressiveness. In this paper, we show that arbitrarily complex, trained, linear CNNs with skip connections can be simplified into a single-layer model, resulting in greatly reduced computational requirements during prediction time. We also present a method for training nonlinear models with skip connections that are gradually removed throughout training, giving the benefits of skip connections without requiring computational overhead during during prediction time. These results are demonstrated with practical examples on Residual Networks (ResNet) architecture.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07815v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.SC</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Johnny Joyce, Jan Verschelde</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SSRFlow: Semantic-aware Fusion with Spatial Temporal Re-embedding for Real-world Scene Flow</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07825</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07825v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Scene flow, which provides the 3D motion field of the first frame from two consecutive point clouds, is vital for dynamic scene perception. However, contemporary scene flow methods face three major challenges. Firstly, they lack global flow embedding or only consider the context of individual point clouds before embedding, leading to embedded points struggling to perceive the consistent semantic relationship of another frame. To address this issue, we propose a novel approach called Dual Cross Attentive (DCA) for the latent fusion and alignment between two frames based on semantic contexts. This is then integrated into Global Fusion Flow Embedding (GF) to initialize flow embedding based on global correlations in both contextual and Euclidean spaces. Secondly, deformations exist in non-rigid objects after the warping layer, which distorts the spatiotemporal relation between the consecutive frames. For a more precise estimation of residual flow at next-level, the Spatial Temporal Re-embedding (STR) module is devised to update the point sequence features at current-level. Lastly, poor generalization is often observed due to the significant domain gap between synthetic and LiDAR-scanned datasets. We leverage novel domain adaptive losses to effectively bridge the gap of motion inference from synthetic to real-world. Experiments demonstrate that our approach achieves state-of-the-art (SOTA) performance across various datasets, with particularly outstanding results in real-world LiDAR-scanned situations. Our code will be released upon publication.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07825v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhiyang Lu, Qinghan Chen, Zhimin Yuan, Ming Cheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Space-scale Exploration of the Poor Reliability of Deep Learning Models: the Case of the Remote Sensing of Rooftop Photovoltaic Systems</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07828</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07828v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Photovoltaic (PV) energy grows rapidly and is crucial for the decarbonization of electric systems. However, centralized registries recording the technical characteristifs of rooftop PV systems are often missing, making it difficult to accurately monitor this growth. The lack of monitoring could threaten the integration of PV energy into the grid. To avoid this situation, the remote sensing of rooftop PV systems using deep learning emerged as a promising solution. However, existing techniques are not reliable enough to be used by public authorities or transmission system operators (TSOs) to construct up-to-date statistics on the rooftop PV fleet. The lack of reliability comes from the fact that deep learning models are sensitive to distribution shifts. This work proposes a comprehensive evaluation of the effects of distribution shifts on the classification accuracy of deep learning models trained to detect rooftop PV panels on overhead imagery. We construct a benchmark to isolate the sources of distribution shift and introduce a novel methodology that leverages explainable artificial intelligence (XAI) and decomposition of the input image and model's decision in terms of scales to understand how distribution shifts affect deep learning models. Finally, based on our analysis, we introduce a data augmentation technique meant to improve the robustness of deep learning classifiers to varying acquisition conditions. We show that our proposed approach outperforms competing methods. We discuss some practical recommendations for mapping PV systems using overhead imagery and deep learning models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07828v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gabriel Kasmi, Laurent Dubus, Yves-Marie Saint Drenan, Philippe Blanc</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learned Single-Pass Multitasking Perceptual Graphics for Immersive Displays</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07836</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07836v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Immersive displays are advancing rapidly in terms of delivering perceptually realistic images by utilizing emerging perceptual graphics methods such as foveated rendering. In practice, multiple such methods need to be performed sequentially for enhanced perceived quality. However, the limited power and computational resources of the devices that drive immersive displays make it challenging to deploy multiple perceptual models simultaneously.
  We address this challenge by proposing a computationally-lightweight, text-guided, learned multitasking perceptual graphics model. Given RGB input images, our model outputs perceptually enhanced images by performing one or more perceptual tasks described by the provided text prompts. Our model supports a variety of perceptual tasks, including foveated rendering, dynamic range enhancement, image denoising, and chromostereopsis, through multitask learning. Uniquely, a single inference step of our model supports different permutations of these perceptual tasks at different prompted rates (i.e., mildly, lightly), eliminating the need for daisy-chaining multiple models to get the desired perceptual effect. We train our model on our new dataset of source and perceptually enhanced images, and their corresponding text prompts. We evaluate our model's performance on embedded platforms and validate the perceptual quality of our model through a user study. Our method achieves on-par quality with the state-of-the-art task-specific methods using a single inference step, while offering faster inference speeds and flexibility to blend effects at various intensities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07836v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Do\u{g}a Y{\i}lmaz, Towaki Takikawa, Duygu Ceylan, Kaan Ak\c{s}it</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Perception Benchmark</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07867</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07867v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Humans continuously perceive and process visual signals. However, current video models typically either sample key frames sparsely or divide videos into chunks and densely sample within each chunk. This approach stems from the fact that most existing video benchmarks can be addressed by analyzing key frames or aggregating information from separate chunks. We anticipate that the next generation of vision models will emulate human perception by processing visual input continuously and holistically. To facilitate the development of such models, we propose the Continuous Perception Benchmark, a video question answering task that cannot be solved by focusing solely on a few frames or by captioning small chunks and then summarizing using language models. Extensive experiments demonstrate that existing models, whether commercial or open-source, struggle with these tasks, indicating the need for new technical advancements in this direction.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07867v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zeyu Wang, Zhenzhen Weng, Serena Yeung-Levy</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Impute or Not: Recommendations for Multibiometric Fusion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07883</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07883v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Combining match scores from different biometric systems via fusion is a well-established approach to improving recognition accuracy. However, missing scores can degrade performance as well as limit the possible fusion techniques that can be applied. Imputation is a promising technique in multibiometric systems for replacing missing data. In this paper, we evaluate various score imputation approaches on three multimodal biometric score datasets, viz. NIST BSSR1, BIOCOP2008, and MIT LL Trimodal, and investigate the factors which might influence the effectiveness of imputation. Our studies reveal three key observations: (1) Imputation is preferable over not imputing missing scores, even when the fusion rule does not require complete score data. (2) Balancing the classes in the training data is crucial to mitigate negative biases in the imputation technique towards the under-represented class, even if it involves dropping a substantial number of score vectors. (3) Multivariate imputation approaches seem to be beneficial when scores between modalities are correlated, while univariate approaches seem to benefit scenarios where scores between modalities are less correlated.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07883v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1109/WIFS58808.2023.10374772</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Melissa R Dale, Elliot Singer, Bengt J. Borgstr\"om, Arun Ross</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MambaVT: Spatio-Temporal Contextual Modeling for robust RGB-T Tracking</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07889</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07889v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Existing RGB-T tracking algorithms have made remarkable progress by leveraging the global interaction capability and extensive pre-trained models of the Transformer architecture. Nonetheless, these methods mainly adopt imagepair appearance matching and face challenges of the intrinsic high quadratic complexity of the attention mechanism, resulting in constrained exploitation of temporal information. Inspired by the recently emerged State Space Model Mamba, renowned for its impressive long sequence modeling capabilities and linear computational complexity, this work innovatively proposes a pure Mamba-based framework (MambaVT) to fully exploit spatio-temporal contextual modeling for robust visible-thermal tracking. Specifically, we devise the long-range cross-frame integration component to globally adapt to target appearance variations, and introduce short-term historical trajectory prompts to predict the subsequent target states based on local temporal location clues. Extensive experiments show the significant potential of vision Mamba for RGB-T tracking, with MambaVT achieving state-of-the-art performance on four mainstream benchmarks while requiring lower computational costs. We aim for this work to serve as a simple yet strong baseline, stimulating future research in this field. The code and pre-trained models will be made available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07889v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Simiao Lai, Chang Liu, Jiawen Zhu, Ben Kang, Yang Liu, Dong Wang, Huchuan Lu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantum-inspired Interpretable Deep Learning Architecture for Text Sentiment Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07891</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07891v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Text has become the predominant form of communication on social media, embedding a wealth of emotional nuances. Consequently, the extraction of emotional information from text is of paramount importance. Despite previous research making some progress, existing text sentiment analysis models still face challenges in integrating diverse semantic information and lack interpretability. To address these issues, we propose a quantum-inspired deep learning architecture that combines fundamental principles of quantum mechanics (QM principles) with deep learning models for text sentiment analysis. Specifically, we analyze the commonalities between text representation and QM principles to design a quantum-inspired text representation method and further develop a quantum-inspired text embedding layer. Additionally, we design a feature extraction layer based on long short-term memory (LSTM) networks and self-attention mechanisms (SAMs). Finally, we calculate the text density matrix using the quantum complex numbers principle and apply 2D-convolution neural networks (CNNs) for feature condensation and dimensionality reduction. Through a series of visualization, comparative, and ablation experiments, we demonstrate that our model not only shows significant advantages in accuracy and efficiency compared to previous related models but also achieves a certain level of interpretability by integrating QM principles. Our code is available at QISA.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07891v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bingyu Li, Da Zhang, Zhiyuan Zhao, Junyu Gao, Yuan Yuan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Persistence Image from 3D Medical Image: Superpixel and Optimized Gaussian Coefficient</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07905</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07905v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Topological data analysis (TDA) uncovers crucial properties of objects in medical imaging. Methods based on persistent homology have demonstrated their advantages in capturing topological features that traditional deep learning methods cannot detect in both radiology and pathology. However, previous research primarily focused on 2D image analysis, neglecting the comprehensive 3D context. In this paper, we propose an innovative 3D TDA approach that incorporates the concept of superpixels to transform 3D medical image features into point cloud data. By Utilizing Optimized Gaussian Coefficient, the proposed 3D TDA method, for the first time, efficiently generate holistic Persistence Images for 3D volumetric data. Our 3D TDA method exhibits superior performance on the MedMNist3D dataset when compared to other traditional methods, showcasing its potential effectiveness in modeling 3D persistent homology-based topological analysis when it comes to classification tasks. The source code is publicly available at https://github.com/hrlblab/TopologicalDataAnalysis3D.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07905v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yanfan Zhu, Yash Singh, Khaled Younis, Shunxing Bao, Yuankai Huo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Deep Features-Based Approach Using Modified ResNet50 and Gradient Boosting for Visual Sentiments Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07922</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07922v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The versatile nature of Visual Sentiment Analysis (VSA) is one reason for its rising profile. It isn't easy to efficiently manage social media data with visual information since previous research has concentrated on Sentiment Analysis (SA) of single modalities, like textual. In addition, most visual sentiment studies need to adequately classify sentiment because they are mainly focused on simply merging modal attributes without investigating their intricate relationships. This prompted the suggestion of developing a fusion of deep learning and machine learning algorithms. In this research, a deep feature-based method for multiclass classification has been used to extract deep features from modified ResNet50. Furthermore, gradient boosting algorithm has been used to classify photos containing emotional content. The approach is thoroughly evaluated on two benchmarked datasets, CrowdFlower and GAPED. Finally, cutting-edge deep learning and machine learning models were used to compare the proposed strategy. When compared to state-of-the-art approaches, the proposed method demonstrates exceptional performance on the datasets presented.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07922v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Muhammad Arslan, Muhammad Mubeen, Arslan Akram, Saadullah Farooq Abbasi, Muhammad Salman Ali, Muhammad Usman Tariq</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surgical SAM 2: Real-time Segment Anything in Surgical Video by Efficient Frame Pruning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07931</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07931v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Surgical video segmentation is a critical task in computer-assisted surgery and is vital for enhancing surgical quality and patient outcomes. Recently, the Segment Anything Model 2 (SAM2) framework has shown superior advancements in image and video segmentation. However, SAM2 struggles with efficiency due to the high computational demands of processing high-resolution images and complex and long-range temporal dynamics in surgical videos. To address these challenges, we introduce Surgical SAM 2 (SurgSAM-2), an advanced model to utilize SAM2 with an Efficient Frame Pruning (EFP) mechanism, to facilitate real-time surgical video segmentation. The EFP mechanism dynamically manages the memory bank by selectively retaining only the most informative frames, reducing memory usage and computational cost while maintaining high segmentation accuracy. Our extensive experiments demonstrate that SurgSAM-2 significantly improves both efficiency and segmentation accuracy compared to the vanilla SAM2. Remarkably, SurgSAM-2 achieves a 3$\times$ FPS compared with SAM2, while also delivering state-of-the-art performance after fine-tuning with lower-resolution data. These advancements establish SurgSAM-2 as a leading model for surgical video analysis, making real-time surgical video segmentation in resource-constrained environments a feasible reality.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07931v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haofeng Liu, Erli Zhang, Junde Wu, Mingxuan Hong, Yueming Jin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Training Spatial-Frequency Visual Prompts and Probabilistic Clusters for Accurate Black-Box Transfer Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07944</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07944v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Despite the growing prevalence of black-box pre-trained models (PTMs) such as prediction API services, there remains a significant challenge in directly applying general models to real-world scenarios due to the data distribution gap. Considering a data deficiency and constrained computational resource scenario, this paper proposes a novel parameter-efficient transfer learning framework for vision recognition models in the black-box setting. Our framework incorporates two novel training techniques. First, we align the input space (i.e., image) of PTMs to the target data distribution by generating visual prompts of spatial and frequency domain. Along with the novel spatial-frequency hybrid visual prompter, we design a novel training technique based on probabilistic clusters, which can enhance class separation in the output space (i.e., prediction probabilities). In experiments, our model demonstrates superior performance in a few-shot transfer learning setting across extensive visual recognition datasets, surpassing state-of-the-art baselines. Additionally, we show that the proposed method efficiently reduces computational costs for training and inference phases.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07944v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wonwoo Cho, Kangyeol Kim, Saemee Choi, Jaegul Choo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FlashGS: Efficient 3D Gaussian Splatting for Large-scale and High-resolution Rendering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07967</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07967v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This work introduces FlashGS, an open-source CUDA Python library, designed to facilitate the efficient differentiable rasterization of 3D Gaussian Splatting through algorithmic and kernel-level optimizations. FlashGS is developed based on the observations from a comprehensive analysis of the rendering process to enhance computational efficiency and bring the technique to wide adoption. The paper includes a suite of optimization strategies, encompassing redundancy elimination, efficient pipelining, refined control and scheduling mechanisms, and memory access optimizations, all of which are meticulously integrated to amplify the performance of the rasterization process. An extensive evaluation of FlashGS' performance has been conducted across a diverse spectrum of synthetic and real-world large-scale scenes, encompassing a variety of image resolutions. The empirical findings demonstrate that FlashGS consistently achieves an average 4x acceleration over mobile consumer GPUs, coupled with reduced memory consumption. These results underscore the superior performance and resource optimization capabilities of FlashGS, positioning it as a formidable tool in the domain of 3D rendering.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07967v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Guofeng Feng, Siyan Chen, Rong Fu, Zimu Liao, Yi Wang, Tao Liu, Zhilin Pei, Hengjie Li, Xingcheng Zhang, Bo Dai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLaVA-Surg: Towards Multimodal Surgical Assistant via Structured Surgical Video Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07981</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07981v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Multimodal large language models (LLMs) have achieved notable success across various domains, while research in the medical field has largely focused on unimodal images. Meanwhile, current general-domain multimodal models for videos still lack the capabilities to understand and engage in conversations about surgical videos. One major contributing factor is the absence of datasets in the surgical field. In this paper, we create a new dataset, Surg-QA, consisting of 102,000 surgical video-instruction pairs, the largest of its kind so far. To build such a dataset, we propose a novel two-stage question-answer generation pipeline with LLM to learn surgical knowledge in a structured manner from the publicly available surgical lecture videos. The pipeline breaks down the generation process into two stages to significantly reduce the task complexity, allowing us to use a more affordable, locally deployed open-source LLM than the premium paid LLM services. It also mitigates the risk of LLM hallucinations during question-answer generation, thereby enhancing the overall quality of the generated data. We further train LLaVA-Surg, a novel vision-language conversational assistant capable of answering open-ended questions about surgical videos, on this Surg-QA dataset, and conduct comprehensive evaluations on zero-shot surgical video question-answering tasks. We show that LLaVA-Surg significantly outperforms all previous general-domain models, demonstrating exceptional multimodal conversational skills in answering open-ended questions about surgical videos. We will release our code, model, and the instruction-tuning dataset.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07981v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiajie Li, Garrett Skinner, Gene Yang, Brian R Quaranto, Steven D Schwaitzberg, Peter C W Kim, Jinjun Xiong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring learning environments for label\-efficient cancer diagnosis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07988</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07988v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Despite significant research efforts and advancements, cancer remains a leading cause of mortality. Early cancer prediction has become a crucial focus in cancer research to streamline patient care and improve treatment outcomes. Manual tumor detection by histopathologists can be time consuming, prompting the need for computerized methods to expedite treatment planning. Traditional approaches to tumor detection rely on supervised learning, necessitates a large amount of annotated data for model training. However, acquiring such extensive labeled data can be laborious and time\-intensive. This research examines the three learning environments: supervised learning (SL), semi\-supervised learning (Semi\-SL), and self\-supervised learning (Self\-SL): to predict kidney, lung, and breast cancer. Three pre\-trained deep learning models (Residual Network\-50, Visual Geometry Group\-16, and EfficientNetB0) are evaluated based on these learning settings using seven carefully curated training sets. To create the first training set (TS1), SL is applied to all annotated image samples. Five training sets (TS2\-TS6) with different ratios of labeled and unlabeled cancer images are used to evaluateSemi\-SL. Unlabeled cancer images from the final training set (TS7) are utilized for Self\-SL assessment. Among different learning environments, outcomes from the Semi\-SL setting show a strong degree of agreement with the outcomes achieved in the SL setting. The uniform pattern of observations from the pre\-trained models across all three datasets validates the methodology and techniques of the research. Based on modest number of labeled samples and minimal computing cost, our study suggests that the Semi\-SL option can be a highly viable replacement for the SL option under label annotation constraint scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07988v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Samta Rani, Tanvir Ahmad, Sarfaraz Masood, Chandni Saxena</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IIU: Independent Inference Units for Knowledge-based Visual Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07989</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07989v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Knowledge-based visual question answering requires external knowledge beyond visible content to answer the question correctly. One limitation of existing methods is that they focus more on modeling the inter-modal and intra-modal correlations, which entangles complex multimodal clues by implicit embeddings and lacks interpretability and generalization ability. The key challenge to solve the above problem is to separate the information and process it separately at the functional level. By reusing each processing unit, the generalization ability of the model to deal with different data can be increased. In this paper, we propose Independent Inference Units (IIU) for fine-grained multi-modal reasoning to decompose intra-modal information by the functionally independent units. Specifically, IIU processes each semantic-specific intra-modal clue by an independent inference unit, which also collects complementary information by communication from different units. To further reduce the impact of redundant information, we propose a memory update module to maintain semantic-relevant memory along with the reasoning process gradually. In comparison with existing non-pretrained multi-modal reasoning models on standard datasets, our model achieves a new state-of-the-art, enhancing performance by 3%, and surpassing basic pretrained multi-modal models. The experimental results show that our IIU model is effective in disentangling intra-modal clues as well as reasoning units to provide explainable reasoning evidence. Our code is available at https://github.com/Lilidamowang/IIU.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07989v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yili Li, Jing Yu, Keke Gai, Gang Xiong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monte Carlo Path Tracing and Statistical Event Detection for Event Camera Simulation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07996</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07996v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper presents a novel event camera simulation system fully based on physically based Monte Carlo path tracing with adaptive path sampling. The adaptive sampling performed in the proposed method is based on a statistical technique, hypothesis testing for the hypothesis whether the difference of logarithmic luminances at two distant periods is significantly larger than a predefined event threshold. To this end, our rendering system collects logarithmic luminances rather than raw luminance in contrast to the conventional rendering system imitating conventional RGB cameras. Then, based on the central limit theorem, we reasonably assume that the distribution of the population mean of logarithmic luminance can be modeled as a normal distribution, allowing us to model the distribution of the difference of logarithmic luminance as a normal distribution. Then, using Student's t-test, we can test the hypothesis and determine whether to discard the null hypothesis for event non-occurrence. When we sample a sufficiently large number of path samples to satisfy the central limit theorem and obtain a clean set of events, our method achieves significant speed up compared to a simple approach of sampling paths uniformly at every pixel. To our knowledge, we are the first to simulate the behavior of event cameras in a physically accurate manner using an adaptive sampling technique in Monte Carlo path tracing, and we believe this study will contribute to the development of computer vision applications using event cameras.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07996v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuichiro Manabe, Tatsuya Yatagawa, Shigeo Morishima, Hiroyuki Kubo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co-Fix3D: Enhancing 3D Object Detection with Collaborative Refinement</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07999</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07999v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In the realm of autonomous driving,accurately detecting occluded or distant objects,referred to as weak positive sample ,presents significant challenges. These challenges predominantly arise during query initialization, where an over-reliance on heatmap confidence often results in a high rate of false positives, consequently masking weaker detections and impairing system performance. To alleviate this issue, we propose a novel approach, Co-Fix3D, which employs a collaborative hybrid multi-stage parallel query generation mechanism for BEV representations. Our method incorporates the Local-Global Feature Enhancement (LGE) module, which refines BEV features to more effectively highlight weak positive samples. It uniquely leverages the Discrete Wavelet Transform (DWT) for accurate noise reduction and features refinement in localized areas, and incorporates an attention mechanism to more comprehensively optimize global BEV features. Moreover, our method increases the volume of BEV queries through a multi-stage parallel processing of the LGE, significantly enhancing the probability of selecting weak positive samples. This enhancement not only improves training efficiency within the decoder framework but also boosts overall system performance. Notably, Co-Fix3D achieves superior results on the stringent nuScenes benchmark, outperforming all previous models with a 69.1% mAP and 72.9% NDS on the LiDAR-based benchmark, and 72.3% mAP and 74.1% NDS on the multi-modality benchmark, without relying on test-time augmentation or additional datasets. The source code will be made publicly available upon acceptance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07999v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenxuan Li, Qin Zou, Chi Chen, Bo Du, Long Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MVInpainter: Learning Multi-View Consistent Inpainting to Bridge 2D and 3D Editing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08000</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08000v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Novel View Synthesis (NVS) and 3D generation have recently achieved prominent improvements. However, these works mainly focus on confined categories or synthetic 3D assets, which are discouraged from generalizing to challenging in-the-wild scenes and fail to be employed with 2D synthesis directly. Moreover, these methods heavily depended on camera poses, limiting their real-world applications. To overcome these issues, we propose MVInpainter, re-formulating the 3D editing as a multi-view 2D inpainting task. Specifically, MVInpainter partially inpaints multi-view images with the reference guidance rather than intractably generating an entirely novel view from scratch, which largely simplifies the difficulty of in-the-wild NVS and leverages unmasked clues instead of explicit pose conditions. To ensure cross-view consistency, MVInpainter is enhanced by video priors from motion components and appearance guidance from concatenated reference key&amp;value attention. Furthermore, MVInpainter incorporates slot attention to aggregate high-level optical flow features from unmasked regions to control the camera movement with pose-free training and inference. Sufficient scene-level experiments on both object-centric and forward-facing datasets verify the effectiveness of MVInpainter, including diverse tasks, such as multi-view object removal, synthesis, insertion, and replacement. The project page is https://ewrfcas.github.io/MVInpainter/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08000v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chenjie Cao, Chaohui Yu, Yanwei Fu, Fan Wang, Xiangyang Xue</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive Learning of Consistency and Inconsistency Information for Fake News Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08013</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08013v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The rapid advancement of social media platforms has significantly reduced the cost of information dissemination, yet it has also led to a proliferation of fake news, posing a threat to societal trust and credibility. Most of fake news detection research focused on integrating text and image information to represent the consistency of multiple modes in news content, while paying less attention to inconsistent information. Besides, existing methods that leveraged inconsistent information often caused one mode overshadowing another, leading to ineffective use of inconsistent clue. To address these issues, we propose an adaptive multi-modal feature fusion network (MFF-Net). Inspired by human judgment processes for determining truth and falsity in news, MFF-Net focuses on inconsistent parts when news content is generally consistent and consistent parts when it is generally inconsistent. Specifically, MFF-Net extracts semantic and global features from images and texts respectively, and learns consistency information between modes through a multiple feature fusion module. To deal with the problem of modal information being easily masked, we design a single modal feature filtering strategy to capture inconsistent information from corresponding modes separately. Finally, similarity scores are calculated based on global features with adaptive adjustments made to achieve weighted fusion of consistent and inconsistent features. Extensive experimental results demonstrate that MFF-Net outperforms state-of-the-art methods across three public news datasets derived from real social medias.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08013v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aohan Li, Jiaxin Chen, Xin Liao, Dengyong Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DIVE: Towards Descriptive and Diverse Visual Commonsense Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08021</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08021v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Towards human-level visual understanding, visual commonsense generation has been introduced to generate commonsense inferences beyond images. However, current research on visual commonsense generation has overlooked an important human cognitive ability: generating descriptive and diverse inferences. In this work, we propose a novel visual commonsense generation framework, called DIVE, which aims to improve the descriptiveness and diversity of generated inferences. DIVE involves two methods, generic inference filtering and contrastive retrieval learning, which address the limitations of existing visual commonsense resources and training objectives. Experimental results verify that DIVE outperforms state-of-the-art models for visual commonsense generation in terms of both descriptiveness and diversity, while showing a superior quality in generating unique and novel inferences. Notably, DIVE achieves human-level descriptiveness and diversity on Visual Commonsense Graphs. Furthermore, human evaluations confirm that DIVE aligns closely with human judgments on descriptiveness and diversity\footnote{Our code and dataset are available at https://github.com/Park-ing-lot/DIVE.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08021v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.18653/v1/2023.emnlp-main.601</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Jun-Hyung Park (Korea University), Hyuntae Park (Korea University), Youjin Kang (Korea University), Eojin Jeon (Korea University), SangKeun Lee (Korea University)</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Advanced Deep Learning Based Three-Stream Hybrid Model for Dynamic Hand Gesture Recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08035</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08035v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In the modern context, hand gesture recognition has emerged as a focal point. This is due to its wide range of applications, which include comprehending sign language, factories, hands-free devices, and guiding robots. Many researchers have attempted to develop more effective techniques for recognizing these hand gestures. However, there are challenges like dataset limitations, variations in hand forms, external environments, and inconsistent lighting conditions. To address these challenges, we proposed a novel three-stream hybrid model that combines RGB pixel and skeleton-based features to recognize hand gestures. In the procedure, we preprocessed the dataset, including augmentation, to make rotation, translation, and scaling independent systems. We employed a three-stream hybrid model to extract the multi-feature fusion using the power of the deep learning module. In the first stream, we extracted the initial feature using the pre-trained Imagenet module and then enhanced this feature by using a multi-layer of the GRU and LSTM modules. In the second stream, we extracted the initial feature with the pre-trained ReseNet module and enhanced it with the various combinations of the GRU and LSTM modules. In the third stream, we extracted the hand pose key points using the media pipe and then enhanced them using the stacked LSTM to produce the hierarchical feature. After that, we concatenated the three features to produce the final. Finally, we employed a classification module to produce the probabilistic map to generate predicted output. We mainly produced a powerful feature vector by taking advantage of the pixel-based deep learning feature and pos-estimation-based stacked deep learning feature, including a pre-trained model with a scratched deep learning model for unequalled gesture detection capabilities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08035v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Md Abdur Rahim, Abu Saleh Musa Miah, Hemel Sharker Akash, Jungpil Shin, Md. Imran Hossain, Md. Najmul Hossain</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CamoTeacher: Dual-Rotation Consistency Learning for Semi-Supervised Camouflaged Object Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08050</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08050v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Existing camouflaged object detection~(COD) methods depend heavily on large-scale pixel-level annotations.However, acquiring such annotations is laborious due to the inherent camouflage characteristics of the objects.Semi-supervised learning offers a promising solution to this challenge.Yet, its application in COD is hindered by significant pseudo-label noise, both pixel-level and instance-level.We introduce CamoTeacher, a novel semi-supervised COD framework, utilizing Dual-Rotation Consistency Learning~(DRCL) to effectively address these noise issues.Specifically, DRCL minimizes pseudo-label noise by leveraging rotation views' consistency in pixel-level and instance-level.First, it employs Pixel-wise Consistency Learning~(PCL) to deal with pixel-level noise by reweighting the different parts within the pseudo-label.Second, Instance-wise Consistency Learning~(ICL) is used to adjust weights for pseudo-labels, which handles instance-level noise.Extensive experiments on four COD benchmark datasets demonstrate that the proposed CamoTeacher not only achieves state-of-the-art compared with semi-supervised learning methods, but also rivals established fully-supervised learning methods.Our code will be available soon.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08050v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xunfa Lai, Zhiyu Yang, Jie Hu, Shengchuan Zhang, Liujuan Cao, Guannan Jiang, Zhiyu Wang, Songan Zhang, Rongrong Ji</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Navigating Data Scarcity using Foundation Models: A Benchmark of Few-Shot and Zero-Shot Learning Approaches in Medical Imaging</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08058</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08058v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Data scarcity is a major limiting factor for applying modern machine learning techniques to clinical tasks. Although sufficient data exists for some well-studied medical tasks, there remains a long tail of clinically relevant tasks with poor data availability. Recently, numerous foundation models have demonstrated high suitability for few-shot learning (FSL) and zero-shot learning (ZSL), potentially making them more accessible to practitioners. However, it remains unclear which foundation model performs best on FSL medical image analysis tasks and what the optimal methods are for learning from limited data. We conducted a comprehensive benchmark study of ZSL and FSL using 16 pretrained foundation models on 19 diverse medical imaging datasets. Our results indicate that BiomedCLIP, a model pretrained exclusively on medical data, performs best on average for very small training set sizes, while very large CLIP models pretrained on LAION-2B perform best with slightly more training samples. However, simply fine-tuning a ResNet-18 pretrained on ImageNet performs similarly with more than five training examples per class. Our findings also highlight the need for further research on foundation models specifically tailored for medical applications and the collection of more datasets to train these models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08058v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Stefano Woerner, Christian F. Baumgartner</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MambaMIM: Pre-training Mamba with State Space Token-interpolation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08070</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08070v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Generative self-supervised learning demonstrates outstanding representation learning capabilities in both Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs) and Vision Transformers (ViTs). However, there are currently no generative pre-training methods related to selective state space models (Mamba) that can handle long-range dependencies effectively. To address this challenge, we introduce a generative self-supervised learning method for Mamba (MambaMIM) based on Selective Structure State Space Sequence Token-interpolation (S6T), a general-purpose pre-training method for arbitrary Mamba architectures. Our method, MambaMIM, incorporates a bottom-up 3D hybrid masking strategy in the encoder to maintain masking consistency across different architectures. Additionally, S6T is employed to learn causal relationships between the masked sequence in the state space. MambaMIM can be used on any single or hybrid Mamba architectures to enhance the Mamba long-range representation capability. Extensive downstream experiments reveal the feasibility and advancement of using Mamba for pre-training medical image tasks. The code is available at: https://github.com/FengheTan9/MambaMIM</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08070v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fenghe Tang, Bingkun Nian, Yingtai Li, Jie Yang, Liu Wei, S. Kevin Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Treat Stillness with Movement: Remote Sensing Change Detection via Coarse-grained Temporal Foregrounds Mining</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08078</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08078v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Current works focus on addressing the remote sensing change detection task using bi-temporal images. Although good performance can be achieved, however, seldom of they consider the motion cues which may also be vital. In this work, we revisit the widely adopted bi-temporal images-based framework and propose a novel Coarse-grained Temporal Mining Augmented (CTMA) framework. To be specific, given the bi-temporal images, we first transform them into a video using interpolation operations. Then, a set of temporal encoders is adopted to extract the motion features from the obtained video for coarse-grained changed region prediction. Subsequently, we design a novel Coarse-grained Foregrounds Augmented Spatial Encoder module to integrate both global and local information. We also introduce a motion augmented strategy that leverages motion cues as an additional output to aggregate with the spatial features for improved results. Meanwhile, we feed the input image pairs into the ResNet to get the different features and also the spatial blocks for fine-grained feature learning. More importantly, we propose a mask augmented strategy that utilizes coarse-grained changed regions, incorporating them into the decoder blocks to enhance the final changed prediction. Extensive experiments conducted on multiple benchmark datasets fully validated the effectiveness of our proposed framework for remote sensing image change detection. The source code of this paper will be released on https://github.com/Event-AHU/CTM_Remote_Sensing_Change_Detection</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08078v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xixi Wang, Zitian Wang, Jingtao Jiang, Lan Chen, Xiao Wang, Bo Jiang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-image coherent reconstruction of objects and humans</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08086</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08086v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Existing methods for reconstructing objects and humans from a monocular image suffer from severe mesh collisions and performance limitations for interacting occluding objects. This paper introduces a method to obtain a globally consistent 3D reconstruction of interacting objects and people from a single image. Our contributions include: 1) an optimization framework, featuring a collision loss, tailored to handle human-object and human-human interactions, ensuring spatially coherent scene reconstruction; and 2) a novel technique to robustly estimate 6 degrees of freedom (DOF) poses, specifically for heavily occluded objects, exploiting image inpainting. Notably, our proposed method operates effectively on images from real-world scenarios, without necessitating scene or object-level 3D supervision. Extensive qualitative and quantitative evaluation against existing methods demonstrates a significant reduction in collisions in the final reconstructions of scenes with multiple interacting humans and objects and a more coherent scene reconstruction.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08086v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sarthak Batra, Partha P. Chakrabarti, Simon Hadfield, Armin Mustafa</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ColorMamba: Towards High-quality NIR-to-RGB Spectral Translation with Mamba</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08087</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08087v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Translating NIR to the visible spectrum is challenging due to cross-domain complexities. Current models struggle to balance a broad receptive field with computational efficiency, limiting practical use. Although the Selective Structured State Space Model, especially the improved version, Mamba, excels in generative tasks by capturing long-range dependencies with linear complexity, its default approach of converting 2D images into 1D sequences neglects local context. In this work, we propose a simple but effective backbone, dubbed ColorMamba, which first introduces Mamba into spectral translation tasks. To explore global long-range dependencies and local context for efficient spectral translation, we introduce learnable padding tokens to enhance the distinction of image boundaries and prevent potential confusion within the sequence model. Furthermore, local convolutional enhancement and agent attention are designed to improve the vanilla Mamba. Moreover, we exploit the HSV color to provide multi-scale guidance in the reconstruction process for more accurate spectral translation. Extensive experiments show that our ColorMamba achieves a 1.02 improvement in terms of PSNR compared with the state-of-the-art method. Our code is available at https://github.com/AlexYangxx/ColorMamba.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08087v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Huiyu Zhai, Guang Jin, Xingxing Yang, Guosheng Kang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HAIR: Hypernetworks-based All-in-One Image Restoration</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08091</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08091v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Image restoration involves recovering a high-quality clean image from its degraded version, which is a fundamental task in computer vision. Recent progress in image restoration has demonstrated the effectiveness of learning models capable of addressing various degradations simultaneously, i.e., the All-in-One image restoration models. However, these existing methods typically utilize the same parameters facing images with different degradation types, which causes the model to be forced to trade off between degradation types, therefore impair the total performance. To solve this problem, we propose HAIR, a Hypernetworks-based plug-in-and-play method that dynamically generated parameters for the corresponding networks based on the contents of input images. HAIR consists of 2 main components: Classifier (Cl) and Hyper Selecting Net (HSN). To be more specific, the Classifier is a simple image classification network which is used to generate a Global Information Vector (GIV) that contains the degradation information of the input image; And the HSNs can be seen as a simple Fully-connected Neural Network that receive the GIV and output parameters for the corresponding modules. Extensive experiments shows that incorporating HAIR into the architectures can significantly improve the performance of different models on image restoration tasks at a low cost, \textbf{although HAIR only generate parameters and haven't change these models' logical structures at all.} With incorporating HAIR into the popular architecture Restormer, our method obtains superior or at least comparable performance to current state-of-the-art methods on a range of image restoration tasks. \href{https://github.com/toummHus/HAIR}{\textcolor{blue}{$\underline{\textbf{Code and pre-trained checkpoints are available here.}}$}}</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08091v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jin Cao, Yi Cao, Li Pang, Deyu Meng, Xiangyong Cao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OC3D: Weakly Supervised Outdoor 3D Object Detection with Only Coarse Click Annotation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08092</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08092v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: LiDAR-based outdoor 3D object detection has received widespread attention. However, training 3D detectors from the LiDAR point cloud typically relies on expensive bounding box annotations. This paper presents OC3D, an innovative weakly supervised method requiring only coarse clicks on the bird' s eye view of the 3D point cloud. A key challenge here is the absence of complete geometric descriptions of the target objects from such simple click annotations. To address this problem, our proposed OC3D adopts a two-stage strategy. In the first stage, we initially design a novel dynamic and static classification strategy and then propose the Click2Box and Click2Mask modules to generate box-level and mask-level pseudo-labels for static and dynamic instances, respectively. In the second stage, we design a Mask2Box module, leveraging the learning capabilities of neural networks to update mask-level pseudo-labels, which contain less information, to box level pseudo-labels. Experimental results on the widely used KITTI and nuScenes datasets demonstrate that our OC3D with only coarse clicks achieves state-of-the-art performance compared to weakly-supervised 3D detection methods. Combining OC3D with a missing click mining strategy, we propose a OC3D++ pipeline, which requires only 0.2% annotation cost in the KITTI dataset to achieve performance comparable to fully supervised methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08092v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qiming Xia, Hongwei Lin, Wei Ye, Hai Wu, Yadan Luo, Shijia Zhao, Xin Li, Chenglu Wen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Video Coding Meets Multimodal Large Language Models: A Unified Paradigm for Video Coding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08093</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08093v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Existing codecs are designed to eliminate intrinsic redundancies to create a compact representation for compression. However, strong external priors from Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) have not been explicitly explored in video compression. Herein, we introduce a unified paradigm for Cross-Modality Video Coding (CMVC), which is a pioneering approach to explore multimodality representation and video generative models in video coding. Specifically, on the encoder side, we disentangle a video into spatial content and motion components, which are subsequently transformed into distinct modalities to achieve very compact representation by leveraging MLLMs. During decoding, previously encoded components and video generation models are leveraged to create multiple encoding-decoding modes that optimize video reconstruction quality for specific decoding requirements, including Text-Text-to-Video (TT2V) mode to ensure high-quality semantic information and Image-Text-to-Video (IT2V) mode to achieve superb perceptual consistency. In addition, we propose an efficient frame interpolation model for IT2V mode via Low-Rank Adaption (LoRA) tuning to guarantee perceptual quality, which allows the generated motion cues to behave smoothly. Experiments on benchmarks indicate that TT2V achieves effective semantic reconstruction, while IT2V exhibits competitive perceptual consistency. These results highlight potential directions for future research in video coding.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08093v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Pingping Zhang, Jinlong Li, Meng Wang, Nicu Sebe, Sam Kwong, Shiqi Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multimodal Causal Reasoning Benchmark: Challenging Vision Large Language Models to Infer Causal Links Between Siamese Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08105</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08105v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have showcased exceptional ability in causal reasoning from textual information. However, will these causalities remain straightforward for Vision Large Language Models (VLLMs) when only visual hints are provided? Motivated by this, we propose a novel Multimodal Causal Reasoning benchmark, namely MuCR, to challenge VLLMs to infer semantic cause-and-effect relationship when solely relying on visual cues such as action, appearance, clothing, and environment. Specifically, we introduce a prompt-driven image synthesis approach to create siamese images with embedded semantic causality and visual cues, which can effectively evaluate VLLMs' causal reasoning capabilities. Additionally, we develop tailored metrics from multiple perspectives, including image-level match, phrase-level understanding, and sentence-level explanation, to comprehensively assess VLLMs' comprehension abilities. Our extensive experiments reveal that the current state-of-the-art VLLMs are not as skilled at multimodal causal reasoning as we might have hoped. Furthermore, we perform a comprehensive analysis to understand these models' shortcomings from different views and suggest directions for future research. We hope MuCR can serve as a valuable resource and foundational benchmark in multimodal causal reasoning research. The project is available at: https://github.com/Zhiyuan-Li-John/MuCR</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08105v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhiyuan Li, Heng Wang, Dongnan Liu, Chaoyi Zhang, Ao Ma, Jieting Long, Weidong Cai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unsupervised Part Discovery via Dual Representation Alignment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08108</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08108v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Object parts serve as crucial intermediate representations in various downstream tasks, but part-level representation learning still has not received as much attention as other vision tasks. Previous research has established that Vision Transformer can learn instance-level attention without labels, extracting high-quality instance-level representations for boosting downstream tasks. In this paper, we achieve unsupervised part-specific attention learning using a novel paradigm and further employ the part representations to improve part discovery performance. Specifically, paired images are generated from the same image with different geometric transformations, and multiple part representations are extracted from these paired images using a novel module, named PartFormer. These part representations from the paired images are then exchanged to improve geometric transformation invariance. Subsequently, the part representations are aligned with the feature map extracted by a feature map encoder, achieving high similarity with the pixel representations of the corresponding part regions and low similarity in irrelevant regions. Finally, the geometric and semantic constraints are applied to the part representations through the intermediate results in alignment for part-specific attention learning, encouraging the PartFormer to focus locally and the part representations to explicitly include the information of the corresponding parts. Moreover, the aligned part representations can further serve as a series of reliable detectors in the testing phase, predicting pixel masks for part discovery. Extensive experiments are carried out on four widely used datasets, and our results demonstrate that the proposed method achieves competitive performance and robustness due to its part-specific attention.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08108v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiahao Xia, Wenjian Huang, Min Xu, Jianguo Zhang, Haimin Zhang, Ziyu Sheng, Dong Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Category-Prompt Refined Feature Learning for Long-Tailed Multi-Label Image Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08125</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08125v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Real-world data consistently exhibits a long-tailed distribution, often spanning multiple categories. This complexity underscores the challenge of content comprehension, particularly in scenarios requiring Long-Tailed Multi-Label image Classification (LTMLC). In such contexts, imbalanced data distribution and multi-object recognition pose significant hurdles. To address this issue, we propose a novel and effective approach for LTMLC, termed Category-Prompt Refined Feature Learning (CPRFL), utilizing semantic correlations between different categories and decoupling category-specific visual representations for each category. Specifically, CPRFL initializes category-prompts from the pretrained CLIP's embeddings and decouples category-specific visual representations through interaction with visual features, thereby facilitating the establishment of semantic correlations between the head and tail classes. To mitigate the visual-semantic domain bias, we design a progressive Dual-Path Back-Propagation mechanism to refine the prompts by progressively incorporating context-related visual information into prompts. Simultaneously, the refinement process facilitates the progressive purification of the category-specific visual representations under the guidance of the refined prompts. Furthermore, taking into account the negative-positive sample imbalance, we adopt the Asymmetric Loss as our optimization objective to suppress negative samples across all classes and potentially enhance the head-to-tail recognition performance. We validate the effectiveness of our method on two LTMLC benchmarks and extensive experiments demonstrate the superiority of our work over baselines.
  The code is available at https://github.com/jiexuanyan/CPRFL.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08125v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiexuan Yan, Sheng Huang, Nankun Mu, Luwen Huangfu, Bo Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CorrAdaptor: Adaptive Local Context Learning for Correspondence Pruning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08134</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08134v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In the fields of computer vision and robotics, accurate pixel-level correspondences are essential for enabling advanced tasks such as structure-from-motion and simultaneous localization and mapping. Recent correspondence pruning methods usually focus on learning local consistency through k-nearest neighbors, which makes it difficult to capture robust context for each correspondence. We propose CorrAdaptor, a novel architecture that introduces a dual-branch structure capable of adaptively adjusting local contexts through both explicit and implicit local graph learning. Specifically, the explicit branch uses KNN-based graphs tailored for initial neighborhood identification, while the implicit branch leverages a learnable matrix to softly assign neighbors and adaptively expand the local context scope, significantly enhancing the model's robustness and adaptability to complex image variations. Moreover, we design a motion injection module to integrate motion consistency into the network to suppress the impact of outliers and refine local context learning, resulting in substantial performance improvements. The experimental results on extensive correspondence-based tasks indicate that our CorrAdaptor achieves state-of-the-art performance both qualitatively and quantitatively. The code and pre-trained models are available at https://github.com/TaoWangzj/CorrAdaptor.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08134v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wei Zhu, Yicheng Liu, Yuping He, Tangfei Liao, Kang Zheng, Xiaoqiu Xu, Tao Wang, Tong Lu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unsupervised Variational Translator for Bridging Image Restoration and High-Level Vision Tasks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08149</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08149v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent research tries to extend image restoration capabilities from human perception to machine perception, thereby enhancing the performance of high-level vision tasks in degraded environments. These methods, primarily based on supervised learning, typically involve the retraining of restoration networks or high-level vision networks. However, collecting paired data in real-world scenarios and retraining large-scale models are challenge. To this end, we propose an unsupervised learning method called \textbf{Va}riational \textbf{T}ranslator (VaT), which does not require retraining existing restoration and high-level vision networks. Instead, it establishes a lightweight network that serves as an intermediate bridge between them. By variational inference, VaT approximates the joint distribution of restoration output and high-level vision input, dividing the optimization objective into preserving content and maximizing marginal likelihood associated with high-level vision tasks. By cleverly leveraging self-training paradigms, VaT achieves the above optimization objective without requiring labels. As a result, the translated images maintain a close resemblance to their original content while also demonstrating exceptional performance on high-level vision tasks. Extensive experiments in dehazing and low-light enhancement for detection and classification show the superiority of our method over other state-of-the-art unsupervised counterparts, even significantly surpassing supervised methods in some complex real-world scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08149v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiawei Wu, Zhi Jin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards flexible perception with visual memory</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08172</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08172v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Training a neural network is a monolithic endeavor, akin to carving knowledge into stone: once the process is completed, editing the knowledge in a network is nearly impossible, since all information is distributed across the network's weights. We here explore a simple, compelling alternative by marrying the representational power of deep neural networks with the flexibility of a database. Decomposing the task of image classification into image similarity (from a pre-trained embedding) and search (via fast nearest neighbor retrieval from a knowledge database), we build a simple and flexible visual memory that has the following key capabilities: (1.) The ability to flexibly add data across scales: from individual samples all the way to entire classes and billion-scale data; (2.) The ability to remove data through unlearning and memory pruning; (3.) An interpretable decision-mechanism on which we can intervene to control its behavior. Taken together, these capabilities comprehensively demonstrate the benefits of an explicit visual memory. We hope that it might contribute to a conversation on how knowledge should be represented in deep vision models -- beyond carving it in ``stone'' weights.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08172v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Robert Geirhos, Priyank Jaini, Austin Stone, Sourabh Medapati, Xi Yi, George Toderici, Abhijit Ogale, Jonathon Shlens</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your Turn: Real-World Turning Angle Estimation for Parkinson's Disease Severity Assessment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08182</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08182v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: People with Parkinson's Disease (PD) often experience progressively worsening gait, including changes in how they turn around, as the disease progresses. Existing clinical rating tools are not capable of capturing hour-by-hour variations of PD symptoms, as they are confined to brief assessments within clinic settings. Measuring real-world gait turning angles continuously and passively is a component step towards using gait characteristics as sensitive indicators of disease progression in PD. This paper presents a deep learning-based approach to automatically quantify turning angles by extracting 3D skeletons from videos and calculating the rotation of hip and knee joints. We utilise state-of-the-art human pose estimation models, Fastpose and Strided Transformer, on a total of 1386 turning video clips from 24 subjects (12 people with PD and 12 healthy control volunteers), trimmed from a PD dataset of unscripted free-living videos in a home-like setting (Turn-REMAP). We also curate a turning video dataset, Turn-H3.6M, from the public Human3.6M human pose benchmark with 3D ground truth, to further validate our method. Previous gait research has primarily taken place in clinics or laboratories evaluating scripted gait outcomes, but this work focuses on real-world settings where complexities exist, such as baggy clothing and poor lighting. Due to difficulties in obtaining accurate ground truth data in a free-living setting, we quantise the angle into the nearest bin $45^\circ$ based on the manual labelling of expert clinicians. Our method achieves a turning calculation accuracy of 41.6%, a Mean Absolute Error (MAE) of 34.7{\deg}, and a weighted precision WPrec of 68.3% for Turn-REMAP. This is the first work to explore the use of single monocular camera data to quantify turns by PD patients in a home setting.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08182v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qiushuo Cheng, Catherine Morgan, Arindam Sikdar, Alessandro Masullo, Alan Whone, Majid Mirmehdi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Not Every Image is Worth a Thousand Words: Quantifying Originality in Stable Diffusion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08184</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08184v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This work addresses the challenge of quantifying originality in text-to-image (T2I) generative diffusion models, with a focus on copyright originality. We begin by evaluating T2I models' ability to innovate and generalize through controlled experiments, revealing that stable diffusion models can effectively recreate unseen elements with sufficiently diverse training data. Then, our key insight is that concepts and combinations of image elements the model is familiar with, and saw more during training, are more concisly represented in the model's latent space. We hence propose a method that leverages textual inversion to measure the originality of an image based on the number of tokens required for its reconstruction by the model. Our approach is inspired by legal definitions of originality and aims to assess whether a model can produce original content without relying on specific prompts or having the training data of the model. We demonstrate our method using both a pre-trained stable diffusion model and a synthetic dataset, showing a correlation between the number of tokens and image originality. This work contributes to the understanding of originality in generative models and has implications for copyright infringement cases.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08184v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Adi Haviv, Shahar Sarfaty, Uri Hacohen, Niva Elkin-Koren, Roi Livni, Amit H Bermano</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FancyVideo: Towards Dynamic and Consistent Video Generation via Cross-frame Textual Guidance</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08189</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08189v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Synthesizing motion-rich and temporally consistent videos remains a challenge in artificial intelligence, especially when dealing with extended durations. Existing text-to-video (T2V) models commonly employ spatial cross-attention for text control, equivalently guiding different frame generations without frame-specific textual guidance. Thus, the model's capacity to comprehend the temporal logic conveyed in prompts and generate videos with coherent motion is restricted. To tackle this limitation, we introduce FancyVideo, an innovative video generator that improves the existing text-control mechanism with the well-designed Cross-frame Textual Guidance Module (CTGM). Specifically, CTGM incorporates the Temporal Information Injector (TII), Temporal Affinity Refiner (TAR), and Temporal Feature Booster (TFB) at the beginning, middle, and end of cross-attention, respectively, to achieve frame-specific textual guidance. Firstly, TII injects frame-specific information from latent features into text conditions, thereby obtaining cross-frame textual conditions. Then, TAR refines the correlation matrix between cross-frame textual conditions and latent features along the time dimension. Lastly, TFB boosts the temporal consistency of latent features. Extensive experiments comprising both quantitative and qualitative evaluations demonstrate the effectiveness of FancyVideo. Our approach achieves state-of-the-art T2V generation results on the EvalCrafter benchmark and facilitates the synthesis of dynamic and consistent videos. The video show results can be available at https://fancyvideo.github.io/, and we will make our code and model weights publicly available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08189v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiasong Feng, Ao Ma, Jing Wang, Bo Cheng, Xiaodan Liang, Dawei Leng, Yuhui Yin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Full Label: Single-Point Prompt for Infrared Small Target Label Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08191</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08191v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this work, we make the first attempt to construct a learning-based single-point annotation paradigm for infrared small target label generation (IRSTLG). Our intuition is that label generation requires just one more point prompt than target detection: IRSTLG can be regarded as an infrared small target detection (IRSTD) task with the target location hint. Based on this insight, we introduce an energy double guided single-point prompt (EDGSP) framework, which adeptly transforms the target detection network into a refined label generation method. Specifically, the proposed EDGSP includes: 1) target energy initialization (TEI) to create a foundational outline for sufficient shape evolution of pseudo label, 2) double prompt embedding (DPE) for rapid localization of interested regions and reinforcement of individual differences to avoid label adhesion, and 3) bounding box-based matching (BBM) to eliminate false alarms. Experimental results show that pseudo labels generated by three baselines equipped with EDGSP achieve 100% object-level probability of detection (Pd) and 0% false-alarm rate (Fa) on SIRST, NUDT-SIRST, and IRSTD-1k datasets, with a pixel-level intersection over union (IoU) improvement of 13.28% over state-of-the-art label generation methods. Additionally, the downstream detection task reveals that our centroid-annotated pseudo labels surpass full labels, even with coarse single-point annotations, it still achieves 99.5% performance of full labeling.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08191v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shuai Yuan, Hanlin Qin, Renke Kou, Xiang Yan, Zechuan Li, Chenxu Peng, Abd-Krim Seghouane</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heavy Labels Out! Dataset Distillation with Label Space Lightening</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08201</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08201v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Dataset distillation or condensation aims to condense a large-scale training dataset into a much smaller synthetic one such that the training performance of distilled and original sets on neural networks are similar. Although the number of training samples can be reduced substantially, current state-of-the-art methods heavily rely on enormous soft labels to achieve satisfactory performance. As a result, the required storage can be comparable even to original datasets, especially for large-scale ones. To solve this problem, instead of storing these heavy labels, we propose a novel label-lightening framework termed HeLlO aiming at effective image-to-label projectors, with which synthetic labels can be directly generated online from synthetic images. Specifically, to construct such projectors, we leverage prior knowledge in open-source foundation models, e.g., CLIP, and introduce a LoRA-like fine-tuning strategy to mitigate the gap between pre-trained and target distributions, so that original models for soft-label generation can be distilled into a group of low-rank matrices. Moreover, an effective image optimization method is proposed to further mitigate the potential error between the original and distilled label generators. Extensive experiments demonstrate that with only about 0.003% of the original storage required for a complete set of soft labels, we achieve comparable performance to current state-of-the-art dataset distillation methods on large-scale datasets. Our code will be available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08201v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ruonan Yu, Songhua Liu, Zigeng Chen, Jingwen Ye, Xinchao Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Practical Human Motion Prediction with LiDAR Point Clouds</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08202</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08202v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Human motion prediction is crucial for human-centric multimedia understanding and interacting. Current methods typically rely on ground truth human poses as observed input, which is not practical for real-world scenarios where only raw visual sensor data is available. To implement these methods in practice, a pre-phrase of pose estimation is essential. However, such two-stage approaches often lead to performance degradation due to the accumulation of errors. Moreover, reducing raw visual data to sparse keypoint representations significantly diminishes the density of information, resulting in the loss of fine-grained features. In this paper, we propose \textit{LiDAR-HMP}, the first single-LiDAR-based 3D human motion prediction approach, which receives the raw LiDAR point cloud as input and forecasts future 3D human poses directly. Building upon our novel structure-aware body feature descriptor, LiDAR-HMP adaptively maps the observed motion manifold to future poses and effectively models the spatial-temporal correlations of human motions for further refinement of prediction results. Extensive experiments show that our method achieves state-of-the-art performance on two public benchmarks and demonstrates remarkable robustness and efficacy in real-world deployments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08202v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiao Han, Yiming Ren, Yichen Yao, Yujing Sun, Yuexin Ma</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Multi-task Adversarial Attack Against Face Authentication</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08205</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08205v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Deep-learning-based identity management systems, such as face authentication systems, are vulnerable to adversarial attacks. However, existing attacks are typically designed for single-task purposes, which means they are tailored to exploit vulnerabilities unique to the individual target rather than being adaptable for multiple users or systems. This limitation makes them unsuitable for certain attack scenarios, such as morphing, universal, transferable, and counter attacks. In this paper, we propose a multi-task adversarial attack algorithm called MTADV that are adaptable for multiple users or systems. By interpreting these scenarios as multi-task attacks, MTADV is applicable to both single- and multi-task attacks, and feasible in the white- and gray-box settings. Furthermore, MTADV is effective against various face datasets, including LFW, CelebA, and CelebA-HQ, and can work with different deep learning models, such as FaceNet, InsightFace, and CurricularFace. Importantly, MTADV retains its feasibility as a single-task attack targeting a single user/system. To the best of our knowledge, MTADV is the first adversarial attack method that can target all of the aforementioned scenarios in one algorithm.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08205v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/366549</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Hanrui Wang, Shuo Wang, Cunjian Chen, Massimo Tistarelli, Zhe Jin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WaterSplatting: Fast Underwater 3D Scene Reconstruction Using Gaussian Splatting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08206</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08206v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The underwater 3D scene reconstruction is a challenging, yet interesting problem with applications ranging from naval robots to VR experiences. The problem was successfully tackled by fully volumetric NeRF-based methods which can model both the geometry and the medium (water). Unfortunately, these methods are slow to train and do not offer real-time rendering. More recently, 3D Gaussian Splatting (3DGS) method offered a fast alternative to NeRFs. However, because it is an explicit method that renders only the geometry, it cannot render the medium and is therefore unsuited for underwater reconstruction. Therefore, we propose a novel approach that fuses volumetric rendering with 3DGS to handle underwater data effectively. Our method employs 3DGS for explicit geometry representation and a separate volumetric field (queried once per pixel) for capturing the scattering medium. This dual representation further allows the restoration of the scenes by removing the scattering medium. Our method outperforms state-of-the-art NeRF-based methods in rendering quality on the underwater SeaThru-NeRF dataset. Furthermore, it does so while offering real-time rendering performance, addressing the efficiency limitations of existing methods. Web: https://water-splatting.github.io</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08206v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Huapeng Li, Wenxuan Song, Tianao Xu, Alexandre Elsig, Jonas Kulhanek</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Dawn of KAN in Image-to-Image (I2I) Translation: Integrating Kolmogorov-Arnold Networks with GANs for Unpaired I2I Translation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08216</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08216v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Image-to-Image translation in Generative Artificial Intelligence (Generative AI) has been a central focus of research, with applications spanning healthcare, remote sensing, physics, chemistry, photography, and more. Among the numerous methodologies, Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs) with contrastive learning have been particularly successful. This study aims to demonstrate that the Kolmogorov-Arnold Network (KAN) can effectively replace the Multi-layer Perceptron (MLP) method in generative AI, particularly in the subdomain of image-to-image translation, to achieve better generative quality. Our novel approach replaces the two-layer MLP with a two-layer KAN in the existing Contrastive Unpaired Image-to-Image Translation (CUT) model, developing the KAN-CUT model. This substitution favors the generation of more informative features in low-dimensional vector representations, which contrastive learning can utilize more effectively to produce high-quality images in the target domain. Extensive experiments, detailed in the results section, demonstrate the applicability of KAN in conjunction with contrastive learning and GANs in Generative AI, particularly for image-to-image translation. This work suggests that KAN could be a valuable component in the broader generative AI domain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08216v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Arpan Mahara, Naphtali D. Rishe, Liangdong Deng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Evaluation of 3D Reconstruction Methods for Object Pose Estimation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08234</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08234v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Object pose estimation is essential to many industrial applications involving robotic manipulation, navigation, and augmented reality. Current generalizable object pose estimators, i.e., approaches that do not need to be trained per object, rely on accurate 3D models. Predominantly, CAD models are used, which can be hard to obtain in practice. At the same time, it is often possible to acquire images of an object. Naturally, this leads to the question whether 3D models reconstructed from images are sufficient to facilitate accurate object pose estimation. We aim to answer this question by proposing a novel benchmark for measuring the impact of 3D reconstruction quality on pose estimation accuracy. Our benchmark provides calibrated images for object reconstruction registered with the test images of the YCB-V dataset for pose evaluation under the BOP benchmark format. Detailed experiments with multiple state-of-the-art 3D reconstruction and object pose estimation approaches show that the geometry produced by modern reconstruction methods is often sufficient for accurate pose estimation. Our experiments lead to interesting observations: (1) Standard metrics for measuring 3D reconstruction quality are not necessarily indicative of pose estimation accuracy, which shows the need for dedicated benchmarks such as ours. (2) Classical, non-learning-based approaches can perform on par with modern learning-based reconstruction techniques and can even offer a better reconstruction time-pose accuracy tradeoff. (3) There is still a sizable gap between performance with reconstructed and with CAD models. To foster research on closing this gap, our benchmark is publicly available at https://github.com/VarunBurde/reconstruction_pose_benchmark}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08234v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Varun Burde, Assia Benbihi, Pavel Burget, Torsten Sattler</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computer Vision Model Compression Techniques for Embedded Systems: A Survey</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08250</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08250v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Deep neural networks have consistently represented the state of the art in most computer vision problems. In these scenarios, larger and more complex models have demonstrated superior performance to smaller architectures, especially when trained with plenty of representative data. With the recent adoption of Vision Transformer (ViT) based architectures and advanced Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs), the total number of parameters of leading backbone architectures increased from 62M parameters in 2012 with AlexNet to 7B parameters in 2024 with AIM-7B. Consequently, deploying such deep architectures faces challenges in environments with processing and runtime constraints, particularly in embedded systems. This paper covers the main model compression techniques applied for computer vision tasks, enabling modern models to be used in embedded systems. We present the characteristics of compression subareas, compare different approaches, and discuss how to choose the best technique and expected variations when analyzing it on various embedded devices. We also share codes to assist researchers and new practitioners in overcoming initial implementation challenges for each subarea and present trends for Model Compression. Case studies for compression models are available at \href{https://github.com/venturusbr/cv-model-compression}{https://github.com/venturusbr/cv-model-compression}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08250v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1016/j.cag.2024.104015</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Computers &amp; Graphics, Volume 123, October 2024, 104015</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Alexandre Lopes, Fernando Pereira dos Santos, Diulhio de Oliveira, Mauricio Schiezaro, Helio Pedrini</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Snuffy: Efficient Whole Slide Image Classifier</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08258</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08258v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Whole Slide Image (WSI) classification with multiple instance learning (MIL) in digital pathology faces significant computational challenges. Current methods mostly rely on extensive self-supervised learning (SSL) for satisfactory performance, requiring long training periods and considerable computational resources. At the same time, no pre-training affects performance due to domain shifts from natural images to WSIs. We introduce \textbf{\textit{Snuffy}} architecture, a novel MIL-pooling method based on sparse transformers that mitigates performance loss with limited pre-training and enables continual few-shot pre-training as a competitive option. Our sparsity pattern is tailored for pathology and is theoretically proven to be a universal approximator with the tightest probabilistic sharp bound on the number of layers for sparse transformers, to date. We demonstrate Snuffy's effectiveness on CAMELYON16 and TCGA Lung cancer datasets, achieving superior WSI and patch-level accuracies. The code is available on \url{https://github.com/jafarinia/snuffy}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08258v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.NE</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hossein Jafarinia, Alireza Alipanah, Danial Hamdi, Saeed Razavi, Nahal Mirzaie, Mohammad Hossein Rohban</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HeightLane: BEV Heightmap guided 3D Lane Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08270</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08270v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Accurate 3D lane detection from monocular images presents significant challenges due to depth ambiguity and imperfect ground modeling. Previous attempts to model the ground have often used a planar ground assumption with limited degrees of freedom, making them unsuitable for complex road environments with varying slopes. Our study introduces HeightLane, an innovative method that predicts a height map from monocular images by creating anchors based on a multi-slope assumption. This approach provides a detailed and accurate representation of the ground. HeightLane employs the predicted heightmap along with a deformable attention-based spatial feature transform framework to efficiently convert 2D image features into 3D bird's eye view (BEV) features, enhancing spatial understanding and lane structure recognition. Additionally, the heightmap is used for the positional encoding of BEV features, further improving their spatial accuracy. This explicit view transformation bridges the gap between front-view perceptions and spatially accurate BEV representations, significantly improving detection performance. To address the lack of the necessary ground truth (GT) height map in the original OpenLane dataset, we leverage the Waymo dataset and accumulate its LiDAR data to generate a height map for the drivable area of each scene. The GT heightmaps are used to train the heightmap extraction module from monocular images. Extensive experiments on the OpenLane validation set show that HeightLane achieves state-of-the-art performance in terms of F-score, highlighting its potential in real-world applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08270v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chaesong Park, Eunbin Seo, Jongwoo Lim</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SLCA++: Unleash the Power of Sequential Fine-tuning for Continual Learning with Pre-training</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08295</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08295v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In recent years, continual learning with pre-training (CLPT) has received widespread interest, instead of its traditional focus of training from scratch. The use of strong pre-trained models (PTMs) can greatly facilitate knowledge transfer and alleviate catastrophic forgetting, but also suffers from progressive overfitting of pre-trained knowledge into specific downstream tasks. A majority of current efforts often keep the PTMs frozen and incorporate task-specific prompts to instruct representation learning, coupled with a prompt selection process for inference. However, due to the limited capacity of prompt parameters, this strategy demonstrates only sub-optimal performance in continual learning. In comparison, tuning all parameters of PTMs often provides the greatest potential for representation learning, making sequential fine-tuning (Seq FT) a fundamental baseline that has been overlooked in CLPT. To this end, we present an in-depth analysis of the progressive overfitting problem from the lens of Seq FT. Considering that the overly fast representation learning and the biased classification layer constitute this particular problem, we introduce the advanced Slow Learner with Classifier Alignment (SLCA++) framework to unleash the power of Seq FT, serving as a strong baseline approach for CLPT. Our approach involves a Slow Learner to selectively reduce the learning rate of backbone parameters, and a Classifier Alignment to align the disjoint classification layers in a post-hoc fashion. We further enhance the efficacy of SL with a symmetric cross-entropy loss, as well as employ a parameter-efficient strategy to implement Seq FT with SLCA++. Across a variety of continual learning scenarios on image classification benchmarks, our approach provides substantial improvements and outperforms state-of-the-art methods by a large margin. Code: https://github.com/GengDavid/SLCA.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08295v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gengwei Zhang, Liyuan Wang, Guoliang Kang, Ling Chen, Yunchao Wei</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Flexible Visual Relationship Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08305</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08305v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Visual relationship understanding has been studied separately in human-object interaction(HOI) detection, scene graph generation(SGG), and referring relationships(RR) tasks. Given the complexity and interconnectedness of these tasks, it is crucial to have a flexible framework that can effectively address these tasks in a cohesive manner. In this work, we propose FleVRS, a single model that seamlessly integrates the above three aspects in standard and promptable visual relationship segmentation, and further possesses the capability for open-vocabulary segmentation to adapt to novel scenarios. FleVRS leverages the synergy between text and image modalities, to ground various types of relationships from images and use textual features from vision-language models to visual conceptual understanding. Empirical validation across various datasets demonstrates that our framework outperforms existing models in standard, promptable, and open-vocabulary tasks, e.g., +1.9 $mAP$ on HICO-DET, +11.4 $Acc$ on VRD, +4.7 $mAP$ on unseen HICO-DET. Our FleVRS represents a significant step towards a more intuitive, comprehensive, and scalable understanding of visual relationships.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08305v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fangrui Zhu, Jianwei Yang, Huaizu Jiang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Guide to Similarity Measures</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07706</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07706v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Similarity measures play a central role in various data science application domains for a wide assortment of tasks. This guide describes a comprehensive set of prevalent similarity measures to serve both non-experts and professional. Non-experts that wish to understand the motivation for a measure as well as how to use it may find a friendly and detailed exposition of the formulas of the measures, whereas experts may find a glance to the principles of designing similarity measures and ideas for a better way to measure similarity for their desired task in a given application domain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07706v1</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Avivit Levy, B. Riva Shalom, Michal Chalamish</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perspectives: Comparison of Deep Learning Segmentation Models on Biophysical and Biomedical Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07786</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07786v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Deep learning based approaches are now widely used across biophysics to help automate a variety of tasks including image segmentation, feature selection, and deconvolution. However, the presence of multiple competing deep learning architectures, each with its own unique advantages and disadvantages, makes it challenging to select an architecture best suited for a specific application. As such, we present a comprehensive comparison of common models. Here, we focus on the task of segmentation assuming the typically small training dataset sizes available from biophysics experiments and compare the following four commonly used architectures: convolutional neural networks, U-Nets, vision transformers, and vision state space models. In doing so, we establish criteria for determining optimal conditions under which each model excels, thereby offering practical guidelines for researchers and practitioners in the field.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07786v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>physics.bio-ph</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>J Shepard Bryan IV, Meyam Tavakoli, Steve Presse</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Efficient and Explanatory Image and Text Clustering System with Multimodal Autoencoder Architecture</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07791</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07791v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We demonstrate the efficiencies and explanatory abilities of extensions to the common tools of Autoencoders and LLM interpreters, in the novel context of comparing different cultural approaches to the same international news event. We develop a new Convolutional-Recurrent Variational Autoencoder (CRVAE) model that extends the modalities of previous CVAE models, by using fully-connected latent layers to embed in parallel the CNN encodings of video frames, together with the LSTM encodings of their related text derived from audio. We incorporate the model within a larger system that includes frame-caption alignment, latent space vector clustering, and a novel LLM-based cluster interpreter. We measure, tune, and apply this system to the task of summarizing a video into three to five thematic clusters, with each theme described by ten LLM-produced phrases. We apply this system to two news topics, COVID-19 and the Winter Olympics, and five other topics are in progress.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07791v1</guid>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tiancheng Shi, Yuanchen Wei, John R. Kender</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regularized Contrastive Partial Multi-view Outlier Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07819</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07819v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In recent years, multi-view outlier detection (MVOD) methods have advanced significantly, aiming to identify outliers within multi-view datasets. A key point is to better detect class outliers and class-attribute outliers, which only exist in multi-view data. However, existing methods either is not able to reduce the impact of outliers when learning view-consistent information, or struggle in cases with varying neighborhood structures. Moreover, most of them do not apply to partial multi-view data in real-world scenarios. To overcome these drawbacks, we propose a novel method named Regularized Contrastive Partial Multi-view Outlier Detection (RCPMOD). In this framework, we utilize contrastive learning to learn view-consistent information and distinguish outliers by the degree of consistency. Specifically, we propose (1) An outlier-aware contrastive loss with a potential outlier memory bank to eliminate their bias motivated by a theoretical analysis. (2) A neighbor alignment contrastive loss to capture the view-shared local structural correlation. (3) A spreading regularization loss to prevent the model from overfitting over outliers. With the Cross-view Relation Transfer technique, we could easily impute the missing view samples based on the features of neighbors. Experimental results on four benchmark datasets demonstrate that our proposed approach could outperform state-of-the-art competitors under different settings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07819v1</guid>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3664647.3681125</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Yijia Wang, Qianqian Xu, Yangbangyan Jiang, Siran Dai, Qingming Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Language Driven Slice Discovery and Error Rectification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07832</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07832v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Error slice discovery associates structured patterns with model errors. Existing methods discover error slices by clustering the error-prone samples with similar patterns or assigning discrete attributes to each sample for post-hoc analysis. While these methods aim for interpretability and easier mitigation through reweighting or rebalancing, they may not capture the full complexity of error patterns due to incomplete or missing attributes. Contrary to the existing approach, this paper utilizes the reasoning capabilities of the Large Language Model (LLM) to analyze complex error patterns and generate testable hypotheses. This paper proposes LADDER: Language Driven slice Discovery and Error Rectification. It first projects the model's representation into a language-aligned feature space (\eg CLIP) to preserve semantics in the original model feature space. This ensures the accurate retrieval of sentences that highlight the model's errors. Next, the LLM utilizes the sentences and generates hypotheses to discover error slices. Finally, we mitigate the error by fine-tuning the classification head by creating a group-balanced dataset using the hypotheses. Our entire method does not require any attribute annotation, either explicitly or through external tagging models. We validate our method with \textbf{five} image classification datasets. The code is available\footnote{\url{https://github.com/batmanlab/Ladder}}</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07832v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shantanu Ghosh, Chenyu Wang, Kayhan Batmanghelich</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Novel Generative Artificial Intelligence Method for Interference Study on Multiplex Brightfield Immunohistochemistry Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07860</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07860v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Multiplex brightfield imaging offers the advantage of simultaneously analyzing multiple biomarkers on a single slide, as opposed to single biomarker labeling on multiple consecutive slides. To accurately analyze multiple biomarkers localized at the same cellular compartment, two representative biomarker sets were selected as assay models - cMET-PDL1-EGFR and CD8-LAG3-PDL1, where all three biomarkers can co-localize on the cell membrane. One of the most crucial preliminary stages for analyzing such assay is identifying each unique chromogen on individual cells. This is a challenging problem due to the co-localization of membrane stains from all the three biomarkers. It requires advanced color unmixing for creating the equivalent singleplex images from each triplex image for each biomarker.
  In this project, we developed a cycle-Generative Adversarial Network (cycle-GAN) method for unmixing the triplex images generated from the above-mentioned assays. Three different models were designed to generate the singleplex image for each of the three stains Tamra (purple), QM-Dabsyl (yellow) and Green. A notable novelty of our approach was that the input to the network were images in the optical density domain instead of conventionally used RGB images. The use of the optical density domain helped in reducing the blurriness of the synthetic singleplex images, which was often observed when the network was trained on RGB images.
  The cycle-GAN models were validated on 10,800 lung, gastric and colon images for the cMET-PDL1-EGFR assay and 3600 colon images for the CD8-LAG3-PDL1 assay. Visual as well as quantified assessments demonstrated that the proposed method is effective and efficient when compared with the manual reviewing results and is readily applicable to various multiplex assays.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07860v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Satarupa Mukherjee, Jim Martin, Yao Nie</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Joint Denoising and Detection for Enhanced Intracellular Particle Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07903</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07903v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Reliable analysis of intracellular dynamic processes in time-lapse fluorescence microscopy images requires complete and accurate tracking of all small particles in all time frames of the image sequences. A fundamental first step towards this goal is particle detection. Given the small size of the particles, their detection is greatly affected by image noise. Recent studies have shown that applying image denoising as a preprocessing step indeed improves particle detection and their subsequent tracking. Deep learning based particle detection methods have shown superior results compared to traditional detection methods. However, they do not explicitly aim to remove noise from the images to facilitate detection. Thus we hypothesize that their performance could be further improved. In this paper, we propose a new deep neural network, called DENODET (denoising-detection network), which performs image denoising and particle detection simultaneously. We show that integrative denoising and detection yields more accurate detection results. Our method achieves superior results compared to state-of-the-art particle detection methods on the particle tracking challenge dataset and our own real fluorescence microscopy image data.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07903v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yao Yao, Ihor Smal, Ilya Grigoriev, Anna Akhmanova, Erik Meijering</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DM2RM: Dual-Mode Multimodal Ranking for Target Objects and Receptacles Based on Open-Vocabulary Instructions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07910</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07910v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In this study, we aim to develop a domestic service robot (DSR) that, guided by open-vocabulary instructions, can carry everyday objects to the specified pieces of furniture. Few existing methods handle mobile manipulation tasks with open-vocabulary instructions in the image retrieval setting, and most do not identify both the target objects and the receptacles. We propose the Dual-Mode Multimodal Ranking model (DM2RM), which enables images of both the target objects and receptacles to be retrieved using a single model based on multimodal foundation models. We introduce a switching mechanism that leverages a mode token and phrase identification via a large language model to switch the embedding space based on the prediction target. To evaluate the DM2RM, we construct a novel dataset including real-world images collected from hundreds of building-scale environments and crowd-sourced instructions with referring expressions. The evaluation results show that the proposed DM2RM outperforms previous approaches in terms of standard metrics in image retrieval settings. Furthermore, we demonstrate the application of the DM2RM on a standardized real-world DSR platform including fetch-and-carry actions, where it achieves a task success rate of 82% despite the zero-shot transfer setting. Demonstration videos, code, and more materials are available at https://kkrr10.github.io/dm2rm/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07910v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ryosuke Korekata, Kanta Kaneda, Shunya Nagashima, Yuto Imai, Komei Sugiura</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GOReloc: Graph-based Object-Level Relocalization for Visual SLAM</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07917</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07917v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This article introduces a novel method for object-level relocalization of robotic systems. It determines the pose of a camera sensor by robustly associating the object detections in the current frame with 3D objects in a lightweight object-level map. Object graphs, considering semantic uncertainties, are constructed for both the incoming camera frame and the pre-built map. Objects are represented as graph nodes, and each node employs unique semantic descriptors based on our devised graph kernels. We extract a subgraph from the target map graph by identifying potential object associations for each object detection, then refine these associations and pose estimations using a RANSAC-inspired strategy. Experiments on various datasets demonstrate that our method achieves more accurate data association and significantly increases relocalization success rates compared to baseline methods. The implementation of our method is released at \url{https://github.com/yutongwangBIT/GOReloc}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07917v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1109/LRA.2024.3442560</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters 2024</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Yutong Wang, Chaoyang Jiang, Xieyuanli Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MobileMEF: Fast and Efficient Method for Multi-Exposure Fusion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07932</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07932v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recent advances in camera design and imaging technology have enabled the capture of high-quality images using smartphones. However, due to the limited dynamic range of digital cameras, the quality of photographs captured in environments with highly imbalanced lighting often results in poor-quality images. To address this issue, most devices capture multi-exposure frames and then use some multi-exposure fusion method to merge those frames into a final fused image. Nevertheless, most traditional and current deep learning approaches are unsuitable for real-time applications on mobile devices due to their heavy computational and memory requirements. We propose a new method for multi-exposure fusion based on an encoder-decoder deep learning architecture with efficient building blocks tailored for mobile devices. This efficient design makes our model capable of processing 4K resolution images in less than 2 seconds on mid-range smartphones. Our method outperforms state-of-the-art techniques regarding full-reference quality measures and computational efficiency (runtime and memory usage), making it ideal for real-time applications on hardware-constrained devices. Our code is available at: https://github.com/LucasKirsten/MobileMEF.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07932v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lucas Nedel Kirsten, Zhicheng Fu, Nikhil Ambha Madhusudhana</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conditional Brownian Bridge Diffusion Model for VHR SAR to Optical Image Translation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07947</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07947v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Synthetic Aperture Radar (SAR) imaging technology provides the unique advantage of being able to collect data regardless of weather conditions and time. However, SAR images exhibit complex backscatter patterns and speckle noise, which necessitate expertise for interpretation. To deal with this challenge, research has been conducted on translating SAR images into optical-like representations to aid the interpretation of SAR data. Nevertheless, existing studies have predominantly utilized low-resolution satellite imagery datasets and have largely been based on Generative Adversarial Network (GAN) which are known for their training instability and low fidelity. To overcome these limitations of low-resolution data usage and GAN-based approaches, this paper introduces a conditional image-to-image translation approach based on Brownian Bridge Diffusion Model (BBDM). We conducted comprehensive experiments on the MSAW dataset, a paired SAR and optical images collection of 0.5m Very-High-Resolution (VHR) images. The experimental results indicate that our method surpasses both the Conditional Diffusion Model (CDM) and the GAN-based models in diverse perceptual quality metrics.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07947v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Seon-Hoon Kim, Dae-won Chung</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polaris: Open-ended Interactive Robotic Manipulation via Syn2Real Visual Grounding and Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07975</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07975v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This paper investigates the task of the open-ended interactive robotic manipulation on table-top scenarios. While recent Large Language Models (LLMs) enhance robots' comprehension of user instructions, their lack of visual grounding constrains their ability to physically interact with the environment. This is because the robot needs to locate the target object for manipulation within the physical workspace. To this end, we introduce an interactive robotic manipulation framework called Polaris, which integrates perception and interaction by utilizing GPT-4 alongside grounded vision models. For precise manipulation, it is essential that such grounded vision models produce detailed object pose for the target object, rather than merely identifying pixels belonging to them in the image. Consequently, we propose a novel Synthetic-to-Real (Syn2Real) pose estimation pipeline. This pipeline utilizes rendered synthetic data for training and is then transferred to real-world manipulation tasks. The real-world performance demonstrates the efficacy of our proposed pipeline and underscores its potential for extension to more general categories. Moreover, real-robot experiments have showcased the impressive performance of our framework in grasping and executing multiple manipulation tasks. This indicates its potential to generalize to scenarios beyond the tabletop. More information and video results are available here: https://star-uu-wang.github.io/Polaris/</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07975v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tianyu Wang, Haitao Lin, Junqiu Yu, Yanwei Fu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analytical Uncertainty-Based Loss Weighting in Multi-Task Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07985</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07985v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: With the rise of neural networks in various domains, multi-task learning (MTL) gained significant relevance. A key challenge in MTL is balancing individual task losses during neural network training to improve performance and efficiency through knowledge sharing across tasks. To address these challenges, we propose a novel task-weighting method by building on the most prevalent approach of Uncertainty Weighting and computing analytically optimal uncertainty-based weights, normalized by a softmax function with tunable temperature. Our approach yields comparable results to the combinatorially prohibitive, brute-force approach of Scalarization while offering a more cost-effective yet high-performing alternative. We conduct an extensive benchmark on various datasets and architectures. Our method consistently outperforms six other common weighting methods. Furthermore, we report noteworthy experimental findings for the practical application of MTL. For example, larger networks diminish the influence of weighting methods, and tuning the weight decay has a low impact compared to the learning rate.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07985v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lukas Kirchdorfer, Cathrin Elich, Simon Kutsche, Heiner Stuckenschmidt, Lukas Schott, Jan M. K\"ohler</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asteroid: Resource-Efficient Hybrid Pipeline Parallelism for Collaborative DNN Training on Heterogeneous Edge Devices</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08015</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08015v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: On-device Deep Neural Network (DNN) training has been recognized as crucial for privacy-preserving machine learning at the edge. However, the intensive training workload and limited onboard computing resources pose significant challenges to the availability and efficiency of model training. While existing works address these challenges through native resource management optimization, we instead leverage our observation that edge environments usually comprise a rich set of accompanying trusted edge devices with idle resources beyond a single terminal. We propose Asteroid, a distributed edge training system that breaks the resource walls across heterogeneous edge devices for efficient model training acceleration. Asteroid adopts a hybrid pipeline parallelism to orchestrate distributed training, along with a judicious parallelism planning for maximizing throughput under certain resource constraints. Furthermore, a fault-tolerant yet lightweight pipeline replay mechanism is developed to tame the device-level dynamics for training robustness and performance stability. We implement Asteroid on heterogeneous edge devices with both vision and language models, demonstrating up to 12.2x faster training than conventional parallelism methods and 2.1x faster than state-of-the-art hybrid parallelism methods through evaluations. Furthermore, Asteroid can recover training pipeline 14x faster than baseline methods while preserving comparable throughput despite unexpected device exiting and failure.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08015v1</guid>
      <category>cs.DC</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.NI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shengyuan Ye, Liekang Zeng, Xiaowen Chu, Guoliang Xing, Xu Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PI-Att: Topology Attention for Segmentation Networks through Adaptive Persistence Image Representation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08038</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08038v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Segmenting multiple objects (e.g., organs) in medical images often requires an understanding of their topology, which simultaneously quantifies the shape of the objects and their positions relative to each other. This understanding is important for segmentation networks to generalize better with limited training data, which is common in medical image analysis. However, many popular networks were trained to optimize only pixel-wise performance, ignoring the topological correctness of the segmentation. In this paper, we introduce a new topology-aware loss function, which we call PI-Att, that explicitly forces the network to minimize the topological dissimilarity between the ground truth and prediction maps. We quantify the topology of each map by the persistence image representation, for the first time in the context of a segmentation network loss. Besides, we propose a new mechanism to adaptively calculate the persistence image at the end of each epoch based on the network's performance. This adaptive calculation enables the network to learn topology outline in the first epochs, and then topology details towards the end of training. The effectiveness of the proposed PI-Att loss is demonstrated on two different datasets for aorta and great vessel segmentation in computed tomography images.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08038v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mehmet Bahadir Erden, Sinan Unver, Ilke Ali Gurses, Rustu Turkay, Cigdem Gunduz-Demir</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlearnable Examples Detection via Iterative Filtering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08143</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08143v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Deep neural networks are proven to be vulnerable to data poisoning attacks. Recently, a specific type of data poisoning attack known as availability attacks has led to the failure of data utilization for model learning by adding imperceptible perturbations to images. Consequently, it is quite beneficial and challenging to detect poisoned samples, also known as Unlearnable Examples (UEs), from a mixed dataset. In response, we propose an Iterative Filtering approach for UEs identification. This method leverages the distinction between the inherent semantic mapping rules and shortcuts, without the need for any additional information. We verify that when training a classifier on a mixed dataset containing both UEs and clean data, the model tends to quickly adapt to the UEs compared to the clean data. Due to the accuracy gaps between training with clean/poisoned samples, we employ a model to misclassify clean samples while correctly identifying the poisoned ones. The incorporation of additional classes and iterative refinement enhances the model's ability to differentiate between clean and poisoned samples. Extensive experiments demonstrate the superiority of our method over state-of-the-art detection approaches across various attacks, datasets, and poison ratios, significantly reducing the Half Total Error Rate (HTER) compared to existing methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08143v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yi Yu, Qichen Zheng, Siyuan Yang, Wenhan Yang, Jun Liu, Shijian Lu, Yap-Peng Tan, Kwok-Yan Lam, Alex Kot</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learned Multimodal Compression for Autonomous Driving</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08211</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08211v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Autonomous driving sensors generate an enormous amount of data. In this paper, we explore learned multimodal compression for autonomous driving, specifically targeted at 3D object detection. We focus on camera and LiDAR modalities and explore several coding approaches. One approach involves joint coding of fused modalities, while others involve coding one modality first, followed by conditional coding of the other modality. We evaluate the performance of these coding schemes on the nuScenes dataset. Our experimental results indicate that joint coding of fused modalities yields better results compared to the alternatives.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08211v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hadi Hadizadeh, Ivan V. Baji\'c</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moving Healthcare AI-Support Systems for Visually Detectable Diseases onto Constrained Devices</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08215</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08215v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Image classification usually requires connectivity and access to the cloud which is often limited in many parts of the world, including hard to reach rural areas. TinyML aims to solve this problem by hosting AI assistants on constrained devices, eliminating connectivity issues by processing data within the device itself, without internet or cloud access. This pilot study explores the use of tinyML to provide healthcare support with low spec devices in low connectivity environments, focusing on diagnosis of skin diseases and the ethical use of AI assistants in a healthcare setting. To investigate this, 10,000 images of skin lesions were used to train a model for classifying visually detectable diseases (VDDs). The model weights were then offloaded to a Raspberry Pi with a webcam attached, to be used for the classification of skin lesions without internet access. It was found that the developed prototype achieved a test accuracy of 78% and a test loss of 1.08.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08215v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tess Watt, Christos Chrysoulas, Peter J Barclay</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Medical Anomaly Detection in Brain MRI: An Image Quality Assessment Perspective</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08228</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08228v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Reconstruction-based methods, particularly those leveraging autoencoders, have been widely adopted to perform anomaly detection in brain MRI. While most existing works try to improve detection accuracy by proposing new model structures or algorithms, we tackle the problem through image quality assessment, an underexplored perspective in the field. We propose a fusion quality loss function that combines Structural Similarity Index Measure loss with l1 loss, offering a more comprehensive evaluation of reconstruction quality. Additionally, we introduce a data pre-processing strategy that enhances the average intensity ratio (AIR) between normal and abnormal regions, further improving the distinction of anomalies. By fusing the aforementioned two methods, we devise the image quality assessment (IQA) approach. The proposed IQA approach achieves significant improvements (&gt;10%) in terms of Dice coefficient (DICE) and Area Under the Precision-Recall Curve (AUPRC) on the BraTS21 (T2, FLAIR) and MSULB datasets when compared with state-of-the-art methods. These results highlight the importance of invoking the comprehensive image quality assessment in medical anomaly detection and provide a new perspective for future research in this field.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08228v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zixuan Pan, Jun Xia, Zheyu Yan, Guoyue Xu, Yawen Wu, Zhenge Jia, Jianxu Chen, Yiyu Shi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Local Geometry of Generative Model Manifolds</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08307</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08307v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Deep generative models learn continuous representations of complex data manifolds using a finite number of samples during training. For a pre-trained generative model, the common way to evaluate the quality of the manifold representation learned, is by computing global metrics like Fr\'echet Inception Distance using a large number of generated and real samples. However, generative model performance is not uniform across the learned manifold, e.g., for \textit{foundation models} like Stable Diffusion generation performance can vary significantly based on the conditioning or initial noise vector being denoised. In this paper we study the relationship between the \textit{local geometry of the learned manifold} and downstream generation. Based on the theory of continuous piecewise-linear (CPWL) generators, we use three geometric descriptors - scaling ($\psi$), rank ($\nu$), and complexity ($\delta$) - to characterize a pre-trained generative model manifold locally. We provide quantitative and qualitative evidence showing that for a given latent, the local descriptors are correlated with generation aesthetics, artifacts, uncertainty, and even memorization. Finally we demonstrate that training a \textit{reward model} on the local geometry can allow controlling the likelihood of a generated sample under the learned distribution.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08307v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ahmed Imtiaz Humayun, Ibtihel Amara, Candice Schumann, Golnoosh Farnadi, Negar Rostamzadeh, Mohammad Havaei</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Large Language Models Understand Symbolic Graphics Programs?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08313</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08313v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Assessing the capabilities of large language models (LLMs) is often challenging, in part, because it is hard to find tasks to which they have not been exposed during training. We take one step to address this challenge by turning to a new task: focusing on symbolic graphics programs, which are a popular representation for graphics content that procedurally generates visual data. LLMs have shown exciting promise towards program synthesis, but do they understand symbolic graphics programs? Unlike conventional programs, symbolic graphics programs can be translated to graphics content. Here, we characterize an LLM's understanding of symbolic programs in terms of their ability to answer questions related to the graphics content. This task is challenging as the questions are difficult to answer from the symbolic programs alone -- yet, they would be easy to answer from the corresponding graphics content as we verify through a human experiment. To understand symbolic programs, LLMs may need to possess the ability to imagine how the corresponding graphics content would look without directly accessing the rendered visual content. We use this task to evaluate LLMs by creating a large benchmark for the semantic understanding of symbolic graphics programs. This benchmark is built via program-graphics correspondence, hence requiring minimal human efforts. We evaluate current LLMs on our benchmark to elucidate a preliminary assessment of their ability to reason about visual scenes from programs. We find that this task distinguishes existing LLMs and models considered good at reasoning perform better. Lastly, we introduce Symbolic Instruction Tuning (SIT) to improve this ability. Specifically, we query GPT4-o with questions and images generated by symbolic programs. Such data are then used to finetune an LLM. We also find that SIT data can improve the general instruction following ability of LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08313v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zeju Qiu, Weiyang Liu, Haiwen Feng, Zhen Liu, Tim Z. Xiao, Katherine M. Collins, Joshua B. Tenenbaum, Adrian Weller, Michael J. Black, Bernhard Sch\"olkopf</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unsupervised Industrial Anomaly Detection via Pattern Generative and Contrastive Networks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2207.09792</link>
      <description>arXiv:2207.09792v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: It is hard to collect enough flaw images for training deep learning network in industrial production. Therefore, existing industrial anomaly detection methods prefer to use CNN-based unsupervised detection and localization network to achieve this task. However, these methods always fail when there are varieties happened in new signals since traditional end-to-end networks suffer barriers of fitting nonlinear model in high-dimensional space. Moreover, they have a memory library by clustering the feature of normal images essentially, which cause it is not robust to texture change. To this end, we propose the Vision Transformer based (VIT-based) unsupervised anomaly detection network. It utilizes a hierarchical task learning and human experience to enhance its interpretability. Our network consists of pattern generation and comparison networks. Pattern generation network uses two VIT-based encoder modules to extract the feature of two consecutive image patches, then uses VIT-based decoder module to learn the human designed style of these features and predict the third image patch. After this, we use the Siamese-based network to compute the similarity of the generation image patch and original image patch. Finally, we refine the anomaly localization by the bi-directional inference strategy. Comparison experiments on public dataset MVTec dataset show our method achieves 99.8% AUC, which surpasses previous state-of-the-art methods. In addition, we give a qualitative illustration on our own leather and cloth datasets. The accurate segment results strongly prove the accuracy of our method in anomaly detection.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2207.09792v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1007/978-981-97-5609-4_8</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Advanced Intelligent Computing Technology and Applications. ICIC 2024. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol 14871</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Jianfeng Huang, Chenyang Li, Yimin Lin, Shiguo Lian</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lane Graph as Path: Continuity-preserving Path-wise Modeling for Online Lane Graph Construction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2303.08815</link>
      <description>arXiv:2303.08815v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Online lane graph construction is a promising but challenging task in autonomous driving. Previous methods usually model the lane graph at the pixel or piece level, and recover the lane graph by pixel-wise or piece-wise connection, which breaks down the continuity of the lane and results in suboptimal performance. Human drivers focus on and drive along the continuous and complete paths instead of considering lane pieces. Autonomous vehicles also require path-specific guidance from lane graph for trajectory planning. We argue that the path, which indicates the traffic flow, is the primitive of the lane graph. Motivated by this, we propose to model the lane graph in a novel path-wise manner, which well preserves the continuity of the lane and encodes traffic information for planning. We present a path-based online lane graph construction method, termed LaneGAP, which end-to-end learns the path and recovers the lane graph via a Path2Graph algorithm. We qualitatively and quantitatively demonstrate the superior accuracy and efficiency of LaneGAP over conventional pixel-based and piece-based methods on the challenging nuScenes and Argoverse2 datasets under controllable and fair conditions. Compared to the recent state-of-the-art piece-wise method TopoNet on the OpenLane-V2 dataset, LaneGAP still outperforms by 1.6 mIoU, further validating the effectiveness of path-wise modeling. Abundant visualizations in the supplementary material show LaneGAP can cope with diverse traffic conditions. Code is released at \url{https://github.com/hustvl/LaneGAP}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2303.08815v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bencheng Liao, Shaoyu Chen, Bo Jiang, Tianheng Cheng, Qian Zhang, Wenyu Liu, Chang Huang, Xinggang Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hi-ResNet: Edge Detail Enhancement for High-Resolution Remote Sensing Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2305.12691</link>
      <description>arXiv:2305.12691v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: High-resolution remote sensing (HRS) semantic segmentation extracts key objects from high-resolution coverage areas. However, objects of the same category within HRS images generally show significant differences in scale and shape across diverse geographical environments, making it difficult to fit the data distribution. Additionally, a complex background environment causes similar appearances of objects of different categories, which precipitates a substantial number of objects into misclassification as background. These issues make existing learning algorithms sub-optimal. In this work, we solve the above-mentioned problems by proposing a High-resolution remote sensing network (Hi-ResNet) with efficient network structure designs, which consists of a funnel module, a multi-branch module with stacks of information aggregation (IA) blocks, and a feature refinement module, sequentially, and Class-agnostic Edge Aware (CEA) loss. Specifically, we propose a funnel module to downsample, which reduces the computational cost, and extract high-resolution semantic information from the initial input image. Secondly, we downsample the processed feature images into multi-resolution branches incrementally to capture image features at different scales and apply IA blocks, which capture key latent information by leveraging attention mechanisms, for effective feature aggregation, distinguishing image features of the same class with variant scales and shapes. Finally, our feature refinement module integrate the CEA loss function, which disambiguates inter-class objects with similar shapes and increases the data distribution distance for correct predictions. With effective pre-training strategies, we demonstrated the superiority of Hi-ResNet over state-of-the-art methods on three HRS segmentation benchmarks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2305.12691v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuxia Chen, Pengcheng Fang, Jianhui Yu, Xiaoling Zhong, Xiaoming Zhang, Tianrui Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interactive Character Control with Auto-Regressive Motion Diffusion Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2306.00416</link>
      <description>arXiv:2306.00416v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Real-time character control is an essential component for interactive experiences, with a broad range of applications, including physics simulations, video games, and virtual reality. The success of diffusion models for image synthesis has led to the use of these models for motion synthesis. However, the majority of these motion diffusion models are primarily designed for offline applications, where space-time models are used to synthesize an entire sequence of frames simultaneously with a pre-specified length. To enable real-time motion synthesis with diffusion model that allows time-varying controls, we propose A-MDM (Auto-regressive Motion Diffusion Model). Our conditional diffusion model takes an initial pose as input, and auto-regressively generates successive motion frames conditioned on the previous frame. Despite its streamlined network architecture, which uses simple MLPs, our framework is capable of generating diverse, long-horizon, and high-fidelity motion sequences. Furthermore, we introduce a suite of techniques for incorporating interactive controls into A-MDM, such as task-oriented sampling, in-painting, and hierarchical reinforcement learning. These techniques enable a pre-trained A-MDM to be efficiently adapted for a variety of new downstream tasks. We conduct a comprehensive suite of experiments to demonstrate the effectiveness of A-MDM, and compare its performance against state-of-the-art auto-regressive methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2306.00416v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yi Shi, Jingbo Wang, Xuekun Jiang, Bingkun Lin, Bo Dai, Xue Bin Peng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DyFFPAD: Dynamic Fusion of Convolutional and Handcrafted Features for Fingerprint Presentation Attack Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2308.10015</link>
      <description>arXiv:2308.10015v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Automatic fingerprint recognition systems suffer from the threat of presentation attacks due to their wide range of deployment in areas including national borders and commercial applications. A presentation attack can be performed by creating a spoof of a user's fingerprint with or without their consent. This paper presents a dynamic ensemble of deep CNN and handcrafted features to detect presentation attacks in known-material and unknown-material protocols of the livness detection competition. The proposed presentation attack detection model, in this way, utilizes the capabilities of both deep CNN and handcrafted features techniques and exhibits better performance than their individual performances. We have validated our proposed method on benchmark databases from the Liveness Detection Competition in 2015, 2017, and 2019, yielding overall accuracy of 96.10\%, 96.49\%, and 94.99\% on them, respectively. The proposed method outperforms state-of-the-art methods in terms of classification accuracy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2308.10015v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Anuj Rai, Parsheel Kumar Tiwari, Jyotishna Baishya, Ram Prakash Sharma, Somnath Dey</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long-Tailed Classification Based on Coarse-Grained Leading Forest and Multi-Center Loss</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.08206</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.08206v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Long-tailed (LT) classification is an unavoidable and challenging problem in the real world. Most existing long-tailed classification methods focus only on solving the class-wise imbalance while ignoring the attribute-wise imbalance. The deviation of a classification model is caused by both class-wise and attribute-wise imbalance. Due to the fact that attributes are implicit in most datasets and the combination of attributes is complex, attribute-wise imbalance is more difficult to handle. For this purpose, we proposed a novel long-tailed classification framework, aiming to build a multi-granularity classification model by means of invariant feature learning. This method first unsupervisedly constructs Coarse-Grained forest (CLF) to better characterize the distribution of attributes within a class. Depending on the distribution of attributes, one can customize suitable sampling strategies to construct different imbalanced datasets. We then introduce multi-center loss (MCL) that aims to gradually eliminate confusing attributes during feature learning process. The proposed framework does not necessarily couple to a specific LT classification model structure and can be integrated with any existing LT method as an independent component. Extensive experiments show that our approach achieves state-of-the-art performance on both existing benchmarks ImageNet-GLT and MSCOCO-GLT and can improve the performance of existing LT methods. Our codes are available on GitHub: \url{https://github.com/jinyery/cognisance}</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.08206v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jinye Yang, Ji Xu, Di Wu, Jianhang Tang, Shaobo Li, Guoyin Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HawkI: Homography &amp; Mutual Information Guidance for 3D-free Single Image to Aerial View</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.15478</link>
      <description>arXiv:2311.15478v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We present HawkI, for synthesizing aerial-view images from text and an exemplar image, without any additional multi-view or 3D information for finetuning or at inference. HawkI uses techniques from classical computer vision and information theory. It seamlessly blends the visual features from the input image within a pretrained text-to-2Dimage stable diffusion model with a test-time optimization process for a careful bias-variance trade-off, which uses an Inverse Perspective Mapping (IPM) homography transformation to provide subtle cues for aerialview synthesis. At inference, HawkI employs a unique mutual information guidance formulation to steer the generated image towards faithfully replicating the semantic details of the input-image, while maintaining a realistic aerial perspective. Mutual information guidance maximizes the semantic consistency between the generated image and the input image, without enforcing pixel-level correspondence between vastly different viewpoints. Through extensive qualitative and quantitative comparisons against text + exemplar-image based methods and 3D/ multi-view based novel-view synthesis methods on proposed synthetic and real datasets, we demonstrate that our method achieves a significantly better bias-variance trade-off towards generating high fidelity aerial-view images.Code and data is available at https://github.com/divyakraman/HawkI2024.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2311.15478v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Divya Kothandaraman, Tianyi Zhou, Ming Lin, Dinesh Manocha</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Capturing Human Motion from Monocular Images in World Space with Weak-supervised Calibration</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.17460</link>
      <description>arXiv:2311.17460v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Previous methods for 3D human motion recovery from monocular images often fall short due to reliance on camera coordinates, leading to inaccuracies in real-world applications where complex shooting conditions are prevalent. The limited availability and diversity of focal length labels further exacerbate misalignment issues in reconstructed 3D human bodies. To address these challenges, we introduce W-HMR, a weak-supervised calibration method that predicts "reasonable" focal lengths based on body distortion information, eliminating the need for precise focal length labels. Our approach enhances 2D supervision precision and recovery accuracy. Additionally, we present the OrientCorrect module, which corrects body orientation for plausible reconstructions in world space, avoiding the error accumulation associated with inaccurate camera rotation predictions. Our contributions include a novel weak-supervised camera calibration technique, an effective orientation correction module, and a decoupling strategy that significantly improves the generalizability and accuracy of human motion recovery in both camera and world coordinates. The robustness of W-HMR is validated through extensive experiments on various datasets, showcasing its superiority over existing methods. Codes and demos have been released on the project page https://yw0208.github.io/w-hmr/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2311.17460v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wei Yao, Hongwen Zhang, Yunlian Sun, Jinhui Tang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DiffPMAE: Diffusion Masked Autoencoders for Point Cloud Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.03298</link>
      <description>arXiv:2312.03298v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Point cloud streaming is increasingly getting popular, evolving into the norm for interactive service delivery and the future Metaverse. However, the substantial volume of data associated with point clouds presents numerous challenges, particularly in terms of high bandwidth consumption and large storage capacity. Despite various solutions proposed thus far, with a focus on point cloud compression, upsampling, and completion, these reconstruction-related methods continue to fall short in delivering high fidelity point cloud output. As a solution, in DiffPMAE, we propose an effective point cloud reconstruction architecture. Inspired by self-supervised learning concepts, we combine Masked Auto-Encoding and Diffusion Model mechanism to remotely reconstruct point cloud data. By the nature of this reconstruction process, DiffPMAE can be extended to many related downstream tasks including point cloud compression, upsampling and completion. Leveraging ShapeNet-55 and ModelNet datasets with over 60000 objects, we validate the performance of DiffPMAE exceeding many state-of-the-art methods in-terms of auto-encoding and downstream tasks considered.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2312.03298v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yanlong Li, Chamara Madarasingha, Kanchana Thilakarathna</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GIR: 3D Gaussian Inverse Rendering for Relightable Scene Factorization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.05133</link>
      <description>arXiv:2312.05133v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper presents a 3D Gaussian Inverse Rendering (GIR) method, employing 3D Gaussian representations to effectively factorize the scene into material properties, light, and geometry. The key contributions lie in three-fold. We compute the normal of each 3D Gaussian using the shortest eigenvector, with a directional masking scheme forcing accurate normal estimation without external supervision. We adopt an efficient voxel-based indirect illumination tracing scheme that stores direction-aware outgoing radiance in each 3D Gaussian to disentangle secondary illumination for approximating multi-bounce light transport. To further enhance the illumination disentanglement, we represent a high-resolution environmental map with a learnable low-resolution map and a lightweight, fully convolutional network. Our method achieves state-of-the-art performance in both relighting and novel view synthesis tasks among the recently proposed inverse rendering methods while achieving real-time rendering. This substantiates our proposed method's efficacy and broad applicability, highlighting its potential as an influential tool in various real-time interactive graphics applications such as material editing and relighting. The code will be released at https://github.com/guduxiaolang/GIR.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2312.05133v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yahao Shi, Yanmin Wu, Chenming Wu, Xing Liu, Chen Zhao, Haocheng Feng, Jian Zhang, Bin Zhou, Errui Ding, Jingdong Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Semantic Space is Worth 256 Language Descriptions: Make Stronger Segmentation Models with Descriptive Properties</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13764</link>
      <description>arXiv:2312.13764v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper introduces ProLab, a novel approach using property-level label space for creating strong interpretable segmentation models. Instead of relying solely on category-specific annotations, ProLab uses descriptive properties grounded in common sense knowledge for supervising segmentation models. It is based on two core designs. First, we employ Large Language Models (LLMs) and carefully crafted prompts to generate descriptions of all involved categories that carry meaningful common sense knowledge and follow a structured format. Second, we introduce a description embedding model preserving semantic correlation across descriptions and then cluster them into a set of descriptive properties (e.g., 256) using K-Means. These properties are based on interpretable common sense knowledge consistent with theories of human recognition. We empirically show that our approach makes segmentation models perform stronger on five classic benchmarks (e.g., ADE20K, COCO-Stuff, Pascal Context, Cityscapes, and BDD). Our method also shows better scalability with extended training steps than category-level supervision. Our interpretable segmentation framework also emerges with the generalization ability to segment out-of-domain or unknown categories using only in-domain descriptive properties. Code is available at https://github.com/lambert-x/ProLab.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2312.13764v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junfei Xiao, Ziqi Zhou, Wenxuan Li, Shiyi Lan, Jieru Mei, Zhiding Yu, Alan Yuille, Yuyin Zhou, Cihang Xie</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identifying Important Group of Pixels using Interactions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03785</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.03785v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: To better understand the behavior of image classifiers, it is useful to visualize the contribution of individual pixels to the model prediction. In this study, we propose a method, MoXI ($\textbf{Mo}$del e$\textbf{X}$planation by $\textbf{I}$nteractions), that efficiently and accurately identifies a group of pixels with high prediction confidence. The proposed method employs game-theoretic concepts, Shapley values and interactions, taking into account the effects of individual pixels and the cooperative influence of pixels on model confidence. Theoretical analysis and experiments demonstrate that our method better identifies the pixels that are highly contributing to the model outputs than widely-used visualization by Grad-CAM, Attention rollout, and Shapley value. While prior studies have suffered from the exponential computational cost in the computation of Shapley value and interactions, we show that this can be reduced to quadratic cost for our task. The code is available at https://github.com/KosukeSumiyasu/MoXI.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.03785v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kosuke Sumiyasu, Kazuhiko Kawamoto, Hiroshi Kera</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robustness-Aware 3D Object Detection in Autonomous Driving: A Review and Outlook</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.06542</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.06542v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In the realm of modern autonomous driving, the perception system is indispensable for accurately assessing the state of the surrounding environment, thereby enabling informed prediction and planning. The key step to this system is related to 3D object detection that utilizes vehicle-mounted sensors such as LiDAR and cameras to identify the size, the category, and the location of nearby objects. Despite the surge in 3D object detection methods aimed at enhancing detection precision and efficiency, there is a gap in the literature that systematically examines their resilience against environmental variations, noise, and weather changes. This study emphasizes the importance of robustness, alongside accuracy and latency, in evaluating perception systems under practical scenarios. Our work presents an extensive survey of camera-only, LiDAR-only, and multi-modal 3D object detection algorithms, thoroughly evaluating their trade-off between accuracy, latency, and robustness, particularly on datasets like KITTI-C and nuScenes-C to ensure fair comparisons. Among these, multi-modal 3D detection approaches exhibit superior robustness, and a novel taxonomy is introduced to reorganize the literature for enhanced clarity. This survey aims to offer a more practical perspective on the current capabilities and the constraints of 3D object detection algorithms in real-world applications, thus steering future research towards robustness-centric advancements.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.06542v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ziying Song, Lin Liu, Feiyang Jia, Yadan Luo, Guoxin Zhang, Lei Yang, Li Wang, Caiyan Jia</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TriSAM: Tri-Plane SAM for zero-shot cortical blood vessel segmentation in VEM images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.13961</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.13961v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: While imaging techniques at macro and mesoscales have garnered substantial attention and resources, microscale Volume Electron Microscopy (vEM) imaging, capable of revealing intricate vascular details, has lacked the necessary benchmarking infrastructure. In this paper, we address a significant gap in this field of neuroimaging by introducing the first-in-class public benchmark, BvEM, designed specifically for cortical blood vessel segmentation in vEM images. Our BvEM benchmark is based on vEM image volumes from three mammals: adult mouse, macaque, and human. We standardized the resolution, addressed imaging variations, and meticulously annotated blood vessels through semi-automatic, manual, and quality control processes, ensuring high-quality 3D segmentation. Furthermore, we developed a zero-shot cortical blood vessel segmentation method named TriSAM, which leverages the powerful segmentation model SAM for 3D segmentation. To extend SAM from 2D to 3D volume segmentation, TriSAM employs a multi-seed tracking framework, leveraging the reliability of certain image planes for tracking while using others to identify potential turning points. This approach effectively achieves long-term 3D blood vessel segmentation without model training or fine-tuning. Experimental results show that TriSAM achieved superior performances on the BvEM benchmark across three species. Our dataset, code, and model are available online at \url{https://jia-wan.github.io/bvem}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.13961v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jia Wan, Wanhua Li, Jason Ken Adhinarta, Atmadeep Banerjee, Evelina Sjostedt, Jingpeng Wu, Jeff Lichtman, Hanspeter Pfister, Donglai Wei</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-graph Graph Matching for Coronary Artery Semantic Labeling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.15894</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.15894v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Coronary artery disease (CAD) stands as the leading cause of death worldwide, and invasive coronary angiography (ICA) remains the gold standard for assessing vascular anatomical information. However, deep learning-based methods encounter challenges in generating semantic labels for arterial segments, primarily due to the morphological similarity between arterial branches and varying anatomy of arterial system between different projection view angles and patients. To address this challenge, we model the vascular tree as a graph and propose a multi-graph graph matching (MGM) algorithm for coronary artery semantic labeling. The MGM algorithm assesses the similarity between arterials in multiple vascular tree graphs, considering the cycle consistency between each pair of graphs. As a result, the unannotated arterial segments are appropriately labeled by matching them with annotated segments. Through the incorporation of anatomical graph structure, radiomics features, and semantic mapping, the proposed MGM model achieves an impressive accuracy of 0.9471 for coronary artery semantic labeling using our multi-site dataset with 718 ICAs. With the semantic labeled arteries, an overall accuracy of 0.9155 was achieved for stenosis detection. The proposed MGM presents a novel tool for coronary artery analysis using multiple ICA-derived graphs, offering valuable insights into vascular health and pathology.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.15894v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chen Zhao, Zhihui Xu, Pukar Baral, Michel Esposito, Weihua Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robust Zero-Shot Crowd Counting and Localization With Adaptive Resolution SAM</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.17514</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.17514v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The existing crowd counting models require extensive training data, which is time-consuming to annotate. To tackle this issue, we propose a simple yet effective crowd counting method by utilizing the Segment-Everything-Everywhere Model (SEEM), an adaptation of the Segmentation Anything Model (SAM), to generate pseudo-labels for training crowd counting models. However, our initial investigation reveals that SEEM's performance in dense crowd scenes is limited, primarily due to the omission of many persons in high-density areas. To overcome this limitation, we propose an adaptive resolution SEEM to handle the scale variations, occlusions, and overlapping of people within crowd scenes. Alongside this, we introduce a robust localization method, based on Gaussian Mixture Models, for predicting the head positions in the predicted people masks. Given the mask and point pseudo-labels, we propose a robust loss function, which is designed to exclude uncertain regions based on SEEM's predictions, thereby enhancing the training process of the counting networks. Finally, we propose an iterative method for generating pseudo-labels. This method aims at improving the quality of the segmentation masks by identifying more tiny persons in high-density regions, which are often missed in the first pseudo-labeling stage. Overall, our proposed method achieves the best unsupervised performance in crowd counting, while also being comparable results to some supervised methods. This makes it a highly effective and versatile tool for crowd counting, especially in situations where labeled data is not available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.17514v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jia Wan, Qiangqiang Wu, Wei Lin, Antoni B. Chan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active Generation for Image Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.06517</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.06517v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recently, the growing capabilities of deep generative models have underscored their potential in enhancing image classification accuracy. However, existing methods often demand the generation of a disproportionately large number of images compared to the original dataset, while having only marginal improvements in accuracy. This computationally expensive and time-consuming process hampers the practicality of such approaches. In this paper, we propose to address the efficiency of image generation by focusing on the specific needs and characteristics of the model. With a central tenet of active learning, our method, named ActGen, takes a training-aware approach to image generation. It aims to create images akin to the challenging or misclassified samples encountered by the current model and incorporates these generated images into the training set to augment model performance. ActGen introduces an attentive image guidance technique, using real images as guides during the denoising process of a diffusion model. The model's attention on class prompt is leveraged to ensure the preservation of similar foreground object while diversifying the background. Furthermore, we introduce a gradient-based generation guidance method, which employs two losses to generate more challenging samples and prevent the generated images from being too similar to previously generated ones. Experimental results on the CIFAR and ImageNet datasets demonstrate that our method achieves better performance with a significantly reduced number of generated images. Code is available at https://github.com/hunto/ActGen.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.06517v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tao Huang, Jiaqi Liu, Shan You, Chang Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Label Dropout: Improved Deep Learning Echocardiography Segmentation Using Multiple Datasets With Domain Shift and Partial Labelling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.07818</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.07818v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Echocardiography (echo) is the first imaging modality used when assessing cardiac function. The measurement of functional biomarkers from echo relies upon the segmentation of cardiac structures and deep learning models have been proposed to automate the segmentation process. However, in order to translate these tools to widespread clinical use it is important that the segmentation models are robust to a wide variety of images (e.g. acquired from different scanners, by operators with different levels of expertise etc.). To achieve this level of robustness it is necessary that the models are trained with multiple diverse datasets. A significant challenge faced when training with multiple diverse datasets is the variation in label presence, i.e. the combined data are often partially-labelled. Adaptations of the cross entropy loss function have been proposed to deal with partially labelled data. In this paper we show that training naively with such a loss function and multiple diverse datasets can lead to a form of shortcut learning, where the model associates label presence with domain characteristics, leading to a drop in performance. To address this problem, we propose a novel label dropout scheme to break the link between domain characteristics and the presence or absence of labels. We demonstrate that label dropout improves echo segmentation Dice score by 62% and 25% on two cardiac structures when training using multiple diverse partially labelled datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.07818v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Iman Islam (King's College London), Esther Puyol-Ant\'on (King's College London), Bram Ruijsink (King's College London), Andrew J. Reader (King's College London), Andrew P. King (King's College London)</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SM4Depth: Seamless Monocular Metric Depth Estimation across Multiple Cameras and Scenes by One Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.08556</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.08556v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In the last year, universal monocular metric depth estimation (universal MMDE) has gained considerable attention, serving as the foundation model for various multimedia tasks, such as video and image editing. Nonetheless, current approaches face challenges in maintaining consistent accuracy across diverse scenes without scene-specific parameters and pre-training, hindering the practicality of MMDE. Furthermore, these methods rely on extensive datasets comprising millions, if not tens of millions, of data for training, leading to significant time and hardware expenses. This paper presents SM$^4$Depth, a model that seamlessly works for both indoor and outdoor scenes, without needing extensive training data and GPU clusters. Firstly, to obtain consistent depth across diverse scenes, we propose a novel metric scale modeling, i.e., variation-based unnormalized depth bins. It reduces the ambiguity of the conventional metric bins and enables better adaptation to large depth gaps of scenes during training. Secondly, we propose a "divide and conquer" solution to reduce reliance on massive training data. Instead of estimating directly from the vast solution space, the metric bins are estimated from multiple solution sub-spaces to reduce complexity. Additionally, we introduce an uncut depth dataset, BUPT Depth, to evaluate the depth accuracy and consistency across various indoor and outdoor scenes. Trained on a consumer-grade GPU using just 150K RGB-D pairs, SM$^4$Depth achieves outstanding performance on the most never-before-seen datasets, especially maintaining consistent accuracy across indoors and outdoors. The code can be found https://github.com/mRobotit/SM4Depth.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.08556v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yihao Liu, Feng Xue, Anlong Ming, Mingshuai Zhao, Huadong Ma, Nicu Sebe</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Supervised Video Desmoking for Laparoscopic Surgery</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.11192</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.11192v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Due to the difficulty of collecting real paired data, most existing desmoking methods train the models by synthesizing smoke, generalizing poorly to real surgical scenarios. Although a few works have explored single-image real-world desmoking in unpaired learning manners, they still encounter challenges in handling dense smoke. In this work, we address these issues together by introducing the self-supervised surgery video desmoking (SelfSVD). On the one hand, we observe that the frame captured before the activation of high-energy devices is generally clear (named pre-smoke frame, PS frame), thus it can serve as supervision for other smoky frames, making real-world self-supervised video desmoking practically feasible. On the other hand, in order to enhance the desmoking performance, we further feed the valuable information from PS frame into models, where a masking strategy and a regularization term are presented to avoid trivial solutions. In addition, we construct a real surgery video dataset for desmoking, which covers a variety of smoky scenes. Extensive experiments on the dataset show that our SelfSVD can remove smoke more effectively and efficiently while recovering more photo-realistic details than the state-of-the-art methods. The dataset, codes, and pre-trained models are available at \url{https://github.com/ZcsrenlongZ/SelfSVD}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.11192v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Renlong Wu, Zhilu Zhang, Shuohao Zhang, Longfei Gou, Haobin Chen, Lei Zhang, Hao Chen, Wangmeng Zuo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>REFRAME: Reflective Surface Real-Time Rendering for Mobile Devices</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.16481</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.16481v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This work tackles the challenging task of achieving real-time novel view synthesis for reflective surfaces across various scenes. Existing real-time rendering methods, especially those based on meshes, often have subpar performance in modeling surfaces with rich view-dependent appearances. Our key idea lies in leveraging meshes for rendering acceleration while incorporating a novel approach to parameterize view-dependent information. We decompose the color into diffuse and specular, and model the specular color in the reflected direction based on a neural environment map. Our experiments demonstrate that our method achieves comparable reconstruction quality for highly reflective surfaces compared to state-of-the-art offline methods, while also efficiently enabling real-time rendering on edge devices such as smartphones.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.16481v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chaojie Ji, Yufeng Li, Yiyi Liao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PlainMamba: Improving Non-Hierarchical Mamba in Visual Recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.17695</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.17695v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We present PlainMamba: a simple non-hierarchical state space model (SSM) designed for general visual recognition. The recent Mamba model has shown how SSMs can be highly competitive with other architectures on sequential data and initial attempts have been made to apply it to images. In this paper, we further adapt the selective scanning process of Mamba to the visual domain, enhancing its ability to learn features from two-dimensional images by (i) a continuous 2D scanning process that improves spatial continuity by ensuring adjacency of tokens in the scanning sequence, and (ii) direction-aware updating which enables the model to discern the spatial relations of tokens by encoding directional information. Our architecture is designed to be easy to use and easy to scale, formed by stacking identical PlainMamba blocks, resulting in a model with constant width throughout all layers. The architecture is further simplified by removing the need for special tokens. We evaluate PlainMamba on a variety of visual recognition tasks, achieving performance gains over previous non-hierarchical models and is competitive with hierarchical alternatives. For tasks requiring high-resolution inputs, in particular, PlainMamba requires much less computing while maintaining high performance. Code and models are available at: https://github.com/ChenhongyiYang/PlainMamba .</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.17695v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chenhongyi Yang, Zehui Chen, Miguel Espinosa, Linus Ericsson, Zhenyu Wang, Jiaming Liu, Elliot J. Crowley</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EgoPoseFormer: A Simple Baseline for Stereo Egocentric 3D Human Pose Estimation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.18080</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.18080v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We present EgoPoseFormer, a simple yet effective transformer-based model for stereo egocentric human pose estimation. The main challenge in egocentric pose estimation is overcoming joint invisibility, which is caused by self-occlusion or a limited field of view (FOV) of head-mounted cameras. Our approach overcomes this challenge by incorporating a two-stage pose estimation paradigm: in the first stage, our model leverages the global information to estimate each joint's coarse location, then in the second stage, it employs a DETR style transformer to refine the coarse locations by exploiting fine-grained stereo visual features. In addition, we present a Deformable Stereo Attention operation to enable our transformer to effectively process multi-view features, which enables it to accurately localize each joint in the 3D world. We evaluate our method on the stereo UnrealEgo dataset and show it significantly outperforms previous approaches while being computationally efficient: it improves MPJPE by 27.4mm (45% improvement) with only 7.9% model parameters and 13.1% FLOPs compared to the state-of-the-art. Surprisingly, with proper training settings, we find that even our first-stage pose proposal network can achieve superior performance compared to previous arts. We also show that our method can be seamlessly extended to monocular settings, which achieves state-of-the-art performance on the SceneEgo dataset, improving MPJPE by 25.5mm (21% improvement) compared to the best existing method with only 60.7% model parameters and 36.4% FLOPs. Code is available at: https://github.com/ChenhongyiYang/egoposeformer .</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.18080v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chenhongyi Yang, Anastasia Tkach, Shreyas Hampali, Linguang Zhang, Elliot J. Crowley, Cem Keskin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nearest Neighbor Classification for Classical Image Upsampling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.19611</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.19611v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Given a set of ordered pixel data in the form of an image, our goal is to perform upsampling on the data such that: the resulting resolution is improved by some factor, the final result passes the human test, having added new, believable, and realistic information and detail to the image, the time complexity for upscaling is relatively close to that of lossy upscaling implementations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.19611v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Evan Matthews, Nicolas Prate</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual-Camera Smooth Zoom on Mobile Phones</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.04908</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.04908v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: When zooming between dual cameras on a mobile, noticeable jumps in geometric content and image color occur in the preview, inevitably affecting the user's zoom experience. In this work, we introduce a new task, ie, dual-camera smooth zoom (DCSZ) to achieve a smooth zoom preview. The frame interpolation (FI) technique is a potential solution but struggles with ground-truth collection. To address the issue, we suggest a data factory solution where continuous virtual cameras are assembled to generate DCSZ data by rendering reconstructed 3D models of the scene. In particular, we propose a novel dual-camera smooth zoom Gaussian Splatting (ZoomGS), where a camera-specific encoding is introduced to construct a specific 3D model for each virtual camera. With the proposed data factory, we construct a synthetic dataset for DCSZ, and we utilize it to fine-tune FI models. In addition, we collect real-world dual-zoom images without ground-truth for evaluation. Extensive experiments are conducted with multiple FI methods. The results show that the fine-tuned FI models achieve a significant performance improvement over the original ones on DCSZ task. The datasets, codes, and pre-trained models will are available at https://github.com/ZcsrenlongZ/ZoomGS.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.04908v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Renlong Wu, Zhilu Zhang, Yu Yang, Wangmeng Zuo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implicit and Explicit Language Guidance for Diffusion-based Visual Perception</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.07600</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.07600v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Text-to-image diffusion models have shown powerful ability on conditional image synthesis. With large-scale vision-language pre-training, diffusion models are able to generate high-quality images with rich texture and reasonable structure under different text prompts. However, it is an open problem to adapt the pre-trained diffusion model for visual perception. In this paper, we propose an implicit and explicit language guidance framework for diffusion-based perception, named IEDP. Our IEDP comprises an implicit language guidance branch and an explicit language guidance branch. The implicit branch employs frozen CLIP image encoder to directly generate implicit text embeddings that are fed to diffusion model, without using explicit text prompts. The explicit branch utilizes the ground-truth labels of corresponding images as text prompts to condition feature extraction of diffusion model. During training, we jointly train diffusion model by sharing the model weights of these two branches. As a result, implicit and explicit branches can jointly guide feature learning. During inference, we only employ implicit branch for final prediction, which does not require any ground-truth labels. Experiments are performed on two typical perception tasks, including semantic segmentation and depth estimation. Our IEDP achieves promising performance on both tasks. For semantic segmentation, our IEDP has the mIoU$^\text{ss}$ score of 55.9% on AD20K validation set, which outperforms the baseline method VPD by 2.2%. For depth estimation, our IEDP outperforms the baseline method VPD with a relative gain of 11.0%.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.07600v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hefeng Wang, Jiale Cao, Jin Xie, Aiping Yang, Yanwei Pang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Detector Collapse: Physical-World Backdooring Object Detection to Catastrophic Overload or Blindness in Autonomous Driving</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.11357</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.11357v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Object detection tasks, crucial in safety-critical systems like autonomous driving, focus on pinpointing object locations. These detectors are known to be susceptible to backdoor attacks. However, existing backdoor techniques have primarily been adapted from classification tasks, overlooking deeper vulnerabilities specific to object detection. This paper is dedicated to bridging this gap by introducing Detector Collapse} (DC), a brand-new backdoor attack paradigm tailored for object detection. DC is designed to instantly incapacitate detectors (i.e., severely impairing detector's performance and culminating in a denial-of-service). To this end, we develop two innovative attack schemes: Sponge for triggering widespread misidentifications and Blinding for rendering objects invisible. Remarkably, we introduce a novel poisoning strategy exploiting natural objects, enabling DC to act as a practical backdoor in real-world environments. Our experiments on different detectors across several benchmarks show a significant improvement ($\sim$10\%-60\% absolute and $\sim$2-7$\times$ relative) in attack efficacy over state-of-the-art attacks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.11357v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hangtao Zhang, Shengshan Hu, Yichen Wang, Leo Yu Zhang, Ziqi Zhou, Xianlong Wang, Yanjun Zhang, Chao Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Get Your Embedding Space in Order: Domain-Adaptive Regression for Forest Monitoring</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.00514</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.00514v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Image-level regression is an important task in Earth observation, where visual domain and label shifts are a core challenge hampering generalization. However, cross-domain regression within remote sensing data remains understudied due to the absence of suited datasets. We introduce a new dataset with aerial and satellite imagery in five countries with three forest-related regression tasks. To match real-world applicative interests, we compare methods through a restrictive setup where no prior on the target domain is available during training, and models are adapted with limited information during testing. Building on the assumption that ordered relationships generalize better, we propose manifold diffusion for regression as a strong baseline for transduction in low-data regimes. Our comparison highlights the comparative advantages of inductive and transductive methods in cross-domain regression.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.00514v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sizhuo Li, Dimitri Gominski, Martin Brandt, Xiaoye Tong, Philippe Ciais</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Few Shot Class Incremental Learning using Vision-Language models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.01040</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.01040v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advancements in deep learning have demonstrated remarkable performance comparable to human capabilities across various supervised computer vision tasks. However, the prevalent assumption of having an extensive pool of training data encompassing all classes prior to model training often diverges from real-world scenarios, where limited data availability for novel classes is the norm. The challenge emerges in seamlessly integrating new classes with few samples into the training data, demanding the model to adeptly accommodate these additions without compromising its performance on base classes. To address this exigency, the research community has introduced several solutions under the realm of few-shot class incremental learning (FSCIL).
  In this study, we introduce an innovative FSCIL framework that utilizes language regularizer and subspace regularizer. During base training, the language regularizer helps incorporate semantic information extracted from a Vision-Language model. The subspace regularizer helps in facilitating the model's acquisition of nuanced connections between image and text semantics inherent to base classes during incremental training. Our proposed framework not only empowers the model to embrace novel classes with limited data, but also ensures the preservation of performance on base classes. To substantiate the efficacy of our approach, we conduct comprehensive experiments on three distinct FSCIL benchmarks, where our framework attains state-of-the-art performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.01040v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Anurag Kumar, Chinmay Bharti, Saikat Dutta, Srikrishna Karanam, Biplab Banerjee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning Innovations for Underwater Waste Detection: An In-Depth Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.18299</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.18299v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Addressing the issue of submerged underwater trash is crucial for safeguarding aquatic ecosystems and preserving marine life. While identifying debris present on the surface of water bodies is straightforward, assessing the underwater submerged waste is a challenge due to the image distortions caused by factors such as light refraction, absorption, suspended particles, color shifts, and occlusion. This paper conducts a comprehensive review of state-of-the-art architectures and on the existing datasets to establish a baseline for submerged waste and trash detection. The primary goal remains to establish the benchmark of the object localization techniques to be leveraged by advanced underwater sensors and autonomous underwater vehicles. The ultimate objective is to explore the underwater environment, to identify, and remove underwater debris. The absence of benchmarks (dataset or algorithm) in many researches emphasizes the need for a more robust algorithmic solution. Through this research, we aim to give performance comparative analysis of various underwater trash detection algorithms.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.18299v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jaskaran Singh Walia, Pavithra L K</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MLAAN: Scaling Supervised Local Learning with Multilaminar Leap Augmented Auxiliary Network</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.16633</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.16633v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Deep neural networks (DNNs) typically employ an end-to-end (E2E) training paradigm which presents several challenges, including high GPU memory consumption, inefficiency, and difficulties in model parallelization during training. Recent research has sought to address these issues, with one promising approach being local learning. This method involves partitioning the backbone network into gradient-isolated modules and manually designing auxiliary networks to train these local modules. Existing methods often neglect the interaction of information between local modules, leading to myopic issues and a performance gap compared to E2E training. To address these limitations, we propose the Multilaminar Leap Augmented Auxiliary Network (MLAAN). Specifically, MLAAN comprises Multilaminar Local Modules (MLM) and Leap Augmented Modules (LAM). MLM captures both local and global features through independent and cascaded auxiliary networks, alleviating performance issues caused by insufficient global features. However, overly simplistic auxiliary networks can impede MLM's ability to capture global information. To address this, we further design LAM, an enhanced auxiliary network that uses the Exponential Moving Average (EMA) method to facilitate information exchange between local modules, thereby mitigating the shortsightedness resulting from inadequate interaction. The synergy between MLM and LAM has demonstrated excellent performance. Our experiments on the CIFAR-10, STL-10, SVHN, and ImageNet datasets show that MLAAN can be seamlessly integrated into existing local learning frameworks, significantly enhancing their performance and even surpassing end-to-end (E2E) training methods, while also reducing GPU memory consumption.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.16633v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuming Zhang, Shouxin Zhang, Peizhe Wang, Feiyu Zhu, Dongzhi Guan, Junhao Su, Jiabin Liu, Changpeng Cai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Masked Generative Extractor for Synergistic Representation and 3D Generation of Point Clouds</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.17342</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.17342v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Representation and generative learning, as reconstruction-based methods, have demonstrated their potential for mutual reinforcement across various domains. In the field of point cloud processing, although existing studies have adopted training strategies from generative models to enhance representational capabilities, these methods are limited by their inability to genuinely generate 3D shapes. To explore the benefits of deeply integrating 3D representation learning and generative learning, we propose an innovative framework called \textit{Point-MGE}. Specifically, this framework first utilizes a vector quantized variational autoencoder to reconstruct a neural field representation of 3D shapes, thereby learning discrete semantic features of point patches. Subsequently, we design a sliding masking ratios to smooth the transition from representation learning to generative learning. Moreover, our method demonstrates strong generalization capability in learning high-capacity models, achieving new state-of-the-art performance across multiple downstream tasks. In shape classification, Point-MGE achieved an accuracy of 94.2% (+1.0%) on the ModelNet40 dataset and 92.9% (+5.5%) on the ScanObjectNN dataset. Experimental results also confirmed that Point-MGE can generate high-quality 3D shapes in both unconditional and conditional settings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.17342v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hongliang Zeng, Ping Zhang, Fang Li, Jiahua Wang, Tingyu Ye, Pengteng Guo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VCD-Texture: Variance Alignment based 3D-2D Co-Denoising for Text-Guided Texturing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.04461</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.04461v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent research on texture synthesis for 3D shapes benefits a lot from dramatically developed 2D text-to-image diffusion models, including inpainting-based and optimization-based approaches. However, these methods ignore the modal gap between the 2D diffusion model and 3D objects, which primarily render 3D objects into 2D images and texture each image separately. In this paper, we revisit the texture synthesis and propose a Variance alignment based 3D-2D Collaborative Denoising framework, dubbed VCD-Texture, to address these issues. Formally, we first unify both 2D and 3D latent feature learning in diffusion self-attention modules with re-projected 3D attention receptive fields. Subsequently, the denoised multi-view 2D latent features are aggregated into 3D space and then rasterized back to formulate more consistent 2D predictions. However, the rasterization process suffers from an intractable variance bias, which is theoretically addressed by the proposed variance alignment, achieving high-fidelity texture synthesis. Moreover, we present an inpainting refinement to further improve the details with conflicting regions. Notably, there is not a publicly available benchmark to evaluate texture synthesis, which hinders its development. Thus we construct a new evaluation set built upon three open-source 3D datasets and propose to use four metrics to thoroughly validate the texturing performance. Comprehensive experiments demonstrate that VCD-Texture achieves superior performance against other counterparts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.04461v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shang Liu, Chaohui Yu, Chenjie Cao, Wen Qian, Fan Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RNNs, CNNs and Transformers in Human Action Recognition: A Survey and a Hybrid Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.06162</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.06162v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Human Action Recognition (HAR) encompasses the task of monitoring human activities across various domains, including but not limited to medical, educational, entertainment, visual surveillance, video retrieval, and the identification of anomalous activities. Over the past decade, the field of HAR has witnessed substantial progress by leveraging Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs) to effectively extract and comprehend intricate information, thereby enhancing the overall performance of HAR systems. Recently, the domain of computer vision has witnessed the emergence of Vision Transformers (ViTs) as a potent solution. The efficacy of transformer architecture has been validated beyond the confines of image analysis, extending their applicability to diverse video-related tasks. Notably, within this landscape, the research community has shown keen interest in HAR, acknowledging its manifold utility and widespread adoption across various domains. This article aims to present an encompassing survey that focuses on CNNs and the evolution of Recurrent Neural Networks (RNNs) to ViTs given their importance in the domain of HAR. By conducting a thorough examination of existing literature and exploring emerging trends, this study undertakes a critical analysis and synthesis of the accumulated knowledge in this field. Additionally, it investigates the ongoing efforts to develop hybrid approaches. Following this direction, this article presents a novel hybrid model that seeks to integrate the inherent strengths of CNNs and ViTs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.06162v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Khaled Alomar, Halil Ibrahim Aysel, Xiaohao Cai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fully Test-Time rPPG Estimation via Synthetic Signal-Guided Feature Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.13322</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.13322v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Many remote photoplethysmography (rPPG) estimation models have achieved promising performance in the training domain but often fail to accurately estimate physiological signals or heart rates (HR) in the target domains. Domain generalization (DG) or domain adaptation (DA) techniques are therefore adopted during the offline training stage to adapt the model to either unobserved or observed target domains by utilizing all available source domain data. However, in rPPG estimation problems, the adapted model usually encounters challenges in estimating target data with significant domain variation. In contrast, Test-Time Adaptation (TTA) enables the model to adaptively estimate rPPG signals in various unseen domains by online adapting to unlabeled target data without referring to any source data. In this paper, we first establish a new TTA-rPPG benchmark that encompasses various domain information and HR distributions to simulate the challenges encountered in real-world rPPG estimation. Next, we propose a novel synthetic signal-guided rPPG estimation framework to address the forgetting issue during the TTA stage and to enhance the adaptation capability of the pre-trained rPPG model. To this end, we develop a synthetic signal-guided feature learning method by synthesizing pseudo rPPG signals as pseudo ground truths to guide a conditional generator in generating latent rPPG features. In addition, we design an effective spectral-based entropy minimization technique to encourage the rPPG model to learn new target domain information. Both the generated rPPG features and synthesized rPPG signals prevent the rPPG model from overfitting to target data and forgetting previously acquired knowledge, while also broadly covering various heart rate (HR) distributions. Our extensive experiments on the TTA-rPPG benchmark show that the proposed method achieves superior performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.13322v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Pei-Kai Huang, Tzu-Hsien Chen, Ya-Ting Chan, Kuan-Wen Chen, Chiou-Ting Hsu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Virchow2: Scaling Self-Supervised Mixed Magnification Models in Pathology</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00738</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00738v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Foundation models are rapidly being developed for computational pathology applications. However, it remains an open question which factors are most important for downstream performance with data scale and diversity, model size, and training algorithm all playing a role. In this work, we propose algorithmic modifications, tailored for pathology, and we present the result of scaling both data and model size, surpassing previous studies in both dimensions. We introduce two new models: Virchow2, a 632 million parameter vision transformer, and Virchow2G, a 1.9 billion parameter vision transformer, each trained with 3.1 million histopathology whole slide images, with diverse tissues, originating institutions, and stains. We achieve state of the art performance on 12 tile-level tasks, as compared to the top performing competing models. Our results suggest that data diversity and domain-specific methods can outperform models that only scale in the number of parameters, but, on average, performance benefits from the combination of domain-specific methods, data scale, and model scale.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00738v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Eric Zimmermann, Eugene Vorontsov, Julian Viret, Adam Casson, Michal Zelechowski, George Shaikovski, Neil Tenenholtz, James Hall, David Klimstra, Razik Yousfi, Thomas Fuchs, Nicolo Fusi, Siqi Liu, Kristen Severson</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual-View Pyramid Pooling in Deep Neural Networks for Improved Medical Image Classification and Confidence Calibration</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02906</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.02906v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Spatial pooling (SP) and cross-channel pooling (CCP) operators have been applied to aggregate spatial features and pixel-wise features from feature maps in deep neural networks (DNNs), respectively. Their main goal is to reduce computation and memory overhead without visibly weakening the performance of DNNs. However, SP often faces the problem of losing the subtle feature representations, while CCP has a high possibility of ignoring salient feature representations, which may lead to both miscalibration of confidence issues and suboptimal medical classification results. To address these problems, we propose a novel dual-view framework, the first to systematically investigate the relative roles of SP and CCP by analyzing the difference between spatial features and pixel-wise features. Based on this framework, we propose a new pooling method, termed dual-view pyramid pooling (DVPP), to aggregate multi-scale dual-view features. DVPP aims to boost both medical image classification and confidence calibration performance by fully leveraging the merits of SP and CCP operators from a dual-axis perspective. Additionally, we discuss how to fulfill DVPP with five parameter-free implementations. Extensive experiments on six 2D/3D medical image classification tasks show that our DVPP surpasses state-of-the-art pooling methods in terms of medical image classification results and confidence calibration across different DNNs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.02906v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoqing Zhang, Qiushi Nie, Zunjie Xiao, Jilu Zhao, Xiao Wu, Pengxin Guo, Runzhi Li, Jin Liu, Yanjie Wei, Yi Pan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DeepInteraction++: Multi-Modality Interaction for Autonomous Driving</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05075</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05075v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Existing top-performance autonomous driving systems typically rely on the multi-modal fusion strategy for reliable scene understanding. This design is however fundamentally restricted due to overlooking the modality-specific strengths and finally hampering the model performance. To address this limitation, in this work, we introduce a novel modality interaction strategy that allows individual per-modality representations to be learned and maintained throughout, enabling their unique characteristics to be exploited during the whole perception pipeline. To demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed strategy, we design DeepInteraction++, a multi-modal interaction framework characterized by a multi-modal representational interaction encoder and a multi-modal predictive interaction decoder. Specifically, the encoder is implemented as a dual-stream Transformer with specialized attention operation for information exchange and integration between separate modality-specific representations. Our multi-modal representational learning incorporates both object-centric, precise sampling-based feature alignment and global dense information spreading, essential for the more challenging planning task. The decoder is designed to iteratively refine the predictions by alternately aggregating information from separate representations in a unified modality-agnostic manner, realizing multi-modal predictive interaction. Extensive experiments demonstrate the superior performance of the proposed framework on both 3D object detection and end-to-end autonomous driving tasks. Our code is available at https://github.com/fudan-zvg/DeepInteraction.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05075v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zeyu Yang, Nan Song, Wei Li, Xiatian Zhu, Li Zhang, Philip H. S. Torr</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAM-FNet: SAM-Guided Fusion Network for Laryngo-Pharyngeal Tumor Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05426</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05426v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Laryngo-pharyngeal cancer (LPC) is a highly fatal malignant disease affecting the head and neck region. Previous studies on endoscopic tumor detection, particularly those leveraging dual-branch network architectures, have shown significant advancements in tumor detection. These studies highlight the potential of dual-branch networks in improving diagnostic accuracy by effectively integrating global and local (lesion) feature extraction. However, they are still limited in their capabilities to accurately locate the lesion region and capture the discriminative feature information between the global and local branches. To address these issues, we propose a novel SAM-guided fusion network (SAM-FNet), a dual-branch network for laryngo-pharyngeal tumor detection. By leveraging the powerful object segmentation capabilities of the Segment Anything Model (SAM), we introduce the SAM into the SAM-FNet to accurately segment the lesion region. Furthermore, we propose a GAN-like feature optimization (GFO) module to capture the discriminative features between the global and local branches, enhancing the fusion feature complementarity. Additionally, we collect two LPC datasets from the First Affiliated Hospital (FAHSYSU) and the Sixth Affiliated Hospital (SAHSYSU) of Sun Yat-sen University. The FAHSYSU dataset is used as the internal dataset for training the model, while the SAHSYSU dataset is used as the external dataset for evaluating the model's performance. Extensive experiments on both datasets of FAHSYSU and SAHSYSU demonstrate that the SAM-FNet can achieve competitive results, outperforming the state-of-the-art counterparts. The source code of SAM-FNet is available at the URL of https://github.com/VVJia/SAM-FNet.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05426v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jia Wei, Yun Li, Meiyu Qiu, Hongyu Chen, Xiaomao Fan, Wenbin Lei</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ControlNeXt: Powerful and Efficient Control for Image and Video Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06070</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06070v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Diffusion models have demonstrated remarkable and robust abilities in both image and video generation. To achieve greater control over generated results, researchers introduce additional architectures, such as ControlNet, Adapters and ReferenceNet, to integrate conditioning controls. However, current controllable generation methods often require substantial additional computational resources, especially for video generation, and face challenges in training or exhibit weak control. In this paper, we propose ControlNeXt: a powerful and efficient method for controllable image and video generation. We first design a more straightforward and efficient architecture, replacing heavy additional branches with minimal additional cost compared to the base model. Such a concise structure also allows our method to seamlessly integrate with other LoRA weights, enabling style alteration without the need for additional training. As for training, we reduce up to 90% of learnable parameters compared to the alternatives. Furthermore, we propose another method called Cross Normalization (CN) as a replacement for Zero-Convolution' to achieve fast and stable training convergence. We have conducted various experiments with different base models across images and videos, demonstrating the robustness of our method.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06070v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bohao Peng, Jian Wang, Yuechen Zhang, Wenbo Li, Ming-Chang Yang, Jiaya Jia</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generalization Enhancement Strategies to Enable Cross-year Cropland Mapping with Convolutional Neural Networks Trained Using Historical Samples</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06467</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06467v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The accuracy of mapping agricultural fields across large areas is steadily improving with high-resolution satellite imagery and deep learning (DL) models, even in regions where fields are small and geometrically irregular. However, developing effective DL models often requires large, expensive label datasets, typically available only for specific years or locations. This limits the ability to create annual maps essential for agricultural monitoring, as domain shifts occur between years and regions due to changes in farming practices and environmental conditions. The challenge is to design a model flexible enough to account for these shifts without needing yearly labels. While domain adaptation techniques or semi-supervised training are common solutions, we explored enhancing the model's generalization power. Our results indicate that a holistic approach is essential, combining methods to improve generalization. Specifically, using an area-based loss function, such as Tversky-focal loss (TFL), significantly improved predictions across multiple years. The use of different augmentation techniques helped to encode different types of invariance, particularly photometric augmentations encoded invariance to brightness changes, though they increased false positives. The combination of photometric augmentation, TFL loss, and MC-dropout produced the best results, although dropout alone led to more false negatives in subsequent year predictions. Additionally, the choice of input normalization had a significant impact, with the best results obtained when statistics were calculated either locally or across the entire dataset over all bands (lab and gab). We developed a workflow that enabled a U-Net model to generate effective multi-year crop maps over large areas. Our code, available at: https://github.com/agroimpacts/cnn-generalization-enhancement, will be regularly updated with improvements.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06467v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sam Khallaghi, Rahebe Abedi, Hanan Abou Ali, Mary Dziedzorm Asipunu, Ismail Alatise, Nguyen Ha, Boka Luo, Cat Mai, Lei Song, Amos Wussah, Sitian Xiong, Qi Zhang, Lyndon D. Estes</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prompt-Based Segmentation at Multiple Resolutions and Lighting Conditions using Segment Anything Model 2</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06970</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06970v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper provides insight into the effectiveness of zero-shot, prompt-based, Segment Anything Model (SAM), and its updated version, SAM 2, and the non-promptable, conventional convolutional network (CNN), in segmenting solar panels, in RGB aerial imagery, across lighting conditions, spatial resolutions, and prompt strategies. SAM 2 demonstrates improvements over SAM, particularly in sub-optimal lighting conditions when prompted by points. Both SAMs, prompted by user-box, outperformed CNN, in all scenarios. Additionally, YOLOv9 prompting outperformed user points prompting. In high-resolution imagery, both in optimal and sub-optimal lighting conditions, Eff-UNet outperformed both SAM models prompted by YOLOv9 boxes, positioning Eff-UNet as the appropriate model for automatic segmentation in high-resolution data. In low-resolution data, user box prompts were found crucial to achieve a reasonable performance. This paper provides details on strengths and limitations of each model and outlines robustness of user prompted image segmentation models in inconsistent resolution and lighting conditions of remotely sensed data.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06970v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Osher Rafaeli, Tal Svoray, Roni Blushtein-Livnon, Ariel Nahlieli</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MagicFace: Training-free Universal-Style Human Image Customized Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07433</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07433v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Existing human image personalized generation methods often require tedious training: either fine-tuning with a few images or retraining on large-scale datasets. In such cases, these methods are prone to overfitting and encounter difficulties when personalizing individuals of diverse styles. Moreover, these training-based approaches also struggle with multi-concept human image customizing. To this end, we propose MagicFace, the first method for universal-style human image personalized synthesis that enables single/multi-concept customization for humans of any style in a training-free manner. MagicFace introduces a coarse-to-fine generation pipeline, involving two sequential stages: semantic scene construction and concept feature injection. This is achieved by our Reference-aware Self-Attention (RSA) and Region-grouped Blend Attention (RBA) mechanisms. Specifically, in the first stage, RSA enables the latent image to query features from reference concepts simultaneously, extracting the coarse-grained overall semantic understanding to facilitate the initial semantic layout establishment. In the second stage, we employ an attention-based semantic segmentation method to pinpoint the generated regions of all concepts in the latent image at each step. Following this, RBA divides the pixels of the latent image into semantic groups, with each group querying fine-grained features from its reference concept, which ensures precise attribute alignment and feature injection. Throughout the two-stage process, a weight mask strategy is employed to ensure the model focuses more on the reference concepts. Extensive experiments demonstrate our superiority in both human-centric subject-to-image synthesis and multi-concept human image customization. Our approach also can be applied to texture transformation, further enhancing its versatility and applicability.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07433v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yibin Wang, Weizhong Zhang, Cheng Jin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BAPLe: Backdoor Attacks on Medical Foundational Models using Prompt Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07440</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07440v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Medical foundation models are gaining prominence in the medical community for their ability to derive general representations from extensive collections of medical image-text pairs. Recent research indicates that these models are susceptible to backdoor attacks, which allow them to classify clean images accurately but fail when specific triggers are introduced. However, traditional backdoor attacks necessitate a considerable amount of additional data to maliciously pre-train a model. This requirement is often impractical in medical imaging applications due to the usual scarcity of data. Inspired by the latest developments in learnable prompts, this work introduces a method to embed a backdoor into the medical foundation model during the prompt learning phase. By incorporating learnable prompts within the text encoder and introducing imperceptible learnable noise trigger to the input images, we exploit the full capabilities of the medical foundation models (Med-FM). Our method, BAPLe, requires only a minimal subset of data to adjust the noise trigger and the text prompts for downstream tasks, enabling the creation of an effective backdoor attack. Through extensive experiments with four medical foundation models, each pre-trained on different modalities and evaluated across six downstream datasets, we demonstrate the efficacy of our approach. BAPLe achieves a high backdoor success rate across all models and datasets, outperforming the baseline backdoor attack methods. Our work highlights the vulnerability of Med-FMs towards backdoor attacks and strives to promote the safe adoption of Med-FMs before their deployment in real-world applications. Code is available at https://asif-hanif.github.io/baple/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07440v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Asif Hanif, Fahad Shamshad, Muhammad Awais, Muzammal Naseer, Fahad Shahbaz Khan, Karthik Nandakumar, Salman Khan, Rao Muhammad Anwer</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DIffSteISR: Harnessing Diffusion Prior for Superior Real-world Stereo Image Super-Resolution</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07516</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07516v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We introduce DiffSteISR, a pioneering framework for reconstructing real-world stereo images. DiffSteISR utilizes the powerful prior knowledge embedded in pre-trained text-to-image model to efficiently recover the lost texture details in low-resolution stereo images. Specifically, DiffSteISR implements a time-aware stereo cross attention with temperature adapter (TASCATA) to guide the diffusion process, ensuring that the generated left and right views exhibit high texture consistency thereby reducing disparity error between the super-resolved images and the ground truth (GT) images. Additionally, a stereo omni attention control network (SOA ControlNet) is proposed to enhance the consistency of super-resolved images with GT images in the pixel, perceptual, and distribution space. Finally, DiffSteISR incorporates a stereo semantic extractor (SSE) to capture unique viewpoint soft semantic information and shared hard tag semantic information, thereby effectively improving the semantic accuracy and consistency of the generated left and right images. Extensive experimental results demonstrate that DiffSteISR accurately reconstructs natural and precise textures from low-resolution stereo images while maintaining a high consistency of semantic and texture between the left and right views.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07516v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuanbo Zhou, Xinlin Zhang, Wei Deng, Tao Wang, Tao Tan, Qinquan Gao, Tong Tong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MathScape: Evaluating MLLMs in multimodal Math Scenarios through a Hierarchical Benchmark</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07543</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07543v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: With the development of Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs), the evaluation of multimodal models in the context of mathematical problems has become a valuable research field. Multimodal visual-textual mathematical reasoning serves as a critical indicator for evaluating the comprehension and complex multi-step quantitative reasoning abilities of MLLMs. However, previous multimodal math benchmarks have not sufficiently integrated visual and textual information. To address this gap, we proposed MathScape, a new benchmark that emphasizes the understanding and application of combined visual and textual information. MathScape is designed to evaluate photo-based math problem scenarios, assessing the theoretical understanding and application ability of MLLMs through a categorical hierarchical approach. We conduct a multi-dimensional evaluation on 11 advanced MLLMs, revealing that our benchmark is challenging even for the most sophisticated models. By analyzing the evaluation results, we identify the limitations of MLLMs, offering valuable insights for enhancing model performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07543v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Minxuan Zhou, Hao Liang, Tianpeng Li, Zhiyu Wu, Mingan Lin, Linzhuang Sun, Yaqi Zhou, Yan Zhang, Xiaoqin Huang, Yicong Chen, Yujing Qiao, Weipeng Chen, Bin Cui, Wentao Zhang, Zenan Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MetaSeg: MetaFormer-based Global Contexts-aware Network for Efficient Semantic Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07576</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07576v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Beyond the Transformer, it is important to explore how to exploit the capacity of the MetaFormer, an architecture that is fundamental to the performance improvements of the Transformer. Previous studies have exploited it only for the backbone network. Unlike previous studies, we explore the capacity of the Metaformer architecture more extensively in the semantic segmentation task. We propose a powerful semantic segmentation network, MetaSeg, which leverages the Metaformer architecture from the backbone to the decoder. Our MetaSeg shows that the MetaFormer architecture plays a significant role in capturing the useful contexts for the decoder as well as for the backbone. In addition, recent segmentation methods have shown that using a CNN-based backbone for extracting the spatial information and a decoder for extracting the global information is more effective than using a transformer-based backbone with a CNN-based decoder. This motivates us to adopt the CNN-based backbone using the MetaFormer block and design our MetaFormer-based decoder, which consists of a novel self-attention module to capture the global contexts. To consider both the global contexts extraction and the computational efficiency of the self-attention for semantic segmentation, we propose a Channel Reduction Attention (CRA) module that reduces the channel dimension of the query and key into the one dimension. In this way, our proposed MetaSeg outperforms the previous state-of-the-art methods with more efficient computational costs on popular semantic segmentation and a medical image segmentation benchmark, including ADE20K, Cityscapes, COCO-stuff, and Synapse. The code is available at https://github.com/hyunwoo137/MetaSeg.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07576v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Beoungwoo Kang, Seunghun Moon, Yubin Cho, Hyunwoo Yu, Suk-Ju Kang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Spitting Image: Modular Superpixel Tokenization in Vision Transformers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07680</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07680v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Vision Transformer (ViT) architectures traditionally employ a grid-based approach to tokenization independent of the semantic content of an image. We propose a modular superpixel tokenization strategy which decouples tokenization and feature extraction; a shift from contemporary approaches where these are treated as an undifferentiated whole. Using on-line content-aware tokenization and scale- and shape-invariant positional embeddings, we perform experiments and ablations that contrast our approach with patch-based tokenization and randomized partitions as baselines. We show that our method significantly improves the faithfulness of attributions, gives pixel-level granularity on zero-shot unsupervised dense prediction tasks, while maintaining predictive performance in classification tasks. Our approach provides a modular tokenization framework commensurable with standard architectures, extending the space of ViTs to a larger class of semantically-rich models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07680v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Marius Aasan, Odd Kolbj{\o}rnsen, Anne Schistad Solberg, Ad\'in Ramirez Rivera</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>End-to-end Autonomous Driving: Challenges and Frontiers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2306.16927</link>
      <description>arXiv:2306.16927v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The autonomous driving community has witnessed a rapid growth in approaches that embrace an end-to-end algorithm framework, utilizing raw sensor input to generate vehicle motion plans, instead of concentrating on individual tasks such as detection and motion prediction. End-to-end systems, in comparison to modular pipelines, benefit from joint feature optimization for perception and planning. This field has flourished due to the availability of large-scale datasets, closed-loop evaluation, and the increasing need for autonomous driving algorithms to perform effectively in challenging scenarios. In this survey, we provide a comprehensive analysis of more than 270 papers, covering the motivation, roadmap, methodology, challenges, and future trends in end-to-end autonomous driving. We delve into several critical challenges, including multi-modality, interpretability, causal confusion, robustness, and world models, amongst others. Additionally, we discuss current advancements in foundation models and visual pre-training, as well as how to incorporate these techniques within the end-to-end driving framework. we maintain an active repository that contains up-to-date literature and open-source projects at https://github.com/OpenDriveLab/End-to-end-Autonomous-Driving.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2306.16927v3</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Li Chen, Penghao Wu, Kashyap Chitta, Bernhard Jaeger, Andreas Geiger, Hongyang Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Examining Common Paradigms in Multi-Task Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.04698</link>
      <description>arXiv:2311.04698v5 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: While multi-task learning (MTL) has gained significant attention in recent years, its underlying mechanisms remain poorly understood. Recent methods did not yield consistent performance improvements over single task learning (STL) baselines, underscoring the importance of gaining more profound insights about challenges specific to MTL. In our study, we investigate paradigms in MTL in the context of STL: First, the impact of the choice of optimizer has only been mildly investigated in MTL. We show the pivotal role of common STL tools such as the Adam optimizer in MTL empirically in various experiments. To further investigate Adam's effectiveness, we theoretical derive a partial loss-scale invariance under mild assumptions. Second, the notion of gradient conflicts has often been phrased as a specific problem in MTL. We delve into the role of gradient conflicts in MTL and compare it to STL. For angular gradient alignment we find no evidence that this is a unique problem in MTL. We emphasize differences in gradient magnitude as the main distinguishing factor. Overall, we find surprising similarities between STL and MTL suggesting to consider methods from both fields in a broader context.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2311.04698v5</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Cathrin Elich, Lukas Kirchdorfer, Jan M. K\"ohler, Lukas Schott</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WATonoBus: Field-Tested All-Weather Autonomous Shuttle Technology</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.00938</link>
      <description>arXiv:2312.00938v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: All-weather autonomous vehicle operation poses significant challenges, encompassing modules from perception and decision-making to path planning and control. The complexity arises from the need to address adverse weather conditions such as rain, snow, and fog across the autonomy stack. Conventional model-based single-module approaches often lack holistic integration with upstream or downstream tasks. We tackle this problem by proposing a multi-module and modular system architecture with considerations for adverse weather across the perception level, through features such as snow covered curb detection, to decision-making and safety monitoring. Through daily weekday service on the WATonoBus platform for almost two years, we demonstrate that our proposed approach is capable of addressing adverse weather conditions and provide valuable insights from edge cases observed during operation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2312.00938v2</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Neel P. Bhatt, Ruihe Zhang, Minghao Ning, Ahmad Reza Alghooneh, Joseph Sun, Pouya Panahandeh, Ehsan Mohammadbagher, Ted Ecclestone, Ben MacCallum, Ehsan Hashemi, Amir Khajepour</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Distributed Privacy Preserving Model for the Detection of Alzheimer's Disease</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.10237</link>
      <description>arXiv:2312.10237v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: BACKGROUND: Segmentation of medical data, concerns about personal health information (PHI) breaches, and the direct and indirect costs of consolidating and managing such segmented date should motivate diagnostic machine learning (DML) researchers to identify privacy-preserving machine learning algorithms that can train on distributed or decentralized datasets of different modalities. Federated learning models provide such a decentralized machine learning framework in which multiple investigators in possession of disparate datasets and working on different devices or servers can train collaboratively a global machine learning models without ever having to exchange local data and thus can meet statutory PHI protections. To this end, a vertical federate learning model is devised and tested for efficacy in the detection of Alzheimer's Disease (AD).
  METHODS: The second version of Open Access Series of Imaging Studies -- with its panoply of demographic, imaging, and clinical assessment datasets -- was used to test a multimodal vertical federated learning (VFL) model for AD detection.
  RESULTS: By training and validating this VFL model on the demographic, clinical, and MRI data in OASIS-2, an 82.9\% accuracy rate is achieved, consistent with previously reported results.
  CONCLUSIONS: The VFL architecture proposed herein offers a novel distributed architecture, enabling collaborative learning across diverse sources of medical data while respecting statutory privacy constraints. By leveraging multiple modalities of data, the robustness and accuracy of AD detection can be enhanced. This model not only contributes to the advancement of federated learning techniques but also holds promise for overcoming the hurdles posed by data segmentation in medical research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2312.10237v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.DC</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Paul K. Mandal</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing chest X-ray datasets with privacy-preserving large language models and multi-type annotations: a data-driven approach for improved classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.04024</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.04024v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In chest X-ray (CXR) image analysis, rule-based systems are usually employed to extract labels from reports for dataset releases. However, there is still room for improvement in label quality. These labelers typically output only presence labels, sometimes with binary uncertainty indicators, which limits their usefulness. Supervised deep learning models have also been developed for report labeling but lack adaptability, similar to rule-based systems. In this work, we present MAPLEZ (Medical report Annotations with Privacy-preserving Large language model using Expeditious Zero shot answers), a novel approach leveraging a locally executable Large Language Model (LLM) to extract and enhance findings labels on CXR reports. MAPLEZ extracts not only binary labels indicating the presence or absence of a finding but also the location, severity, and radiologists' uncertainty about the finding. Over eight abnormalities from five test sets, we show that our method can extract these annotations with an increase of 3.6 percentage points (pp) in macro F1 score for categorical presence annotations and more than 20 pp increase in F1 score for the location annotations over competing labelers. Additionally, using the combination of improved annotations and multi-type annotations in classification supervision, we demonstrate substantial advancements in model quality, with an increase of 1.1 pp in AUROC over models trained with annotations from the best alternative approach. We share code and annotations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.04024v2</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ricardo Bigolin Lanfredi, Pritam Mukherjee, Ronald Summers</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research on the Spatial Data Intelligent Large Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.19730</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.19730v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: This report focuses on spatial data intelligent large models, delving into the principles, methods, and cutting-edge applications of these models. It provides an in-depth discussion on the definition, development history, current status, and trends of spatial data intelligent large models, as well as the challenges they face. The report systematically elucidates the key technologies of spatial data intelligent large models and their applications in urban environments, aerospace remote sensing, geography, transportation, and other scenarios. Additionally, it summarizes the latest application cases of spatial data intelligent large models in themes such as urban development, multimodal systems, remote sensing, smart transportation, and resource environments. Finally, the report concludes with an overview and outlook on the development prospects of spatial data intelligent large models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.19730v3</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shaohua Wang (Aerospace Information Research Institute, Chinese Academy of Sciences), Xing Xie (Microsoft Research Asia), Yong Li (Tsinghua University), Danhuai Guo (Beijing University of Chemical Technology), Zhi Cai (Beijing University of Technology), Yu Liu (Peking University), Yang Yue (Shenzhen University), Xiao Pan (Shijiazhuang Railway University), Feng Lu (Institute of Geographic Sciences and Natural Resources Research, Chinese Academy of Sciences), Huayi Wu (Wuhan University), Zhipeng Gui (Wuhan University), Zhiming Ding (Research Institute of Software, Chinese Academy of Sciences), Bolong Zheng (Huazhong University of Science and Technology), Fuzheng Zhang (Fast Natural Language Processing Center and Audio Center), Jingyuan Wang (Beihang University), Zhengchao Chen (Aerospace Information Research Institute, Chinese Academy of Sciences), Hao Lu (SuperMap Software Co. Ltd), Jiayi Li (Wuhan University), Peng Yue (Wuhan University), Wenhao Yu (China University of Geosciences), Yao Yao (China University of Geosciences), Leilei Sun (Beihang University), Yong Zhang (Beijing University of Technology), Longbiao Chen (Xiamen University), Xiaoping Du (Key Laboratory of Digital Geography, Chinese Academy of Sciences), Xiang Li (East China Normal University), Xueying Zhang (Nanjing Normal University), Kun Qin (Wuhan University), Zhaoya Gong (Peking University), Weihua Dong (Beijing Normal University), Xiaofeng Meng (Renmin University of China)</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multimodal Emotion Recognition using Audio-Video Transformer Fusion with Cross Attention</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.18552</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.18552v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Understanding emotions is a fundamental aspect of human communication. Integrating audio and video signals offers a more comprehensive understanding of emotional states compared to traditional methods that rely on a single data source, such as speech or facial expressions. Despite its potential, multimodal emotion recognition faces significant challenges, particularly in synchronization, feature extraction, and fusion of diverse data sources. To address these issues, this paper introduces a novel transformer-based model named Audio-Video Transformer Fusion with Cross Attention (AVT-CA). The AVT-CA model employs a transformer fusion approach to effectively capture and synchronize interlinked features from both audio and video inputs, thereby resolving synchronization problems. Additionally, the Cross Attention mechanism within AVT-CA selectively extracts and emphasizes critical features while discarding irrelevant ones from both modalities, addressing feature extraction and fusion challenges. Extensive experimental analysis conducted on the CMU-MOSEI, RAVDESS and CREMA-D datasets demonstrates the efficacy of the proposed model. The results underscore the importance of AVT-CA in developing precise and reliable multimodal emotion recognition systems for practical applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.18552v2</guid>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Joe Dhanith P R, Shravan Venkatraman, Modigari Narendra, Vigya Sharma, Santhosh Malarvannan, Amir H. Gandomi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Llama 3 Herd of Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.21783</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.21783v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Modern artificial intelligence (AI) systems are powered by foundation models. This paper presents a new set of foundation models, called Llama 3. It is a herd of language models that natively support multilinguality, coding, reasoning, and tool usage. Our largest model is a dense Transformer with 405B parameters and a context window of up to 128K tokens. This paper presents an extensive empirical evaluation of Llama 3. We find that Llama 3 delivers comparable quality to leading language models such as GPT-4 on a plethora of tasks. We publicly release Llama 3, including pre-trained and post-trained versions of the 405B parameter language model and our Llama Guard 3 model for input and output safety. The paper also presents the results of experiments in which we integrate image, video, and speech capabilities into Llama 3 via a compositional approach. We observe this approach performs competitively with the state-of-the-art on image, video, and speech recognition tasks. The resulting models are not yet being broadly released as they are still under development.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.21783v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Abhimanyu Dubey (Jack), Abhinav Jauhri (Jack), Abhinav Pandey (Jack), Abhishek Kadian (Jack), Ahmad Al-Dahle (Jack), Aiesha Letman (Jack), Akhil Mathur (Jack), Alan Schelten (Jack), Amy Yang (Jack), Angela Fan (Jack), Anirudh Goyal (Jack), Anthony Hartshorn (Jack), Aobo Yang (Jack), Archi Mitra (Jack), Archie Sravankumar (Jack), Artem Korenev (Jack), Arthur Hinsvark (Jack), Arun Rao (Jack), Aston Zhang (Jack), Aurelien Rodriguez (Jack), Austen Gregerson (Jack), Ava Spataru (Jack), Baptiste Roziere (Jack), Bethany Biron (Jack), Binh Tang (Jack), Bobbie Chern (Jack), Charlotte Caucheteux (Jack), Chaya Nayak (Jack), Chloe Bi (Jack), Chris Marra (Jack), Chris McConnell (Jack), Christian Keller (Jack), Christophe Touret (Jack), Chunyang Wu (Jack), Corinne Wong (Jack), Cristian Canton Ferrer (Jack), Cyrus Nikolaidis (Jack), Damien Allonsius (Jack), Daniel Song (Jack), Danielle Pintz (Jack), Danny Livshits (Jack), David Esiobu (Jack), Dhruv Choudhary (Jack), Dhruv Mahajan (Jack), Diego Garcia-Olano (Jack), Diego Perino (Jack), Dieuwke Hupkes (Jack), Egor Lakomkin (Jack), Ehab AlBadawy (Jack), Elina Lobanova (Jack), Emily Dinan (Jack), Eric Michael Smith (Jack), Filip Radenovic (Jack), Frank Zhang (Jack), Gabriel Synnaeve (Jack), Gabrielle Lee (Jack), Georgia Lewis Anderson (Jack), Graeme Nail (Jack), Gregoire Mialon (Jack), Guan Pang (Jack), Guillem Cucurell (Jack), Hailey Nguyen (Jack), Hannah Korevaar (Jack), Hu Xu (Jack), Hugo Touvron (Jack), Iliyan Zarov (Jack), Imanol Arrieta Ibarra (Jack), Isabel Kloumann (Jack), Ishan Misra (Jack), Ivan Evtimov (Jack), Jade Copet (Jack), Jaewon Lee (Jack), Jan Geffert (Jack), Jana Vranes (Jack), Jason Park (Jack), Jay Mahadeokar (Jack), Jeet Shah (Jack), Jelmer van der Linde (Jack), Jennifer Billock (Jack), Jenny Hong (Jack), Jenya Lee (Jack), Jeremy Fu (Jack), Jianfeng Chi (Jack), Jianyu Huang (Jack), Jiawen Liu (Jack), Jie Wang (Jack), Jiecao Yu (Jack), Joanna Bitton (Jack), Joe Spisak (Jack), Jongsoo Park (Jack), Joseph Rocca (Jack), Joshua Johnstun (Jack), Joshua Saxe (Jack), Junteng Jia (Jack), Kalyan Vasuden Alwala (Jack), Kartikeya Upasani (Jack), Kate Plawiak (Jack), Ke Li (Jack), Kenneth Heafield (Jack), Kevin Stone (Jack), Khalid El-Arini (Jack), Krithika Iyer (Jack), Kshitiz Malik (Jack), Kuenley Chiu (Jack), Kunal Bhalla (Jack), Lauren Rantala-Yeary (Jack), Laurens van der Maaten (Jack), Lawrence Chen (Jack), Liang Tan (Jack), Liz Jenkins (Jack), Louis Martin (Jack), Lovish Madaan (Jack), Lubo Malo (Jack), Lukas Blecher (Jack), Lukas Landzaat (Jack), Luke de Oliveira (Jack), Madeline Muzzi (Jack), Mahesh Pasupuleti (Jack), Mannat Singh (Jack), Manohar Paluri (Jack), Marcin Kardas (Jack), Mathew Oldham (Jack), Mathieu Rita (Jack), Maya Pavlova (Jack), Melanie Kambadur (Jack), Mike Lewis (Jack), Min Si (Jack), Mitesh Kumar Singh (Jack), Mona Hassan (Jack), Naman Goyal (Jack), Narjes Torabi (Jack), Nikolay Bashlykov (Jack), Nikolay Bogoychev (Jack), Niladri Chatterji (Jack), Olivier Duchenne (Jack), Onur \c{C}elebi (Jack), Patrick Alrassy (Jack), Pengchuan Zhang (Jack), Pengwei Li (Jack), Petar Vasic (Jack), Peter Weng (Jack), Prajjwal Bhargava (Jack), Pratik Dubal (Jack), Praveen Krishnan (Jack), Punit Singh Koura (Jack), Puxin Xu (Jack), Qing He (Jack), Qingxiao Dong (Jack), Ragavan Srinivasan (Jack), Raj Ganapathy (Jack), Ramon Calderer (Jack), Ricardo Silveira Cabral (Jack), Robert Stojnic (Jack), Roberta Raileanu (Jack), Rohit Girdhar (Jack), Rohit Patel (Jack), Romain Sauvestre (Jack), Ronnie Polidoro (Jack), Roshan Sumbaly (Jack), Ross Taylor (Jack), Ruan Silva (Jack), Rui Hou (Jack), Rui Wang (Jack), Saghar Hosseini (Jack), Sahana Chennabasappa (Jack), Sanjay Singh (Jack), Sean Bell (Jack), Seohyun Sonia Kim (Jack), Sergey Edunov (Jack), Shaoliang Nie (Jack), Sharan Narang (Jack), Sharath Raparthy (Jack), Sheng Shen (Jack), Shengye Wan (Jack), Shruti Bhosale (Jack), Shun Zhang (Jack), Simon Vandenhende (Jack), Soumya Batra (Jack), Spencer Whitman (Jack), Sten Sootla (Jack), Stephane Collot (Jack), Suchin Gururangan (Jack), Sydney Borodinsky (Jack), Tamar Herman (Jack), Tara Fowler (Jack), Tarek Sheasha (Jack), Thomas Georgiou (Jack), Thomas Scialom (Jack), Tobias Speckbacher (Jack), Todor Mihaylov (Jack), Tong Xiao (Jack), Ujjwal Karn (Jack), Vedanuj Goswami (Jack), Vibhor Gupta (Jack), Vignesh Ramanathan (Jack), Viktor Kerkez (Jack), Vincent Gonguet (Jack), Virginie Do (Jack), Vish Vogeti (Jack), Vladan Petrovic (Jack), Weiwei Chu (Jack), Wenhan Xiong (Jack), Wenyin Fu (Jack), Whitney Meers (Jack), Xavier Martinet (Jack), Xiaodong Wang (Jack), Xiaoqing Ellen Tan (Jack), Xinfeng Xie (Jack), Xuchao Jia (Jack), Xuewei Wang (Jack), Yaelle Goldschlag (Jack), Yashesh Gaur (Jack), Yasmine Babaei (Jack), Yi Wen (Jack), Yiwen Song (Jack), Yuchen Zhang (Jack), Yue Li (Jack), Yuning Mao (Jack), Zacharie Delpierre Coudert (Jack), Zheng Yan (Jack), Zhengxing Chen (Jack), Zoe Papakipos (Jack), Aaditya Singh (Jack), Aaron Grattafiori (Jack), Abha Jain (Jack), Adam Kelsey (Jack), Adam Shajnfeld (Jack), Adithya Gangidi (Jack), Adolfo Victoria (Jack), Ahuva Goldstand (Jack), Ajay Menon (Jack), Ajay Sharma (Jack), Alex Boesenberg (Jack), Alex Vaughan (Jack), Alexei Baevski (Jack), Allie Feinstein (Jack), Amanda Kallet (Jack), Amit Sangani (Jack), Anam Yunus (Jack), Andrei Lupu (Jack), Andres Alvarado (Jack), Andrew Caples (Jack), Andrew Gu (Jack), Andrew Ho (Jack), Andrew Poulton (Jack), Andrew Ryan (Jack), Ankit Ramchandani (Jack), Annie Franco (Jack), Aparajita Saraf (Jack), Arkabandhu Chowdhury (Jack), Ashley Gabriel (Jack), Ashwin Bharambe (Jack), Assaf Eisenman (Jack), Azadeh Yazdan (Jack), Beau James (Jack), Ben Maurer (Jack), Benjamin Leonhardi (Jack), Bernie Huang (Jack), Beth Loyd (Jack), Beto De Paola (Jack), Bhargavi Paranjape (Jack), Bing Liu (Jack), Bo Wu (Jack), Boyu Ni (Jack), Braden Hancock (Jack), Bram Wasti (Jack), Brandon Spence (Jack), Brani Stojkovic (Jack), Brian Gamido (Jack), Britt Montalvo (Jack), Carl Parker (Jack), Carly Burton (Jack), Catalina Mejia (Jack), Changhan Wang (Jack), Changkyu Kim (Jack), Chao Zhou (Jack), Chester Hu (Jack), Ching-Hsiang Chu (Jack), Chris Cai (Jack), Chris Tindal (Jack), Christoph Feichtenhofer (Jack), Damon Civin (Jack), Dana Beaty (Jack), Daniel Kreymer (Jack), Daniel Li (Jack), Danny Wyatt (Jack), David Adkins (Jack), David Xu (Jack), Davide Testuggine (Jack), Delia David (Jack), Devi Parikh (Jack), Diana Liskovich (Jack), Didem Foss (Jack), Dingkang Wang (Jack), Duc Le (Jack), Dustin Holland (Jack), Edward Dowling (Jack), Eissa Jamil (Jack), Elaine Montgomery (Jack), Eleonora Presani (Jack), Emily Hahn (Jack), Emily Wood (Jack), Erik Brinkman (Jack), Esteban Arcaute (Jack), Evan Dunbar (Jack), Evan Smothers (Jack), Fei Sun (Jack), Felix Kreuk (Jack), Feng Tian (Jack), Firat Ozgenel (Jack), Francesco Caggioni (Jack), Francisco Guzm\'an (Jack), Frank Kanayet (Jack), Frank Seide (Jack), Gabriela Medina Florez (Jack), Gabriella Schwarz (Jack), Gada Badeer (Jack), Georgia Swee (Jack), Gil Halpern (Jack), Govind Thattai (Jack), Grant Herman (Jack), Grigory Sizov (Jack),  Guangyi (Jack),  Zhang (Sid), Guna Lakshminarayanan (Sid), Hamid Shojanazeri (Sid), Han Zou (Sid), Hannah Wang (Sid), Hanwen Zha (Sid), Haroun Habeeb (Sid), Harrison Rudolph (Sid), Helen Suk (Sid), Henry Aspegren (Sid), Hunter Goldman (Sid), Ibrahim Damlaj (Sid), Igor Molybog (Sid), Igor Tufanov (Sid), Irina-Elena Veliche (Sid), Itai Gat (Sid), Jake Weissman (Sid), James Geboski (Sid), James Kohli (Sid), Japhet Asher (Sid), Jean-Baptiste Gaya (Sid), Jeff Marcus (Sid), Jeff Tang (Sid), Jennifer Chan (Sid), Jenny Zhen (Sid), Jeremy Reizenstein (Sid), Jeremy Teboul (Sid), Jessica Zhong (Sid), Jian Jin (Sid), Jingyi Yang (Sid), Joe Cummings (Sid), Jon Carvill (Sid), Jon Shepard (Sid), Jonathan McPhie (Sid), Jonathan Torres (Sid), Josh Ginsburg (Sid), Junjie Wang (Sid), Kai Wu (Sid), Kam Hou U (Sid), Karan Saxena (Sid), Karthik Prasad (Sid), Kartikay Khandelwal (Sid), Katayoun Zand (Sid), Kathy Matosich (Sid), Kaushik Veeraraghavan (Sid), Kelly Michelena (Sid), Keqian Li (Sid), Kun Huang (Sid), Kunal Chawla (Sid), Kushal Lakhotia (Sid), Kyle Huang (Sid), Lailin Chen (Sid), Lakshya Garg (Sid), Lavender A (Sid), Leandro Silva (Sid), Lee Bell (Sid), Lei Zhang (Sid), Liangpeng Guo (Sid), Licheng Yu (Sid), Liron Moshkovich (Sid), Luca Wehrstedt (Sid), Madian Khabsa (Sid), Manav Avalani (Sid), Manish Bhatt (Sid), Maria Tsimpoukelli (Sid), Martynas Mankus (Sid), Matan Hasson (Sid), Matthew Lennie (Sid), Matthias Reso (Sid), Maxim Groshev (Sid), Maxim Naumov (Sid), Maya Lathi (Sid), Meghan Keneally (Sid), Michael L. Seltzer (Sid), Michal Valko (Sid), Michelle Restrepo (Sid), Mihir Patel (Sid), Mik Vyatskov (Sid), Mikayel Samvelyan (Sid), Mike Clark (Sid), Mike Macey (Sid), Mike Wang (Sid), Miquel Jubert Hermoso (Sid), Mo Metanat (Sid), Mohammad Rastegari (Sid), Munish Bansal (Sid), Nandhini Santhanam (Sid), Natascha Parks (Sid), Natasha White (Sid), Navyata Bawa (Sid), Nayan Singhal (Sid), Nick Egebo (Sid), Nicolas Usunier (Sid), Nikolay Pavlovich Laptev (Sid), Ning Dong (Sid), Ning Zhang (Sid), Norman Cheng (Sid), Oleg Chernoguz (Sid), Olivia Hart (Sid), Omkar Salpekar (Sid), Ozlem Kalinli (Sid), Parkin Kent (Sid), Parth Parekh (Sid), Paul Saab (Sid), Pavan Balaji (Sid), Pedro Rittner (Sid), Philip Bontrager (Sid), Pierre Roux (Sid), Piotr Dollar (Sid), Polina Zvyagina (Sid), Prashant Ratanchandani (Sid), Pritish Yuvraj (Sid), Qian Liang (Sid), Rachad Alao (Sid), Rachel Rodriguez (Sid), Rafi Ayub (Sid), Raghotham Murthy (Sid), Raghu Nayani (Sid), Rahul Mitra (Sid), Raymond Li (Sid), Rebekkah Hogan (Sid), Robin Battey (Sid), Rocky Wang (Sid), Rohan Maheswari (Sid), Russ Howes (Sid), Ruty Rinott (Sid), Sai Jayesh Bondu (Sid), Samyak Datta (Sid), Sara Chugh (Sid), Sara Hunt (Sid), Sargun Dhillon (Sid), Sasha Sidorov (Sid), Satadru Pan (Sid), Saurabh Verma (Sid), Seiji Yamamoto (Sid), Sharadh Ramaswamy (Sid), Shaun Lindsay (Sid), Shaun Lindsay (Sid), Sheng Feng (Sid), Shenghao Lin (Sid), Shengxin Cindy Zha (Sid), Shiva Shankar (Sid), Shuqiang Zhang (Sid), Shuqiang Zhang (Sid), Sinong Wang (Sid), Sneha Agarwal (Sid), Soji Sajuyigbe (Sid), Soumith Chintala (Sid), Stephanie Max (Sid), Stephen Chen (Sid), Steve Kehoe (Sid), Steve Satterfield (Sid), Sudarshan Govindaprasad (Sid), Sumit Gupta (Sid), Sungmin Cho (Sid), Sunny Virk (Sid), Suraj Subramanian (Sid), Sy Choudhury (Sid), Sydney Goldman (Sid), Tal Remez (Sid), Tamar Glaser (Sid), Tamara Best (Sid), Thilo Kohler (Sid), Thomas Robinson (Sid), Tianhe Li (Sid), Tianjun Zhang (Sid), Tim Matthews (Sid), Timothy Chou (Sid), Tzook Shaked (Sid), Varun Vontimitta (Sid), Victoria Ajayi (Sid), Victoria Montanez (Sid), Vijai Mohan (Sid), Vinay Satish Kumar (Sid), Vishal Mangla (Sid), V\'itor Albiero (Sid), Vlad Ionescu (Sid), Vlad Poenaru (Sid), Vlad Tiberiu Mihailescu (Sid), Vladimir Ivanov (Sid), Wei Li (Sid), Wenchen Wang (Sid), Wenwen Jiang (Sid), Wes Bouaziz (Sid), Will Constable (Sid), Xiaocheng Tang (Sid), Xiaofang Wang (Sid), Xiaojian Wu (Sid), Xiaolan Wang (Sid), Xide Xia (Sid), Xilun Wu (Sid), Xinbo Gao (Sid), Yanjun Chen (Sid), Ye Hu (Sid), Ye Jia (Sid), Ye Qi (Sid), Yenda Li (Sid), Yilin Zhang (Sid), Ying Zhang (Sid), Yossi Adi (Sid), Youngjin Nam (Sid),  Yu (Sid),  Wang, Yuchen Hao, Yundi Qian, Yuzi He, Zach Rait, Zachary DeVito, Zef Rosnbrick, Zhaoduo Wen, Zhenyu Yang, Zhiwei Zhao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMAES: Augmented Masked Autoencoder Pretraining on Public Brain MRI Data for 3D-Native Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00640</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00640v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: This study investigates the impact of self-supervised pretraining of 3D semantic segmentation models on a large-scale, domain-specific dataset. We introduce BRAINS-45K, a dataset of 44,756 brain MRI volumes from public sources, the largest public dataset available, and revisit a number of design choices for pretraining modern segmentation architectures by simplifying and optimizing state-of-the-art methods, and combining them with a novel augmentation strategy. The resulting AMAES framework is based on masked-image-modeling and intensity-based augmentation reversal and balances memory usage, runtime, and finetuning performance. Using the popular U-Net and the recent MedNeXt architecture as backbones, we evaluate the effect of pretraining on three challenging downstream tasks, covering single-sequence, low-resource settings, and out-of-domain generalization. The results highlight that pretraining on the proposed dataset with AMAES significantly improves segmentation performance in the majority of evaluated cases, and that it is beneficial to pretrain the model with augmentations, despite pretraing on a large-scale dataset. Code and model checkpoints for reproducing results, as well as the BRAINS-45K dataset are available at \url{https://github.com/asbjrnmunk/amaes}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00640v2</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Asbj{\o}rn Munk, Jakob Ambsdorf, Sebastian Llambias, Mads Nielsen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Non-negative VAE:the Generalized Gamma Belief Network</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03388</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03388v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The gamma belief network (GBN), often regarded as a deep topic model, has demonstrated its potential for uncovering multi-layer interpretable latent representations in text data. Its notable capability to acquire interpretable latent factors is partially attributed to sparse and non-negative gamma-distributed latent variables. However, the existing GBN and its variations are constrained by the linear generative model, thereby limiting their expressiveness and applicability. To address this limitation, we introduce the generalized gamma belief network (Generalized GBN) in this paper, which extends the original linear generative model to a more expressive non-linear generative model. Since the parameters of the Generalized GBN no longer possess an analytic conditional posterior, we further propose an upward-downward Weibull inference network to approximate the posterior distribution of the latent variables. The parameters of both the generative model and the inference network are jointly trained within the variational inference framework. Finally, we conduct comprehensive experiments on both expressivity and disentangled representation learning tasks to evaluate the performance of the Generalized GBN against state-of-the-art Gaussian variational autoencoders serving as baselines.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03388v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhibin Duan, Tiansheng Wen, Muyao Wang, Bo Chen, Mingyuan Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scene-wise Adaptive Network for Dynamic Cold-start Scenes Optimization in CTR Prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07278</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07278v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In the realm of modern mobile E-commerce, providing users with nearby commercial service recommendations through location-based online services has become increasingly vital. While machine learning approaches have shown promise in multi-scene recommendation, existing methodologies often struggle to address cold-start problems in unprecedented scenes: the increasing diversity of commercial choices, along with the short online lifespan of scenes, give rise to the complexity of effective recommendations in online and dynamic scenes. In this work, we propose Scene-wise Adaptive Network (SwAN), a novel approach that emphasizes high-performance cold-start online recommendations for new scenes. Our approach introduces several crucial capabilities, including scene similarity learning, user-specific scene transition cognition, scene-specific information construction for the new scene, and enhancing the diverged logical information between scenes. We demonstrate SwAN's potential to optimize dynamic multi-scene recommendation problems by effectively online handling cold-start recommendations for any newly arrived scenes. More encouragingly, SwAN has been successfully deployed in Meituan's online catering recommendation service, which serves millions of customers per day, and SwAN has achieved a 5.64% CTR index improvement relative to the baselines and a 5.19% increase in daily order volume proportion.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07278v2</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3640457.3688115</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Wenhao Li, Jie Zhou, Chuan Luo, Chao Tang, Kun Zhang, Shixiong Zhao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Model Merging in LLMs, MLLMs, and Beyond: Methods, Theories, Applications and Opportunities</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07666</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07666v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Model merging is an efficient empowerment technique in the machine learning community that does not require the collection of raw training data and does not require expensive computation. As model merging becomes increasingly prevalent across various fields, it is crucial to understand the available model merging techniques comprehensively. However, there is a significant gap in the literature regarding a systematic and thorough review of these techniques. This survey provides a comprehensive overview of model merging methods and theories, their applications in various domains and settings, and future research directions. Specifically, we first propose a new taxonomic approach that exhaustively discusses existing model merging methods. Secondly, we discuss the application of model merging techniques in large language models, multimodal large language models, and 10+ machine learning subfields, including continual learning, multi-task learning, few-shot learning, etc. Finally, we highlight the remaining challenges of model merging and discuss future research directions. A comprehensive list of papers about model merging is available at \url{https://github.com/EnnengYang/Awesome-Model-Merging-Methods-Theories-Applications}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07666v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Enneng Yang, Li Shen, Guibing Guo, Xingwei Wang, Xiaochun Cao, Jie Zhang, Dacheng Tao</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
