<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL</link>
    <description>cs.CL updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 04:00:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Saturday</day>
      <day>Sunday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>ReLiK: Retrieve and LinK, Fast and Accurate Entity Linking and Relation Extraction on an Academic Budget</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00103</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00103v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Entity Linking (EL) and Relation Extraction (RE) are fundamental tasks in Natural Language Processing, serving as critical components in a wide range of applications. In this paper, we propose ReLiK, a Retriever-Reader architecture for both EL and RE, where, given an input text, the Retriever module undertakes the identification of candidate entities or relations that could potentially appear within the text. Subsequently, the Reader module is tasked to discern the pertinent retrieved entities or relations and establish their alignment with the corresponding textual spans. Notably, we put forward an innovative input representation that incorporates the candidate entities or relations alongside the text, making it possible to link entities or extract relations in a single forward pass and to fully leverage pre-trained language models contextualization capabilities, in contrast with previous Retriever-Reader-based methods, which require a forward pass for each candidate. Our formulation of EL and RE achieves state-of-the-art performance in both in-domain and out-of-domain benchmarks while using academic budget training and with up to 40x inference speed compared to competitors. Finally, we show how our architecture can be used seamlessly for Information Extraction (cIE), i.e. EL + RE, and setting a new state of the art by employing a shared Reader that simultaneously extracts entities and relations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00103v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Riccardo Orlando, Pere-Lluis Huguet-Cabot, Edoardo Barba, Roberto Navigli</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gemma 2: Improving Open Language Models at a Practical Size</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00118</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00118v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this work, we introduce Gemma 2, a new addition to the Gemma family of lightweight, state-of-the-art open models, ranging in scale from 2 billion to 27 billion parameters. In this new version, we apply several known technical modifications to the Transformer architecture, such as interleaving local-global attentions (Beltagy et al., 2020a) and group-query attention (Ainslie et al., 2023). We also train the 2B and 9B models with knowledge distillation (Hinton et al., 2015) instead of next token prediction. The resulting models deliver the best performance for their size, and even offer competitive alternatives to models that are 2-3 times bigger. We release all our models to the community.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00118v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator> Gemma Team, Morgane Riviere, Shreya Pathak, Pier Giuseppe Sessa, Cassidy Hardin, Surya Bhupatiraju, L\'eonard Hussenot, Thomas Mesnard, Bobak Shahriari, Alexandre Ram\'e, Johan Ferret, Peter Liu, Pouya Tafti, Abe Friesen, Michelle Casbon, Sabela Ramos, Ravin Kumar, Charline Le Lan, Sammy Jerome, Anton Tsitsulin, Nino Vieillard, Piotr Stanczyk, Sertan Girgin, Nikola Momchev, Matt Hoffman, Shantanu Thakoor, Jean-Bastien Grill, Behnam Neyshabur, Alanna Walton, Aliaksei Severyn, Alicia Parrish, Aliya Ahmad, Allen Hutchison, Alvin Abdagic, Amanda Carl, Amy Shen, Andy Brock, Andy Coenen, Anthony Laforge, Antonia Paterson, Ben Bastian, Bilal Piot, Bo Wu, Brandon Royal, Charlie Chen, Chintu Kumar, Chris Perry, Chris Welty, Christopher A. Choquette-Choo, Danila Sinopalnikov, David Weinberger, Dimple Vijaykumar, Dominika Rogozi\'nska, Dustin Herbison, Elisa Bandy, Emma Wang, Eric Noland, Erica Moreira, Evan Senter, Evgenii Eltyshev, Francesco Visin, Gabriel Rasskin, Gary Wei, Glenn Cameron, Gus Martins, Hadi Hashemi, Hanna Klimczak-Pluci\'nska, Harleen Batra, Harsh Dhand, Ivan Nardini, Jacinda Mein, Jack Zhou, James Svensson, Jeff Stanway, Jetha Chan, Jin Zhou, Joana Carrasqueira, Joana Iljazi, Jocelyn Becker, Joe Fernandez, Joost van Amersfoort, Josh Gordon, Josh Lipschultz, Josh Newlan, Ju-yeong Ji, Kareem Mohamed, Kartikeya Badola, Kat Black, Katie Millican, Keelin McDonell, Kelvin Nguyen, Kiranbir Sodhia, Kish Greene, Lars Lowe Sjoesund, Lauren Usui, Laurent Sifre, Lena Heuermann, Leticia Lago, Lilly McNealus, Livio Baldini Soares, Logan Kilpatrick, Lucas Dixon, Luciano Martins, Machel Reid, Manvinder Singh, Mark Iverson, Martin G\"orner, Mat Velloso, Mateo Wirth, Matt Davidow, Matt Miller, Matthew Rahtz, Matthew Watson, Meg Risdal, Mehran Kazemi, Michael Moynihan, Ming Zhang, Minsuk Kahng, Minwoo Park, Mofi Rahman, Mohit Khatwani, Natalie Dao, Nenshad Bardoliwalla, Nesh Devanathan, Neta Dumai, Nilay Chauhan, Oscar Wahltinez, Pankil Botarda, Parker Barnes, Paul Barham, Paul Michel, Pengchong Jin, Petko Georgiev, Phil Culliton, Pradeep Kuppala, Ramona Comanescu, Ramona Merhej, Reena Jana, Reza Ardeshir Rokni, Rishabh Agarwal, Ryan Mullins, Samaneh Saadat, Sara Mc Carthy, Sarah Perrin, S\'ebastien Arnold, Sebastian Krause, Shengyang Dai, Shruti Garg, Shruti Sheth, Sue Ronstrom, Susan Chan, Timothy Jordan, Ting Yu, Tom Eccles, Tom Hennigan, Tomas Kocisky, Tulsee Doshi, Vihan Jain, Vikas Yadav, Vilobh Meshram, Vishal Dharmadhikari, Warren Barkley, Wei Wei, Wenming Ye, Woohyun Han, Woosuk Kwon, Xiang Xu, Zhe Shen, Zhitao Gong, Zichuan Wei, Victor Cotruta, Phoebe Kirk, Anand Rao, Minh Giang, Ludovic Peran, Tris Warkentin, Eli Collins, Joelle Barral, Zoubin Ghahramani, Raia Hadsell, D. Sculley, Jeanine Banks, Anca Dragan, Slav Petrov, Oriol Vinyals, Jeff Dean, Demis Hassabis, Koray Kavukcuoglu, Clement Farabet, Elena Buchatskaya, Sebastian Borgeaud, Noah Fiedel, Armand Joulin, Kathleen Kenealy, Robert Dadashi, Alek Andreev</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Course Shared Task on Evaluating LLM Output for Clinical Questions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00122</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00122v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper presents a shared task that we organized at the Foundations of Language Technology (FoLT) course in 2023/2024 at the Technical University of Darmstadt, which focuses on evaluating the output of Large Language Models (LLMs) in generating harmful answers to health-related clinical questions. We describe the task design considerations and report the feedback we received from the students. We expect the task and the findings reported in this paper to be relevant for instructors teaching natural language processing (NLP) and designing course assignments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00122v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yufang Hou, Thy Thy Tran, Doan Nam Long Vu, Yiwen Cao, Kai Li, Lukas Rohde, Iryna Gurevych</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correcting Negative Bias in Large Language Models through Negative Attention Score Alignment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00137</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00137v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: A binary decision task, like yes-no questions or answer verification, reflects a significant real-world scenario such as where users look for confirmation about the correctness of their decisions on specific issues. In this work, we observe that language models exhibit a negative bias in the binary decisions of complex reasoning tasks. Based on our observations and the rationale about attention-based model dynamics, we propose a negative attention score (NAS) to systematically and quantitatively formulate negative bias. Based on NAS, we identify attention heads that attend to negative tokens provided in the instructions as answer candidate of binary decisions, regardless of the question in the prompt, and validate their association with the negative bias. Additionally, we propose the negative attention score alignment (NASA) method, which is a parameter-efficient fine-tuning technique to address the extracted negatively biased attention heads. Experimental results from various domains of reasoning tasks and large model search space demonstrate that NASA significantly reduces the gap between precision and recall caused by negative bias while preserving their generalization abilities. Our codes are available at \url{https://github.com/ysw1021/NASA}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00137v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sangwon Yu, Jongyoon Song, Bongkyu Hwang, Hoyoung Kang, Sooah Cho, Junhwa Choi, Seongho Joe, Taehee Lee, Youngjune L. Gwon, Sungroh Yoon</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distributed In-Context Learning under Non-IID Among Clients</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00144</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00144v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Advancements in large language models (LLMs) have shown their effectiveness in multiple complicated natural language reasoning tasks. A key challenge remains in adapting these models efficiently to new or unfamiliar tasks. In-context learning (ICL) provides a promising solution for few-shot adaptation by retrieving a set of data points relevant to a query, called in-context examples (ICE), from a training dataset and providing them during the inference as context. Most existing studies utilize a centralized training dataset, yet many real-world datasets may be distributed among multiple clients, and remote data retrieval can be associated with costs. Especially when the client data are non-identical independent distributions (non-IID), retrieving from clients a proper set of ICEs needed for a test query presents critical challenges. In this paper, we first show that in this challenging setting, test queries will have different preferences among clients because of non-IIDness, and equal contribution often leads to suboptimal performance. We then introduce a novel approach to tackle the distributed non-IID ICL problem when a data usage budget is present. The principle is that each client's proper contribution (budget) should be designed according to the preference of each query for that client. Our approach uses a data-driven manner to allocate a budget for each client, tailored to each test query. Through extensive empirical studies on diverse datasets, our framework demonstrates superior performance relative to competing baselines.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00144v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Siqi Liang, Sumyeong Ahn, Jiayu Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Generation of Behavioral Test Cases For Natural Language Processing Using Clustering and Prompting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00161</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00161v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent work in behavioral testing for natural language processing (NLP) models, such as Checklist, is inspired by related paradigms in software engineering testing. They allow evaluation of general linguistic capabilities and domain understanding, hence can help evaluate conceptual soundness and identify model weaknesses. However, a major challenge is the creation of test cases. The current packages rely on semi-automated approach using manual development which requires domain expertise and can be time consuming. This paper introduces an automated approach to develop test cases by exploiting the power of large language models and statistical techniques. It clusters the text representations to carefully construct meaningful groups and then apply prompting techniques to automatically generate Minimal Functionality Tests (MFT). The well-known Amazon Reviews corpus is used to demonstrate our approach. We analyze the behavioral test profiles across four different classification algorithms and discuss the limitations and strengths of those models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00161v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.ET</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ying Li, Rahul Singh, Tarun Joshi, Agus Sudjianto</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sentence-wise Speech Summarization: Task, Datasets, and End-to-End Modeling with LM Knowledge Distillation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00205</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00205v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper introduces a novel approach called sentence-wise speech summarization (Sen-SSum), which generates text summaries from a spoken document in a sentence-by-sentence manner. Sen-SSum combines the real-time processing of automatic speech recognition (ASR) with the conciseness of speech summarization. To explore this approach, we present two datasets for Sen-SSum: Mega-SSum and CSJ-SSum. Using these datasets, our study evaluates two types of Transformer-based models: 1) cascade models that combine ASR and strong text summarization models, and 2) end-to-end (E2E) models that directly convert speech into a text summary. While E2E models are appealing to develop compute-efficient models, they perform worse than cascade models. Therefore, we propose knowledge distillation for E2E models using pseudo-summaries generated by the cascade models. Our experiments show that this proposed knowledge distillation effectively improves the performance of the E2E model on both datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00205v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kohei Matsuura, Takanori Ashihara, Takafumi Moriya, Masato Mimura, Takatomo Kano, Atsunori Ogawa, Marc Delcroix</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Structured State Space Models via Grouped FIR Filtering and Attention Sink Mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00244</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00244v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Structured State Space Models (SSMs) have emerged as compelling alternatives to Transformer architectures, offering linear-time complexity and superior performance in various sequence modeling tasks. Despite their advantages, SSMs like the original Mamba-2 face training difficulties due to the sensitivities introduced by the extended series of recurrent matrix multiplications. In this paper, we propose an advanced architecture that mitigates these challenges by decomposing A-multiplications into multiple groups and optimizing positional encoding through Grouped Finite Impulse Response (FIR) filtering. This new structure, denoted as Grouped FIR-enhanced SSM (GFSSM), employs semiseparable matrices for efficient computation. Furthermore, inspired by the "attention sink" phenomenon identified in streaming language models, we incorporate a similar mechanism to enhance the stability and performance of our model over extended sequences. Our approach further bridges the gap between SSMs and Transformer architectures, offering a viable path forward for scalable and high-performing sequence modeling.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00244v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tian Meng, Yang Tao, Wuliang Yin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clover-2: Accurate Inference for Regressive Lightweight Speculative Decoding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00264</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00264v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) frequently suffer from inefficiencies, largely attributable to the discord between the requirements of auto-regressive decoding and the architecture of contemporary GPUs. Recently, regressive lightweight speculative decoding has garnered attention for its notable efficiency improvements in text generation tasks. This approach utilizes a lightweight regressive draft model, like a Recurrent Neural Network (RNN) or a single transformer decoder layer, leveraging sequential information to iteratively predict potential tokens. Specifically, RNN draft models are computationally economical but tend to deliver lower accuracy, while attention decoder layer models exhibit the opposite traits. This paper presents Clover-2, an advanced iteration of Clover, an RNN-based draft model designed to achieve comparable accuracy to that of attention decoder layer models while maintaining minimal computational overhead. Clover-2 enhances the model architecture and incorporates knowledge distillation to increase Clover's accuracy and improve overall efficiency. We conducted experiments using the open-source Vicuna 7B and LLaMA3-Instruct 8B models. The results demonstrate that Clover-2 surpasses existing methods across various model architectures, showcasing its efficacy and robustness.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00264v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bin Xiao, Lujun Gui, Lei Su, Weipeng Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>QUITO: Accelerating Long-Context Reasoning through Query-Guided Context Compression</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00274</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00274v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In-context learning (ICL) capabilities are foundational to the success of large language models (LLMs). Recently, context compression has attracted growing interest since it can largely reduce reasoning complexities and computation costs of LLMs. In this paper, we introduce a novel Query-gUIded aTtention cOmpression (QUITO) method, which leverages attention of the question over the contexts to filter useless information. Specifically, we take a trigger token to calculate the attention distribution of the context in response to the question. Based on the distribution, we propose three different filtering methods to satisfy the budget constraints of the context length. We evaluate the QUITO using two widely-used datasets, namely, NaturalQuestions and ASQA. Experimental results demonstrate that QUITO significantly outperforms established baselines across various datasets and downstream LLMs, underscoring its effectiveness. Our code is available at https://github.com/Wenshansilvia/attention_compressor.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00274v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenshan Wang, Yihang Wang, Yixing Fan, Huaming Liao, Jiafeng Guo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Navigating Text-to-Image Generative Bias across Indic Languages</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00283</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00283v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This research investigates biases in text-to-image (TTI) models for the Indic languages widely spoken across India. It evaluates and compares the generative performance and cultural relevance of leading TTI models in these languages against their performance in English. Using the proposed IndicTTI benchmark, we comprehensively assess the performance of 30 Indic languages with two open-source diffusion models and two commercial generation APIs. The primary objective of this benchmark is to evaluate the support for Indic languages in these models and identify areas needing improvement. Given the linguistic diversity of 30 languages spoken by over 1.4 billion people, this benchmark aims to provide a detailed and insightful analysis of TTI models' effectiveness within the Indic linguistic landscape. The data and code for the IndicTTI benchmark can be accessed at https://iab-rubric.org/resources/other-databases/indictti.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00283v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Surbhi Mittal, Arnav Sudan, Mayank Vatsa, Richa Singh, Tamar Glaser, Tal Hassner</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bailing-TTS: Chinese Dialectal Speech Synthesis Towards Human-like Spontaneous Representation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00284</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00284v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large-scale text-to-speech (TTS) models have made significant progress recently.However, they still fall short in the generation of Chinese dialectal speech. Toaddress this, we propose Bailing-TTS, a family of large-scale TTS models capable of generating high-quality Chinese dialectal speech. Bailing-TTS serves as a foundation model for Chinese dialectal speech generation. First, continual semi-supervised learning is proposed to facilitate the alignment of text tokens and speech tokens. Second, the Chinese dialectal representation learning is developed using a specific transformer architecture and multi-stage training processes. With the proposed design of novel network architecture and corresponding strategy, Bailing-TTS is able to generate Chinese dialectal speech from text effectively and efficiently. Experiments demonstrate that Bailing-TTS generates Chinese dialectal speech towards human-like spontaneous representation. Readers are encouraged to listen to demos at \url{https://c9412600.github.io/bltts_tech_report/index.html}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00284v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xinhan Di, Zihao Chen, Yunming Liang, Junjie Zheng, Yihua Wang, Chaofan Ding</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DeliLaw: A Chinese Legal Counselling System Based on a Large Language Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00357</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00357v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Traditional legal retrieval systems designed to retrieve legal documents, statutes, precedents, and other legal information are unable to give satisfactory answers due to lack of semantic understanding of specific questions. Large Language Models (LLMs) have achieved excellent results in a variety of natural language processing tasks, which inspired us that we train a LLM in the legal domain to help legal retrieval. However, in the Chinese legal domain, due to the complexity of legal questions and the rigour of legal articles, there is no legal large model with satisfactory practical application yet. In this paper, we present DeliLaw, a Chinese legal counselling system based on a large language model. DeliLaw integrates a legal retrieval module and a case retrieval module to overcome the model hallucination. Users can consult professional legal questions, search for legal articles and relevant judgement cases, etc. on the DeliLaw system in a dialogue mode. In addition, DeliLaw supports the use of English for counseling. we provide the address of the system: https://data.delilegal.com/lawQuestion.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00357v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3627673.3679219</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Nan Xie, Yuelin Bai, Hengyuan Gao, Feiteng Fang, Qixuan Zhao, Zhijian Li, Ziqiang Xue, Liang Zhu, Shiwen Ni, Min Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-Context Example Selection via Similarity Search Improves Low-Resource Machine Translation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00397</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00397v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The ability of generative large language models (LLMs) to perform in-context learning has given rise to a large body of research into how best to prompt models for various natural language processing tasks. In this paper, we focus on machine translation (MT), a task that has been shown to benefit from in-context translation examples. However no systematic studies have been published on how best to select examples, and mixed results have been reported on the usefulness of similarity-based selection over random selection. We provide a study covering multiple LLMs and multiple in-context example retrieval strategies, comparing multilingual sentence embeddings. We cover several language directions, representing different levels of language resourcedness (English into French, German, Swahili and Wolof). Contrarily to previously published results, we find that sentence embedding similarity can improve MT, especially for low-resource language directions, and discuss the balance between selection pool diversity and quality. We also highlight potential problems with the evaluation of LLM-based MT and suggest a more appropriate evaluation protocol, adapting the COMET metric to the evaluation of LLMs. Code and outputs are freely available at https://github.com/ArmelRandy/ICL-MT.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00397v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Armel Zebaze, Beno\^it Sagot, Rachel Bawden</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GalleryGPT: Analyzing Paintings with Large Multimodal Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00491</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00491v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Artwork analysis is important and fundamental skill for art appreciation, which could enrich personal aesthetic sensibility and facilitate the critical thinking ability. Understanding artworks is challenging due to its subjective nature, diverse interpretations, and complex visual elements, requiring expertise in art history, cultural background, and aesthetic theory. However, limited by the data collection and model ability, previous works for automatically analyzing artworks mainly focus on classification, retrieval, and other simple tasks, which is far from the goal of AI. To facilitate the research progress, in this paper, we step further to compose comprehensive analysis inspired by the remarkable perception and generation ability of large multimodal models. Specifically, we first propose a task of composing paragraph analysis for artworks, i.e., painting in this paper, only focusing on visual characteristics to formulate more comprehensive understanding of artworks. To support the research on formal analysis, we collect a large dataset PaintingForm, with about 19k painting images and 50k analysis paragraphs. We further introduce a superior large multimodal model for painting analysis composing, dubbed GalleryGPT, which is slightly modified and fine-tuned based on LLaVA architecture leveraging our collected data. We conduct formal analysis generation and zero-shot experiments across several datasets to assess the capacity of our model. The results show remarkable performance improvements comparing with powerful baseline LMMs, demonstrating its superb ability of art analysis and generalization. \textcolor{blue}{The codes and model are available at: https://github.com/steven640pixel/GalleryGPT.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00491v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3664647.3681656</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Yi Bin, Wenhao Shi, Yujuan Ding, Zhiqiang Hu, Zheng Wang, Yang Yang, See-Kiong Ng, Heng Tao Shen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intermittent Semi-working Mask: A New Masking Paradigm for LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00539</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00539v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Multi-turn dialogues are a key interaction method between humans and Large Language Models (LLMs), as conversations extend over multiple rounds, keeping LLMs' high generation quality and low latency is a challenge. Mainstream LLMs can be grouped into two categories based on masking strategy: causal LLM and prefix LLM. Several works have demonstrated that prefix LLMs tend to outperform causal ones in scenarios that heavily depend on historical context such as multi-turn dialogues or in-context learning, thanks to their bidirectional attention on prefix sequences. However, prefix LLMs have an inherent inefficient training problem in multi-turn dialogue datasets. In addition, the attention mechanism of prefix LLM makes it unable to reuse Key-Value Cache (KV Cache) across dialogue rounds to reduce generation latency. In this paper, we propose a novel masking scheme called Intermittent Semi-working Mask (ISM) to address these problems. Specifically, we apply alternate bidirectional and unidirectional attention on queries and answers in the dialogue history. In this way, ISM is able to maintain the high quality of prefix LLM and low generation latency of causal LLM, simultaneously. Extensive experiments illustrate that our ISM achieves significant performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00539v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mingcong Lu, Jiangcai Zhu, Wang Hao, Zheng Li, Shusheng Zhang, Kailai Shao, Chao Chen, Nan Li, Feng Wang, Xin Lu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non Verbis, Sed Rebus: Large Language Models are Weak Solvers of Italian Rebuses</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00584</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00584v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Rebuses are puzzles requiring constrained multi-step reasoning to identify a hidden phrase from a set of images and letters. In this work, we introduce a large collection of verbalized rebuses for the Italian language and use it to assess the rebus-solving capabilities of state-of-the-art large language models. While general-purpose systems such as LLaMA-3 and GPT-4o perform poorly on this task, ad-hoc fine-tuning seems to improve models' performance. However, we find that performance gains from training are largely motivated by memorization. Our results suggest that rebus solving remains a challenging test bed to evaluate large language models' linguistic proficiency and sequential instruction-following skills.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00584v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gabriele Sarti, Tommaso Caselli, Malvina Nissim, Arianna Bisazza</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Closing the gap between open-source and commercial large language models for medical evidence summarization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00588</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00588v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) hold great promise in summarizing medical evidence. Most recent studies focus on the application of proprietary LLMs. Using proprietary LLMs introduces multiple risk factors, including a lack of transparency and vendor dependency. While open-source LLMs allow better transparency and customization, their performance falls short compared to proprietary ones. In this study, we investigated to what extent fine-tuning open-source LLMs can further improve their performance in summarizing medical evidence. Utilizing a benchmark dataset, MedReview, consisting of 8,161 pairs of systematic reviews and summaries, we fine-tuned three broadly-used, open-sourced LLMs, namely PRIMERA, LongT5, and Llama-2. Overall, the fine-tuned LLMs obtained an increase of 9.89 in ROUGE-L (95% confidence interval: 8.94-10.81), 13.21 in METEOR score (95% confidence interval: 12.05-14.37), and 15.82 in CHRF score (95% confidence interval: 13.89-16.44). The performance of fine-tuned LongT5 is close to GPT-3.5 with zero-shot settings. Furthermore, smaller fine-tuned models sometimes even demonstrated superior performance compared to larger zero-shot models. The above trends of improvement were also manifested in both human and GPT4-simulated evaluations. Our results can be applied to guide model selection for tasks demanding particular domain knowledge, such as medical evidence summarization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00588v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gongbo Zhang, Qiao Jin, Yiliang Zhou, Song Wang, Betina R. Idnay, Yiming Luo, Elizabeth Park, Jordan G. Nestor, Matthew E. Spotnitz, Ali Soroush, Thomas Campion, Zhiyong Lu, Chunhua Weng, Yifan Peng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Downstream bias mitigation is all you need</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00612</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00612v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The advent of transformer-based architectures and large language models (LLMs) have significantly advanced the performance of natural language processing (NLP) models. Since these LLMs are trained on huge corpuses of data from the web and other sources, there has been a major concern about harmful prejudices that may potentially be transferred from the data. In many applications, these pre-trained LLMs are fine-tuned on task specific datasets, which can further contribute to biases. This paper studies the extent of biases absorbed by LLMs during pre-training as well as task-specific behaviour after fine-tuning. We found that controlled interventions on pre-trained LLMs, prior to fine-tuning, have minimal effect on lowering biases in classifiers. However, the biases present in domain-specific datasets play a much bigger role, and hence mitigating them at this stage has a bigger impact. While pre-training does matter, but after the model has been pre-trained, even slight changes to co-occurrence rates in the fine-tuning dataset has a significant effect on the bias of the model.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00612v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Arkadeep Baksi, Rahul Singh, Tarun Joshi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aligning Multiple Knowledge Graphs in a Single Pass</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00662</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00662v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Entity alignment (EA) is to identify equivalent entities across different knowledge graphs (KGs), which can help fuse these KGs into a more comprehensive one. Previous EA methods mainly focus on aligning a pair of KGs, and to the best of our knowledge, no existing EA method considers aligning multiple (more than two) KGs. To fill this research gap, in this work, we study a novel problem of aligning multiple KGs and propose an effective framework named MultiEA to solve the problem. First, we embed the entities of all the candidate KGs into a common feature space by a shared KG encoder. Then, we explore three alignment strategies to minimize the distances among pre-aligned entities. In particular, we propose an innovative inference enhancement technique to improve the alignment performance by incorporating high-order similarities. Finally, to verify the effectiveness of MultiEA, we construct two new real-world benchmark datasets and conduct extensive experiments on them. The results show that our MultiEA can effectively and efficiently align multiple KGs in a single pass.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00662v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yaming Yang, Zhe Wang, Ziyu Guan, Wei Zhao, Weigang Lu, Xinyan Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Entailment Judgements in Cross-Lingual Summarisation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00675</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00675v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Synthetically created Cross-Lingual Summarisation (CLS) datasets are prone to include document-summary pairs where the reference summary is unfaithful to the corresponding document as it contains content not supported by the document (i.e., hallucinated content). This low data quality misleads model learning and obscures evaluation results. Automatic ways to assess hallucinations and improve training have been proposed for monolingual summarisation, predominantly in English. For CLS, we propose to use off-the-shelf cross-lingual Natural Language Inference (X-NLI) to evaluate faithfulness of reference and model generated summaries. Then, we study training approaches that are aware of faithfulness issues in the training data and propose an approach that uses unlikelihood loss to teach a model about unfaithful summary sequences. Our results show that it is possible to train CLS models that yield more faithful summaries while maintaining comparable or better informativess.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00675v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Huajian Zhang, Laura Perez-Beltrachini</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the Variety of a Concept Space Using an Unbiased Estimate of Rao's Quadratic Index</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00684</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00684v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Past research relates design creativity to 'divergent thinking,' i.e., how well the concept space is explored during the early phase of design. Researchers have argued that generating several concepts would increase the chances of producing better design solutions. 'Variety' is one of the parameters by which one can quantify the breadth of a concept space explored by the designers. It is useful to assess variety at the conceptual design stage because, at this stage, designers have the freedom to explore different solution principles so as to satisfy a design problem with substantially novel concepts. This article elaborates on and critically examines the existing variety metrics from the engineering design literature, discussing their limitations. A new distance-based variety metric is proposed, along with a prescriptive framework to support the assessment process. This framework uses the SAPPhIRE model of causality as a knowledge representation scheme to measure the real-valued distance between two design concepts. The proposed framework is implemented in a software tool called 'VariAnT.' Furthermore, the tool's application is demonstrated through an illustrative example.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00684v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Anubhab Majumder, Ujjwal Pal, Amaresh Chakrabarti</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Text Embeddings for Smaller Language Models Using Contrastive Fine-tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00690</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00690v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: While Large Language Models show remarkable performance in natural language understanding, their resource-intensive nature makes them less accessible. In contrast, smaller language models such as MiniCPM offer more sustainable scalability, but often underperform without specialized optimization. In this paper, we explore the enhancement of smaller language models through the improvement of their text embeddings. We select three language models, MiniCPM, Phi-2, and Gemma, to conduct contrastive fine-tuning on the NLI dataset. Our results demonstrate that this fine-tuning method enhances the quality of text embeddings for all three models across various benchmarks, with MiniCPM showing the most significant improvements of an average 56.33\% performance gain. The contrastive fine-tuning code is publicly available at https://github.com/trapoom555/Language-Model-STS-CFT.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00690v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Trapoom Ukarapol, Zhicheng Lee, Amy Xin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Retrieval-Augmented Generation in Medicine with Iterative Follow-up Questions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00727</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00727v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The emergent abilities of large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated great potential in solving medical questions. They can possess considerable medical knowledge, but may still hallucinate and are inflexible in the knowledge updates. While Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) has been proposed to enhance the medical question-answering capabilities of LLMs with external knowledge bases, it may still fail in complex cases where multiple rounds of information-seeking are required. To address such an issue, we propose iterative RAG for medicine (i-MedRAG), where LLMs can iteratively ask follow-up queries based on previous information-seeking attempts. In each iteration of i-MedRAG, the follow-up queries will be answered by a vanilla RAG system and they will be further used to guide the query generation in the next iteration. Our experiments show the improved performance of various LLMs brought by i-MedRAG compared with vanilla RAG on complex questions from clinical vignettes in the United States Medical Licensing Examination (USMLE), as well as various knowledge tests in the Massive Multitask Language Understanding (MMLU) dataset. Notably, our zero-shot i-MedRAG outperforms all existing prompt engineering and fine-tuning methods on GPT-3.5, achieving an accuracy of 69.68\% on the MedQA dataset. In addition, we characterize the scaling properties of i-MedRAG with different iterations of follow-up queries and different numbers of queries per iteration. Our case studies show that i-MedRAG can flexibly ask follow-up queries to form reasoning chains, providing an in-depth analysis of medical questions. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first-of-its-kind study on incorporating follow-up queries into medical RAG.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00727v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Guangzhi Xiong, Qiao Jin, Xiao Wang, Minjia Zhang, Zhiyong Lu, Aidong Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CERT-ED: Certifiably Robust Text Classification for Edit Distance</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00728</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00728v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: With the growing integration of AI in daily life, ensuring the robustness of systems to inference-time attacks is crucial. Among the approaches for certifying robustness to such adversarial examples, randomized smoothing has emerged as highly promising due to its nature as a wrapper around arbitrary black-box models. Previous work on randomized smoothing in natural language processing has primarily focused on specific subsets of edit distance operations, such as synonym substitution or word insertion, without exploring the certification of all edit operations. In this paper, we adapt Randomized Deletion (Huang et al., 2023) and propose, CERTified Edit Distance defense (CERT-ED) for natural language classification. Through comprehensive experiments, we demonstrate that CERT-ED outperforms the existing Hamming distance method RanMASK (Zeng et al., 2023) in 4 out of 5 datasets in terms of both accuracy and the cardinality of the certificate. By covering various threat models, including 5 direct and 5 transfer attacks, our method improves empirical robustness in 38 out of 50 settings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00728v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhuoqun Huang, Neil G Marchant, Olga Ohrimenko, Benjamin I. P. Rubinstein</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AgentGen: Enhancing Planning Abilities for Large Language Model based Agent via Environment and Task Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00764</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00764v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Model (LLM) based agents have garnered significant attention and are becoming increasingly popular. Furthermore, planning ability is a crucial component of an LLM-based agent, involving interaction with the environment and executing actions to complete a planning task, which generally entails achieving a desired goal from an initial state. This paper investigates enhancing the planning abilities of LLMs through instruction tuning, referred to as agent training. Recent studies have demonstrated that utilizing expert-level trajectory for instruction-tuning LLMs effectively enhances their planning capabilities. However, existing work primarily focuses on synthesizing trajectories from manually designed planning tasks and environments. The labor-intensive nature of creating these environments and tasks impedes the generation of sufficiently varied and extensive trajectories. To address this limitation, this paper explores the automated synthesis of diverse environments and a gradual range of planning tasks, from easy to difficult. We introduce a framework, AgentGen, that leverages LLMs first to generate environments and subsequently generate planning tasks conditioned on these environments. Specifically, to improve environmental diversity, we propose using an inspiration corpus composed of various domain-specific text segments as the context for synthesizing environments. Moreover, to increase the difficulty diversity of generated planning tasks, we propose a bidirectional evolution method, Bi-Evol, that evolves planning tasks from easier and harder directions to synthesize a task set with a smoother difficulty curve. The evaluation results derived from AgentBoard show that AgentGen greatly improves LLMs' planning ability, e.g., the AgentGen instruction-tuned Llama-3 8B surpasses GPT-3.5 in overall performance. Moreover, in certain tasks, it even outperforms GPT-4.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00764v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mengkang Hu, Pu Zhao, Can Xu, Qingfeng Sun, Jianguang Lou, Qingwei Lin, Ping Luo, Saravan Rajmohan, Dongmei Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Handling Numeric Expressions in Automatic Speech Recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00004</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00004v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This paper addresses the problem of correctly formatting numeric expressions in automatic speech recognition (ASR) transcripts. This is challenging since the expected transcript format depends on the context, e.g., 1945 (year) vs. 19:45 (timestamp). We compare cascaded and end-to-end approaches to recognize and format numeric expression, such as years, timestamps, currency amounts, and quantities. For the end-to-end approach we employed a data generation strategy using a large language model (LLM) together with a text to speech (TTS) model to generate adaptation data. The results on our test dataset show that while approaches based on LLMs perform well on recognizing formatted numeric expressions, adapted end-to-end models offer competitive performance with the advantage of lower latency and inference cost.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00004v1</guid>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Christian Huber, Alexander Waibel</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Framework for Curating Speech Datasets and Evaluating ASR Systems: A Case Study for Polish</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00005</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00005v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Speech datasets available in the public domain are often underutilized because of challenges in discoverability and interoperability. A comprehensive framework has been designed to survey, catalog, and curate available speech datasets, which allows replicable evaluation of automatic speech recognition (ASR) systems. A case study focused on the Polish language was conducted; the framework was applied to curate more than 24 datasets and evaluate 25 combinations of ASR systems and models. This research constitutes the most extensive comparison to date of both commercial and free ASR systems for the Polish language. It draws insights from 600 system-model-test set evaluations, marking a significant advancement in both scale and comprehensiveness. The results of surveys and performance comparisons are available as interactive dashboards (https://huggingface.co/spaces/amu-cai/pl-asr-leaderboard) along with curated datasets (https://huggingface.co/datasets/amu-cai/pl-asr-bigos-v2, https://huggingface.co/datasets/pelcra/pl-asr-pelcra-for-bigos) and the open challenge call (https://poleval.pl/tasks/task3). Tools used for evaluation are open-sourced (https://github.com/goodmike31/pl-asr-bigos-tools), facilitating replication and adaptation for other languages, as well as continuous expansion with new datasets and systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00005v1</guid>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Micha{\l} Junczyk</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards a Universal Method for Meaningful Signal Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00016</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00016v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: It is known that human speech and certain animal vocalizations can convey meaningful content because we can decipher the content that a given utterance does convey. This paper explores an alternative approach to determining whether a signal is meaningful, one that analyzes only the signal itself and is independent of what the conveyed meaning might be. We devise a method that takes a waveform as input and outputs a score indicating its degree of `meaningfulness`. We cluster contiguous portions of the input to minimize the total description length, and then take the length of the code of the assigned cluster labels as meaningfulness score. We evaluate our method empirically, against several baselines, and show that it is the only one to give a high score to human speech in various languages and with various speakers, a moderate score to animal vocalizations from birds and orcas, and a low score to ambient noise from various sources.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00016v1</guid>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Louis Mahon</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measuring Progress in Dictionary Learning for Language Model Interpretability with Board Game Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00113</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00113v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: What latent features are encoded in language model (LM) representations? Recent work on training sparse autoencoders (SAEs) to disentangle interpretable features in LM representations has shown significant promise. However, evaluating the quality of these SAEs is difficult because we lack a ground-truth collection of interpretable features that we expect good SAEs to recover. We thus propose to measure progress in interpretable dictionary learning by working in the setting of LMs trained on chess and Othello transcripts. These settings carry natural collections of interpretable features -- for example, "there is a knight on F3" -- which we leverage into $\textit{supervised}$ metrics for SAE quality. To guide progress in interpretable dictionary learning, we introduce a new SAE training technique, $\textit{p-annealing}$, which improves performance on prior unsupervised metrics as well as our new metrics.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00113v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Adam Karvonen, Benjamin Wright, Can Rager, Rico Angell, Jannik Brinkmann, Logan Smith, Claudio Mayrink Verdun, David Bau, Samuel Marks</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Taxonomy of Stereotype Content in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00162</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00162v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This study introduces a taxonomy of stereotype content in contemporary large language models (LLMs). We prompt ChatGPT 3.5, Llama 3, and Mixtral 8x7B, three powerful and widely used LLMs, for the characteristics associated with 87 social categories (e.g., gender, race, occupations). We identify 14 stereotype dimensions (e.g., Morality, Ability, Health, Beliefs, Emotions), accounting for ~90% of LLM stereotype associations. Warmth and Competence facets were the most frequent content, but all other dimensions were significantly prevalent. Stereotypes were more positive in LLMs (vs. humans), but there was significant variability across categories and dimensions. Finally, the taxonomy predicted the LLMs' internal evaluations of social categories (e.g., how positively/negatively the categories were represented), supporting the relevance of a multidimensional taxonomy for characterizing LLM stereotypes. Our findings suggest that high-dimensional human stereotypes are reflected in LLMs and must be considered in AI auditing and debiasing to minimize unidentified harms from reliance in low-dimensional views of bias in LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00162v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gandalf Nicolas, Aylin Caliskan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automated Software Vulnerability Static Code Analysis Using Generative Pre-Trained Transformer Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00197</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00197v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Generative Pre-Trained Transformer models have been shown to be surprisingly effective at a variety of natural language processing tasks -- including generating computer code. We evaluate the effectiveness of open source GPT models for the task of automatic identification of the presence of vulnerable code syntax (specifically targeting C and C++ source code). This task is evaluated on a selection of 36 source code examples from the NIST SARD dataset, which are specifically curated to not contain natural English that indicates the presence, or lack thereof, of a particular vulnerability. The NIST SARD source code dataset contains identified vulnerable lines of source code that are examples of one out of the 839 distinct Common Weakness Enumerations (CWE), allowing for exact quantification of the GPT output classification error rate. A total of 5 GPT models are evaluated, using 10 different inference temperatures and 100 repetitions at each setting, resulting in 5,000 GPT queries per vulnerable source code analyzed. Ultimately, we find that the GPT models that we evaluated are not suitable for fully automated vulnerability scanning because the false positive and false negative rates are too high to likely be useful in practice. However, we do find that the GPT models perform surprisingly well at automated vulnerability detection for some of the test cases, in particular surpassing random sampling, and being able to identify the exact lines of code that are vulnerable albeit at a low success rate. The best performing GPT model result found was Llama-2-70b-chat-hf with inference temperature of 0.1 applied to NIST SARD test case 149165 (which is an example of a buffer overflow vulnerability), which had a binary classification recall score of 1.0 and a precision of 1.0 for correctly and uniquely identifying the vulnerable line of code and the correct CWE number.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00197v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Elijah Pelofske, Vincent Urias, Lorie M. Liebrock</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OmniParser for Pure Vision Based GUI Agent</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00203</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00203v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The recent success of large vision language models shows great potential in driving the agent system operating on user interfaces. However, we argue that the power multimodal models like GPT-4V as a general agent on multiple operating systems across different applications is largely underestimated due to the lack of a robust screen parsing technique capable of: 1) reliably identifying interactable icons within the user interface, and 2) understanding the semantics of various elements in a screenshot and accurately associate the intended action with the corresponding region on the screen. To fill these gaps, we introduce \textsc{OmniParser}, a comprehensive method for parsing user interface screenshots into structured elements, which significantly enhances the ability of GPT-4V to generate actions that can be accurately grounded in the corresponding regions of the interface. We first curated an interactable icon detection dataset using popular webpages and an icon description dataset. These datasets were utilized to fine-tune specialized models: a detection model to parse interactable regions on the screen and a caption model to extract the functional semantics of the detected elements. \textsc{OmniParser} significantly improves GPT-4V's performance on ScreenSpot benchmark. And on Mind2Web and AITW benchmark, \textsc{OmniParser} with screenshot only input outperforms the GPT-4V baselines requiring additional information outside of screenshot.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00203v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yadong Lu, Jianwei Yang, Yelong Shen, Ahmed Awadallah</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost in Translation: Latent Concept Misalignment in Text-to-Image Diffusion Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00230</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00230v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Advancements in text-to-image diffusion models have broadened extensive downstream practical applications, but such models often encounter misalignment issues between text and image. Taking the generation of a combination of two disentangled concepts as an example, say given the prompt "a tea cup of iced coke", existing models usually generate a glass cup of iced coke because the iced coke usually co-occurs with the glass cup instead of the tea one during model training. The root of such misalignment is attributed to the confusion in the latent semantic space of text-to-image diffusion models, and hence we refer to the "a tea cup of iced coke" phenomenon as Latent Concept Misalignment (LC-Mis). We leverage large language models (LLMs) to thoroughly investigate the scope of LC-Mis, and develop an automated pipeline for aligning the latent semantics of diffusion models to text prompts. Empirical assessments confirm the effectiveness of our approach, substantially reducing LC-Mis errors and enhancing the robustness and versatility of text-to-image diffusion models. Our code and dataset have been available online for reference.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00230v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Juntu Zhao, Junyu Deng, Yixin Ye, Chongxuan Li, Zhijie Deng, Dequan Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ABC Align: Large Language Model Alignment for Safety &amp; Accuracy</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00307</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00307v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Alignment of Large Language Models (LLMs) remains an unsolved problem. Human preferences are highly distributed and can be captured at multiple levels of abstraction, from the individual to diverse populations. Organisational preferences, represented by standards and principles, are defined to mitigate reputational risk or meet legislative obligations. In this paper, we present ABC Align, a novel alignment methodology for LLMs that enables integration of the standards and preferences of a large media organisation into the LLM itself. We combine a set of data and methods that build on recent breakthroughs in synthetic data generation, preference optimisation, and post-training model quantisation. Our unified approach mitigates bias and improves accuracy, while preserving reasoning capability, as measured against standard benchmarks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00307v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gareth Seneque, Lap-Hang Ho, Ariel Kuperman, Nafise Erfanian Saeedi, Jeffrey Molendijk</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Monetisation of Toxicity: Analysing YouTube Content Creators and Controversy-Driven Engagement</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00534</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00534v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: YouTube is a major social media platform that plays a significant role in digital culture, with content creators at its core. These creators often engage in controversial behaviour to drive engagement, which can foster toxicity. This paper presents a quantitative analysis of controversial content on YouTube, focusing on the relationship between controversy, toxicity, and monetisation. We introduce a curated dataset comprising 20 controversial YouTube channels extracted from Reddit discussions, including 16,349 videos and more than 105 million comments. We identify and categorise monetisation cues from video descriptions into various models, including affiliate marketing and direct selling, using lists of URLs and keywords. Additionally, we train a machine learning model to measure the toxicity of comments in these videos. Our findings reveal that while toxic comments correlate with higher engagement, they negatively impact monetisation, indicating that controversy-driven interaction does not necessarily lead to financial gain. We also observed significant variation in monetisation strategies, with some creators showing extensive monetisation despite high toxicity levels. Our study introduces a curated dataset, lists of URLs and keywords to categorise monetisation, a machine learning model to measure toxicity, and is a significant step towards understanding the complex relationship between controversy, engagement, and monetisation on YouTube. The lists used for detecting and categorising monetisation cues are available on https://github.com/thalesbertaglia/toxmon.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00534v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3677117.3685005</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Thales Bertaglia, Catalina Goanta, Adriana Iamnitchi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mitigating Multilingual Hallucination in Large Vision-Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00550</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00550v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: While Large Vision-Language Models (LVLMs) have exhibited remarkable capabilities across a wide range of tasks, they suffer from hallucination problems, where models generate plausible yet incorrect answers given the input image-query pair. This hallucination phenomenon is even more severe when querying the image in non-English languages, while existing methods for mitigating hallucinations in LVLMs only consider the English scenarios. In this paper, we make the first attempt to mitigate this important multilingual hallucination in LVLMs. With thorough experiment analysis, we found that multilingual hallucination in LVLMs is a systemic problem that could arise from deficiencies in multilingual capabilities or inadequate multimodal abilities. To this end, we propose a two-stage Multilingual Hallucination Removal (MHR) framework for LVLMs, aiming to improve resistance to hallucination for both high-resource and low-resource languages. Instead of relying on the intricate manual annotations of multilingual resources, we fully leverage the inherent capabilities of the LVLM and propose a novel cross-lingual alignment method, which generates multiple responses for each image-query input and then identifies the hallucination-aware pairs for each language. These data pairs are finally used for direct preference optimization to prompt the LVLMs to favor non-hallucinating responses. Experimental results show that our MHR achieves a substantial reduction in hallucination generation for LVLMs. Notably, on our extended multilingual POPE benchmark, our framework delivers an average increase of 19.0% in accuracy across 13 different languages. Our code and model weights are available at https://github.com/ssmisya/MHR</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00550v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoye Qu, Mingyang Song, Wei Wei, Jianfeng Dong, Yu Cheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alleviating Hallucination in Large Vision-Language Models with Active Retrieval Augmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00555</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00555v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Despite the remarkable ability of large vision-language models (LVLMs) in image comprehension, these models frequently generate plausible yet factually incorrect responses, a phenomenon known as hallucination.Recently, in large language models (LLMs), augmenting LLMs by retrieving information from external knowledge resources has been proven as a promising solution to mitigate hallucinations.However, the retrieval augmentation in LVLM significantly lags behind the widespread applications of LVLM. Moreover, when transferred to augmenting LVLMs, sometimes the hallucination degree of the model is even exacerbated.Motivated by the research gap and counter-intuitive phenomenon, we introduce a novel framework, the Active Retrieval-Augmented large vision-language model (ARA), specifically designed to address hallucinations by incorporating three critical dimensions: (i) dissecting the retrieval targets based on the inherent hierarchical structures of images. (ii) pinpointing the most effective retrieval methods and filtering out the reliable retrieval results. (iii) timing the retrieval process to coincide with episodes of low certainty, while circumventing unnecessary retrieval during periods of high certainty. To assess the capability of our proposed ARA model in reducing hallucination, we employ three widely used LVLM models (LLaVA-1.5, Qwen-VL, and mPLUG-Owl2) across four benchmarks. Our empirical observations suggest that by utilizing fitting retrieval mechanisms and timing the retrieval judiciously, we can effectively mitigate the hallucination problem. We hope that this study can provide deeper insights into how to adapt the retrieval augmentation to LVLMs for reducing hallucinations with more effective retrieval and minimal retrieval occurrences.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00555v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoye Qu, Qiyuan Chen, Wei Wei, Jishuo Sun, Jianfeng Dong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Bigger Encoders Always Better in Vision Large Models?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00620</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00620v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In recent years, multimodal large language models (MLLMs) have shown strong potential in real-world applications. They are developing rapidly due to their remarkable ability to comprehend multimodal information and their inherent powerful cognitive and reasoning capabilities. Among MLLMs, vision language models (VLM) stand out for their ability to understand vision information. However, the scaling trend of VLMs under the current mainstream paradigm has not been extensively studied. Whether we can achieve better performance by training even larger models is still unclear. To address this issue, we conducted experiments on the pretraining stage of MLLMs. We conduct our experiment using different encoder sizes and large language model (LLM) sizes. Our findings indicate that merely increasing the size of encoders does not necessarily enhance the performance of VLMs. Moreover, we analyzed the effects of LLM backbone parameter size and data quality on the pretraining outcomes. Additionally, we explored the differences in scaling laws between LLMs and VLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00620v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bozhou Li, Hao Liang, Zimo Meng, Wentao Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SynesLM: A Unified Approach for Audio-visual Speech Recognition and Translation via Language Model and Synthetic Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00624</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00624v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In this work, we present SynesLM, an unified model which can perform three multimodal language understanding tasks: audio-visual automatic speech recognition(AV-ASR) and visual-aided speech/machine translation(VST/VMT). Unlike previous research that focused on lip motion as visual cues for speech signals, our work explores more general visual information within entire frames, such as objects and actions. Additionally, we use synthetic image data to enhance the correlation between image and speech data. We benchmark SynesLM against the How2 dataset, demonstrating performance on par with state-of-the-art (SOTA) models dedicated to AV-ASR while maintaining our multitasking framework. Remarkably, for zero-shot AV-ASR, SynesLM achieved SOTA performance by lowering the Word Error Rate (WER) from 43.4% to 39.4% on the VisSpeech Dataset. Furthermore, our results in VST and VMT outperform the previous results, improving the BLEU score to 43.5 from 37.2 for VST, and to 54.8 from 54.4 for VMT.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00624v1</guid>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yichen Lu, Jiaqi Song, Xuankai Chang, Hengwei Bian, Soumi Maiti, Shinji Watanabe</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SentenceVAE: Faster, Longer and More Accurate Inference with Next-sentence Prediction for Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00655</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00655v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Contemporary large language models (LLMs) predominantly utilize a next-token prediction method for inference, which significantly impedes their processing speed. In this paper, we introduce a novel inference methodology termed next-sentence prediction, aimed at enhancing the inference efficiency of LLMs. We present SentenceVAE, a tiny model consisting of an encoder and a decoder. The encoder effectively condenses the information within a sentence into a singular token, while the decoder reconstructs this compressed data back into its original sentential form. By integrating SentenceVAE into the input and output layers of LLMs, we develop Sentence-level LLMs (SLLMs) that employ a sentence-by-sentence inference approach, markedly accelerating inference speeds. SentenceVAE also maintains the integrity of the original semantic content by segmenting the text into sentences, thereby preserving accuracy while boosting inference speeds. Compared to traditional LLMs, SLLMs process fewer tokens over equivalent context lengths, significantly reducing memory demands for Self-Attention computations and facilitating the handling of longer contexts. Our experimental findings reveal that this method can increase inference speeds by 204~365%, reduce perplexity (PPL) to 46~75% of its original metric, and decrease memory overhead by 86~91% for the same context length. The advantages of this approach are further amplified with increases in model parameters.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00655v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hongjun An, Yifan Chen, Xiaozhen Qiao, Zhe Sun, Xuelong Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tamper-Resistant Safeguards for Open-Weight LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00761</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00761v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Rapid advances in the capabilities of large language models (LLMs) have raised widespread concerns regarding their potential for malicious use. Open-weight LLMs present unique challenges, as existing safeguards lack robustness to tampering attacks that modify model weights. For example, recent works have demonstrated that refusal and unlearning safeguards can be trivially removed with a few steps of fine-tuning. These vulnerabilities necessitate new approaches for enabling the safe release of open-weight LLMs. We develop a method, called TAR, for building tamper-resistant safeguards into open-weight LLMs such that adversaries cannot remove the safeguards even after thousands of steps of fine-tuning. In extensive evaluations and red teaming analyses, we find that our method greatly improves tamper-resistance while preserving benign capabilities. Our results demonstrate that tamper-resistance is a tractable problem, opening up a promising new avenue to improve the safety and security of open-weight LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00761v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rishub Tamirisa, Bhrugu Bharathi, Long Phan, Andy Zhou, Alice Gatti, Tarun Suresh, Maxwell Lin, Justin Wang, Rowan Wang, Ron Arel, Andy Zou, Dawn Song, Bo Li, Dan Hendrycks, Mantas Mazeika</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MM-Vet v2: A Challenging Benchmark to Evaluate Large Multimodal Models for Integrated Capabilities</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00765</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00765v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: MM-Vet, with open-ended vision-language questions targeting at evaluating integrated capabilities, has become one of the most popular benchmarks for large multimodal model evaluation. MM-Vet assesses six core vision-language (VL) capabilities: recognition, knowledge, spatial awareness, language generation, OCR, and math. However, its question format is restricted to single image-text pairs, lacking the interleaved image and text sequences prevalent in real-world scenarios. To address this limitation, we introduce MM-Vet v2, which includes a new VL capability called "image-text sequence understanding", evaluating models' ability to process VL sequences. Furthermore, we maintain the high quality of evaluation samples while further expanding the evaluation set size. Using MM-Vet v2 to benchmark large multimodal models, we found that Claude 3.5 Sonnet is the best model with a score of 71.8, slightly outperforming GPT-4o which scored 71.0. Among open-weight models, InternVL2-Llama3-76B leads with a score of 68.4.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00765v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weihao Yu, Zhengyuan Yang, Linfeng Ren, Linjie Li, Jianfeng Wang, Kevin Lin, Chung-Ching Lin, Zicheng Liu, Lijuan Wang, Xinchao Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicting the Geolocation of Tweets Using transformer models on Customized Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2303.07865</link>
      <description>arXiv:2303.07865v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This research is aimed to solve the tweet/user geolocation prediction task and provide a flexible methodology for the geotagging of textual big data. The suggested approach implements neural networks for natural language processing (NLP) to estimate the location as coordinate pairs (longitude, latitude) and two-dimensional Gaussian Mixture Models (GMMs). The scope of proposed models has been finetuned on a Twitter dataset using pretrained Bidirectional Encoder Representations from Transformers (BERT) as base models. Performance metrics show a median error of fewer than 30 km on a worldwide-level, and fewer than 15 km on the US-level datasets for the models trained and evaluated on text features of tweets' content and metadata context. Our source code and data are available at https://github.com/K4TEL/geo-twitter.git</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2303.07865v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kateryna Lutsai, Christoph H. Lampert</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instructive Dialogue Summarization with Query Aggregations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.10981</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.10981v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Conventional dialogue summarization methods directly generate summaries and do not consider user's specific interests. This poses challenges in cases where the users are more focused on particular topics or aspects. With the advancement of instruction-finetuned language models, we introduce instruction-tuning to dialogues to expand the capability set of dialogue summarization models. To overcome the scarcity of instructive dialogue summarization data, we propose a three-step approach to synthesize high-quality query-based summarization triples. This process involves summary-anchored query generation, query filtering, and query-based summary generation. By training a unified model called InstructDS (Instructive Dialogue Summarization) on three summarization datasets with multi-purpose instructive triples, we expand the capability of dialogue summarization models. We evaluate our method on four datasets, including dialogue summarization and dialogue reading comprehension. Experimental results show that our approach outperforms the state-of-the-art models and even models with larger sizes. Additionally, our model exhibits higher generalizability and faithfulness, as confirmed by human subjective evaluations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.10981v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bin Wang, Zhengyuan Liu, Nancy F. Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Survey of Text Watermarking in the Era of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.07913</link>
      <description>arXiv:2312.07913v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Text watermarking algorithms are crucial for protecting the copyright of textual content. Historically, their capabilities and application scenarios were limited. However, recent advancements in large language models (LLMs) have revolutionized these techniques. LLMs not only enhance text watermarking algorithms with their advanced abilities but also create a need for employing these algorithms to protect their own copyrights or prevent potential misuse. This paper conducts a comprehensive survey of the current state of text watermarking technology, covering four main aspects: (1) an overview and comparison of different text watermarking techniques; (2) evaluation methods for text watermarking algorithms, including their detectability, impact on text or LLM quality, robustness under target or untargeted attacks; (3) potential application scenarios for text watermarking technology; (4) current challenges and future directions for text watermarking. This survey aims to provide researchers with a thorough understanding of text watermarking technology in the era of LLM, thereby promoting its further advancement.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2312.07913v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aiwei Liu, Leyi Pan, Yijian Lu, Jingjing Li, Xuming Hu, Xi Zhang, Lijie Wen, Irwin King, Hui Xiong, Philip S. Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Narrowing the Knowledge Evaluation Gap: Open-Domain Question Answering with Multi-Granularity Answers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04695</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.04695v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Factual questions typically can be answered correctly at different levels of granularity. For example, both ``August 4, 1961'' and ``1961'' are correct answers to the question ``When was Barack Obama born?''. Standard question answering (QA) evaluation protocols, however, do not explicitly take this into account and compare a predicted answer against answers of a single granularity level. In this work, we propose GRANOLA QA, a novel evaluation setting where a predicted answer is evaluated in terms of accuracy and informativeness against a set of multi-granularity answers. We present a simple methodology for enriching existing datasets with multi-granularity answers, and create GRANOLA-EQ, a multi-granularity version of the EntityQuestions dataset. We evaluate a range of decoding methods on GRANOLA-EQ, including a new algorithm, called Decoding with Response Aggregation (DRAG), that is geared towards aligning the response granularity with the model's uncertainty. Our experiments show that large language models with standard decoding tend to generate specific answers, which are often incorrect. In contrast, when evaluated on multi-granularity answers, DRAG yields a nearly 20 point increase in accuracy on average, which further increases for rare entities. Overall, this reveals that standard evaluation and decoding schemes may significantly underestimate the knowledge encapsulated in LMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.04695v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gal Yona, Roee Aharoni, Mor Geva</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distilling Mathematical Reasoning Capabilities into Small Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.11864</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.11864v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This work addresses the challenge of democratizing advanced Large Language Models (LLMs) by compressing their mathematical reasoning capabilities into sub-billion parameter Small Language Models (SLMs) without compromising performance. We introduce Equation-of-Thought Distillation (EoTD), a novel technique that encapsulates the reasoning process into equation-based representations to construct an EoTD dataset for fine-tuning SLMs. Additionally, we propose the Ensemble Thoughts Distillation (ETD) framework to enhance the reasoning performance of SLMs. This involves creating a reasoning dataset with multiple thought processes, including Chain-of-Thought (CoT), Program-of-Thought (PoT), and Equation-of-Thought (EoT), and using it for fine-tuning. Our experimental performance demonstrates that EoTD significantly boosts the reasoning abilities of SLMs, while ETD enables these models to achieve state-of-the-art reasoning performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.11864v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xunyu Zhu, Jian Li, Yong Liu, Can Ma, Weiping Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Hybrid Strategy for Chat Transcript Summarization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.01510</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.01510v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Text summarization is the process of condensing a piece of text to fewer sentences, while still preserving its content. Chat transcript, in this context, is a textual copy of a digital or online conversation between a customer (caller) and agent(s). This paper presents an indigenously (locally) developed hybrid method that first combines extractive and abstractive summarization techniques in compressing ill-punctuated or un-punctuated chat transcripts to produce more readable punctuated summaries and then optimizes the overall quality of summarization through reinforcement learning. Extensive testing, evaluations, comparisons, and validation have demonstrated the efficacy of this approach for large-scale deployment of chat transcript summarization, in the absence of manually generated reference (annotated) summaries.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.01510v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Pratik K. Biswas</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DefInt: A Default-interventionist Framework for Efficient Reasoning with Hybrid Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.02563</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.02563v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have shown impressive emergent abilities in a wide range of tasks, but still face challenges in handling complex reasoning problems. Previous works like chain-of-thought (CoT) and tree-of-thoughts (ToT) have predominately focused on enhancing accuracy, but overlook the rapidly increasing token cost, which could be particularly problematic for open-ended real-world tasks with huge solution spaces. Motivated by the dual process theory of human cognition, we propose a Default-Interventionist framework (DefInt) to unleash the synergistic potential of hybrid LLMs. By default, DefInt uses smaller-scale language models to generate low-cost reasoning thoughts, which resembles the fast intuitions produced by System 1. If the intuitions are considered with low confidence, DefInt will invoke the reflective reasoning of scaled-up language models as the intervention of System 2, which can override the default thoughts and rectify the reasoning process. Experiments on five representative reasoning tasks show that DefInt consistently achieves state-of-the-art reasoning accuracy and solution diversity. More importantly, it substantially reduces the token cost by 49%-79% compared to the second accurate baselines. Specifically, the open-ended tasks have an average 75% token cost reduction. Code repo with all prompts will be released upon publication.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.02563v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yu Shang, Yu Li, Fengli Xu, Yong Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inducing Generalization across Languages and Tasks using Featurized Low-Rank Mixtures</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.17934</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.17934v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Adapting pretrained large language models (LLMs) to various downstream tasks in tens or hundreds of human languages is computationally expensive. Parameter-efficient fine-tuning (PEFT) significantly reduces the adaptation cost, by tuning only a small amount of parameters. However, common PEFT methods LoRA (Hu et al., 2022) suffer from suboptimal performance on diverse dataset mixtures, due to aggressive parameter tying and negative interference among different datasets. In this work, we propose Featurized Low-rank Mixtures (FLix), a novel PEFT method designed for effective multitask multilingual adaptation. FLix associates each unique dataset feature, such as the dataset's language or task, with its own low-rank weight update parameters. By composing feature-specific parameters for each dataset, FLix can accommodate diverse dataset mixtures and generalize better to unseen datasets. Our experiments show that FLix leads to significant improvements over a variety of tasks for both supervised learning and zero-shot settings with gains of up to $14.2$ inexact match points in zero-shot semantic parsing.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.17934v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chu-Cheng Lin, Xinyi Wang, Jonathan H. Clark, Han Lu, Yun Zhu, Chenxi Whitehouse, Hongkun Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The opportunities and risks of large language models in mental health</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.14814</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.14814v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Global rates of mental health concerns are rising, and there is increasing realization that existing models of mental health care will not adequately expand to meet the demand. With the emergence of large language models (LLMs) has come great optimism regarding their promise to create novel, large-scale solutions to support mental health. Despite their nascence, LLMs have already been applied to mental health related tasks. In this paper, we summarize the extant literature on efforts to use LLMs to provide mental health education, assessment, and intervention and highlight key opportunities for positive impact in each area. We then highlight risks associated with LLMs' application to mental health and encourage the adoption of strategies to mitigate these risks. The urgent need for mental health support must be balanced with responsible development, testing, and deployment of mental health LLMs. It is especially critical to ensure that mental health LLMs are fine-tuned for mental health, enhance mental health equity, and adhere to ethical standards and that people, including those with lived experience with mental health concerns, are involved in all stages from development through deployment. Prioritizing these efforts will minimize potential harms to mental health and maximize the likelihood that LLMs will positively impact mental health globally.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.14814v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.2196/59479</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>JMIR Ment Health 2024;11:e59479</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Hannah R. Lawrence, Renee A. Schneider, Susan B. Rubin, Maja J. Mataric, Daniel J. McDuff, Megan Jones Bell</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metadata Integration for Spam Reviews Detection on Vietnamese E-commerce Websites</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.13292</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.13292v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The problem of detecting spam reviews (opinions) has received significant attention in recent years, especially with the rapid development of e-commerce. Spam reviews are often classified based on comment content, but in some cases, it is insufficient for models to accurately determine the review label. In this work, we introduce the ViSpamReviews v2 dataset, which includes metadata of reviews with the objective of integrating supplementary attributes for spam review classification. We propose a novel approach to simultaneously integrate both textual and categorical attributes into the classification model. In our experiments, the product category proved effective when combined with deep neural network (DNN) models, while text features performed well on both DNN models and the model achieved state-of-the-art performance in the problem of detecting spam reviews on Vietnamese e-commerce websites, namely PhoBERT. Specifically, the PhoBERT model achieves the highest accuracy when combined with product description features generated from the SPhoBert model, which is the combination of PhoBERT and SentenceBERT. Using the macro-averaged F1 score, the task of classifying spam reviews achieved 87.22% (an increase of 1.64% compared to the baseline), while the task of identifying the type of spam reviews achieved an accuracy of 73.49% (an increase of 1.93% compared to the baseline).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.13292v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1142/S2717554524500024</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Co Van Dinh, Son T. Luu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Quantization on Retrieval-Augmented Generation: An Analysis of Small LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10251</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10251v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Post-training quantization reduces the computational demand of Large Language Models (LLMs) but can weaken some of their capabilities. Since LLM abilities emerge with scale, smaller LLMs are more sensitive to quantization. In this paper, we explore how quantization affects smaller LLMs' ability to perform retrieval-augmented generation (RAG), specifically in longer contexts. We chose personalization for evaluation because it is a challenging domain to perform using RAG as it requires long-context reasoning over multiple documents. We compare the original FP16 and the quantized INT4 performance of multiple 7B and 8B LLMs on two tasks while progressively increasing the number of retrieved documents to test how quantized models fare against longer contexts. To better understand the effect of retrieval, we evaluate three retrieval models in our experiments. Our findings reveal that if a 7B LLM performs the task well, quantization does not impair its performance and long-context reasoning capabilities. We conclude that it is possible to utilize RAG with quantized smaller LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10251v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mert Yazan, Suzan Verberne, Frederik Situmeang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Are LLMs Mitigating Stereotyping Harms? Learning from Search Engine Studies</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.11733</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.11733v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: With the widespread availability of LLMs since the release of ChatGPT and increased public scrutiny, commercial model development appears to have focused their efforts on 'safety' training concerning legal liabilities at the expense of social impact evaluation. This mimics a similar trend which we could observe for search engine autocompletion some years prior. We draw on scholarship from NLP and search engine auditing and present a novel evaluation task in the style of autocompletion prompts to assess stereotyping in LLMs. We assess LLMs by using four metrics, namely refusal rates, toxicity, sentiment and regard, with and without safety system prompts. Our findings indicate an improvement to stereotyping outputs with the system prompt, but overall a lack of attention by LLMs under study to certain harms classified as toxic, particularly for prompts about peoples/ethnicities and sexual orientation. Mentions of intersectional identities trigger a disproportionate amount of stereotyping. Finally, we discuss the implications of these findings about stereotyping harms in light of the coming intermingling of LLMs and search and the choice of stereotyping mitigation policy to adopt. We address model builders, academics, NLP practitioners and policy makers, calling for accountability and awareness concerning stereotyping harms, be it for training data curation, leader board design and usage, or social impact measurement.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.11733v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alina Leidinger, Richard Rogers</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prover-Verifier Games improve legibility of LLM outputs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.13692</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.13692v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: One way to increase confidence in the outputs of Large Language Models (LLMs) is to support them with reasoning that is clear and easy to check -- a property we call legibility. We study legibility in the context of solving grade-school math problems and show that optimizing chain-of-thought solutions only for answer correctness can make them less legible. To mitigate the loss in legibility, we propose a training algorithm inspired by Prover-Verifier Game from Anil et al. (2021). Our algorithm iteratively trains small verifiers to predict solution correctness, "helpful" provers to produce correct solutions that the verifier accepts, and "sneaky" provers to produce incorrect solutions that fool the verifier. We find that the helpful prover's accuracy and the verifier's robustness to adversarial attacks increase over the course of training. Furthermore, we show that legibility training transfers to time-constrained humans tasked with verifying solution correctness. Over course of LLM training human accuracy increases when checking the helpful prover's solutions, and decreases when checking the sneaky prover's solutions. Hence, training for checkability by small verifiers is a plausible technique for increasing output legibility. Our results suggest legibility training against small verifiers as a practical avenue for increasing legibility of large LLMs to humans, and thus could help with alignment of superhuman models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.13692v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jan Hendrik Kirchner, Yining Chen, Harri Edwards, Jan Leike, Nat McAleese, Yuri Burda</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Semantic Similarity Understanding in Arabic NLP with Nested Embedding Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.21139</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.21139v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This work presents a novel framework for training Arabic nested embedding models through Matryoshka Embedding Learning, leveraging multilingual, Arabic-specific, and English-based models, to highlight the power of nested embeddings models in various Arabic NLP downstream tasks. Our innovative contribution includes the translation of various sentence similarity datasets into Arabic, enabling a comprehensive evaluation framework to compare these models across different dimensions. We trained several nested embedding models on the Arabic Natural Language Inference triplet dataset and assessed their performance using multiple evaluation metrics, including Pearson and Spearman correlations for cosine similarity, Manhattan distance, Euclidean distance, and dot product similarity. The results demonstrate the superior performance of the Matryoshka embedding models, particularly in capturing semantic nuances unique to the Arabic language. Results demonstrated that Arabic Matryoshka embedding models have superior performance in capturing semantic nuances unique to the Arabic language, significantly outperforming traditional models by up to 20-25\% across various similarity metrics. These results underscore the effectiveness of language-specific training and highlight the potential of Matryoshka models in enhancing semantic textual similarity tasks for Arabic NLP.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.21139v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Omer Nacar, Anis Koubaa</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Silent Letters: Amplifying LLMs in Emotion Recognition with Vocal Nuances</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.21315</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.21315v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper introduces a novel approach to emotion detection in speech using Large Language Models (LLMs). We address the limitation of LLMs in processing audio inputs by translating speech characteristics into natural language descriptions. Our method integrates these descriptions into text prompts, enabling LLMs to perform multimodal emotion analysis without architectural modifications. We evaluate our approach on two datasets: IEMOCAP and MELD, demonstrating significant improvements in emotion recognition accuracy, particularly for high-quality audio data. Our experiments show that incorporating speech descriptions yields a 2 percentage point increase in weighted F1 score on IEMOCAP (from 70.111\% to 72.596\%). We also compare various LLM architectures and explore the effectiveness of different feature representations. Our findings highlight the potential of this approach in enhancing emotion detection capabilities of LLMs and underscore the importance of audio quality in speech-based emotion recognition tasks. We'll release the source code on Github.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.21315v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zehui Wu, Ziwei Gong, Lin Ai, Pengyuan Shi, Kaan Donbekci, Julia Hirschberg</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>QuestGen: Effectiveness of Question Generation Methods for Fact-Checking Applications</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.21441</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.21441v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Verifying fact-checking claims poses a significant challenge, even for humans. Recent approaches have demonstrated that decomposing claims into relevant questions to gather evidence enhances the efficiency of the fact-checking process. In this paper, we provide empirical evidence showing that this question decomposition can be effectively automated. We demonstrate that smaller generative models, fine-tuned for the question generation task using data augmentation from various datasets, outperform large language models by up to 8%. Surprisingly, in some cases, the evidence retrieved using machine-generated questions proves to be significantly more effective for fact-checking than that obtained from human-written questions. We also perform manual evaluation of the decomposed questions to assess the quality of the questions generated.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.21441v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3627673.3679985</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Ritvik Setty, Vinay Setty</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generative Expressive Conversational Speech Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.21491</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.21491v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Conversational Speech Synthesis (CSS) aims to express a target utterance with the proper speaking style in a user-agent conversation setting. Existing CSS methods employ effective multi-modal context modeling techniques to achieve empathy understanding and expression. However, they often need to design complex network architectures and meticulously optimize the modules within them. In addition, due to the limitations of small-scale datasets containing scripted recording styles, they often fail to simulate real natural conversational styles. To address the above issues, we propose a novel generative expressive CSS system, termed GPT-Talker.We transform the multimodal information of the multi-turn dialogue history into discrete token sequences and seamlessly integrate them to form a comprehensive user-agent dialogue context. Leveraging the power of GPT, we predict the token sequence, that includes both semantic and style knowledge, of response for the agent. After that, the expressive conversational speech is synthesized by the conversation-enriched VITS to deliver feedback to the user.Furthermore, we propose a large-scale Natural CSS Dataset called NCSSD, that includes both naturally recorded conversational speech in improvised styles and dialogues extracted from TV shows. It encompasses both Chinese and English languages, with a total duration of 236 hours.We conducted comprehensive experiments on the reliability of the NCSSD and the effectiveness of our GPT-Talker. Both subjective and objective evaluations demonstrate that our model outperforms other state-of-the-art CSS systems significantly in terms of naturalness and expressiveness. The Code, Dataset, and Pre-trained Model are available at: https://github.com/AI-S2-Lab/GPT-Talker.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.21491v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rui Liu, Yifan Hu, Yi Ren, Xiang Yin, Haizhou Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defending Jailbreak Attack in VLMs via Cross-modality Information Detector</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.21659</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.21659v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Vision Language Models (VLMs) extend the capacity of LLMs to comprehensively understand vision information, achieving remarkable performance in many vision-centric tasks. Despite that, recent studies have shown that these models are susceptible to jailbreak attacks, which refer to an exploitative technique where malicious users can break the safety alignment of the target model and generate misleading and harmful answers. This potential threat is caused by both the inherent vulnerabilities of LLM and the larger attack scope introduced by vision input. To enhance the security of VLMs against jailbreak attacks, researchers have developed various defense techniques. However, these methods either require modifications to the model's internal structure or demand significant computational resources during the inference phase. Multimodal information is a double-edged sword. While it increases the risk of attacks, it also provides additional data that can enhance safeguards. Inspired by this, we propose $\underline{\textbf{C}}$ross-modality $\underline{\textbf{I}}$nformation $\underline{\textbf{DE}}$tecto$\underline{\textbf{R}}$ ($\textit{CIDER})$, a plug-and-play jailbreaking detector designed to identify maliciously perturbed image inputs, utilizing the cross-modal similarity between harmful queries and adversarial images. This simple yet effective cross-modality information detector, $\textit{CIDER}$, is independent of the target VLMs and requires less computation cost. Extensive experimental results demonstrate the effectiveness and efficiency of $\textit{CIDER}$, as well as its transferability to both white-box and black-box VLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.21659v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yue Xu, Xiuyuan Qi, Zhan Qin, Wenjie Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Psychoacoustic Challenges Of Speech Enhancement On VoIP Platforms</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.07161</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.07161v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Within the ambit of VoIP (Voice over Internet Protocol) telecommunications, the complexities introduced by acoustic transformations merit rigorous analysis. This research, rooted in the exploration of proprietary sender-side denoising effects, meticulously evaluates platforms such as Google Meets and Zoom. The study draws upon the Deep Noise Suppression (DNS) 2020 dataset, ensuring a structured examination tailored to various denoising settings and receiver interfaces. A methodological novelty is introduced via Blinder-Oaxaca decomposition, traditionally an econometric tool, repurposed herein to analyze acoustic-phonetic perturbations within VoIP systems. To further ground the implications of these transformations, psychoacoustic metrics, specifically PESQ and STOI, were used to explain of perceptual quality and intelligibility. Cumulatively, the insights garnered underscore the intricate landscape of VoIP-influenced acoustic dynamics. In addition to the primary findings, a multitude of metrics are reported, extending the research purview. Moreover, out-of-domain benchmarking for both time and time-frequency domain speech enhancement models is included, thereby enhancing the depth and applicability of this inquiry.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.07161v3</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Joseph Konan, Shikhar Agnihotri, Ojas Bhargave, Shuo Han, Yunyang Zeng, Ankit Shah, Bhiksha Raj</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KGLens: Towards Efficient and Effective Knowledge Probing of Large Language Models with Knowledge Graphs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11539</link>
      <description>arXiv:2312.11539v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) might hallucinate facts, while curated Knowledge Graph (KGs) are typically factually reliable especially with domain-specific knowledge. Measuring the alignment between KGs and LLMs can effectively probe the factualness and identify the knowledge blind spots of LLMs. However, verifying the LLMs over extensive KGs can be expensive. In this paper, we present KGLens, a Thompson-sampling-inspired framework aimed at effectively and efficiently measuring the alignment between KGs and LLMs. KGLens features a graph-guided question generator for converting KGs into natural language, along with a carefully designed importance sampling strategy based on parameterized KG structure to expedite KG traversal. Our simulation experiment compares the brute force method with KGLens under six different sampling methods, demonstrating that our approach achieves superior probing efficiency. Leveraging KGLens, we conducted in-depth analyses of the factual accuracy of ten LLMs across three large domain-specific KGs from Wikidata, composing over 19K edges, 700 relations, and 21K entities. Human evaluation results indicate that KGLens can assess LLMs with a level of accuracy nearly equivalent to that of human annotators, achieving 95.7% of the accuracy rate.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2312.11539v3</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shangshang Zheng, He Bai, Yizhe Zhang, Yi Su, Xiaochuan Niu, Navdeep Jaitly</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can ChatGPT Read Who You Are?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.16070</link>
      <description>arXiv:2312.16070v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The interplay between artificial intelligence (AI) and psychology, particularly in personality assessment, represents an important emerging area of research. Accurate personality trait estimation is crucial not only for enhancing personalization in human-computer interaction but also for a wide variety of applications ranging from mental health to education. This paper analyzes the capability of a generic chatbot, ChatGPT, to effectively infer personality traits from short texts. We report the results of a comprehensive user study featuring texts written in Czech by a representative population sample of 155 participants. Their self-assessments based on the Big Five Inventory (BFI) questionnaire serve as the ground truth. We compare the personality trait estimations made by ChatGPT against those by human raters and report ChatGPT's competitive performance in inferring personality traits from text. We also uncover a 'positivity bias' in ChatGPT's assessments across all personality dimensions and explore the impact of prompt composition on accuracy. This work contributes to the understanding of AI capabilities in psychological assessment, highlighting both the potential and limitations of using large language models for personality inference. Our research underscores the importance of responsible AI development, considering ethical implications such as privacy, consent, autonomy, and bias in AI applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2312.16070v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1016/j.chbah.2024.100088</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Erik Derner, Dalibor Ku\v{c}era, Nuria Oliver, Jan Zah\'alka</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChunkAttention: Efficient Self-Attention with Prefix-Aware KV Cache and Two-Phase Partition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.15220</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.15220v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Self-attention is an essential component of large language models (LLM) but a significant source of inference latency for long sequences. In multi-tenant LLM serving scenarios, the compute and memory operation cost of self-attention can be optimized by using the probability that multiple LLM requests have shared system prompts in prefixes. In this paper, we introduce ChunkAttention, a prefix-aware self-attention module that can detect matching prompt prefixes across multiple requests and share their key/value tensors in memory at runtime to improve the memory utilization of KV cache. This is achieved by breaking monolithic key/value tensors into smaller chunks and structuring them into the auxiliary prefix tree. Consequently, on top of the prefix-tree based KV cache, we design an efficient self-attention kernel, where a two-phase partition algorithm is implemented to improve the data locality during self-attention computation in the presence of shared system prompts. Experiments show that ChunkAttention can speed up the self-attention kernel by 3.2-4.8$\times$ compared to the state-of-the-art implementation, with the length of the system prompt ranging from 1024 to 4096.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.15220v4</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lu Ye, Ze Tao, Yong Huang, Yang Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Hybrid Intelligence Method for Argument Mining</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.09713</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.09713v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large-scale survey tools enable the collection of citizen feedback in opinion corpora. Extracting the key arguments from a large and noisy set of opinions helps in understanding the opinions quickly and accurately. Fully automated methods can extract arguments but (1) require large labeled datasets that induce large annotation costs and (2) work well for known viewpoints, but not for novel points of view. We propose HyEnA, a hybrid (human + AI) method for extracting arguments from opinionated texts, combining the speed of automated processing with the understanding and reasoning capabilities of humans. We evaluate HyEnA on three citizen feedback corpora. We find that, on the one hand, HyEnA achieves higher coverage and precision than a state-of-the-art automated method when compared to a common set of diverse opinions, justifying the need for human insight. On the other hand, HyEnA requires less human effort and does not compromise quality compared to (fully manual) expert analysis, demonstrating the benefit of combining human and artificial intelligence.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.09713v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1613/jair.1.15135</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Journal of Artificial Intelligence Research (JAIR), 80:1187-1222, 2024</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Michiel van der Meer, Enrico Liscio, Catholijn M. Jonker, Aske Plaat, Piek Vossen, Pradeep K. Murukannaiah</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Retrieval for RAG based Question Answering Models on Financial Documents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.07221</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.07221v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The effectiveness of Large Language Models (LLMs) in generating accurate responses relies heavily on the quality of input provided, particularly when employing Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) techniques. RAG enhances LLMs by sourcing the most relevant text chunk(s) to base queries upon. Despite the significant advancements in LLMs' response quality in recent years, users may still encounter inaccuracies or irrelevant answers; these issues often stem from suboptimal text chunk retrieval by RAG rather than the inherent capabilities of LLMs. To augment the efficacy of LLMs, it is crucial to refine the RAG process. This paper explores the existing constraints of RAG pipelines and introduces methodologies for enhancing text retrieval. It delves into strategies such as sophisticated chunking techniques, query expansion, the incorporation of metadata annotations, the application of re-ranking algorithms, and the fine-tuning of embedding algorithms. Implementing these approaches can substantially improve the retrieval quality, thereby elevating the overall performance and reliability of LLMs in processing and responding to queries.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.07221v2</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>q-fin.GN</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Spurthi Setty, Harsh Thakkar, Alyssa Lee, Eden Chung, Natan Vidra</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Supervised Learning Based Handwriting Verification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.18320</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.18320v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We present SSL-HV: Self-Supervised Learning approaches applied to the task of Handwriting Verification. This task involves determining whether a given pair of handwritten images originate from the same or different writer distribution. We have compared the performance of multiple generative, contrastive SSL approaches against handcrafted feature extractors and supervised learning on CEDAR AND dataset. We show that ResNet based Variational Auto-Encoder (VAE) outperforms other generative approaches achieving 76.3% accuracy, while ResNet-18 fine-tuned using Variance-Invariance-Covariance Regularization (VICReg) outperforms other contrastive approaches achieving 78% accuracy. Using a pre-trained VAE and VICReg for the downstream task of writer verification we observed a relative improvement in accuracy of 6.7% and 9% over ResNet-18 supervised baseline with 10% writer labels.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.18320v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mihir Chauhan, Mohammad Abuzar Hashemi, Abhishek Satbhai, Mir Basheer Ali, Bina Ramamurthy, Mingchen Gao, Siwei Lyu, Sargur Srihari</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Notion of Complexity for Theory of Mind via Discrete World Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.11911</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.11911v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Theory of Mind (ToM) can be used to assess the capabilities of Large Language Models (LLMs) in complex scenarios where social reasoning is required. While the research community has proposed many ToM benchmarks, their hardness varies greatly, and their complexity is not well defined. This work proposes a framework to measure the complexity of ToM tasks. We quantify a problem's complexity as the number of states necessary to solve it correctly. Our complexity measure also accounts for spurious states of a ToM problem designed to make it apparently harder. We use our method to assess the complexity of five widely adopted ToM benchmarks. On top of this framework, we design a prompting technique that augments the information available to a model with a description of how the environment changes with the agents' interactions. We name this technique Discrete World Models (DWM) and show how it elicits superior performance on ToM tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.11911v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>X. Angelo Huang, Emanuele La Malfa, Samuele Marro, Andrea Asperti, Anthony Cohn, Michael Wooldridge</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GLiNER multi-task: Generalist Lightweight Model for Various Information Extraction Tasks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.12925</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.12925v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Information extraction tasks require both accurate, efficient, and generalisable models. Classical supervised deep learning approaches can achieve the required performance, but they need large datasets and are limited in their ability to adapt to different tasks. On the other hand, large language models (LLMs) demonstrate good generalization, meaning that they can adapt to many different tasks based on user requests. However, LLMs are computationally expensive and tend to fail to generate structured outputs. In this article, we will introduce a new kind of GLiNER model that can be used for various information extraction tasks while being a small encoder model. Our model achieved SoTA performance on zero-shot NER benchmarks and leading performance on question-answering, summarization and relation extraction tasks. Additionally, in this article, we will cover experimental results on self-learning approaches for named entity recognition using GLiNER models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.12925v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ihor Stepanov, Mykhailo Shtopko</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoder-only Architecture for Streaming End-to-end Speech Recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.16107</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.16107v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Decoder-only language models (LMs) have been successfully adopted for speech-processing tasks including automatic speech recognition (ASR). The LMs have ample expressiveness and perform efficiently. This efficiency is a suitable characteristic for streaming applications of ASR. In this work, we propose to use a decoder-only architecture for blockwise streaming ASR. In our approach, speech features are compressed using CTC output and context embedding using blockwise speech subnetwork, and are sequentially provided as prompts to the decoder. The decoder estimates the output tokens promptly at each block. To this end, we also propose a novel training scheme using random-length prefix prompts to make the model robust to the truncated prompts caused by blockwise processing. An experimental comparison shows that our proposed decoder-only streaming ASR achieves 8% relative word error rate reduction in the LibriSpeech test-other set while being twice as fast as the baseline model.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.16107v2</guid>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Emiru Tsunoo, Hayato Futami, Yosuke Kashiwagi, Siddhant Arora, Shinji Watanabe</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pistis-RAG: A Scalable Cascading Framework Towards Trustworthy Retrieval-Augmented Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.00072</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.00072v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In Greek mythology, Pistis symbolized good faith, trust, and reliability. Drawing inspiration from these principles, Pistis-RAG is a scalable multi-stage framework designed to address the challenges of large-scale retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) systems. This framework consists of distinct stages: matching, pre-ranking, ranking, reasoning, and aggregating. Each stage contributes to narrowing the search space, prioritizing semantically relevant documents, aligning with the large language model's (LLM) preferences, supporting complex chain-of-thought (CoT) methods, and combining information from multiple sources.
  Our ranking stage introduces a significant innovation by recognizing that semantic relevance alone may not lead to improved generation quality, due to the sensitivity of the few-shot prompt order, as noted in previous research. This critical aspect is often overlooked in current RAG frameworks.
  We argue that the alignment issue between LLMs and external knowledge ranking methods is tied to the model-centric paradigm dominant in RAG systems. We propose a content-centric approach, emphasizing seamless integration between LLMs and external information sources to optimize content transformation for specific tasks.
  Our novel ranking stage is designed specifically for RAG systems, incorporating principles of information retrieval while considering the unique business scenarios reflected in LLM preferences and user feedback. We simulated feedback signals on the MMLU benchmark, resulting in a 9.3% performance improvement. Our model and code will be open-sourced on GitHub. Additionally, experiments on real-world, large-scale data validate the scalability of our framework.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.00072v4</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yu Bai, Yukai Miao, Li Chen, Dan Li, Yanyu Ren, Hongtao Xie, Ce Yang, Xuhui Cai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KeyVideoLLM: Towards Large-scale Video Keyframe Selection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.03104</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.03104v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Recently, with the rise of web videos, managing and understanding large-scale video datasets has become increasingly important. Video Large Language Models (VideoLLMs) have emerged in recent years due to their strong video understanding capabilities. However, training and inference processes for VideoLLMs demand vast amounts of data, presenting significant challenges to data management, particularly regarding efficiency, robustness, and effectiveness. In this work, we present KeyVideoLLM, a text-video frame similarity-based keyframe selection method designed to manage VideoLLM data efficiently, robustly, and effectively. Specifically, KeyVideoLLM achieves a remarkable data compression rate of up to 60.9 times, substantially lowering disk space requirements, which proves its high efficiency. Additionally, it maintains a 100% selection success rate across all video formats and scales, enhances processing speed by up to 200 times compared to existing keyframe selection methods, and does not require hyperparameter tuning. Beyond its outstanding efficiency and robustness, KeyVideoLLM further improves model performance in video question-answering tasks during both training and inference stages. Notably, it consistently achieved the state-of-the-art (SoTA) experimental results on diverse datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.03104v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hao Liang, Jiapeng Li, Tianyi Bai, Xijie Huang, Linzhuang Sun, Zhengren Wang, Conghui He, Bin Cui, Chong Chen, Wentao Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Pre-training of Multimodal Language Models Customized for Chart Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.14506</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.14506v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Recent studies customizing Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) for domain-specific tasks have yielded promising results, especially in the field of scientific chart comprehension. These studies generally utilize visual instruction tuning with specialized datasets to enhance question and answer (QA) accuracy within the chart domain. However, they often neglect the fundamental discrepancy between natural image-caption pre-training data and digital chart image-QA data, particularly in the models' capacity to extract underlying numeric values from charts. This paper tackles this oversight by exploring the training processes necessary to improve MLLMs' comprehension of charts. We present three key findings: (1) Incorporating raw data values in alignment pre-training markedly improves comprehension of chart data. (2) Replacing images with their textual representation randomly during end-to-end fine-tuning transfer the language reasoning capability to chart interpretation skills. (3) Requiring the model to first extract the underlying chart data and then answer the question in the fine-tuning can further improve the accuracy. Consequently, we introduce CHOPINLLM, an MLLM tailored for in-depth chart comprehension. CHOPINLLM effectively interprets various types of charts, including unannotated ones, while maintaining robust reasoning abilities. Furthermore, we establish a new benchmark to evaluate MLLMs' understanding of different chart types across various comprehension levels. Experimental results show that CHOPINLLM exhibits strong performance in understanding both annotated and unannotated charts across a wide range of types.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.14506v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wan-Cyuan Fan, Yen-Chun Chen, Mengchen Liu, Lu Yuan, Leonid Sigal</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CultureVo: The Serious Game of Utilizing Gen AI for Enhancing Cultural Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.20685</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.20685v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: CultureVo, Inc. has developed the Integrated Culture Learning Suite (ICLS) to deliver foundational knowledge of world cultures through a combination of interactive lessons and gamified experiences. This paper explores how Generative AI powered by open source Large Langauge Models are utilized within the ICLS to enhance cultural intelligence. The suite employs Generative AI techniques to automate the assessment of learner knowledge, analyze behavioral patterns, and manage interactions with non-player characters using real time learner assessment. Additionally, ICLS provides contextual hint and recommend course content by assessing learner proficiency, while Generative AI facilitates the automated creation and validation of educational content.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.20685v2</guid>
      <category>cs.ET</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ajita Agarwala, Anupam Purwar, Viswanadhasai Rao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SynthVLM: High-Efficiency and High-Quality Synthetic Data for Vision Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.20756</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.20756v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Recently, with the rise of web images, managing and understanding large-scale image datasets has become increasingly important. Vision Large Language Models (VLLMs) have recently emerged due to their robust vision-understanding capabilities. However, training these models requires vast amounts of data, posing challenges to efficiency, effectiveness, data quality, and privacy. In this paper, we introduce SynthVLM, a novel data synthesis pipeline for VLLMs. Unlike existing methods that generate captions from images, SynthVLM employs advanced diffusion models and high-quality captions to automatically generate and select high-resolution images from captions, creating precisely aligned image-text pairs. Leveraging these pairs, we achieve state-of-the-art (SoTA) performance on various vision question answering tasks, maintaining high alignment quality and preserving advanced language abilities. Moreover, SynthVLM surpasses traditional GPT-4 Vision-based caption generation methods in performance while significantly reducing computational overhead. Crucially, our method's reliance on purely generated data ensures the preservation of privacy, achieving SoTA performance with just 100k data points (only 18% of the official dataset size).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.20756v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zheng Liu, Hao Liang, Xijie Huang, Wentao Xiong, Qinhan Yu, Linzhuang Sun, Chong Chen, Conghui He, Bin Cui, Wentao Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
