<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CV updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CV</link>
    <description>cs.CV updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CV" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 04:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Sunday</day>
      <day>Saturday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>Solution for Point Tracking Task of ECCV 2nd Perception Test Challenge 2024</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16286</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16286v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This report introduces an improved method for the Tracking Any Point~(TAP), focusing on monitoring physical surfaces in video footage. Despite their success with short-sequence scenarios, TAP methods still face performance degradation and resource overhead in long-sequence situations. To address these issues, we propose a simple yet effective approach called Fine-grained Point Discrimination~(\textbf{FPD}), which focuses on perceiving and rectifying point tracking at multiple granularities in zero-shot manner, especially for static points in the videos shot by a static camera. The proposed FPD contains two key components: $(1)$ Multi-granularity point perception, which can detect static sequences in video and points. $(2)$ Dynamic trajectory correction, which replaces point trajectories based on the type of tracked point. Our approach achieved the second highest score in the final test with a score of $0.4720$.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16286v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuxuan Zhang, Pengsong Niu, Kun Yu, Qingguo Chen, Yang Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solution for OOD-CV UNICORN Challenge 2024 Object Detection Assistance LLM Counting Ability Improvement</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16287</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16287v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This report provide a detailed description of the method that we explored and proposed in the ECCV OOD-CV UNICORN Challenge 2024, which focusing on the robustness of responses from large language models. The dataset of this competition are OODCA-VQA and SketchyQA. In order to test the robustness of the model. The organizer extended two variants of the dataset OODCV-Counterfactual and Sketchy-Challenging. There are several difficulties with these datasets. Firstly, the Sketchy-Challenging dataset uses some rarer item categories to test the model's generalization ability. Secondly, in the OODCV-Counterfactual dataset, the given problems often have inflection points and computational steps, requiring the model to recognize them during the inference process. In order to address this issue, we propose a simple yet effective approach called Object Detection Assistance Large Language Model(LLM) Counting Ability Improvement(ODAC), which focuses on using the object detection model to assist the LLM. To clarify, our approach contains two main blocks: (1)Object Detection Assistance. (2) Counterfactual Specific prompt. Our approach ranked second in the final test with a score of 0.86.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16287v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhouyang Chi, Qingyuan Jiang, Yang Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Biological Spatial Cluster Analysis with the Parallel Integral Image Technique</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16291</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16291v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Spatial cluster analysis (SCA) offers valuable insights into biological images; a common SCA technique is sliding window analysis (SWA). Unfortunately, SWA's computational cost hinders its application to larger images, limiting its use to small-scale images. With advancements in high-resolution microscopy, images now exceed the capabilities of previous SWA approaches, reaching sizes up to 70,000 by 85,000 pixels. To overcome these limitations, this paper introduces the parallel integral image approach to SWA, surpassing previous methods. We achieve a remarkable speedup of 131,806x on small-scale images and consistent speedups of over 10,000x on a variety of large-scale microscopy images. We analyze the computational complexity advantages of the parallel integral image approach and present experimental results that validate the superior performance of integral-image-based methods. Our approach is made available as an open-source Python PIP package available at https://github.com/OckermanSethGVSU/BioPII.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16291v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Seth Ockerman, Zachary Klamer, Brian Haab</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Object Detection with YOLOv4 for Real-Time Applications</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16320</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16320v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Object Detection is related to Computer Vision. Object detection enables detecting instances of objects in images and videos. Due to its increased utilization in surveillance, tracking system used in security and many others applications have propelled researchers to continuously derive more efficient and competitive algorithms. However, problems emerges while implementing it in real-time because of their dynamic environment and complex algorithms used in object detection. In the last few years, Convolution Neural Network (CNN) have emerged as a powerful tool for recognizing image content and in computer vision approach for most problems. In this paper, We revived begins the brief introduction of deep learning and object detection framework like Convolutional Neural Network(CNN), You only look once - version 4 (YOLOv4). Then we focus on our proposed object detection architectures along with some modifications. The traditional model detects a small object in images. We have some modifications to the model. Our proposed method gives the correct result with accuracy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16320v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>K. Senthil Kumar, K. M. B. Abdullah Safwan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Solution for Single Object Tracking Task of Perception Test Challenge 2024</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16329</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16329v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This report presents our method for Single Object Tracking (SOT), which aims to track a specified object throughout a video sequence. We employ the LoRAT method. The essence of the work lies in adapting LoRA, a technique that fine-tunes a small subset of model parameters without adding inference latency, to the domain of visual tracking. We train our model using the extensive LaSOT and GOT-10k datasets, which provide a solid foundation for robust performance. Additionally, we implement the alpha-refine technique for post-processing the bounding box outputs. Although the alpha-refine method does not yield the anticipated results, our overall approach achieves a score of 0.813, securing first place in the competition.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16329v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhiqiang Zhong, Yang Yang, Fengqiang Wan, Henglu Wei, Xiangyang Ji</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disambiguating Monocular Reconstruction of 3D Clothed Human with Spatial-Temporal Transformer</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16337</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16337v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Reconstructing 3D clothed humans from monocular camera data is highly challenging due to viewpoint limitations and image ambiguity. While implicit function-based approaches, combined with prior knowledge from parametric models, have made significant progress, there are still two notable problems. Firstly, the back details of human models are ambiguous due to viewpoint invisibility. The quality of the back details depends on the back normal map predicted by a convolutional neural network (CNN). However, the CNN lacks global information awareness for comprehending the back texture, resulting in excessively smooth back details. Secondly, a single image suffers from local ambiguity due to lighting conditions and body movement. However, implicit functions are highly sensitive to pixel variations in ambiguous regions. To address these ambiguities, we propose the Spatial-Temporal Transformer (STT) network for 3D clothed human reconstruction. A spatial transformer is employed to extract global information for normal map prediction. The establishment of global correlations facilitates the network in comprehending the holistic texture and shape of the human body. Simultaneously, to compensate for local ambiguity in images, a temporal transformer is utilized to extract temporal features from adjacent frames. The incorporation of temporal features can enhance the accuracy of input features in implicit networks. Furthermore, to obtain more accurate temporal features, joint tokens are employed to establish local correspondences between frames. Experimental results on the Adobe and MonoPerfCap datasets have shown that our method outperforms state-of-the-art methods and maintains robust generalization even under low-light outdoor conditions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16337v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yong Deng, Baoxing Li, Xu Zhao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joker: Conditional 3D Head Synthesis with Extreme Facial Expressions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16395</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16395v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We introduce Joker, a new method for the conditional synthesis of 3D human heads with extreme expressions. Given a single reference image of a person, we synthesize a volumetric human head with the reference identity and a new expression. We offer control over the expression via a 3D morphable model (3DMM) and textual inputs. This multi-modal conditioning signal is essential since 3DMMs alone fail to define subtle emotional changes and extreme expressions, including those involving the mouth cavity and tongue articulation. Our method is built upon a 2D diffusion-based prior that generalizes well to out-of-domain samples, such as sculptures, heavy makeup, and paintings while achieving high levels of expressiveness. To improve view consistency, we propose a new 3D distillation technique that converts predictions of our 2D prior into a neural radiance field (NeRF). Both the 2D prior and our distillation technique produce state-of-the-art results, which are confirmed by our extensive evaluations. Also, to the best of our knowledge, our method is the first to achieve view-consistent extreme tongue articulation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16395v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Malte Prinzler, Egor Zakharov, Vanessa Sklyarova, Berna Kabadayi, Justus Thies</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AttentionPainter: An Efficient and Adaptive Stroke Predictor for Scene Painting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16418</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16418v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Stroke-based Rendering (SBR) aims to decompose an input image into a sequence of parameterized strokes, which can be rendered into a painting that resembles the input image. Recently, Neural Painting methods that utilize deep learning and reinforcement learning models to predict the stroke sequences have been developed, but suffer from longer inference time or unstable training. To address these issues, we propose AttentionPainter, an efficient and adaptive model for single-step neural painting. First, we propose a novel scalable stroke predictor, which predicts a large number of stroke parameters within a single forward process, instead of the iterative prediction of previous Reinforcement Learning or auto-regressive methods, which makes AttentionPainter faster than previous neural painting methods. To further increase the training efficiency, we propose a Fast Stroke Stacking algorithm, which brings 13 times acceleration for training. Moreover, we propose Stroke-density Loss, which encourages the model to use small strokes for detailed information, to help improve the reconstruction quality. Finally, we propose a new stroke diffusion model for both conditional and unconditional stroke-based generation, which denoises in the stroke parameter space and facilitates stroke-based inpainting and editing applications helpful for human artists design. Extensive experiments show that AttentionPainter outperforms the state-of-the-art neural painting methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16418v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yizhe Tang, Yue Wang, Teng Hu, Ran Yi, Xin Tan, Lizhuang Ma, Yu-Kun Lai, Paul L. Rosin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HaHeAE: Learning Generalisable Joint Representations of Human Hand and Head Movements in Extended Reality</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16430</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16430v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Human hand and head movements are the most pervasive input modalities in extended reality (XR) and are significant for a wide range of applications. However, prior works on hand and head modelling in XR only explored a single modality or focused on specific applications. We present HaHeAE - a novel self-supervised method for learning generalisable joint representations of hand and head movements in XR. At the core of our method is an autoencoder (AE) that uses a graph convolutional network-based semantic encoder and a diffusion-based stochastic encoder to learn the joint semantic and stochastic representations of hand-head movements. It also features a diffusion-based decoder to reconstruct the original signals. Through extensive evaluations on three public XR datasets, we show that our method 1) significantly outperforms commonly used self-supervised methods by up to 74.0% in terms of reconstruction quality and is generalisable across users, activities, and XR environments, 2) enables new applications, including interpretable hand-head cluster identification and variable hand-head movement generation, and 3) can serve as an effective feature extractor for downstream tasks. Together, these results demonstrate the effectiveness of our method and underline the potential of self-supervised methods for jointly modelling hand-head behaviours in extended reality.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16430v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhiming Hu, Guanhua Zhang, Zheming Yin, Daniel Haeufle, Syn Schmitt, Andreas Bulling</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GenGMM: Generalized Gaussian-Mixture-based Domain Adaptation Model for Semantic Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16485</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16485v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Domain adaptive semantic segmentation is the task of generating precise and dense predictions for an unlabeled target domain using a model trained on a labeled source domain. While significant efforts have been devoted to improving unsupervised domain adaptation for this task, it is crucial to note that many models rely on a strong assumption that the source data is entirely and accurately labeled, while the target data is unlabeled. In real-world scenarios, however, we often encounter partially or noisy labeled data in source and target domains, referred to as Generalized Domain Adaptation (GDA). In such cases, we suggest leveraging weak or unlabeled data from both domains to narrow the gap between them, resulting in effective adaptation. We introduce the Generalized Gaussian-mixture-based (GenGMM) domain adaptation model, which harnesses the underlying data distribution in both domains to refine noisy weak and pseudo labels. The experiments demonstrate the effectiveness of our approach.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16485v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nazanin Moradinasab, Hassan Jafarzadeh, Donald E. Brown</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SINGAPO: Single Image Controlled Generation of Articulated Parts in Object</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16499</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16499v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We address the challenge of creating 3D assets for household articulated objects from a single image. Prior work on articulated object creation either requires multi-view multi-state input, or only allows coarse control over the generation process. These limitations hinder the scalability and practicality for articulated object modeling. In this work, we propose a method to generate articulated objects from a single image. Observing the object in resting state from an arbitrary view, our method generates an articulated object that is visually consistent with the input image. To capture the ambiguity in part shape and motion posed by a single view of the object, we design a diffusion model that learns the plausible variations of objects in terms of geometry and kinematics. To tackle the complexity of generating structured data with attributes in multiple domains, we design a pipeline that produces articulated objects from high-level structure to geometric details in a coarse-to-fine manner, where we use a part connectivity graph and part abstraction as proxies. Our experiments show that our method outperforms the state-of-the-art in articulated object creation by a large margin in terms of the generated object realism, resemblance to the input image, and reconstruction quality.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16499v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiayi Liu, Denys Iliash, Angel X. Chang, Manolis Savva, Ali Mahdavi-Amiri</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TIPS: Text-Image Pretraining with Spatial Awareness</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16512</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16512v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: While image-text representation learning has become very popular in recent years, existing models tend to lack spatial awareness and have limited direct applicability for dense understanding tasks. For this reason, self-supervised image-only pretraining is still the go-to method for many dense vision applications (e.g. depth estimation, semantic segmentation), despite the lack of explicit supervisory signals. In this paper, we close this gap between image-text and self-supervised learning, by proposing a novel general-purpose image-text model, which can be effectively used off-the-shelf for dense and global vision tasks. Our method, which we refer to as Text-Image Pretraining with Spatial awareness (TIPS), leverages two simple and effective insights. First, on textual supervision: we reveal that replacing noisy web image captions by synthetically generated textual descriptions boosts dense understanding performance significantly, due to a much richer signal for learning spatially aware representations. We propose an adapted training method that combines noisy and synthetic captions, resulting in improvements across both dense and global understanding tasks. Second, on the learning technique: we propose to combine contrastive image-text learning with self-supervised masked image modeling, to encourage spatial coherence, unlocking substantial enhancements for downstream applications. Building on these two ideas, we scale our model using the transformer architecture, trained on a curated set of public images. Our experiments are conducted on 8 tasks involving 16 datasets in total, demonstrating strong off-the-shelf performance on both dense and global understanding, for several image-only and image-text tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16512v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kevis-Kokitsi Maninis, Kaifeng Chen, Soham Ghosh, Arjun Karpur, Koert Chen, Ye Xia, Bingyi Cao, Daniel Salz, Guangxing Han, Jan Dlabal, Dan Gnanapragasam, Mojtaba Seyedhosseini, Howard Zhou, Andre Araujo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gradient-Free Supervised Learning using Spike-Timing-Dependent Plasticity for Image Recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16524</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16524v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: An approach to supervised learning in spiking neural networks is presented using a gradient-free method combined with spike-timing-dependent plasticity for image recognition. The proposed network architecture is scalable to multiple layers, enabling the development of more complex and deeper SNN models. The effectiveness of this method is demonstrated by its application to the MNIST dataset, showing good learning accuracy. The proposed method provides a robust and efficient alternative to the backpropagation-based method in supervised learning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16524v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>q-bio.NC</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wei Xie</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PlaneSAM: Multimodal Plane Instance Segmentation Using the Segment Anything Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16545</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16545v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Plane instance segmentation from RGB-D data is a crucial research topic for many downstream tasks. However, most existing deep-learning-based methods utilize only information within the RGB bands, neglecting the important role of the depth band in plane instance segmentation. Based on EfficientSAM, a fast version of SAM, we propose a plane instance segmentation network called PlaneSAM, which can fully integrate the information of the RGB bands (spectral bands) and the D band (geometric band), thereby improving the effectiveness of plane instance segmentation in a multimodal manner. Specifically, we use a dual-complexity backbone, with primarily the simpler branch learning D-band features and primarily the more complex branch learning RGB-band features. Consequently, the backbone can effectively learn D-band feature representations even when D-band training data is limited in scale, retain the powerful RGB-band feature representations of EfficientSAM, and allow the original backbone branch to be fine-tuned for the current task. To enhance the adaptability of our PlaneSAM to the RGB-D domain, we pretrain our dual-complexity backbone using the segment anything task on large-scale RGB-D data through a self-supervised pretraining strategy based on imperfect pseudo-labels. To support the segmentation of large planes, we optimize the loss function combination ratio of EfficientSAM. In addition, Faster R-CNN is used as a plane detector, and its predicted bounding boxes are fed into our dual-complexity network as prompts, thereby enabling fully automatic plane instance segmentation. Experimental results show that the proposed PlaneSAM sets a new SOTA performance on the ScanNet dataset, and outperforms previous SOTA approaches in zero-shot transfer on the 2D-3D-S, Matterport3D, and ICL-NUIM RGB-D datasets, while only incurring a 10% increase in computational overhead compared to EfficientSAM.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16545v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhongchen Deng, Zhechen Yang, Chi Chen, Cheng Zeng, Yan Meng, Bisheng Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Foundation Models for Remote Sensing and Earth Observation: A Survey</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16602</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16602v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Remote Sensing (RS) is a crucial technology for observing, monitoring, and interpreting our planet, with broad applications across geoscience, economics, humanitarian fields, etc. While artificial intelligence (AI), particularly deep learning, has achieved significant advances in RS, unique challenges persist in developing more intelligent RS systems, including the complexity of Earth's environments, diverse sensor modalities, distinctive feature patterns, varying spatial and spectral resolutions, and temporal dynamics. Meanwhile, recent breakthroughs in large Foundation Models (FMs) have expanded AI's potential across many domains due to their exceptional generalizability and zero-shot transfer capabilities. However, their success has largely been confined to natural data like images and video, with degraded performance and even failures for RS data of various non-optical modalities. This has inspired growing interest in developing Remote Sensing Foundation Models (RSFMs) to address the complex demands of Earth Observation (EO) tasks, spanning the surface, atmosphere, and oceans. This survey systematically reviews the emerging field of RSFMs. It begins with an outline of their motivation and background, followed by an introduction of their foundational concepts. It then categorizes and reviews existing RSFM studies including their datasets and technical contributions across Visual Foundation Models (VFMs), Visual-Language Models (VLMs), Large Language Models (LLMs), and beyond. In addition, we benchmark these models against publicly available datasets, discuss existing challenges, and propose future research directions in this rapidly evolving field.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16602v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aoran Xiao, Weihao Xuan, Junjue Wang, Jiaxing Huang, Dacheng Tao, Shijian Lu, Naoto Yokoya</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EVC-MF: End-to-end Video Captioning Network with Multi-scale Features</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16624</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16624v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Conventional approaches for video captioning leverage a variety of offline-extracted features to generate captions. Despite the availability of various offline-feature-extractors that offer diverse information from different perspectives, they have several limitations due to fixed parameters. Concretely, these extractors are solely pre-trained on image/video comprehension tasks, making them less adaptable to video caption datasets. Additionally, most of these extractors only capture features prior to the classifier of the pre-training task, ignoring a significant amount of valuable shallow information. Furthermore, employing multiple offline-features may introduce redundant information. To address these issues, we propose an end-to-end encoder-decoder-based network (EVC-MF) for video captioning, which efficiently utilizes multi-scale visual and textual features to generate video descriptions. Specifically, EVC-MF consists of three modules. Firstly, instead of relying on multiple feature extractors, we directly feed video frames into a transformer-based network to obtain multi-scale visual features and update feature extractor parameters. Secondly, we fuse the multi-scale features and input them into a masked encoder to reduce redundancy and encourage learning useful features. Finally, we utilize an enhanced transformer-based decoder, which can efficiently leverage shallow textual information, to generate video descriptions. To evaluate our proposed model, we conduct extensive experiments on benchmark datasets. The results demonstrate that EVC-MF yields competitive performance compared with the state-of-theart methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16624v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tian-Zi Niu, Zhen-Duo Chen, Xin Luo, Xin-Shun Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking Multi-Scene Fire and Smoke Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16631</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16631v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The current irregularities in existing public Fire and Smoke Detection (FSD) datasets have become a bottleneck in the advancement of FSD technology. Upon in-depth analysis, we identify the core issue as the lack of standardized dataset construction, uniform evaluation systems, and clear performance benchmarks. To address this issue and drive innovation in FSD technology, we systematically gather diverse resources from public sources to create a more comprehensive and refined FSD benchmark. Additionally, recognizing the inadequate coverage of existing dataset scenes, we strategically expand scenes, relabel, and standardize existing public FSD datasets to ensure accuracy and consistency. We aim to establish a standardized, realistic, unified, and efficient FSD research platform that mirrors real-life scenes closely. Through our efforts, we aim to provide robust support for the breakthrough and development of FSD technology. The project is available at \href{https://xiaoyihan6.github.io/FSD/}{https://xiaoyihan6.github.io/FSD/}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16631v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoyi Han, Nan Pu, Zunlei Feng, Yijun Bei, Qifei Zhang, Lechao Cheng, Liang Xue</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fire and Smoke Detection with Burning Intensity Representation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16642</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16642v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: An effective Fire and Smoke Detection (FSD) and analysis system is of paramount importance due to the destructive potential of fire disasters. However, many existing FSD methods directly employ generic object detection techniques without considering the transparency of fire and smoke, which leads to imprecise localization and reduces detection performance. To address this issue, a new Attentive Fire and Smoke Detection Model (a-FSDM) is proposed. This model not only retains the robust feature extraction and fusion capabilities of conventional detection algorithms but also redesigns the detection head specifically for transparent targets in FSD, termed the Attentive Transparency Detection Head (ATDH). In addition, Burning Intensity (BI) is introduced as a pivotal feature for fire-related downstream risk assessments in traditional FSD methodologies. Extensive experiments on multiple FSD datasets showcase the effectiveness and versatility of the proposed FSD model. The project is available at \href{https://xiaoyihan6.github.io/FSD/}{https://xiaoyihan6.github.io/FSD/}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16642v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoyi Han, Yanfei Wu, Nan Pu, Zunlei Feng, Qifei Zhang, Yijun Bei, Lechao Cheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TopoDiffusionNet: A Topology-aware Diffusion Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16646</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16646v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Diffusion models excel at creating visually impressive images but often struggle to generate images with a specified topology. The Betti number, which represents the number of structures in an image, is a fundamental measure in topology. Yet, diffusion models fail to satisfy even this basic constraint. This limitation restricts their utility in applications requiring exact control, like robotics and environmental modeling. To address this, we propose TopoDiffusionNet (TDN), a novel approach that enforces diffusion models to maintain the desired topology. We leverage tools from topological data analysis, particularly persistent homology, to extract the topological structures within an image. We then design a topology-based objective function to guide the denoising process, preserving intended structures while suppressing noisy ones. Our experiments across four datasets demonstrate significant improvements in topological accuracy. TDN is the first to integrate topology with diffusion models, opening new avenues of research in this area.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16646v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Saumya Gupta, Dimitris Samaras, Chao Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MPT: A Large-scale Multi-Phytoplankton Tracking Benchmark</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16695</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16695v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Phytoplankton are a crucial component of aquatic ecosystems, and effective monitoring of them can provide valuable insights into ocean environments and ecosystem changes. Traditional phytoplankton monitoring methods are often complex and lack timely analysis. Therefore, deep learning algorithms offer a promising approach for automated phytoplankton monitoring. However, the lack of large-scale, high-quality training samples has become a major bottleneck in advancing phytoplankton tracking. In this paper, we propose a challenging benchmark dataset, Multiple Phytoplankton Tracking (MPT), which covers diverse background information and variations in motion during observation. The dataset includes 27 species of phytoplankton and zooplankton, 14 different backgrounds to simulate diverse and complex underwater environments, and a total of 140 videos. To enable accurate real-time observation of phytoplankton, we introduce a multi-object tracking method, Deviation-Corrected Multi-Scale Feature Fusion Tracker(DSFT), which addresses issues such as focus shifts during tracking and the loss of small target information when computing frame-to-frame similarity. Specifically, we introduce an additional feature extractor to predict the residuals of the standard feature extractor's output, and compute multi-scale frame-to-frame similarity based on features from different layers of the extractor. Extensive experiments on the MPT have demonstrated the validity of the dataset and the superiority of DSFT in tracking phytoplankton, providing an effective solution for phytoplankton monitoring.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16695v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yang Yu, Yuezun Li, Xin Sun, Junyu Dong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DI-MaskDINO: A Joint Object Detection and Instance Segmentation Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16707</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16707v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper is motivated by an interesting phenomenon: the performance of object detection lags behind that of instance segmentation (i.e., performance imbalance) when investigating the intermediate results from the beginning transformer decoder layer of MaskDINO (i.e., the SOTA model for joint detection and segmentation). This phenomenon inspires us to think about a question: will the performance imbalance at the beginning layer of transformer decoder constrain the upper bound of the final performance? With this question in mind, we further conduct qualitative and quantitative pre-experiments, which validate the negative impact of detection-segmentation imbalance issue on the model performance. To address this issue, this paper proposes DI-MaskDINO model, the core idea of which is to improve the final performance by alleviating the detection-segmentation imbalance. DI-MaskDINO is implemented by configuring our proposed De-Imbalance (DI) module and Balance-Aware Tokens Optimization (BATO) module to MaskDINO. DI is responsible for generating balance-aware query, and BATO uses the balance-aware query to guide the optimization of the initial feature tokens. The balance-aware query and optimized feature tokens are respectively taken as the Query and Key&amp;Value of transformer decoder to perform joint object detection and instance segmentation. DI-MaskDINO outperforms existing joint object detection and instance segmentation models on COCO and BDD100K benchmarks, achieving +1.2 $AP^{box}$ and +0.9 $AP^{mask}$ improvements compared to SOTA joint detection and segmentation model MaskDINO. In addition, DI-MaskDINO also obtains +1.0 $AP^{box}$ improvement compared to SOTA object detection model DINO and +3.0 $AP^{mask}$ improvement compared to SOTA segmentation model Mask2Former.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16707v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhixiong Nan, Xianghong Li, Tao Xiang, Jifeng Dai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of CNN Architectures using Transfer Learning Methods for Medical Image Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16711</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16711v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The application of deep learning-based architecture has seen a tremendous rise in recent years. For example, medical image classification using deep learning achieved breakthrough results. Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs) are implemented predominantly in medical image classification and segmentation. On the other hand, transfer learning has emerged as a prominent supporting tool for enhancing the efficiency and accuracy of deep learning models. This paper investigates the development of CNN architectures using transfer learning techniques in the field of medical image classification using a timeline mapping model for key image classification challenges. Our findings help make an informed decision while selecting the optimum and state-of-the-art CNN architectures.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16711v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ganga Prasad Basyal, David Zeng, Bhaskar Pm Rimal</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progressive Compositionality In Text-to-Image Generative Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16719</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16719v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Despite the impressive text-to-image (T2I) synthesis capabilities of diffusion models, they often struggle to understand compositional relationships between objects and attributes, especially in complex settings. Existing solutions have tackled these challenges by optimizing the cross-attention mechanism or learning from the caption pairs with minimal semantic changes. However, can we generate high-quality complex contrastive images that diffusion models can directly discriminate based on visual representations? In this work, we leverage large-language models (LLMs) to compose realistic, complex scenarios and harness Visual-Question Answering (VQA) systems alongside diffusion models to automatically curate a contrastive dataset, ConPair, consisting of 15k pairs of high-quality contrastive images. These pairs feature minimal visual discrepancies and cover a wide range of attribute categories, especially complex and natural scenarios. To learn effectively from these error cases, i.e., hard negative images, we propose EvoGen, a new multi-stage curriculum for contrastive learning of diffusion models. Through extensive experiments across a wide range of compositional scenarios, we showcase the effectiveness of our proposed framework on compositional T2I benchmarks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16719v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xu Han, Linghao Jin, Xiaofeng Liu, Paul Pu Liang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polyp-E: Benchmarking the Robustness of Deep Segmentation Models via Polyp Editing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16732</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16732v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Automatic polyp segmentation is helpful to assist clinical diagnosis and treatment. In daily clinical practice, clinicians exhibit robustness in identifying polyps with both location and size variations. It is uncertain if deep segmentation models can achieve comparable robustness in automated colonoscopic analysis. To benchmark the model robustness, we focus on evaluating the robustness of segmentation models on the polyps with various attributes (e.g. location and size) and healthy samples. Based on the Latent Diffusion Model, we perform attribute editing on real polyps and build a new dataset named Polyp-E. Our synthetic dataset boasts exceptional realism, to the extent that clinical experts find it challenging to discern them from real data. We evaluate several existing polyp segmentation models on the proposed benchmark. The results reveal most of the models are highly sensitive to attribute variations. As a novel data augmentation technique, the proposed editing pipeline can improve both in-distribution and out-of-distribution generalization ability. The code and datasets will be released.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16732v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Runpu Wei, Zijin Yin, Kongming Liang, Min Min, Chengwei Pan, Gang Yu, Haonan Huang, Yan Liu, Zhanyu Ma</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time-Resolved MNIST Dataset for Single-Photon Recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16744</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16744v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Time-resolved single photon imaging is a promising imaging modality characterized by the unique capability of timestamping the arrivals of single photons. Single-Photon Avalanche Diodes (SPADs) are the leading technology for implementing modern time-resolved pixels, suitable for passive imaging with asynchronous readout. However, they are currently limited to small sized arrays, thus there is a lack of datasets for passive time-resolved SPAD imaging, which in turn hinders research on this peculiar imaging data. In this paper we describe a realistic simulation process for SPAD imaging, which takes into account both the stochastic nature of photon arrivals and all the noise sources involved in the acquisition process of time-resolved SPAD arrays. We have implemented this simulator in a software prototype able to generate arbitrary-sized time-resolved SPAD arrays operating in passive mode. Starting from a reference image, our simulator generates a realistic stream of timestamped photon detections. We use our simulator to generate a time-resolved version of MNIST, which we make publicly available. Our dataset has the purpose of encouraging novel research directions in time-resolved SPAD imaging, as well as investigating the performance of CNN classifiers in extremely low-light conditions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16744v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>physics.ins-det</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aleksi Suonsivu, Lauri Salmela, Edoardo Peretti, Leevi Uosukainen, Radu Ciprian Bilcu, Giacomo Boracchi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SpikMamba: When SNN meets Mamba in Event-based Human Action Recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16746</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16746v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Human action recognition (HAR) plays a key role in various applications such as video analysis, surveillance, autonomous driving, robotics, and healthcare. Most HAR algorithms are developed from RGB images, which capture detailed visual information. However, these algorithms raise concerns in privacy-sensitive environments due to the recording of identifiable features. Event cameras offer a promising solution by capturing scene brightness changes sparsely at the pixel level, without capturing full images. Moreover, event cameras have high dynamic ranges that can effectively handle scenarios with complex lighting conditions, such as low light or high contrast environments. However, using event cameras introduces challenges in modeling the spatially sparse and high temporal resolution event data for HAR. To address these issues, we propose the SpikMamba framework, which combines the energy efficiency of spiking neural networks and the long sequence modeling capability of Mamba to efficiently capture global features from spatially sparse and high a temporal resolution event data. Additionally, to improve the locality of modeling, a spiking window-based linear attention mechanism is used. Extensive experiments show that SpikMamba achieves remarkable recognition performance, surpassing the previous state-of-the-art by 1.45%, 7.22%, 0.15%, and 3.92% on the PAF, HARDVS, DVS128, and E-FAction datasets, respectively. The code is available at https://github.com/Typistchen/SpikMamba.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16746v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiaqi Chen, Yan Yang, Shizhuo Deng, Da Teng, Liyuan Pan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DSORT-MCU: Detecting Small Objects in Real-Time on Microcontroller Units</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16769</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16769v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Advances in lightweight neural networks have revolutionized computer vision in a broad range of IoT applications, encompassing remote monitoring and process automation. However, the detection of small objects, which is crucial for many of these applications, remains an underexplored area in current computer vision research, particularly for low-power embedded devices that host resource-constrained processors. To address said gap, this paper proposes an adaptive tiling method for lightweight and energy-efficient object detection networks, including YOLO-based models and the popular FOMO network. The proposed tiling enables object detection on low-power MCUs with no compromise on accuracy compared to large-scale detection models. The benefit of the proposed method is demonstrated by applying it to FOMO and TinyissimoYOLO networks on a novel RISC-V-based MCU with built-in ML accelerators. Extensive experimental results show that the proposed tiling method boosts the F1-score by up to 225% for both FOMO and TinyissimoYOLO networks while reducing the average object count error by up to 76% with FOMO and up to 89% for TinyissimoYOLO. Furthermore, the findings of this work indicate that using a soft F1 loss over the popular binary cross-entropy loss can serve as an implicit non-maximum suppression for the FOMO network. To evaluate the real-world performance, the networks are deployed on the RISC-V based GAP9 microcontroller from GreenWaves Technologies, showcasing the proposed method's ability to strike a balance between detection performance ($58% - 95%$ F1 score), low latency (0.6 ms/Inference - 16.2 ms/Inference}), and energy efficiency (31 uJ/Inference} - 1.27 mJ/Inference) while performing multiple predictions using high-resolution images on a MCU.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16769v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1109/JSEN.2024.3425904</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Liam Boyle, Julian Moosmann, Nicolas Baumann, Seonyeong Heo, Michele Magno</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Scene Language: Representing Scenes with Programs, Words, and Embeddings</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16770</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16770v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We introduce the Scene Language, a visual scene representation that concisely and precisely describes the structure, semantics, and identity of visual scenes. It represents a scene with three key components: a program that specifies the hierarchical and relational structure of entities in the scene, words in natural language that summarize the semantic class of each entity, and embeddings that capture the visual identity of each entity. This representation can be inferred from pre-trained language models via a training-free inference technique, given text or image inputs. The resulting scene can be rendered into images using traditional, neural, or hybrid graphics renderers. Together, this forms a robust, automated system for high-quality 3D and 4D scene generation. Compared with existing representations like scene graphs, our proposed Scene Language generates complex scenes with higher fidelity, while explicitly modeling the scene structures to enable precise control and editing.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16770v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yunzhi Zhang, Zizhang Li, Matt Zhou, Shangzhe Wu, Jiajun Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-Step Diffusion Distillation through Score Implicit Matching</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16794</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16794v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Despite their strong performances on many generative tasks, diffusion models require a large number of sampling steps in order to generate realistic samples. This has motivated the community to develop effective methods to distill pre-trained diffusion models into more efficient models, but these methods still typically require few-step inference or perform substantially worse than the underlying model. In this paper, we present Score Implicit Matching (SIM) a new approach to distilling pre-trained diffusion models into single-step generator models, while maintaining almost the same sample generation ability as the original model as well as being data-free with no need of training samples for distillation. The method rests upon the fact that, although the traditional score-based loss is intractable to minimize for generator models, under certain conditions we can efficiently compute the gradients for a wide class of score-based divergences between a diffusion model and a generator. SIM shows strong empirical performances for one-step generators: on the CIFAR10 dataset, it achieves an FID of 2.06 for unconditional generation and 1.96 for class-conditional generation. Moreover, by applying SIM to a leading transformer-based diffusion model, we distill a single-step generator for text-to-image (T2I) generation that attains an aesthetic score of 6.42 with no performance decline over the original multi-step counterpart, clearly outperforming the other one-step generators including SDXL-TURBO of 5.33, SDXL-LIGHTNING of 5.34 and HYPER-SDXL of 5.85. We will release this industry-ready one-step transformer-based T2I generator along with this paper.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16794v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>NeurIPS 2024</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Weijian Luo, Zemin Huang, Zhengyang Geng, J. Zico Kolter, Guo-jun Qi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the Effectiveness of Attack-Agnostic Features for Morphing Attack Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16802</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16802v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Morphing attacks have diversified significantly over the past years, with new methods based on generative adversarial networks (GANs) and diffusion models posing substantial threats to face recognition systems. Recent research has demonstrated the effectiveness of features extracted from large vision models pretrained on bonafide data only (attack-agnostic features) for detecting deep generative images. Building on this, we investigate the potential of these image representations for morphing attack detection (MAD). We develop supervised detectors by training a simple binary linear SVM on the extracted features and one-class detectors by modeling the distribution of bonafide features with a Gaussian Mixture Model (GMM). Our method is evaluated across a comprehensive set of attacks and various scenarios, including generalization to unseen attacks, different source datasets, and print-scan data. Our results indicate that attack-agnostic features can effectively detect morphing attacks, outperforming traditional supervised and one-class detectors from the literature in most scenarios. Additionally, we provide insights into the strengths and limitations of each considered representation and discuss potential future research directions to further enhance the robustness and generalizability of our approach.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16802v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Laurent Colbois, S\'ebastien Marcel</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AttriPrompter: Auto-Prompting with Attribute Semantics for Zero-shot Nuclei Detection via Visual-Language Pre-trained Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16820</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16820v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large-scale visual-language pre-trained models (VLPMs) have demonstrated exceptional performance in downstream object detection through text prompts for natural scenes. However, their application to zero-shot nuclei detection on histopathology images remains relatively unexplored, mainly due to the significant gap between the characteristics of medical images and the web-originated text-image pairs used for pre-training. This paper aims to investigate the potential of the object-level VLPM, Grounded Language-Image Pre-training (GLIP), for zero-shot nuclei detection. Specifically, we propose an innovative auto-prompting pipeline, named AttriPrompter, comprising attribute generation, attribute augmentation, and relevance sorting, to avoid subjective manual prompt design. AttriPrompter utilizes VLPMs' text-to-image alignment to create semantically rich text prompts, which are then fed into GLIP for initial zero-shot nuclei detection. Additionally, we propose a self-trained knowledge distillation framework, where GLIP serves as the teacher with its initial predictions used as pseudo labels, to address the challenges posed by high nuclei density, including missed detections, false positives, and overlapping instances. Our method exhibits remarkable performance in label-free nuclei detection, outperforming all existing unsupervised methods and demonstrating excellent generality. Notably, this work highlights the astonishing potential of VLPMs pre-trained on natural image-text pairs for downstream tasks in the medical field as well. Code will be released at https://github.com/wuyongjianCODE/AttriPrompter.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16820v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1109/TMI.2024.3473745</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Yongjian Wu, Yang Zhou, Jiya Saiyin, Bingzheng Wei, Maode Lai, Jianzhong Shou, Yan Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PerspectiveNet: Multi-View Perception for Dynamic Scene Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16824</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16824v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Generating detailed descriptions from multiple cameras and viewpoints is challenging due to the complex and inconsistent nature of visual data. In this paper, we introduce PerspectiveNet, a lightweight yet efficient model for generating long descriptions across multiple camera views. Our approach utilizes a vision encoder, a compact connector module to convert visual features into a fixed-size tensor, and large language models (LLMs) to harness the strong natural language generation capabilities of LLMs. The connector module is designed with three main goals: mapping visual features onto LLM embeddings, emphasizing key information needed for description generation, and producing a fixed-size feature matrix. Additionally, we augment our solution with a secondary task, the correct frame sequence detection, enabling the model to search for the correct sequence of frames to generate descriptions. Finally, we integrate the connector module, the secondary task, the LLM, and a visual feature extraction model into a single architecture, which is trained for the Traffic Safety Description and Analysis task. This task requires generating detailed, fine-grained descriptions of events from multiple cameras and viewpoints. The resulting model is lightweight, ensuring efficient training and inference, while remaining highly effective.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16824v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Vinh Nguyen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MPDS: A Movie Posters Dataset for Image Generation with Diffusion Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16840</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16840v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Movie posters are vital for captivating audiences, conveying themes, and driving market competition in the film industry. While traditional designs are laborious, intelligent generation technology offers efficiency gains and design enhancements. Despite exciting progress in image generation, current models often fall short in producing satisfactory poster results. The primary issue lies in the absence of specialized poster datasets for targeted model training. In this work, we propose a Movie Posters DataSet (MPDS), tailored for text-to-image generation models to revolutionize poster production. As dedicated to posters, MPDS stands out as the first image-text pair dataset to our knowledge, composing of 373k+ image-text pairs and 8k+ actor images (covering 4k+ actors). Detailed poster descriptions, such as movie titles, genres, casts, and synopses, are meticulously organized and standardized based on public movie synopsis, also named movie-synopsis prompt. To bolster poster descriptions as well as reduce differences from movie synopsis, further, we leverage a large-scale vision-language model to automatically produce vision-perceptive prompts for each poster, then perform manual rectification and integration with movie-synopsis prompt. In addition, we introduce a prompt of poster captions to exhibit text elements in posters like actor names and movie titles. For movie poster generation, we develop a multi-condition diffusion framework that takes poster prompt, poster caption, and actor image (for personalization) as inputs, yielding excellent results through the learning of a diffusion model. Experiments demonstrate the valuable role of our proposed MPDS dataset in advancing personalized movie poster generation. MPDS is available at https://anonymous.4open.science/r/MPDS-373k-BD3B.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16840v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Meng Xu (Nanjing University of Science and Technology, Nanjing, China), Tong Zhang (Nanjing University of Science and Technology, Nanjing, China), Fuyun Wang (Nanjing University of Science and Technology, Nanjing, China), Yi Lei (Nanjing University of Science and Technology, Nanjing, China), Xin Liu (SeetaCloud, Nanjing, China), Zhen Cui (Nanjing University of Science and Technology, Nanjing, China)</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the Modality Gap: Dimension Information Alignment and Sparse Spatial Constraint for Image-Text Matching</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16853</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16853v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Many contrastive learning based models have achieved advanced performance in image-text matching tasks. The key of these models lies in analyzing the correlation between image-text pairs, which involves cross-modal interaction of embeddings in corresponding dimensions. However, the embeddings of different modalities are from different models or modules, and there is a significant modality gap. Directly interacting such embeddings lacks rationality and may capture inaccurate correlation. Therefore, we propose a novel method called DIAS to bridge the modality gap from two aspects: (1) We align the information representation of embeddings from different modalities in corresponding dimension to ensure the correlation calculation is based on interactions of similar information. (2) The spatial constraints of inter- and intra-modalities unmatched pairs are introduced to ensure the effectiveness of semantic alignment of the model. Besides, a sparse correlation algorithm is proposed to select strong correlated spatial relationships, enabling the model to learn more significant features and avoid being misled by weak correlation. Extensive experiments demonstrate the superiority of DIAS, achieving 4.3\%-10.2\% rSum improvements on Flickr30k and MSCOCO benchmarks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16853v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiang Ma, Xuemei Li, Lexin Fang, Caiming Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Network Inversion for Training-Like Data Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16884</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16884v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Machine Learning models are often trained on proprietary and private data that cannot be shared, though the trained models themselves are distributed openly assuming that sharing model weights is privacy preserving, as training data is not expected to be inferred from the model weights. In this paper, we present Training-Like Data Reconstruction (TLDR), a network inversion-based approach to reconstruct training-like data from trained models. To begin with, we introduce a comprehensive network inversion technique that learns the input space corresponding to different classes in the classifier using a single conditioned generator. While inversion may typically return random and arbitrary input images for a given output label, we modify the inversion process to incentivize the generator to reconstruct training-like data by exploiting key properties of the classifier with respect to the training data along with some prior knowledge about the images. To validate our approach, we conduct empirical evaluations on multiple standard vision classification datasets, thereby highlighting the potential privacy risks involved in sharing machine learning models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16884v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Pirzada Suhail, Amit Sethi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VistaDream: Sampling multiview consistent images for single-view scene reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16892</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16892v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this paper, we propose VistaDream a novel framework to reconstruct a 3D scene from a single-view image. Recent diffusion models enable generating high-quality novel-view images from a single-view input image. Most existing methods only concentrate on building the consistency between the input image and the generated images while losing the consistency between the generated images. VistaDream addresses this problem by a two-stage pipeline. In the first stage, VistaDream begins with building a global coarse 3D scaffold by zooming out a little step with inpainted boundaries and an estimated depth map. Then, on this global scaffold, we use iterative diffusion-based RGB-D inpainting to generate novel-view images to inpaint the holes of the scaffold. In the second stage, we further enhance the consistency between the generated novel-view images by a novel training-free Multiview Consistency Sampling (MCS) that introduces multi-view consistency constraints in the reverse sampling process of diffusion models. Experimental results demonstrate that without training or fine-tuning existing diffusion models, VistaDream achieves consistent and high-quality novel view synthesis using just single-view images and outperforms baseline methods by a large margin. The code, videos, and interactive demos are available at https://vistadream-project-page.github.io/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16892v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haiping Wang, Yuan Liu, Ziwei Liu, Wenping Wang, Zhen Dong, Bisheng Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Generalization in Convolutional Neural Networks through Regularization with Edge and Line Features</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16897</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16897v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper proposes a novel regularization approach to bias Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs) toward utilizing edge and line features in their hidden layers. Rather than learning arbitrary kernels, we constrain the convolution layers to edge and line detection kernels. This intentional bias regularizes the models, improving generalization performance, especially on small datasets. As a result, test accuracies improve by margins of 5-11 percentage points across four challenging fine-grained classification datasets with limited training data and an identical number of trainable parameters. Instead of traditional convolutional layers, we use Pre-defined Filter Modules, which convolve input data using a fixed set of 3x3 pre-defined edge and line filters. A subsequent ReLU erases information that did not trigger any positive response. Next, a 1x1 convolutional layer generates linear combinations. Notably, the pre-defined filters are a fixed component of the architecture, remaining unchanged during the training phase. Our findings reveal that the number of dimensions spanned by the set of pre-defined filters has a low impact on recognition performance. However, the size of the set of filters matters, with nine or more filters providing optimal results.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16897v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1007/978-3-031-72332-2_28</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Artificial Neural Networks and Machine Learning - ICANN 2024, Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol 15016. Springer</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Christoph Linse, Beatrice Br\"uckner, Thomas Martinetz</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mitigating Vanishing Activations in Deep CapsNets Using Channel Pruning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16908</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16908v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Capsule Networks outperform Convolutional Neural Networks in learning the part-whole relationships with viewpoint invariance, and the credit goes to their multidimensional capsules. It was assumed that increasing the number of capsule layers in the capsule networks would enhance the model performance. However, recent studies found that Capsule Networks lack scalability due to vanishing activations in the capsules of deeper layers. This paper thoroughly investigates the vanishing activation problem in deep Capsule Networks. To analyze this issue and understand how increasing capsule dimensions can facilitate deeper networks, various Capsule Network models are constructed and evaluated with different numbers of capsules, capsule dimensions, and intermediate layers for this paper. Unlike traditional model pruning, which reduces the number of model parameters and expedites model training, this study uses pruning to mitigate the vanishing activations in the deeper capsule layers. In addition, the backbone network and capsule layers are pruned with different pruning ratios to reduce the number of inactive capsules and achieve better model accuracy than the unpruned models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16908v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Siddharth Sahu, Abdulrahman Altahhan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Clustering for Conditional Diffusion in Image Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16910</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16910v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Finding clusters of data points with similar characteristics and generating new cluster-specific samples can significantly enhance our understanding of complex data distributions. While clustering has been widely explored using Variational Autoencoders, these models often lack generation quality in real-world datasets. This paper addresses this gap by introducing TreeDiffusion, a deep generative model that conditions Diffusion Models on hierarchical clusters to obtain high-quality, cluster-specific generations. The proposed pipeline consists of two steps: a VAE-based clustering model that learns the hierarchical structure of the data, and a conditional diffusion model that generates realistic images for each cluster. We propose this two-stage process to ensure that the generated samples remain representative of their respective clusters and enhance image fidelity to the level of diffusion models. A key strength of our method is its ability to create images for each cluster, providing better visualization of the learned representations by the clustering model, as demonstrated through qualitative results. This method effectively addresses the generative limitations of VAE-based approaches while preserving their clustering performance. Empirically, we demonstrate that conditioning diffusion models on hierarchical clusters significantly enhances generative performance, thereby advancing the state of generative clustering models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16910v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jorge da Silva Goncalves, Laura Manduchi, Moritz Vandenhirtz, Julia E. Vogt</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LIMIS: Towards Language-based Interactive Medical Image Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16939</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16939v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Within this work, we introduce LIMIS: The first purely language-based interactive medical image segmentation model. We achieve this by adapting Grounded SAM to the medical domain and designing a language-based model interaction strategy that allows radiologists to incorporate their knowledge into the segmentation process. LIMIS produces high-quality initial segmentation masks by leveraging medical foundation models and allows users to adapt segmentation masks using only language, opening up interactive segmentation to scenarios where physicians require using their hands for other tasks. We evaluate LIMIS on three publicly available medical datasets in terms of performance and usability with experts from the medical domain confirming its high-quality segmentation masks and its interactive usability.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16939v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lena Heinemann, Alexander Jaus, Zdravko Marinov, Moon Kim, Maria Francesca Spadea, Jens Kleesiek, Rainer Stiefelhagen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DiP-GO: A Diffusion Pruner via Few-step Gradient Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16942</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16942v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Diffusion models have achieved remarkable progress in the field of image generation due to their outstanding capabilities. However, these models require substantial computing resources because of the multi-step denoising process during inference. While traditional pruning methods have been employed to optimize these models, the retraining process necessitates large-scale training datasets and extensive computational costs to maintain generalization ability, making it neither convenient nor efficient. Recent studies attempt to utilize the similarity of features across adjacent denoising stages to reduce computational costs through simple and static strategies. However, these strategies cannot fully harness the potential of the similar feature patterns across adjacent timesteps. In this work, we propose a novel pruning method that derives an efficient diffusion model via a more intelligent and differentiable pruner. At the core of our approach is casting the model pruning process into a SubNet search process. Specifically, we first introduce a SuperNet based on standard diffusion via adding some backup connections built upon the similar features. We then construct a plugin pruner network and design optimization losses to identify redundant computation. Finally, our method can identify an optimal SubNet through few-step gradient optimization and a simple post-processing procedure. We conduct extensive experiments on various diffusion models including Stable Diffusion series and DiTs. Our DiP-GO approach achieves 4.4 x speedup for SD-1.5 without any loss of accuracy, significantly outperforming the previous state-of-the-art methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16942v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haowei Zhu, Dehua Tang, Ji Liu, Mingjie Lu, Jintu Zheng, Jinzhang Peng, Dong Li, Yu Wang, Fan Jiang, Lu Tian, Spandan Tiwari, Ashish Sirasao, Jun-Hai Yong, Bin Wang, Emad Barsoum</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ISImed: A Framework for Self-Supervised Learning using Intrinsic Spatial Information in Medical Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16947</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16947v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper demonstrates that spatial information can be used to learn interpretable representations in medical images using Self-Supervised Learning (SSL). Our proposed method, ISImed, is based on the observation that medical images exhibit a much lower variability among different images compared to classic data vision benchmarks. By leveraging this resemblance of human body structures across multiple images, we establish a self-supervised objective that creates a latent representation capable of capturing its location in the physical realm. More specifically, our method involves sampling image crops and creating a distance matrix that compares the learned representation vectors of all possible combinations of these crops to the true distance between them. The intuition is, that the learned latent space is a positional encoding for a given image crop. We hypothesize, that by learning these positional encodings, comprehensive image representations have to be generated. To test this hypothesis and evaluate our method, we compare our learned representation with two state-of-the-art SSL benchmarking methods on two publicly available medical imaging datasets. We show that our method can efficiently learn representations that capture the underlying structure of the data and can be used to transfer to a downstream classification task.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16947v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nabil Jabareen, Dongsheng Yuan, S\"oren Lukassen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Real Zero-Shot Camouflaged Object Segmentation without Camouflaged Annotations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16953</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16953v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Camouflaged Object Segmentation (COS) faces significant challenges due to the scarcity of annotated data, where meticulous pixel-level annotation is both labor-intensive and costly, primarily due to the intricate object-background boundaries. Addressing the core question, "Can COS be effectively achieved in a zero-shot manner without manual annotations for any camouflaged object?" we affirmatively respond and introduce a robust zero-shot COS framework. This framework leverages the inherent local pattern bias of COS and employs a broad semantic feature space derived from salient object segmentation (SOS) for efficient zero-shot transfer. We incorporate an Masked Image Modeling (MIM) based image encoder optimized for Parameter-Efficient Fine-Tuning (PEFT), a Multimodal Large Language Model (M-LLM), and a Multi-scale Fine-grained Alignment (MFA) mechanism. The MIM pre-trained image encoder focuses on capturing essential low-level features, while the M-LLM generates caption embeddings processed alongside these visual cues. These embeddings are precisely aligned using MFA, enabling our framework to accurately interpret and navigate complex semantic contexts. To optimize operational efficiency, we introduce a learnable codebook that represents the M-LLM during inference, significantly reducing computational overhead. Our framework demonstrates its versatility and efficacy through rigorous experimentation, achieving state-of-the-art performance in zero-shot COS with $F_{\beta}^w$ scores of 72.9\% on CAMO and 71.7\% on COD10K. By removing the M-LLM during inference, we achieve an inference speed comparable to that of traditional end-to-end models, reaching 18.1 FPS. Code: https://github.com/R-LEI360725/ZSCOS-CaMF</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16953v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Cheng Lei, Jie Fan, Xinran Li, Tianzhu Xiang, Ao Li, Ce Zhu, Le Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PGCS: Physical Law embedded Generative Cloud Synthesis in Remote Sensing Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16955</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16955v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Data quantity and quality are both critical for information extraction and analyzation in remote sensing. However, the current remote sensing datasets often fail to meet these two requirements, for which cloud is a primary factor degrading the data quantity and quality. This limitation affects the precision of results in remote sensing application, particularly those derived from data-driven techniques. In this paper, a physical law embedded generative cloud synthesis method (PGCS) is proposed to generate diverse realistic cloud images to enhance real data and promote the development of algorithms for subsequent tasks, such as cloud correction, cloud detection, and data augmentation for classification, recognition, and segmentation. The PGCS method involves two key phases: spatial synthesis and spectral synthesis. In the spatial synthesis phase, a style-based generative adversarial network is utilized to simulate the spatial characteristics, generating an infinite number of single-channel clouds. In the spectral synthesis phase, the atmospheric scattering law is embedded through a local statistics and global fitting method, converting the single-channel clouds into multi-spectral clouds. The experimental results demonstrate that PGCS achieves a high accuracy in both phases and performs better than three other existing cloud synthesis methods. Two cloud correction methods are developed from PGCS and exhibits a superior performance compared to state-of-the-art methods in the cloud correction task. Furthermore, the application of PGCS with data from various sensors was investigated and successfully extended. Code will be provided at https://github.com/Liying-Xu/PGCS.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16955v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Liying Xu, Huifang Li, Huanfeng Shen, Mingyang Lei, Tao Jiang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leaky ReLUs That Differ in Forward and Backward Pass Facilitate Activation Maximization in Deep Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16958</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16958v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Activation maximization (AM) strives to generate optimal input stimuli, revealing features that trigger high responses in trained deep neural networks. AM is an important method of explainable AI. We demonstrate that AM fails to produce optimal input stimuli for simple functions containing ReLUs or Leaky ReLUs, casting doubt on the practical usefulness of AM and the visual interpretation of the generated images. This paper proposes a solution based on using Leaky ReLUs with a high negative slope in the backward pass while keeping the original, usually zero, slope in the forward pass. The approach significantly increases the maxima found by AM. The resulting ProxyGrad algorithm implements a novel optimization technique for neural networks that employs a secondary network as a proxy for gradient computation. This proxy network is designed to have a simpler loss landscape with fewer local maxima than the original network. Our chosen proxy network is an identical copy of the original network, including its weights, with distinct negative slopes in the Leaky ReLUs. Moreover, we show that ProxyGrad can be used to train the weights of Convolutional Neural Networks for classification such that, on some of the tested benchmarks, they outperform traditional networks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16958v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1109/IJCNN60899.2024.10650881</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>2024 International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN)</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Christoph Linse, Erhardt Barth, Thomas Martinetz</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>E-3DGS: Gaussian Splatting with Exposure and Motion Events</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16995</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16995v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Estimating Neural Radiance Fields (NeRFs) from images captured under optimal conditions has been extensively explored in the vision community. However, robotic applications often face challenges such as motion blur, insufficient illumination, and high computational overhead, which adversely affect downstream tasks like navigation, inspection, and scene visualization. To address these challenges, we propose E-3DGS, a novel event-based approach that partitions events into motion (from camera or object movement) and exposure (from camera exposure), using the former to handle fast-motion scenes and using the latter to reconstruct grayscale images for high-quality training and optimization of event-based 3D Gaussian Splatting (3DGS). We introduce a novel integration of 3DGS with exposure events for high-quality reconstruction of explicit scene representations. Our versatile framework can operate on motion events alone for 3D reconstruction, enhance quality using exposure events, or adopt a hybrid mode that balances quality and effectiveness by optimizing with initial exposure events followed by high-speed motion events. We also introduce EME-3D, a real-world 3D dataset with exposure events, motion events, camera calibration parameters, and sparse point clouds. Our method is faster and delivers better reconstruction quality than event-based NeRF while being more cost-effective than NeRF methods that combine event and RGB data by using a single event sensor. By combining motion and exposure events, E-3DGS sets a new benchmark for event-based 3D reconstruction with robust performance in challenging conditions and lower hardware demands. The source code and dataset will be available at https://github.com/MasterHow/E-3DGS.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16995v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoting Yin, Hao Shi, Yuhan Bao, Zhenshan Bing, Yiyi Liao, Kailun Yang, Kaiwei Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AGSENet: A Robust Road Ponding Detection Method for Proactive Traffic Safety</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16999</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16999v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Road ponding, a prevalent traffic hazard, poses a serious threat to road safety by causing vehicles to lose control and leading to accidents ranging from minor fender benders to severe collisions. Existing technologies struggle to accurately identify road ponding due to complex road textures and variable ponding coloration influenced by reflection characteristics. To address this challenge, we propose a novel approach called Self-Attention-based Global Saliency-Enhanced Network (AGSENet) for proactive road ponding detection and traffic safety improvement. AGSENet incorporates saliency detection techniques through the Channel Saliency Information Focus (CSIF) and Spatial Saliency Information Enhancement (SSIE) modules. The CSIF module, integrated into the encoder, employs self-attention to highlight similar features by fusing spatial and channel information. The SSIE module, embedded in the decoder, refines edge features and reduces noise by leveraging correlations across different feature levels. To ensure accurate and reliable evaluation, we corrected significant mislabeling and missing annotations in the Puddle-1000 dataset. Additionally, we constructed the Foggy-Puddle and Night-Puddle datasets for road ponding detection in low-light and foggy conditions, respectively. Experimental results demonstrate that AGSENet outperforms existing methods, achieving IoU improvements of 2.03\%, 0.62\%, and 1.06\% on the Puddle-1000, Foggy-Puddle, and Night-Puddle datasets, respectively, setting a new state-of-the-art in this field. Finally, we verified the algorithm's reliability on edge computing devices. This work provides a valuable reference for proactive warning research in road traffic safety.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16999v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ronghui Zhang, Shangyu Yang, Dakang Lyu, Zihan Wang, Junzhou Chen, Yilong Ren, Bolin Gao, Zhihan Lv</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joint Point Cloud Upsampling and Cleaning with Octree-based CNNs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.17001</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.17001v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recovering dense and uniformly distributed point clouds from sparse or noisy data remains a significant challenge. Recently, great progress has been made on these tasks, but usually at the cost of increasingly intricate modules or complicated network architectures, leading to long inference time and huge resource consumption. Instead, we embrace simplicity and present a simple yet efficient method for jointly upsampling and cleaning point clouds. Our method leverages an off-the-shelf octree-based 3D U-Net (OUNet) with minor modifications, enabling the upsampling and cleaning tasks within a single network. Our network directly processes each input point cloud as a whole instead of processing each point cloud patch as in previous works, which significantly eases the implementation and brings at least 47 times faster inference. Extensive experiments demonstrate that our method achieves state-of-the-art performances under huge efficiency advantages on a series of benchmarks. We expect our method to serve simple baselines and inspire researchers to rethink the method design on point cloud upsampling and cleaning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.17001v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jihe Li, Bo Pang, Peng-Shuai Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPVSoAP3D: A Second-order Average Pooling Approach to enhance 3D Place Recognition in Horticultural Environments</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.17017</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.17017v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: 3D LiDAR-based place recognition has been extensively researched in urban environments, yet it remains underexplored in agricultural settings. Unlike urban contexts, horticultural environments, characterized by their permeability to laser beams, result in sparse and overlapping LiDAR scans with suboptimal geometries. This phenomenon leads to intra- and inter-row descriptor ambiguity. In this work, we address this challenge by introducing SPVSoAP3D, a novel modeling approach that combines a voxel-based feature extraction network with an aggregation technique based on a second-order average pooling operator, complemented by a descriptor enhancement stage. Furthermore, we augment the existing HORTO-3DLM dataset by introducing two new sequences derived from horticultural environments. We evaluate the performance of SPVSoAP3D against state-of-the-art (SOTA) models, including OverlapTransformer, PointNetVLAD, and LOGG3D-Net, utilizing a cross-validation protocol on both the newly introduced sequences and the existing HORTO-3DLM dataset. The findings indicate that the average operator is more suitable for horticultural environments compared to the max operator and other first-order pooling techniques. Additionally, the results highlight the improvements brought by the descriptor enhancement stage.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.17017v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>T. Barros, C. Premebida, S. Aravecchia, C. Pradalier, U. J. Nunes</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi Kernel Estimation based Object Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.17064</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.17064v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper presents a novel approach for multi-kernel estimation by enhancing the KernelGAN algorithm, which traditionally estimates a single kernel for the entire image. We introduce Multi-KernelGAN, which extends KernelGAN's capabilities by estimating two distinct kernels based on object segmentation masks. Our approach is validated through three distinct methods: texture-based patch Fast Fourier Transform (FFT) calculation, detail-based segmentation, and deep learning-based object segmentation using YOLOv8 and the Segment Anything Model (SAM). Among these methods, the combination of YOLO and SAM yields the best results for kernel estimation. Experimental results demonstrate that our multi-kernel estimation technique outperforms conventional single-kernel methods in super-resolution tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.17064v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haim Goldfisher, Asaf Yekutiel</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neuronal Competition Groups with Supervised STDP for Spike-Based Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.17066</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.17066v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Spike Timing-Dependent Plasticity (STDP) is a promising substitute to backpropagation for local training of Spiking Neural Networks (SNNs) on neuromorphic hardware. STDP allows SNNs to address classification tasks by combining unsupervised STDP for feature extraction and supervised STDP for classification. Unsupervised STDP is usually employed with Winner-Takes-All (WTA) competition to learn distinct patterns. However, WTA for supervised STDP classification faces unbalanced competition challenges. In this paper, we propose a method to effectively implement WTA competition in a spiking classification layer employing first-spike coding and supervised STDP training. We introduce the Neuronal Competition Group (NCG), an architecture that improves classification capabilities by promoting the learning of various patterns per class. An NCG is a group of neurons mapped to a specific class, implementing intra-class WTA and a novel competition regulation mechanism based on two-compartment thresholds. We incorporate our proposed architecture into spiking classification layers trained with state-of-the-art supervised STDP rules. On top of two different unsupervised feature extractors, we obtain significant accuracy improvements on image recognition datasets such as CIFAR-10 and CIFAR-100. We show that our competition regulation mechanism is crucial for ensuring balanced competition and improved class separation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.17066v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gaspard Goupy, Pierre Tirilly, Ioan Marius Bilasco</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Survey on Deep Learning-based Gaze Direction Regression: Searching for the State-of-the-art</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.17082</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.17082v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this paper, we present a survey of deep learning-based methods for the regression of gaze direction vector from head and eye images. We describe in detail numerous published methods with a focus on the input data, architecture of the model, and loss function used to supervise the model. Additionally, we present a list of datasets that can be used to train and evaluate gaze direction regression methods. Furthermore, we noticed that the results reported in the literature are often not comparable one to another due to differences in the validation or even test subsets used. To address this problem, we re-evaluated several methods on the commonly used in-the-wild Gaze360 dataset using the same validation setup. The experimental results show that the latest methods, although claiming state-of-the-art results, significantly underperform compared with some older methods. Finally, we show that the temporal models outperform the static models under static test conditions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.17082v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Franko \v{S}iki\'c, Donik Vr\v{s}nak, Sven Lon\v{c}ari\'c</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Masked Differential Privacy</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.17098</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.17098v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Privacy-preserving computer vision is an important emerging problem in machine learning and artificial intelligence. The prevalent methods tackling this problem use differential privacy or anonymization and obfuscation techniques to protect the privacy of individuals. In both cases, the utility of the trained model is sacrificed heavily in this process. In this work, we propose an effective approach called masked differential privacy (MaskDP), which allows for controlling sensitive regions where differential privacy is applied, in contrast to applying DP on the entire input. Our method operates selectively on the data and allows for defining non-sensitive spatio-temporal regions without DP application or combining differential privacy with other privacy techniques within data samples. Experiments on four challenging action recognition datasets demonstrate that our proposed techniques result in better utility-privacy trade-offs compared to standard differentially private training in the especially demanding $\epsilon&lt;1$ regime.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.17098v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Proceedings of the 2nd International Workshop on Privacy-Preserving Computer Vision, ECCV 2024</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>David Schneider, Sina Sajadmanesh, Vikash Sehwag, Saquib Sarfraz, Rainer Stiefelhagen, Lingjuan Lyu, Vivek Sharma</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CLAP: Concave Linear APproximation for Quadratic Graph Matching</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.17101</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.17101v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Solving point-wise feature correspondence in visual data is a fundamental problem in computer vision. A powerful model that addresses this challenge is to formulate it as graph matching, which entails solving a Quadratic Assignment Problem (QAP) with node-wise and edge-wise constraints. However, solving such a QAP can be both expensive and difficult due to numerous local extreme points. In this work, we introduce a novel linear model and solver designed to accelerate the computation of graph matching. Specifically, we employ a positive semi-definite matrix approximation to establish the structural attribute constraint.We then transform the original QAP into a linear model that is concave for maximization. This model can subsequently be solved using the Sinkhorn optimal transport algorithm, known for its enhanced efficiency and numerical stability compared to existing approaches. Experimental results on the widely used benchmark PascalVOC showcase that our algorithm achieves state-of-the-art performance with significantly improved efficiency. Source code: https://github.com/xmlyqing00/clap</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.17101v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yongqing Liang, Huijun Han, Xin Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AlphaChimp: Tracking and Behavior Recognition of Chimpanzees</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.17136</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.17136v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Understanding non-human primate behavior is crucial for improving animal welfare, modeling social behavior, and gaining insights into both distinctly human and shared behaviors. Despite recent advances in computer vision, automated analysis of primate behavior remains challenging due to the complexity of their social interactions and the lack of specialized algorithms. Existing methods often struggle with the nuanced behaviors and frequent occlusions characteristic of primate social dynamics. This study aims to develop an effective method for automated detection, tracking, and recognition of chimpanzee behaviors in video footage. Here we show that our proposed method, AlphaChimp, an end-to-end approach that simultaneously detects chimpanzee positions and estimates behavior categories from videos, significantly outperforms existing methods in behavior recognition. AlphaChimp achieves approximately 10% higher tracking accuracy and a 20% improvement in behavior recognition compared to state-of-the-art methods, particularly excelling in the recognition of social behaviors. This superior performance stems from AlphaChimp's innovative architecture, which integrates temporal feature fusion with a Transformer-based self-attention mechanism, enabling more effective capture and interpretation of complex social interactions among chimpanzees. Our approach bridges the gap between computer vision and primatology, enhancing technical capabilities and deepening our understanding of primate communication and sociality. We release our code and models and hope this will facilitate future research in animal social dynamics. This work contributes to ethology, cognitive science, and artificial intelligence, offering new perspectives on social intelligence.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.17136v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoxuan Ma, Yutang Lin, Yuan Xu, Stephan P. Kaufhold, Jack Terwilliger, Andres Meza, Yixin Zhu, Federico Rossano, Yizhou Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YOLO-TS: Real-Time Traffic Sign Detection with Enhanced Accuracy Using Optimized Receptive Fields and Anchor-Free Fusion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.17144</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.17144v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Ensuring safety in both autonomous driving and advanced driver-assistance systems (ADAS) depends critically on the efficient deployment of traffic sign recognition technology. While current methods show effectiveness, they often compromise between speed and accuracy. To address this issue, we present a novel real-time and efficient road sign detection network, YOLO-TS. This network significantly improves performance by optimizing the receptive fields of multi-scale feature maps to align more closely with the size distribution of traffic signs in various datasets. Moreover, our innovative feature-fusion strategy, leveraging the flexibility of Anchor-Free methods, allows for multi-scale object detection on a high-resolution feature map abundant in contextual information, achieving remarkable enhancements in both accuracy and speed. To mitigate the adverse effects of the grid pattern caused by dilated convolutions on the detection of smaller objects, we have devised a unique module that not only mitigates this grid effect but also widens the receptive field to encompass an extensive range of spatial contextual information, thus boosting the efficiency of information usage. Evaluation on challenging public datasets, TT100K and CCTSDB2021, demonstrates that YOLO-TS surpasses existing state-of-the-art methods in terms of both accuracy and speed. The code for our method will be available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.17144v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junzhou Chen, Heqiang Huang, Ronghui Zhang, Nengchao Lyu, Yanyong Guo, Hong-Ning Dai, Hong Yan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Visual-Language Models Effective in Action Recognition? A Comparative Study</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.17149</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.17149v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Current vision-language foundation models, such as CLIP, have recently shown significant improvement in performance across various downstream tasks. However, whether such foundation models significantly improve more complex fine-grained action recognition tasks is still an open question. To answer this question and better find out the future research direction on human behavior analysis in-the-wild, this paper provides a large-scale study and insight on current state-of-the-art vision foundation models by comparing their transfer ability onto zero-shot and frame-wise action recognition tasks. Extensive experiments are conducted on recent fine-grained, human-centric action recognition datasets (e.g., Toyota Smarthome, Penn Action, UAV-Human, TSU, Charades) including action classification and segmentation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.17149v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mahmoud Ali, Di Yang, Fran\c{c}ois Br\'emond</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KANICE: Kolmogorov-Arnold Networks with Interactive Convolutional Elements</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.17172</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.17172v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We introduce KANICE (Kolmogorov-Arnold Networks with Interactive Convolutional Elements), a novel neural architecture that combines Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs) with Kolmogorov-Arnold Network (KAN) principles. KANICE integrates Interactive Convolutional Blocks (ICBs) and KAN linear layers into a CNN framework. This leverages KANs' universal approximation capabilities and ICBs' adaptive feature learning. KANICE captures complex, non-linear data relationships while enabling dynamic, context-dependent feature extraction based on the Kolmogorov-Arnold representation theorem. We evaluated KANICE on four datasets: MNIST, Fashion-MNIST, EMNIST, and SVHN, comparing it against standard CNNs, CNN-KAN hybrids, and ICB variants. KANICE consistently outperformed baseline models, achieving 99.35% accuracy on MNIST and 90.05% on the SVHN dataset.
  Furthermore, we introduce KANICE-mini, a compact variant designed for efficiency. A comprehensive ablation study demonstrates that KANICE-mini achieves comparable performance to KANICE with significantly fewer parameters. KANICE-mini reached 90.00% accuracy on SVHN with 2,337,828 parameters, compared to KANICE's 25,432,000. This study highlights the potential of KAN-based architectures in balancing performance and computational efficiency in image classification tasks. Our work contributes to research in adaptive neural networks, integrates mathematical theorems into deep learning architectures, and explores the trade-offs between model complexity and performance, advancing computer vision and pattern recognition. The source code for this paper is publicly accessible through our GitHub repository (https://github.com/m-ferdaus/kanice).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.17172v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Md Meftahul Ferdaus, Mahdi Abdelguerfi, Elias Ioup, David Dobson, Kendall N. Niles, Ken Pathak, Steven Sloan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emphasizing Discriminative Features for Dataset Distillation in Complex Scenarios</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.17193</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.17193v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Dataset distillation has demonstrated strong performance on simple datasets like CIFAR, MNIST, and TinyImageNet but struggles to achieve similar results in more complex scenarios. In this paper, we propose EDF (emphasizes the discriminative features), a dataset distillation method that enhances key discriminative regions in synthetic images using Grad-CAM activation maps. Our approach is inspired by a key observation: in simple datasets, high-activation areas typically occupy most of the image, whereas in complex scenarios, the size of these areas is much smaller. Unlike previous methods that treat all pixels equally when synthesizing images, EDF uses Grad-CAM activation maps to enhance high-activation areas. From a supervision perspective, we downplay supervision signals that have lower losses, as they contain common patterns. Additionally, to help the DD community better explore complex scenarios, we build the Complex Dataset Distillation (Comp-DD) benchmark by meticulously selecting sixteen subsets, eight easy and eight hard, from ImageNet-1K. In particular, EDF consistently outperforms SOTA results in complex scenarios, such as ImageNet-1K subsets. Hopefully, more researchers will be inspired and encouraged to improve the practicality and efficacy of DD. Our code and benchmark will be made public at https://github.com/NUS-HPC-AI-Lab/EDF.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.17193v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kai Wang, Zekai Li, Zhi-Qi Cheng, Samir Khaki, Ahmad Sajedi, Ramakrishna Vedantam, Konstantinos N Plataniotis, Alexander Hauptmann, Yang You</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EPContrast: Effective Point-level Contrastive Learning for Large-scale Point Cloud Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.17207</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.17207v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The acquisition of inductive bias through point-level contrastive learning holds paramount significance in point cloud pre-training. However, the square growth in computational requirements with the scale of the point cloud poses a substantial impediment to the practical deployment and execution. To address this challenge, this paper proposes an Effective Point-level Contrastive Learning method for large-scale point cloud understanding dubbed \textbf{EPContrast}, which consists of AGContrast and ChannelContrast. In practice, AGContrast constructs positive and negative pairs based on asymmetric granularity embedding, while ChannelContrast imposes contrastive supervision between channel feature maps. EPContrast offers point-level contrastive loss while concurrently mitigating the computational resource burden. The efficacy of EPContrast is substantiated through comprehensive validation on S3DIS and ScanNetV2, encompassing tasks such as semantic segmentation, instance segmentation, and object detection. In addition, rich ablation experiments demonstrate remarkable bias induction capabilities under label-efficient and one-epoch training settings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.17207v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhiyi Pan, Guoqing Liu, Wei Gao, Thomas H. Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LVSM: A Large View Synthesis Model with Minimal 3D Inductive Bias</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.17242</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.17242v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We propose the Large View Synthesis Model (LVSM), a novel transformer-based approach for scalable and generalizable novel view synthesis from sparse-view inputs. We introduce two architectures: (1) an encoder-decoder LVSM, which encodes input image tokens into a fixed number of 1D latent tokens, functioning as a fully learned scene representation, and decodes novel-view images from them; and (2) a decoder-only LVSM, which directly maps input images to novel-view outputs, completely eliminating intermediate scene representations. Both models bypass the 3D inductive biases used in previous methods -- from 3D representations (e.g., NeRF, 3DGS) to network designs (e.g., epipolar projections, plane sweeps) -- addressing novel view synthesis with a fully data-driven approach. While the encoder-decoder model offers faster inference due to its independent latent representation, the decoder-only LVSM achieves superior quality, scalability, and zero-shot generalization, outperforming previous state-of-the-art methods by 1.5 to 3.5 dB PSNR. Comprehensive evaluations across multiple datasets demonstrate that both LVSM variants achieve state-of-the-art novel view synthesis quality. Notably, our models surpass all previous methods even with reduced computational resources (1-2 GPUs). Please see our website for more details: https://haian-jin.github.io/projects/LVSM/ .</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.17242v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haian Jin, Hanwen Jiang, Hao Tan, Kai Zhang, Sai Bi, Tianyuan Zhang, Fujun Luan, Noah Snavely, Zexiang Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Memory Barrier: Near Infinite Batch Size Scaling for Contrastive Loss</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.17243</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.17243v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Contrastive loss is a powerful approach for representation learning, where larger batch sizes enhance performance by providing more negative samples to better distinguish between similar and dissimilar data. However, scaling batch sizes is constrained by the quadratic growth in GPU memory consumption, primarily due to the full instantiation of the similarity matrix. To address this, we propose a tile-based computation strategy that partitions the contrastive loss calculation into arbitrary small blocks, avoiding full materialization of the similarity matrix. Furthermore, we introduce a multi-level tiling strategy to leverage the hierarchical structure of distributed systems, employing ring-based communication at the GPU level to optimize synchronization and fused kernels at the CUDA core level to reduce I/O overhead. Experimental results show that the proposed method scales batch sizes to unprecedented levels. For instance, it enables contrastive training of a CLIP-ViT-L/14 model with a batch size of 4M or 12M using 8 or 32 A800 80GB without sacrificing any accuracy. Compared to SOTA memory-efficient solutions, it achieves a two-order-of-magnitude reduction in memory while maintaining comparable speed. The code will be made publicly available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.17243v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zesen Cheng, Hang Zhang, Kehan Li, Sicong Leng, Zhiqiang Hu, Fei Wu, Deli Zhao, Xin Li, Lidong Bing</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PyramidDrop: Accelerating Your Large Vision-Language Models via Pyramid Visual Redundancy Reduction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.17247</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.17247v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In large vision-language models (LVLMs), images serve as inputs that carry a wealth of information. As the idiom "A picture is worth a thousand words" implies, representing a single image in current LVLMs can require hundreds or even thousands of tokens. This results in significant computational costs, which grow quadratically as input image resolution increases, thereby severely impacting the efficiency of both training and inference. Previous approaches have attempted to reduce the number of image tokens either before or within the early layers of LVLMs. However, these strategies inevitably result in the loss of crucial image information, ultimately diminishing model performance. To address this challenge, we conduct an empirical study revealing that all visual tokens are necessary for LVLMs in the shallow layers, and token redundancy progressively increases in the deeper layers of the model. To this end, we propose PyramidDrop, a visual redundancy reduction strategy for LVLMs to boost their efficiency in both training and inference with neglectable performance loss. Specifically, we partition the LVLM into several stages and drop part of the image tokens at the end of each stage with a pre-defined ratio, creating pyramid-like visual tokens across model layers. The dropping is based on a lightweight similarity calculation with a negligible time overhead. Extensive experiments demonstrate that PyramidDrop can achieve a 40% training time and 55% inference FLOPs acceleration of LLaVA-NeXT with comparable performance. Besides, the PyramidDrop could also serve as a plug-and-play strategy for inference acceleration without training, with better performance and lower inference cost than counterparts. We hope that the insights and approach introduced by PyramidDrop will inspire future research to further investigate the role of image tokens in LVLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.17247v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Long Xing, Qidong Huang, Xiaoyi Dong, Jiajie Lu, Pan Zhang, Yuhang Zang, Yuhang Cao, Conghui He, Jiaqi Wang, Feng Wu, Dahua Lin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SpectroMotion: Dynamic 3D Reconstruction of Specular Scenes</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.17249</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.17249v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present SpectroMotion, a novel approach that combines 3D Gaussian Splatting (3DGS) with physically-based rendering (PBR) and deformation fields to reconstruct dynamic specular scenes. Previous methods extending 3DGS to model dynamic scenes have struggled to accurately represent specular surfaces. Our method addresses this limitation by introducing a residual correction technique for accurate surface normal computation during deformation, complemented by a deformable environment map that adapts to time-varying lighting conditions. We implement a coarse-to-fine training strategy that significantly enhances both scene geometry and specular color prediction. We demonstrate that our model outperforms prior methods for view synthesis of scenes containing dynamic specular objects and that it is the only existing 3DGS method capable of synthesizing photorealistic real-world dynamic specular scenes, outperforming state-of-the-art methods in rendering complex, dynamic, and specular scenes.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.17249v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Cheng-De Fan, Chen-Wei Chang, Yi-Ruei Liu, Jie-Ying Lee, Jiun-Long Huang, Yu-Chee Tseng, Yu-Lun Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Altogether: Image Captioning via Re-aligning Alt-text</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.17251</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.17251v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper focuses on creating synthetic data to improve the quality of image captions. Existing works typically have two shortcomings. First, they caption images from scratch, ignoring existing alt-text metadata, and second, lack transparency if the captioners' training data (e.g. GPT) is unknown. In this paper, we study a principled approach Altogether based on the key idea to edit and re-align existing alt-texts associated with the images. To generate training data, we perform human annotation where annotators start with the existing alt-text and re-align it to the image content in multiple rounds, consequently constructing captions with rich visual concepts. This differs from prior work that carries out human annotation as a one-time description task solely based on images and annotator knowledge. We train a captioner on this data that generalizes the process of re-aligning alt-texts at scale. Our results show our Altogether approach leads to richer image captions that also improve text-to-image generation and zero-shot image classification tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.17251v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hu Xu, Po-Yao Huang, Xiaoqing Ellen Tan, Ching-Feng Yeh, Jacob Kahn, Christine Jou, Gargi Ghosh, Omer Levy, Luke Zettlemoyer, Wen-tau Yih, Shang-Wen Li, Saining Xie, Christoph Feichtenhofer</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unifying Subsampling Pattern Variations for Compressed Sensing MRI with Neural Operators</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16290</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16290v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Compressed Sensing MRI (CS-MRI) reconstructs images of the body's internal anatomy from undersampled and compressed measurements, thereby reducing scan times and minimizing the duration patients need to remain still. Recently, deep neural networks have shown great potential for reconstructing high-quality images from highly undersampled measurements. However, since deep neural networks operate on a fixed discretization, one needs to train multiple models for different measurement subsampling patterns and image resolutions. This approach is highly impractical in clinical settings, where subsampling patterns and image resolutions are frequently varied to accommodate different imaging and diagnostic requirements. We propose a unified model that is robust to different subsampling patterns and image resolutions in CS-MRI. Our model is based on neural operators, a discretization-agnostic architecture. We use neural operators in both image and measurement (frequency) space, which capture local and global image features for MRI reconstruction. Empirically, we achieve consistent performance across different subsampling rates and patterns, with up to 4x lower NMSE and 5 dB PSNR improvements over the state-of-the-art method. We also show the model is agnostic to image resolutions with zero-shot super-resolution results. Our unified model is a promising tool that is agnostic to measurement subsampling and imaging resolutions in MRI, offering significant utility in clinical settings where flexibility and adaptability are essential for efficient and reliable imaging.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16290v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Armeet Singh Jatyani, Jiayun Wang, Zihui Wu, Miguel Liu-Schiaffini, Bahareh Tolooshams, Anima Anandkumar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CirrMRI600+: Large Scale MRI Collection and Segmentation of Cirrhotic Liver</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16296</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16296v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Liver cirrhosis, the end stage of chronic liver disease, is characterized by extensive bridging fibrosis and nodular regeneration, leading to an increased risk of liver failure, complications of portal hypertension, malignancy and death. Early diagnosis and management of end-stage cirrhosis are significant clinical challenges. Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) is a widely available, non-invasive imaging technique for cirrhosis assessment. However, the stage of liver fibrosis cannot be easily differentiated. Moreover, the fibrotic liver tissue (cirrhotic liver) causes significant change in liver enhancement, morphology and signal characteristics, which poses substantial challenges for the development of computer-aided diagnostic applications. Deep learning (DL) offers a promising solution for automatically segmenting and recognizing cirrhotic livers in MRI scans, potentially enabling fibrosis stage classification. However, the lack of datasets specifically focused on cirrhotic livers has hindered progress. CirrMRI600+ addresses this critical gap. This extensive dataset, the first of its kind, comprises 628 high-resolution abdominal MRI scans (310 T1-weighted and 318 T2-weighted, totaling nearly 40,000 slices) with annotated segmentation labels for cirrhotic livers. Unlike previous datasets, CirrMRI600+ specifically focuses on cirrhotic livers, capturing the complexities of this disease state. The link to the dataset is made publicly available at: https://osf.io/cuk24/. We also share 11 baseline deep learning segmentation methods used in our rigorous benchmarking experiments: https://github.com/NUBagciLab/CirrMRI600Plus.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16296v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Debesh Jha, Onkar Kishor Susladkar, Vandan Gorade, Elif Keles, Matthew Antalek, Deniz Seyithanoglu, Timurhan Cebeci, Halil Ertugrul Aktas, Gulbiz Dagoglu Kartal, Sabahattin Kaymakoglu, Sukru Mehmet Erturk, Yuri Velichko, Daniela Ladner, Amir A. Borhani, Alpay Medetalibeyoglu, Gorkem Durak, Ulas Bagci</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Survey on Physical Adversarial Attacks against Face Recognition Systems</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16317</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16317v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: As Face Recognition (FR) technology becomes increasingly prevalent in finance, the military, public safety, and everyday life, security concerns have grown substantially. Physical adversarial attacks targeting FR systems in real-world settings have attracted considerable research interest due to their practicality and the severe threats they pose. However, a systematic overview focused on physical adversarial attacks against FR systems is still lacking, hindering an in-depth exploration of the challenges and future directions in this field. In this paper, we bridge this gap by comprehensively collecting and analyzing physical adversarial attack methods targeting FR systems. Specifically, we first investigate the key challenges of physical attacks on FR systems. We then categorize existing physical attacks into three categories based on the physical medium used and summarize how the research in each category has evolved to address these challenges. Furthermore, we review current defense strategies and discuss potential future research directions. Our goal is to provide a fresh, comprehensive, and deep understanding of physical adversarial attacks against FR systems, thereby inspiring relevant research in this area.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16317v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mingsi Wang, Jiachen Zhou, Tianlin Li, Guozhu Meng, Kai Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Domain-Adaptive Neural Posterior Estimation for Strong Gravitational Lens Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16347</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16347v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Modeling strong gravitational lenses is prohibitively expensive for modern and next-generation cosmic survey data. Neural posterior estimation (NPE), a simulation-based inference (SBI) approach, has been studied as an avenue for efficient analysis of strong lensing data. However, NPE has not been demonstrated to perform well on out-of-domain target data -- e.g., when trained on simulated data and then applied to real, observational data. In this work, we perform the first study of the efficacy of NPE in combination with unsupervised domain adaptation (UDA). The source domain is noiseless, and the target domain has noise mimicking modern cosmology surveys. We find that combining UDA and NPE improves the accuracy of the inference by 1-2 orders of magnitude and significantly improves the posterior coverage over an NPE model without UDA. We anticipate that this combination of approaches will help enable future applications of NPE models to real observational data.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16347v1</guid>
      <category>astro-ph.IM</category>
      <category>astro-ph.CO</category>
      <category>astro-ph.GA</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Paxson Swierc, Marcos Tamargo-Arizmendi, Aleksandra \'Ciprijanovi\'c, Brian D. Nord</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AlignVSR: Audio-Visual Cross-Modal Alignment for Visual Speech Recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16438</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16438v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Visual Speech Recognition (VSR) aims to recognize corresponding text by analyzing visual information from lip movements. Due to the high variability and weak information of lip movements, VSR tasks require effectively utilizing any information from any source and at any level. In this paper, we propose a VSR method based on audio-visual cross-modal alignment, named AlignVSR. The method leverages the audio modality as an auxiliary information source and utilizes the global and local correspondence between the audio and visual modalities to improve visual-to-text inference. Specifically, the method first captures global alignment between video and audio through a cross-modal attention mechanism from video frames to a bank of audio units. Then, based on the temporal correspondence between audio and video, a frame-level local alignment loss is introduced to refine the global alignment, improving the utility of the audio information. Experimental results on the LRS2 and CNVSRC.Single datasets consistently show that AlignVSR outperforms several mainstream VSR methods, demonstrating its superior and robust performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16438v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zehua Liu, Xiaolou Li, Chen Chen, Li Guo, Lantian Li, Dong Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Allo-AVA: A Large-Scale Multimodal Conversational AI Dataset for Allocentric Avatar Gesture Animation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16503</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16503v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The scarcity of high-quality, multimodal training data severely hinders the creation of lifelike avatar animations for conversational AI in virtual environments. Existing datasets often lack the intricate synchronization between speech, facial expressions, and body movements that characterize natural human communication. To address this critical gap, we introduce Allo-AVA, a large-scale dataset specifically designed for text and audio-driven avatar gesture animation in an allocentric (third person point-of-view) context. Allo-AVA consists of $\sim$1,250 hours of diverse video content, complete with audio, transcripts, and extracted keypoints. Allo-AVA uniquely maps these keypoints to precise timestamps, enabling accurate replication of human movements (body and facial gestures) in synchronization with speech. This comprehensive resource enables the development and evaluation of more natural, context-aware avatar animation models, potentially transforming applications ranging from virtual reality to digital assistants.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16503v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Saif Punjwani, Larry Heck</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Neural Network Training via Subset Pretraining</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16523</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16523v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In training neural networks, it is common practice to use partial gradients computed over batches, mostly very small subsets of the training set. This approach is motivated by the argument that such a partial gradient is close to the true one, with precision growing only with the square root of the batch size. A theoretical justification is with the help of stochastic approximation theory. However, the conditions for the validity of this theory are not satisfied in the usual learning rate schedules. Batch processing is also difficult to combine with efficient second-order optimization methods. This proposal is based on another hypothesis: the loss minimum of the training set can be expected to be well-approximated by the minima of its subsets. Such subset minima can be computed in a fraction of the time necessary for optimizing over the whole training set. This hypothesis has been tested with the help of the MNIST, CIFAR-10, and CIFAR-100 image classification benchmarks, optionally extended by training data augmentation. The experiments have confirmed that results equivalent to conventional training can be reached. In summary, even small subsets are representative if the overdetermination ratio for the given model parameter set sufficiently exceeds unity. The computing expense can be reduced to a tenth or less.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16523v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>stat.CO</category>
      <category>stat.ME</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jan Sp\"orer, Bernhard Bermeitinger, Tomas Hrycej, Niklas Limacher, Siegfried Handschuh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Body Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16533</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16533v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: As virtual agents become increasingly prevalent in human-computer interaction, generating realistic and contextually appropriate gestures in real-time remains a significant challenge. While neural rendering techniques have made substantial progress with static scripts, their applicability to human-computer interactions remains limited. To address this, we introduce Large Body Language Models (LBLMs) and present LBLM-AVA, a novel LBLM architecture that combines a Transformer-XL large language model with a parallelized diffusion model to generate human-like gestures from multimodal inputs (text, audio, and video). LBLM-AVA incorporates several key components enhancing its gesture generation capabilities, such as multimodal-to-pose embeddings, enhanced sequence-to-sequence mapping with redefined attention mechanisms, a temporal smoothing module for gesture sequence coherence, and an attention-based refinement module for enhanced realism. The model is trained on our large-scale proprietary open-source dataset Allo-AVA. LBLM-AVA achieves state-of-the-art performance in generating lifelike and contextually appropriate gestures with a 30% reduction in Fr\'echet Gesture Distance (FGD), and a 25% improvement in Fr\'echet Inception Distance compared to existing approaches.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16533v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Saif Punjwani, Larry Heck</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual-Model Defense: Safeguarding Diffusion Models from Membership Inference Attacks through Disjoint Data Splitting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16657</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16657v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Diffusion models have demonstrated remarkable capabilities in image synthesis, but their recently proven vulnerability to Membership Inference Attacks (MIAs) poses a critical privacy concern. This paper introduces two novel and efficient approaches (DualMD and DistillMD) to protect diffusion models against MIAs while maintaining high utility. Both methods are based on training two separate diffusion models on disjoint subsets of the original dataset. DualMD then employs a private inference pipeline that utilizes both models. This strategy significantly reduces the risk of black-box MIAs by limiting the information any single model contains about individual training samples. The dual models can also generate "soft targets" to train a private student model in DistillMD, enhancing privacy guarantees against all types of MIAs. Extensive evaluations of DualMD and DistillMD against state-of-the-art MIAs across various datasets in white-box and black-box settings demonstrate their effectiveness in substantially reducing MIA success rates while preserving competitive image generation performance. Notably, our experiments reveal that DistillMD not only defends against MIAs but also mitigates model memorization, indicating that both vulnerabilities stem from overfitting and can be addressed simultaneously with our unified approach.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16657v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bao Q. Tran, Viet Nguyen, Anh Tran, Toan Tran</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visual Question Answering in Ophthalmology: A Progressive and Practical Perspective</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16662</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16662v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Accurate diagnosis of ophthalmic diseases relies heavily on the interpretation of multimodal ophthalmic images, a process often time-consuming and expertise-dependent. Visual Question Answering (VQA) presents a potential interdisciplinary solution by merging computer vision and natural language processing to comprehend and respond to queries about medical images. This review article explores the recent advancements and future prospects of VQA in ophthalmology from both theoretical and practical perspectives, aiming to provide eye care professionals with a deeper understanding and tools for leveraging the underlying models. Additionally, we discuss the promising trend of large language models (LLM) in enhancing various components of the VQA framework to adapt to multimodal ophthalmic tasks. Despite the promising outlook, ophthalmic VQA still faces several challenges, including the scarcity of annotated multimodal image datasets, the necessity of comprehensive and unified evaluation methods, and the obstacles to achieving effective real-world applications. This article highlights these challenges and clarifies future directions for advancing ophthalmic VQA with LLMs. The development of LLM-based ophthalmic VQA systems calls for collaborative efforts between medical professionals and AI experts to overcome existing obstacles and advance the diagnosis and care of eye diseases.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16662v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaolan Chen, Ruoyu Chen, Pusheng Xu, Weiyi Zhang, Xianwen Shang, Mingguang He, Danli Shi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NucleiMix: Realistic Data Augmentation for Nuclei Instance Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16671</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16671v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Nuclei instance segmentation is an essential task in pathology image analysis, serving as the foundation for many downstream applications. The release of several public datasets has significantly advanced research in this area, yet many existing methods struggle with data imbalance issues. To address this challenge, this study introduces a data augmentation method, called NucleiMix, which is designed to balance the distribution of nuclei types by increasing the number of rare-type nuclei within datasets. NucleiMix operates in two phases. In the first phase, it identifies candidate locations similar to the surroundings of rare-type nuclei and inserts rare-type nuclei into the candidate locations. In the second phase, it employs a progressive inpainting strategy using a pre-trained diffusion model to seamlessly integrate rare-type nuclei into their new environments in replacement of major-type nuclei or background locations. We systematically evaluate the effectiveness of NucleiMix on three public datasets using two popular nuclei instance segmentation models. The results demonstrate the superior ability of NucleiMix to synthesize realistic rare-type nuclei and to enhance the quality of nuclei segmentation and classification in an accurate and robust manner.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16671v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiamu Wang, Jin Tae Kwak</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nash Meets Wertheimer: Using Good Continuation in Jigsaw Puzzles</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16857</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16857v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Jigsaw puzzle solving is a challenging task for computer vision since it requires high-level spatial and semantic reasoning. To solve the problem, existing approaches invariably use color and/or shape information but in many real-world scenarios, such as in archaeological fresco reconstruction, this kind of clues is often unreliable due to severe physical and pictorial deterioration of the individual fragments. This makes state-of-the-art approaches entirely unusable in practice. On the other hand, in such cases, simple geometrical patterns such as lines or curves offer a powerful yet unexplored clue. In an attempt to fill in this gap, in this paper we introduce a new challenging version of the puzzle solving problem in which one deliberately ignores conventional color and shape features and relies solely on the presence of linear geometrical patterns. The reconstruction process is then only driven by one of the most fundamental principles of Gestalt perceptual organization, namely Wertheimer's {\em law of good continuation}. In order to tackle this problem, we formulate the puzzle solving problem as the problem of finding a Nash equilibrium of a (noncooperative) multiplayer game and use classical multi-population replicator dynamics to solve it. The proposed approach is general and allows us to deal with pieces of arbitrary shape, size and orientation. We evaluate our approach on both synthetic and real-world data and compare it with state-of-the-art algorithms. The results show the intrinsic complexity of our purely line-based puzzle problem as well as the relative effectiveness of our game-theoretic formulation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16857v1</guid>
      <category>cs.GT</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>ACCV2024</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Marina Khoroshiltseva, Luca Palmieri, Sinem Aslan, Sebastiano Vascon, Marcello Pelillo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking generalization of classifiers in separable classes scenarios and over-parameterized regimes</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16868</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16868v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We investigate the learning dynamics of classifiers in scenarios where classes are separable or classifiers are over-parameterized. In both cases, Empirical Risk Minimization (ERM) results in zero training error. However, there are many global minima with a training error of zero, some of which generalize well and some of which do not. We show that in separable classes scenarios the proportion of "bad" global minima diminishes exponentially with the number of training data n. Our analysis provides bounds and learning curves dependent solely on the density distribution of the true error for the given classifier function set, irrespective of the set's size or complexity (e.g., number of parameters). This observation may shed light on the unexpectedly good generalization of over-parameterized Neural Networks. For the over-parameterized scenario, we propose a model for the density distribution of the true error, yielding learning curves that align with experiments on MNIST and CIFAR-10.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16868v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1109/IJCNN60899.2024.10650680</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>2024 International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN), Yokohama, Japan, 2024, pp. 1-10</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Julius Martinetz, Christoph Linse, Thomas Martinetz</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MBD: Multi b-value Denoising of Diffusion Magnetic Resonance Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16898</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16898v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We propose a novel approach to denoising diffusion magnetic resonance images (dMRI) using convolutional neural networks, that exploits the benefits of data acquired at multiple b-values to offset the need for many redundant observations. Denoising is especially relevant in dMRI since noise can have a deleterious impact on both quantification accuracy and image preprocessing. The most successful methods proposed to date, like Marchenko-Pastur Principal Component Analysis (MPPCA) denoising, are tailored to diffusion-weighting repeated for many encoding directions. They exploit high redundancy of the dataset that oversamples the diffusion-encoding direction space, since many directions have collinear components.
  However, there are many dMRI techniques that do not entail a large number of encoding directions or repetitions, and are therefore less suited to this approach. For example, clinical dMRI exams may include as few as three encoding directions, with low or negligible data redundancy across directions. Moreover, promising new dMRI approaches, like spherical b-tensor encoding (STE), benefit from high b-values while sensitizing the signal to diffusion along all directions in just a single shot.
  We introduce a convolutional neural network approach that we call multi-b-value-based denoising (MBD). MBD exploits the similarity in diffusion-weighted images (DWI) across different b-values but along the same diffusion encoding direction. It allows denoising of diffusion images with high noise variance while avoiding blurring, and using just a small number input images.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16898v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jakub Jurek, Andrzej Materka, Kamil Ludwisiak, Agata Majos, Filip Szczepankiewicz</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IdenBAT: Disentangled Representation Learning for Identity-Preserved Brain Age Transformation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16945</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16945v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Brain age transformation aims to convert reference brain images into synthesized images that accurately reflect the age-specific features of a target age group. The primary objective of this task is to modify only the age-related attributes of the reference image while preserving all other age-irrelevant attributes. However, achieving this goal poses substantial challenges due to the inherent entanglement of various image attributes within features extracted from a backbone encoder, resulting in simultaneous alterations during the image generation. To address this challenge, we propose a novel architecture that employs disentangled representation learning for identity-preserved brain age transformation called IdenBAT. This approach facilitates the decomposition of image features, ensuring the preservation of individual traits while selectively transforming age-related characteristics to match those of the target age group. Through comprehensive experiments conducted on both 2D and full-size 3D brain datasets, our method adeptly converts input images to target age while retaining individual characteristics accurately. Furthermore, our approach demonstrates superiority over existing state-of-the-art regarding performance fidelity.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16945v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>q-bio.NC</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junyeong Maeng, Kwanseok Oh, Wonsik Jung, Heung-Il Suk</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Layer Gaussian Splatting for Immersive Anatomy Visualization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16978</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16978v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In medical image visualization, path tracing of volumetric medical data like CT scans produces lifelike three-dimensional visualizations. Immersive VR displays can further enhance the understanding of complex anatomies. Going beyond the diagnostic quality of traditional 2D slices, they enable interactive 3D evaluation of anatomies, supporting medical education and planning. Rendering high-quality visualizations in real-time, however, is computationally intensive and impractical for compute-constrained devices like mobile headsets.
  We propose a novel approach utilizing GS to create an efficient but static intermediate representation of CT scans. We introduce a layered GS representation, incrementally including different anatomical structures while minimizing overlap and extending the GS training to remove inactive Gaussians. We further compress the created model with clustering across layers.
  Our approach achieves interactive frame rates while preserving anatomical structures, with quality adjustable to the target hardware. Compared to standard GS, our representation retains some of the explorative qualities initially enabled by immersive path tracing. Selective activation and clipping of layers are possible at rendering time, adding a degree of interactivity to otherwise static GS models. This could enable scenarios where high computational demands would otherwise prohibit using path-traced medical volumes.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16978v1</guid>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Constantin Kleinbeck, Hannah Schieber, Klaus Engel, Ralf Gutjahr, Daniel Roth</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LFME: A Simple Framework for Learning from Multiple Experts in Domain Generalization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.17020</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.17020v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Domain generalization (DG) methods aim to maintain good performance in an unseen target domain by using training data from multiple source domains. While success on certain occasions are observed, enhancing the baseline across most scenarios remains challenging. This work introduces a simple yet effective framework, dubbed learning from multiple experts (LFME), that aims to make the target model an expert in all source domains to improve DG. Specifically, besides learning the target model used in inference, LFME will also train multiple experts specialized in different domains, whose output probabilities provide professional guidance by simply regularizing the logit of the target model. Delving deep into the framework, we reveal that the introduced logit regularization term implicitly provides effects of enabling the target model to harness more information, and mining hard samples from the experts during training. Extensive experiments on benchmarks from different DG tasks demonstrate that LFME is consistently beneficial to the baseline and can achieve comparable performance to existing arts. Code is available at~\url{https://github.com/liangchen527/LFME}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.17020v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Liang Chen, Yong Zhang, Yibing Song, Zhiqiang Shen, Lingqiao Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LiNeS: Post-training Layer Scaling Prevents Forgetting and Enhances Model Merging</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.17146</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.17146v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large pre-trained models exhibit impressive zero-shot performance across diverse tasks, but fine-tuning often leads to catastrophic forgetting, where improvements on a target domain degrade generalization on other tasks. To address this challenge, we introduce LiNeS, Layer-increasing Network Scaling, a post-training editing technique designed to preserve pre-trained generalization while enhancing fine-tuned task performance. LiNeS scales parameter updates linearly based on their layer depth within the network, maintaining shallow layers close to their pre-trained values to preserve general features while allowing deeper layers to retain task-specific representations. We further extend this approach to multi-task model merging scenarios, where layer-wise scaling of merged parameters reduces negative task interference. LiNeS demonstrates significant improvements in both single-task and multi-task settings across various benchmarks in vision and natural language processing. It mitigates forgetting, enhances out-of-distribution generalization, integrates seamlessly with existing multi-task model merging baselines improving their performance across benchmarks and model sizes, and can boost generalization when merging LLM policies aligned with different rewards via RLHF. Importantly, our method is simple to implement and complementary to many existing techniques.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.17146v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ke Wang, Nikolaos Dimitriadis, Alessandro Favero, Guillermo Ortiz-Jimenez, Francois Fleuret, Pascal Frossard</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automated Spinal MRI Labelling from Reports Using a Large Language Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.17235</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.17235v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We propose a general pipeline to automate the extraction of labels from radiology reports using large language models, which we validate on spinal MRI reports. The efficacy of our labelling method is measured on five distinct conditions: spinal cancer, stenosis, spondylolisthesis, cauda equina compression and herniation. Using open-source models, our method equals or surpasses GPT-4 on a held-out set of reports. Furthermore, we show that the extracted labels can be used to train imaging models to classify the identified conditions in the accompanying MR scans. All classifiers trained using automated labels achieve comparable performance to models trained using scans manually annotated by clinicians. Code can be found at https://github.com/robinyjpark/AutoLabelClassifier.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.17235v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Robin Y. Park, Rhydian Windsor, Amir Jamaludin, Andrew Zisserman</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frontiers in Intelligent Colonoscopy</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.17241</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.17241v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Colonoscopy is currently one of the most sensitive screening methods for colorectal cancer. This study investigates the frontiers of intelligent colonoscopy techniques and their prospective implications for multimodal medical applications. With this goal, we begin by assessing the current data-centric and model-centric landscapes through four tasks for colonoscopic scene perception, including classification, detection, segmentation, and vision-language understanding. This assessment enables us to identify domain-specific challenges and reveals that multimodal research in colonoscopy remains open for further exploration. To embrace the coming multimodal era, we establish three foundational initiatives: a large-scale multimodal instruction tuning dataset ColonINST, a colonoscopy-designed multimodal language model ColonGPT, and a multimodal benchmark. To facilitate ongoing monitoring of this rapidly evolving field, we provide a public website for the latest updates: https://github.com/ai4colonoscopy/IntelliScope.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.17241v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ge-Peng Ji, Jingyi Liu, Peng Xu, Nick Barnes, Fahad Shahbaz Khan, Salman Khan, Deng-Ping Fan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JMMMU: A Japanese Massive Multi-discipline Multimodal Understanding Benchmark for Culture-aware Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.17250</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.17250v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Accelerating research on Large Multimodal Models (LMMs) in non-English languages is crucial for enhancing user experiences across broader populations. In this paper, we introduce JMMMU (Japanese MMMU), the first large-scale Japanese benchmark designed to evaluate LMMs on expert-level tasks based on the Japanese cultural context. To facilitate comprehensive culture-aware evaluation, JMMMU features two complementary subsets: (i) culture-agnostic (CA) subset, where the culture-independent subjects (e.g., Math) are selected and translated into Japanese, enabling one-to-one comparison with its English counterpart MMMU; and (ii) culture-specific (CS) subset, comprising newly crafted subjects that reflect Japanese cultural context. Using the CA subset, we observe performance drop in many LMMs when evaluated in Japanese, which is purely attributable to language variation. Using the CS subset, we reveal their inadequate Japanese cultural understanding. Further, by combining both subsets, we identify that some LMMs perform well on the CA subset but not on the CS subset, exposing a shallow understanding of the Japanese language that lacks depth in cultural understanding. We hope this work will not only help advance LMM performance in Japanese but also serve as a guideline to create high-standard, culturally diverse benchmarks for multilingual LMM development. The project page is https://mmmu-japanese-benchmark.github.io/JMMMU/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.17250v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shota Onohara, Atsuyuki Miyai, Yuki Imajuku, Kazuki Egashira, Jeonghun Baek, Xiang Yue, Graham Neubig, Kiyoharu Aizawa</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Diversity-based Active Learning for 3D Object Detection in Autonomous Driving</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2205.07708</link>
      <description>arXiv:2205.07708v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: 3D object detection has recently received much attention due to its great potential in autonomous vehicle (AV). The success of deep learning based object detectors relies on the availability of large-scale annotated datasets, which is time-consuming and expensive to compile, especially for 3D bounding box annotation. In this work, we investigate diversity-based active learning (AL) as a potential solution to alleviate the annotation burden. Given limited annotation budget, only the most informative frames and objects are automatically selected for human to annotate. Technically, we take the advantage of the multimodal information provided in an AV dataset, and propose a novel acquisition function that enforces spatial and temporal diversity in the selected samples. We benchmark the proposed method against other AL strategies under realistic annotation cost measurement, where the realistic costs for annotating a frame and a 3D bounding box are both taken into consideration. We demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed method on the nuScenes dataset and show that it outperforms existing AL strategies significantly. Code is available at https://github.com/Linkon87/Exploring-Diversity-based-Active-Learning-for-3D-Object-Detection-in-Autonomous-Driving</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2205.07708v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jinpeng Lin, Zhihao Liang, Shengheng Deng, Lile Cai, Tao Jiang, Tianrui Li, Kui Jia, Xun Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Test-Time Augmentation via Differentiable Functions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2212.04681</link>
      <description>arXiv:2212.04681v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Distribution shifts, which often occur in the real world, degrade the accuracy of deep learning systems, and thus improving robustness to distribution shifts is essential for practical applications. To improve robustness, we study an image enhancement method that generates recognition-friendly images without retraining the recognition model. We propose a novel image enhancement method, DynTTA, which is based on differentiable data augmentation techniques and generates a blended image from many augmented images to improve the recognition accuracy under distribution shifts. In addition to standard data augmentations, DynTTA also incorporates deep neural network-based image transformation, further improving the robustness. Because DynTTA is composed of differentiable functions, it can be directly trained with the classification loss of the recognition model. In experiments with widely used image recognition datasets using various classification models, DynTTA improves the robustness with almost no reduction in classification accuracy for clean images, thus outperforming the existing methods. Furthermore, the results show that robustness is significantly improved by estimating the training-time augmentations for distribution-shifted datasets using DynTTA and retraining the recognition model with the estimated augmentations. DynTTA is a promising approach for applications that require both clean accuracy and robustness. Our code is available at \url{https://github.com/s-enmt/DynTTA}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2212.04681v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>IEEE Access, vol. 12, pp. 149593-149605, 2024</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Shohei Enomoto, Monikka Roslianna Busto, Takeharu Eda</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the Generalization Ability for Hyperspectral Image Classification using Spectral-spatial Axial Aggregation Transformer</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2306.16759</link>
      <description>arXiv:2306.16759v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In the hyperspectral image classification (HSIC) task, the most commonly used model validation paradigm is partitioning the training-test dataset through pixel-wise random sampling. By training on a small amount of data, the deep learning model can achieve almost perfect accuracy. However, in our experiments, we found that the high accuracy was reached because the training and test datasets share a lot of information. On non-overlapping dataset partitions, well-performing models suffer significant performance degradation. To this end, we propose a spectral-spatial axial aggregation transformer model, namely SaaFormer, that preserves generalization across dataset partitions. SaaFormer applies a multi-level spectral extraction structure to segment the spectrum into multiple spectrum clips, such that the wavelength continuity of the spectrum across the channel are preserved. For each spectrum clip, the axial aggregation attention mechanism, which integrates spatial features along multiple spectral axes is applied to mine the spectral characteristic. The multi-level spectral extraction and the axial aggregation attention emphasize spectral characteristic to improve the model generalization. The experimental results on five publicly available datasets demonstrate that our model exhibits comparable performance on the random partition, while significantly outperforming other methods on non-overlapping partitions. Moreover, SaaFormer shows excellent performance on background classification.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2306.16759v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Enzhe Zhao, Zhichang Guo, Shengzhu Shi, Yao Li, Jia Li, Dazhi Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Volume Mixup for Video Action Recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2309.09534</link>
      <description>arXiv:2309.09534v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The recent advances in Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs) and Vision Transformers have convincingly demonstrated high learning capability for video action recognition on large datasets. Nevertheless, deep models often suffer from the overfitting effect on small-scale datasets with a limited number of training videos. A common solution is to exploit the existing image augmentation strategies for each frame individually including Mixup, Cutmix, and RandAugment, which are not particularly optimized for video data. In this paper, we propose a novel video augmentation strategy named Selective Volume Mixup (SV-Mix) to improve the generalization ability of deep models with limited training videos. SV-Mix devises a learnable selective module to choose the most informative volumes from two videos and mixes the volumes up to achieve a new training video. Technically, we propose two new modules, i.e., a spatial selective module to select the local patches for each spatial position, and a temporal selective module to mix the entire frames for each timestamp and maintain the spatial pattern. At each time, we randomly choose one of the two modules to expand the diversity of training samples. The selective modules are jointly optimized with the video action recognition framework to find the optimal augmentation strategy. We empirically demonstrate the merits of the SV-Mix augmentation on a wide range of video action recognition benchmarks and consistently boot the performances of both CNN-based and transformer-based models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2309.09534v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yi Tan, Zhaofan Qiu, Yanbin Hao, Ting Yao, Tao Mei</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feature Extraction for Generative Medical Imaging Evaluation: New Evidence Against an Evolving Trend</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.13717</link>
      <description>arXiv:2311.13717v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Fr\'echet Inception Distance (FID) is a widely used metric for assessing synthetic image quality. It relies on an ImageNet-based feature extractor, making its applicability to medical imaging unclear. A recent trend is to adapt FID to medical imaging through feature extractors trained on medical images. Our study challenges this practice by demonstrating that ImageNet-based extractors are more consistent and aligned with human judgment than their RadImageNet counterparts. We evaluated sixteen StyleGAN2 networks across four medical imaging modalities and four data augmentation techniques with Fr\'echet distances (FDs) computed using eleven ImageNet or RadImageNet-trained feature extractors. Comparison with human judgment via visual Turing tests revealed that ImageNet-based extractors produced rankings consistent with human judgment, with the FD derived from the ImageNet-trained SwAV extractor significantly correlating with expert evaluations. In contrast, RadImageNet-based rankings were volatile and inconsistent with human judgment. Our findings challenge prevailing assumptions, providing novel evidence that medical image-trained feature extractors do not inherently improve FDs and can even compromise their reliability. Our code is available at https://github.com/mckellwoodland/fid-med-eval.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2311.13717v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1007/978-3-031-72390-2_9</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>MICCAI 2024. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol 15012. Springer, Cham (2024)</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>McKell Woodland, Austin Castelo, Mais Al Taie, Jessica Albuquerque Marques Silva, Mohamed Eltaher, Frank Mohn, Alexander Shieh, Suprateek Kundu, Joshua P. Yung, Ankit B. Patel, Kristy K. Brock</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GazeMoDiff: Gaze-guided Diffusion Model for Stochastic Human Motion Prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12090</link>
      <description>arXiv:2312.12090v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Human motion prediction is important for many virtual and augmented reality (VR/AR) applications such as collision avoidance and realistic avatar generation. Existing methods have synthesised body motion only from observed past motion, despite the fact that human eye gaze is known to correlate strongly with body movements and is readily available in recent VR/AR headsets. We present GazeMoDiff - a novel gaze-guided denoising diffusion model to generate stochastic human motions. Our method first uses a gaze encoder and a motion encoder to extract the gaze and motion features respectively, then employs a graph attention network to fuse these features, and finally injects the gaze-motion features into a noise prediction network via a cross-attention mechanism to progressively generate multiple reasonable human motions in the future. Extensive experiments on the MoGaze and GIMO datasets demonstrate that our method outperforms the state-of-the-art methods by a large margin in terms of multi-modal final displacement error (17.3% on MoGaze and 13.3% on GIMO). We further conducted a human study (N=21) and validated that the motions generated by our method were perceived as both more precise and more realistic than those of prior methods. Taken together, these results reveal the significant information content available in eye gaze for stochastic human motion prediction as well as the effectiveness of our method in exploiting this information.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2312.12090v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haodong Yan, Zhiming Hu, Syn Schmitt, Andreas Bulling</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transformer for Object Re-Identification: A Survey</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.06960</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.06960v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Object Re-identification (Re-ID) aims to identify specific objects across different times and scenes, which is a widely researched task in computer vision. For a prolonged period, this field has been predominantly driven by deep learning technology based on convolutional neural networks. In recent years, the emergence of Vision Transformers has spurred a growing number of studies delving deeper into Transformer-based Re-ID, continuously breaking performance records and witnessing significant progress in the Re-ID field. Offering a powerful, flexible, and unified solution, Transformers cater to a wide array of Re-ID tasks with unparalleled efficacy. This paper provides a comprehensive review and in-depth analysis of the Transformer-based Re-ID. In categorizing existing works into Image/Video-Based Re-ID, Re-ID with limited data/annotations, Cross-Modal Re-ID, and Special Re-ID Scenarios, we thoroughly elucidate the advantages demonstrated by the Transformer in addressing a multitude of challenges across these domains. Considering the trending unsupervised Re-ID, we propose a new Transformer baseline, UntransReID, achieving state-of-the-art performance on both single/cross modal tasks. For the under-explored animal Re-ID, we devise a standardized experimental benchmark and conduct extensive experiments to explore the applicability of Transformer for this task and facilitate future research. Finally, we discuss some important yet under-investigated open issues in the large foundation model era, we believe it will serve as a new handbook for researchers in this field. A periodically updated website will be available at https://github.com/mangye16/ReID-Survey.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.06960v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mang Ye, Shuoyi Chen, Chenyue Li, Wei-Shi Zheng, David Crandall, Bo Du</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cross-Modality Perturbation Synergy Attack for Person Re-identification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.10090</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.10090v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In recent years, there has been significant research focusing on addressing security concerns in single-modal person re-identification (ReID) systems that are based on RGB images. However, the safety of cross-modality scenarios, which are more commonly encountered in practical applications involving images captured by infrared cameras, has not received adequate attention. The main challenge in cross-modality ReID lies in effectively dealing with visual differences between different modalities. For instance, infrared images are typically grayscale, unlike visible images that contain color information. Existing attack methods have primarily focused on the characteristics of the visible image modality, overlooking the features of other modalities and the variations in data distribution among different modalities. This oversight can potentially undermine the effectiveness of these methods in image retrieval across diverse modalities. This study represents the first exploration into the security of cross-modality ReID models and proposes a universal perturbation attack specifically designed for cross-modality ReID. This attack optimizes perturbations by leveraging gradients from diverse modality data, thereby disrupting the discriminator and reinforcing the differences between modalities. We conducted experiments on three widely used cross-modality datasets, namely RegDB, SYSU, and LLCM. The results not only demonstrate the effectiveness of our method but also provide insights for future improvements in the robustness of cross-modality ReID systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.10090v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yunpeng Gong, Zhun Zhong, Yansong Qu, Zhiming Luo, Rongrong Ji, Min Jiang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Auxiliary CycleGAN-guidance for Task-Aware Domain Translation from Duplex to Monoplex IHC Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.07389</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.07389v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Generative models enable the translation from a source image domain where readily trained models are available to a target domain unseen during training. While Cycle Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs) are well established, the associated cycle consistency constrain relies on that an invertible mapping exists between the two domains. This is, however, not the case for the translation between images stained with chromogenic monoplex and duplex immunohistochemistry (IHC) assays. Focusing on the translation from the latter to the first, we propose - through the introduction of a novel training design, an alternative constrain leveraging a set of immunofluorescence (IF) images as an auxiliary unpaired image domain. Quantitative and qualitative results on a downstream segmentation task show the benefit of the proposed method in comparison to baseline approaches.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.07389v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nicolas Brieu, Nicolas Triltsch, Philipp Wortmann, Dominik Winter, Shashank Saran, Marlon Rebelatto, G\"unter Schmidt</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Incremental Joint Learning of Depth, Pose and Implicit Scene Representation on Monocular Camera in Large-scale Scenes</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.06050</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.06050v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Dense scene reconstruction for photo-realistic view synthesis has various applications, such as VR/AR, autonomous vehicles. However, most existing methods have difficulties in large-scale scenes due to three core challenges: \textit{(a) inaccurate depth input.} Accurate depth input is impossible to get in real-world large-scale scenes. \textit{(b) inaccurate pose estimation.} Most existing approaches rely on accurate pre-estimated camera poses. \textit{(c) insufficient scene representation capability.} A single global radiance field lacks the capacity to effectively scale to large-scale scenes. To this end, we propose an incremental joint learning framework, which can achieve accurate depth, pose estimation, and large-scale scene reconstruction. A vision transformer-based network is adopted as the backbone to enhance performance in scale information estimation. For pose estimation, a feature-metric bundle adjustment (FBA) method is designed for accurate and robust camera tracking in large-scale scenes. In terms of implicit scene representation, we propose an incremental scene representation method to construct the entire large-scale scene as multiple local radiance fields to enhance the scalability of 3D scene representation. Extended experiments have been conducted to demonstrate the effectiveness and accuracy of our method in depth estimation, pose estimation, and large-scale scene reconstruction.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.06050v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tianchen Deng, Nailin Wang, Chongdi Wang, Shenghai Yuan, Jingchuan Wang, Danwei Wang, Weidong Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Context and Geometry Aware Voxel Transformer for Semantic Scene Completion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.13675</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.13675v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Vision-based Semantic Scene Completion (SSC) has gained much attention due to its widespread applications in various 3D perception tasks. Existing sparse-to-dense approaches typically employ shared context-independent queries across various input images, which fails to capture distinctions among them as the focal regions of different inputs vary and may result in undirected feature aggregation of cross-attention. Additionally, the absence of depth information may lead to points projected onto the image plane sharing the same 2D position or similar sampling points in the feature map, resulting in depth ambiguity. In this paper, we present a novel context and geometry aware voxel transformer. It utilizes a context aware query generator to initialize context-dependent queries tailored to individual input images, effectively capturing their unique characteristics and aggregating information within the region of interest. Furthermore, it extend deformable cross-attention from 2D to 3D pixel space, enabling the differentiation of points with similar image coordinates based on their depth coordinates. Building upon this module, we introduce a neural network named CGFormer to achieve semantic scene completion. Simultaneously, CGFormer leverages multiple 3D representations (i.e., voxel and TPV) to boost the semantic and geometric representation abilities of the transformed 3D volume from both local and global perspectives. Experimental results demonstrate that CGFormer achieves state-of-the-art performance on the SemanticKITTI and SSCBench-KITTI-360 benchmarks, attaining a mIoU of 16.87 and 20.05, as well as an IoU of 45.99 and 48.07, respectively. Remarkably, CGFormer even outperforms approaches employing temporal images as inputs or much larger image backbone networks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.13675v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhu Yu, Runmin Zhang, Jiacheng Ying, Junchen Yu, Xiaohai Hu, Lun Luo, Si-Yuan Cao, Hui-Liang Shen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RectifID: Personalizing Rectified Flow with Anchored Classifier Guidance</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.14677</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.14677v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Customizing diffusion models to generate identity-preserving images from user-provided reference images is an intriguing new problem. The prevalent approaches typically require training on extensive domain-specific images to achieve identity preservation, which lacks flexibility across different use cases. To address this issue, we exploit classifier guidance, a training-free technique that steers diffusion models using an existing classifier, for personalized image generation. Our study shows that based on a recent rectified flow framework, the major limitation of vanilla classifier guidance in requiring a special classifier can be resolved with a simple fixed-point solution, allowing flexible personalization with off-the-shelf image discriminators. Moreover, its solving procedure proves to be stable when anchored to a reference flow trajectory, with a convergence guarantee. The derived method is implemented on rectified flow with different off-the-shelf image discriminators, delivering advantageous personalization results for human faces, live subjects, and certain objects. Code is available at https://github.com/feifeiobama/RectifID.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.14677v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhicheng Sun, Zhenhao Yang, Yang Jin, Haozhe Chi, Kun Xu, Kun Xu, Liwei Chen, Hao Jiang, Yang Song, Kun Gai, Yadong Mu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Understanding the Working Mechanism of Text-to-Image Diffusion Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.15330</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.15330v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recently, the strong latent Diffusion Probabilistic Model (DPM) has been applied to high-quality Text-to-Image (T2I) generation (e.g., Stable Diffusion), by injecting the encoded target text prompt into the gradually denoised diffusion image generator. Despite the success of DPM in practice, the mechanism behind it remains to be explored. To fill this blank, we begin by examining the intermediate statuses during the gradual denoising generation process in DPM. The empirical observations indicate, the shape of image is reconstructed after the first few denoising steps, and then the image is filled with details (e.g., texture). The phenomenon is because the low-frequency signal (shape relevant) of the noisy image is not corrupted until the final stage in the forward process (initial stage of generation) of adding noise in DPM. Inspired by the observations, we proceed to explore the influence of each token in the text prompt during the two stages. After a series of experiments of T2I generations conditioned on a set of text prompts. We conclude that in the earlier generation stage, the image is mostly decided by the special token [\texttt{EOS}] in the text prompt, and the information in the text prompt is already conveyed in this stage. After that, the diffusion model completes the details of generated images by information from themselves. Finally, we propose to apply this observation to accelerate the process of T2I generation by properly removing text guidance, which finally accelerates the sampling up to 25\%+.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.15330v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>published in NeuriPS 2024</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Mingyang Yi, Aoxue Li, Yi Xin, Zhenguo Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meteor: Mamba-based Traversal of Rationale for Large Language and Vision Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.15574</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.15574v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The rapid development of large language and vision models (LLVMs) has been driven by advances in visual instruction tuning. Recently, open-source LLVMs have curated high-quality visual instruction tuning datasets and utilized additional vision encoders or multiple computer vision models in order to narrow the performance gap with powerful closed-source LLVMs. These advancements are attributed to multifaceted information required for diverse capabilities, including fundamental image understanding, real-world knowledge about common-sense and non-object concepts (e.g., charts, diagrams, symbols, signs, and math problems), and step-by-step procedures for solving complex questions. Drawing from the multifaceted information, we present a new efficient LLVM, Mamba-based traversal of rationales (Meteor), which leverages multifaceted rationale to enhance understanding and answering capabilities. To embed lengthy rationales containing abundant information, we employ the Mamba architecture, capable of processing sequential data with linear time complexity. We introduce a new concept of traversal of rationale that facilitates efficient embedding of rationale. Subsequently, the backbone multimodal language model (MLM) is trained to generate answers with the aid of rationale. Through these steps, Meteor achieves significant improvements in vision language performances across multiple evaluation benchmarks requiring diverse capabilities, without scaling up the model size or employing additional vision encoders and computer vision models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.15574v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Byung-Kwan Lee, Chae Won Kim, Beomchan Park, Yong Man Ro</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Typography Leads Semantic Diversifying: Amplifying Adversarial Transferability across Multimodal Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.20090</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.20090v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recently, Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) achieve remarkable performance in numerous zero-shot tasks due to their outstanding cross-modal interaction and comprehension abilities. However, MLLMs are found to still be vulnerable to human-imperceptible adversarial examples. In the exploration of security vulnerabilities in real-world scenarios, transferability, which can achieve cross-model impact, is considered the greatest threat posed by adversarial examples. However, there is currently no systematic research on the threat of cross-MLLMs adversarial transferability. Therefore, this paper as the first step to provide a comprehensive evaluation of the transferability of adversarial examples generated by various MLLMs. Furthermore, leveraging two key factors that influence transferability performance: 1) The strength of information diversity involved in the adversarial generation process; 2) Editing across vision-language modality information. We propose a boosting method called Typography Augment Transferability Method (TATM) to investigate the adversarial transferability performance across MLLMs further. Through extensive experimental validation, our TATM demonstrates exceptional performance in real-world applications of "Harmful Word Insertion" and "Important Information Protection".</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.20090v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hao Cheng, Erjia Xiao, Jiayan Yang, Jiahang Cao, Qiang Zhang, Le Yang, Jize Zhang, Kaidi Xu, Jindong Gu, Renjing Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4Diffusion: Multi-view Video Diffusion Model for 4D Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.20674</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.20674v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Current 4D generation methods have achieved noteworthy efficacy with the aid of advanced diffusion generative models. However, these methods lack multi-view spatial-temporal modeling and encounter challenges in integrating diverse prior knowledge from multiple diffusion models, resulting in inconsistent temporal appearance and flickers. In this paper, we propose a novel 4D generation pipeline, namely 4Diffusion, aimed at generating spatial-temporally consistent 4D content from a monocular video. We first design a unified diffusion model tailored for multi-view video generation by incorporating a learnable motion module into a frozen 3D-aware diffusion model to capture multi-view spatial-temporal correlations. After training on a curated dataset, our diffusion model acquires reasonable temporal consistency and inherently preserves the generalizability and spatial consistency of the 3D-aware diffusion model. Subsequently, we propose 4D-aware Score Distillation Sampling loss, which is based on our multi-view video diffusion model, to optimize 4D representation parameterized by dynamic NeRF. This aims to eliminate discrepancies arising from multiple diffusion models, allowing for generating spatial-temporally consistent 4D content. Moreover, we devise an anchor loss to enhance the appearance details and facilitate the learning of dynamic NeRF. Extensive qualitative and quantitative experiments demonstrate that our method achieves superior performance compared to previous methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.20674v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haiyu Zhang, Xinyuan Chen, Yaohui Wang, Xihui Liu, Yunhong Wang, Yu Qiao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Localize, Understand, Collaborate: Semantic-Aware Dragging via Intention Reasoner</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.00432</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.00432v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Flexible and accurate drag-based editing is a challenging task that has recently garnered significant attention. Current methods typically model this problem as automatically learning "how to drag" through point dragging and often produce one deterministic estimation, which presents two key limitations: 1) Overlooking the inherently ill-posed nature of drag-based editing, where multiple results may correspond to a given input, as illustrated in Fig.1; 2) Ignoring the constraint of image quality, which may lead to unexpected distortion. To alleviate this, we propose LucidDrag, which shifts the focus from "how to drag" to "what-then-how" paradigm. LucidDrag comprises an intention reasoner and a collaborative guidance sampling mechanism. The former infers several optimal editing strategies, identifying what content and what semantic direction to be edited. Based on the former, the latter addresses "how to drag" by collaboratively integrating existing editing guidance with the newly proposed semantic guidance and quality guidance. Specifically, semantic guidance is derived by establishing a semantic editing direction based on reasoned intentions, while quality guidance is achieved through classifier guidance using an image fidelity discriminator. Both qualitative and quantitative comparisons demonstrate the superiority of LucidDrag over previous methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.00432v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xing Cui, Peipei Li, Zekun Li, Xuannan Liu, Yueying Zou, Zhaofeng He</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Binarized Diffusion Model for Image Super-Resolution</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.05723</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.05723v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Advanced diffusion models (DMs) perform impressively in image super-resolution (SR), but the high memory and computational costs hinder their deployment. Binarization, an ultra-compression algorithm, offers the potential for effectively accelerating DMs. Nonetheless, due to the model structure and the multi-step iterative attribute of DMs, existing binarization methods result in significant performance degradation. In this paper, we introduce a novel binarized diffusion model, BI-DiffSR, for image SR. First, for the model structure, we design a UNet architecture optimized for binarization. We propose the consistent-pixel-downsample (CP-Down) and consistent-pixel-upsample (CP-Up) to maintain dimension consistent and facilitate the full-precision information transfer. Meanwhile, we design the channel-shuffle-fusion (CS-Fusion) to enhance feature fusion in skip connection. Second, for the activation difference across timestep, we design the timestep-aware redistribution (TaR) and activation function (TaA). The TaR and TaA dynamically adjust the distribution of activations based on different timesteps, improving the flexibility and representation alability of the binarized module. Comprehensive experiments demonstrate that our BI-DiffSR outperforms existing binarization methods. Code is released at: https://github.com/zhengchen1999/BI-DiffSR.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.05723v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zheng Chen, Haotong Qin, Yong Guo, Xiongfei Su, Xin Yuan, Linghe Kong, Yulun Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward Fairer Face Recognition Datasets</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.16592</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.16592v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Face recognition and verification are two computer vision tasks whose performance has progressed with the introduction of deep representations. However, ethical, legal, and technical challenges due to the sensitive character of face data and biases in real training datasets hinder their development. Generative AI addresses privacy by creating fictitious identities, but fairness problems persist. We promote fairness by introducing a demographic attributes balancing mechanism in generated training datasets. We experiment with an existing real dataset, three generated training datasets, and the balanced versions of a diffusion-based dataset. We propose a comprehensive evaluation that considers accuracy and fairness equally and includes a rigorous regression-based statistical analysis of attributes. The analysis shows that balancing reduces demographic unfairness. Also, a performance gap persists despite generation becoming more accurate with time. The proposed balancing method and comprehensive verification evaluation promote fairer and transparent face recognition and verification.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.16592v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alexandre Fournier-Mongieux, Michael Soumm, Adrian Popescu, Bertrand Luvison, Herv\'e Le Borgne</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SCMIL: Sparse Context-aware Multiple Instance Learning for Predicting Cancer Survival Probability Distribution in Whole Slide Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.00664</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.00664v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Cancer survival prediction is a challenging task that involves analyzing of the tumor microenvironment within Whole Slide Image (WSI). Previous methods cannot effectively capture the intricate interaction features among instances within the local area of WSI. Moreover, existing methods for cancer survival prediction based on WSI often fail to provide better clinically meaningful predictions. To overcome these challenges, we propose a Sparse Context-aware Multiple Instance Learning (SCMIL) framework for predicting cancer survival probability distributions. SCMIL innovatively segments patches into various clusters based on their morphological features and spatial location information, subsequently leveraging sparse self-attention to discern the relationships between these patches with a context-aware perspective. Considering many patches are irrelevant to the task, we introduce a learnable patch filtering module called SoftFilter, which ensures that only interactions between task-relevant patches are considered. To enhance the clinical relevance of our prediction, we propose a register-based mixture density network to forecast the survival probability distribution for individual patients. We evaluate SCMIL on two public WSI datasets from the The Cancer Genome Atlas (TCGA) specifically focusing on lung adenocarcinom (LUAD) and kidney renal clear cell carcinoma (KIRC). Our experimental results indicate that SCMIL outperforms current state-of-the-art methods for survival prediction, offering more clinically meaningful and interpretable outcomes. Our code is accessible at https://github.com/yang-ze-kang/SCMIL.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.00664v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1007/978-3-031-72083-3_42</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Zekang Yang, Hong Liu, Xiangdong Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3D Adaptive Structural Convolution Network for Domain-Invariant Point Cloud Recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.04833</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.04833v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Adapting deep learning networks for point cloud data recognition in self-driving vehicles faces challenges due to the variability in datasets and sensor technologies, emphasizing the need for adaptive techniques to maintain accuracy across different conditions. In this paper, we introduce the 3D Adaptive Structural Convolution Network (3D-ASCN), a cutting-edge framework for 3D point cloud recognition. It combines 3D convolution kernels, a structural tree structure, and adaptive neighborhood sampling for effective geometric feature extraction. This method obtains domain-invariant features and demonstrates robust, adaptable performance on a variety of point cloud datasets, ensuring compatibility across diverse sensor configurations without the need for parameter adjustments. This highlights its potential to significantly enhance the reliability and efficiency of self-driving vehicle technology.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.04833v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>ACCV 2024 (Asian Conference on Computer Vision)</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Younggun Kim, Beomsik Cho, Seonghoon Ryoo, Soomok Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ReCAP: Recursive Cross Attention Network for Pseudo-Label Generation in Robotic Surgical Skill Assessment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.05180</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.05180v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In surgical skill assessment, Objective Structured Assessments of Technical Skills (OSATS scores) and the Global Rating Scale (GRS) are established tools for evaluating the performance of surgeons during training. These metrics, coupled with feedback on their performance, enable surgeons to improve and achieve standards of practice. Recent studies on the open-source dataset JIGSAW, which contains both GRS and OSATS labels, have focused on regressing GRS scores from kinematic signals, video data, or a combination of both. In this paper, we argue that regressing the GRS score, a unitless value, by itself is too restrictive, and variations throughout the surgical trial do not hold significant clinical meaning. To address this gap, we developed a recurrent transformer model that outputs the surgeon's performance throughout their training session by relating the model's hidden states to five OSATS scores derived from kinematic signals. These scores are averaged and aggregated to produce a GRS prediction, enabling assessment of the model's performance against the state-of-the-art (SOTA). We report Spearman's Correlation Coefficient (SCC), demonstrating that our model outperforms SOTA models for all tasks, except for Suturing under the leave-one-subject-out (LOSO) scheme (SCC 0.68-0.89), while achieving comparable performance for suturing and across tasks under the leave-one-user-out (LOUO) scheme (SCC 0.45-0.68) and beating SOTA for Needle Passing (0.69). We argue that relating final OSATS scores to short instances throughout a surgeon's procedure is more clinically meaningful than a single GRS score. This approach also allows us to translate quantitative predictions into qualitative feedback, which is crucial for any automated surgical skill assessment pipeline. A senior surgeon validated our model's behaviour and agreed with the semi-supervised predictions 77 \% (p = 0.006) of the time.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.05180v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Julien Quarez, Matthew Elliot, Oscar Maccormac, Marc Modat, Sebastien Ourselin, Jonathan Shapey, Alejandro Granados</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DPEC: Dual-Path Error Compensation Method for Enhanced Low-Light Image Clarity</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.09553</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.09553v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: For the task of low-light image enhancement, deep learning-based algorithms have demonstrated superiority and effectiveness compared to traditional methods. Existing deep learning algorithms are proposed mainly based on the Retinex theory but overlook the noise and color distortion present in the input, which frequently results in significant noise amplification and local color distortion in the final results. To address this, we propose a Dual-Path Error Compensation method (DPEC), which aims to improve image quality in low-light conditions. DPEC performs precise pixel-level error estimation, which accurately captures subtle pixels differences, and independent denoising, which effectively removes unnecessary noise. This method restores image brightness while preserving local texture details and avoiding noise amplification. Furthermore, to compensate for the traditional CNN's limited ability to capture long-range semantic information and considering both computational speed and resource efficiency, we integrated the VMamba architecture into the backbone of DPEC. In addition, we introduced the HIS-Retinex loss to constrain the training of DPEC, ensuring that the overall brightness distribution of the images more closely aligns with real-world conditions. Comprehensive quantitative and qualitative experimental results demonstrate that our algorithm significantly outperforms state-of-the-art methods across six benchmark tests.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.09553v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shuang Wang, Qianwen Lu, Yihe Nie, Qingchuan Tao, Yanmei Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mask-guided cross-image attention for zero-shot in-silico histopathologic image generation with a diffusion model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.11664</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.11664v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Creating in-silico data with generative AI promises a cost-effective alternative to staining, imaging, and annotating whole slide images in computational pathology. Diffusion models are the state-of-the-art solution for generating in-silico images, offering unparalleled fidelity and realism. Using appearance transfer diffusion models allows for zero-shot image generation, facilitating fast application and making model training unnecessary. However current appearance transfer diffusion models are designed for natural images, where the main task is to transfer the foreground object from an origin to a target domain, while the background is of insignificant importance. In computational pathology, specifically in oncology, it is however not straightforward to define which objects in an image should be classified as foreground and background, as all objects in an image may be of critical importance for the detailed understanding the tumor micro-environment. We contribute to the applicability of appearance transfer diffusion models to immunohistochemistry-stained images by modifying the appearance transfer guidance to alternate between class-specific AdaIN feature statistics matchings using existing segmentation masks. The performance of the proposed method is demonstrated on the downstream task of supervised epithelium segmentation, showing that the number of manual annotations required for model training can be reduced by 75%, outperforming the baseline approach. Additionally, we consulted with a certified pathologist to investigate future improvements. We anticipate this work to inspire the application of zero-shot diffusion models in computational pathology, providing an efficient method to generate in-silico images with unmatched fidelity and realism, which prove meaningful for downstream tasks, such as training existing deep learning models or finetuning foundation models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.11664v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dominik Winter, Nicolas Triltsch, Marco Rosati, Anatoliy Shumilov, Ziya Kokaragac, Yuri Popov, Thomas Padel, Laura Sebastian Monasor, Ross Hill, Markus Schick, Nicolas Brieu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UrbanWorld: An Urban World Model for 3D City Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.11965</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.11965v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Cities, as the essential environment of human life, encompass diverse physical elements such as buildings, roads and vegetation, which continuously interact with dynamic entities like people and vehicles. Crafting realistic, interactive 3D urban environments is essential for nurturing AGI systems and constructing AI agents capable of perceiving, decision-making, and acting like humans in real-world environments. However, creating high-fidelity 3D urban environments usually entails extensive manual labor from designers, involving intricate detailing and representation of complex urban elements. Therefore, accomplishing this automatically remains a longstanding challenge. Toward this problem, we propose UrbanWorld, the first generative urban world model that can automatically create a customized, realistic and interactive 3D urban world with flexible control conditions. UrbanWorld incorporates four key stages in the generation pipeline: flexible 3D layout generation from OSM data or urban layout with semantic and height maps, urban scene design with Urban MLLM, controllable urban asset rendering via progressive 3D diffusion, and MLLM-assisted scene refinement. We conduct extensive quantitative analysis on five visual metrics, demonstrating that UrbanWorld achieves SOTA generation realism. Next, we provide qualitative results about the controllable generation capabilities of UrbanWorld using both textual and image-based prompts. Lastly, we verify the interactive nature of these environments by showcasing the agent perception and navigation within the created environments. We contribute UrbanWorld as an open-source tool available at https://github.com/Urban-World/UrbanWorld.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.11965v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yu Shang, Yuming Lin, Yu Zheng, Hangyu Fan, Jingtao Ding, Jie Feng, Jiansheng Chen, Li Tian, Yong Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mitral Regurgitation Recognition based on Unsupervised Out-of-Distribution Detection with Residual Diffusion Amplification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.21497</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.21497v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Mitral regurgitation (MR) is a serious heart valve disease. Early and accurate diagnosis of MR via ultrasound video is critical for timely clinical decision-making and surgical intervention. However, manual MR diagnosis heavily relies on the operator's experience, which may cause misdiagnosis and inter-observer variability. Since MR data is limited and has large intra-class variability, we propose an unsupervised out-of-distribution (OOD) detection method to identify MR rather than building a deep classifier. To our knowledge, we are the first to explore OOD in MR ultrasound videos. Our method consists of a feature extractor, a feature reconstruction model, and a residual accumulation amplification algorithm. The feature extractor obtains features from the video clips and feeds them into the feature reconstruction model to restore the original features. The residual accumulation amplification algorithm then iteratively performs noise feature reconstruction, amplifying the reconstructed error of OOD features. This algorithm is straightforward yet efficient and can seamlessly integrate as a plug-and-play component in reconstruction-based OOD detection methods. We validated the proposed method on a large ultrasound dataset containing 893 non-MR and 267 MR videos. Experimental results show that our OOD detection method can effectively identify MR samples.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.21497v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhe Liu, Xiliang Zhu, Tong Han, Yuhao Huang, Jian Wang, Lian Liu, Fang Wang, Dong Ni, Zhongshan Gou, Xin Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Lightweight Modular Framework for Low-Cost Open-Vocabulary Object Detection Training</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.10787</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.10787v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Object detection is a fundamental challenge in computer vision, centered on recognizing objects within images, with diverse applications in areas like image analysis, robotics, and autonomous vehicles. Although existing methods have achieved great success, they are often constrained by a fixed vocabulary of objects. To overcome this limitation, approaches like MDETR have redefined object detection by incorporating region-level vision-language pre-training, enabling open-vocabulary object detectors. However, these methods are computationally heavy due to the simultaneous training of large models for both vision and language representations. To address this, we introduce a lightweight framework that significantly reduces the number of parameters while preserving, or even improving, performance. Our solution is applied to MDETR, resulting in the development of Lightweight MDETR (LightMDETR), an optimized version of MDETR designed to enhance computational efficiency without sacrificing accuracy. The core of our approach involves freezing the MDETR backbone and training only the Universal Projection module (UP), which bridges vision and language representations. A learnable modality token parameter allows the UP to seamlessly switch between modalities. Evaluations on tasks like phrase grounding, referring expression comprehension, and segmentation show that LightMDETR not only reduces computational costs but also outperforms several state-of-the-art methods in terms of accuracy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.10787v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bilal Faye, Binta Sow, Hanane Azzag, Mustapha Lebbah</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compress Guidance in Conditional Diffusion Sampling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11194</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11194v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We found that enforcing guidance throughout the sampling process is often counterproductive due to the model-fitting issue, where samples are 'tuned' to match the classifier's parameters rather than generalizing the expected condition. This work identifies and quantifies the problem, demonstrating that reducing or excluding guidance at numerous timesteps can mitigate this issue. By distributing a small amount of guidance over a large number of sampling timesteps, we observe a significant improvement in image quality and diversity while also reducing the required guidance timesteps by nearly 40%. This approach addresses a major challenge in applying guidance effectively to generative tasks. Consequently, our proposed method, termed Compress Guidance, allows for the exclusion of a substantial number of guidance timesteps while still surpassing baseline models in image quality. We validate our approach through benchmarks on label-conditional and text-to-image generative tasks across various datasets and models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11194v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Anh-Dung Dinh, Daochang Liu, Chang Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Onboard Satellite Image Classification for Earth Observation: A Comparative Study of ViT Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.03901</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.03901v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This study focuses on identifying the most effective pre-trained model for land use classification in onboard satellite processing, emphasizing achieving high accuracy, computational efficiency, and robustness against noisy data conditions commonly encountered during satellite-based inference. Through extensive experimentation, we compare the performance of traditional CNN-based, ResNet-based, and various pre-trained vision Transformer models. Our findings demonstrate that pre-trained Vision Transformer (ViT) models, particularly MobileViTV2 and EfficientViT-M2, outperform models trained from scratch in terms of accuracy and efficiency. These models achieve high performance with reduced computational requirements and exhibit greater resilience during inference under noisy conditions. While MobileViTV2 has excelled on clean validation data, EfficientViT-M2 has proved more robust when handling noise, making it the most suitable model for onboard satellite EO tasks. Our experimental results demonstrate that EfficientViT-M2 is the optimal choice for reliable and efficient RS-IC in satellite operations, achieving 98.76 % of accuracy, precision, and recall. Precisely, EfficientViT-M2 delivers the highest performance across all metrics, excels in training efficiency (1,000s) and inference time (10s), and demonstrates greater robustness (overall robustness score of 0.79). Consequently, EfficientViT-M2 consumes 63.93 % less power than MobileViTV2 (79.23 W) and 73.26 % less power than SwinTransformer (108.90 W). This highlights its significant advantage in energy efficiency.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.03901v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.SP</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Thanh-Dung Le, Vu Nguyen Ha, Ti Ti Nguyen, Geoffrey Eappen, Prabhu Thiruvasagam, Luis M. Garces-Socarras, Hong-fu Chou, Jorge L. Gonzalez-Rios, Juan Carlos Merlano-Duncan, Symeon Chatzinotas</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taming Diffusion Models for Image Restoration: A Review</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.10353</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.10353v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Diffusion models have achieved remarkable progress in generative modelling, particularly in enhancing image quality to conform to human preferences. Recently, these models have also been applied to low-level computer vision for photo-realistic image restoration (IR) in tasks such as image denoising, deblurring, dehazing, etc. In this review paper, we introduce key constructions in diffusion models and survey contemporary techniques that make use of diffusion models in solving general IR tasks. Furthermore, we point out the main challenges and limitations of existing diffusion-based IR frameworks and provide potential directions for future work.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.10353v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ziwei Luo, Fredrik K. Gustafsson, Zheng Zhao, Jens Sj\"olund, Thomas B. Sch\"on</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Playground v3: Improving Text-to-Image Alignment with Deep-Fusion Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.10695</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.10695v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We introduce Playground v3 (PGv3), our latest text-to-image model that achieves state-of-the-art (SoTA) performance across multiple testing benchmarks, excels in graphic design abilities and introduces new capabilities. Unlike traditional text-to-image generative models that rely on pre-trained language models like T5 or CLIP text encoders, our approach fully integrates Large Language Models (LLMs) with a novel structure that leverages text conditions exclusively from a decoder-only LLM. Additionally, to enhance image captioning quality-we developed an in-house captioner, capable of generating captions with varying levels of detail, enriching the diversity of text structures. We also introduce a new benchmark CapsBench to evaluate detailed image captioning performance. Experimental results demonstrate that PGv3 excels in text prompt adherence, complex reasoning, and accurate text rendering. User preference studies indicate the super-human graphic design ability of our model for common design applications, such as stickers, posters, and logo designs. Furthermore, PGv3 introduces new capabilities, including precise RGB color control and robust multilingual understanding.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.10695v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bingchen Liu, Ehsan Akhgari, Alexander Visheratin, Aleks Kamko, Linmiao Xu, Shivam Shrirao, Chase Lambert, Joao Souza, Suhail Doshi, Daiqing Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oryx MLLM: On-Demand Spatial-Temporal Understanding at Arbitrary Resolution</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.12961</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.12961v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Visual data comes in various forms, ranging from small icons of just a few pixels to long videos spanning hours. Existing multi-modal LLMs usually standardize these diverse visual inputs to a fixed resolution for visual encoders and yield similar numbers of tokens for LLMs. This approach is non-optimal for multimodal understanding and inefficient for processing inputs with long and short visual contents. To solve the problem, we propose Oryx, a unified multimodal architecture for the spatial-temporal understanding of images, videos, and multi-view 3D scenes. Oryx offers an on-demand solution to seamlessly and efficiently process visual inputs with arbitrary spatial sizes and temporal lengths through two core innovations: 1) a pre-trained OryxViT model that can encode images at any resolution into LLM-friendly visual representations; 2) a dynamic compressor module that supports 1x to 16x compression on visual tokens by request. These design features enable Oryx to accommodate extremely long visual contexts, such as videos, with lower resolution and high compression while maintaining high recognition precision for tasks like document understanding with native resolution and no compression. Beyond the architectural improvements, enhanced data curation and specialized training on long-context retrieval and spatial-aware data help Oryx achieve strong capabilities in image, video, and 3D multimodal understanding simultaneously. Our work is open-sourced at https://github.com/Oryx-mllm/Oryx.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.12961v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zuyan Liu, Yuhao Dong, Ziwei Liu, Winston Hu, Jiwen Lu, Yongming Rao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PixelBytes: Catching Unified Embedding for Multimodal Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.15512</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.15512v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This report introduces PixelBytes Embedding, a novel approach for unified multimodal representation learning. Our method captures diverse inputs in a single, cohesive representation, enabling emergent properties for multimodal sequence generation, particularly for text and pixelated images. Inspired by state-of-the-art sequence models such as Image Transformers, PixelCNN, and Mamba-Bytes, PixelBytes aims to address the challenges of integrating different data types. We explore various model architectures, including Recurrent Neural Networks (RNNs), State Space Models (SSMs), and Attention-based models, focusing on bidirectional processing and our innovative PxBy embedding technique. Our experiments, conducted on a specialized PixelBytes Pok{\'e}mon dataset, demonstrate that bidirectional sequence models with PxBy embedding and convolutional layers can generate coherent multimodal sequences. This work contributes to the advancement of integrated AI models capable of understanding and generating multimodal data in a unified manner.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.15512v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fabien Furfaro</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EP-SAM: Weakly Supervised Histopathology Segmentation via Enhanced Prompt with Segment Anything</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.13621</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.13621v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This work proposes a novel approach beyond supervised learning for effective pathological image analysis, addressing the challenge of limited robust labeled data. Pathological diagnosis of diseases like cancer has conventionally relied on the evaluation of morphological features by physicians and pathologists. However, recent advancements in compute-aided diagnosis (CAD) systems are gaining significant attention as diagnostic support tools. Although the advancement of deep learning has improved CAD significantly, segmentation models typically require large pixel-level annotated dataset, and such labeling is expensive. Existing studies not based on supervised approaches still struggle with limited generalization, and no practical approach has emerged yet. To address this issue, we present a weakly supervised semantic segmentation (WSSS) model by combining class activation map and Segment Anything Model (SAM)-based pseudo-labeling. For effective pretraining, we adopt the SAM-a foundation model that is pretrained on large datasets and operates in zero-shot configurations using only coarse prompts. The proposed approach transfer enhanced Attention Dropout Layer's knowledge to SAM, thereby generating pseudo-labels. To demonstrate the superiority of the proposed method, experimental studies are conducted on histopathological breast cancer datasets. The proposed method outperformed other WSSS methods across three datasets, demonstrating its efficiency by achieving this with only 12GB of GPU memory during training. Our code is available at : https://github.com/QI-NemoSong/EP-SAM</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.13621v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Joonhyeon Song, Seohwan Yun, Seongho Yoon, Joohyeok Kim, Sangmin Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NaturalBench: Evaluating Vision-Language Models on Natural Adversarial Samples</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.14669</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.14669v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Vision-language models (VLMs) have made significant progress in recent visual-question-answering (VQA) benchmarks that evaluate complex visio-linguistic reasoning. However, are these models truly effective? In this work, we show that VLMs still struggle with natural images and questions that humans can easily answer, which we term natural adversarial samples. We also find it surprisingly easy to generate these VQA samples from natural image-text corpora using off-the-shelf models like CLIP and ChatGPT. We propose a semi-automated approach to collect a new benchmark, NaturalBench, for reliably evaluating VLMs with 10,000 human-verified VQA samples. Crucially, we adopt a $\textbf{vision-centric}$ design by pairing each question with two images that yield different answers, preventing blind solutions from answering without using the images. This makes NaturalBench more challenging than previous benchmarks that can be solved with commonsense priors. We evaluate 53 state-of-the-art VLMs on NaturalBench, showing that models like LLaVA-OneVision, Cambrian-1, Llama3.2-Vision, Molmo, Qwen2-VL, and even GPT-4o lag 50%-70% behind human performance (over 90%). We analyze why NaturalBench is hard from two angles: (1) Compositionality: Solving NaturalBench requires diverse visio-linguistic skills, including understanding attribute bindings, object relationships, and advanced reasoning like logic and counting. To this end, unlike prior work that uses a single tag per sample, we tag each NaturalBench sample with 1 to 8 skill tags for fine-grained evaluation. (2) Biases: NaturalBench exposes severe biases in VLMs, as models often choose the same answer regardless of the image. Lastly, we apply our benchmark curation method to diverse data sources, including long captions (over 100 words) and non-English languages like Chinese and Hindi, highlighting its potential for dynamic evaluations of VLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.14669v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Baiqi Li, Zhiqiu Lin, Wenxuan Peng, Jean de Dieu Nyandwi, Daniel Jiang, Zixian Ma, Simran Khanuja, Ranjay Krishna, Graham Neubig, Deva Ramanan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DCDepth: Progressive Monocular Depth Estimation in Discrete Cosine Domain</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.14980</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.14980v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this paper, we introduce DCDepth, a novel framework for the long-standing monocular depth estimation task. Moving beyond conventional pixel-wise depth estimation in the spatial domain, our approach estimates the frequency coefficients of depth patches after transforming them into the discrete cosine domain. This unique formulation allows for the modeling of local depth correlations within each patch. Crucially, the frequency transformation segregates the depth information into various frequency components, with low-frequency components encapsulating the core scene structure and high-frequency components detailing the finer aspects. This decomposition forms the basis of our progressive strategy, which begins with the prediction of low-frequency components to establish a global scene context, followed by successive refinement of local details through the prediction of higher-frequency components. We conduct comprehensive experiments on NYU-Depth-V2, TOFDC, and KITTI datasets, and demonstrate the state-of-the-art performance of DCDepth. Code is available at https://github.com/w2kun/DCDepth.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.14980v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kun Wang, Zhiqiang Yan, Junkai Fan, Wanlu Zhu, Xiang Li, Jun Li, Jian Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fully Explicit Dynamic Gaussian Splatting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.15629</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.15629v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: 3D Gaussian Splatting has shown fast and high-quality rendering results in static scenes by leveraging dense 3D prior and explicit representations. Unfortunately, the benefits of the prior and representation do not involve novel view synthesis for dynamic motions. Ironically, this is because the main barrier is the reliance on them, which requires increasing training and rendering times to account for dynamic motions. In this paper, we design a Explicit 4D Gaussian Splatting(Ex4DGS). Our key idea is to firstly separate static and dynamic Gaussians during training, and to explicitly sample positions and rotations of the dynamic Gaussians at sparse timestamps. The sampled positions and rotations are then interpolated to represent both spatially and temporally continuous motions of objects in dynamic scenes as well as reducing computational cost. Additionally, we introduce a progressive training scheme and a point-backtracking technique that improves Ex4DGS's convergence. We initially train Ex4DGS using short timestamps and progressively extend timestamps, which makes it work well with a few point clouds. The point-backtracking is used to quantify the cumulative error of each Gaussian over time, enabling the detection and removal of erroneous Gaussians in dynamic scenes. Comprehensive experiments on various scenes demonstrate the state-of-the-art rendering quality from our method, achieving fast rendering of 62 fps on a single 2080Ti GPU.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.15629v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junoh Lee, Chang-Yeon Won, Hyunjun Jung, Inhwan Bae, Hae-Gon Jeon</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LucidFusion: Generating 3D Gaussians with Arbitrary Unposed Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.15636</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.15636v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent large reconstruction models have made notable progress in generating high-quality 3D objects from single images. However, these methods often struggle with controllability, as they lack information from multiple views, leading to incomplete or inconsistent 3D reconstructions. To address this limitation, we introduce LucidFusion, a flexible end-to-end feed-forward framework that leverages the Relative Coordinate Map (RCM). Unlike traditional methods linking images to 3D world thorough pose, LucidFusion utilizes RCM to align geometric features coherently across different views, making it highly adaptable for 3D generation from arbitrary, unposed images. Furthermore, LucidFusion seamlessly integrates with the original single-image-to-3D pipeline, producing detailed 3D Gaussians at a resolution of $512 \times 512$, making it well-suited for a wide range of applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.15636v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hao He, Yixun Liang, Luozhou Wang, Yuanhao Cai, Xinli Xu, Hao-Xiang Guo, Xiang Wen, Yingcong Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reducing Hallucinations in Vision-Language Models via Latent Space Steering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.15778</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.15778v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Hallucination poses a challenge to the deployment of large vision-language models (LVLMs) in applications. Unlike in large language models (LLMs), hallucination in LVLMs often arises from misalignments between visual inputs and textual outputs. This paper investigates the underlying mechanisms of hallucination, focusing on the unique structure of LVLMs that distinguishes them from large language models (LLMs). We identify that hallucinations often arise from the sensitivity of text decoders to vision inputs, a natural phenomenon when image encoders and text decoders are pre-trained separately. Inspired by this, we introduce Visual and Textual Intervention (VTI), a novel technique designed to reduce hallucinations by steering latent space representations during inference to enhance the stability of vision features. As a task-agnostic test-time intervention, VTI can be easily applied to any problem without additional cost. Extensive experiments demonstrate that it can effectively reduce hallucinations and outperform baseline methods across multiple metrics, highlighting the critical role of vision feature stability in LVLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.15778v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sheng Liu, Haotian Ye, Lei Xing, James Zou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CamI2V: Camera-Controlled Image-to-Video Diffusion Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.15957</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.15957v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recently, camera pose, as a user-friendly and physics-related condition, has been introduced into text-to-video diffusion model for camera control. However, existing methods simply inject camera conditions through a side input. These approaches neglect the inherent physical knowledge of camera pose, resulting in imprecise camera control, inconsistencies, and also poor interpretability. In this paper, we emphasize the necessity of integrating explicit physical constraints into model design. Epipolar attention is proposed for modeling all cross-frame relationships from a novel perspective of noised condition. This ensures that features are aggregated from corresponding epipolar lines in all noised frames, overcoming the limitations of current attention mechanisms in tracking displaced features across frames, especially when features move significantly with the camera and become obscured by noise. Additionally, we introduce register tokens to handle cases without intersections between frames, commonly caused by rapid camera movements, dynamic objects, or occlusions. To support image-to-video, we propose the multiple guidance scale to allow for precise control for image, text, and camera, respectively. Furthermore, we establish a more robust and reproducible evaluation pipeline to solve the inaccuracy and instability of existing camera control measurement. We achieve a 25.5% improvement in camera controllability on RealEstate10K while maintaining strong generalization to out-of-domain images. Only 24GB and 12GB are required for training and inference, respectively. We plan to release checkpoints, along with training and evaluation codes. Dynamic videos are best viewed at https://zgctroy.github.io/CamI2V.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.15957v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Guangcong Zheng, Teng Li, Rui Jiang, Yehao Lu, Tao Wu, Xi Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Granularity Matters in Long-Tail Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.15980</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.15980v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Balancing training on long-tail data distributions remains a long-standing challenge in deep learning. While methods such as re-weighting and re-sampling help alleviate the imbalance issue, limited sample diversity continues to hinder models from learning robust and generalizable feature representations, particularly for tail classes. In contrast to existing methods, we offer a novel perspective on long-tail learning, inspired by an observation: datasets with finer granularity tend to be less affected by data imbalance. In this paper, we investigate this phenomenon through both quantitative and qualitative studies, showing that increased granularity enhances the generalization of learned features in tail categories. Motivated by these findings, we propose a method to increase dataset granularity through category extrapolation. Specifically, we introduce open-set auxiliary classes that are visually similar to existing ones, aiming to enhance representation learning for both head and tail classes. This forms the core contribution and insight of our approach. To automate the curation of auxiliary data, we leverage large language models (LLMs) as knowledge bases to search for auxiliary categories and retrieve relevant images through web crawling. To prevent the overwhelming presence of auxiliary classes from disrupting training, we introduce a neighbor-silencing loss that encourages the model to focus on class discrimination within the target dataset. During inference, the classifier weights for auxiliary categories are masked out, leaving only the target class weights for use. Extensive experiments and ablation studies on three standard long-tail benchmarks demonstrate the effectiveness of our approach, notably outperforming strong baseline methods that use the same amount of data. The code will be made publicly available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.15980v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shizhen Zhao, Xin Wen, Jiahui Liu, Chuofan Ma, Chunfeng Yuan, Xiaojuan Qi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Warped Diffusion: Solving Video Inverse Problems with Image Diffusion Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16152</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16152v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Using image models naively for solving inverse video problems often suffers from flickering, texture-sticking, and temporal inconsistency in generated videos. To tackle these problems, in this paper, we view frames as continuous functions in the 2D space, and videos as a sequence of continuous warping transformations between different frames. This perspective allows us to train function space diffusion models only on images and utilize them to solve temporally correlated inverse problems. The function space diffusion models need to be equivariant with respect to the underlying spatial transformations. To ensure temporal consistency, we introduce a simple post-hoc test-time guidance towards (self)-equivariant solutions. Our method allows us to deploy state-of-the-art latent diffusion models such as Stable Diffusion XL to solve video inverse problems. We demonstrate the effectiveness of our method for video inpainting and $8\times$ video super-resolution, outperforming existing techniques based on noise transformations. We provide generated video results: https://giannisdaras.github.io/warped_diffusion.github.io/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16152v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Giannis Daras, Weili Nie, Karsten Kreis, Alex Dimakis, Morteza Mardani, Nikola Borislavov Kovachki, Arash Vahdat</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mini-InternVL: A Flexible-Transfer Pocket Multimodal Model with 5% Parameters and 90% Performance</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16261</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.16261v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Multimodal large language models (MLLMs) have demonstrated impressive performance in vision-language tasks across a broad spectrum of domains. However, the large model scale and associated high computational costs pose significant challenges for training and deploying MLLMs on consumer-grade GPUs or edge devices, thereby hindering their widespread application. In this work, we introduce Mini-InternVL, a series of MLLMs with parameters ranging from 1B to 4B, which achieves 90% of the performance with only 5% of the parameters. This significant improvement in efficiency and effectiveness makes our models more accessible and applicable in various real-world scenarios. To further promote the adoption of our models, we develop a unified adaptation framework for Mini-InternVL, which enables our models to transfer and outperform specialized models in downstream tasks, including autonomous driving, medical images, and remote sensing. We believe that our study can provide valuable insights and resources to advance the development of efficient and effective MLLMs. Code is available at https://github.com/OpenGVLab/InternVL.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.16261v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhangwei Gao, Zhe Chen, Erfei Cui, Yiming Ren, Weiyun Wang, Jinguo Zhu, Hao Tian, Shenglong Ye, Junjun He, Xizhou Zhu, Lewei Lu, Tong Lu, Yu Qiao, Jifeng Dai, Wenhai Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TensorProjection Layer: A Tensor-Based Dimension Reduction Method in Deep Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2004.04454</link>
      <description>arXiv:2004.04454v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In this paper, we propose a dimension reduction method specifically designed for tensor-structured feature data in deep neural networks. The method is implemented as a hidden layer, called the TensorProjection layer, which transforms input tensors into output tensors with reduced dimensions through mode-wise projections. The projection directions are treated as model parameters of the layer and are optimized during model training. Our method can serve as an alternative to pooling layers for summarizing image data, or to convolutional layers as a technique for reducing the number of channels. We conduct experiments on tasks such as medical image classification and segmentation, integrating the TensorProjection layer into commonly used baseline architectures to evaluate its effectiveness. Numerical experiments indicate that the proposed method can outperform traditional downsampling methods, such as pooling layers, in our tasks, suggesting it as a promising alternative for feature summarization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2004.04454v2</guid>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Toshinari Morimoto, Su-Yun Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Feature Attribution Methods for Electrocardiogram</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2211.12702</link>
      <description>arXiv:2211.12702v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The performance of cardiac arrhythmia detection with electrocardiograms(ECGs) has been considerably improved since the introduction of deep learning models. In practice, the high performance alone is not sufficient and a proper explanation is also required. Recently, researchers have started adopting feature attribution methods to address this requirement, but it has been unclear which of the methods are appropriate for ECG. In this work, we identify and customize three evaluation metrics for feature attribution methods based on the characteristics of ECG: localization score, pointing game, and degradation score. Using the three evaluation metrics, we evaluate and analyze eleven widely-used feature attribution methods. We find that some of the feature attribution methods are much more adequate for explaining ECG, where Grad-CAM outperforms the second-best method by a large margin.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2211.12702v2</guid>
      <category>eess.SP</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jangwon Suh, Jimyeong Kim, Euna Jung, Wonjong Rhee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forgettable Federated Linear Learning with Certified Data Unlearning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2306.02216</link>
      <description>arXiv:2306.02216v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The advent of Federated Learning (FL) has revolutionized the way distributed systems handle collaborative model training while preserving user privacy. Recently, Federated Unlearning (FU) has emerged to address demands for the "right to be forgotten"" and unlearning of the impact of poisoned clients without requiring retraining in FL. Most FU algorithms require the cooperation of retained or target clients (clients to be unlearned), introducing additional communication overhead and potential security risks. In addition, some FU methods need to store historical models to execute the unlearning process. These challenges hinder the efficiency and memory constraints of the current FU methods. Moreover, due to the complexity of nonlinear models and their training strategies, most existing FU methods for deep neural networks (DNN) lack theoretical certification. In this work, we introduce a novel FL training and unlearning strategy in DNN, termed Forgettable Federated Linear Learning (F^2L^2). F^2L^2 considers a common practice of using pre-trained models to approximate DNN linearly, allowing them to achieve similar performance as the original networks via Federated Linear Training (FLT). We then present FedRemoval, a certified, efficient, and secure unlearning strategy that enables the server to unlearn a target client without requiring client communication or adding additional storage. We have conducted extensive empirical validation on small- to large-scale datasets, using both convolutional neural networks and modern foundation models. These experiments demonstrate the effectiveness of F^2L^2 in balancing model accuracy with the successful unlearning of target clients. F^2L^2 represents a promising pipeline for efficient and trustworthy FU. The code is available here.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2306.02216v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ruinan Jin, Minghui Chen, Qiong Zhang, Xiaoxiao Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>StochGradAdam: Accelerating Neural Networks Training with Stochastic Gradient Sampling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.17042</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.17042v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In this paper, we introduce StochGradAdam, a novel optimizer designed as an extension of the Adam algorithm, incorporating stochastic gradient sampling techniques to improve computational efficiency while maintaining robust performance. StochGradAdam optimizes by selectively sampling a subset of gradients during training, reducing the computational cost while preserving the advantages of adaptive learning rates and bias corrections found in Adam. Our experimental results, applied to image classification and segmentation tasks, demonstrate that StochGradAdam can achieve comparable or superior performance to Adam, even when using fewer gradient updates per iteration. By focusing on key gradient updates, StochGradAdam offers stable convergence and enhanced exploration of the loss landscape, while mitigating the impact of noisy gradients. The results suggest that this approach is particularly effective for large-scale models and datasets, providing a promising alternative to traditional optimization techniques for deep learning applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.17042v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.NE</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Juyoung Yun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Simplicity Bias of Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.02622</link>
      <description>arXiv:2311.02622v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Neural networks often exhibit simplicity bias, favoring simpler features over more complex ones, even when both are equally predictive. We introduce a novel method called imbalanced label coupling to explore and extend this simplicity bias across multiple hierarchical levels. Our approach demonstrates that trained networks sequentially consider features of increasing complexity based on their correlation with labels in the training set, regardless of their actual predictive power. For example, in CIFAR-10, simple spurious features can cause misclassifications where most cats are predicted as dogs and most trucks as automobiles. We empirically show that last-layer retraining with target data distribution \citep{kirichenko2022last} is insufficient to fully recover core features when spurious features perfectly correlate with target labels in our synthetic datasets. Our findings deepen the understanding of the implicit biases inherent in neural networks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2311.02622v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhehang Du</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Point Cloud Matters: Rethinking the Impact of Different Observation Spaces on Robot Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.02500</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.02500v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In robot learning, the observation space is crucial due to the distinct characteristics of different modalities, which can potentially become a bottleneck alongside policy design. In this study, we explore the influence of various observation spaces on robot learning, focusing on three predominant modalities: RGB, RGB-D, and point cloud. We introduce OBSBench, a benchmark comprising two simulators and 125 tasks, along with standardized pipelines for various encoders and policy baselines. Extensive experiments on diverse contact-rich manipulation tasks reveal a notable trend: point cloud-based methods, even those with the simplest designs, frequently outperform their RGB and RGB-D counterparts. This trend persists in both scenarios: training from scratch and utilizing pre-training. Furthermore, our findings demonstrate that point cloud observations often yield better policy performance and significantly stronger generalization capabilities across various geometric and visual conditions. These outcomes suggest that the 3D point cloud is a valuable observation modality for intricate robotic tasks. We also suggest that incorporating both appearance and coordinate information can enhance the performance of point cloud methods. We hope our work provides valuable insights and guidance for designing more generalizable and robust robotic models. Codes are available at https://github.com/HaoyiZhu/PointCloudMatters.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.02500v3</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haoyi Zhu, Yating Wang, Di Huang, Weicai Ye, Wanli Ouyang, Tong He</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Domain Adaptive Neural Contextual Bandits</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09564</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09564v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Contextual bandit algorithms are essential for solving real-world decision making problems. In practice, collecting a contextual bandit's feedback from different domains may involve different costs. For example, measuring drug reaction from mice (as a source domain) and humans (as a target domain). Unfortunately, adapting a contextual bandit algorithm from a source domain to a target domain with distribution shift still remains a major challenge and largely unexplored. In this paper, we introduce the first general domain adaptation method for contextual bandits. Our approach learns a bandit model for the target domain by collecting feedback from the source domain. Our theoretical analysis shows that our algorithm maintains a sub-linear regret bound even adapting across domains. Empirical results show that our approach outperforms the state-of-the-art contextual bandit algorithms on real-world datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09564v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CE</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ziyan Wang, Xiaoming Huo, Hao Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Language Structures through Grounding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09662</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09662v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Language is highly structured, with syntactic and semantic structures, to some extent, agreed upon by speakers of the same language. With implicit or explicit awareness of such structures, humans can learn and use language efficiently and generalize to sentences that contain unseen words. Motivated by human language learning, in this dissertation, we consider a family of machine learning tasks that aim to learn language structures through grounding. We seek distant supervision from other data sources (i.e., grounds), including but not limited to other modalities (e.g., vision), execution results of programs, and other languages.
  We demonstrate the potential of this task formulation and advocate for its adoption through three schemes. In Part I, we consider learning syntactic parses through visual grounding. We propose the task of visually grounded grammar induction, present the first models to induce syntactic structures from visually grounded text and speech, and find that the visual grounding signals can help improve the parsing quality over language-only models. As a side contribution, we propose a novel evaluation metric that enables the evaluation of speech parsing without text or automatic speech recognition systems involved. In Part II, we propose two execution-aware methods to map sentences into corresponding semantic structures (i.e., programs), significantly improving compositional generalization and few-shot program synthesis. In Part III, we propose methods that learn language structures from annotations in other languages. Specifically, we propose a method that sets a new state of the art on cross-lingual word alignment. We then leverage the learned word alignments to improve the performance of zero-shot cross-lingual dependency parsing, by proposing a novel substructure-based projection method that preserves structural knowledge learned from the source language.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09662v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Freda Shi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slicing Through Bias: Explaining Performance Gaps in Medical Image Analysis using Slice Discovery Methods</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.12142</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.12142v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Machine learning models have achieved high overall accuracy in medical image analysis. However, performance disparities on specific patient groups pose challenges to their clinical utility, safety, and fairness. This can affect known patient groups - such as those based on sex, age, or disease subtype - as well as previously unknown and unlabeled groups. Furthermore, the root cause of such observed performance disparities is often challenging to uncover, hindering mitigation efforts. In this paper, to address these issues, we leverage Slice Discovery Methods (SDMs) to identify interpretable underperforming subsets of data and formulate hypotheses regarding the cause of observed performance disparities. We introduce a novel SDM and apply it in a case study on the classification of pneumothorax and atelectasis from chest x-rays. Our study demonstrates the effectiveness of SDMs in hypothesis formulation and yields an explanation of previously observed but unexplained performance disparities between male and female patients in widely used chest X-ray datasets and models. Our findings indicate shortcut learning in both classification tasks, through the presence of chest drains and ECG wires, respectively. Sex-based differences in the prevalence of these shortcut features appear to cause the observed classification performance gap, representing a previously underappreciated interaction between shortcut learning and model fairness analyses.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.12142v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1007/978-3-031-72787-0_1</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Vincent Olesen, Nina Weng, Aasa Feragen, Eike Petersen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Your HD Map Constructor Reliable under Sensor Corruptions?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.12214</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.12214v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Driving systems often rely on high-definition (HD) maps for precise environmental information, which is crucial for planning and navigation. While current HD map constructors perform well under ideal conditions, their resilience to real-world challenges, \eg, adverse weather and sensor failures, is not well understood, raising safety concerns. This work introduces MapBench, the first comprehensive benchmark designed to evaluate the robustness of HD map construction methods against various sensor corruptions. Our benchmark encompasses a total of 29 types of corruptions that occur from cameras and LiDAR sensors. Extensive evaluations across 31 HD map constructors reveal significant performance degradation of existing methods under adverse weather conditions and sensor failures, underscoring critical safety concerns. We identify effective strategies for enhancing robustness, including innovative approaches that leverage multi-modal fusion, advanced data augmentation, and architectural techniques. These insights provide a pathway for developing more reliable HD map construction methods, which are essential for the advancement of autonomous driving technology. The benchmark toolkit and affiliated code and model checkpoints have been made publicly accessible.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.12214v3</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoshuai Hao, Mengchuan Wei, Yifan Yang, Haimei Zhao, Hui Zhang, Yi Zhou, Qiang Wang, Weiming Li, Lingdong Kong, Jing Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AIM 2024 Challenge on Compressed Video Quality Assessment: Methods and Results</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11982</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11982v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Video quality assessment (VQA) is a crucial task in the development of video compression standards, as it directly impacts the viewer experience. This paper presents the results of the Compressed Video Quality Assessment challenge, held in conjunction with the Advances in Image Manipulation (AIM) workshop at ECCV 2024. The challenge aimed to evaluate the performance of VQA methods on a diverse dataset of 459 videos, encoded with 14 codecs of various compression standards (AVC/H.264, HEVC/H.265, AV1, and VVC/H.266) and containing a comprehensive collection of compression artifacts. To measure the methods performance, we employed traditional correlation coefficients between their predictions and subjective scores, which were collected via large-scale crowdsourced pairwise human comparisons. For training purposes, participants were provided with the Compressed Video Quality Assessment Dataset (CVQAD), a previously developed dataset of 1022 videos. Up to 30 participating teams registered for the challenge, while we report the results of 6 teams, which submitted valid final solutions and code for reproducing the results. Moreover, we calculated and present the performance of state-of-the-art VQA methods on the developed dataset, providing a comprehensive benchmark for future research. The dataset, results, and online leaderboard are publicly available at https://challenges.videoprocessing.ai/challenges/compressedvideo-quality-assessment.html.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11982v3</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Maksim Smirnov, Aleksandr Gushchin, Anastasia Antsiferova, Dmitry Vatolin, Radu Timofte, Ziheng Jia, Zicheng Zhang, Wei Sun, Jiaying Qian, Yuqin Cao, Yinan Sun, Yuxin Zhu, Xiongkuo Min, Guangtao Zhai, Kanjar De, Qing Luo, Ao-Xiang Zhang, Peng Zhang, Haibo Lei, Linyan Jiang, Yaqing Li, Wenhui Meng, Zhenzhong Chen, Zhengxue Cheng, Jiahao Xiao, Jun Xu, Chenlong He, Qi Zheng, Ruoxi Zhu, Min Li, Yibo Fan, Zhengzhong Tu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Competency-Aware Planning for Probabilistically Safe Navigation Under Perception Uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.06111</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.06111v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Perception-based navigation systems are useful for unmanned ground vehicle (UGV) navigation in complex terrains, where traditional depth-based navigation schemes are insufficient. However, these data-driven methods are highly dependent on their training data and can fail in surprising and dramatic ways with little warning. To ensure the safety of the vehicle and the surrounding environment, it is imperative that the navigation system is able to recognize the predictive uncertainty of the perception model and respond safely and effectively in the face of uncertainty. In an effort to enable safe navigation under perception uncertainty, we develop a probabilistic and reconstruction-based competency estimation (PaRCE) method to estimate the model's level of familiarity with an input image as a whole and with specific regions in the image. We find that the overall competency score can correctly predict correctly classified, misclassified, and out-of-distribution (OOD) samples. We also confirm that the regional competency maps can accurately distinguish between familiar and unfamiliar regions across images. We then use this competency information to develop a planning and control scheme that enables effective navigation while maintaining a low probability of error. We find that the competency-aware scheme greatly reduces the number of collisions with unfamiliar obstacles, compared to a baseline controller with no competency awareness. Furthermore, the regional competency information is very valuable in enabling efficient navigation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.06111v2</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.SY</category>
      <category>eess.SY</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sara Pohland, Claire Tomlin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing a Thailand solar irradiance map using Himawari-8 satellite imageries and deep learning models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.16320</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.16320v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: This paper presents an online platform that shows Thailand's solar irradiance map every 30 minutes. It is available at https://www.cusolarforecast.com. The methodology for estimating global horizontal irradiance (GHI) across Thailand relies on cloud index extracted from Himawari-8 satellite imagery, Ineichen clear-sky model with locally-tuned Linke turbidity, and machine learning models. The methods take clear-sky irradiance, cloud index, re-analyzed GHI and temperature data from the MERRA-2 database, and date-time as inputs for GHI estimation models, including LightGBM, LSTM, Informer, and Transformer. These are benchmarked with the estimate from a commercial service X by evaluating 15-minute ground GHI data from 53 ground stations over 1.5 years from 2022-2023. The results show that the four models have competitive performances and outperform the service X. The best model is LightGBM, with an MAE of 78.58 W/sqm and RMSE of 118.97 W/sqm. Obtaining re-analyzed MERRA-2 data for Thailand is not economically feasible for deployment. When removing these features, the Informer model has a winning performance of 78.67 W/sqm in MAE. The obtained performance aligns with existing literature by taking the climate zone and time granularity of data into consideration. As the map shows an estimate of GHI over 93,000 grids with a frequent update, the paper also describes a computational framework for displaying the entire map. It tests the runtime performance of deep learning models in the GHI estimation process.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.16320v2</guid>
      <category>physics.ao-ph</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Suwichaya Suwanwimolkul, Natanon Tongamrak, Nuttamon Thungka, Naebboon Hoonchareon, Jitkomut Songsiri</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Neural Optimal Transport via Displacement Interpolation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.03783</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.03783v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Optimal Transport (OT) theory investigates the cost-minimizing transport map that moves a source distribution to a target distribution. Recently, several approaches have emerged for learning the optimal transport map for a given cost function using neural networks. We refer to these approaches as the OT Map. OT Map provides a powerful tool for diverse machine learning tasks, such as generative modeling and unpaired image-to-image translation. However, existing methods that utilize max-min optimization often experience training instability and sensitivity to hyperparameters. In this paper, we propose a novel method to improve stability and achieve a better approximation of the OT Map by exploiting displacement interpolation, dubbed Displacement Interpolation Optimal Transport Model (DIOTM). We derive the dual formulation of displacement interpolation at specific time $t$ and prove how these dual problems are related across time. This result allows us to utilize the entire trajectory of displacement interpolation in learning the OT Map. Our method improves the training stability and achieves superior results in estimating optimal transport maps. We demonstrate that DIOTM outperforms existing OT-based models on image-to-image translation tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.03783v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jaemoo Choi, Yongxin Chen, Jaewoong Choi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unsupervised Assessment of Landscape Shifts Based on Persistent Entropy and Topological Preservation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.04183</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.04183v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In Continual Learning (CL) contexts, concept drift typically refers to the analysis of changes in data distribution. A drift in the input data can have negative consequences on a learning predictor and the system's stability. The majority of concept drift methods emphasize the analysis of statistical changes in non-stationary data over time. In this context, we consider another perspective, where the concept drift also integrates substantial changes in the topological characteristics of the data stream. In this article, we introduce a novel framework for monitoring changes in multi-dimensional data streams. We explore variations in the topological structures of the data, presenting another angle on the standard concept drift. Our developed approach is based on persistent entropy and topology-preserving projections in a continual learning scenario. The framework operates in both unsupervised and supervised environments. To show the utility of the proposed framework, we analyze the model across three scenarios using data streams generated with MNIST samples. The obtained results reveal the potential of applying topological data analysis for shift detection and encourage further research in this area.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.04183v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sebastian Basterrech</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Layer Feature Fusion with Cross-Channel Attention-Based U-Net for Kidney Tumor Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.15472</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.15472v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Renal tumors, especially renal cell carcinoma (RCC), show significant heterogeneity, posing challenges for diagnosis using radiology images such as MRI, echocardiograms, and CT scans. U-Net based deep learning techniques are emerging as a promising approach for automated medical image segmentation for minimally invasive diagnosis of renal tumors. However, current techniques need further improvements in accuracy to become clinically useful to radiologists. In this study, we present an improved U-Net based model for end-to-end automated semantic segmentation of CT scan images to identify renal tumors. The model uses residual connections across convolution layers, integrates a multi-layer feature fusion (MFF) and cross-channel attention (CCA) within encoder blocks, and incorporates skip connections augmented with additional information derived using MFF and CCA. We evaluated our model on the KiTS19 dataset, which contains data from 210 patients. For kidney segmentation, our model achieves a Dice Similarity Coefficient (DSC) of 0.97 and a Jaccard index (JI) of 0.95. For renal tumor segmentation, our model achieves a DSC of 0.96 and a JI of 0.91. Based on a comparison of available DSC scores, our model outperforms the current leading models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.15472v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.11159/icbes24.158</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Proceedings of the 10th World Congress on Electrical Engineering and Computer Systems and Science, Avestia Publishing, ISSN = 2369-811X, 2024</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Fnu Neha, Arvind K. Bansal</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
