<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CV updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CV</link>
    <description>cs.CV updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CV" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 04:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Sunday</day>
      <day>Saturday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Laws for Galaxy Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.02973</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.02973v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present the first systematic investigation of supervised scaling laws outside of an ImageNet-like context - on images of galaxies. We use 840k galaxy images and over 100M annotations by Galaxy Zoo volunteers, comparable in scale to Imagenet-1K. We find that adding annotated galaxy images provides a power law improvement in performance across all architectures and all tasks, while adding trainable parameters is effective only for some (typically more subjectively challenging) tasks. We then compare the downstream performance of finetuned models pretrained on either ImageNet-12k alone vs. additionally pretrained on our galaxy images. We achieve an average relative error rate reduction of 31% across 5 downstream tasks of scientific interest. Our finetuned models are more label-efficient and, unlike their ImageNet-12k-pretrained equivalents, often achieve linear transfer performance equal to that of end-to-end finetuning. We find relatively modest additional downstream benefits from scaling model size, implying that scaling alone is not sufficient to address our domain gap, and suggest that practitioners with qualitatively different images might benefit more from in-domain adaption followed by targeted downstream labelling.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.02973v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>astro-ph.GA</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mike Walmsley, Micah Bowles, Anna M. M. Scaife, Jason Shingirai Makechemu, Alexander J. Gordon, Annette M. N. Ferguson, Robert G. Mann, James Pearson, J\"urgen J. Popp, Jo Bovy, Josh Speagle, Hugh Dickinson, Lucy Fortson, Tobias G\'eron, Sandor Kruk, Chris J. Lintott, Kameswara Mantha, Devina Mohan, David O'Ryan, Inigo V. Slijepevic</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASAP: Interpretable Analysis and Summarization of AI-generated Image Patterns at Scale</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.02990</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.02990v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Generative image models have emerged as a promising technology to produce realistic images. Despite potential benefits, concerns grow about its misuse, particularly in generating deceptive images that could raise significant ethical, legal, and societal issues. Consequently, there is growing demand to empower users to effectively discern and comprehend patterns of AI-generated images. To this end, we developed ASAP, an interactive visualization system that automatically extracts distinct patterns of AI-generated images and allows users to interactively explore them via various views. To uncover fake patterns, ASAP introduces a novel image encoder, adapted from CLIP, which transforms images into compact "distilled" representations, enriched with information for differentiating authentic and fake images. These representations generate gradients that propagate back to the attention maps of CLIP's transformer block. This process quantifies the relative importance of each pixel to image authenticity or fakeness, exposing key deceptive patterns. ASAP enables the at scale interactive analysis of these patterns through multiple, coordinated visualizations. This includes a representation overview with innovative cell glyphs to aid in the exploration and qualitative evaluation of fake patterns across a vast array of images, as well as a pattern view that displays authenticity-indicating patterns in images and quantifies their impact. ASAP supports the analysis of cutting-edge generative models with the latest architectures, including GAN-based models like proGAN and diffusion models like the latent diffusion model. We demonstrate ASAP's usefulness through two usage scenarios using multiple fake image detection benchmark datasets, revealing its ability to identify and understand hidden patterns in AI-generated images, especially in detecting fake human faces produced by diffusion-based techniques.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.02990v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jinbin Huang, Chen Chen, Aditi Mishra, Bum Chul Kwon, Zhicheng Liu, Chris Bryan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DPFT: Dual Perspective Fusion Transformer for Camera-Radar-based Object Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03015</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03015v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The perception of autonomous vehicles has to be efficient, robust, and cost-effective. However, cameras are not robust against severe weather conditions, lidar sensors are expensive, and the performance of radar-based perception is still inferior to the others. Camera-radar fusion methods have been proposed to address this issue, but these are constrained by the typical sparsity of radar point clouds and often designed for radars without elevation information. We propose a novel camera-radar fusion approach called Dual Perspective Fusion Transformer (DPFT), designed to overcome these limitations. Our method leverages lower-level radar data (the radar cube) instead of the processed point clouds to preserve as much information as possible and employs projections in both the camera and ground planes to effectively use radars with elevation information and simplify the fusion with camera data. As a result, DPFT has demonstrated state-of-the-art performance on the K-Radar dataset while showing remarkable robustness against adverse weather conditions and maintaining a low inference time. The code is made available as open-source software under https://github.com/TUMFTM/DPFT.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03015v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Felix Fent, Andras Palffy, Holger Caesar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWOL: Analysis WithOut synthesis using Language</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03042</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03042v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Many classical parametric 3D shape models exist, but creating novel shapes with such models requires expert knowledge of their parameters. For example, imagine creating a specific type of tree using procedural graphics or a new kind of animal from a statistical shape model. Our key idea is to leverage language to control such existing models to produce novel shapes. This involves learning a mapping between the latent space of a vision-language model and the parameter space of the 3D model, which we do using a small set of shape and text pairs. Our hypothesis is that mapping from language to parameters allows us to generate parameters for objects that were never seen during training. If the mapping between language and parameters is sufficiently smooth, then interpolation or generalization in language should translate appropriately into novel 3D shapes. We test our approach with two very different types of parametric shape models (quadrupeds and arboreal trees). We use a learned statistical shape model of quadrupeds and show that we can use text to generate new animals not present during training. In particular, we demonstrate state-of-the-art shape estimation of 3D dogs. This work also constitutes the first language-driven method for generating 3D trees. Finally, embedding images in the CLIP latent space enables us to generate animals and trees directly from images.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03042v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Silvia Zuffi, Michael J. Black</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linear Anchored Gaussian Mixture Model for Location and Width Computation of Objects in Thick Line Shape</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03043</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03043v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: An accurate detection of the centerlines of linear objects is a challenging topic in many sensitive real-world applications such X-ray imaging, remote sensing and lane marking detection in road traffic. Model-based approaches using Hough and Radon transforms are often used but, are not recommended for thick line detection, whereas approaches based on image derivatives need further step-by-step processing, making their efficiency dependent on each step outcomes. In this paper, we aim to detect linear structures found in images by considering the 3D representation of the image gray levels as a finite mixture model of statistical distribution. The latter, which we named linear anchored Gaussian distribution could be parametrized by a scale value {\sigma} describing the linear structure thickness and a line equation, parametrized, in turn, by a radius \r{ho} and an orientation angle {\theta}, describing the linear structure centerline location. Expectation-Maximization (EM) algorithm is used for the mixture model parameter estimation, where a new paradigm, using the background subtraction for the likelihood function computation, is proposed. For the EM algorithm, two {\theta} parameter initialization schemes are used: the first one is based on a random choice of the first component of {\theta} vector, whereas the second is based on the image Hessian with a simultaneous computation of the mixture model components number. Experiments on real world images and synthetic images corrupted by blur and additive noise show the good performance of the proposed methods, where the algorithm using background subtraction and Hessian-based {\theta} initialization provides an outstanding accuracy of the linear structure detection despite irregular image background and presence of blur and noise.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03043v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nafaa Nacereddine, Djemel Ziou, Aicha Baya Goumeidane</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Behind the Veil: Enhanced Indoor 3D Scene Reconstruction with Occluded Surfaces Completion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03070</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03070v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this paper, we present a novel indoor 3D reconstruction method with occluded surface completion, given a sequence of depth readings. Prior state-of-the-art (SOTA) methods only focus on the reconstruction of the visible areas in a scene, neglecting the invisible areas due to the occlusions, e.g., the contact surface between furniture, occluded wall and floor. Our method tackles the task of completing the occluded scene surfaces, resulting in a complete 3D scene mesh. The core idea of our method is learning 3D geometry prior from various complete scenes to infer the occluded geometry of an unseen scene from solely depth measurements. We design a coarse-fine hierarchical octree representation coupled with a dual-decoder architecture, i.e., Geo-decoder and 3D Inpainter, which jointly reconstructs the complete 3D scene geometry. The Geo-decoder with detailed representation at fine levels is optimized online for each scene to reconstruct visible surfaces. The 3D Inpainter with abstract representation at coarse levels is trained offline using various scenes to complete occluded surfaces. As a result, while the Geo-decoder is specialized for an individual scene, the 3D Inpainter can be generally applied across different scenes. We evaluate the proposed method on the 3D Completed Room Scene (3D-CRS) and iTHOR datasets, significantly outperforming the SOTA methods by a gain of 16.8% and 24.2% in terms of the completeness of 3D reconstruction. 3D-CRS dataset including a complete 3D mesh of each scene is provided at project webpage.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03070v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Su Sun, Cheng Zhao, Yuliang Guo, Ruoyu Wang, Xinyu Huang, Yingjie Victor Chen, Liu Ren</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SalFoM: Dynamic Saliency Prediction with Video Foundation Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03097</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03097v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent advancements in video saliency prediction (VSP) have shown promising performance compared to the human visual system, whose emulation is the primary goal of VSP. However, current state-of-the-art models employ spatio-temporal transformers trained on limited amounts of data, hindering generalizability adaptation to downstream tasks. The benefits of vision foundation models present a potential solution to improve the VSP process. However, adapting image foundation models to the video domain presents significant challenges in modeling scene dynamics and capturing temporal information. To address these challenges, and as the first initiative to design a VSP model based on video foundation models, we introduce SalFoM, a novel encoder-decoder video transformer architecture. Our model employs UnMasked Teacher (UMT) as feature extractor and presents a heterogeneous decoder which features a locality-aware spatio-temporal transformer and integrates local and global spatio-temporal information from various perspectives to produce the final saliency map. Our qualitative and quantitative experiments on the challenging VSP benchmark datasets of DHF1K, Hollywood-2 and UCF-Sports demonstrate the superiority of our proposed model in comparison with the state-of-the-art methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03097v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Morteza Moradi, Mohammad Moradi, Francesco Rundo, Concetto Spampinato, Ali Borji, Simone Palazzo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Many-to-many Image Generation with Auto-regressive Diffusion Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03109</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03109v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent advancements in image generation have made significant progress, yet existing models present limitations in perceiving and generating an arbitrary number of interrelated images within a broad context. This limitation becomes increasingly critical as the demand for multi-image scenarios, such as multi-view images and visual narratives, grows with the expansion of multimedia platforms. This paper introduces a domain-general framework for many-to-many image generation, capable of producing interrelated image series from a given set of images, offering a scalable solution that obviates the need for task-specific solutions across different multi-image scenarios. To facilitate this, we present MIS, a novel large-scale multi-image dataset, containing 12M synthetic multi-image samples, each with 25 interconnected images. Utilizing Stable Diffusion with varied latent noises, our method produces a set of interconnected images from a single caption. Leveraging MIS, we learn M2M, an autoregressive model for many-to-many generation, where each image is modeled within a diffusion framework. Throughout training on the synthetic MIS, the model excels in capturing style and content from preceding images - synthetic or real - and generates novel images following the captured patterns. Furthermore, through task-specific fine-tuning, our model demonstrates its adaptability to various multi-image generation tasks, including Novel View Synthesis and Visual Procedure Generation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03109v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ying Shen, Yizhe Zhang, Shuangfei Zhai, Lifu Huang, Joshua M. Susskind, Jiatao Gu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ego-Motion Aware Target Prediction Module for Robust Multi-Object Tracking</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03110</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03110v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Multi-object tracking (MOT) is a prominent task in computer vision with application in autonomous driving, responsible for the simultaneous tracking of multiple object trajectories. Detection-based multi-object tracking (DBT) algorithms detect objects using an independent object detector and predict the imminent location of each target. Conventional prediction methods in DBT utilize Kalman Filter(KF) to extrapolate the target location in the upcoming frames by supposing a constant velocity motion model. These methods are especially hindered in autonomous driving applications due to dramatic camera motion or unavailable detections. Such limitations lead to tracking failures manifested by numerous identity switches and disrupted trajectories. In this paper, we introduce a novel KF-based prediction module called the Ego-motion Aware Target Prediction (EMAP) module by focusing on the integration of camera motion and depth information with object motion models. Our proposed method decouples the impact of camera rotational and translational velocity from the object trajectories by reformulating the Kalman Filter. This reformulation enables us to reject the disturbances caused by camera motion and maximizes the reliability of the object motion model. We integrate our module with four state-of-the-art base MOT algorithms, namely OC-SORT, Deep OC-SORT, ByteTrack, and BoT-SORT. In particular, our evaluation on the KITTI MOT dataset demonstrates that EMAP remarkably drops the number of identity switches (IDSW) of OC-SORT and Deep OC-SORT by 73% and 21%, respectively. At the same time, it elevates other performance metrics such as HOTA by more than 5%. Our source code is available at https://github.com/noyzzz/EMAP.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03110v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Navid Mahdian, Mohammad Jani, Amir M. Soufi Enayati, Homayoun Najjaran</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LVLM-Intrepret: An Interpretability Tool for Large Vision-Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03118</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03118v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In the rapidly evolving landscape of artificial intelligence, multi-modal large language models are emerging as a significant area of interest. These models, which combine various forms of data input, are becoming increasingly popular. However, understanding their internal mechanisms remains a complex task. Numerous advancements have been made in the field of explainability tools and mechanisms, yet there is still much to explore. In this work, we present a novel interactive application aimed towards understanding the internal mechanisms of large vision-language models. Our interface is designed to enhance the interpretability of the image patches, which are instrumental in generating an answer, and assess the efficacy of the language model in grounding its output in the image. With our application, a user can systematically investigate the model and uncover system limitations, paving the way for enhancements in system capabilities. Finally, we present a case study of how our application can aid in understanding failure mechanisms in a popular large multi-modal model: LLaVA.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03118v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gabriela Ben Melech Stan, Raanan Yehezkel Rohekar, Yaniv Gurwicz, Matthew Lyle Olson, Anahita Bhiwandiwalla, Estelle Aflalo, Chenfei Wu, Nan Duan, Shao-Yen Tseng, Vasudev Lal</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utilizing Computer Vision for Continuous Monitoring of Vaccine Side Effects in Experimental Mice</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03121</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03121v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The demand for improved efficiency and accuracy in vaccine safety assessments is increasing. Here, we explore the application of computer vision technologies to automate the monitoring of experimental mice for potential side effects after vaccine administration. Traditional observation methods are labor-intensive and lack the capability for continuous monitoring. By deploying a computer vision system, our research aims to improve the efficiency and accuracy of vaccine safety assessments. The methodology involves training machine learning models on annotated video data of mice behaviors pre- and post-vaccination. Preliminary results indicate that computer vision effectively identify subtle changes, signaling possible side effects. Therefore, our approach has the potential to significantly enhance the monitoring process in vaccine trials in animals, providing a practical solution to the limitations of human observation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03121v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>q-bio.NC</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chuang Li, Shuai Shao, Willian Mikason, Rubing Lin, Yantong Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discontinuity-preserving Normal Integration with Auxiliary Edges</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03138</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03138v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Many surface reconstruction methods incorporate normal integration, which is a process to obtain a depth map from surface gradients. In this process, the input may represent a surface with discontinuities, e.g., due to self-occlusion. To reconstruct an accurate depth map from the input normal map, hidden surface gradients occurring from the jumps must be handled. To model these jumps correctly, we design a novel discretization scheme for the domain of normal integration. Our key idea is to introduce auxiliary edges, which bridge between piecewise-smooth patches in the domain so that the magnitude of hidden jumps can be explicitly expressed. Using the auxiliary edges, we design a novel algorithm to optimize the discontinuity and the depth map from the input normal map. Our method optimizes discontinuities by using a combination of iterative re-weighted least squares and iterative filtering of the jump magnitudes on auxiliary edges to provide strong sparsity regularization. Compared to previous discontinuity-preserving normal integration methods, which model the magnitudes of jumps only implicitly, our method reconstructs subtle discontinuities accurately thanks to our explicit representation of jumps allowing for strong sparsity regularization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03138v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hyomin Kim, Yucheol Jung, Seungyong Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diverse and Tailored Image Generation for Zero-shot Multi-label Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03144</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03144v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recently, zero-shot multi-label classification has garnered considerable attention for its capacity to operate predictions on unseen labels without human annotations. Nevertheless, prevailing approaches often use seen classes as imperfect proxies for unseen ones, resulting in suboptimal performance. Drawing inspiration from the success of text-to-image generation models in producing realistic images, we propose an innovative solution: generating synthetic data to construct a training set explicitly tailored for proxyless training on unseen labels. Our approach introduces a novel image generation framework that produces multi-label synthetic images of unseen classes for classifier training. To enhance diversity in the generated images, we leverage a pre-trained large language model to generate diverse prompts. Employing a pre-trained multi-modal CLIP model as a discriminator, we assess whether the generated images accurately represent the target classes. This enables automatic filtering of inaccurately generated images, preserving classifier accuracy. To refine text prompts for more precise and effective multi-label object generation, we introduce a CLIP score-based discriminative loss to fine-tune the text encoder in the diffusion model. Additionally, to enhance visual features on the target task while maintaining the generalization of original features and mitigating catastrophic forgetting resulting from fine-tuning the entire visual encoder, we propose a feature fusion module inspired by transformer attention mechanisms. This module aids in capturing global dependencies between multiple objects more effectively. Extensive experimental results validate the effectiveness of our approach, demonstrating significant improvements over state-of-the-art methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03144v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kaixin Zhang, Zhixiang Yuan, Tao Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DreamWalk: Style Space Exploration using Diffusion Guidance</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03145</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03145v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Text-conditioned diffusion models can generate impressive images, but fall short when it comes to fine-grained control. Unlike direct-editing tools like Photoshop, text conditioned models require the artist to perform "prompt engineering," constructing special text sentences to control the style or amount of a particular subject present in the output image. Our goal is to provide fine-grained control over the style and substance specified by the prompt, for example to adjust the intensity of styles in different regions of the image (Figure 1). Our approach is to decompose the text prompt into conceptual elements, and apply a separate guidance term for each element in a single diffusion process. We introduce guidance scale functions to control when in the diffusion process and \emph{where} in the image to intervene. Since the method is based solely on adjusting diffusion guidance, it does not require fine-tuning or manipulating the internal layers of the diffusion model's neural network, and can be used in conjunction with LoRA- or DreamBooth-trained models (Figure2). Project page: https://mshu1.github.io/dreamwalk.github.io/</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03145v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Michelle Shu, Charles Herrmann, Richard Strong Bowen, Forrester Cole, Ramin Zabih</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HandDiff: 3D Hand Pose Estimation with Diffusion on Image-Point Cloud</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03159</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03159v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Extracting keypoint locations from input hand frames, known as 3D hand pose estimation, is a critical task in various human-computer interaction applications. Essentially, the 3D hand pose estimation can be regarded as a 3D point subset generative problem conditioned on input frames. Thanks to the recent significant progress on diffusion-based generative models, hand pose estimation can also benefit from the diffusion model to estimate keypoint locations with high quality. However, directly deploying the existing diffusion models to solve hand pose estimation is non-trivial, since they cannot achieve the complex permutation mapping and precise localization. Based on this motivation, this paper proposes HandDiff, a diffusion-based hand pose estimation model that iteratively denoises accurate hand pose conditioned on hand-shaped image-point clouds. In order to recover keypoint permutation and accurate location, we further introduce joint-wise condition and local detail condition. Experimental results demonstrate that the proposed HandDiff significantly outperforms the existing approaches on four challenging hand pose benchmark datasets. Codes and pre-trained models are publicly available at https://github.com/cwc1260/HandDiff.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03159v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wencan Cheng, Hao Tang, Luc Van Gool, Jong Hwan Ko</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BioVL-QR: Egocentric Biochemical Video-and-Language Dataset Using Micro QR Codes</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03161</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03161v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper introduces a biochemical vision-and-language dataset, which consists of 24 egocentric experiment videos, corresponding protocols, and video-and-language alignments. The key challenge in the wet-lab domain is detecting equipment, reagents, and containers is difficult because the lab environment is scattered by filling objects on the table and some objects are indistinguishable. Therefore, previous studies assume that objects are manually annotated and given for downstream tasks, but this is costly and time-consuming. To address this issue, this study focuses on Micro QR Codes to detect objects automatically. From our preliminary study, we found that detecting objects only using Micro QR Codes is still difficult because the researchers manipulate objects, causing blur and occlusion frequently. To address this, we also propose a novel object labeling method by combining a Micro QR Code detector and an off-the-shelf hand object detector. As one of the applications of our dataset, we conduct the task of generating protocols from experiment videos and find that our approach can generate accurate protocols.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03161v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Taichi Nishimura, Koki Yamamoto, Yuto Haneji, Keiya Kajimura, Chihiro Nishiwaki, Eriko Daikoku, Natsuko Okuda, Fumihito Ono, Hirotaka Kameko, Shinsuke Mori</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UniAV: Unified Audio-Visual Perception for Multi-Task Video Localization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03179</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03179v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Video localization tasks aim to temporally locate specific instances in videos, including temporal action localization (TAL), sound event detection (SED) and audio-visual event localization (AVEL). Existing methods over-specialize on each task, overlooking the fact that these instances often occur in the same video to form the complete video content. In this work, we present UniAV, a Unified Audio-Visual perception network, to achieve joint learning of TAL, SED and AVEL tasks for the first time. UniAV can leverage diverse data available in task-specific datasets, allowing the model to learn and share mutually beneficial knowledge across tasks and modalities. To tackle the challenges posed by substantial variations in datasets (size/domain/duration) and distinct task characteristics, we propose to uniformly encode visual and audio modalities of all videos to derive generic representations, while also designing task-specific experts to capture unique knowledge for each task. Besides, we develop a unified language-aware classifier by utilizing a pre-trained text encoder, enabling the model to flexibly detect various types of instances and previously unseen ones by simply changing prompts during inference. UniAV outperforms its single-task counterparts by a large margin with fewer parameters, achieving on-par or superior performances compared to state-of-the-art task-specific methods across ActivityNet 1.3, DESED and UnAV-100 benchmarks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03179v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tiantian Geng, Teng Wang, Yanfu Zhang, Jinming Duan, Weili Guan, Feng Zheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MonoCD: Monocular 3D Object Detection with Complementary Depths</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03181</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03181v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Monocular 3D object detection has attracted widespread attention due to its potential to accurately obtain object 3D localization from a single image at a low cost. Depth estimation is an essential but challenging subtask of monocular 3D object detection due to the ill-posedness of 2D to 3D mapping. Many methods explore multiple local depth clues such as object heights and keypoints and then formulate the object depth estimation as an ensemble of multiple depth predictions to mitigate the insufficiency of single-depth information. However, the errors of existing multiple depths tend to have the same sign, which hinders them from neutralizing each other and limits the overall accuracy of combined depth. To alleviate this problem, we propose to increase the complementarity of depths with two novel designs. First, we add a new depth prediction branch named complementary depth that utilizes global and efficient depth clues from the entire image rather than the local clues to reduce the correlation of depth predictions. Second, we propose to fully exploit the geometric relations between multiple depth clues to achieve complementarity in form. Benefiting from these designs, our method achieves higher complementarity. Experiments on the KITTI benchmark demonstrate that our method achieves state-of-the-art performance without introducing extra data. In addition, complementary depth can also be a lightweight and plug-and-play module to boost multiple existing monocular 3d object detectors. Code is available at https://github.com/elvintanhust/MonoCD.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03181v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Longfei Yan, Pei Yan, Shengzhou Xiong, Xuanyu Xiang, Yihua Tan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BodyMAP -- Jointly Predicting Body Mesh and 3D Applied Pressure Map for People in Bed</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03183</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03183v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Accurately predicting the 3D human posture and the pressure exerted on the body for people resting in bed, visualized as a body mesh (3D pose &amp; shape) with a 3D pressure map, holds significant promise for healthcare applications, particularly, in the prevention of pressure ulcers. Current methods focus on singular facets of the problem -- predicting only 2D/3D poses, generating 2D pressure images, predicting pressure only for certain body regions instead of the full body, or forming indirect approximations to the 3D pressure map. In contrast, we introduce BodyMAP, which jointly predicts the human body mesh and 3D applied pressure map across the entire human body. Our network leverages multiple visual modalities, incorporating both a depth image of a person in bed and its corresponding 2D pressure image acquired from a pressure-sensing mattress. The 3D pressure map is represented as a pressure value at each mesh vertex and thus allows for precise localization of high-pressure regions on the body. Additionally, we present BodyMAP-WS, a new formulation of pressure prediction in which we implicitly learn pressure in 3D by aligning sensed 2D pressure images with a differentiable 2D projection of the predicted 3D pressure maps. In evaluations with real-world human data, our method outperforms the current state-of-the-art technique by 25% on both body mesh and 3D applied pressure map prediction tasks for people in bed.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03183v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Abhishek Tandon, Anujraaj Goyal, Henry M. Clever, Zackory Erickson</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AGL-NET: Aerial-Ground Cross-Modal Global Localization with Varying Scales</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03187</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03187v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present AGL-NET, a novel learning-based method for global localization using LiDAR point clouds and satellite maps. AGL-NET tackles two critical challenges: bridging the representation gap between image and points modalities for robust feature matching, and handling inherent scale discrepancies between global view and local view. To address these challenges, AGL-NET leverages a unified network architecture with a novel two-stage matching design. The first stage extracts informative neural features directly from raw sensor data and performs initial feature matching. The second stage refines this matching process by extracting informative skeleton features and incorporating a novel scale alignment step to rectify scale variations between LiDAR and map data. Furthermore, a novel scale and skeleton loss function guides the network toward learning scale-invariant feature representations, eliminating the need for pre-processing satellite maps. This significantly improves real-world applicability in scenarios with unknown map scales. To facilitate rigorous performance evaluation, we introduce a meticulously designed dataset within the CARLA simulator specifically tailored for metric localization training and assessment. The code and dataset will be made publicly available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03187v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tianrui Guan, Ruiqi Xian, Xijun Wang, Xiyang Wu, Mohamed Elnoor, Daeun Song, Dinesh Manocha</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive Discrete Disparity Volume for Self-supervised Monocular Depth Estimation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03190</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03190v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In self-supervised monocular depth estimation tasks, discrete disparity prediction has been proven to attain higher quality depth maps than common continuous methods. However, current discretization strategies often divide depth ranges of scenes into bins in a handcrafted and rigid manner, limiting model performance. In this paper, we propose a learnable module, Adaptive Discrete Disparity Volume (ADDV), which is capable of dynamically sensing depth distributions in different RGB images and generating adaptive bins for them. Without any extra supervision, this module can be integrated into existing CNN architectures, allowing networks to produce representative values for bins and a probability volume over them. Furthermore, we introduce novel training strategies - uniformizing and sharpening - through a loss term and temperature parameter, respectively, to provide regularizations under self-supervised conditions, preventing model degradation or collapse. Empirical results demonstrate that ADDV effectively processes global information, generating appropriate bins for various scenes and producing higher quality depth maps compared to handcrafted methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03190v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jianwei Ren</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CORP: A Multi-Modal Dataset for Campus-Oriented Roadside Perception Tasks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03191</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03191v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Numerous roadside perception datasets have been introduced to propel advancements in autonomous driving and intelligent transportation systems research and development. However, it has been observed that the majority of their concentrates is on urban arterial roads, inadvertently overlooking residential areas such as parks and campuses that exhibit entirely distinct characteristics. In light of this gap, we propose CORP, which stands as the first public benchmark dataset tailored for multi-modal roadside perception tasks under campus scenarios. Collected in a university campus, CORP consists of over 205k images plus 102k point clouds captured from 18 cameras and 9 LiDAR sensors. These sensors with different configurations are mounted on roadside utility poles to provide diverse viewpoints within the campus region. The annotations of CORP encompass multi-dimensional information beyond 2D and 3D bounding boxes, providing extra support for 3D seamless tracking and instance segmentation with unique IDs and pixel masks for identifying targets, to enhance the understanding of objects and their behaviors distributed across the campus premises. Unlike other roadside datasets about urban traffic, CORP extends the spectrum to highlight the challenges for multi-modal perception in campuses and other residential areas.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03191v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Beibei Wang, Lu Zhang, Shuang Meng, Chenjie Wang, Jingjing Huang, Yao Li, Haojie Ren, Yuxuan Xiao, Yuru Peng, Jianmin Ji, Yu Zhang, Yanyong Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OmniGS: Omnidirectional Gaussian Splatting for Fast Radiance Field Reconstruction using Omnidirectional Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03202</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03202v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Photorealistic reconstruction relying on 3D Gaussian Splatting has shown promising potential in robotics. However, the current 3D Gaussian Splatting system only supports radiance field reconstruction using undistorted perspective images. In this paper, we present OmniGS, a novel omnidirectional Gaussian splatting system, to take advantage of omnidirectional images for fast radiance field reconstruction. Specifically, we conduct a theoretical analysis of spherical camera model derivatives in 3D Gaussian Splatting. According to the derivatives, we then implement a new GPU-accelerated omnidirectional rasterizer that directly splats 3D Gaussians onto the equirectangular screen space for omnidirectional image rendering. As a result, we realize differentiable optimization of the radiance field without the requirement of cube-map rectification or tangent-plane approximation. Extensive experiments conducted in egocentric and roaming scenarios demonstrate that our method achieves state-of-the-art reconstruction quality and high rendering speed using omnidirectional images. To benefit the research community, the code will be made publicly available once the paper is published.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03202v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Longwei Li, Huajian Huang, Sai-Kit Yeung, Hui Cheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HDR Imaging for Dynamic Scenes with Events</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03210</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03210v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: High dynamic range imaging (HDRI) for real-world dynamic scenes is challenging because moving objects may lead to hybrid degradation of low dynamic range and motion blur. Existing event-based approaches only focus on a separate task, while cascading HDRI and motion deblurring would lead to sub-optimal solutions, and unavailable ground-truth sharp HDR images aggravate the predicament. To address these challenges, we propose an Event-based HDRI framework within a Self-supervised learning paradigm, i.e., Self-EHDRI, which generalizes HDRI performance in real-world dynamic scenarios. Specifically, a self-supervised learning strategy is carried out by learning cross-domain conversions from blurry LDR images to sharp LDR images, which enables sharp HDR images to be accessible in the intermediate process even though ground-truth sharp HDR images are missing. Then, we formulate the event-based HDRI and motion deblurring model and conduct a unified network to recover the intermediate sharp HDR results, where both the high dynamic range and high temporal resolution of events are leveraged simultaneously for compensation. We construct large-scale synthetic and real-world datasets to evaluate the effectiveness of our method. Comprehensive experiments demonstrate that the proposed Self-EHDRI outperforms state-of-the-art approaches by a large margin. The codes, datasets, and results are available at https://lxp-whu.github.io/Self-EHDRI.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03210v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Li Xiaopeng, Zeng Zhaoyuan, Fan Cien, Zhao Chen, Deng Lei, Yu Lei</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LeGrad: An Explainability Method for Vision Transformers via Feature Formation Sensitivity</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03214</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03214v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Vision Transformers (ViTs), with their ability to model long-range dependencies through self-attention mechanisms, have become a standard architecture in computer vision. However, the interpretability of these models remains a challenge. To address this, we propose LeGrad, an explainability method specifically designed for ViTs. LeGrad computes the gradient with respect to the attention maps of ViT layers, considering the gradient itself as the explainability signal. We aggregate the signal over all layers, combining the activations of the last as well as intermediate tokens to produce the merged explainability map. This makes LeGrad a conceptually simple and an easy-to-implement tool for enhancing the transparency of ViTs. We evaluate LeGrad in challenging segmentation, perturbation, and open-vocabulary settings, showcasing its versatility compared to other SotA explainability methods demonstrating its superior spatial fidelity and robustness to perturbations. A demo and the code is available at https://github.com/WalBouss/LeGrad.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03214v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Walid Bousselham, Angie Boggust, Sofian Chaybouti, Hendrik Strobelt, Hilde Kuehne</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iSeg: Interactive 3D Segmentation via Interactive Attention</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03219</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03219v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present iSeg, a new interactive technique for segmenting 3D shapes. Previous works have focused mainly on leveraging pre-trained 2D foundation models for 3D segmentation based on text. However, text may be insufficient for accurately describing fine-grained spatial segmentations. Moreover, achieving a consistent 3D segmentation using a 2D model is challenging since occluded areas of the same semantic region may not be visible together from any 2D view. Thus, we design a segmentation method conditioned on fine user clicks, which operates entirely in 3D. Our system accepts user clicks directly on the shape's surface, indicating the inclusion or exclusion of regions from the desired shape partition. To accommodate various click settings, we propose a novel interactive attention module capable of processing different numbers and types of clicks, enabling the training of a single unified interactive segmentation model. We apply iSeg to a myriad of shapes from different domains, demonstrating its versatility and faithfulness to the user's specifications. Our project page is at https://threedle.github.io/iSeg/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03219v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Itai Lang, Fei Xu, Dale Decatur, Sudarshan Babu, Rana Hanocka</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FACTUAL: A Novel Framework for Contrastive Learning Based Robust SAR Image Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03225</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03225v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Deep Learning (DL) Models for Synthetic Aperture Radar (SAR) Automatic Target Recognition (ATR), while delivering improved performance, have been shown to be quite vulnerable to adversarial attacks. Existing works improve robustness by training models on adversarial samples. However, by focusing mostly on attacks that manipulate images randomly, they neglect the real-world feasibility of such attacks. In this paper, we propose FACTUAL, a novel Contrastive Learning framework for Adversarial Training and robust SAR classification. FACTUAL consists of two components: (1) Differing from existing works, a novel perturbation scheme that incorporates realistic physical adversarial attacks (such as OTSA) to build a supervised adversarial pre-training network. This network utilizes class labels for clustering clean and perturbed images together into a more informative feature space. (2) A linear classifier cascaded after the encoder to use the computed representations to predict the target labels. By pre-training and fine-tuning our model on both clean and adversarial samples, we show that our model achieves high prediction accuracy on both cases. Our model achieves 99.7% accuracy on clean samples, and 89.6% on perturbed samples, both outperforming previous state-of-the-art methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03225v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xu Wang, Tian Ye, Rajgopal Kannan, Viktor Prasanna</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Would Deep Generative Models Amplify Bias in Future Models?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03242</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03242v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We investigate the impact of deep generative models on potential social biases in upcoming computer vision models. As the internet witnesses an increasing influx of AI-generated images, concerns arise regarding inherent biases that may accompany them, potentially leading to the dissemination of harmful content. This paper explores whether a detrimental feedback loop, resulting in bias amplification, would occur if generated images were used as the training data for future models. We conduct simulations by progressively substituting original images in COCO and CC3M datasets with images generated through Stable Diffusion. The modified datasets are used to train OpenCLIP and image captioning models, which we evaluate in terms of quality and bias. Contrary to expectations, our findings indicate that introducing generated images during training does not uniformly amplify bias. Instead, instances of bias mitigation across specific tasks are observed. We further explore the factors that may influence these phenomena, such as artifacts in image generation (e.g., blurry faces) or pre-existing biases in the original datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03242v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tianwei Chen, Yusuke Hirota, Mayu Otani, Noa Garcia, Yuta Nakashima</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Transferable Negative Prompts for Out-of-Distribution Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03248</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03248v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Existing prompt learning methods have shown certain capabilities in Out-of-Distribution (OOD) detection, but the lack of OOD images in the target dataset in their training can lead to mismatches between OOD images and In-Distribution (ID) categories, resulting in a high false positive rate. To address this issue, we introduce a novel OOD detection method, named 'NegPrompt', to learn a set of negative prompts, each representing a negative connotation of a given class label, for delineating the boundaries between ID and OOD images. It learns such negative prompts with ID data only, without any reliance on external outlier data. Further, current methods assume the availability of samples of all ID classes, rendering them ineffective in open-vocabulary learning scenarios where the inference stage can contain novel ID classes not present during training. In contrast, our learned negative prompts are transferable to novel class labels. Experiments on various ImageNet benchmarks show that NegPrompt surpasses state-of-the-art prompt-learning-based OOD detection methods and maintains a consistent lead in hard OOD detection in closed- and open-vocabulary classification scenarios. Code is available at https://github.com/mala-lab/negprompt.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03248v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tianqi Li, Guansong Pang, Xiao Bai, Wenjun Miao, Jin Zheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Real-time Noise Source Estimation of a Camera System from an Image and Metadata</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03251</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03251v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Autonomous machines must self-maintain proper functionality to ensure the safety of humans and themselves. This pertains particularly to its cameras as predominant sensors to perceive the environment and support actions. A fundamental camera problem addressed in this study is noise. Solutions often focus on denoising images a posteriori, that is, fighting symptoms rather than root causes. However, tackling root causes requires identifying the noise sources, considering the limitations of mobile platforms. This work investigates a real-time, memory-efficient and reliable noise source estimator that combines data- and physically-based models. To this end, a DNN that examines an image with camera metadata for major camera noise sources is built and trained. In addition, it quantifies unexpected factors that impact image noise or metadata. This study investigates seven different estimators on six datasets that include synthetic noise, real-world noise from two camera systems, and real field campaigns. For these, only the model with most metadata is capable to accurately and robustly quantify all individual noise contributions. This method outperforms total image noise estimators and can be plug-and-play deployed. It also serves as a basis to include more advanced noise sources, or as part of an automatic countermeasure feedback-loop to approach fully reliable machines.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03251v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1002/aisy.202300479</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Advanced Intelligent Systems, 2024</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Maik Wischow, Patrick Irmisch, Anko Boerner, Guillermo Gallego</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi Positive Contrastive Learning with Pose-Consistent Generated Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03256</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03256v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Model pre-training has become essential in various recognition tasks. Meanwhile, with the remarkable advancements in image generation models, pre-training methods utilizing generated images have also emerged given their ability to produce unlimited training data. However, while existing methods utilizing generated images excel in classification, they fall short in more practical tasks, such as human pose estimation. In this paper, we have experimentally demonstrated it and propose the generation of visually distinct images with identical human poses. We then propose a novel multi-positive contrastive learning, which optimally utilize the previously generated images to learn structural features of the human body. We term the entire learning pipeline as GenPoCCL. Despite using only less than 1% amount of data compared to current state-of-the-art method, GenPoCCL captures structural features of the human body more effectively, surpassing existing methods in a variety of human-centric perception tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03256v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sho Inayoshi, Aji Resindra Widya, Satoshi Ozaki, Junji Otsuka, Takeshi Ohashi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and Development of a Framework For Stroke-Based Handwritten Gujarati Font Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03277</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03277v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Handwritten font generation is important for preserving cultural heritage and creating personalized designs. It adds an authentic and expressive touch to printed materials, making them visually appealing and establishing a stronger connection with the audience. This paper aims to design a framework for generating handwritten fonts in the Gujarati script, mimicking the variation of human handwriting. The proposed font generation model consists of a learning phase and a generation phase. In the learning phase, Gujarati scripts are analyzed, and rules for designing each character are formulated. This ruleset involves the concatenation of strokes in a stroke-based manner, ensuring visual consistency in the resulting glyphs. The generation phase involves the user providing a small subset of characters, and the system automatically generates the remaining character glyphs based on extracted strokes and learned rules, resulting in handwritten Gujarati fonts. The resulting character glyphs are converted into an open-type font using the FontForge tool, making them compatible with any Gujarati editor. Both subjective and objective evaluations are conducted to assess the synthesized images and fonts. Subjective evaluation through user studies provides feedback on quality and visual appeal, achieving an overall accuracy of 84.84%. Notably, eleven characters demonstrated a success ratio above 90%. Objective evaluation using an existing recognition system achieves an overall accuracy of 84.28% in OCR evaluation. Notably, fifteen characters had a success ratio of 80% or higher.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03277v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Preeti P. Bhatt, Jitendra V. Nasriwala, Rakesh R. Savant</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AdaBM: On-the-Fly Adaptive Bit Mapping for Image Super-Resolution</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03296</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03296v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Although image super-resolution (SR) problem has experienced unprecedented restoration accuracy with deep neural networks, it has yet limited versatile applications due to the substantial computational costs. Since different input images for SR face different restoration difficulties, adapting computational costs based on the input image, referred to as adaptive inference, has emerged as a promising solution to compress SR networks. Specifically, adapting the quantization bit-widths has successfully reduced the inference and memory cost without sacrificing the accuracy. However, despite the benefits of the resultant adaptive network, existing works rely on time-intensive quantization-aware training with full access to the original training pairs to learn the appropriate bit allocation policies, which limits its ubiquitous usage. To this end, we introduce the first on-the-fly adaptive quantization framework that accelerates the processing time from hours to seconds. We formulate the bit allocation problem with only two bit mapping modules: one to map the input image to the image-wise bit adaptation factor and one to obtain the layer-wise adaptation factors. These bit mappings are calibrated and fine-tuned using only a small number of calibration images. We achieve competitive performance with the previous adaptive quantization methods, while the processing time is accelerated by x2000. Codes are available at https://github.com/Cheeun/AdaBM.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03296v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Cheeun Hong, Kyoung Mu Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sparse Concept Bottleneck Models: Gumbel Tricks in Contrastive Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03323</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03323v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We propose a novel architecture and method of explainable classification with Concept Bottleneck Models (CBMs). While SOTA approaches to Image Classification task work as a black box, there is a growing demand for models that would provide interpreted results. Such a models often learn to predict the distribution over class labels using additional description of this target instances, called concepts. However, existing Bottleneck methods have a number of limitations: their accuracy is lower than that of a standard model and CBMs require an additional set of concepts to leverage. We provide a framework for creating Concept Bottleneck Model from pre-trained multi-modal encoder and new CLIP-like architectures. By introducing a new type of layers known as Concept Bottleneck Layers, we outline three methods for training them: with $\ell_1$-loss, contrastive loss and loss function based on Gumbel-Softmax distribution (Sparse-CBM), while final FC layer is still trained with Cross-Entropy. We show a significant increase in accuracy using sparse hidden layers in CLIP-based bottleneck models. Which means that sparse representation of concepts activation vector is meaningful in Concept Bottleneck Models. Moreover, with our Concept Matrix Search algorithm we can improve CLIP predictions on complex datasets without any additional training or fine-tuning. The code is available at: https://github.com/Andron00e/SparseCBM.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03323v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Andrei Semenov, Vladimir Ivanov, Aleksandr Beznosikov, Alexander Gasnikov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DI-Retinex: Digital-Imaging Retinex Theory for Low-Light Image Enhancement</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03327</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03327v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Many existing methods for low-light image enhancement (LLIE) based on Retinex theory ignore important factors that affect the validity of this theory in digital imaging, such as noise, quantization error, non-linearity, and dynamic range overflow. In this paper, we propose a new expression called Digital-Imaging Retinex theory (DI-Retinex) through theoretical and experimental analysis of Retinex theory in digital imaging. Our new expression includes an offset term in the enhancement model, which allows for pixel-wise brightness contrast adjustment with a non-linear mapping function. In addition, to solve the lowlight enhancement problem in an unsupervised manner, we propose an image-adaptive masked reverse degradation loss in Gamma space. We also design a variance suppression loss for regulating the additional offset term. Extensive experiments show that our proposed method outperforms all existing unsupervised methods in terms of visual quality, model size, and speed. Our algorithm can also assist downstream face detectors in low-light, as it shows the most performance gain after the low-light enhancement compared to other methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03327v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shangquan Sun, Wenqi Ren, Jingyang Peng, Fenglong Song, Xiaochun Cao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meta Invariance Defense Towards Generalizable Robustness to Unknown Adversarial Attacks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03340</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03340v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Despite providing high-performance solutions for computer vision tasks, the deep neural network (DNN) model has been proved to be extremely vulnerable to adversarial attacks. Current defense mainly focuses on the known attacks, but the adversarial robustness to the unknown attacks is seriously overlooked. Besides, commonly used adaptive learning and fine-tuning technique is unsuitable for adversarial defense since it is essentially a zero-shot problem when deployed. Thus, to tackle this challenge, we propose an attack-agnostic defense method named Meta Invariance Defense (MID). Specifically, various combinations of adversarial attacks are randomly sampled from a manually constructed Attacker Pool to constitute different defense tasks against unknown attacks, in which a student encoder is supervised by multi-consistency distillation to learn the attack-invariant features via a meta principle. The proposed MID has two merits: 1) Full distillation from pixel-, feature- and prediction-level between benign and adversarial samples facilitates the discovery of attack-invariance. 2) The model simultaneously achieves robustness to the imperceptible adversarial perturbations in high-level image classification and attack-suppression in low-level robust image regeneration. Theoretical and empirical studies on numerous benchmarks such as ImageNet verify the generalizable robustness and superiority of MID under various attacks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03340v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lei Zhang, Yuhang Zhou, Yi Yang, Xinbo Gao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VF-NeRF: Viewshed Fields for Rigid NeRF Registration</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03349</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03349v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: 3D scene registration is a fundamental problem in computer vision that seeks the best 6-DoF alignment between two scenes. This problem was extensively investigated in the case of point clouds and meshes, but there has been relatively limited work regarding Neural Radiance Fields (NeRF). In this paper, we consider the problem of rigid registration between two NeRFs when the position of the original cameras is not given. Our key novelty is the introduction of Viewshed Fields (VF), an implicit function that determines, for each 3D point, how likely it is to be viewed by the original cameras. We demonstrate how VF can help in the various stages of NeRF registration, with an extensive evaluation showing that VF-NeRF achieves SOTA results on various datasets with different capturing approaches such as LLFF and Objaverese.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03349v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Leo Segre, Shai Avidan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LongVLM: Efficient Long Video Understanding via Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03384</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03384v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Empowered by Large Language Models (LLMs), recent advancements in VideoLLMs have driven progress in various video understanding tasks. These models encode video representations through pooling or query aggregation over a vast number of visual tokens, making computational and memory costs affordable. Despite successfully providing an overall comprehension of video content, existing VideoLLMs still face challenges in achieving detailed understanding in videos due to overlooking local information in long-term videos. To tackle this challenge, we introduce LongVLM, a straightforward yet powerful VideoLLM for long video understanding, building upon the observation that long videos often consist of sequential key events, complex actions, and camera movements. Our approach proposes to decompose long videos into multiple short-term segments and encode local features for each local segment via a hierarchical token merging module. These features are concatenated in temporal order to maintain the storyline across sequential short-term segments. Additionally, we propose to integrate global semantics into each local feature to enhance context understanding. In this way, we encode video representations that incorporate both local and global information, enabling the LLM to generate comprehensive responses for long-term videos. Experimental results on the VideoChatGPT benchmark and zero-shot video question-answering datasets demonstrate the superior capabilities of our model over the previous state-of-the-art methods. Qualitative examples demonstrate that our model produces more precise responses for long videos understanding. Code is available at \url{https://github.com/ziplab/LongVLM}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03384v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuetian Weng, Mingfei Han, Haoyu He, Xiaojun Chang, Bohan Zhuang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two Tricks to Improve Unsupervised Segmentation Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03392</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03392v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present two practical improvement techniques for unsupervised segmentation learning. These techniques address limitations in the resolution and accuracy of predicted segmentation maps of recent state-of-the-art methods. Firstly, we leverage image post-processing techniques such as guided filtering to refine the output masks, improving accuracy while avoiding substantial computational costs. Secondly, we introduce a multi-scale consistency criterion, based on a teacher-student training scheme. This criterion matches segmentation masks predicted from regions of the input image extracted at different resolutions to each other. Experimental results on several benchmarks used in unsupervised segmentation learning demonstrate the effectiveness of our proposed techniques.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03392v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alp Eren Sari, Francesco Locatello, Paolo Favar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Background Noise Reduction of Attention Map for Weakly Supervised Semantic Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03394</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03394v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In weakly-supervised semantic segmentation (WSSS) using only image-level class labels, a problem with CNN-based Class Activation Maps (CAM) is that they tend to activate the most discriminative local regions of objects. On the other hand, methods based on Transformers learn global features but suffer from the issue of background noise contamination. This paper focuses on addressing the issue of background noise in attention weights within the existing WSSS method based on Conformer, known as TransCAM. The proposed method successfully reduces background noise, leading to improved accuracy of pseudo labels. Experimental results demonstrate that our model achieves segmentation performance of 70.5% on the PASCAL VOC 2012 validation data, 71.1% on the test data, and 45.9% on MS COCO 2014 data, outperforming TransCAM in terms of segmentation performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03394v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Izumi Fujimori, Masaki Oono, Masami Shishibori</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Up Video Summarization Pretraining with Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03398</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03398v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Long-form video content constitutes a significant portion of internet traffic, making automated video summarization an essential research problem. However, existing video summarization datasets are notably limited in their size, constraining the effectiveness of state-of-the-art methods for generalization. Our work aims to overcome this limitation by capitalizing on the abundance of long-form videos with dense speech-to-video alignment and the remarkable capabilities of recent large language models (LLMs) in summarizing long text. We introduce an automated and scalable pipeline for generating a large-scale video summarization dataset using LLMs as Oracle summarizers. By leveraging the generated dataset, we analyze the limitations of existing approaches and propose a new video summarization model that effectively addresses them. To facilitate further research in the field, our work also presents a new benchmark dataset that contains 1200 long videos each with high-quality summaries annotated by professionals. Extensive experiments clearly indicate that our proposed approach sets a new state-of-the-art in video summarization across several benchmarks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03398v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dawit Mureja Argaw, Seunghyun Yoon, Fabian Caba Heilbron, Hanieh Deilamsalehy, Trung Bui, Zhaowen Wang, Franck Dernoncourt, Joon Son Chung</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AIGIQA-20K: A Large Database for AI-Generated Image Quality Assessment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03407</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03407v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: With the rapid advancements in AI-Generated Content (AIGC), AI-Generated Images (AIGIs) have been widely applied in entertainment, education, and social media. However, due to the significant variance in quality among different AIGIs, there is an urgent need for models that consistently match human subjective ratings. To address this issue, we organized a challenge towards AIGC quality assessment on NTIRE 2024 that extensively considers 15 popular generative models, utilizing dynamic hyper-parameters (including classifier-free guidance, iteration epochs, and output image resolution), and gather subjective scores that consider perceptual quality and text-to-image alignment altogether comprehensively involving 21 subjects. This approach culminates in the creation of the largest fine-grained AIGI subjective quality database to date with 20,000 AIGIs and 420,000 subjective ratings, known as AIGIQA-20K. Furthermore, we conduct benchmark experiments on this database to assess the correspondence between 16 mainstream AIGI quality models and human perception. We anticipate that this large-scale quality database will inspire robust quality indicators for AIGIs and propel the evolution of AIGC for vision. The database is released on https://www.modelscope.cn/datasets/lcysyzxdxc/AIGCQA-30K-Image.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03407v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chunyi Li, Tengchuan Kou, Yixuan Gao, Yuqin Cao, Wei Sun, Zicheng Zhang, Yingjie Zhou, Zhichao Zhang, Weixia Zhang, Haoning Wu, Xiaohong Liu, Xiongkuo Min, Guangtao Zhai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MiniGPT4-Video: Advancing Multimodal LLMs for Video Understanding with Interleaved Visual-Textual Tokens</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03413</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03413v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper introduces MiniGPT4-Video, a multimodal Large Language Model (LLM) designed specifically for video understanding. The model is capable of processing both temporal visual and textual data, making it adept at understanding the complexities of videos. Building upon the success of MiniGPT-v2, which excelled in translating visual features into the LLM space for single images and achieved impressive results on various image-text benchmarks, this paper extends the model's capabilities to process a sequence of frames, enabling it to comprehend videos. MiniGPT4-video does not only consider visual content but also incorporates textual conversations, allowing the model to effectively answer queries involving both visual and text components. The proposed model outperforms existing state-of-the-art methods, registering gains of 4.22%, 1.13%, 20.82%, and 13.1% on the MSVD, MSRVTT, TGIF, and TVQA benchmarks respectively. Our models and code have been made publicly available here https://vision-cair.github.io/MiniGPT4-video/</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03413v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kirolos Ataallah, Xiaoqian Shen, Eslam Abdelrahman, Essam Sleiman, Deyao Zhu, Jian Ding, Mohamed Elhoseiny</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NMF-Based Analysis of Mobile Eye-Tracking Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03417</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03417v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The depiction of scanpaths from mobile eye-tracking recordings by thumbnails from the stimulus allows the application of visual computing to detect areas of interest in an unsupervised way. We suggest using nonnegative matrix factorization (NMF) to identify such areas in stimuli. For a user-defined integer k, NMF produces an explainable decomposition into k components, each consisting of a spatial representation associated with a temporal indicator. In the context of multiple eye-tracking recordings, this leads to k spatial representations, where the temporal indicator highlights the appearance within recordings. The choice of k provides an opportunity to control the refinement of the decomposition, i.e., the number of areas to detect. We combine our NMF-based approach with visualization techniques to enable an exploratory analysis of multiple recordings. Finally, we demonstrate the usefulness of our approach with mobile eye-tracking data of an art gallery.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03417v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3649902.3653518</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Daniel Kl\"otzl, Tim Krake, Frank Heyen, Michael Becher, Maurice Koch, Daniel Weiskopf, Kuno Kurzhals</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generalizable 3D Scene Reconstruction via Divide and Conquer from a Single View</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03421</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03421v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Single-view 3D reconstruction is currently approached from two dominant perspectives: reconstruction of scenes with limited diversity using 3D data supervision or reconstruction of diverse singular objects using large image priors. However, real-world scenarios are far more complex and exceed the capabilities of these methods. We therefore propose a hybrid method following a divide-and-conquer strategy. We first process the scene holistically, extracting depth and semantic information, and then leverage a single-shot object-level method for the detailed reconstruction of individual components. By following a compositional processing approach, the overall framework achieves full reconstruction of complex 3D scenes from a single image. We purposely design our pipeline to be highly modular by carefully integrating specific procedures for each processing step, without requiring an end-to-end training of the whole system. This enables the pipeline to naturally improve as future methods can replace the individual modules. We demonstrate the reconstruction performance of our approach on both synthetic and real-world scenes, comparing favorable against prior works. Project page: https://andreeadogaru.github.io/Gen3DSR.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03421v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Andreea Dogaru, Mert \"Ozer, Bernhard Egger</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part-Attention Based Model Make Occluded Person Re-Identification Stronger</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03443</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03443v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The goal of occluded person re-identification (ReID) is to retrieve specific pedestrians in occluded situations. However, occluded person ReID still suffers from background clutter and low-quality local feature representations, which limits model performance. In our research, we introduce a new framework called PAB-ReID, which is a novel ReID model incorporating part-attention mechanisms to tackle the aforementioned issues effectively. Firstly, we introduce the human parsing label to guide the generation of more accurate human part attention maps. In addition, we propose a fine-grained feature focuser for generating fine-grained human local feature representations while suppressing background interference. Moreover, We also design a part triplet loss to supervise the learning of human local features, which optimizes intra/inter-class distance. We conducted extensive experiments on specialized occlusion and regular ReID datasets, showcasing that our approach outperforms the existing state-of-the-art methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03443v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhihao Chen, Yiyuan Ge</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SP$^2$OT: Semantic-Regularized Progressive Partial Optimal Transport for Imbalanced Clustering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03446</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03446v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Deep clustering, which learns representation and semantic clustering without labels information, poses a great challenge for deep learning-based approaches. Despite significant progress in recent years, most existing methods focus on uniformly distributed datasets, significantly limiting the practical applicability of their methods. In this paper, we propose a more practical problem setting named deep imbalanced clustering, where the underlying classes exhibit an imbalance distribution. To address this challenge, we introduce a novel optimal transport-based pseudo-label learning framework. Our framework formulates pseudo-label generation as a Semantic-regularized Progressive Partial Optimal Transport (SP$^2$OT) problem, which progressively transports each sample to imbalanced clusters under several prior distribution and semantic relation constraints, thus generating high-quality and imbalance-aware pseudo-labels. To solve SP$^2$OT, we develop a Majorization-Minimization-based optimization algorithm. To be more precise, we employ the strategy of majorization to reformulate the SP$^2$OT problem into a Progressive Partial Optimal Transport problem, which can be transformed into an unbalanced optimal transport problem with augmented constraints and can be solved efficiently by a fast matrix scaling algorithm. Experiments on various datasets, including a human-curated long-tailed CIFAR100, challenging ImageNet-R, and large-scale subsets of fine-grained iNaturalist2018 datasets, demonstrate the superiority of our method.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03446v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chuyu Zhang, Hui Ren, Xuming He</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Much Data are Enough? Investigating Dataset Requirements for Patch-Based Brain MRI Segmentation Tasks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03451</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03451v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Training deep neural networks reliably requires access to large-scale datasets. However, obtaining such datasets can be challenging, especially in the context of neuroimaging analysis tasks, where the cost associated with image acquisition and annotation can be prohibitive. To mitigate both the time and financial costs associated with model development, a clear understanding of the amount of data required to train a satisfactory model is crucial. This paper focuses on an early stage phase of deep learning research, prior to model development, and proposes a strategic framework for estimating the amount of annotated data required to train patch-based segmentation networks. This framework includes the establishment of performance expectations using a novel Minor Boundary Adjustment for Threshold (MinBAT) method, and standardizing patch selection through the ROI-based Expanded Patch Selection (REPS) method. Our experiments demonstrate that tasks involving regions of interest (ROIs) with different sizes or shapes may yield variably acceptable Dice Similarity Coefficient (DSC) scores. By setting an acceptable DSC as the target, the required amount of training data can be estimated and even predicted as data accumulates. This approach could assist researchers and engineers in estimating the cost associated with data collection and annotation when defining a new segmentation task based on deep neural networks, ultimately contributing to their efficient translation to real-world applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03451v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dongang Wang, Peilin Liu, Hengrui Wang, Heidi Beadnall, Kain Kyle, Linda Ly, Mariano Cabezas, Geng Zhan, Ryan Sullivan, Weidong Cai, Wanli Ouyang, Fernando Calamante, Michael Barnett, Chenyu Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Only Scan Once: A Dynamic Scene Reconstruction Pipeline for 6-DoF Robotic Grasping of Novel Objects</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03462</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03462v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In the realm of robotic grasping, achieving accurate and reliable interactions with the environment is a pivotal challenge. Traditional methods of grasp planning methods utilizing partial point clouds derived from depth image often suffer from reduced scene understanding due to occlusion, ultimately impeding their grasping accuracy. Furthermore, scene reconstruction methods have primarily relied upon static techniques, which are susceptible to environment change during manipulation process limits their efficacy in real-time grasping tasks. To address these limitations, this paper introduces a novel two-stage pipeline for dynamic scene reconstruction. In the first stage, our approach takes scene scanning as input to register each target object with mesh reconstruction and novel object pose tracking. In the second stage, pose tracking is still performed to provide object poses in real-time, enabling our approach to transform the reconstructed object point clouds back into the scene. Unlike conventional methodologies, which rely on static scene snapshots, our method continuously captures the evolving scene geometry, resulting in a comprehensive and up-to-date point cloud representation. By circumventing the constraints posed by occlusion, our method enhances the overall grasp planning process and empowers state-of-the-art 6-DoF robotic grasping algorithms to exhibit markedly improved accuracy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03462v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lei Zhou, Haozhe Wang, Zhengshen Zhang, Zhiyang Liu, Francis EH Tay, adn Marcelo H. Ang. Jr</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Performance of computer vision algorithms for fine-grained classification using crowdsourced insect images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03474</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03474v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: With fine-grained classification, we identify unique characteristics to distinguish among classes of the same super-class. We are focusing on species recognition in Insecta, as they are critical for biodiversity monitoring and at the base of many ecosystems. With citizen science campaigns, billions of images are collected in the wild. Once these are labelled, experts can use them to create distribution maps. However, the labelling process is time-consuming, which is where computer vision comes in. The field of computer vision offers a wide range of algorithms, each with its strengths and weaknesses; how do we identify the algorithm that is in line with our application? To answer this question, we provide a full and detailed evaluation of nine algorithms among deep convolutional networks (CNN), vision transformers (ViT), and locality-based vision transformers (LBVT) on 4 different aspects: classification performance, embedding quality, computational cost, and gradient activity. We offer insights that we haven't yet had in this domain proving to which extent these algorithms solve the fine-grained tasks in Insecta. We found that the ViT performs the best on inference speed and computational cost while the LBVT outperforms the others on performance and embedding quality; the CNN provide a trade-off among the metrics.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03474v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rita Pucci, Vincent J. Kalkman, Dan Stowell</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Automated Movie Trailer Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03477</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03477v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Movie trailers are an essential tool for promoting films and attracting audiences. However, the process of creating trailers can be time-consuming and expensive. To streamline this process, we propose an automatic trailer generation framework that generates plausible trailers from a full movie by automating shot selection and composition. Our approach draws inspiration from machine translation techniques and models the movies and trailers as sequences of shots, thus formulating the trailer generation problem as a sequence-to-sequence task. We introduce Trailer Generation Transformer (TGT), a deep-learning framework utilizing an encoder-decoder architecture. TGT movie encoder is tasked with contextualizing each movie shot representation via self-attention, while the autoregressive trailer decoder predicts the feature representation of the next trailer shot, accounting for the relevance of shots' temporal order in trailers. Our TGT significantly outperforms previous methods on a comprehensive suite of metrics.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03477v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dawit Mureja Argaw, Mattia Soldan, Alejandro Pardo, Chen Zhao, Fabian Caba Heilbron, Joon Son Chung, Bernard Ghanem</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AdaGlimpse: Active Visual Exploration with Arbitrary Glimpse Position and Scale</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03482</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03482v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Active Visual Exploration (AVE) is a task that involves dynamically selecting observations (glimpses), which is critical to facilitate comprehension and navigation within an environment. While modern AVE methods have demonstrated impressive performance, they are constrained to fixed-scale glimpses from rigid grids. In contrast, existing mobile platforms equipped with optical zoom capabilities can capture glimpses of arbitrary positions and scales. To address this gap between software and hardware capabilities, we introduce AdaGlimpse. It uses Soft Actor-Critic, a reinforcement learning algorithm tailored for exploration tasks, to select glimpses of arbitrary position and scale. This approach enables our model to rapidly establish a general awareness of the environment before zooming in for detailed analysis. Experimental results demonstrate that AdaGlimpse surpasses previous methods across various visual tasks while maintaining greater applicability in realistic AVE scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03482v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Adam Pardyl, Micha{\l} Wronka, Maciej Wo{\l}czyk, Kamil Adamczewski, Tomasz Trzci\'nski, Bartosz Zieli\'nski</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DQ-DETR: DETR with Dynamic Query for Tiny Object Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03507</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03507v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Despite previous DETR-like methods having performed successfully in generic object detection, tiny object detection is still a challenging task for them since the positional information of object queries is not customized for detecting tiny objects, whose scale is extraordinarily smaller than general objects. Also, DETR-like methods using a fixed number of queries make them unsuitable for aerial datasets, which only contain tiny objects, and the numbers of instances are imbalanced between different images. Thus, we present a simple yet effective model, named DQ-DETR, which consists of three different components: categorical counting module, counting-guided feature enhancement, and dynamic query selection to solve the above-mentioned problems. DQ-DETR uses the prediction and density maps from the categorical counting module to dynamically adjust the number of object queries and improve the positional information of queries. Our model DQ-DETR outperforms previous CNN-based and DETR-like methods, achieving state-of-the-art mAP 30.2% on the AI-TOD-V2 dataset, which mostly consists of tiny objects.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03507v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yi-Xin Huang, Hou-I Liu, Hong-Han Shuai, Wen-Huang Cheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SDPose: Tokenized Pose Estimation via Circulation-Guide Self-Distillation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03518</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03518v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recently, transformer-based methods have achieved state-of-the-art prediction quality on human pose estimation(HPE). Nonetheless, most of these top-performing transformer-based models are too computation-consuming and storage-demanding to deploy on edge computing platforms. Those transformer-based models that require fewer resources are prone to under-fitting due to their smaller scale and thus perform notably worse than their larger counterparts. Given this conundrum, we introduce SDPose, a new self-distillation method for improving the performance of small transformer-based models. To mitigate the problem of under-fitting, we design a transformer module named Multi-Cycled Transformer(MCT) based on multiple-cycled forwards to more fully exploit the potential of small model parameters. Further, in order to prevent the additional inference compute-consuming brought by MCT, we introduce a self-distillation scheme, extracting the knowledge from the MCT module to a naive forward model. Specifically, on the MSCOCO validation dataset, SDPose-T obtains 69.7% mAP with 4.4M parameters and 1.8 GFLOPs. Furthermore, SDPose-S-V2 obtains 73.5% mAP on the MSCOCO validation dataset with 6.2M parameters and 4.7 GFLOPs, achieving a new state-of-the-art among predominant tiny neural network methods. Our code is available at https://github.com/MartyrPenink/SDPose.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03518v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sichen Chen, Yingyi Zhang, Siming Huang, Ran Yi, Ke Fan, Ruixin Zhang, Peixian Chen, Jun Wang, Shouhong Ding, Lizhuang Ma</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HAPNet: Toward Superior RGB-Thermal Scene Parsing via Hybrid, Asymmetric, and Progressive Heterogeneous Feature Fusion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03527</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03527v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Data-fusion networks have shown significant promise for RGB-thermal scene parsing. However, the majority of existing studies have relied on symmetric duplex encoders for heterogeneous feature extraction and fusion, paying inadequate attention to the inherent differences between RGB and thermal modalities. Recent progress in vision foundation models (VFMs) trained through self-supervision on vast amounts of unlabeled data has proven their ability to extract informative, general-purpose features. However, this potential has yet to be fully leveraged in the domain. In this study, we take one step toward this new research area by exploring a feasible strategy to fully exploit VFM features for RGB-thermal scene parsing. Specifically, we delve deeper into the unique characteristics of RGB and thermal modalities, thereby designing a hybrid, asymmetric encoder that incorporates both a VFM and a convolutional neural network. This design allows for more effective extraction of complementary heterogeneous features, which are subsequently fused in a dual-path, progressive manner. Moreover, we introduce an auxiliary task to further enrich the local semantics of the fused features, thereby improving the overall performance of RGB-thermal scene parsing. Our proposed HAPNet, equipped with all these components, demonstrates superior performance compared to all other state-of-the-art RGB-thermal scene parsing networks, achieving top ranks across three widely used public RGB-thermal scene parsing datasets. We believe this new paradigm has opened up new opportunities for future developments in data-fusion scene parsing approaches.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03527v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiahang Li, Peng Yun, Qijun Chen, Rui Fan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COMO: Compact Mapping and Odometry</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03531</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03531v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present COMO, a real-time monocular mapping and odometry system that encodes dense geometry via a compact set of 3D anchor points. Decoding anchor point projections into dense geometry via per-keyframe depth covariance functions guarantees that depth maps are joined together at visible anchor points. The representation enables joint optimization of camera poses and dense geometry, intrinsic 3D consistency, and efficient second-order inference. To maintain a compact yet expressive map, we introduce a frontend that leverages the covariance function for tracking and initializing potentially visually indistinct 3D points across frames. Altogether, we introduce a real-time system capable of estimating accurate poses and consistent geometry.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03531v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Eric Dexheimer, Andrew J. Davison</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If It's Not Enough, Make It So: Reducing Authentic Data Demand in Face Recognition through Synthetic Faces</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03537</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03537v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent advances in deep face recognition have spurred a growing demand for large, diverse, and manually annotated face datasets. Acquiring authentic, high-quality data for face recognition has proven to be a challenge, primarily due to privacy concerns. Large face datasets are primarily sourced from web-based images, lacking explicit user consent. In this paper, we examine whether and how synthetic face data can be used to train effective face recognition models with reduced reliance on authentic images, thereby mitigating data collection concerns. First, we explored the performance gap among recent state-of-the-art face recognition models, trained with synthetic data only and authentic (scarce) data only. Then, we deepened our analysis by training a state-of-the-art backbone with various combinations of synthetic and authentic data, gaining insights into optimizing the limited use of the latter for verification accuracy. Finally, we assessed the effectiveness of data augmentation approaches on synthetic and authentic data, with the same goal in mind. Our results highlighted the effectiveness of FR trained on combined datasets, particularly when combined with appropriate augmentation techniques.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03537v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Andrea Atzori, Fadi Boutros, Naser Damer, Gianni Fenu, Mirko Marras</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is CLIP the main roadblock for fine-grained open-world perception?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03539</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03539v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Modern applications increasingly demand flexible computer vision models that adapt to novel concepts not encountered during training. This necessity is pivotal in emerging domains like extended reality, robotics, and autonomous driving, which require the ability to respond to open-world stimuli. A key ingredient is the ability to identify objects based on free-form textual queries defined at inference time - a task known as open-vocabulary object detection. Multimodal backbones like CLIP are the main enabling technology for current open-world perception solutions. Despite performing well on generic queries, recent studies highlighted limitations on the fine-grained recognition capabilities in open-vocabulary settings - i.e., for distinguishing subtle object features like color, shape, and material. In this paper, we perform a detailed examination of these open-vocabulary object recognition limitations to find the root cause. We evaluate the performance of CLIP, the most commonly used vision-language backbone, against a fine-grained object-matching benchmark, revealing interesting analogies between the limitations of open-vocabulary object detectors and their backbones. Experiments suggest that the lack of fine-grained understanding is caused by the poor separability of object characteristics in the CLIP latent space. Therefore, we try to understand whether fine-grained knowledge is present in CLIP embeddings but not exploited at inference time due, for example, to the unsuitability of the cosine similarity matching function, which may discard important object characteristics. Our preliminary experiments show that simple CLIP latent-space re-projections help separate fine-grained concepts, paving the way towards the development of backbones inherently able to process fine-grained details. The code for reproducing these experiments is available at https://github.com/lorebianchi98/FG-CLIP.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03539v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lorenzo Bianchi, Fabio Carrara, Nicola Messina, Fabrizio Falchi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PointInfinity: Resolution-Invariant Point Diffusion Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03566</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03566v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present PointInfinity, an efficient family of point cloud diffusion models. Our core idea is to use a transformer-based architecture with a fixed-size, resolution-invariant latent representation. This enables efficient training with low-resolution point clouds, while allowing high-resolution point clouds to be generated during inference. More importantly, we show that scaling the test-time resolution beyond the training resolution improves the fidelity of generated point clouds and surfaces. We analyze this phenomenon and draw a link to classifier-free guidance commonly used in diffusion models, demonstrating that both allow trading off fidelity and variability during inference. Experiments on CO3D show that PointInfinity can efficiently generate high-resolution point clouds (up to 131k points, 31 times more than Point-E) with state-of-the-art quality.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03566v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zixuan Huang, Justin Johnson, Shoubhik Debnath, James M. Rehg, Chao-Yuan Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terrain Point Cloud Inpainting via Signal Decomposition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03572</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03572v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The rapid development of 3D acquisition technology has made it possible to obtain point clouds of real-world terrains. However, due to limitations in sensor acquisition technology or specific requirements, point clouds often contain defects such as holes with missing data. Inpainting algorithms are widely used to patch these holes. However, existing traditional inpainting algorithms rely on precise hole boundaries, which limits their ability to handle cases where the boundaries are not well-defined. On the other hand, learning-based completion methods often prioritize reconstructing the entire point cloud instead of solely focusing on hole filling. Based on the fact that real-world terrain exhibits both global smoothness and rich local detail, we propose a novel representation for terrain point clouds. This representation can help to repair the holes without clear boundaries. Specifically, it decomposes terrains into low-frequency and high-frequency components, which are represented by B-spline surfaces and relative height maps respectively. In this way, the terrain point cloud inpainting problem is transformed into a B-spline surface fitting and 2D image inpainting problem. By solving the two problems, the highly complex and irregular holes on the terrain point clouds can be well-filled, which not only satisfies the global terrain undulation but also exhibits rich geometric details. The experimental results also demonstrate the effectiveness of our method.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03572v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yizhou Xie, Xiangning Xie, Yuran Wang, Yanci Zhang, Zejun Lv</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TinyVQA: Compact Multimodal Deep Neural Network for Visual Question Answering on Resource-Constrained Devices</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03574</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03574v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Traditional machine learning models often require powerful hardware, making them unsuitable for deployment on resource-limited devices. Tiny Machine Learning (tinyML) has emerged as a promising approach for running machine learning models on these devices, but integrating multiple data modalities into tinyML models still remains a challenge due to increased complexity, latency, and power consumption. This paper proposes TinyVQA, a novel multimodal deep neural network for visual question answering tasks that can be deployed on resource-constrained tinyML hardware. TinyVQA leverages a supervised attention-based model to learn how to answer questions about images using both vision and language modalities. Distilled knowledge from the supervised attention-based VQA model trains the memory aware compact TinyVQA model and low bit-width quantization technique is employed to further compress the model for deployment on tinyML devices. The TinyVQA model was evaluated on the FloodNet dataset, which is used for post-disaster damage assessment. The compact model achieved an accuracy of 79.5%, demonstrating the effectiveness of TinyVQA for real-world applications. Additionally, the model was deployed on a Crazyflie 2.0 drone, equipped with an AI deck and GAP8 microprocessor. The TinyVQA model achieved low latencies of 56 ms and consumes 693 mW power while deployed on the tiny drone, showcasing its suitability for resource-constrained embedded systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03574v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hasib-Al Rashid, Argho Sarkar, Aryya Gangopadhyay, Maryam Rahnemoonfar, Tinoosh Mohsenin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DreamScene: 3D Gaussian-based Text-to-3D Scene Generation via Formation Pattern Sampling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03575</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03575v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Text-to-3D scene generation holds immense potential for the gaming, film, and architecture sectors. Despite significant progress, existing methods struggle with maintaining high quality, consistency, and editing flexibility. In this paper, we propose DreamScene, a 3D Gaussian-based novel text-to-3D scene generation framework, to tackle the aforementioned three challenges mainly via two strategies. First, DreamScene employs Formation Pattern Sampling (FPS), a multi-timestep sampling strategy guided by the formation patterns of 3D objects, to form fast, semantically rich, and high-quality representations. FPS uses 3D Gaussian filtering for optimization stability, and leverages reconstruction techniques to generate plausible textures. Second, DreamScene employs a progressive three-stage camera sampling strategy, specifically designed for both indoor and outdoor settings, to effectively ensure object-environment integration and scene-wide 3D consistency. Last, DreamScene enhances scene editing flexibility by integrating objects and environments, enabling targeted adjustments. Extensive experiments validate DreamScene's superiority over current state-of-the-art techniques, heralding its wide-ranging potential for diverse applications. Code and demos will be released at https://dreamscene-project.github.io .</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03575v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haoran Li, Haolin Shi, Wenli Zhang, Wenjun Wu, Yong Liao, Lin Wang, Lik-hang Lee, Pengyuan Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards more realistic human motion prediction with attention to motion coordination</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03584</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03584v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Joint relation modeling is a curial component in human motion prediction. Most existing methods rely on skeletal-based graphs to build the joint relations, where local interactive relations between joint pairs are well learned. However, the motion coordination, a global joint relation reflecting the simultaneous cooperation of all joints, is usually weakened because it is learned from part to whole progressively and asynchronously. Thus, the final predicted motions usually appear unrealistic. To tackle this issue, we learn a medium, called coordination attractor (CA), from the spatiotemporal features of motion to characterize the global motion features, which is subsequently used to build new relative joint relations. Through the CA, all joints are related simultaneously, and thus the motion coordination of all joints can be better learned. Based on this, we further propose a novel joint relation modeling module, Comprehensive Joint Relation Extractor (CJRE), to combine this motion coordination with the local interactions between joint pairs in a unified manner. Additionally, we also present a Multi-timescale Dynamics Extractor (MTDE) to extract enriched dynamics from the raw position information for effective prediction. Extensive experiments show that the proposed framework outperforms state-of-the-art methods in both short- and long-term predictions on H3.6M, CMU-Mocap, and 3DPW.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03584v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1109/TCSVT.2022.3163782</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Pengxiang Ding, Jianqin Yin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SemGrasp: Semantic Grasp Generation via Language Aligned Discretization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03590</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03590v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Generating natural human grasps necessitates consideration of not just object geometry but also semantic information. Solely depending on object shape for grasp generation confines the applications of prior methods in downstream tasks. This paper presents a novel semantic-based grasp generation method, termed SemGrasp, which generates a static human grasp pose by incorporating semantic information into the grasp representation. We introduce a discrete representation that aligns the grasp space with semantic space, enabling the generation of grasp postures in accordance with language instructions. A Multimodal Large Language Model (MLLM) is subsequently fine-tuned, integrating object, grasp, and language within a unified semantic space. To facilitate the training of SemGrasp, we have compiled a large-scale, grasp-text-aligned dataset named CapGrasp, featuring about 260k detailed captions and 50k diverse grasps. Experimental findings demonstrate that SemGrasp efficiently generates natural human grasps in alignment with linguistic intentions. Our code, models, and dataset are available publicly at: https://kailinli.github.io/SemGrasp.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03590v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kailin Li, Jingbo Wang, Lixin Yang, Cewu Lu, Bo Dai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>InsectMamba: Insect Pest Classification with State Space Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03611</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03611v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The classification of insect pests is a critical task in agricultural technology, vital for ensuring food security and environmental sustainability. However, the complexity of pest identification, due to factors like high camouflage and species diversity, poses significant obstacles. Existing methods struggle with the fine-grained feature extraction needed to distinguish between closely related pest species. Although recent advancements have utilized modified network structures and combined deep learning approaches to improve accuracy, challenges persist due to the similarity between pests and their surroundings. To address this problem, we introduce InsectMamba, a novel approach that integrates State Space Models (SSMs), Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs), Multi-Head Self-Attention mechanism (MSA), and Multilayer Perceptrons (MLPs) within Mix-SSM blocks. This integration facilitates the extraction of comprehensive visual features by leveraging the strengths of each encoding strategy. A selective module is also proposed to adaptively aggregate these features, enhancing the model's ability to discern pest characteristics. InsectMamba was evaluated against strong competitors across five insect pest classification datasets. The results demonstrate its superior performance and verify the significance of each model component by an ablation study.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03611v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qianning Wang, Chenglin Wang, Zhixin Lai, Yucheng Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Per-Gaussian Embedding-Based Deformation for Deformable 3D Gaussian Splatting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03613</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03613v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: As 3D Gaussian Splatting (3DGS) provides fast and high-quality novel view synthesis, it is a natural extension to deform a canonical 3DGS to multiple frames. However, previous works fail to accurately reconstruct dynamic scenes, especially 1) static parts moving along nearby dynamic parts, and 2) some dynamic areas are blurry. We attribute the failure to the wrong design of the deformation field, which is built as a coordinate-based function. This approach is problematic because 3DGS is a mixture of multiple fields centered at the Gaussians, not just a single coordinate-based framework. To resolve this problem, we define the deformation as a function of per-Gaussian embeddings and temporal embeddings. Moreover, we decompose deformations as coarse and fine deformations to model slow and fast movements, respectively. Also, we introduce an efficient training strategy for faster convergence and higher quality. Project page: https://jeongminb.github.io/e-d3dgs/</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03613v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jeongmin Bae, Seoha Kim, Youngsik Yun, Hahyun Lee, Gun Bang, Youngjung Uh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DeViDe: Faceted medical knowledge for improved medical vision-language pre-training</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03618</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03618v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Vision-language pre-training for chest X-rays has made significant strides, primarily by utilizing paired radiographs and radiology reports. However, existing approaches often face challenges in encoding medical knowledge effectively. While radiology reports provide insights into the current disease manifestation, medical definitions (as used by contemporary methods) tend to be overly abstract, creating a gap in knowledge. To address this, we propose DeViDe, a novel transformer-based method that leverages radiographic descriptions from the open web. These descriptions outline general visual characteristics of diseases in radiographs, and when combined with abstract definitions and radiology reports, provide a holistic snapshot of knowledge. DeViDe incorporates three key features for knowledge-augmented vision language alignment: First, a large-language model-based augmentation is employed to homogenise medical knowledge from diverse sources. Second, this knowledge is aligned with image information at various levels of granularity. Third, a novel projection layer is proposed to handle the complexity of aligning each image with multiple descriptions arising in a multi-label setting. In zero-shot settings, DeViDe performs comparably to fully supervised models on external datasets and achieves state-of-the-art results on three large-scale datasets. Additionally, fine-tuning DeViDe on four downstream tasks and six segmentation tasks showcases its superior performance across data from diverse distributions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03618v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haozhe Luo, Ziyu Zhou, Corentin Royer, Anjany Sekuboyina, Bjoern Menze</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LCM-Lookahead for Encoder-based Text-to-Image Personalization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03620</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03620v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent advancements in diffusion models have introduced fast sampling methods that can effectively produce high-quality images in just one or a few denoising steps. Interestingly, when these are distilled from existing diffusion models, they often maintain alignment with the original model, retaining similar outputs for similar prompts and seeds. These properties present opportunities to leverage fast sampling methods as a shortcut-mechanism, using them to create a preview of denoised outputs through which we can backpropagate image-space losses. In this work, we explore the potential of using such shortcut-mechanisms to guide the personalization of text-to-image models to specific facial identities. We focus on encoder-based personalization approaches, and demonstrate that by tuning them with a lookahead identity loss, we can achieve higher identity fidelity, without sacrificing layout diversity or prompt alignment. We further explore the use of attention sharing mechanisms and consistent data generation for the task of personalization, and find that encoder training can benefit from both.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03620v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rinon Gal, Or Lichter, Elad Richardson, Or Patashnik, Amit H. Bermano, Gal Chechik, Daniel Cohen-Or</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robust Concept Erasure Using Task Vectors</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03631</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03631v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: With the rapid growth of text-to-image models, a variety of techniques have been suggested to prevent undesirable image generations. Yet, these methods often only protect against specific user prompts and have been shown to allow unsafe generations with other inputs. Here we focus on unconditionally erasing a concept from a text-to-image model rather than conditioning the erasure on the user's prompt. We first show that compared to input-dependent erasure methods, concept erasure that uses Task Vectors (TV) is more robust to unexpected user inputs, not seen during training. However, TV-based erasure can also affect the core performance of the edited model, particularly when the required edit strength is unknown. To this end, we propose a method called Diverse Inversion, which we use to estimate the required strength of the TV edit. Diverse Inversion finds within the model input space a large set of word embeddings, each of which induces the generation of the target concept. We find that encouraging diversity in the set makes our estimation more robust to unexpected prompts. Finally, we show that Diverse Inversion enables us to apply a TV edit only to a subset of the model weights, enhancing the erasure capabilities while better maintaining the core functionality of the model.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03631v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Minh Pham, Kelly O. Marshall, Chinmay Hegde, Niv Cohen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reference-Based 3D-Aware Image Editing with Triplane</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03632</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03632v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs) have emerged as powerful tools not only for high-quality image generation but also for real image editing through manipulation of their interpretable latent spaces. Recent advancements in GANs include the development of 3D-aware models such as EG3D, characterized by efficient triplane-based architectures enabling the reconstruction of 3D geometry from single images. However, scant attention has been devoted to providing an integrated framework for high-quality reference-based 3D-aware image editing within this domain. This study addresses this gap by exploring and demonstrating the effectiveness of EG3D's triplane space for achieving advanced reference-based edits, presenting a unique perspective on 3D-aware image editing through our novel pipeline. Our approach integrates the encoding of triplane features, spatial disentanglement and automatic localization of features in the triplane domain, and fusion learning for desired image editing. Moreover, our framework demonstrates versatility across domains, extending its effectiveness to animal face edits and partial stylization of cartoon portraits. The method shows significant improvements over relevant 3D-aware latent editing and 2D reference-based editing methods, both qualitatively and quantitatively. Project page: https://three-bee.github.io/triplane_edit</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03632v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bahri Batuhan Bilecen, Yigit Yalin, Ning Yu, Aysegul Dundar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WorDepth: Variational Language Prior for Monocular Depth Estimation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03635</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03635v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Three-dimensional (3D) reconstruction from a single image is an ill-posed problem with inherent ambiguities, i.e. scale. Predicting a 3D scene from text description(s) is similarly ill-posed, i.e. spatial arrangements of objects described. We investigate the question of whether two inherently ambiguous modalities can be used in conjunction to produce metric-scaled reconstructions. To test this, we focus on monocular depth estimation, the problem of predicting a dense depth map from a single image, but with an additional text caption describing the scene. To this end, we begin by encoding the text caption as a mean and standard deviation; using a variational framework, we learn the distribution of the plausible metric reconstructions of 3D scenes corresponding to the text captions as a prior. To "select" a specific reconstruction or depth map, we encode the given image through a conditional sampler that samples from the latent space of the variational text encoder, which is then decoded to the output depth map. Our approach is trained alternatingly between the text and image branches: in one optimization step, we predict the mean and standard deviation from the text description and sample from a standard Gaussian, and in the other, we sample using a (image) conditional sampler. Once trained, we directly predict depth from the encoded text using the conditional sampler. We demonstrate our approach on indoor (NYUv2) and outdoor (KITTI) scenarios, where we show that language can consistently improve performance in both.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03635v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ziyao Zeng, Daniel Wang, Fengyu Yang, Hyoungseob Park, Yangchao Wu, Stefano Soatto, Byung-Woo Hong, Dong Lao, Alex Wong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DiffBody: Human Body Restoration by Imagining with Generative Diffusion Prior</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03642</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03642v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Human body restoration plays a vital role in various applications related to the human body. Despite recent advances in general image restoration using generative models, their performance in human body restoration remains mediocre, often resulting in foreground and background blending, over-smoothing surface textures, missing accessories, and distorted limbs. Addressing these challenges, we propose a novel approach by constructing a human body-aware diffusion model that leverages domain-specific knowledge to enhance performance. Specifically, we employ a pretrained body attention module to guide the diffusion model's focus on the foreground, addressing issues caused by blending between the subject and background. We also demonstrate the value of revisiting the language modality of the diffusion model in restoration tasks by seamlessly incorporating text prompt to improve the quality of surface texture and additional clothing and accessories details. Additionally, we introduce a diffusion sampler tailored for fine-grained human body parts, utilizing local semantic information to rectify limb distortions. Lastly, we collect a comprehensive dataset for benchmarking and advancing the field of human body restoration. Extensive experimental validation showcases the superiority of our approach, both quantitatively and qualitatively, over existing methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03642v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yiming Zhang, Zhe Wang, Xinjie Li, Yunchen Yuan, Chengsong Zhang, Xiao Sun, Zhihang Zhong, Jian Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoupling Static and Hierarchical Motion Perception for Referring Video Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03645</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03645v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Referring video segmentation relies on natural language expressions to identify and segment objects, often emphasizing motion clues. Previous works treat a sentence as a whole and directly perform identification at the video-level, mixing up static image-level cues with temporal motion cues. However, image-level features cannot well comprehend motion cues in sentences, and static cues are not crucial for temporal perception. In fact, static cues can sometimes interfere with temporal perception by overshadowing motion cues. In this work, we propose to decouple video-level referring expression understanding into static and motion perception, with a specific emphasis on enhancing temporal comprehension. Firstly, we introduce an expression-decoupling module to make static cues and motion cues perform their distinct role, alleviating the issue of sentence embeddings overlooking motion cues. Secondly, we propose a hierarchical motion perception module to capture temporal information effectively across varying timescales. Furthermore, we employ contrastive learning to distinguish the motions of visually similar objects. These contributions yield state-of-the-art performance across five datasets, including a remarkable $\textbf{9.2%}$ $\mathcal{J\&amp;F}$ improvement on the challenging $\textbf{MeViS}$ dataset. Code is available at https://github.com/heshuting555/DsHmp.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03645v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shuting He, Henghui Ding</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenNeRF: Open Set 3D Neural Scene Segmentation with Pixel-Wise Features and Rendered Novel Views</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03650</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03650v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large visual-language models (VLMs), like CLIP, enable open-set image segmentation to segment arbitrary concepts from an image in a zero-shot manner. This goes beyond the traditional closed-set assumption, i.e., where models can only segment classes from a pre-defined training set. More recently, first works on open-set segmentation in 3D scenes have appeared in the literature. These methods are heavily influenced by closed-set 3D convolutional approaches that process point clouds or polygon meshes. However, these 3D scene representations do not align well with the image-based nature of the visual-language models. Indeed, point cloud and 3D meshes typically have a lower resolution than images and the reconstructed 3D scene geometry might not project well to the underlying 2D image sequences used to compute pixel-aligned CLIP features. To address these challenges, we propose OpenNeRF which naturally operates on posed images and directly encodes the VLM features within the NeRF. This is similar in spirit to LERF, however our work shows that using pixel-wise VLM features (instead of global CLIP features) results in an overall less complex architecture without the need for additional DINO regularization. Our OpenNeRF further leverages NeRF's ability to render novel views and extract open-set VLM features from areas that are not well observed in the initial posed images. For 3D point cloud segmentation on the Replica dataset, OpenNeRF outperforms recent open-vocabulary methods such as LERF and OpenScene by at least +4.9 mIoU.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03650v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>ICLR 2024</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Francis Engelmann, Fabian Manhardt, Michael Niemeyer, Keisuke Tateno, Marc Pollefeys, Federico Tombari</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The More You See in 2D, the More You Perceive in 3D</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03652</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03652v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Humans can infer 3D structure from 2D images of an object based on past experience and improve their 3D understanding as they see more images. Inspired by this behavior, we introduce SAP3D, a system for 3D reconstruction and novel view synthesis from an arbitrary number of unposed images. Given a few unposed images of an object, we adapt a pre-trained view-conditioned diffusion model together with the camera poses of the images via test-time fine-tuning. The adapted diffusion model and the obtained camera poses are then utilized as instance-specific priors for 3D reconstruction and novel view synthesis. We show that as the number of input images increases, the performance of our approach improves, bridging the gap between optimization-based prior-less 3D reconstruction methods and single-image-to-3D diffusion-based methods. We demonstrate our system on real images as well as standard synthetic benchmarks. Our ablation studies confirm that this adaption behavior is key for more accurate 3D understanding.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03652v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xinyang Han, Zelin Gao, Angjoo Kanazawa, Shubham Goel, Yossi Gandelsman</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoMat: Aligning Text-to-Image Diffusion Model with Image-to-Text Concept Matching</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03653</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03653v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Diffusion models have demonstrated great success in the field of text-to-image generation. However, alleviating the misalignment between the text prompts and images is still challenging. The root reason behind the misalignment has not been extensively investigated. We observe that the misalignment is caused by inadequate token attention activation. We further attribute this phenomenon to the diffusion model's insufficient condition utilization, which is caused by its training paradigm. To address the issue, we propose CoMat, an end-to-end diffusion model fine-tuning strategy with an image-to-text concept matching mechanism. We leverage an image captioning model to measure image-to-text alignment and guide the diffusion model to revisit ignored tokens. A novel attribute concentration module is also proposed to address the attribute binding problem. Without any image or human preference data, we use only 20K text prompts to fine-tune SDXL to obtain CoMat-SDXL. Extensive experiments show that CoMat-SDXL significantly outperforms the baseline model SDXL in two text-to-image alignment benchmarks and achieves start-of-the-art performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03653v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dongzhi Jiang, Guanglu Song, Xiaoshi Wu, Renrui Zhang, Dazhong Shen, Zhuofan Zong, Yu Liu, Hongsheng Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RaFE: Generative Radiance Fields Restoration</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03654</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03654v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: NeRF (Neural Radiance Fields) has demonstrated tremendous potential in novel view synthesis and 3D reconstruction, but its performance is sensitive to input image quality, which struggles to achieve high-fidelity rendering when provided with low-quality sparse input viewpoints. Previous methods for NeRF restoration are tailored for specific degradation type, ignoring the generality of restoration. To overcome this limitation, we propose a generic radiance fields restoration pipeline, named RaFE, which applies to various types of degradations, such as low resolution, blurriness, noise, compression artifacts, or their combinations. Our approach leverages the success of off-the-shelf 2D restoration methods to recover the multi-view images individually. Instead of reconstructing a blurred NeRF by averaging inconsistencies, we introduce a novel approach using Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs) for NeRF generation to better accommodate the geometric and appearance inconsistencies present in the multi-view images. Specifically, we adopt a two-level tri-plane architecture, where the coarse level remains fixed to represent the low-quality NeRF, and a fine-level residual tri-plane to be added to the coarse level is modeled as a distribution with GAN to capture potential variations in restoration. We validate RaFE on both synthetic and real cases for various restoration tasks, demonstrating superior performance in both quantitative and qualitative evaluations, surpassing other 3D restoration methods specific to single task. Please see our project website https://zkaiwu.github.io/RaFE-Project/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03654v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhongkai Wu, Ziyu Wan, Jing Zhang, Jing Liao, Dong Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MVD-Fusion: Single-view 3D via Depth-consistent Multi-view Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03656</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03656v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present MVD-Fusion: a method for single-view 3D inference via generative modeling of multi-view-consistent RGB-D images. While recent methods pursuing 3D inference advocate learning novel-view generative models, these generations are not 3D-consistent and require a distillation process to generate a 3D output. We instead cast the task of 3D inference as directly generating mutually-consistent multiple views and build on the insight that additionally inferring depth can provide a mechanism for enforcing this consistency. Specifically, we train a denoising diffusion model to generate multi-view RGB-D images given a single RGB input image and leverage the (intermediate noisy) depth estimates to obtain reprojection-based conditioning to maintain multi-view consistency. We train our model using large-scale synthetic dataset Obajverse as well as the real-world CO3D dataset comprising of generic camera viewpoints. We demonstrate that our approach can yield more accurate synthesis compared to recent state-of-the-art, including distillation-based 3D inference and prior multi-view generation methods. We also evaluate the geometry induced by our multi-view depth prediction and find that it yields a more accurate representation than other direct 3D inference approaches.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03656v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hanzhe Hu, Zhizhuo Zhou, Varun Jampani, Shubham Tulsiani</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OW-VISCap: Open-World Video Instance Segmentation and Captioning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03657</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03657v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Open-world video instance segmentation is an important video understanding task. Yet most methods either operate in a closed-world setting, require an additional user-input, or use classic region-based proposals to identify never before seen objects. Further, these methods only assign a one-word label to detected objects, and don't generate rich object-centric descriptions. They also often suffer from highly overlapping predictions. To address these issues, we propose Open-World Video Instance Segmentation and Captioning (OW-VISCap), an approach to jointly segment, track, and caption previously seen or unseen objects in a video. For this, we introduce open-world object queries to discover never before seen objects without additional user-input. We generate rich and descriptive object-centric captions for each detected object via a masked attention augmented LLM input. We introduce an inter-query contrastive loss to ensure that the object queries differ from one another. Our generalized approach matches or surpasses state-of-the-art on three tasks: open-world video instance segmentation on the BURST dataset, dense video object captioning on the VidSTG dataset, and closed-world video instance segmentation on the OVIS dataset.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03657v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Anwesa Choudhuri, Girish Chowdhary, Alexander G. Schwing</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Know Your Neighbors: Improving Single-View Reconstruction via Spatial Vision-Language Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03658</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03658v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recovering the 3D scene geometry from a single view is a fundamental yet ill-posed problem in computer vision. While classical depth estimation methods infer only a 2.5D scene representation limited to the image plane, recent approaches based on radiance fields reconstruct a full 3D representation. However, these methods still struggle with occluded regions since inferring geometry without visual observation requires (i) semantic knowledge of the surroundings, and (ii) reasoning about spatial context. We propose KYN, a novel method for single-view scene reconstruction that reasons about semantic and spatial context to predict each point's density. We introduce a vision-language modulation module to enrich point features with fine-grained semantic information. We aggregate point representations across the scene through a language-guided spatial attention mechanism to yield per-point density predictions aware of the 3D semantic context. We show that KYN improves 3D shape recovery compared to predicting density for each 3D point in isolation. We achieve state-of-the-art results in scene and object reconstruction on KITTI-360, and show improved zero-shot generalization compared to prior work. Project page: https://ruili3.github.io/kyn.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03658v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rui Li, Tobias Fischer, Mattia Segu, Marc Pollefeys, Luc Van Gool, Federico Tombari</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MeshBrush: Painting the Anatomical Mesh with Neural Stylization for Endoscopy</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.02999</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.02999v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Style transfer is a promising approach to close the sim-to-real gap in medical endoscopy. Rendering realistic endoscopic videos by traversing pre-operative scans (such as MRI or CT) can generate realistic simulations as well as ground truth camera poses and depth maps. Although image-to-image (I2I) translation models such as CycleGAN perform well, they are unsuitable for video-to-video synthesis due to the lack of temporal consistency, resulting in artifacts between frames. We propose MeshBrush, a neural mesh stylization method to synthesize temporally consistent videos with differentiable rendering. MeshBrush uses the underlying geometry of patient imaging data while leveraging existing I2I methods. With learned per-vertex textures, the stylized mesh guarantees consistency while producing high-fidelity outputs. We demonstrate that mesh stylization is a promising approach for creating realistic simulations for downstream tasks such as training and preoperative planning. Although our method is tested and designed for ureteroscopy, its components are transferable to general endoscopic and laparoscopic procedures.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.02999v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>John J. Han, Ayberk Acar, Nicholas Kavoussi, Jie Ying Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Skeleton Recall Loss for Connectivity Conserving and Resource Efficient Segmentation of Thin Tubular Structures</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03010</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03010v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Accurately segmenting thin tubular structures, such as vessels, nerves, roads or concrete cracks, is a crucial task in computer vision. Standard deep learning-based segmentation loss functions, such as Dice or Cross-Entropy, focus on volumetric overlap, often at the expense of preserving structural connectivity or topology. This can lead to segmentation errors that adversely affect downstream tasks, including flow calculation, navigation, and structural inspection. Although current topology-focused losses mark an improvement, they introduce significant computational and memory overheads. This is particularly relevant for 3D data, rendering these losses infeasible for larger volumes as well as increasingly important multi-class segmentation problems. To mitigate this, we propose a novel Skeleton Recall Loss, which effectively addresses these challenges by circumventing intensive GPU-based calculations with inexpensive CPU operations. It demonstrates overall superior performance to current state-of-the-art approaches on five public datasets for topology-preserving segmentation, while substantially reducing computational overheads by more than 90%. In doing so, we introduce the first multi-class capable loss function for thin structure segmentation, excelling in both efficiency and efficacy for topology-preservation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03010v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yannick Kirchhoff, Maximilian R. Rokuss, Saikat Roy, Balint Kovacs, Constantin Ulrich, Tassilo Wald, Maximilian Zenk, Philipp Vollmuth, Jens Kleesiek, Fabian Isensee, Klaus Maier-Hein</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BCAmirs at SemEval-2024 Task 4: Beyond Words: A Multimodal and Multilingual Exploration of Persuasion in Memes</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03022</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03022v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Memes, combining text and images, frequently use metaphors to convey persuasive messages, shaping public opinion. Motivated by this, our team engaged in SemEval-2024 Task 4, a hierarchical multi-label classification task designed to identify rhetorical and psychological persuasion techniques embedded within memes. To tackle this problem, we introduced a caption generation step to assess the modality gap and the impact of additional semantic information from images, which improved our result. Our best model utilizes GPT-4 generated captions alongside meme text to fine-tune RoBERTa as the text encoder and CLIP as the image encoder. It outperforms the baseline by a large margin in all 12 subtasks. In particular, it ranked in top-3 across all languages in Subtask 2a, and top-4 in Subtask 2b, demonstrating quantitatively strong performance. The improvement achieved by the introduced intermediate step is likely attributable to the metaphorical essence of images that challenges visual encoders. This highlights the potential for improving abstract visual semantics encoding.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03022v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.IT</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>math.IT</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Amirhossein Abaskohi, Amirhossein Dabiriaghdam, Lele Wang, Giuseppe Carenini</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-supervised 6-DoF Robot Grasping by Demonstration via Augmented Reality Teleoperation System</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03067</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03067v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Most existing 6-DoF robot grasping solutions depend on strong supervision on grasp pose to ensure satisfactory performance, which could be laborious and impractical when the robot works in some restricted area. To this end, we propose a self-supervised 6-DoF grasp pose detection framework via an Augmented Reality (AR) teleoperation system that can efficiently learn human demonstrations and provide 6-DoF grasp poses without grasp pose annotations. Specifically, the system collects the human demonstration from the AR environment and contrastively learns the grasping strategy from the demonstration. For the real-world experiment, the proposed system leads to satisfactory grasping abilities and learning to grasp unknown objects within three demonstrations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03067v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiwen Dengxiong, Xueting Wang, Shi Bai, Yunbo Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GaSpCT: Gaussian Splatting for Novel CT Projection View Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03126</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03126v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We present GaSpCT, a novel view synthesis and 3D scene representation method used to generate novel projection views for Computer Tomography (CT) scans. We adapt the Gaussian Splatting framework to enable novel view synthesis in CT based on limited sets of 2D image projections and without the need for Structure from Motion (SfM) methodologies. Therefore, we reduce the total scanning duration and the amount of radiation dose the patient receives during the scan. We adapted the loss function to our use-case by encouraging a stronger background and foreground distinction using two sparsity promoting regularizers: a beta loss and a total variation (TV) loss. Finally, we initialize the Gaussian locations across the 3D space using a uniform prior distribution of where the brain's positioning would be expected to be within the field of view. We evaluate the performance of our model using brain CT scans from the Parkinson's Progression Markers Initiative (PPMI) dataset and demonstrate that the rendered novel views closely match the original projection views of the simulated scan, and have better performance than other implicit 3D scene representations methodologies. Furthermore, we empirically observe reduced training time compared to neural network based image synthesis for sparse-view CT image reconstruction. Finally, the memory requirements of the Gaussian Splatting representations are reduced by 17% compared to the equivalent voxel grid image representations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03126v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Emmanouil Nikolakakis, Utkarsh Gupta, Jonathan Vengosh, Justin Bui, Razvan Marinescu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Classification of Nasopharyngeal Cases using DenseNet Deep Learning Architecture</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03188</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03188v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Nasopharyngeal carcinoma (NPC) is one of the understudied yet deadliest cancers in South East Asia. In Malaysia, the prevalence is identified mainly in Sarawak, among the ethnic of Bidayuh. NPC is often late-diagnosed because it is asymptomatic at the early stage. There are several tissue representations from the nasopharynx biopsy, such as nasopharyngeal inflammation (NPI), lymphoid hyperplasia (LHP), nasopharyngeal carcinoma (NPC) and normal tissue. This paper is our first initiative to identify the difference between NPC, NPI and normal cases. Seven whole slide images (WSIs) with gigapixel resolutions from seven different patients and two hospitals were experimented with using two test setups, consisting of a different set of images. The tissue regions are patched into smaller blocks and classified using DenseNet architecture with 21 dense layers. Two tests are carried out, each for proof of concept (Test 1) and real-test scenario (Test 2). The accuracy achieved for NPC class is 94.8% for Test 1 and 67.0% for Test 2.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03188v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>W. S. H. M. W. Ahmad, M. F. A. Fauzi, M. K. Abdullahi, Jenny T. H. Lee, N. S. A. Basry, A Yahaya, A. M. Ismail, A. Adam, Elaine W. L. Chan, F. S. Abas</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Future-Proofing Class Incremental Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03200</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03200v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Exemplar-Free Class Incremental Learning is a highly challenging setting where replay memory is unavailable. Methods relying on frozen feature extractors have drawn attention recently in this setting due to their impressive performances and lower computational costs. However, those methods are highly dependent on the data used to train the feature extractor and may struggle when an insufficient amount of classes are available during the first incremental step. To overcome this limitation, we propose to use a pre-trained text-to-image diffusion model in order to generate synthetic images of future classes and use them to train the feature extractor. Experiments on the standard benchmarks CIFAR100 and ImageNet-Subset demonstrate that our proposed method can be used to improve state-of-the-art methods for exemplar-free class incremental learning, especially in the most difficult settings where the first incremental step only contains few classes. Moreover, we show that using synthetic samples of future classes achieves higher performance than using real data from different classes, paving the way for better and less costly pre-training methods for incremental learning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03200v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Quentin Jodelet, Xin Liu, Yin Jun Phua, Tsuyoshi Murata</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A dataset of primary nasopharyngeal carcinoma MRI with multi-modalities segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03253</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03253v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Multi-modality magnetic resonance imaging data with various sequences facilitate the early diagnosis, tumor segmentation, and disease staging in the management of nasopharyngeal carcinoma (NPC). The lack of publicly available, comprehensive datasets limits advancements in diagnosis, treatment planning, and the development of machine learning algorithms for NPC. Addressing this critical need, we introduce the first comprehensive NPC MRI dataset, encompassing MR axial imaging of 277 primary NPC patients. This dataset includes T1-weighted, T2-weighted, and contrast-enhanced T1-weighted sequences, totaling 831 scans. In addition to the corresponding clinical data, manually annotated and labeled segmentations by experienced radiologists offer high-quality data resources from untreated primary NPC.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03253v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yin Li, Qi Chen, Kai Wang, Meige Li, Liping Si, Yingwei Guo, Yu Xiong, Qixing Wang, Yang Qin, Ling Xu, Patrick van der Smagt, Jun Tang, Nutan Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Future Predictive Success-or-Failure Classification for Long-Horizon Robotic Tasks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03415</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03415v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Automating long-horizon tasks with a robotic arm has been a central research topic in robotics. Optimization-based action planning is an efficient approach for creating an action plan to complete a given task. Construction of a reliable planning method requires a design process of conditions, e.g., to avoid collision between objects. The design process, however, has two critical issues: 1) iterative trials--the design process is time-consuming due to the trial-and-error process of modifying conditions, and 2) manual redesign--it is difficult to cover all the necessary conditions manually. To tackle these issues, this paper proposes a future-predictive success-or-failure-classification method to obtain conditions automatically. The key idea behind the proposed method is an end-to-end approach for determining whether the action plan can complete a given task instead of manually redesigning the conditions. The proposed method uses a long-horizon future-prediction method to enable success-or-failure classification without the execution of an action plan. This paper also proposes a regularization term called transition consistency regularization to provide easy-to-predict feature distribution. The regularization term improves future prediction and classification performance. The effectiveness of our method is demonstrated through classification and robotic-manipulation experiments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03415v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Naoya Sogi, Hiroyuki Oyama, Takashi Shibata, Makoto Terao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChangeMamba: Remote Sensing Change Detection with Spatio-Temporal State Space Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03425</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03425v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Convolutional neural networks (CNN) and Transformers have made impressive progress in the field of remote sensing change detection (CD). However, both architectures have their inherent shortcomings. Recently, the Mamba architecture, based on spatial state models, has shown remarkable performance in a series of natural language processing tasks, which can effectively compensate for the shortcomings of the above two architectures. In this paper, we explore for the first time the potential of the Mamba architecture for remote sensing change detection tasks. We tailor the corresponding frameworks, called MambaBCD, MambaSCD, and MambaBDA, for binary change detection (BCD), semantic change detection (SCD), and building damage assessment (BDA), respectively. All three frameworks adopt the cutting-edge visual Mamba architecture as the encoder, which allows full learning of global spatial contextual information from the input images. For the change decoder, which is available in all three architectures, we propose three spatio-temporal relationship modeling mechanisms, which can be naturally combined with the Mamba architecture and fully utilize its attribute to achieve spatio-temporal interaction of multi-temporal features and obtain accurate change information. On five benchmark datasets, our proposed frameworks outperform current CNN- and Transformer-based approaches without using any complex strategies or tricks, fully demonstrating the potential of the Mamba architecture. Specifically, we obtained 83.11%, 88.39% and 94.19% F1 scores on the three BCD datasets SYSU, LEVIR-CD+, and WHU-CD; on the SCD dataset SECOND, we obtained 24.04% SeK; and on the xBD dataset, we obtained 81.41% overall F1 score. The source code will be available in https://github.com/ChenHongruixuan/MambaCD</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03425v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hongruixuan Chen, Jian Song, Chengxi Han, Junshi Xia, Naoto Yokoya</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Segmentation-Guided Knee Radiograph Generation using Conditional Diffusion Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03541</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03541v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Deep learning-based medical image processing algorithms require representative data during development. In particular, surgical data might be difficult to obtain, and high-quality public datasets are limited. To overcome this limitation and augment datasets, a widely adopted solution is the generation of synthetic images. In this work, we employ conditional diffusion models to generate knee radiographs from contour and bone segmentations. Remarkably, two distinct strategies are presented by incorporating the segmentation as a condition into the sampling and training process, namely, conditional sampling and conditional training. The results demonstrate that both methods can generate realistic images while adhering to the conditioning segmentation. The conditional training method outperforms the conditional sampling method and the conventional U-Net.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03541v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Siyuan Mei, Fuxin Fan, Fabian Wagner, Mareike Thies, Mingxuan Gu, Yipeng Sun, Andreas Maier</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Efficiency of Convolutional Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03617</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03617v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Since the breakthrough performance of AlexNet in 2012, convolutional neural networks (convnets) have grown into extremely powerful vision models. Deep learning researchers have used convnets to produce accurate results that were unachievable a decade ago. Yet computer scientists make computational efficiency their primary objective. Accuracy with exorbitant cost is not acceptable; an algorithm must also minimize its computational requirements. Confronted with the daunting computation that convnets use, deep learning researchers also became interested in efficiency. Researchers applied tremendous effort to find the convnet architectures that have the greatest efficiency. However, skepticism grew among researchers and engineers alike about the relevance of arithmetic complexity. Contrary to the prevailing view that latency and arithmetic complexity are irreconcilable, a simple formula relates both through computational efficiency. This insight enabled us to co-optimize the separate factors that determine latency. We observed that the degenerate conv2d layers that produce the best accuracy-complexity trade-off also have low operational intensity. Therefore, kernels that implement these layers use significant memory resources. We solved this optimization problem with block-fusion kernels that implement all layers of a residual block, thereby creating temporal locality, avoiding communication, and reducing workspace size. Our ConvFirst model with block-fusion kernels ran approximately four times as fast as the ConvNeXt baseline with PyTorch Inductor, at equal accuracy on the ImageNet-1K classification task. Our unified approach to convnet efficiency envisions a new era of models and kernels that achieve greater accuracy at lower cost.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03617v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Andrew Lavin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PreAfford: Universal Affordance-Based Pre-Grasping for Diverse Objects and Environments</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03634</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03634v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Robotic manipulation of ungraspable objects with two-finger grippers presents significant challenges due to the paucity of graspable features, while traditional pre-grasping techniques, which rely on repositioning objects and leveraging external aids like table edges, lack the adaptability across object categories and scenes. Addressing this, we introduce PreAfford, a novel pre-grasping planning framework that utilizes a point-level affordance representation and a relay training approach to enhance adaptability across a broad range of environments and object types, including those previously unseen. Demonstrated on the ShapeNet-v2 dataset, PreAfford significantly improves grasping success rates by 69% and validates its practicality through real-world experiments. This work offers a robust and adaptable solution for manipulating ungraspable objects.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03634v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kairui Ding, Boyuan Chen, Ruihai Wu, Yuyang Li, Zongzheng Zhang, Huan-ang Gao, Siqi Li, Yixin Zhu, Guyue Zhou, Hao Dong, Hao Zhao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning in Cardiology</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/1902.11122</link>
      <description>arXiv:1902.11122v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The medical field is creating large amount of data that physicians are unable to decipher and use efficiently. Moreover, rule-based expert systems are inefficient in solving complicated medical tasks or for creating insights using big data. Deep learning has emerged as a more accurate and effective technology in a wide range of medical problems such as diagnosis, prediction and intervention. Deep learning is a representation learning method that consists of layers that transform the data non-linearly, thus, revealing hierarchical relationships and structures. In this review we survey deep learning application papers that use structured data, signal and imaging modalities from cardiology. We discuss the advantages and limitations of applying deep learning in cardiology that also apply in medicine in general, while proposing certain directions as the most viable for clinical use.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1902.11122v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1109/RBME.2018.2885714</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>IEEE Reviews in Biomedical Engineering 12 (2019): 168-193</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Paschalis Bizopoulos, Dimitrios Koutsouris</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Fine-grained Large Object Segmentation 1st Place Solution to 3D AI Challenge 2020 -- Instance Segmentation Track</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2009.04650</link>
      <description>arXiv:2009.04650v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This technical report introduces our solutions of Team 'FineGrainedSeg' for Instance Segmentation track in 3D AI Challenge 2020. In order to handle extremely large objects in 3D-FUTURE, we adopt PointRend as our basic framework, which outputs more fine-grained masks compared to HTC and SOLOv2. Our final submission is an ensemble of 5 PointRend models, which achieves the 1st place on both validation and test leaderboards. The code is available at https://github.com/zehuichen123/3DFuture_ins_seg.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2009.04650v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zehui Chen, Qiaofei Li, Feng Zhao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Aligning Depth-regularized Radiance Fields for Asynchronous RGB-D Sequences</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2211.07459</link>
      <description>arXiv:2211.07459v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: It has been shown that learning radiance fields with depth rendering and depth supervision can effectively promote the quality and convergence of view synthesis. However, this paradigm requires input RGB-D sequences to be synchronized, hindering its usage in the UAV city modeling scenario. As there exists asynchrony between RGB images and depth images due to high-speed flight, we propose a novel time-pose function, which is an implicit network that maps timestamps to $\rm SE(3)$ elements. To simplify the training process, we also design a joint optimization scheme to jointly learn the large-scale depth-regularized radiance fields and the time-pose function. Our algorithm consists of three steps: (1) time-pose function fitting, (2) radiance field bootstrapping, (3) joint pose error compensation and radiance field refinement. In addition, we propose a large synthetic dataset with diverse controlled mismatches and ground truth to evaluate this new problem setting systematically. Through extensive experiments, we demonstrate that our method outperforms baselines without regularization. We also show qualitatively improved results on a real-world asynchronous RGB-D sequence captured by drone. Codes, data, and models will be made publicly available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2211.07459v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuxin Huang, Andong Yang, Zirui Wu, Yuantao Chen, Runyi Yang, Zhenxin Zhu, Chao Hou, Hao Zhao, Guyue Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NEMTO: Neural Environment Matting for Novel View and Relighting Synthesis of Transparent Objects</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2303.11963</link>
      <description>arXiv:2303.11963v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We propose NEMTO, the first end-to-end neural rendering pipeline to model 3D transparent objects with complex geometry and unknown indices of refraction. Commonly used appearance modeling such as the Disney BSDF model cannot accurately address this challenging problem due to the complex light paths bending through refractions and the strong dependency of surface appearance on illumination. With 2D images of the transparent object as input, our method is capable of high-quality novel view and relighting synthesis. We leverage implicit Signed Distance Functions (SDF) to model the object geometry and propose a refraction-aware ray bending network to model the effects of light refraction within the object. Our ray bending network is more tolerant to geometric inaccuracies than traditional physically-based methods for rendering transparent objects. We provide extensive evaluations on both synthetic and real-world datasets to demonstrate our high-quality synthesis and the applicability of our method.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2303.11963v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dongqing Wang, Tong Zhang, Sabine S\"usstrunk</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>$CrowdDiff$: Multi-hypothesis Crowd Density Estimation using Diffusion Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2303.12790</link>
      <description>arXiv:2303.12790v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Crowd counting is a fundamental problem in crowd analysis which is typically accomplished by estimating a crowd density map and summing over the density values. However, this approach suffers from background noise accumulation and loss of density due to the use of broad Gaussian kernels to create the ground truth density maps. This issue can be overcome by narrowing the Gaussian kernel. However, existing approaches perform poorly when trained with ground truth density maps with broad kernels. To deal with this limitation, we propose using conditional diffusion models to predict density maps, as diffusion models show high fidelity to training data during generation. With that, we present $CrowdDiff$ that generates the crowd density map as a reverse diffusion process. Furthermore, as the intermediate time steps of the diffusion process are noisy, we incorporate a regression branch for direct crowd estimation only during training to improve the feature learning. In addition, owing to the stochastic nature of the diffusion model, we introduce producing multiple density maps to improve the counting performance contrary to the existing crowd counting pipelines. We conduct extensive experiments on publicly available datasets to validate the effectiveness of our method. $CrowdDiff$ outperforms existing state-of-the-art crowd counting methods on several public crowd analysis benchmarks with significant improvements.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2303.12790v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yasiru Ranasinghe, Nithin Gopalakrishnan Nair, Wele Gedara Chaminda Bandara, Vishal M. Patel</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WM-MoE: Weather-aware Multi-scale Mixture-of-Experts for Blind Adverse Weather Removal</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2303.13739</link>
      <description>arXiv:2303.13739v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Adverse weather removal tasks like deraining, desnowing, and dehazing are usually treated as separate tasks. However, in practical autonomous driving scenarios, the type, intensity,and mixing degree of weather are unknown, so handling each task separately cannot deal with the complex practical scenarios. In this paper, we study the blind adverse weather removal problem. Mixture-of-Experts (MoE) is a popular model that adopts a learnable gate to route the input to different expert networks. The principle of MoE involves using adaptive networks to process different types of unknown inputs. Therefore, MoE has great potential for blind adverse weather removal. However, the original MoE module is inadequate for coupled multiple weather types and fails to utilize multi-scale features for better performance. To this end, we propose a method called Weather-aware Multi-scale MoE (WM-MoE) based on Transformer for blind weather removal. WM-MoE includes two key designs: WEather-Aware Router (WEAR) and Multi-Scale Experts (MSE). WEAR assigns experts for each image token based on decoupled content and weather features, which enhances the model's capability to process multiple adverse weathers. To obtain discriminative weather features from images, we propose Weather Guidance Fine-grained Contrastive Learning (WGF-CL), which utilizes weather cluster information to guide the assignment of positive and negative samples for each image token. Since processing different weather types requires different receptive fields, MSE leverages multi-scale features to enhance the spatial relationship modeling capability, facilitating the high-quality restoration of diverse weather types and intensities. Our method achieves state-of-the-art performance in blind adverse weather removal on two public datasets and our dataset. We also demonstrate the advantage of our method on downstream segmentation tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2303.13739v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yulin Luo, Rui Zhao, Xiaobao Wei, Jinwei Chen, Yijie Lu, Shenghao Xie, Tianyu Wang, Ruiqin Xiong, Ming Lu, Shanghang Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generating Images with 3D Annotations Using Diffusion Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2306.08103</link>
      <description>arXiv:2306.08103v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Diffusion models have emerged as a powerful generative method, capable of producing stunning photo-realistic images from natural language descriptions. However, these models lack explicit control over the 3D structure in the generated images. Consequently, this hinders our ability to obtain detailed 3D annotations for the generated images or to craft instances with specific poses and distances. In this paper, we propose 3D Diffusion Style Transfer (3D-DST), which incorporates 3D geometry control into diffusion models. Our method exploits ControlNet, which extends diffusion models by using visual prompts in addition to text prompts. We generate images of the 3D objects taken from 3D shape repositories (e.g., ShapeNet and Objaverse), render them from a variety of poses and viewing directions, compute the edge maps of the rendered images, and use these edge maps as visual prompts to generate realistic images. With explicit 3D geometry control, we can easily change the 3D structures of the objects in the generated images and obtain ground-truth 3D annotations automatically. This allows us to improve a wide range of vision tasks, e.g., classification and 3D pose estimation, in both in-distribution (ID) and out-of-distribution (OOD) settings. We demonstrate the effectiveness of our method through extensive experiments on ImageNet-100/200, ImageNet-R, PASCAL3D+, ObjectNet3D, and OOD-CV. The results show that our method significantly outperforms existing methods, e.g., 3.8 percentage points on ImageNet-100 using DeiT-B.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2306.08103v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wufei Ma, Qihao Liu, Jiahao Wang, Angtian Wang, Xiaoding Yuan, Yi Zhang, Zihao Xiao, Guofeng Zhang, Beijia Lu, Ruxiao Duan, Yongrui Qi, Adam Kortylewski, Yaoyao Liu, Alan Yuille</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Image Outlier Detection Without Training using RANSAC</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2307.12301</link>
      <description>arXiv:2307.12301v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Image outlier detection (OD) is an essential tool to ensure the quality of images used in computer vision tasks. Existing algorithms often involve training a model to represent the inlier distribution, and outliers are determined by some deviation measure. Although existing methods proved effective when trained on strictly inlier samples, their performance remains questionable when undesired outliers are included during training. As a result of this limitation, it is necessary to carefully examine the data when developing OD models for new domains. In this work, we present a novel image OD algorithm called RANSAC-NN that eliminates the need of data examination and model training altogether. Unlike existing approaches, RANSAC-NN can be directly applied on datasets containing outliers by sampling and comparing subsets of the data. Our algorithm maintains favorable performance compared to existing methods on a range of benchmarks. Furthermore, we show that RANSAC-NN can enhance the robustness of existing methods by incorporating our algorithm as part of the data preparation process.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2307.12301v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chen-Han Tsai, Yu-Shao Peng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Upcycling Knowledge Distillation for Image Super-Resolution</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2309.14162</link>
      <description>arXiv:2309.14162v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Knowledge distillation (KD) compresses deep neural networks by transferring task-related knowledge from cumbersome pre-trained teacher models to compact student models. However, current KD methods for super-resolution (SR) networks overlook the nature of SR task that the outputs of the teacher model are noisy approximations to the ground-truth distribution of high-quality images (GT), which shades the teacher model's knowledge to result in limited KD effects. To utilize the teacher model beyond the GT upper-bound, we present the Data Upcycling Knowledge Distillation (DUKD), to transfer the teacher model's knowledge to the student model through the upcycled in-domain data derived from training data. Besides, we impose label consistency regularization to KD for SR by the paired invertible augmentations to improve the student model's performance and robustness. Comprehensive experiments demonstrate that the DUKD method significantly outperforms previous arts on several SR tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2309.14162v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yun Zhang, Wei Li, Simiao Li, Hanting Chen, Zhijun Tu, Wenjia Wang, Bingyi Jing, Shaohui Lin, Jie Hu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scene-aware Human Motion Forecasting via Mutual Distance Prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.00615</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.00615v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this paper, we tackle the problem of scene-aware 3D human motion forecasting. A key challenge of this task is to predict future human motions that are consistent with the scene by modeling the human-scene interactions. While recent works have demonstrated that explicit constraints on human-scene interactions can prevent the occurrence of ghost motion, they only provide constraints on partial human motion e.g., the global motion of the human or a few joints contacting the scene, leaving the rest of the motion unconstrained. To address this limitation, we propose to model the human-scene interaction with the mutual distance between the human body and the scene. Such mutual distances constrain both the local and global human motion, resulting in a whole-body motion constrained prediction. In particular, mutual distance constraints consist of two components, the signed distance of each vertex on the human mesh to the scene surface and the distance of basis scene points to the human mesh. We further introduce a global scene representation learned from a signed distance function (SDF) volume to ensure coherence between the global scene representation and the explicit constraint from the mutual distance. We develop a pipeline with two sequential steps: predicting the future mutual distances first, followed by forecasting future human motion. During training, we explicitly encourage consistency between predicted poses and mutual distances. Extensive evaluations on the existing synthetic and real datasets demonstrate that our approach consistently outperforms the state-of-the-art methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.00615v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chaoyue Xing, Wei Mao, Miaomiao Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mirasol3B: A Multimodal Autoregressive model for time-aligned and contextual modalities</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.05698</link>
      <description>arXiv:2311.05698v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: One of the main challenges of multimodal learning is the need to combine heterogeneous modalities (e.g., video, audio, text). For example, video and audio are obtained at much higher rates than text and are roughly aligned in time. They are often not synchronized with text, which comes as a global context, e.g., a title, or a description. Furthermore, video and audio inputs are of much larger volumes, and grow as the video length increases, which naturally requires more compute dedicated to these modalities and makes modeling of long-range dependencies harder.
  We here decouple the multimodal modeling, dividing it into separate, focused autoregressive models, processing the inputs according to the characteristics of the modalities. We propose a multimodal model, called Mirasol3B, consisting of an autoregressive component for the time-synchronized modalities (audio and video), and an autoregressive component for the context modalities which are not necessarily aligned in time but are still sequential. To address the long-sequences of the video-audio inputs, we propose to further partition the video and audio sequences in consecutive snippets and autoregressively process their representations. To that end, we propose a Combiner mechanism, which models the audio-video information jointly within a timeframe. The Combiner learns to extract audio and video features from raw spatio-temporal signals, and then learns to fuse these features producing compact but expressive representations per snippet.
  Our approach achieves the state-of-the-art on well established multimodal benchmarks, outperforming much larger models. It effectively addresses the high computational demand of media inputs by both learning compact representations, controlling the sequence length of the audio-video feature representations, and modeling their dependencies in time.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2311.05698v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>AJ Piergiovanni, Isaac Noble, Dahun Kim, Michael S. Ryoo, Victor Gomes, Anelia Angelova</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MorpheuS: Neural Dynamic 360{\deg} Surface Reconstruction from Monocular RGB-D Video</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.00778</link>
      <description>arXiv:2312.00778v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Neural rendering has demonstrated remarkable success in dynamic scene reconstruction. Thanks to the expressiveness of neural representations, prior works can accurately capture the motion and achieve high-fidelity reconstruction of the target object. Despite this, real-world video scenarios often feature large unobserved regions where neural representations struggle to achieve realistic completion. To tackle this challenge, we introduce MorpheuS, a framework for dynamic 360{\deg} surface reconstruction from a casually captured RGB-D video. Our approach models the target scene as a canonical field that encodes its geometry and appearance, in conjunction with a deformation field that warps points from the current frame to the canonical space. We leverage a view-dependent diffusion prior and distill knowledge from it to achieve realistic completion of unobserved regions. Experimental results on various real-world and synthetic datasets show that our method can achieve high-fidelity 360{\deg} surface reconstruction of a deformable object from a monocular RGB-D video.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2312.00778v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hengyi Wang, Jingwen Wang, Lourdes Agapito</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Adapter for Face Recognition in the Wild</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.01734</link>
      <description>arXiv:2312.01734v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this paper, we tackle the challenge of face recognition in the wild, where images often suffer from low quality and real-world distortions. Traditional heuristic approaches-either training models directly on these degraded images or their enhanced counterparts using face restoration techniques-have proven ineffective, primarily due to the degradation of facial features and the discrepancy in image domains. To overcome these issues, we propose an effective adapter for augmenting existing face recognition models trained on high-quality facial datasets. The key of our adapter is to process both the unrefined and enhanced images using two similar structures, one fixed and the other trainable. Such design can confer two benefits. First, the dual-input system minimizes the domain gap while providing varied perspectives for the face recognition model, where the enhanced image can be regarded as a complex non-linear transformation of the original one by the restoration model. Second, both two similar structures can be initialized by the pre-trained models without dropping the past knowledge. The extensive experiments in zero-shot settings show the effectiveness of our method by surpassing baselines of about 3%, 4%, and 7% in three datasets. Our code will be publicly available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2312.01734v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yunhao Liu, Yu-Ju Tsai, Kelvin C. K. Chan, Xiangtai Li, Lu Qi, Ming-Hsuan Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bootstrapping SparseFormers from Vision Foundation Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.01987</link>
      <description>arXiv:2312.01987v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The recently proposed SparseFormer architecture provides an alternative approach to visual understanding by utilizing a significantly lower number of visual tokens via adjusting RoIs, greatly reducing computational costs while still achieving promising performance. However, training SparseFormers from scratch is still expensive, and scaling up the number of parameters can be challenging. In this paper, we propose to bootstrap SparseFormers from ViT-based vision foundation models in a simple and efficient way. Since the majority of SparseFormer blocks are the standard transformer ones, we can inherit weights from large-scale pre-trained vision transformers and freeze them as much as possible. Therefore, we only need to train the SparseFormer-specific lightweight focusing transformer to adjust token RoIs and fine-tune a few early pre-trained blocks to align the final token representation. In such a way, we can bootstrap SparseFormer architectures from various large-scale pre-trained models (e.g., IN-21K pre-trained AugRegs or CLIPs) using a rather smaller amount of training samples (e.g., IN-1K) and without labels or captions within just a few hours. As a result, the bootstrapped unimodal SparseFormer (from AugReg-ViT-L/16-384) can reach 84.9% accuracy on IN-1K with only 49 tokens, and the multimodal SparseFormer from CLIPs also demonstrates notable zero-shot performance with highly reduced computational cost without seeing any caption during the bootstrapping procedure. In addition, CLIP-bootstrapped SparseFormers, which align the output space with language without seeing a word, can serve as efficient vision encoders in multimodal large language models. Code and models are available at https://github.com/showlab/sparseformer</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2312.01987v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ziteng Gao, Zhan Tong, Kevin Qinghong Lin, Joya Chen, Mike Zheng Shou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HumanNeRF-SE: A Simple yet Effective Approach to Animate HumanNeRF with Diverse Poses</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.02232</link>
      <description>arXiv:2312.02232v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We present HumanNeRF-SE, a simple yet effective method that synthesizes diverse novel pose images with simple input. Previous HumanNeRF works require a large number of optimizable parameters to fit the human images. Instead, we reload these approaches by combining explicit and implicit human representations to design both generalized rigid deformation and specific non-rigid deformation. Our key insight is that explicit shape can reduce the sampling points used to fit implicit representation, and frozen blending weights from SMPL constructing a generalized rigid deformation can effectively avoid overfitting and improve pose generalization performance. Our architecture involving both explicit and implicit representation is simple yet effective. Experiments demonstrate our model can synthesize images under arbitrary poses with few-shot input and increase the speed of synthesizing images by 15 times through a reduction in computational complexity without using any existing acceleration modules. Compared to the state-of-the-art HumanNeRF studies, HumanNeRF-SE achieves better performance with fewer learnable parameters and less training time.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2312.02232v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Caoyuan Ma, Yu-Lun Liu, Zhixiang Wang, Wu Liu, Xinchen Liu, Zheng Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3DGS-Avatar: Animatable Avatars via Deformable 3D Gaussian Splatting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09228</link>
      <description>arXiv:2312.09228v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We introduce an approach that creates animatable human avatars from monocular videos using 3D Gaussian Splatting (3DGS). Existing methods based on neural radiance fields (NeRFs) achieve high-quality novel-view/novel-pose image synthesis but often require days of training, and are extremely slow at inference time. Recently, the community has explored fast grid structures for efficient training of clothed avatars. Albeit being extremely fast at training, these methods can barely achieve an interactive rendering frame rate with around 15 FPS. In this paper, we use 3D Gaussian Splatting and learn a non-rigid deformation network to reconstruct animatable clothed human avatars that can be trained within 30 minutes and rendered at real-time frame rates (50+ FPS). Given the explicit nature of our representation, we further introduce as-isometric-as-possible regularizations on both the Gaussian mean vectors and the covariance matrices, enhancing the generalization of our model on highly articulated unseen poses. Experimental results show that our method achieves comparable and even better performance compared to state-of-the-art approaches on animatable avatar creation from a monocular input, while being 400x and 250x faster in training and inference, respectively.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2312.09228v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhiyin Qian, Shaofei Wang, Marko Mihajlovic, Andreas Geiger, Siyu Tang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Expressive Forecasting of 3D Whole-body Human Motions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11972</link>
      <description>arXiv:2312.11972v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Human motion forecasting, with the goal of estimating future human behavior over a period of time, is a fundamental task in many real-world applications. However, existing works typically concentrate on predicting the major joints of the human body without considering the delicate movements of the human hands. In practical applications, hand gesture plays an important role in human communication with the real world, and expresses the primary intention of human beings. In this work, we are the first to formulate a whole-body human pose forecasting task, which jointly predicts the future body and hand activities. Correspondingly, we propose a novel Encoding-Alignment-Interaction (EAI) framework that aims to predict both coarse (body joints) and fine-grained (gestures) activities collaboratively, enabling expressive and cross-facilitated forecasting of 3D whole-body human motions. Specifically, our model involves two key constituents: cross-context alignment (XCA) and cross-context interaction (XCI). Considering the heterogeneous information within the whole-body, XCA aims to align the latent features of various human components, while XCI focuses on effectively capturing the context interaction among the human components. We conduct extensive experiments on a newly-introduced large-scale benchmark and achieve state-of-the-art performance. The code is public for research purposes at https://github.com/Dingpx/EAI.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2312.11972v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Pengxiang Ding, Qiongjie Cui, Min Zhang, Mengyuan Liu, Haofan Wang, Donglin Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Subject-Aware Cropping by Outpainting Professional Photos</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12080</link>
      <description>arXiv:2312.12080v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: How to frame (or crop) a photo often depends on the image subject and its context; e.g., a human portrait. Recent works have defined the subject-aware image cropping task as a nuanced and practical version of image cropping. We propose a weakly-supervised approach (GenCrop) to learn what makes a high-quality, subject-aware crop from professional stock images. Unlike supervised prior work, GenCrop requires no new manual annotations beyond the existing stock image collection. The key challenge in learning from this data, however, is that the images are already cropped and we do not know what regions were removed. Our insight is to combine a library of stock images with a modern, pre-trained text-to-image diffusion model. The stock image collection provides diversity and its images serve as pseudo-labels for a good crop, while the text-image diffusion model is used to out-paint (i.e., outward inpainting) realistic uncropped images. Using this procedure, we are able to automatically generate a large dataset of cropped-uncropped training pairs to train a cropping model. Despite being weakly-supervised, GenCrop is competitive with state-of-the-art supervised methods and significantly better than comparable weakly-supervised baselines on quantitative and qualitative evaluation metrics.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2312.12080v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>James Hong, Lu Yuan, Micha\"el Gharbi, Matthew Fisher, Kayvon Fatahalian</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved Zero-Shot Classification by Adapting VLMs with Text Descriptions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02460</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.02460v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The zero-shot performance of existing vision-language models (VLMs) such as CLIP is limited by the availability of large-scale, aligned image and text datasets in specific domains. In this work, we leverage two complementary sources of information -- descriptions of categories generated by large language models (LLMs) and abundant, fine-grained image classification datasets -- to improve the zero-shot classification performance of VLMs across fine-grained domains. On the technical side, we develop methods to train VLMs with this "bag-level" image-text supervision. We find that simply using these attributes at test-time does not improve performance, but our training strategy, for example, on the iNaturalist dataset, leads to an average improvement of 4-5% in zero-shot classification accuracy for novel categories of birds and flowers. Similar improvements are observed in domains where a subset of the categories was used to fine-tune the model. By prompting LLMs in various ways, we generate descriptions that capture visual appearance, habitat, and geographic regions and pair them with existing attributes such as the taxonomic structure of the categories. We systematically evaluate their ability to improve zero-shot categorization in natural domains. Our findings suggest that geographic priors can be just as effective and are complementary to visual appearance. Our method also outperforms prior work on prompt-based tuning of VLMs. We release the benchmark, consisting of 14 datasets at https://github.com/cvl-umass/AdaptCLIPZS , which will contribute to future research in zero-shot recognition.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.02460v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Oindrila Saha, Grant Van Horn, Subhransu Maji</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ModaVerse: Efficiently Transforming Modalities with LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.06395</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.06395v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Humans possess the capability to comprehend diverse modalities and seamlessly transfer information between them. In this work, we introduce ModaVerse, a Multi-modal Large Language Model (MLLM) capable of comprehending and transforming content across various modalities including images, videos, and audio. Predominant MLLM frameworks have largely relied on the alignment of latent spaces of textual and non-textual features. This alignment process, which synchronizes a language model trained on textual data with encoders and decoders trained on multi-modal data, often necessitates extensive training of several projection layers in multiple stages. Inspired by LLM-as-agent methodologies, we propose a novel Input/Output (I/O) alignment mechanism that operates directly at the level of natural language. It aligns the LLM's output with the input of generative models, avoiding the complexities associated with latent feature alignments, and simplifying the multiple training stages of existing MLLMs into a single, efficient process. This conceptual advancement leads to significant reductions in both data and computational costs. By conducting experiments on several benchmarks, we demonstrate that our approach attains comparable performance with the state of the art while achieving considerable efficiencies in data usage and training duration.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.06395v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xinyu Wang, Bohan Zhuang, Qi Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Novel Garment Transfer Method Supervised by Distilled Knowledge of Virtual Try-on Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12433</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.12433v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper proposes a novel garment transfer method supervised with knowledge distillation from virtual try-on. Our method first reasons the transfer parsing to provide shape prior to downstream tasks. We employ a multi-phase teaching strategy to supervise the training of the transfer parsing reasoning model, learning the response and feature knowledge from the try-on parsing reasoning model. To correct the teaching error, it transfers the garment back to its owner to absorb the hard knowledge in the self-study phase. Guided by the transfer parsing, we adjust the position of the transferred garment via STN to prevent distortion. Afterward, we estimate a progressive flow to precisely warp the garment with shape and content correspondences. To ensure warping rationality, we supervise the training of the garment warping model using target shape and warping knowledge from virtual try-on. To better preserve body features in the transfer result, we propose a well-designed training strategy for the arm regrowth task to infer new exposure skin. Experiments demonstrate that our method has state-of-the-art performance compared with other virtual try-on and garment transfer methods in garment transfer, especially for preserving garment texture and body features.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.12433v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Naiyu Fang, Lemiao Qiu, Shuyou Zhang, Zili Wang, Kerui Hu, Jianrong Tan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unified Spatio-Temporal Tri-Perspective View Representation for 3D Semantic Occupancy Prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.13785</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.13785v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Holistic understanding and reasoning in 3D scenes play a vital role in the success of autonomous driving systems. The evolution of 3D semantic occupancy prediction as a pretraining task for autonomous driving and robotic downstream tasks capture finer 3D details compared to methods like 3D detection. Existing approaches predominantly focus on spatial cues such as tri-perspective view embeddings (TPV), often overlooking temporal cues. This study introduces a spatiotemporal transformer architecture S2TPVFormer for temporally coherent 3D semantic occupancy prediction. We enrich the prior process by including temporal cues using a novel temporal cross-view hybrid attention mechanism (TCVHA) and generate spatiotemporal TPV embeddings (i.e. S2TPV embeddings). Experimental evaluations on the nuScenes dataset demonstrate a substantial 4.1% improvement in mean Intersection over Union (mIoU) for 3D Semantic Occupancy compared to TPVFormer, confirming the effectiveness of the proposed S2TPVFormer in enhancing 3D scene perception.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.13785v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sathira Silva, Savindu Bhashitha Wannigama, Gihan Jayatilaka, Muhammad Haris Khan, Roshan Ragel</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Video Diffusion Models with 2D Triplane and 3D Wavelet Representation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.13729</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.13729v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Generating high-quality videos that synthesize desired realistic content is a challenging task due to their intricate high-dimensionality and complexity of videos. Several recent diffusion-based methods have shown comparable performance by compressing videos to a lower-dimensional latent space, using traditional video autoencoder architecture. However, such method that employ standard frame-wise 2D and 3D convolution fail to fully exploit the spatio-temporal nature of videos. To address this issue, we propose a novel hybrid video diffusion model, called HVDM, which can capture spatio-temporal dependencies more effectively. The HVDM is trained by a hybrid video autoencoder which extracts a disentangled representation of the video including: (i) a global context information captured by a 2D projected latent (ii) a local volume information captured by 3D convolutions with wavelet decomposition (iii) a frequency information for improving the video reconstruction. Based on this disentangled representation, our hybrid autoencoder provide a more comprehensive video latent enriching the generated videos with fine structures and details. Experiments on video generation benchamarks (UCF101, SkyTimelapse, and TaiChi) demonstrate that the proposed approach achieves state-of-the-art video generation quality, showing a wide range of video applications (e.g., long video generation, image-to-video, and video dynamics control).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.13729v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kihong Kim, Haneol Lee, Jihye Park, Seyeon Kim, Kwanghee Lee, Seungryong Kim, Jaejun Yoo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cameras as Rays: Pose Estimation via Ray Diffusion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.14817</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.14817v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Estimating camera poses is a fundamental task for 3D reconstruction and remains challenging given sparsely sampled views (&lt;10). In contrast to existing approaches that pursue top-down prediction of global parametrizations of camera extrinsics, we propose a distributed representation of camera pose that treats a camera as a bundle of rays. This representation allows for a tight coupling with spatial image features improving pose precision. We observe that this representation is naturally suited for set-level transformers and develop a regression-based approach that maps image patches to corresponding rays. To capture the inherent uncertainties in sparse-view pose inference, we adapt this approach to learn a denoising diffusion model which allows us to sample plausible modes while improving performance. Our proposed methods, both regression- and diffusion-based, demonstrate state-of-the-art performance on camera pose estimation on CO3D while generalizing to unseen object categories and in-the-wild captures.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.14817v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jason Y. Zhang, Amy Lin, Moneish Kumar, Tzu-Hsuan Yang, Deva Ramanan, Shubham Tulsiani</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoDA: Instructive Chain-of-Domain Adaptation with Severity-Aware Visual Prompt Tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.17369</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.17369v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Unsupervised Domain Adaptation (UDA) aims to adapt models from labeled source domains to unlabeled target domains. When adapting to adverse scenes, existing UDA methods fail to perform well due to the lack of instructions, leading their models to overlook discrepancies within all adverse scenes. To tackle this, we propose CoDA which instructs models to distinguish, focus, and learn from these discrepancies at scene and image levels. Specifically, CoDA consists of a Chain-of-Domain (CoD) strategy and a Severity-Aware Visual Prompt Tuning (SAVPT) mechanism. CoD focuses on scene-level instructions to divide all adverse scenes into easy and hard scenes, guiding models to adapt from source to easy domains with easy scene images, and then to hard domains with hard scene images, thereby laying a solid foundation for whole adaptations. Building upon this foundation, we employ SAVPT to dive into more detailed image-level instructions to boost performance. SAVPT features a novel metric Severity that divides all adverse scene images into low-severity and high-severity images. Then Severity directs visual prompts and adapters, instructing models to concentrate on unified severity features instead of scene-specific features, without adding complexity to the model architecture. CoDA achieves SOTA performances on widely-used benchmarks under all adverse scenes. Notably, CoDA outperforms the existing ones by 4.6%, and 10.3% mIoU on the Foggy Driving, and Foggy Zurich benchmarks, respectively. Our code is available at https://github.com/Cuzyoung/CoDA</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.17369v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ziyang Gong, Fuhao Li, Yupeng Deng, Deblina Bhattacharjee, Xiangwei Zhu, Zhenming Ji</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ILPO-NET: Network for the invariant recognition of arbitrary volumetric patterns in 3D</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.19612</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.19612v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Effective recognition of spatial patterns and learning their hierarchy is crucial in modern spatial data analysis. Volumetric data applications seek techniques ensuring invariance not only to shifts but also to pattern rotations. While traditional methods can readily achieve translational invariance, rotational invariance possesses multiple challenges and remains an active area of research. Here, we present ILPO-Net (Invariant to Local Patterns Orientation Network), a novel approach that handles arbitrarily shaped patterns with the convolutional operation inherently invariant to local spatial pattern orientations using the Wigner matrix expansions. Our architecture seamlessly integrates the new convolution operator and, when benchmarked on diverse volumetric datasets such as MedMNIST and CATH, demonstrates superior performance over the baselines with significantly reduced parameter counts - up to 1000 times fewer in the case of MedMNIST. Beyond these demonstrations, ILPO-Net's rotational invariance paves the way for other applications across multiple disciplines. Our code is publicly available at https://gricad-gitlab.univ-grenoble-alpes.fr/GruLab/ILPONet.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.19612v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dmitrii Zhemchuzhnikov, Sergei Grudinin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ShapeFusion: A 3D diffusion model for localized shape editing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.19773</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.19773v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In the realm of 3D computer vision, parametric models have emerged as a ground-breaking methodology for the creation of realistic and expressive 3D avatars. Traditionally, they rely on Principal Component Analysis (PCA), given its ability to decompose data to an orthonormal space that maximally captures shape variations. However, due to the orthogonality constraints and the global nature of PCA's decomposition, these models struggle to perform localized and disentangled editing of 3D shapes, which severely affects their use in applications requiring fine control such as face sculpting. In this paper, we leverage diffusion models to enable diverse and fully localized edits on 3D meshes, while completely preserving the un-edited regions. We propose an effective diffusion masking training strategy that, by design, facilitates localized manipulation of any shape region, without being limited to predefined regions or to sparse sets of predefined control vertices. Following our framework, a user can explicitly set their manipulation region of choice and define an arbitrary set of vertices as handles to edit a 3D mesh. Compared to the current state-of-the-art our method leads to more interpretable shape manipulations than methods relying on latent code state, greater localization and generation diversity while offering faster inference than optimization based approaches. Project page: https://rolpotamias.github.io/Shapefusion/</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.19773v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rolandos Alexandros Potamias, Michail Tarasiou, Stylianos Ploumpis, Stefanos Zafeiriou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roadside Monocular 3D Detection via 2D Detection Prompting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.01064</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.01064v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The problem of roadside monocular 3D detection requires detecting objects of interested classes in a 2D RGB frame and predicting their 3D information such as locations in bird's-eye-view (BEV). It has broad applications in traffic control, vehicle-vehicle communication, and vehicle-infrastructure cooperative perception. To approach this problem, we present a novel and simple method by prompting the 3D detector using 2D detections. Our method builds on a key insight that, compared with 3D detectors, a 2D detector is much easier to train and performs significantly better w.r.t detections on the 2D image plane. That said, one can exploit 2D detections of a well-trained 2D detector as prompts to a 3D detector, being trained in a way of inflating such 2D detections to 3D towards 3D detection. To construct better prompts using the 2D detector, we explore three techniques: (a) concatenating both 2D and 3D detectors' features, (b) attentively fusing 2D and 3D detectors' features, and (c) encoding predicted 2D boxes x, y, width, height, label and attentively fusing such with the 3D detector's features. Surprisingly, the third performs the best. Moreover, we present a yaw tuning tactic and a class-grouping strategy that merges classes based on their functionality; these techniques improve 3D detection performance further. Comprehensive ablation studies and extensive experiments demonstrate that our method resoundingly outperforms prior works, achieving the state-of-the-art on two large-scale roadside 3D detection benchmarks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.01064v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yechi Ma, Shuoquan Wei, Churun Zhang, Wei Hua, Yanan Li, Shu Kong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temporally Consistent Unbalanced Optimal Transport for Unsupervised Action Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.01518</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.01518v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We propose a novel approach to the action segmentation task for long, untrimmed videos, based on solving an optimal transport problem. By encoding a temporal consistency prior into a Gromov-Wasserstein problem, we are able to decode a temporally consistent segmentation from a noisy affinity/matching cost matrix between video frames and action classes. Unlike previous approaches, our method does not require knowing the action order for a video to attain temporal consistency. Furthermore, our resulting (fused) Gromov-Wasserstein problem can be efficiently solved on GPUs using a few iterations of projected mirror descent. We demonstrate the effectiveness of our method in an unsupervised learning setting, where our method is used to generate pseudo-labels for self-training. We evaluate our segmentation approach and unsupervised learning pipeline on the Breakfast, 50-Salads, YouTube Instructions and Desktop Assembly datasets, yielding state-of-the-art results for the unsupervised video action segmentation task.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.01518v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ming Xu, Stephen Gould</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Image Super-Resolution for Image Recognition with Task-Driven Perceptual Loss</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.01692</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.01692v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In real-world scenarios, image recognition tasks, such as semantic segmentation and object detection, often pose greater challenges due to the lack of information available within low-resolution (LR) content. Image super-resolution (SR) is one of the promising solutions for addressing the challenges. However, due to the ill-posed property of SR, it is challenging for typical SR methods to restore task-relevant high-frequency contents, which may dilute the advantage of utilizing the SR method. Therefore, in this paper, we propose Super-Resolution for Image Recognition (SR4IR) that effectively guides the generation of SR images beneficial to achieving satisfactory image recognition performance when processing LR images. The critical component of our SR4IR is the task-driven perceptual (TDP) loss that enables the SR network to acquire task-specific knowledge from a network tailored for a specific task. Moreover, we propose a cross-quality patch mix and an alternate training framework that significantly enhances the efficacy of the TDP loss by addressing potential problems when employing the TDP loss. Through extensive experiments, we demonstrate that our SR4IR achieves outstanding task performance by generating SR images useful for a specific image recognition task, including semantic segmentation, object detection, and image classification. The implementation code is available at https://github.com/JaehaKim97/SR4IR.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.01692v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jaeha Kim, Junghun Oh, Kyoung Mu Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GEARS: Local Geometry-aware Hand-object Interaction Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.01758</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.01758v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Generating realistic hand motion sequences in interaction with objects has gained increasing attention with the growing interest in digital humans. Prior work has illustrated the effectiveness of employing occupancy-based or distance-based virtual sensors to extract hand-object interaction features. Nonetheless, these methods show limited generalizability across object categories, shapes and sizes. We hypothesize that this is due to two reasons: 1) the limited expressiveness of employed virtual sensors, and 2) scarcity of available training data. To tackle this challenge, we introduce a novel joint-centered sensor designed to reason about local object geometry near potential interaction regions. The sensor queries for object surface points in the neighbourhood of each hand joint. As an important step towards mitigating the learning complexity, we transform the points from global frame to hand template frame and use a shared module to process sensor features of each individual joint. This is followed by a spatio-temporal transformer network aimed at capturing correlation among the joints in different dimensions. Moreover, we devise simple heuristic rules to augment the limited training sequences with vast static hand grasping samples. This leads to a broader spectrum of grasping types observed during training, in turn enhancing our model's generalization capability. We evaluate on two public datasets, GRAB and InterCap, where our method shows superiority over baselines both quantitatively and perceptually.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.01758v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Keyang Zhou, Bharat Lal Bhatnagar, Jan Eric Lenssen, Gerard Pons-moll</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cooperative Students: Navigating Unsupervised Domain Adaptation in Nighttime Object Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.01988</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.01988v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Unsupervised Domain Adaptation (UDA) has shown significant advancements in object detection under well-lit conditions; however, its performance degrades notably in low-visibility scenarios, especially at night, posing challenges not only for its adaptability in low signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) conditions but also for the reliability and efficiency of automated vehicles. To address this problem, we propose a \textbf{Co}operative \textbf{S}tudents (\textbf{CoS}) framework that innovatively employs global-local transformations (GLT) and a proxy-based target consistency (PTC) mechanism to capture the spatial consistency in day- and night-time scenarios effectively, and thus bridge the significant domain shift across contexts. Building upon this, we further devise an adaptive IoU-informed thresholding (AIT) module to gradually avoid overlooking potential true positives and enrich the latent information in the target domain. Comprehensive experiments show that CoS essentially enhanced UDA performance in low-visibility conditions and surpasses current state-of-the-art techniques, achieving an increase in mAP of 3.0\%, 1.9\%, and 2.5\% on BDD100K, SHIFT, and ACDC datasets, respectively. Code is available at https://github.com/jichengyuan/Cooperitive_Students.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.01988v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jicheng Yuan, Anh Le-Tuan, Manfred Hauswirth, Danh Le-Phuoc</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EGTR: Extracting Graph from Transformer for Scene Graph Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.02072</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.02072v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Scene Graph Generation (SGG) is a challenging task of detecting objects and predicting relationships between objects. After DETR was developed, one-stage SGG models based on a one-stage object detector have been actively studied. However, complex modeling is used to predict the relationship between objects, and the inherent relationship between object queries learned in the multi-head self-attention of the object detector has been neglected. We propose a lightweight one-stage SGG model that extracts the relation graph from the various relationships learned in the multi-head self-attention layers of the DETR decoder. By fully utilizing the self-attention by-products, the relation graph can be extracted effectively with a shallow relation extraction head. Considering the dependency of the relation extraction task on the object detection task, we propose a novel relation smoothing technique that adjusts the relation label adaptively according to the quality of the detected objects. By the relation smoothing, the model is trained according to the continuous curriculum that focuses on object detection task at the beginning of training and performs multi-task learning as the object detection performance gradually improves. Furthermore, we propose a connectivity prediction task that predicts whether a relation exists between object pairs as an auxiliary task of the relation extraction. We demonstrate the effectiveness and efficiency of our method for the Visual Genome and Open Image V6 datasets. Our code is publicly available at https://github.com/naver-ai/egtr.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.02072v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jinbae Im, JeongYeon Nam, Nokyung Park, Hyungmin Lee, Seunghyun Park</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ViTamin: Designing Scalable Vision Models in the Vision-Language Era</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.02132</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.02132v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent breakthroughs in vision-language models (VLMs) start a new page in the vision community. The VLMs provide stronger and more generalizable feature embeddings compared to those from ImageNet-pretrained models, thanks to the training on the large-scale Internet image-text pairs. However, despite the amazing achievement from the VLMs, vanilla Vision Transformers (ViTs) remain the default choice for the image encoder. Although pure transformer proves its effectiveness in the text encoding area, it remains questionable whether it is also the case for image encoding, especially considering that various types of networks are proposed on the ImageNet benchmark, which, unfortunately, are rarely studied in VLMs. Due to small data/model scale, the original conclusions of model design on ImageNet can be limited and biased. In this paper, we aim at building an evaluation protocol of vision models in the vision-language era under the contrastive language-image pretraining (CLIP) framework. We provide a comprehensive way to benchmark different vision models, covering their zero-shot performance and scalability in both model and training data sizes. To this end, we introduce ViTamin, a new vision models tailored for VLMs. ViTamin-L significantly outperforms ViT-L by 2.0% ImageNet zero-shot accuracy, when using the same publicly available DataComp-1B dataset and the same OpenCLIP training scheme. ViTamin-L presents promising results on 60 diverse benchmarks, including classification, retrieval, open-vocabulary detection and segmentation, and large multi-modal models. When further scaling up the model size, our ViTamin-XL with only 436M parameters attains 82.9% ImageNet zero-shot accuracy, surpassing 82.0% achieved by EVA-E that has ten times more parameters (4.4B).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.02132v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jieneng Chen, Qihang Yu, Xiaohui Shen, Alan Yuille, Liang-Chieh Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smooth Deep Saliency</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.02282</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.02282v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this work, we investigate methods to reduce the noise in deep saliency maps coming from convolutional downsampling, with the purpose of explaining how a deep learning model detects tumors in scanned histological tissue samples. Those methods make the investigated models more interpretable for gradient-based saliency maps, computed in hidden layers. We test our approach on different models trained for image classification on ImageNet1K, and models trained for tumor detection on Camelyon16 and in-house real-world digital pathology scans of stained tissue samples. Our results show that the checkerboard noise in the gradient gets reduced, resulting in smoother and therefore easier to interpret saliency maps.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.02282v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rudolf Herdt, Maximilian Schmidt, Daniel Otero Baguer, Peter Maa{\ss}</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CAPE: CAM as a Probabilistic Ensemble for Enhanced DNN Interpretation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.02388</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.02388v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Deep Neural Networks (DNNs) are widely used for visual classification tasks, but their complex computation process and black-box nature hinder decision transparency and interpretability. Class activation maps (CAMs) and recent variants provide ways to visually explain the DNN decision-making process by displaying 'attention' heatmaps of the DNNs. Nevertheless, the CAM explanation only offers relative attention information, that is, on an attention heatmap, we can interpret which image region is more or less important than the others. However, these regions cannot be meaningfully compared across classes, and the contribution of each region to the model's class prediction is not revealed. To address these challenges that ultimately lead to better DNN Interpretation, in this paper, we propose CAPE, a novel reformulation of CAM that provides a unified and probabilistically meaningful assessment of the contributions of image regions. We quantitatively and qualitatively compare CAPE with state-of-the-art CAM methods on CUB and ImageNet benchmark datasets to demonstrate enhanced interpretability. We also test on a cytology imaging dataset depicting a challenging Chronic Myelomonocytic Leukemia (CMML) diagnosis problem. Code is available at: https://github.com/AIML-MED/CAPE.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.02388v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Townim Faisal Chowdhury, Kewen Liao, Vu Minh Hieu Phan, Minh-Son To, Yutong Xie, Kevin Hung, David Ross, Anton van den Hengel, Johan W. Verjans, Zhibin Liao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TE-TAD: Towards Full End-to-End Temporal Action Detection via Time-Aligned Coordinate Expression</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.02405</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.02405v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this paper, we investigate that the normalized coordinate expression is a key factor as reliance on hand-crafted components in query-based detectors for temporal action detection (TAD). Despite significant advancements towards an end-to-end framework in object detection, query-based detectors have been limited in achieving full end-to-end modeling in TAD. To address this issue, we propose \modelname{}, a full end-to-end temporal action detection transformer that integrates time-aligned coordinate expression. We reformulate coordinate expression utilizing actual timeline values, ensuring length-invariant representations from the extremely diverse video duration environment. Furthermore, our proposed adaptive query selection dynamically adjusts the number of queries based on video length, providing a suitable solution for varying video durations compared to a fixed query set. Our approach not only simplifies the TAD process by eliminating the need for hand-crafted components but also significantly improves the performance of query-based detectors. Our TE-TAD outperforms the previous query-based detectors and achieves competitive performance compared to state-of-the-art methods on popular benchmark datasets. Code is available at: https://github.com/Dotori-HJ/TE-TAD</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.02405v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ho-Joong Kim, Jung-Ho Hong, Heejo Kong, Seong-Whan Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-negative Subspace Feature Representation for Few-shot Learning in Medical Imaging</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.02656</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.02656v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Unlike typical visual scene recognition domains, in which massive datasets are accessible to deep neural networks, medical image interpretations are often obstructed by the paucity of data. In this paper, we investigate the effectiveness of data-based few-shot learning in medical imaging by exploring different data attribute representations in a low-dimensional space. We introduce different types of non-negative matrix factorization (NMF) in few-shot learning, addressing the data scarcity issue in medical image classification. Extensive empirical studies are conducted in terms of validating the effectiveness of NMF, especially its supervised variants (e.g., discriminative NMF, and supervised and constrained NMF with sparseness), and the comparison with principal component analysis (PCA), i.e., the collaborative representation-based dimensionality reduction technique derived from eigenvectors. With 14 different datasets covering 11 distinct illness categories, thorough experimental results and comparison with related techniques demonstrate that NMF is a competitive alternative to PCA for few-shot learning in medical imaging, and the supervised NMF algorithms are more discriminative in the subspace with greater effectiveness. Furthermore, we show that the part-based representation of NMF, especially its supervised variants, is dramatically impactful in detecting lesion areas in medical imaging with limited samples.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.02656v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Keqiang Fan, Xiaohao Cai, Mahesan Niranjan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving the Reconstruction of Disentangled Representation Learners via Multi-Stage Modeling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2010.13187</link>
      <description>arXiv:2010.13187v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Current autoencoder-based disentangled representation learning methods achieve disentanglement by penalizing the (aggregate) posterior to encourage statistical independence of the latent factors. This approach introduces a trade-off between disentangled representation learning and reconstruction quality since the model does not have enough capacity to learn correlated latent variables that capture detail information present in most image data. To overcome this trade-off, we present a novel multi-stage modeling approach where the disentangled factors are first learned using a penalty-based disentangled representation learning method; then, the low-quality reconstruction is improved with another deep generative model that is trained to model the missing correlated latent variables, adding detail information while maintaining conditioning on the previously learned disentangled factors. Taken together, our multi-stage modelling approach results in a single, coherent probabilistic model that is theoretically justified by the principal of D-separation and can be realized with a variety of model classes including likelihood-based models such as variational autoencoders, implicit models such as generative adversarial networks, and tractable models like normalizing flows or mixtures of Gaussians. We demonstrate that our multi-stage model has higher reconstruction quality than current state-of-the-art methods with equivalent disentanglement performance across multiple standard benchmarks. In addition, we apply the multi-stage model to generate synthetic tabular datasets, showcasing an enhanced performance over benchmark models across a variety of metrics. The interpretability analysis further indicates that the multi-stage model can effectively uncover distinct and meaningful features of variations from which the original distribution can be recovered.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2010.13187v2</guid>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Akash Srivastava, Yamini Bansal, Yukun Ding, Cole Lincoln Hurwitz, Kai Xu, Bernhard Egger, Prasanna Sattigeri, Joshua B. Tenenbaum, Phuong Le, Arun Prakash R, Nengfeng Zhou, Joel Vaughan, Yaquan Wang, Anwesha Bhattacharyya, Kristjan Greenewald, David D. Cox, Dan Gutfreund</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robust deep learning for eye fundus images: Bridging real and synthetic data for enhancing generalization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2203.13856</link>
      <description>arXiv:2203.13856v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Deep learning applications for assessing medical images are limited because the datasets are often small and imbalanced. The use of synthetic data has been proposed in the literature, but neither a robust comparison of the different methods nor generalizability has been reported. Our approach integrates a retinal image quality assessment model and StyleGAN2 architecture to enhance Age-related Macular Degeneration (AMD) detection capabilities and improve generalizability. This work compares ten different Generative Adversarial Network (GAN) architectures to generate synthetic eye-fundus images with and without AMD. We combined subsets of three public databases (iChallenge-AMD, ODIR-2019, and RIADD) to form a single training and test set. We employed the STARE dataset for external validation, ensuring a comprehensive assessment of the proposed approach. The results show that StyleGAN2 reached the lowest Frechet Inception Distance (166.17), and clinicians could not accurately differentiate between real and synthetic images. ResNet-18 architecture obtained the best performance with 85% accuracy and outperformed the two human experts (80% and 75%) in detecting AMD fundus images. The accuracy rates were 82.8% for the test set and 81.3% for the STARE dataset, demonstrating the model's generalizability. The proposed methodology for synthetic medical image generation has been validated for robustness and accuracy, with free access to its code for further research and development in this field.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2203.13856v2</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1016/j.bspc.2024.106263</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Biomedical Signal Processing and Control, 94 (2024), 106263</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Guilherme C. Oliveira, Gustavo H. Rosa, Daniel C. G. Pedronette, Jo\~ao P. Papa, Himeesh Kumar, Leandro A. Passos, Dinesh Kumar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weighted structure tensor total variation for image denoising</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2306.10482</link>
      <description>arXiv:2306.10482v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: For image denoising problems, the structure tensor total variation (STV)-based models show good performances when compared with other competing regularization approaches. However, the STV regularizer does not couple the local information of the image and may not maintain the image details. Therefore, we employ the anisotropic weighted matrix introduced in the anisotropic total variation (ATV) model to improve the STV model. By applying the weighted matrix to the discrete gradient of the patch-based Jacobian operator in STV, our proposed weighted STV (WSTV) model can effectively capture local information from images and maintain their details during the denoising process. The optimization problem in the model is solved by a fast first-order gradient projection algorithm with a complexity result of $O(1 / i^2)$. For images with different Gaussian noise levels, the experimental results demonstrate that the WSTV model can effectively improve the quality of restored images compared to other TV and STV-based models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2306.10482v2</guid>
      <category>math.OC</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiuhan Sheng, Lijuan Yang, Jingya Chang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DeepIPCv2: LiDAR-powered Robust Environmental Perception and Navigational Control for Autonomous Vehicle</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2307.06647</link>
      <description>arXiv:2307.06647v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We present DeepIPCv2, an autonomous driving model that perceives the environment using a LiDAR sensor for more robust drivability, especially when driving under poor illumination conditions where everything is not clearly visible. DeepIPCv2 takes a set of LiDAR point clouds as the main perception input. Since point clouds are not affected by illumination changes, they can provide a clear observation of the surroundings no matter what the condition is. This results in a better scene understanding and stable features provided by the perception module to support the controller module in estimating navigational control properly. To evaluate its performance, we conduct several tests by deploying the model to predict a set of driving records and perform real automated driving under three different conditions. We also conduct ablation and comparative studies with some recent models to justify its performance. Based on the experimental results, DeepIPCv2 shows a robust performance by achieving the best drivability in all driving scenarios. Furthermore, to support future research, we will upload the codes and data to https://github.com/oskarnatan/DeepIPCv2.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2307.06647v3</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Oskar Natan, Jun Miura</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bias Behind the Wheel: Fairness Analysis of Autonomous Driving Systems</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2308.02935</link>
      <description>arXiv:2308.02935v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: This paper analyzes fairness in automated pedestrian detection, a crucial but under-explored issue in autonomous driving systems. We evaluate eight state-of-the-art deep learning-based pedestrian detectors across demographic groups on large-scale real-world datasets. To enable thorough fairness testing, we provide extensive annotations for the datasets, resulting in 8,311 images with 16,070 gender labels, 20,115 age labels, and 3,513 skin tone labels. Our findings reveal significant fairness issues, particularly related to age. The undetected proportions for children are 20.14% higher compared to adults. Furthermore, we explore how various driving scenarios affect the fairness of pedestrian detectors. We find that pedestrian detectors demonstrate significant gender biases during night time, potentially exacerbating the prevalent societal issue of female safety concerns during nighttime out. Moreover, we observe that pedestrian detectors can demonstrate both enhanced fairness and superior performance under specific driving conditions, which challenges the fairness-performance trade-off theory widely acknowledged in the fairness literature. We publicly release the code, data, and results to support future research on fairness in autonomous driving.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2308.02935v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xinyue Li, Zhenpeng Chen, Jie M. Zhang, Federica Sarro, Ying Zhang, Xuanzhe Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>APISR: Anime Production Inspired Real-World Anime Super-Resolution</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.01598</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.01598v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: While real-world anime super-resolution (SR) has gained increasing attention in the SR community, existing methods still adopt techniques from the photorealistic domain. In this paper, we analyze the anime production workflow and rethink how to use characteristics of it for the sake of the real-world anime SR. First, we argue that video networks and datasets are not necessary for anime SR due to the repetition use of hand-drawing frames. Instead, we propose an anime image collection pipeline by choosing the least compressed and the most informative frames from the video sources. Based on this pipeline, we introduce the Anime Production-oriented Image (API) dataset. In addition, we identify two anime-specific challenges of distorted and faint hand-drawn lines and unwanted color artifacts. We address the first issue by introducing a prediction-oriented compression module in the image degradation model and a pseudo-ground truth preparation with enhanced hand-drawn lines. In addition, we introduce the balanced twin perceptual loss combining both anime and photorealistic high-level features to mitigate unwanted color artifacts and increase visual clarity. We evaluate our method through extensive experiments on the public benchmark, showing our method outperforms state-of-the-art anime dataset-trained approaches.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.01598v2</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Boyang Wang, Fengyu Yang, Xihang Yu, Chao Zhang, Hanbin Zhao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calibrating Bayesian UNet++ for Sub-Seasonal Forecasting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.16612</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.16612v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Seasonal forecasting is a crucial task when it comes to detecting the extreme heat and colds that occur due to climate change. Confidence in the predictions should be reliable since a small increase in the temperatures in a year has a big impact on the world. Calibration of the neural networks provides a way to ensure our confidence in the predictions. However, calibrating regression models is an under-researched topic, especially in forecasters. We calibrate a UNet++ based architecture, which was shown to outperform physics-based models in temperature anomalies. We show that with a slight trade-off between prediction error and calibration error, it is possible to get more reliable and sharper forecasts. We believe that calibration should be an important part of safety-critical machine learning applications such as weather forecasters.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.16612v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Busra Asan, Abdullah Akg\"ul, Alper Unal, Melih Kandemir, Gozde Unal</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vestibular schwannoma growth prediction from longitudinal MRI by time conditioned neural fields</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.02614</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.02614v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Vestibular schwannomas (VS) are benign tumors that are generally managed by active surveillance with MRI examination. To further assist clinical decision-making and avoid overtreatment, an accurate prediction of tumor growth based on longitudinal imaging is highly desirable. In this paper, we introduce DeepGrowth, a deep learning method that incorporates neural fields and recurrent neural networks for prospective tumor growth prediction. In the proposed method, each tumor is represented as a signed distance function (SDF) conditioned on a low-dimensional latent code. Unlike previous studies that perform tumor shape prediction directly in the image space, we predict the latent codes instead and then reconstruct future shapes from it. To deal with irregular time intervals, we introduce a time-conditioned recurrent module based on a ConvLSTM and a novel temporal encoding strategy, which enables the proposed model to output varying tumor shapes over time. The experiments on an in-house longitudinal VS dataset showed that the proposed model significantly improved the performance ($\ge 1.6\%$ Dice score and $\ge0.20$ mm 95\% Hausdorff distance), in particular for top 20\% tumors that grow or shrink the most ($\ge 4.6\%$ Dice score and $\ge 0.73$ mm 95\% Hausdorff distance). Our code is available at ~\burl{https://github.com/cyjdswx/DeepGrowth}</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.02614v2</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yunjie Chen, Jelmer M. Wolterink, Olaf M. Neve, Stephan R. Romeijn, Berit M. Verbist, Erik F. Hensen, Qian Tao, Marius Staring</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
