<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL</link>
    <description>cs.CL updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 04:00:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Saturday</day>
      <day>Sunday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>Large Model Strategic Thinking, Small Model Efficiency: Transferring Theory of Mind in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05241</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05241v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: As the performance of larger, newer Large Language Models continues to improve for strategic Theory of Mind (ToM) tasks, the demand for these state of the art models increases commensurately. However, their deployment is costly both in terms of processing power and time. In this paper, we investigate the feasibility of creating smaller, simulation-ready agents by way of fine-tuning. To do this, we present a large pre-trained model with 20 unique scenarios that combine a social context with a social dilemma, recording its answers, and using them for Q\&amp;A fine-tuning on a smaller model of the same family. Our focus is on in-context game-theoretic decision-making, the same domain within which human interaction occurs and that requires both a theory of mind (or a semblance thereof) and an understanding of social dynamics. We find that the fine-tuned smaller language model exhibited significant performance closer to that of its larger relative, and that their improvements extended in areas and contexts beyond the ones provided in the training examples. On average for all games, through fine-tuning, the smaller model showed a \%46 improvement in aligning with the behavior of the larger model, with \%100 representing complete alignment. This suggests that our pipeline represents an efficient method to transmit some form of theory of mind to smaller models, creating improved and cheaply deployable algorithms in the process. Despite their simplicity and their associated shortcomings and limitations, our findings represent a stepping stone in the pursuit and training of specialized models for strategic and social decision making.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05241v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.ET</category>
      <category>cs.GT</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nunzio Lore (Sepehr),  Alireza (Sepehr),  Ilami, Babak Heydari</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MUSE: Multi-Knowledge Passing on the Edges, Boosting Knowledge Graph Completion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05283</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05283v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Knowledge Graph Completion (KGC) aims to predict the missing information in the (head entity)-[relation]-(tail entity) triplet. Deep Neural Networks have achieved significant progress in the relation prediction task. However, most existing KGC methods focus on single features (e.g., entity IDs) and sub-graph aggregation, which cannot fully explore all the features in the Knowledge Graph (KG), and neglect the external semantic knowledge injection. To address these problems, we propose MUSE, a knowledge-aware reasoning model to learn a tailored embedding space in three dimensions for missing relation prediction through a multi-knowledge representation learning mechanism. Our MUSE consists of three parallel components: 1) Prior Knowledge Learning for enhancing the triplets' semantic representation by fine-tuning BERT; 2) Context Message Passing for enhancing the context messages of KG; 3) Relational Path Aggregation for enhancing the path representation from the head entity to the tail entity. Our experimental results show that MUSE significantly outperforms other baselines on four public datasets, such as over 5.50% improvement in H@1 and 4.20% improvement in MRR on the NELL995 dataset. The code and all datasets will be released via https://github.com/NxxTGT/MUSE.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05283v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Pengjie Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Psychology-based Unified Dynamic Framework for Curriculum Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05326</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05326v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Directly learning from examples of random difficulty levels is often challenging for both humans and machine learning models. A more effective strategy involves exposing learners to examples in a progressive order, from easy to difficult. Curriculum Learning (CL) has been proposed to implement this strategy in machine learning model training. However, two key challenges persist in CL framework design: defining the difficulty of training data and determining the appropriate amount of data to input at each training step. This paper presents a Psychology-based Unified Dynamic Framework for Curriculum Learning (PUDF), drawing inspiration from psychometrics. We quantify the difficulty of training data by applying Item Response Theory (IRT) to responses from Artificial Crowds (AC). This theory-driven IRT-AC approach leads to global (i.e., model-independent) and interpretable difficulty values. Leveraging IRT, we propose a Dynamic Data Selection via Model Ability Estimation (DDS-MAE) strategy to schedule the appropriate amount of data during model training. Since our difficulty labeling and model ability estimation are based on a consistent theory, namely IRT, their values are comparable within the same scope, potentially leading to a faster convergence compared to the other CL methods. Experimental results demonstrate that fine-tuning pre-trained language models with PUDF enhances their performance on the GLUE benchmark. Moreover, PUDF surpasses other state-of-the-art (SOTA) CL methods on the GLUE benchmark. We further explore the components of PUDF, namely the difficulty measurer (IRT-AC) and the training scheduler (DDS-MAE) qualitatively and quantitatively. Lastly, we conduct an ablation study to clarify which components of PUDF contribute to faster convergence and higher accuracy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05326v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Guangyu Meng, Qingkai Zeng, John P. Lalor, Hong Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Text to Insight: Leveraging Large Language Models for Performance Evaluation in Management</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05328</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05328v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This study explores the potential of Large Language Models (LLMs), specifically GPT-4, to enhance objectivity in organizational task performance evaluations. Through comparative analyses across two studies, including various task performance outputs, we demonstrate that LLMs can serve as a reliable and even superior alternative to human raters in evaluating knowledge-based performance outputs, which are a key contribution of knowledge workers. Our results suggest that GPT ratings are comparable to human ratings but exhibit higher consistency and reliability. Additionally, combined multiple GPT ratings on the same performance output show strong correlations with aggregated human performance ratings, akin to the consensus principle observed in performance evaluation literature. However, we also find that LLMs are prone to contextual biases, such as the halo effect, mirroring human evaluative biases. Our research suggests that while LLMs are capable of extracting meaningful constructs from text-based data, their scope is currently limited to specific forms of performance evaluation. By highlighting both the potential and limitations of LLMs, our study contributes to the discourse on AI role in management studies and sets a foundation for future research to refine AI theoretical and practical applications in management.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05328v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.ET</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>econ.GN</category>
      <category>q-fin.EC</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ning Li, Huaikang Zhou, Mingze Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DataNarrative: Automated Data-Driven Storytelling with Visualizations and Texts</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05346</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05346v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Data-driven storytelling is a powerful method for conveying insights by combining narrative techniques with visualizations and text. These stories integrate visual aids, such as highlighted bars and lines in charts, along with textual annotations explaining insights. However, creating such stories requires a deep understanding of the data and meticulous narrative planning, often necessitating human intervention, which can be time-consuming and mentally taxing. While Large Language Models (LLMs) excel in various NLP tasks, their ability to generate coherent and comprehensive data stories remains underexplored. In this work, we introduce a novel task for data story generation and a benchmark containing 1,449 stories from diverse sources. To address the challenges of crafting coherent data stories, we propose a multiagent framework employing two LLM agents designed to replicate the human storytelling process: one for understanding and describing the data (Reflection), generating the outline, and narration, and another for verification at each intermediary step. While our agentic framework generally outperforms non-agentic counterparts in both model-based and human evaluations, the results also reveal unique challenges in data story generation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05346v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mohammed Saidul Islam, Enamul Hoque, Shafiq Joty, Md Tahmid Rahman Laskar, Md Rizwan Parvez</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FiST-Financial Style Transfer with Hallucination and Creativity Control Framework</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05365</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05365v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Financial report generation using general purpose large language models pose two major challenges, including the lack of compound sentences and hallucinations. Advanced prompt engineering and retrieval augmented generation (RAG) techniques are incapable of curing the writing style discrepancies. In this work we propose a novel two-stage fine-tuning process wherein public domain financial reports are processed into prompt-completions and augmented using simple LLM prompts to then enable sectional financial report generation using minimal instructions and tabular data inputs. Our proposed fine-tuning framework results doubles the number of correct questions answers and reduces hallucinations by over 50%. Additionally, the two-stage fine tuned models have lower perplexity, improved ROUGE, TER and BLEU scores, higher creativity and knowledge density with lower uncertainty and cross entropy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05365v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CE</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sohini Roychowdhury, Marko Krema, Brian Moore, Xingjian Lai, Dike Effedua, Bharat Jethwani</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LaiDA: Linguistics-aware In-context Learning with Data Augmentation for Metaphor Components Identification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05404</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05404v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Metaphor Components Identification (MCI) contributes to enhancing machine understanding of metaphors, thereby advancing downstream natural language processing tasks. However, the complexity, diversity, and dependency on context and background knowledge pose significant challenges for MCI. Large language models (LLMs) offer new avenues for accurate comprehension of complex natural language texts due to their strong semantic analysis and extensive commonsense knowledge. In this research, a new LLM-based framework is proposed, named Linguistics-aware In-context Learning with Data Augmentation (LaiDA). Specifically, ChatGPT and supervised fine-tuning are utilized to tailor a high-quality dataset. LaiDA incorporates a simile dataset for pre-training. A graph attention network encoder generates linguistically rich feature representations to retrieve similar examples. Subsequently, LLM is fine-tuned with prompts that integrate linguistically similar examples. LaiDA ranked 2nd in Subtask 2 of NLPCC2024 Shared Task 9, demonstrating its effectiveness. Code and data are available at https://github.com/WXLJZ/LaiDA.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05404v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hongde Liu, Chenyuan He, Feiyang Meng, Changyong Niu, Yuxiang Jia</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chain of Condition: Construct, Verify and Solve Conditions for Conditional Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05442</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05442v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Conditional question answering (CQA) is an important task that aims to find probable answers and identify conditions that need to be satisfied to support the answer. Existing approaches struggle with CQA due to two main challenges: (1) precisely identifying conditions and their logical relationship, and (2) verifying and solving the conditions. To address these challenges, we propose Chain of Condition, a novel prompting approach by firstly identifying all conditions and constructing their logical relationships explicitly according to the document, then verifying whether these conditions are satisfied, finally solving the logical expression by tools to indicate any missing conditions and generating the answer based on the resolved conditions. The experiments on two benchmark conditional question answering datasets shows chain of condition outperforms existing prompting baselines, establishing a new state-of-the-art. Furthermore, with backbone models like GPT-3.5-Turbo or GPT-4, it surpasses all supervised baselines with only few-shot settings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05442v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiuheng Lin, Yuxuan Lai, Yansong Feng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Path-LLM: A Shortest-Path-based LLM Learning for Unified Graph Representation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05456</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05456v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Unified graph representation learning aims to produce node embeddings, which can be applied to multiple downstream applications. However, existing studies based on graph neural networks and language models either suffer from the limitations of numerous training needed toward specific downstream predictions or have shallow semantic features. In this work, we propose a novel Path-LLM model to learn unified graph representation, which leverages a powerful large language model (LLM) to incorporate our proposed path features. Our Path-LLM framework consists of several well-designed techniques. First, we develop a new mechanism of long-to-short shortest path (L2SP) selection, which covers essential connections between different dense groups. An in-depth comparison of different path selection plans is offered to illustrate the strength of our designed L2SP. Then, we design path textualization to obtain L2SP-based training texts. Next, we feed the texts into a self-supervised LLM training process to learn embeddings. Extensive experiments on benchmarks validate the superiority of Path-LLM against the state-of-the-art WalkLM method on two classical graph learning tasks (node classification and link prediction) and one NP-hard graph query processing task (keyword search), meanwhile saving more than 90% of training paths.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05456v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenbo Shang, Xuliang Zhu, Xin Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating Instruction Tuning Large Language Models on Graphs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05457</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05457v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Inspired by the recent advancements of Large Language Models (LLMs) in NLP tasks, there's growing interest in applying LLMs to graph-related tasks. This study delves into the capabilities of instruction-following LLMs for engaging with real-world graphs, aiming to offer empirical insights into how LLMs can effectively interact with graphs and generalize across graph tasks. We begin by constructing a dataset designed for instruction tuning, which comprises a diverse collection of 79 graph-related tasks from academic and e-commerce domains, featuring 44,240 training instances and 18,960 test samples. Utilizing this benchmark, our initial investigation focuses on identifying the optimal graph representation that serves as a conduit for LLMs to understand complex graph structures. Our findings indicate that JSON format for graph representation consistently outperforms natural language and code formats across various LLMs and graph types. Furthermore, we examine the key factors that influence the generalization abilities of instruction-tuned LLMs by evaluating their performance on both in-domain and out-of-domain graph tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05457v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kerui Zhu, Bo-Wei Huang, Bowen Jin, Yizhu Jiao, Ming Zhong, Kevin Chang, Shou-De Lin, Jiawei Han</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MABR: A Multilayer Adversarial Bias Removal Approach Without Prior Bias Knowledge</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05497</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05497v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Models trained on real-world data often mirror and exacerbate existing social biases. Traditional methods for mitigating these biases typically require prior knowledge of the specific biases to be addressed, such as gender or racial biases, and the social groups associated with each instance. In this paper, we introduce a novel adversarial training strategy that operates independently of prior bias-type knowledge and protected attribute labels. Our approach proactively identifies biases during model training by utilizing auxiliary models, which are trained concurrently by predicting the performance of the main model without relying on task labels. Additionally, we implement these auxiliary models at various levels of the feature maps of the main model, enabling the detection of a broader and more nuanced range of bias features. Through experiments on racial and gender biases in sentiment and occupation classification tasks, our method effectively reduces social biases without the need for demographic annotations. Moreover, our approach not only matches but often surpasses the efficacy of methods that require detailed demographic insights, marking a significant advancement in bias mitigation techniques.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05497v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Maxwell J. Yin, Boyu Wang, Charles Ling</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your Context Is Not an Array: Unveiling Random Access Limitations in Transformers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05506</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05506v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Despite their recent successes, Transformer-based large language models show surprising failure modes. A well-known example of such failure modes is their inability to length-generalize: solving problem instances at inference time that are longer than those seen during training. In this work, we further explore the root cause of this failure by performing a detailed analysis of model behaviors on the simple parity task. Our analysis suggests that length generalization failures are intricately related to a model's inability to perform random memory accesses within its context window. We present supporting evidence for this hypothesis by demonstrating the effectiveness of methodologies that circumvent the need for indexing or that enable random token access indirectly, through content-based addressing. We further show where and how the failure to perform random memory access manifests through attention map visualizations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05506v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>MohammadReza Ebrahimi, Sunny Panchal, Roland Memisevic</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SWIFT:A Scalable lightWeight Infrastructure for Fine-Tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05517</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05517v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent development in Large Language Models (LLMs) and Multi-modal Large Language Models (MLLMs) have leverage Attention-based Transformer architectures and achieved superior performance and generalization capabilities. They have since covered extensive areas of traditional learning tasks. For instance, text-based tasks such as text-classification and sequence-labeling, as well as multi-modal tasks like Visual Question Answering (VQA) and Optical Character Recognition (OCR), which were previously addressed using different models, can now be tackled based on one foundation model. Consequently, the training and lightweight fine-tuning of LLMs and MLLMs, especially those based on Transformer architecture, has become particularly important. In recognition of these overwhelming needs, we develop SWIFT, a customizable one-stop infrastructure for large models. With support of over $300+$ LLMs and $50+$ MLLMs, SWIFT stands as the open-source framework that provide the \textit{most comprehensive support} for fine-tuning large models. In particular, it is the first training framework that provides systematic support for MLLMs. In addition to the core functionalities of fine-tuning, SWIFT also integrates post-training processes such as inference, evaluation, and model quantization, to facilitate fast adoptions of large models in various application scenarios. With a systematic integration of various training techniques, SWIFT offers helpful utilities such as benchmark comparisons among different training techniques for large models. For fine-tuning models specialized in agent framework, we show that notable improvements on the ToolBench leader-board can be achieved by training with customized dataset on SWIFT, with an increase of 5.2\%-21.8\% in the Act.EM metric over various baseline models, a reduction in hallucination by 1.6\%-14.1\%, and an average performance improvement of 8\%-17\%.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05517v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuze Zhao, Jintao Huang, Jinghan Hu, Daoze Zhang, Zeyinzi Jiang, Zhikai Wu, Baole Ai, Ang Wang, Wenmeng Zhou, Yingda Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Context-Driven Index Trimming: A Data Quality Perspective to Enhancing Precision of RALMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05524</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05524v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Retrieval-Augmented Large Language Models (RALMs) have made significant strides in enhancing the accuracy of generated responses.However, existing research often overlooks the data quality issues within retrieval results, often caused by inaccurate existing vector-distance-based retrieval methods.We propose to boost the precision of RALMs' answers from a data quality perspective through the Context-Driven Index Trimming (CDIT) framework, where Context Matching Dependencies (CMDs) are employed as logical data quality rules to capture and regulate the consistency between retrieved contexts.Based on the semantic comprehension capabilities of Large Language Models (LLMs), CDIT can effectively identify and discard retrieval results that are inconsistent with the query context and further modify indexes in the database, thereby improving answer quality.Experiments demonstrate on challenging question-answering tasks.Also, the flexibility of CDIT is verified through its compatibility with various language models and indexing methods, which offers a promising approach to bolster RALMs' data quality and retrieval precision jointly.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05524v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.DB</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kexin Ma, Ruochun Jin, Xi Wang, Huan Chen, Jing Ren, Yuhua Tang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>P3: A Policy-Driven, Pace-Adaptive, and Diversity-Promoted Framework for Optimizing LLM Training</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05541</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05541v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In the rapidly evolving field of Large Language Models (LLMs), selecting high-quality data for fine-tuning is essential. This paper focuses on task-specific data pruning and selection to enhance fine-tuning. We introduce an innovative framework, termed P3, which improves LLM performance through a dynamic, adaptive training strategy. Specifically, P3 comprises the following components: (1) Policy-driven Difficulty Measurement: we begin by measuring the difficulty of data based on the model's real-time performance, transitioning from static, predefined metrics to more dynamic and adaptable ones. (2) Pace-adaptive Selection: we employ self-paced learning (SPL) to gradually select increasingly challenging data, thereby progressively enhancing the model's performance. (3) Diversity Promotion: we integrate Determinantal Point Process (DPP) into the selection process to promote the diversity within and between samples, enriching the learning process. We have validated our method on two well-known LLM datasets, APPS and MATH, designed for logical reasoning scenarios. The results show that our P3 framework significantly improves training outcomes compared to traditional methods. By fundamentally refining data selection and utilization strategies, P3 not only advances theoretical understanding of dynamic training approaches but also provides a versatile framework that can revolutionize model training in natural language processing.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05541v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yingxuan Yang, Huayi Wang, Muning Wen, Weinan Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-layer Sequence Labeling-based Joint Biomedical Event Extraction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05545</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05545v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In recent years, biomedical event extraction has been dominated by complicated pipeline and joint methods, which need to be simplified. In addition, existing work has not effectively utilized trigger word information explicitly. Hence, we propose MLSL, a method based on multi-layer sequence labeling for joint biomedical event extraction. MLSL does not introduce prior knowledge and complex structures. Moreover, it explicitly incorporates the information of candidate trigger words into the sequence labeling to learn the interaction relationships between trigger words and argument roles. Based on this, MLSL can learn well with just a simple workflow. Extensive experimentation demonstrates the superiority of MLSL in terms of extraction performance compared to other state-of-the-art methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05545v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gongchi Chen, Pengchao Wu, Jinghang Gu, Longhua Qian, Guodong Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Language Model-based Role-Playing for Personalized Medical Jargon Extraction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05555</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05555v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Previous studies reveal that Electronic Health Records (EHR), which have been widely adopted in the U.S. to allow patients to access their personal medical information, do not have high readability to patients due to the prevalence of medical jargon. Tailoring medical notes to individual comprehension by identifying jargon that is difficult for each person will enhance the utility of generative models. We present the first quantitative analysis to measure the impact of role-playing in LLM in medical term extraction. By comparing the results of Mechanical Turk workers over 20 sentences, our study demonstrates that LLM role-playing improves F1 scores in 95% of cases across 14 different socio-demographic backgrounds. Furthermore, applying role-playing with in-context learning outperformed the previous state-of-the-art models. Our research showed that ChatGPT can improve traditional medical term extraction systems by utilizing role-play to deliver personalized patient education, a potential that previous models had not achieved.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05555v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jung Hoon Lim, Sunjae Kwon, Zonghai Yao, John P. Lalor, Hong Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Document-Level Event Extraction with Definition-Driven ICL</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05566</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05566v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In the field of Natural Language Processing (NLP), Large Language Models (LLMs) have shown great potential in document-level event extraction tasks, but existing methods face challenges in the design of prompts. To address this issue, we propose an optimization strategy called "Definition-driven Document-level Event Extraction (DDEE)." By adjusting the length of the prompt and enhancing the clarity of heuristics, we have significantly improved the event extraction performance of LLMs. We used data balancing techniques to solve the long-tail effect problem, enhancing the model's generalization ability for event types. At the same time, we refined the prompt to ensure it is both concise and comprehensive, adapting to the sensitivity of LLMs to the style of prompts. In addition, the introduction of structured heuristic methods and strict limiting conditions has improved the precision of event and argument role extraction. These strategies not only solve the prompt engineering problems of LLMs in document-level event extraction but also promote the development of event extraction technology, providing new research perspectives for other tasks in the NLP field.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05566v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhuoyuan Liu, Yilin Luo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speculative Diffusion Decoding: Accelerating Language Generation through Diffusion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05636</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05636v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Speculative decoding has emerged as a widely adopted method to accelerate large language model inference without sacrificing the quality of the model outputs. While this technique has facilitated notable speed improvements by enabling parallel sequence verification, its efficiency remains inherently limited by the reliance on incremental token generation in existing draft models. To overcome this limitation, this paper proposes an adaptation of speculative decoding which uses discrete diffusion models to generate draft sequences. This allows parallelization of both the drafting and verification steps, providing significant speed-ups to the inference process. Our proposed approach, \textit{Speculative Diffusion Decoding (SpecDiff)}, is validated on standard language generation benchmarks and empirically demonstrated to provide a \textbf{up to 8.7x speed-up over standard generation processes and up to 2.5x speed-up over existing speculative decoding approaches.}</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05636v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jacob K Christopher, Brian R Bartoldson, Bhavya Kailkhura, Ferdinando Fioretto</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WiDe-analysis: Enabling One-click Content Moderation Analysis on Wikipedia's Articles for Deletion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05655</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05655v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Content moderation in online platforms is crucial for ensuring activity therein adheres to existing policies, especially as these platforms grow. NLP research in this area has typically focused on automating some part of it given that it is not feasible to monitor all active discussions effectively. Past works have focused on revealing deletion patterns with like sentiment analysis, or on developing platform-specific models such as Wikipedia policy or stance detectors. Unsurprisingly, however, this valuable body of work is rather scattered, with little to no agreement with regards to e.g., the deletion discussions corpora used for training or the number of stance labels. Moreover, while efforts have been made to connect stance with rationales (e.g., to ground a deletion decision on the relevant policy), there is little explanability work beyond that. In this paper, we introduce a suite of experiments on Wikipedia deletion discussions and wide-analyis (Wikipedia Deletion Analysis), a Python package aimed at providing one click analysis to content moderation discussions. We release all assets associated with wide-analysis, including data, models and the Python package, and a HuggingFace space with the goal to accelerate research on automating content moderation in Wikipedia and beyond.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05655v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hsuvas Borkakoty, Luis Espinosa-Anke</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Training an NLP Scholar at a Small Liberal Arts College: A Backwards Designed Course Proposal</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05664</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05664v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The rapid growth in natural language processing (NLP) over the last couple years has generated student interest and excitement in learning more about the field. In this paper, we present two types of students that NLP courses might want to train. First, an "NLP engineer" who is able to flexibly design, build and apply new technologies in NLP for a wide range of tasks. Second, an "NLP scholar" who is able to pose, refine and answer questions in NLP and how it relates to the society, while also learning to effectively communicate these answers to a broader audience. While these two types of skills are not mutually exclusive -- NLP engineers should be able to think critically, and NLP scholars should be able to build systems -- we think that courses can differ in the balance of these skills. As educators at Small Liberal Arts Colleges, the strengths of our students and our institution favors an approach that is better suited to train NLP scholars. In this paper we articulate what kinds of skills an NLP scholar should have, and then adopt a backwards design to propose course components that can aid the acquisition of these skills.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05664v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Grusha Prasad, Forrest Davis</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Language-Informed Beam Search Decoding for Multilingual Machine Translation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05738</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05738v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Beam search decoding is the de-facto method for decoding auto-regressive Neural Machine Translation (NMT) models, including multilingual NMT where the target language is specified as an input. However, decoding multilingual NMT models commonly produces ``off-target'' translations -- yielding translation outputs not in the intended language. In this paper, we first conduct an error analysis of off-target translations for a strong multilingual NMT model and identify how these decodings are produced during beam search. We then propose Language-informed Beam Search (LiBS), a general decoding algorithm incorporating an off-the-shelf Language Identification (LiD) model into beam search decoding to reduce off-target translations. LiBS is an inference-time procedure that is NMT-model agnostic and does not require any additional parallel data. Results show that our proposed LiBS algorithm on average improves +1.1 BLEU and +0.9 BLEU on WMT and OPUS datasets, and reduces off-target rates from 22.9\% to 7.7\% and 65.8\% to 25.3\% respectively.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05738v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yilin Yang, Stefan Lee, Prasad Tadepalli</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reference-free Hallucination Detection for Large Vision-Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05767</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05767v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large vision-language models (LVLMs) have made significant progress in recent years. While LVLMs exhibit excellent ability in language understanding, question answering, and conversations of visual inputs, they are prone to producing hallucinations. While several methods are proposed to evaluate the hallucinations in LVLMs, most are reference-based and depend on external tools, which complicates their practical application. To assess the viability of alternative methods, it is critical to understand whether the reference-free approaches, which do not rely on any external tools, can efficiently detect hallucinations. Therefore, we initiate an exploratory study to demonstrate the effectiveness of different reference-free solutions in detecting hallucinations in LVLMs. In particular, we conduct an extensive study on three kinds of techniques: uncertainty-based, consistency-based, and supervised uncertainty quantification methods on four representative LVLMs across two different tasks. The empirical results show that the reference-free approaches are capable of effectively detecting non-factual responses in LVLMs, with the supervised uncertainty quantification method outperforming the others, achieving the best performance across different settings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05767v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qing Li, Chenyang Lyu, Jiahui Geng, Derui Zhu, Maxim Panov, Fakhri Karray</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LI-TTA: Language Informed Test-Time Adaptation for Automatic Speech Recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05769</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05769v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Test-Time Adaptation (TTA) has emerged as a crucial solution to the domain shift challenge, wherein the target environment diverges from the original training environment. A prime exemplification is TTA for Automatic Speech Recognition (ASR), which enhances model performance by leveraging output prediction entropy minimization as a self-supervision signal. However, a key limitation of this self-supervision lies in its primary focus on acoustic features, with minimal attention to the linguistic properties of the input. To address this gap, we propose Language Informed Test-Time Adaptation (LI-TTA), which incorporates linguistic insights during TTA for ASR. LI-TTA integrates corrections from an external language model to merge linguistic with acoustic information by minimizing the CTC loss from the correction alongside the standard TTA loss. With extensive experiments, we show that LI-TTA effectively improves the performance of TTA for ASR in various distribution shift situations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05769v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Eunseop Yoon, Hee Suk Yoon, John Harvill, Mark Hasegawa-Johnson, Chang D. Yoo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HiLight: A Hierarchy-aware Light Global Model with Hierarchical Local ConTrastive Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05786</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05786v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Hierarchical text classification (HTC) is a special sub-task of multi-label classification (MLC) whose taxonomy is constructed as a tree and each sample is assigned with at least one path in the tree. Latest HTC models contain three modules: a text encoder, a structure encoder and a multi-label classification head. Specially, the structure encoder is designed to encode the hierarchy of taxonomy. However, the structure encoder has scale problem. As the taxonomy size increases, the learnable parameters of recent HTC works grow rapidly. Recursive regularization is another widely-used method to introduce hierarchical information but it has collapse problem and generally relaxed by assigning with a small weight (ie. 1e-6). In this paper, we propose a Hierarchy-aware Light Global model with Hierarchical local conTrastive learning (HiLight), a lightweight and efficient global model only consisting of a text encoder and a multi-label classification head. We propose a new learning task to introduce the hierarchical information, called Hierarchical Local Contrastive Learning (HiLCL). Extensive experiments are conducted on two benchmark datasets to demonstrate the effectiveness of our model.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05786v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhijian Chen, Zhonghua Li, Jianxin Yang, Ye Qi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAGA: A Participant-specific Examination of Story Alternatives and Goal Applicability for a Deeper Understanding of Complex Events</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05793</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05793v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Interpreting and assessing goal driven actions is vital to understanding and reasoning over complex events. It is important to be able to acquire the knowledge needed for this understanding, though doing so is challenging. We argue that such knowledge can be elicited through a participant achievement lens. We analyze a complex event in a narrative according to the intended achievements of the participants in that narrative, the likely future actions of the participants, and the likelihood of goal success. We collect 6.3K high quality goal and action annotations reflecting our proposed participant achievement lens, with an average weighted Fleiss-Kappa IAA of 80%. Our collection contains annotated alternate versions of each narrative. These alternate versions vary minimally from the "original" story, but can license drastically different inferences. Our findings suggest that while modern large language models can reflect some of the goal-based knowledge we study, they find it challenging to fully capture the design and intent behind concerted actions, even when the model pretraining included the data from which we extracted the goal knowledge. We show that smaller models fine-tuned on our dataset can achieve performance surpassing larger models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05793v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sai Vallurupalli, Katrin Erk, Francis Ferraro</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iterative Improvement of an Additively Regularized Topic Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05840</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05840v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Topic modelling is fundamentally a soft clustering problem (of known objects -- documents, over unknown clusters -- topics). That is, the task is incorrectly posed. In particular, the topic models are unstable and incomplete. All this leads to the fact that the process of finding a good topic model (repeated hyperparameter selection, model training, and topic quality assessment) can be particularly long and labor-intensive. We aim to simplify the process, to make it more deterministic and provable. To this end, we present a method for iterative training of a topic model. The essence of the method is that a series of related topic models are trained so that each subsequent model is at least as good as the previous one, i.e., that it retains all the good topics found earlier. The connection between the models is achieved by additive regularization. The result of this iterative training is the last topic model in the series, which we call the iteratively updated additively regularized topic model (ITAR). Experiments conducted on several collections of natural language texts show that the proposed ITAR model performs better than other popular topic models (LDA, ARTM, BERTopic), its topics are diverse, and its perplexity (ability to "explain" the underlying data) is moderate.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05840v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>math.PR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alex Gorbulev, Vasiliy Alekseev, Konstantin Vorontsov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defining Boundaries: A Spectrum of Task Feasibility for Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05873</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05873v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have shown remarkable performance in various tasks but often fail to handle queries that exceed their knowledge and capabilities, leading to incorrect or fabricated responses. This paper addresses the need for LLMs to recognize and refuse infeasible tasks due to the required skills surpassing their capabilities. We first systematically conceptualize infeasible tasks for LLMs, providing formal definitions and categorizations that cover a spectrum of related hallucinations. We develop and benchmark a new dataset comprising diverse infeasible and feasible tasks to test multiple LLMs' abilities on task feasibility. Furthermore, we explore the potential of training enhancements to increase LLMs' refusal capabilities with fine-tuning. Experiments validate the effectiveness of our methods, offering promising directions for refining the operational boundaries of LLMs in real applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05873v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenbo Zhang, Zihang Xu, Hengrui Cai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM-Based Robust Product Classification in Commerce and Compliance</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05874</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05874v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Product classification is a crucial task in international trade, as compliance regulations are verified and taxes and duties are applied based on product categories. Manual classification of products is time-consuming and error-prone, and the sheer volume of products imported and exported renders the manual process infeasible. Consequently, e-commerce platforms and enterprises involved in international trade have turned to automatic product classification using machine learning. However, current approaches do not consider the real-world challenges associated with product classification, such as very abbreviated and incomplete product descriptions. In addition, recent advancements in generative Large Language Models (LLMs) and their reasoning capabilities are mainly untapped in product classification and e-commerce. In this research, we explore the real-life challenges of industrial classification and we propose data perturbations that allow for realistic data simulation. Furthermore, we employ LLM-based product classification to improve the robustness of the prediction in presence of incomplete data. Our research shows that LLMs with in-context learning outperform the supervised approaches in the clean-data scenario. Additionally, we illustrate that LLMs are significantly more robust than the supervised approaches when data attacks are present.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05874v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sina Gholamian, Gianfranco Romani, Bartosz Rudnikowicz, Laura Skylaki</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating Arabic LLM Prompts at Scale</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05882</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05882v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The debut of chatGPT and BARD has popularized instruction following text generation using LLMs, where a user can interrogate an LLM using natural language requests and obtain natural language answers that matches their requests. Training LLMs to respond in this manner requires a large number of worked out examples of user requests (aka prompts) with corresponding gold responses. In this paper, we introduce two methods for creating such prompts for Arabic cheaply and quickly. The first methods entails automatically translating existing prompt datasets from English, such as PromptSource and Super-NaturalInstructions, and then using machine translation quality estimation to retain high quality translations only. The second method involves creating natural language prompts on top of existing Arabic NLP datasets. Using these two methods we were able to create more than 67.4 million Arabic prompts that cover a variety of tasks including summarization, headline generation, grammar checking, open/closed question answering, creative writing, etc. We show that fine tuning an open 7 billion parameter large language model, namely base Qwen2 7B, enables it to outperform a state-of-the-art 70 billion parameter instruction tuned model, namely Llama3 70B, in handling Arabic prompts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05882v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Abdelrahman El-Sheikh, Ahmed Elmogtaba, Kareem Darwish, Muhammad Elmallah, Ashraf Elneima, Hassan Sawaf</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AdTEC: A Unified Benchmark for Evaluating Text Quality in Search Engine Advertising</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05906</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05906v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: With the increase in the more fluent ad texts automatically created by natural language generation technology, it is in the high demand to verify the quality of these creatives in a real-world setting. We propose AdTEC, the first public benchmark to evaluate ad texts in multiple aspects from the perspective of practical advertising operations. Our contributions are: (i) Defining five tasks for evaluating the quality of ad texts and building a dataset based on the actual operational experience of advertising agencies, which is typically kept in-house. (ii) Validating the performance of existing pre-trained language models (PLMs) and human evaluators on the dataset. (iii) Analyzing the characteristics and providing challenges of the benchmark. The results show that while PLMs have already reached the practical usage level in several tasks, human still outperforms in certain domains, implying that there is significant room for improvement in such area.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05906v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Peinan Zhang, Yusuke Sakai, Masato Mita, Hiroki Ouchi, Taro Watanabe</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New Pipeline For Generating Instruction Dataset via RAG and Self Fine-Tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05911</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05911v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: With the rapid development of large language models in recent years, there has been an increasing demand for domain-specific Agents that can cater to the unique needs of enterprises and organizations. Unlike general models, which strive for broad coverage, these specialized Agents rely on focused datasets tailored to their intended applications. This research proposes a pipeline that leverages the power of LLMs and the Retrieval-Augmented Generation related framework to construct high-quality instruction datasets for fine-tuning on specific domains using custom document collections. By ingesting domain-specific documents, the pipeline generates relevant and contextually appropriate instructions, thus effectively creating a comprehensive dataset for fine-tuning LLMs on the target domain. This approach overcomes the limitations of traditional dataset creation methods, which often rely on manual curation or web-scraping techniques that may introduce noise and irrelevant data. Notably, our pipeline offers a dynamic solution that can quickly adapt to updates or modifications in the domain-specific document collection, eliminating the need for complete retraining. Additionally, it addresses the challenge of data scarcity by enabling the generation of instruction datasets from a limited set of initial documents, rendering it suitable for unpopular or specialized domains where comprehensive datasets are scarce. As a case study, we apply this approach to the domain of psychiatry, a field requiring specialized knowledge and sensitive handling of patient information. The resulting fine-tuned LLM demonstrates showcases the viability of the proposed approach and underscores its potential for widespread adoption across various industries and domains where tailored, accurate, and contextually relevant language models are indispensable.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05911v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chih-Wei Song, Yu-Kai Lee, Yin-Te Tsai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ConvKGYarn: Spinning Configurable and Scalable Conversational Knowledge Graph QA datasets with Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05948</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05948v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The rapid advancement of Large Language Models (LLMs) and conversational assistants necessitates dynamic, scalable, and configurable conversational datasets for training and evaluation. These datasets must accommodate diverse user interaction modes, including text and voice, each presenting unique modeling challenges. Knowledge Graphs (KGs), with their structured and evolving nature, offer an ideal foundation for current and precise knowledge. Although human-curated KG-based conversational datasets exist, they struggle to keep pace with the rapidly changing user information needs. We present ConvKGYarn, a scalable method for generating up-to-date and configurable conversational KGQA datasets. Qualitative psychometric analyses confirm our method can generate high-quality datasets rivaling a popular conversational KGQA dataset while offering it at scale and covering a wide range of human-interaction configurations. We showcase its utility by testing LLMs on diverse conversations - exploring model behavior on conversational KGQA sets with different configurations grounded in the same KG fact set. Our results highlight the ability of ConvKGYarn to improve KGQA foundations and evaluate parametric knowledge of LLMs, thus offering a robust solution to the constantly evolving landscape of conversational assistants.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05948v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ronak Pradeep, Daniel Lee, Ali Mousavi, Jeff Pound, Yisi Sang, Jimmy Lin, Ihab Ilyas, Saloni Potdar, Mostafa Arefiyan, Yunyao Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Language of Trauma: Modeling Traumatic Event Descriptions Across Domains with Explainable AI</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05977</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05977v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Psychological trauma can manifest following various distressing events and is captured in diverse online contexts. However, studies traditionally focus on a single aspect of trauma, often neglecting the transferability of findings across different scenarios. We address this gap by training language models with progressing complexity on trauma-related datasets, including genocide-related court data, a Reddit dataset on post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD), counseling conversations, and Incel forum posts. Our results show that the fine-tuned RoBERTa model excels in predicting traumatic events across domains, slightly outperforming large language models like GPT-4. Additionally, SLALOM-feature scores and conceptual explanations effectively differentiate and cluster trauma-related language, highlighting different trauma aspects and identifying sexual abuse and experiences related to death as a common traumatic event across all datasets. This transferability is crucial as it allows for the development of tools to enhance trauma detection and intervention in diverse populations and settings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05977v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Miriam Schirmer, Tobias Leemann, Gjergji Kasneci, J\"urgen Pfeffer, David Jurgens</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Dialogue Speech Recognition with Robust Contextual Awareness via Noise Representation Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06043</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06043v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent dialogue systems rely on turn-based spoken interactions, requiring accurate Automatic Speech Recognition (ASR). Errors in ASR can significantly impact downstream dialogue tasks. To address this, using dialogue context from user and agent interactions for transcribing subsequent utterances has been proposed. This method incorporates the transcription of the user's speech and the agent's response as model input, using the accumulated context generated by each turn. However, this context is susceptible to ASR errors because it is generated by the ASR model in an auto-regressive fashion. Such noisy context can further degrade the benefits of context input, resulting in suboptimal ASR performance. In this paper, we introduce Context Noise Representation Learning (CNRL) to enhance robustness against noisy context, ultimately improving dialogue speech recognition accuracy. To maximize the advantage of context awareness, our approach includes decoder pre-training using text-based dialogue data and noise representation learning for a context encoder. Based on the evaluation of speech dialogues, our method shows superior results compared to baselines. Furthermore, the strength of our approach is highlighted in noisy environments where user speech is barely audible due to real-world noise, relying on contextual information to transcribe the input accurately.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06043v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wonjun Lee, San Kim, Gary Geunbae Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DiagESC: Dialogue Synthesis for Integrating Depression Diagnosis into Emotional Support Conversation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06044</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06044v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Dialogue systems for mental health care aim to provide appropriate support to individuals experiencing mental distress. While extensive research has been conducted to deliver adequate emotional support, existing studies cannot identify individuals who require professional medical intervention and cannot offer suitable guidance. We introduce the Diagnostic Emotional Support Conversation task for an advanced mental health management system. We develop the DESC dataset to assess depression symptoms while maintaining user experience by utilizing task-specific utterance generation prompts and a strict filtering algorithm. Evaluations by professional psychological counselors indicate that DESC has a superior ability to diagnose depression than existing data. Additionally, conversational quality evaluation reveals that DESC maintains fluent, consistent, and coherent dialogues.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06044v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Seungyeon Seo, Gary Geunbae Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Tables with Numbers, with Numbers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06062</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06062v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper is a critical reflection on the epistemic culture of contemporary computational linguistics, framed in the context of its growing obsession with tables with numbers. We argue against tables with numbers on the basis of their epistemic irrelevance, their environmental impact, their role in enabling and exacerbating social inequalities, and their deep ties to commercial applications and profit-driven research. We substantiate our arguments with empirical evidence drawn from a meta-analysis of computational linguistics research over the last decade.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06062v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Konstantinos Kogkalidis, Stergios Chatzikyriakidis</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Investigation Into Explainable Audio Hate Speech Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06065</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06065v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Research on hate speech has predominantly revolved around detection and interpretation from textual inputs, leaving verbal content largely unexplored. While there has been limited exploration into hate speech detection within verbal acoustic speech inputs, the aspect of interpretability has been overlooked. Therefore, we introduce a new task of explainable audio hate speech detection. Specifically, we aim to identify the precise time intervals, referred to as audio frame-level rationales, which serve as evidence for hate speech classification. Towards this end, we propose two different approaches: cascading and End-to-End (E2E). The cascading approach initially converts audio to transcripts, identifies hate speech within these transcripts, and subsequently locates the corresponding audio time frames. Conversely, the E2E approach processes audio utterances directly, which allows it to pinpoint hate speech within specific time frames. Additionally, due to the lack of explainable audio hate speech datasets that include audio frame-level rationales, we curated a synthetic audio dataset to train our models. We further validated these models on actual human speech utterances and found that the E2E approach outperforms the cascading method in terms of the audio frame Intersection over Union (IoU) metric. Furthermore, we observed that including frame-level rationales significantly enhances hate speech detection accuracy for the E2E approach.
  \textbf{Disclaimer} The reader may encounter content of an offensive or hateful nature. However, given the nature of the work, this cannot be avoided.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06065v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jinmyeong An, Wonjun Lee, Yejin Jeon, Jungseul Ok, Yunsu Kim, Gary Geunbae Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Decision Making Models Through Language Model Regime</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06087</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06087v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We propose a novel approach for decision making problems leveraging the generalization capabilities of large language models (LLMs). Traditional methods such as expert systems, planning algorithms, and reinforcement learning often exhibit limited generalization, typically requiring the training of new models for each unique task. In contrast, LLMs demonstrate remarkable success in generalizing across varied language tasks, inspiring a new strategy for training decision making models. Our approach, referred to as "Learning then Using" (LTU), entails a two-stage process. Initially, the \textit{learning} phase develops a robust foundational decision making model by integrating diverse knowledge from various domains and decision making contexts. The subsequent \textit{using} phase refines this foundation model for specific decision making scenarios. Distinct from other studies that employ LLMs for decision making through supervised learning, our LTU method embraces a versatile training methodology that combines broad pre-training with targeted fine-tuning. Experiments in e-commerce domains such as advertising and search optimization have shown that LTU approach outperforms traditional supervised learning regimes in decision making capabilities and generalization. The LTU approach is the first practical training architecture for both single-step and multi-step decision making tasks combined with LLMs, which can be applied beyond game and robot domains. It provides a robust and adaptable framework for decision making, enhances the effectiveness and flexibility of various systems in tackling various challenges.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06087v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yu Zhang, Haoxiang Liu, Feijun Jiang, Weihua Luo, Kaifu Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How ChatGPT Changed the Media's Narratives on AI: A Semi-Automated Narrative Analysis Through Frame Semantics</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06120</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06120v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The recent explosion of attention to AI is arguably one of the biggest in the technology's media coverage. To investigate the effects it has on the discourse, we perform a mixed-method frame semantics-based analysis on a dataset of more than 49,000 sentences collected from 5846 news articles that mention AI. The dataset covers the twelve-month period centred around the launch of OpenAI's chatbot ChatGPT and is collected from the most visited open-access English-language news publishers. Our findings indicate that during the half year succeeding the launch, media attention rose tenfold$\unicode{x2014}$from already historically high levels. During this period, discourse has become increasingly centred around experts and political leaders, and AI has become more closely associated with dangers and risks. A deeper review of the data also suggests a qualitative shift in the types of threat AI is thought to represent, as well as the anthropomorphic qualities ascribed to it.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06120v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Igor Ryazanov, Carl \"Ohman, Johanna Bj\"orklund</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utilize Transformers for translating Wikipedia category names</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06124</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06124v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: On Wikipedia, articles are categorized to aid readers in navigating content efficiently. The manual creation of new categories can be laborious and time-intensive. To tackle this issue, we built language models to translate Wikipedia categories from English to Vietnamese with a dataset containing 15,000 English-Vietnamese category pairs. Subsequently, small to medium-scale Transformer pre-trained models with a sequence-to-sequence architecture were fine-tuned for category translation. The experiments revealed that OPUS-MT-en-vi surpassed other models, attaining the highest performance with a BLEU score of 0.73, despite its smaller model storage. We expect our paper to be an alternative solution for translation tasks with limited computer resources.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06124v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hoang-Thang Ta, Quoc Thang La</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Med42-v2: A Suite of Clinical LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06142</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06142v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Med42-v2 introduces a suite of clinical large language models (LLMs) designed to address the limitations of generic models in healthcare settings. These models are built on Llama3 architecture and fine-tuned using specialized clinical data. They underwent multi-stage preference alignment to effectively respond to natural prompts. While generic models are often preference-aligned to avoid answering clinical queries as a precaution, Med42-v2 is specifically trained to overcome this limitation, enabling its use in clinical settings. Med42-v2 models demonstrate superior performance compared to the original Llama3 models in both 8B and 70B parameter configurations and GPT-4 across various medical benchmarks. These LLMs are developed to understand clinical queries, perform reasoning tasks, and provide valuable assistance in clinical environments. The models are now publicly available at \href{https://huggingface.co/m42-health}{https://huggingface.co/m42-health}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06142v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Cl\'ement Christophe, Praveen K Kanithi, Tathagata Raha, Shadab Khan, Marco AF Pimentel</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LipidBERT: A Lipid Language Model Pre-trained on METiS de novo Lipid Library</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06150</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06150v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this study, we generate and maintain a database of 10 million virtual lipids through METiS's in-house de novo lipid generation algorithms and lipid virtual screening techniques. These virtual lipids serve as a corpus for pre-training, lipid representation learning, and downstream task knowledge transfer, culminating in state-of-the-art LNP property prediction performance. We propose LipidBERT, a BERT-like model pre-trained with the Masked Language Model (MLM) and various secondary tasks. Additionally, we compare the performance of embeddings generated by LipidBERT and PhatGPT, our GPT-like lipid generation model, on downstream tasks. The proposed bilingual LipidBERT model operates in two languages: the language of ionizable lipid pre-training, using in-house dry-lab lipid structures, and the language of LNP fine-tuning, utilizing in-house LNP wet-lab data. This dual capability positions LipidBERT as a key AI-based filter for future screening tasks, including new versions of METiS de novo lipid libraries and, more importantly, candidates for in vivo testing for orgran-targeting LNPs. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first successful demonstration of the capability of a pre-trained language model on virtual lipids and its effectiveness in downstream tasks using web-lab data. This work showcases the clever utilization of METiS's in-house de novo lipid library as well as the power of dry-wet lab integration.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06150v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>physics.chem-ph</category>
      <category>q-bio.BM</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tianhao Yu, Cai Yao, Zhuorui Sun, Feng Shi, Lin Zhang, Kangjie Lyu, Xuan Bai, Andong Liu, Xicheng Zhang, Jiali Zou, Wenshou Wang, Chris Lai, Kai Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Structural Diversity of Blackbox LLMs via Chain-of-Specification Prompting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06186</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06186v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The capability to generate diverse text is a key challenge facing large language models (LLMs). Thus far, diversity has been studied via metrics such as $n$-gram diversity or diversity of BERT embeddings. However, for these kinds of diversity, the user has little control over the dimensions along which diversity is considered. For example, in the poetry domain, one might desire diversity in terms of rhyme and meter, whereas in the code domain, one might desire diversity in terms of the kinds of expressions used to solve a problem. We propose a diversity metric called structural diversity, where the user provides a mapping from generated text to features capturing the kinds of diversity that they care about. In addition, we propose a novel strategy called chain-of-specification (CoS) prompting for improving diversity by first having the LLM generate a specification encoding one instance of structural features, and then prompting the LLM to generate text that satisfies these features; notably, our strategy works with blackbox LLMs. In our experiments, we show that for structural diversity in the poetry and code domains, CoS significantly improves diversity compared to several baselines.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06186v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Halley Young, Yimeng Zeng, Jacob Gardner, Osbert Bastani</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mutual Reasoning Makes Smaller LLMs Stronger Problem-Solvers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06195</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06195v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper introduces rStar, a self-play mutual reasoning approach that significantly improves reasoning capabilities of small language models (SLMs) without fine-tuning or superior models. rStar decouples reasoning into a self-play mutual generation-discrimination process. First, a target SLM augments the Monte Carlo Tree Search (MCTS) with a rich set of human-like reasoning actions to construct higher quality reasoning trajectories. Next, another SLM, with capabilities similar to the target SLM, acts as a discriminator to verify each trajectory generated by the target SLM. The mutually agreed reasoning trajectories are considered mutual consistent, thus are more likely to be correct. Extensive experiments across five SLMs demonstrate rStar can effectively solve diverse reasoning problems, including GSM8K, GSM-Hard, MATH, SVAMP, and StrategyQA. Remarkably, rStar boosts GSM8K accuracy from 12.51% to 63.91% for LLaMA2-7B, from 36.46% to 81.88% for Mistral-7B, from 74.53% to 91.13% for LLaMA3-8B-Instruct. Code will be available at https://github.com/zhentingqi/rStar.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06195v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhenting Qi, Mingyuan Ma, Jiahang Xu, Li Lyna Zhang, Fan Yang, Mao Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Effects of Steering Latent Representation for Large Language Model Unlearning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06223</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06223v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Representation Misdirection for Unlearning (RMU), which steers model representation in the intermediate layer to a target random representation, is an effective method for large language model (LLM) unlearning. Despite its high performance, the underlying cause and explanation remain underexplored. In this paper, we first theoretically demonstrate that steering forget representations in the intermediate layer reduces token confidence, causing LLMs to generate wrong or nonsense responses. Second, we investigate how the coefficient influences the alignment of forget-sample representations with the random direction and hint at the optimal coefficient values for effective unlearning across different network layers. Third, we show that RMU unlearned models are robust against adversarial jailbreak attacks. Last, our empirical analysis shows that RMU is less effective when applied to the middle and later layers in LLMs. To resolve this drawback, we propose Adaptive RMU -- a simple yet effective alternative method that makes unlearning effective with most layers. Extensive experiments demonstrate that Adaptive RMU significantly improves the unlearning performance compared to prior art while incurring no additional computational cost.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06223v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dang Huu-Tien, Trung-Tin Pham, Hoang Thanh-Tung, Naoya Inoue</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FLEURS-R: A Restored Multilingual Speech Corpus for Generation Tasks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06227</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06227v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper introduces FLEURS-R, a speech restoration applied version of the Few-shot Learning Evaluation of Universal Representations of Speech (FLEURS) corpus. FLEURS-R maintains an N-way parallel speech corpus in 102 languages as FLEURS, with improved audio quality and fidelity by applying the speech restoration model Miipher. The aim of FLEURS-R is to advance speech technology in more languages and catalyze research including text-to-speech (TTS) and other speech generation tasks in low-resource languages. Comprehensive evaluations with the restored speech and TTS baseline models trained from the new corpus show that the new corpus obtained significantly improved speech quality while maintaining the semantic contents of the speech. The corpus is publicly released via Hugging Face.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06227v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>INTERSPEECH 2024</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Min Ma, Yuma Koizumi, Shigeki Karita, Heiga Zen, Jason Riesa, Haruko Ishikawa, Michiel Bacchiani</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Context-aware Visual Storytelling with Visual Prefix Tuning and Contrastive Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06259</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06259v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Visual storytelling systems generate multi-sentence stories from image sequences. In this task, capturing contextual information and bridging visual variation bring additional challenges. We propose a simple yet effective framework that leverages the generalization capabilities of pretrained foundation models, only training a lightweight vision-language mapping network to connect modalities, while incorporating context to enhance coherence. We introduce a multimodal contrastive objective that also improves visual relevance and story informativeness. Extensive experimental results, across both automatic metrics and human evaluations, demonstrate that the stories generated by our framework are diverse, coherent, informative, and interesting.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06259v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yingjin Song, Denis Paperno, Albert Gatt</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FuxiTranyu: A Multilingual Large Language Model Trained with Balanced Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06273</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06273v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated prowess in a wide range of tasks. However, many LLMs exhibit significant performance discrepancies between high- and low-resource languages. To mitigate this challenge, we present FuxiTranyu, an open-source multilingual LLM, which is designed to satisfy the need of the research community for balanced and high-performing multilingual capabilities. FuxiTranyu-8B, the base model with 8 billion parameters, is trained from scratch on a meticulously balanced multilingual data repository that contains 600 billion tokens covering 43 natural languages and 16 programming languages. In addition to the base model, we also develop two instruction-tuned models: FuxiTranyu-8B-SFT that is fine-tuned on a diverse multilingual instruction dataset, and FuxiTranyu-8B-DPO that is further refined with DPO on a preference dataset for enhanced alignment ability. Extensive experiments on a wide range of multilingual benchmarks demonstrate the competitive performance of FuxiTranyu against existing multilingual LLMs, e.g., BLOOM-7B, PolyLM-13B, Llama-2-Chat-7B and Mistral-7B-Instruct. Interpretability analyses at both the neuron and representation level suggest that FuxiTranyu is able to learn consistent multilingual representations across different languages. To promote further research into multilingual LLMs and their working mechanisms, we release both the base and instruction-tuned FuxiTranyu models together with 58 pretraining checkpoints at HuggingFace and Github.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06273v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haoran Sun, Renren Jin, Shaoyang Xu, Leiyu Pan,  Supryadi, Menglong Cui, Jiangcun Dui, Yikun Lei, Lei Yang, Ling Shi, Juesi Xiao, Shaolin Zhu, Deyi Xiong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review-driven Personalized Preference Reasoning with Large Language Models for Recommendation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06276</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06276v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent advancements in Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated exceptional performance across a wide range of tasks, generating significant interest in their application to recommendation systems. However, existing methods have not fully capitalized on the potential of LLMs, often constrained by limited input information or failing to fully utilize their advanced reasoning capabilities. To address these limitations, we introduce EXP3RT, a novel LLM-based recommender designed to leverage rich preference information contained in user and item reviews. EXP3RT is basically fine-tuned through distillation from a teacher LLM to perform three key tasks in order: EXP3RT first extracts and encapsulates essential subjective preferences from raw reviews, aggregates and summarizes them according to specific criteria to create user and item profiles. It then generates detailed step-by-step reasoning followed by predicted rating, i.e., reasoning-enhanced rating prediction, by considering both subjective and objective information from user/item profiles and item descriptions. This personalized preference reasoning from EXP3RT enhances rating prediction accuracy and also provides faithful and reasonable explanations for recommendation. Extensive experiments show that EXP3RT outperforms existing methods on both rating prediction and candidate item reranking for top-k recommendation, while significantly enhancing the explainability of recommendation systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06276v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jieyong Kim, Hyunseo Kim, Hyunjin Cho, SeongKu Kang, Buru Chang, Jinyoung Yeo, Dongha Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MovieSum: An Abstractive Summarization Dataset for Movie Screenplays</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06281</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06281v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Movie screenplay summarization is challenging, as it requires an understanding of long input contexts and various elements unique to movies. Large language models have shown significant advancements in document summarization, but they often struggle with processing long input contexts. Furthermore, while television transcripts have received attention in recent studies, movie screenplay summarization remains underexplored. To stimulate research in this area, we present a new dataset, MovieSum, for abstractive summarization of movie screenplays. This dataset comprises 2200 movie screenplays accompanied by their Wikipedia plot summaries. We manually formatted the movie screenplays to represent their structural elements. Compared to existing datasets, MovieSum possesses several distinctive features: (1) It includes movie screenplays, which are longer than scripts of TV episodes. (2) It is twice the size of previous movie screenplay datasets. (3) It provides metadata with IMDb IDs to facilitate access to additional external knowledge. We also show the results of recently released large language models applied to summarization on our dataset to provide a detailed baseline.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06281v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rohit Saxena, Frank Keller</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthetic Patient-Physician Dialogue Generation from Clinical Notes Using LLM</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06285</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06285v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Medical dialogue systems (MDS) enhance patient-physician communication, improve healthcare accessibility, and reduce costs. However, acquiring suitable data to train these systems poses significant challenges. Privacy concerns prevent the use of real conversations, necessitating synthetic alternatives. Synthetic dialogue generation from publicly available clinical notes offers a promising solution to this issue, providing realistic data while safeguarding privacy. Our approach, SynDial, uses a single LLM iteratively with zero-shot prompting and a feedback loop to generate and refine high-quality synthetic dialogues. The feedback consists of weighted evaluation scores for similarity and extractiveness. The iterative process ensures dialogues meet predefined thresholds, achieving superior extractiveness as a result of the feedback loop. Additionally, evaluation shows that the generated dialogues excel in factuality metric compared to the baselines and has comparable diversity scores with GPT4.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06285v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Trisha Das, Dina Albassam, Jimeng Sun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long-Form Answers to Visual Questions from Blind and Low Vision People</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06303</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06303v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Vision language models can now generate long-form answers to questions about images - long-form visual question answers (LFVQA). We contribute VizWiz-LF, a dataset of long-form answers to visual questions posed by blind and low vision (BLV) users. VizWiz-LF contains 4.2k long-form answers to 600 visual questions, collected from human expert describers and six VQA models. We develop and annotate functional roles of sentences of LFVQA and demonstrate that long-form answers contain information beyond the question answer such as explanations and suggestions. We further conduct automatic and human evaluations with BLV and sighted people to evaluate long-form answers. BLV people perceive both human-written and generated long-form answers to be plausible, but generated answers often hallucinate incorrect visual details, especially for unanswerable visual questions (e.g., blurry or irrelevant images). To reduce hallucinations, we evaluate the ability of VQA models to abstain from answering unanswerable questions across multiple prompting strategies.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06303v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mina Huh, Fangyuan Xu, Yi-Hao Peng, Chongyan Chen, Hansika Murugu, Danna Gurari, Eunsol Choi, Amy Pavel</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Animate, or Inanimate, That is the Question for Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06332</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06332v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The cognitive essence of humans is deeply intertwined with the concept of animacy, which plays an essential role in shaping their memory, vision, and multi-layered language understanding. Although animacy appears in language via nuanced constraints on verbs and adjectives, it is also learned and refined through extralinguistic information. Similarly, we assume that the LLMs' limited abilities to understand natural language when processing animacy are motivated by the fact that these models are trained exclusively on text.
  Hence, the question this paper aims to answer arises: can LLMs, in their digital wisdom, process animacy in a similar way to what humans would do? We then propose a systematic analysis via prompting approaches. In particular, we probe different LLMs by prompting them using animate, inanimate, usual, and stranger contexts. Results reveal that, although LLMs have been trained predominantly on textual data, they exhibit human-like behavior when faced with typical animate and inanimate entities in alignment with earlier studies. Hence, LLMs can adapt to understand unconventional situations by recognizing oddities as animated without needing to interface with unspoken cognitive triggers humans rely on to break down animations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06332v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Leonardo Ranaldi, Giulia Pucci, Fabio Massimo Zanzotto</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FastFiD: Improve Inference Efficiency of Open Domain Question Answering via Sentence Selection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06333</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06333v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Open Domain Question Answering (ODQA) has been advancing rapidly in recent times, driven by significant developments in dense passage retrieval and pretrained language models. Current models typically incorporate the FiD framework, which is composed by a neural retriever alongside an encoder-decoder neural reader. In the answer generation process, the retriever will retrieve numerous passages (around 100 for instance), each of which is then individually encoded by the encoder. Subsequently, the decoder makes predictions based on these encoded passages. Nevertheless, this framework can be relatively time-consuming, particularly due to the extensive length of the gathered passages. To address this, we introduce FastFiD in this paper, a novel approach that executes sentence selection on the encoded passages. This aids in retaining valuable sentences while reducing the context length required for generating answers. Experiments on three commonly used datasets (Natural Questions, TriviaQA and ASQA) demonstrate that our method can enhance the inference speed by 2.3X-5.7X, while simultaneously maintaining the model's performance. Moreover, an in-depth analysis of the model's attention reveals that the selected sentences indeed hold a substantial contribution towards the final answer. The codes are publicly available at https://github.com/thunlp/FastFiD.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06333v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yufei Huang, Xu Han, Maosong Sun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LOLgorithm: Integrating Semantic,Syntactic and Contextual Elements for Humor Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06335</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06335v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper explores humor detection through a linguistic lens, prioritizing syntactic, semantic, and contextual features over computational methods in Natural Language Processing. We categorize features into syntactic, semantic, and contextual dimensions, including lexicons, structural statistics, Word2Vec, WordNet, and phonetic style. Our proposed model, Colbert, utilizes BERT embeddings and parallel hidden layers to capture sentence congruity. By combining syntactic, semantic, and contextual features, we train Colbert for humor detection. Feature engineering examines essential syntactic and semantic features alongside BERT embeddings. SHAP interpretations and decision trees identify influential features, revealing that a holistic approach improves humor detection accuracy on unseen data. Integrating linguistic cues from different dimensions enhances the model's ability to understand humor complexity beyond traditional computational methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06335v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tanisha Khurana, Kaushik Pillalamarri, Vikram Pande, Munindar Singh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting Multi-Modal LLM Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05334</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05334v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: With the advent of multi-modal large language models (MLLMs), datasets used for visual question answering (VQA) and referring expression comprehension have seen a resurgence. However, the most popular datasets used to evaluate MLLMs are some of the earliest ones created, and they have many known problems, including extreme bias, spurious correlations, and an inability to permit fine-grained analysis. In this paper, we pioneer evaluating recent MLLMs (LLaVA 1.5, LLaVA-NeXT, BLIP2, InstructBLIP, GPT-4V, and GPT-4o) on datasets designed to address weaknesses in earlier ones. We assess three VQA datasets: 1) TDIUC, which permits fine-grained analysis on 12 question types; 2) TallyQA, which has simple and complex counting questions; and 3) DVQA, which requires optical character recognition for chart understanding. We also study VQDv1, a dataset that requires identifying all image regions that satisfy a given query. Our experiments reveal the weaknesses of many MLLMs that have not previously been reported. Our code is integrated into the widely used LAVIS framework for MLLM evaluation, enabling the rapid assessment of future MLLMs. Project webpage: https://kevinlujian.github.io/MLLM_Evaluations/</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05334v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jian Lu, Shikhar Srivastava, Junyu Chen, Robik Shrestha, Manoj Acharya, Kushal Kafle, Christopher Kanan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GEM: Context-Aware Gaze EstiMation with Visual Search Behavior Matching for Chest Radiograph</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05502</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05502v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Gaze estimation is pivotal in human scene comprehension tasks, particularly in medical diagnostic analysis. Eye-tracking technology facilitates the recording of physicians' ocular movements during image interpretation, thereby elucidating their visual attention patterns and information-processing strategies. In this paper, we initially define the context-aware gaze estimation problem in medical radiology report settings. To understand the attention allocation and cognitive behavior of radiologists during the medical image interpretation process, we propose a context-aware Gaze EstiMation (GEM) network that utilizes eye gaze data collected from radiologists to simulate their visual search behavior patterns throughout the image interpretation process. It consists of a context-awareness module, visual behavior graph construction, and visual behavior matching. Within the context-awareness module, we achieve intricate multimodal registration by establishing connections between medical reports and images. Subsequently, for a more accurate simulation of genuine visual search behavior patterns, we introduce a visual behavior graph structure, capturing such behavior through high-order relationships (edges) between gaze points (nodes). To maintain the authenticity of visual behavior, we devise a visual behavior-matching approach, adjusting the high-order relationships between them by matching the graph constructed from real and estimated gaze points. Extensive experiments on four publicly available datasets demonstrate the superiority of GEM over existing methods and its strong generalizability, which also provides a new direction for the effective utilization of diverse modalities in medical image interpretation and enhances the interpretability of models in the field of medical imaging. https://github.com/Tiger-SN/GEM</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05502v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shaonan Liu, Wenting Chen, Jie Liu, Xiaoling Luo, Linlin Shen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Whisper's Recognition Performance for Under-Represented Language Kazakh Leveraging Unpaired Speech and Text</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05554</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05554v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Whisper and other large-scale automatic speech recognition models have made significant progress in performance. However, their performance on many low-resource languages, such as Kazakh, is not satisfactory. It is worth researching how to utilize low-cost data to improve the performance of Whisper on under-represented languages. In this study, we utilized easily accessible unpaired speech and text data and combined the language model GPT with Whisper on Kazakh. We implemented end of transcript (EOT) judgment modification and hallucination penalty to improve the performance of speech recognition. Further, we employed the decoding average token log probability as a criterion to select samples from unlabeled speech data and used pseudo-labeled data to fine-tune the model to further improve its performance. Ultimately, we achieved more than 10\% absolute WER reduction in multiple experiments, and the whole process has the potential to be generalized to other under-represented languages.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05554v1</guid>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jinpeng Li, Yu Pu, Qi Sun, Wei-Qiang Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metacognitive Myopia in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05568</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05568v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) exhibit potentially harmful biases that reinforce culturally inherent stereotypes, cloud moral judgments, or amplify positive evaluations of majority groups. Previous explanations mainly attributed bias in LLMs to human annotators and the selection of training data. Consequently, they have typically been addressed with bottom-up approaches such as reinforcement learning or debiasing corpora. However, these methods only treat the effects of LLM biases by indirectly influencing the model architecture, but do not address the underlying causes in the computational process. Here, we propose metacognitive myopia as a cognitive-ecological framework that can account for a conglomerate of established and emerging LLM biases and provide a lever to address problems in powerful but vulnerable tools. Our theoretical framework posits that a lack of the two components of metacognition, monitoring and control, causes five symptoms of metacognitive myopia in LLMs: integration of invalid tokens and embeddings, susceptibility to redundant information, neglect of base rates in conditional computation, decision rules based on frequency, and inappropriate higher-order statistical inference for nested data structures. As a result, LLMs produce erroneous output that reaches into the daily high-stakes decisions of humans. By introducing metacognitive regulatory processes into LLMs, engineers and scientists can develop precise remedies for the underlying causes of these biases. Our theory sheds new light on flawed human-machine interactions and raises ethical concerns regarding the increasing, imprudent implementation of LLMs in organizational structures.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05568v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>stat.AP</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Florian Scholten, Tobias R. Rebholz, Mandy H\"utter</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VQ-CTAP: Cross-Modal Fine-Grained Sequence Representation Learning for Speech Processing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05758</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05758v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Deep learning has brought significant improvements to the field of cross-modal representation learning. For tasks such as text-to-speech (TTS), voice conversion (VC), and automatic speech recognition (ASR), a cross-modal fine-grained (frame-level) sequence representation is desired, emphasizing the semantic content of the text modality while de-emphasizing the paralinguistic information of the speech modality. We propose a method called "Vector Quantized Contrastive Token-Acoustic Pre-training (VQ-CTAP)", which uses the cross-modal aligned sequence transcoder to bring text and speech into a joint multimodal space, learning how to connect text and speech at the frame level. The proposed VQ-CTAP is a paradigm for cross-modal sequence representation learning, offering a promising solution for fine-grained generation and recognition tasks in speech processing. The VQ-CTAP can be directly applied to VC and ASR tasks without fine-tuning or additional structures. We propose a sequence-aware semantic connector, which connects multiple frozen pre-trained modules for the TTS task, exhibiting a plug-and-play capability. We design a stepping optimization strategy to ensure effective model convergence by gradually injecting and adjusting the influence of various loss components. Furthermore, we propose a semantic-transfer-wise paralinguistic consistency loss to enhance representational capabilities, allowing the model to better generalize to unseen data and capture the nuances of paralinguistic information. In addition, VQ-CTAP achieves high-compression speech coding at a rate of 25Hz from 24kHz input waveforms, which is a 960-fold reduction in the sampling rate. The audio demo is available at https://qiangchunyu.github.io/VQCTAP/</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05758v1</guid>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chunyu Qiang, Wang Geng, Yi Zhao, Ruibo Fu, Tao Wang, Cheng Gong, Tianrui Wang, Qiuyu Liu, Jiangyan Yi, Zhengqi Wen, Chen Zhang, Hao Che, Longbiao Wang, Jianwu Dang, Jianhua Tao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GlyphPattern: An Abstract Pattern Recognition for Vision-Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05894</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05894v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Vision-Language Models (VLMs) building upon the foundation of powerful large language models have made rapid progress in reasoning across visual and textual data. While VLMs perform well on vision tasks that they are trained on, our results highlight key challenges in abstract pattern recognition. We present GlyphPattern, a 954 item dataset that pairs 318 human-written descriptions of visual patterns from 40 writing systems with three visual presentation styles.
  GlyphPattern evaluates abstract pattern recognition in VLMs, requiring models to understand and judge natural language descriptions of visual patterns. GlyphPattern patterns are drawn from a large-scale cognitive science investigation of human writing systems; as a result, they are rich in spatial reference and compositionality. Our experiments show that GlyphPattern is challenging for state-of-the-art VLMs (GPT-4o achieves only 55% accuracy), with marginal gains from few-shot prompting. Our detailed error analysis reveals challenges at multiple levels, including visual processing, natural language understanding, and pattern generalization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05894v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zixuan Wu, Yoolim Kim, Carolyn Jane Anderson</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlling Surprisal in Music Generation via Information Content Curve Matching</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06022</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06022v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In recent years, the quality and public interest in music generation systems have grown, encouraging research into various ways to control these systems. We propose a novel method for controlling surprisal in music generation using sequence models. To achieve this goal, we define a metric called Instantaneous Information Content (IIC). The IIC serves as a proxy function for the perceived musical surprisal (as estimated from a probabilistic model) and can be calculated at any point within a music piece. This enables the comparison of surprisal across different musical content even if the musical events occur in irregular time intervals. We use beam search to generate musical material whose IIC curve closely approximates a given target IIC. We experimentally show that the IIC correlates with harmonic and rhythmic complexity and note density. The correlation decreases with the length of the musical context used for estimating the IIC. Finally, we conduct a qualitative user study to test if human listeners can identify the IIC curves that have been used as targets when generating the respective musical material. We provide code for creating IIC interpolations and IIC visualizations on https://github.com/muthissar/iic.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06022v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mathias Rose Bjare, Stefan Lattner, Gerhard Widmer</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ARPA: A Novel Hybrid Model for Advancing Visual Word Disambiguation Using Large Language Models and Transformers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06040</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06040v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In the rapidly evolving fields of natural language processing and computer vision, Visual Word Sense Disambiguation (VWSD) stands as a critical, yet challenging task. The quest for models that can seamlessly integrate and interpret multimodal data is more pressing than ever. Imagine a system that can understand language with the depth and nuance of human cognition, while simultaneously interpreting the rich visual context of the world around it.
  We present ARPA, an architecture that fuses the unparalleled contextual understanding of large language models with the advanced feature extraction capabilities of transformers, which then pass through a custom Graph Neural Network (GNN) layer to learn intricate relationships and subtle nuances within the data. This innovative architecture not only sets a new benchmark in visual word disambiguation but also introduces a versatile framework poised to transform how linguistic and visual data interact by harnessing the synergistic strengths of its components, ensuring robust performance even in the most complex disambiguation scenarios. Through a series of experiments and comparative analysis, we reveal the substantial advantages of our model, underscoring its potential to redefine standards in the field. Beyond its architectural prowess, our architecture excels through experimental enrichments, including sophisticated data augmentation and multi-modal training techniques.
  ARPA's introduction marks a significant milestone in visual word disambiguation, offering a compelling solution that bridges the gap between linguistic and visual modalities. We invite researchers and practitioners to explore the capabilities of our model, envisioning a future where such hybrid models drive unprecedented advancements in artificial intelligence.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06040v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aristi Papastavrou, Maria Lymperaiou, Giorgos Stamou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Algorithms for Compositional Text Processing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06061</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06061v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Quantum computing and AI have found a fruitful intersection in the field of natural language processing. We focus on the recently proposed DisCoCirc framework for natural language, and propose a quantum adaptation, QDisCoCirc. This is motivated by a compositional approach to rendering AI interpretable: the behavior of the whole can be understood in terms of the behavior of parts, and the way they are put together. For the model-native primitive operation of text similarity, we derive quantum algorithms for fault-tolerant quantum computers to solve the task of question-answering within QDisCoCirc, and show that this is BQP-hard; note that we do not consider the complexity of question-answering in other natural language processing models. Assuming widely-held conjectures, implementing the proposed model classically would require super-polynomial resources. Therefore, it could provide a meaningful demonstration of the power of practical quantum processors. The model construction builds on previous work in compositional quantum natural language processing. Word embeddings are encoded as parameterized quantum circuits, and compositionality here means that the quantum circuits compose according to the linguistic structure of the text. We outline a method for evaluating the model on near-term quantum processors, and elsewhere we report on a recent implementation of this on quantum hardware. In addition, we adapt a quantum algorithm for the closest vector problem to obtain a Grover-like speedup in the fault-tolerant regime for our model. This provides an unconditional quadratic speedup over any classical algorithm in certain circumstances, which we will verify empirically in future work.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06061v1</guid>
      <category>quant-ph</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.4204/EPTCS.406.8</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>EPTCS 406, 2024, pp. 162-196</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Tuomas Laakkonen (Quantinuum), Konstantinos Meichanetzidis (Quantinuum), Bob Coecke (Quantinuum)</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anchored Preference Optimization and Contrastive Revisions: Addressing Underspecification in Alignment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06266</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06266v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) are often aligned using contrastive alignment objectives and preference pair datasets. The interaction between model, paired data, and objective makes alignment a complicated procedure, sometimes producing subpar results. We study this and find that (i) preference data gives a better learning signal when the underlying responses are contrastive, and (ii) alignment objectives lead to better performance when they specify more control over the model during training. Based on these insights, we introduce Contrastive Learning from AI Revisions (CLAIR), a data-creation method which leads to more contrastive preference pairs, and Anchored Preference Optimization (APO), a controllable and more stable alignment objective. We align Llama-3-8B-Instruct using various comparable datasets and alignment objectives and measure MixEval-Hard scores, which correlate highly with human judgments. The CLAIR preferences lead to the strongest performance out of all datasets, and APO consistently outperforms less controllable objectives. Our best model, trained on 32K CLAIR preferences with APO, improves Llama-3-8B-Instruct by 7.65%, closing the gap with GPT4-turbo by 45%. Our code is available at https://github.com/ContextualAI/CLAIR_and_APO.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06266v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Karel D'Oosterlinck, Winnie Xu, Chris Develder, Thomas Demeester, Amanpreet Singh, Christopher Potts, Douwe Kiela, Shikib Mehri</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The AI Scientist: Towards Fully Automated Open-Ended Scientific Discovery</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06292</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06292v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: One of the grand challenges of artificial general intelligence is developing agents capable of conducting scientific research and discovering new knowledge. While frontier models have already been used as aids to human scientists, e.g. for brainstorming ideas, writing code, or prediction tasks, they still conduct only a small part of the scientific process. This paper presents the first comprehensive framework for fully automatic scientific discovery, enabling frontier large language models to perform research independently and communicate their findings. We introduce The AI Scientist, which generates novel research ideas, writes code, executes experiments, visualizes results, describes its findings by writing a full scientific paper, and then runs a simulated review process for evaluation. In principle, this process can be repeated to iteratively develop ideas in an open-ended fashion, acting like the human scientific community. We demonstrate its versatility by applying it to three distinct subfields of machine learning: diffusion modeling, transformer-based language modeling, and learning dynamics. Each idea is implemented and developed into a full paper at a cost of less than $15 per paper. To evaluate the generated papers, we design and validate an automated reviewer, which we show achieves near-human performance in evaluating paper scores. The AI Scientist can produce papers that exceed the acceptance threshold at a top machine learning conference as judged by our automated reviewer. This approach signifies the beginning of a new era in scientific discovery in machine learning: bringing the transformative benefits of AI agents to the entire research process of AI itself, and taking us closer to a world where endless affordable creativity and innovation can be unleashed on the world's most challenging problems. Our code is open-sourced at https://github.com/SakanaAI/AI-Scientist</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06292v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chris Lu, Cong Lu, Robert Tjarko Lange, Jakob Foerster, Jeff Clune, David Ha</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VisualAgentBench: Towards Large Multimodal Models as Visual Foundation Agents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06327</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06327v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large Multimodal Models (LMMs) have ushered in a new era in artificial intelligence, merging capabilities in both language and vision to form highly capable Visual Foundation Agents. These agents are postulated to excel across a myriad of tasks, potentially approaching general artificial intelligence. However, existing benchmarks fail to sufficiently challenge or showcase the full potential of LMMs in complex, real-world environments. To address this gap, we introduce VisualAgentBench (VAB), a comprehensive and pioneering benchmark specifically designed to train and evaluate LMMs as visual foundation agents across diverse scenarios, including Embodied, Graphical User Interface, and Visual Design, with tasks formulated to probe the depth of LMMs' understanding and interaction capabilities. Through rigorous testing across nine proprietary LMM APIs and eight open models, we demonstrate the considerable yet still developing agent capabilities of these models. Additionally, VAB constructs a trajectory training set constructed through hybrid methods including Program-based Solvers, LMM Agent Bootstrapping, and Human Demonstrations, promoting substantial performance improvements in LMMs through behavior cloning. Our work not only aims to benchmark existing models but also provides a solid foundation for future development into visual foundation agents. Code, train \&amp; test data, and part of fine-tuned open LMMs are available at \url{https://github.com/THUDM/VisualAgentBench}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06327v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiao Liu, Tianjie Zhang, Yu Gu, Iat Long Iong, Yifan Xu, Xixuan Song, Shudan Zhang, Hanyu Lai, Xinyi Liu, Hanlin Zhao, Jiadai Sun, Xinyue Yang, Yu Yang, Zehan Qi, Shuntian Yao, Xueqiao Sun, Siyi Cheng, Qinkai Zheng, Hao Yu, Hanchen Zhang, Wenyi Hong, Ming Ding, Lihang Pan, Xiaotao Gu, Aohan Zeng, Zhengxiao Du, Chan Hee Song, Yu Su, Yuxiao Dong, Jie Tang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AutoTemplate: A Simple Recipe for Lexically Constrained Text Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2211.08387</link>
      <description>arXiv:2211.08387v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Lexically constrained text generation is one of the constrained text generation tasks, which aims to generate text that covers all the given constraint lexicons. While the existing approaches tackle this problem using a lexically constrained beam search algorithm or dedicated model using non-autoregressive decoding, there is a trade-off between the generated text quality and the hard constraint satisfaction. We introduce AutoTemplate, a simple yet effective lexically constrained text generation framework divided into template generation and lexicalization tasks. The template generation is to generate the text with the placeholders, and lexicalization replaces them into the constraint lexicons to perform lexically constrained text generation. We conducted the experiments on two tasks: keywords-to-sentence generations and entity-guided summarization. Experimental results show that the AutoTemplate outperforms the competitive baselines on both tasks while satisfying the hard lexical constraints. The code is available at https://github.com/megagonlabs/autotemplate</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2211.08387v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hayate Iso</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Noisy Pairing and Partial Supervision for Stylized Opinion Summarization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2211.08723</link>
      <description>arXiv:2211.08723v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Opinion summarization research has primarily focused on generating summaries reflecting important opinions from customer reviews without paying much attention to the writing style. In this paper, we propose the stylized opinion summarization task, which aims to generate a summary of customer reviews in the desired (e.g., professional) writing style. To tackle the difficulty in collecting customer and professional review pairs, we develop a non-parallel training framework, Noisy Pairing and Partial Supervision (NAPA), which trains a stylized opinion summarization system from non-parallel customer and professional review sets. We create a benchmark ProSum by collecting customer and professional reviews from Yelp and Michelin. Experimental results on ProSum and FewSum demonstrate that our non-parallel training framework consistently improves both automatic and human evaluations, successfully building a stylized opinion summarization model that can generate professionally-written summaries from customer reviews. The code is available at https://github.com/megagonlabs/napa</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2211.08723v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hayate Iso, Xiaolan Wang, Yoshi Suhara</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How would Stance Detection Techniques Evolve after the Launch of ChatGPT?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2212.14548</link>
      <description>arXiv:2212.14548v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Stance detection refers to the task of extracting the standpoint (Favor, Against or Neither) towards a target in given texts. Such research gains increasing attention with the proliferation of social media contents. The conventional framework of handling stance detection is converting it into text classification tasks. Deep learning models have already replaced rule-based models and traditional machine learning models in solving such problems. Current deep neural networks are facing two main challenges which are insufficient labeled data and information in social media posts and the unexplainable nature of deep learning models. A new pre-trained language model chatGPT was launched on Nov 30, 2022. For the stance detection tasks, our experiments show that ChatGPT can achieve SOTA or similar performance for commonly used datasets including SemEval-2016 and P-Stance. At the same time, ChatGPT can provide explanation for its own prediction, which is beyond the capability of any existing model. The explanations for the cases it cannot provide classification results are especially useful. ChatGPT has the potential to be the best AI model for stance detection tasks in NLP, or at least change the research paradigm of this field. ChatGPT also opens up the possibility of building explanatory AI for stance detection.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2212.14548v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bowen Zhang, Daijun Ding, Liwen Jing, Genan Dai, Nan Yin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PK-ICR: Persona-Knowledge Interactive Context Retrieval for Grounded Dialogue</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2302.06674</link>
      <description>arXiv:2302.06674v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Identifying relevant persona or knowledge for conversational systems is critical to grounded dialogue response generation. However, each grounding has been mostly researched in isolation with more practical multi-context dialogue tasks introduced in recent works. We define Persona and Knowledge Dual Context Identification as the task to identify persona and knowledge jointly for a given dialogue, which could be of elevated importance in complex multi-context dialogue settings. We develop a novel grounding retrieval method that utilizes all contexts of dialogue simultaneously. Our method requires less computational power via utilizing neural QA retrieval models. We further introduce our novel null-positive rank test which measures ranking performance on semantically dissimilar samples (i.e. hard negatives) in relation to data augmentation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2302.06674v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Minsik Oh, Joosung Lee, Jiwei Li, Guoyin Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accuracy and Political Bias of News Source Credibility Ratings by Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2304.00228</link>
      <description>arXiv:2304.00228v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Search engines increasingly leverage large language models (LLMs) to generate direct answers, and AI chatbots now access the Internet for fresh data. As information curators for billions of users, LLMs must assess the accuracy and reliability of different sources. This paper audits eight widely used LLMs from three major providers -- OpenAI, Google, and Meta -- to evaluate their ability to discern credible and high-quality information sources from low-credibility ones. We find that while LLMs can rate most tested news outlets, larger models more frequently refuse to provide ratings due to insufficient information, whereas smaller models are more prone to hallucination in their ratings. For sources where ratings are provided, LLMs exhibit a high level of agreement among themselves (average Spearman's $\rho = 0.81$), but their ratings align only moderately with human expert evaluations (average $\rho = 0.59$). Analyzing news sources with different political leanings in the US, we observe a liberal bias in credibility ratings yielded by all LLMs in default configurations. Additionally, assigning partisan identities to LLMs consistently results in strong politically congruent bias in the ratings. These findings have important implications for the use of LLMs in curating news and political information.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2304.00228v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kai-Cheng Yang, Filippo Menczer</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inspecting and Editing Knowledge Representations in Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2304.00740</link>
      <description>arXiv:2304.00740v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Neural language models (LMs) represent facts about the world described by text. Sometimes these facts derive from training data (in most LMs, a representation of the word "banana" encodes the fact that bananas are fruits). Sometimes facts derive from input text itself (a representation of the sentence "I poured out the bottle" encodes the fact that the bottle became empty). We describe REMEDI, a method for learning to map statements in natural language to fact encodings in an LM's internal representation system. REMEDI encodings can be used as knowledge editors: when added to LM hidden representations, they modify downstream generation to be consistent with new facts. REMEDI encodings may also be used as probes: when compared to LM representations, they reveal which properties LMs already attribute to mentioned entities, in some cases making it possible to predict when LMs will generate outputs that conflict with background knowledge or input text. REMEDI thus links work on probing, prompting, and LM editing, and offers steps toward general tools for fine-grained inspection and control of knowledge in LMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2304.00740v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Evan Hernandez, Belinda Z. Li, Jacob Andreas</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bot or Human? Detecting ChatGPT Imposters with A Single Question</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2305.06424</link>
      <description>arXiv:2305.06424v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) like GPT-4 have recently demonstrated impressive capabilities in natural language understanding and generation. However, there is a concern that they can be misused for malicious purposes, such as fraud or denial-of-service attacks. Therefore, it is crucial to develop methods for detecting whether the party involved in a conversation is a bot or a human. In this paper, we propose a framework named FLAIR, Finding Large Language Model Authenticity via a Single Inquiry and Response, to detect conversational bots in an online manner. Specifically, we target a single question scenario that can effectively differentiate human users from bots. The questions are divided into two categories: those that are easy for humans but difficult for bots (e.g., counting, substitution, searching, and ASCII art reasoning), and those that are easy for bots but difficult for humans (e.g., memorization and computation). Our approach shows different strengths of these questions in their effectiveness, providing a new way for online service providers to protect themselves against nefarious activities. Our code and question set are available at https://github.com/hongwang600/FLAIR.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2305.06424v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hong Wang, Xuan Luo, Weizhi Wang, Xifeng Yan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPARSEFIT: Few-shot Prompting with Sparse Fine-tuning for Jointly Generating Predictions and Natural Language Explanations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2305.13235</link>
      <description>arXiv:2305.13235v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Models that generate natural language explanations (NLEs) for their predictions have recently gained increasing interest. However, this approach usually demands large datasets of human-written NLEs for the ground-truth answers at training time, which can be expensive and potentially infeasible for some applications. When only a few NLEs are available (a few-shot setup), fine-tuning pre-trained language models (PLMs) in conjunction with prompt-based learning has recently shown promising results. However, PLMs typically have billions of parameters, making full fine-tuning expensive. We propose SparseFit, a sparse few-shot fine-tuning strategy that leverages discrete prompts to jointly generate predictions and NLEs. We experiment with SparseFit on three sizes of the T5 language model and four datasets and compare it against existing state-of-the-art Parameter-Efficient Fine-Tuning (PEFT) techniques. We find that fine-tuning only 6.8% of the model parameters leads to competitive results for both the task performance and the quality of the generated NLEs compared to full fine-tuning of the model and produces better results on average than other PEFT methods in terms of predictive accuracy and NLE quality.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2305.13235v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>ACL 2024</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Jesus Solano, Mardhiyah Sanni, Oana-Maria Camburu, Pasquale Minervini</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BiomedGPT: A Generalist Vision-Language Foundation Model for Diverse Biomedical Tasks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2305.17100</link>
      <description>arXiv:2305.17100v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Traditional biomedical artificial intelligence (AI) models, designed for specific tasks or modalities, often exhibit limited flexibility in real-world deployment and struggle to utilize holistic information. Generalist AI holds the potential to address these limitations due to its versatility in interpreting different data types and generating tailored outputs for diverse needs. However, existing biomedical generalist AI solutions are typically heavyweight and closed source to researchers, practitioners, and patients. Here, we propose BiomedGPT, the first open-source and lightweight vision-language foundation model, designed as a generalist capable of performing various biomedical tasks. BiomedGPT achieved state-of-the-art results in 16 out of 25 experiments while maintaining a computing-friendly model scale. We also conducted human evaluations to assess the capabilities of BiomedGPT in radiology visual question answering, report generation, and summarization. BiomedGPT exhibits robust prediction ability with a low error rate of 3.8% in question answering, satisfactory performance with an error rate of 8.3% in writing complex radiology reports, and competitive summarization ability with a nearly equivalent preference score to human experts. Our method demonstrates that effective training with diverse data can lead to more practical biomedical AI for improving diagnosis and workflow efficiency.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2305.17100v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1038/s41591-024-03185-2</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Kai Zhang, Rong Zhou, Eashan Adhikarla, Zhiling Yan, Yixin Liu, Jun Yu, Zhengliang Liu, Xun Chen, Brian D. Davison, Hui Ren, Jing Huang, Chen Chen, Yuyin Zhou, Sunyang Fu, Wei Liu, Tianming Liu, Xiang Li, Yong Chen, Lifang He, James Zou, Quanzheng Li, Hongfang Liu, Lichao Sun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking Cognitive Biases in Large Language Models as Evaluators</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2309.17012</link>
      <description>arXiv:2309.17012v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have recently been shown to be effective as automatic evaluators with simple prompting and in-context learning. In this work, we assemble 15 LLMs of four different size ranges and evaluate their output responses by preference ranking from the other LLMs as evaluators, such as System Star is better than System Square. We then evaluate the quality of ranking outputs introducing the Cognitive Bias Benchmark for LLMs as Evaluators (CoBBLEr), a benchmark to measure six different cognitive biases in LLM evaluation outputs, such as the Egocentric bias where a model prefers to rank its own outputs highly in evaluation. We find that LLMs are biased text quality evaluators, exhibiting strong indications on our bias benchmark (average of 40% of comparisons across all models) within each of their evaluations that question their robustness as evaluators. Furthermore, we examine the correlation between human and machine preferences and calculate the average Rank-Biased Overlap (RBO) score to be 49.6%, indicating that machine preferences are misaligned with humans. According to our findings, LLMs may still be unable to be utilized for automatic annotation aligned with human preferences. Our project page is at: https://minnesotanlp.github.io/cobbler.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2309.17012v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ryan Koo, Minhwa Lee, Vipul Raheja, Jong Inn Park, Zae Myung Kim, Dongyeop Kang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LongLLMLingua: Accelerating and Enhancing LLMs in Long Context Scenarios via Prompt Compression</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.06839</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.06839v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In long context scenarios, large language models (LLMs) face three main challenges: higher computational cost, performance reduction, and position bias. Research indicates that LLM performance hinges on the density and position of key information in the input prompt. Inspired by these findings, we propose LongLLMLingua for prompt compression towards improving LLMs' perception of the key information to simultaneously address the three challenges. Our extensive evaluation across various long context scenarios demonstrates that LongLLMLingua not only enhances performance but also significantly reduces costs and latency. For instance, in the NaturalQuestions benchmark, LongLLMLingua boosts performance by up to 21.4% with around 4x fewer tokens in GPT-3.5-Turbo, leading to substantial cost savings. It achieves a 94.0% cost reduction in the LooGLE benchmark. Moreover, when compressing prompts of about 10k tokens at ratios of 2x-6x, LongLLMLingua can accelerate end-to-end latency by 1.4x-2.6x. Our code is available at https://aka.ms/LongLLMLingua.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.06839v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Huiqiang Jiang, Qianhui Wu, Xufang Luo, Dongsheng Li, Chin-Yew Lin, Yuqing Yang, Lili Qiu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ExpNote: Black-box Large Language Models are Better Task Solvers with Experience Notebook</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.07032</link>
      <description>arXiv:2311.07032v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Black-box Large Language Models (LLMs) have shown great power in solving various tasks and are considered general problem solvers. However, LLMs still fail in many specific tasks although understand the task instruction. In this paper, we focus on the problem of boosting the ability of black-box LLMs to solve downstream tasks. We propose ExpNote, an automated framework to help LLMs better adapt to unfamiliar tasks through reflecting and noting experiences from training data and retrieving them from external memory during testing. We evaluate ExpNote on multiple tasks and the experimental results demonstrate that the proposed method significantly improves the performance of black-box LLMs. The data and code are available at https://github.com/forangel2014/ExpNote</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2311.07032v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wangtao Sun, Xuanqing Yu, Shizhu He, Jun Zhao, Kang Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital Socrates: Evaluating LLMs through Explanation Critiques</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.09613</link>
      <description>arXiv:2311.09613v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: While LLMs can provide reasoned explanations along with their answers, the nature and quality of those explanations are still poorly understood. In response, our goal is to define a detailed way of characterizing the explanation capabilities of modern models and to create a nuanced, interpretable explanation evaluation tool that can generate such characterizations automatically, without relying on expensive API calls or human annotations. Our approach is to (a) define the new task of explanation critiquing - identifying and categorizing any main flaw in an explanation and providing suggestions to address the flaw, (b) create a sizeable, human-verified dataset for this task, and (c) train an open-source, automatic critique model (called Digital Socrates) using this data. Through quantitative and qualitative analysis, we demonstrate how Digital Socrates is useful for revealing insights about student models by examining their reasoning chains, and how it can provide high-quality, nuanced, automatic evaluation of those model explanations for the first time. Digital Socrates thus fills an important gap in evaluation tools for understanding and improving the explanation behavior of models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2311.09613v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuling Gu, Oyvind Tafjord, Peter Clark</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Impact of Calibration Data in Post-training Quantization and Pruning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.09755</link>
      <description>arXiv:2311.09755v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Quantization and pruning form the foundation of compression for neural networks, enabling efficient inference for large language models (LLMs). Recently, various quantization and pruning techniques have demonstrated remarkable performance in a post-training setting. They rely upon calibration data, a small set of unlabeled examples that are used to generate layer activations. However, no prior work has systematically investigated how the calibration data impacts the effectiveness of model compression methods. In this paper, we present the first extensive empirical study on the effect of calibration data upon LLM performance. We trial a variety of quantization and pruning methods, datasets, tasks, and models. Surprisingly, we find substantial variations in downstream task performance, contrasting existing work that suggests a greater level of robustness to the calibration data. Finally, we make a series of recommendations for the effective use of calibration data in LLM quantization and pruning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2311.09755v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Miles Williams, Nikolaos Aletras</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From text to multimodal: a survey of adversarial example generation in question answering systems</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.16156</link>
      <description>arXiv:2312.16156v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Integrating adversarial machine learning with Question Answering (QA) systems has emerged as a critical area for understanding the vulnerabilities and robustness of these systems. This article aims to comprehensively review adversarial example-generation techniques in the QA field, including textual and multimodal contexts. We examine the techniques employed through systematic categorization, providing a comprehensive, structured review. Beginning with an overview of traditional QA models, we traverse the adversarial example generation by exploring rule-based perturbations and advanced generative models. We then extend our research to include multimodal QA systems, analyze them across various methods, and examine generative models, seq2seq architectures, and hybrid methodologies. Our research grows to different defense strategies, adversarial datasets, and evaluation metrics and illustrates the comprehensive literature on adversarial QA. Finally, the paper considers the future landscape of adversarial question generation, highlighting potential research directions that can advance textual and multimodal QA systems in the context of adversarial challenges.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2312.16156v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1007/s10115-024-02199-z</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Knowl Inf Syst (2024)</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Gulsum Yigit, Mehmet Fatih Amasyali</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MambaByte: Token-free Selective State Space Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.13660</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.13660v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Token-free language models learn directly from raw bytes and remove the inductive bias of subword tokenization. Operating on bytes, however, results in significantly longer sequences. In this setting, standard autoregressive Transformers scale poorly as the effective memory required grows with sequence length. The recent development of the Mamba state space model (SSM) offers an appealing alternative approach with a fixed-sized memory state and efficient decoding. We propose MambaByte, a token-free adaptation of the Mamba SSM trained autoregressively on byte sequences. In terms of modeling, we show MambaByte to be competitive with, and even to outperform, state-of-the-art subword Transformers on language modeling tasks while maintaining the benefits of token-free language models, such as robustness to noise. In terms of efficiency, we develop an adaptation of speculative decoding with tokenized drafting and byte-level verification. This results in a $2.6\times$ inference speedup to the standard MambaByte implementation, showing similar decoding efficiency as the subword Mamba. These findings establish the viability of SSMs in enabling token-free language modeling.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.13660v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junxiong Wang, Tushaar Gangavarapu, Jing Nathan Yan, Alexander M. Rush</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DAIRstega: Dynamically Allocated Interval-Based Generative Linguistic Steganography with Roulette Wheel</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.15656</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.15656v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Linguistic steganography (LS) tasks aim to generate steganographic text (stego) based on secret. Only authorized receivers can perceive and extract secrets, thereby protecting privacy. However, existing generative LS schemes often do not consider the conditional probability of tokens in the candidate pool, and allocate one or the same number of codings to all tokens. The tokens with lower probabilities are selected to embed secrets that will affect the quality of stegos. As a result, the stegos are easy to perceive and detect. This paper proposes the LS scheme based on dynamically allocated intervals, called DAIRstega. DAIRstega uses the idea of the roulette wheel and takes the conditional probabilities of tokens as the main basis for allocating the roulette area (i.e., the interval length). Thus, the token with a larger conditional probability is allocated more. The secret will be more likely to select the tokens with larger probabilities. In the allocation process, we design some functions between probability and allocated interval length. Based on the invisible characteristics of LS, we give three constraints that need to be met to design the function. To simplify the form, the expression of the allocation function is condensed. Furthermore, DAIRstega can receive additional instruction and controllably generate stegos. Rich experiments show that the proposed embedding way and DAIRstega perform superior to the existing ways and LS schemes, which shows strong perceptual, statistical, and semantic concealment and anti-steganalysis ability. This scheme can also generate high-quality longer stegos, improving the deficiencies in this task. The experiment also verified that DAIRstega can be used as a secure watermarking scheme, providing some ideas for its development.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.15656v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yihao Wang, Ruiqi Song, Lingxiao Li, Ru Zhang, Jianyi Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TrustAgent: Towards Safe and Trustworthy LLM-based Agents through Agent Constitution</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.01586</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.01586v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The rise of LLM-based agents shows great potential to revolutionize task planning, capturing significant attention. Given that these agents will be integrated into high-stake domains, ensuring their reliability and safety is crucial. This paper presents an Agent-Constitution-based agent framework, TrustAgent, with a particular focus on improving the LLM-based agent safety. The proposed framework ensures strict adherence to the Agent Constitution through three strategic components: pre-planning strategy which injects safety knowledge to the model before plan generation, in-planning strategy which enhances safety during plan generation, and post-planning strategy which ensures safety by post-planning inspection. Our experimental results demonstrate that the proposed framework can effectively enhance an LLM agent's safety across multiple domains by identifying and mitigating potential dangers during the planning. Further analysis reveals that the framework not only improves safety but also enhances the helpfulness of the agent. Additionally, we highlight the importance of the LLM reasoning ability in adhering to the Constitution. This paper sheds light on how to ensure the safe integration of LLM-based agents into human-centric environments. Data and code are available at https://github.com/agiresearch/TrustAgent.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.01586v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenyue Hua, Xianjun Yang, Mingyu Jin, Wei Cheng, Ruixiang Tang, Yongfeng Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time Series Forecasting with LLMs: Understanding and Enhancing Model Capabilities</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.10835</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.10835v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have been applied in many fields and have developed rapidly in recent years. As a classic machine learning task, time series forecasting has recently been boosted by LLMs. Recent works treat large language models as \emph{zero-shot} time series reasoners without further fine-tuning, which achieves remarkable performance. However, there are some unexplored research problems when applying LLMs for time series forecasting under the zero-shot setting. For instance, the LLMs' preferences for the input time series are less understood. In this paper, by comparing LLMs with traditional time series forecasting models, we observe many interesting properties of LLMs in the context of time series forecasting. First, our study shows that LLMs perform well in predicting time series with clear patterns and trends, but face challenges with datasets lacking periodicity. This observation can be explained by the ability of LLMs to recognize the underlying period within datasets, which is supported by our experiments. In addition, the input strategy is investigated, and it is found that incorporating external knowledge and adopting natural language paraphrases substantially improve the predictive performance of LLMs for time series. Overall, our study contributes insight into LLMs' advantages and limitations in time series forecasting under different conditions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.10835v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hua Tang, Chong Zhang, Mingyu Jin, Qinkai Yu, Zhenting Wang, Xiaobo Jin, Yongfeng Zhang, Mengnan Du</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning or Self-aligning? Rethinking Instruction Fine-tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18243</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.18243v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Instruction Fine-tuning~(IFT) is a critical phase in building large language models~(LLMs). Previous works mainly focus on the IFT's role in the transfer of behavioral norms and the learning of additional world knowledge. However, the understanding of the underlying mechanisms of IFT remains significantly limited. In this paper, we design a knowledge intervention framework to decouple the potential underlying factors of IFT, thereby enabling individual analysis of different factors. Surprisingly, our experiments reveal that attempting to learn additional world knowledge through IFT often struggles to yield positive impacts and can even lead to markedly negative effects. Further, we discover that maintaining internal knowledge consistency before and after IFT is a critical factor for achieving successful IFT. Our findings reveal the underlying mechanisms of IFT and provide robust support for some very recent and potential future works.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.18243v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mengjie Ren, Boxi Cao, Hongyu Lin, Cao Liu, Xianpei Han, Ke Zeng, Guanglu Wan, Xunliang Cai, Le Sun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LIEDER: Linguistically-Informed Evaluation for Discourse Entity Recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.06301</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.06301v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Discourse Entity (DE) recognition is the task of identifying novel and known entities introduced within a text. While previous work has found that large language models have basic, if imperfect, DE recognition abilities (Schuster and Linzen, 2022), it remains largely unassessed which of the fundamental semantic properties that govern the introduction and subsequent reference to DEs they have knowledge of. We propose the Linguistically-Informed Evaluation for Discourse Entity Recognition (LIEDER) dataset that allows for a detailed examination of language models' knowledge of four crucial semantic properties: existence, uniqueness, plurality, and novelty. We find evidence that state-of-the-art large language models exhibit sensitivity to all of these properties except novelty, which demonstrates that they have yet to reach human-level language understanding abilities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.06301v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaomeng Zhu, Robert Frank</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ConspEmoLLM: Conspiracy Theory Detection Using an Emotion-Based Large Language Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.06765</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.06765v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The internet has brought both benefits and harms to society. A prime example of the latter is misinformation, including conspiracy theories, which flood the web. Recent advances in natural language processing, particularly the emergence of large language models (LLMs), have improved the prospects of accurate misinformation detection. However, most LLM-based approaches to conspiracy theory detection focus only on binary classification and fail to account for the important relationship between misinformation and affective features (i.e., sentiment and emotions). Driven by a comprehensive analysis of conspiracy text that reveals its distinctive affective features, we propose ConspEmoLLM, the first open-source LLM that integrates affective information and is able to perform diverse tasks relating to conspiracy theories. These tasks include not only conspiracy theory detection, but also classification of theory type and detection of related discussion (e.g., opinions towards theories). ConspEmoLLM is fine-tuned based on an emotion-oriented LLM using our novel ConDID dataset, which includes five tasks to support LLM instruction tuning and evaluation. We demonstrate that when applied to these tasks, ConspEmoLLM largely outperforms several open-source general domain LLMs and ChatGPT, as well as an LLM that has been fine-tuned using ConDID, but which does not use affective features. This project will be released on https://github.com/lzw108/ConspEmoLLM/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.06765v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhiwei Liu, Boyang Liu, Paul Thompson, Kailai Yang, Sophia Ananiadou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RAGGED: Towards Informed Design of Retrieval Augmented Generation Systems</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.09040</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.09040v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) can significantly improve the performance of language models (LMs) by providing additional context for tasks such as document-based question answering (DBQA). However, the effectiveness of RAG is highly dependent on its configuration. To systematically find the optimal configuration, we introduce RAGGED, a framework for analyzing RAG configurations across various DBQA tasks. Using the framework, we discover distinct LM behaviors in response to varying context quantities, context qualities, and retrievers. For instance, while some models are robust to noisy contexts, monotonically performing better with more contexts, others are more noise-sensitive and can effectively use only a few contexts before declining in performance. This framework also provides a deeper analysis of these differences by evaluating the LMs' sensitivity to signal and noise under specific context quality conditions. Using RAGGED, researchers and practitioners can derive actionable insights about how to optimally configure their RAG systems for their specific question-answering tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.09040v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jennifer Hsia, Afreen Shaikh, Zhiruo Wang, Graham Neubig</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLMLingua-2: Data Distillation for Efficient and Faithful Task-Agnostic Prompt Compression</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.12968</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.12968v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper focuses on task-agnostic prompt compression for better generalizability and efficiency. Considering the redundancy in natural language, existing approaches compress prompts by removing tokens or lexical units according to their information entropy obtained from a causal language model such as LLaMa-7B. The challenge is that information entropy may be a suboptimal compression metric: (i) it only leverages unidirectional context and may fail to capture all essential information needed for prompt compression; (ii) it is not aligned with the prompt compression objective.
  To address these issues, we propose a data distillation procedure to derive knowledge from an LLM to compress prompts without losing crucial information, and meantime, introduce an extractive text compression dataset. We formulate prompt compression as a token classification problem to guarantee the faithfulness of the compressed prompt to the original one, and use a Transformer encoder as the base architecture to capture all essential information for prompt compression from the full bidirectional context. Our approach leads to lower latency by explicitly learning the compression objective with smaller models such as XLM-RoBERTa-large and mBERT.
  We evaluate our method on both in-domain and out-of-domain datasets, including MeetingBank, LongBench, ZeroScrolls, GSM8K, and BBH. Despite its small size, our model shows significant performance gains over strong baselines and demonstrates robust generalization ability across different LLMs. Additionally, our model is 3x-6x faster than existing prompt compression methods, while accelerating the end-to-end latency by 1.6x-2.9x with compression ratios of 2x-5x. Our code is available at https://aka.ms/LLMLingua-2.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.12968v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhuoshi Pan, Qianhui Wu, Huiqiang Jiang, Menglin Xia, Xufang Luo, Jue Zhang, Qingwei Lin, Victor R\"uhle, Yuqing Yang, Chin-Yew Lin, H. Vicky Zhao, Lili Qiu, Dongmei Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protecting Copyrighted Material with Unique Identifiers in Large Language Model Training</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.15740</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.15740v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: A major public concern regarding the training of large language models (LLMs) is whether they abusing copyrighted online text. Previous membership inference methods may be misled by similar examples in vast amounts of training data. Additionally, these methods are often too complex for general users to understand and use, making them centralized, lacking transparency, and trustworthiness. To address these issues, we propose an alternative \textit{insert-and-detection} methodology, advocating that web users and content platforms employ \textbf{\textit{unique identifiers}} for reliable and independent membership inference. Users and platforms can create their own identifiers, embed them in copyrighted text, and independently detect them in future LLMs. As an initial demonstration, we introduce \textit{ghost sentences}, a primitive form of unique identifiers, consisting primarily of passphrases made up of random words. By embedding one ghost sentences in a few copyrighted texts, users can detect its membership using a perplexity test and a \textit{user-friendly} last-$k$ words test. The perplexity test is based on the fact that LLMs trained on natural language should exhibit high perplexity when encountering unnatural passphrases. As the repetition increases, users can leverage the verbatim memorization ability of LLMs to perform a last-$k$ words test by chatting with LLMs without writing any code. Both tests offer rigorous statistical guarantees for membership inference. For LLaMA-13B, a perplexity test on 30 ghost sentences with an average of 7 repetitions in 148K examples yields a 0.891 ROC AUC. For the last-$k$ words test with OpenLLaMA-3B, 11 out of 16 users, with an average of 24 examples each, successfully identify their data from 1.8M examples.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.15740v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shuai Zhao, Linchao Zhu, Ruijie Quan, Yi Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aligning with Human Judgement: The Role of Pairwise Preference in Large Language Model Evaluators</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.16950</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.16950v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated promising capabilities as automatic evaluators in assessing the quality of generated natural language. However, LLMs still exhibit biases in evaluation and often struggle to generate coherent evaluations that align with human assessments. In this work, we first conduct a systematic study of the misalignment between LLM evaluators and human judgement, revealing that existing calibration methods aimed at mitigating biases are insufficient for effectively aligning LLM evaluators. Inspired by the use of preference data in RLHF, we formulate the evaluation as a ranking problem and introduce Pairwise-preference Search (PairS), an uncertainty-guided search method that employs LLMs to conduct pairwise comparisons and efficiently ranks candidate texts. PairS achieves state-of-the-art performance on representative evaluation tasks and demonstrates significant improvements over direct scoring. Furthermore, we provide insights into the role of pairwise preference in quantifying the transitivity of LLMs and demonstrate how PairS benefits from calibration.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.16950v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yinhong Liu, Han Zhou, Zhijiang Guo, Ehsan Shareghi, Ivan Vuli\'c, Anna Korhonen, Nigel Collier</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Language Models Learn Rare Phenomena from Less Rare Phenomena: The Case of the Missing AANNs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.19827</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.19827v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Language models learn rare syntactic phenomena, but the extent to which this is attributable to generalization vs. memorization is a major open question. To that end, we iteratively trained transformer language models on systematically manipulated corpora which were human-scale in size, and then evaluated their learning of a rare grammatical phenomenon: the English Article+Adjective+Numeral+Noun (AANN) construction (``a beautiful five days''). We compared how well this construction was learned on the default corpus relative to a counterfactual corpus in which AANN sentences were removed. We found that AANNs were still learned better than systematically perturbed variants of the construction. Using additional counterfactual corpora, we suggest that this learning occurs through generalization from related constructions (e.g., ``a few days''). An additional experiment showed that this learning is enhanced when there is more variability in the input. Taken together, our results provide an existence proof that LMs can learn rare grammatical phenomena by generalization from less rare phenomena. Data and code: https://github.com/kanishkamisra/aannalysis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.19827v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kanishka Misra, Kyle Mahowald</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LITE: Modeling Environmental Ecosystems with Multimodal Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.01165</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.01165v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The modeling of environmental ecosystems plays a pivotal role in the sustainable management of our planet. Accurate prediction of key environmental variables over space and time can aid in informed policy and decision-making, thus improving people's livelihood. Recently, deep learning-based methods have shown promise in modeling the spatial-temporal relationships for predicting environmental variables. However, these approaches often fall short in handling incomplete features and distribution shifts, which are commonly observed in environmental data due to the substantial cost of data collection and malfunctions in measuring instruments. To address these issues, we propose LITE -- a multimodal large language model for environmental ecosystems modeling. Specifically, LITE unifies different environmental variables by transforming them into natural language descriptions and line graph images. Then, LITE utilizes unified encoders to capture spatial-temporal dynamics and correlations in different modalities. During this step, the incomplete features are imputed by a sparse Mixture-of-Experts framework, and the distribution shift is handled by incorporating multi-granularity information from past observations. Finally, guided by domain instructions, a language model is employed to fuse the multimodal representations for the prediction. Our experiments demonstrate that LITE significantly enhances performance in environmental spatial-temporal prediction across different domains compared to the best baseline, with a 41.25% reduction in prediction error. This justifies its effectiveness. Our data and code are available at https://github.com/hrlics/LITE.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.01165v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haoran Li, Junqi Liu, Zexian Wang, Shiyuan Luo, Xiaowei Jia, Huaxiu Yao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ethos and Pathos in Online Group Discussions: Corpora for Polarisation Issues in Social Media</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.04889</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.04889v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Growing polarisation in society caught the attention of the scientific community as well as news media, which devote special issues to this phenomenon. At the same time, digitalisation of social interactions requires to revise concepts from social science regarding establishment of trust, which is a key feature of all human interactions, and group polarisation, as well as new computational tools to process large quantities of available data. Existing methods seem insufficient to tackle the problem fully, thus, we propose to approach the problem by investigating rhetorical strategies employed by individuals in polarising discussions online. To this end, we develop multi-topic and multi-platform corpora with manual annotation of appeals to ethos and pathos, two modes of persuasion in Aristotelian rhetoric. It can be employed for training language models to advance the study of communication strategies online on a large scale. With the use of computational methods, our corpora allows an investigation of recurring patterns in polarising exchanges across topics of discussion and media platforms, and conduct both quantitative and qualitative analyses of language structures leading to and engaged in polarisation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.04889v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ewelina Gajewska, Katarzyna Budzynska, Barbara Konat, Marcin Koszowy, Konrad Kiljan, Maciej Uberna, He Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM Reasoners: New Evaluation, Library, and Analysis of Step-by-Step Reasoning with Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.05221</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.05221v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Generating accurate step-by-step reasoning is essential for Large Language Models (LLMs) to address complex problems and enhance robustness and interpretability. Despite the flux of research on developing advanced reasoning approaches, systematically analyzing the diverse LLMs and reasoning strategies in generating reasoning chains remains a significant challenge. The difficulties stem from the lack of two key elements: (1) an automatic method for evaluating the generated reasoning chains on different tasks, and (2) a unified formalism and implementation of the diverse reasoning approaches for systematic comparison. This paper aims to close the gap: (1) We introduce AutoRace for fully automated reasoning chain evaluation. Existing metrics rely on expensive human annotations or pre-defined LLM prompts not adaptable to different tasks. In contrast, AutoRace automatically creates detailed evaluation criteria tailored for each task, and uses GPT-4 for accurate evaluation following the criteria. (2) We develop LLM Reasoners, a library for standardized modular implementation of existing and new reasoning algorithms, under a unified formulation of the search, reward, and world model components. With the new evaluation and library, (3) we conduct extensive study of different reasoning approaches (e.g., CoT, ToT, RAP). The analysis reveals interesting findings about different factors contributing to reasoning, including the reward-guidance, breadth-vs-depth in search, world model, and prompt formats, etc.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.05221v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shibo Hao, Yi Gu, Haotian Luo, Tianyang Liu, Xiyan Shao, Xinyuan Wang, Shuhua Xie, Haodi Ma, Adithya Samavedhi, Qiyue Gao, Zhen Wang, Zhiting Hu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leave No Context Behind: Efficient Infinite Context Transformers with Infini-attention</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.07143</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.07143v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This work introduces an efficient method to scale Transformer-based Large Language Models (LLMs) to infinitely long inputs with bounded memory and computation. A key component in our proposed approach is a new attention technique dubbed Infini-attention. The Infini-attention incorporates a compressive memory into the vanilla attention mechanism and builds in both masked local attention and long-term linear attention mechanisms in a single Transformer block. We demonstrate the effectiveness of our approach on long-context language modeling benchmarks, 1M sequence length passkey context block retrieval and 500K length book summarization tasks with 1B and 8B LLMs. Our approach introduces minimal bounded memory parameters and enables fast streaming inference for LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.07143v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.NE</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tsendsuren Munkhdalai, Manaal Faruqui, Siddharth Gopal</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices and Lessons Learned on Synthetic Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.07503</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.07503v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The success of AI models relies on the availability of large, diverse, and high-quality datasets, which can be challenging to obtain due to data scarcity, privacy concerns, and high costs. Synthetic data has emerged as a promising solution by generating artificial data that mimics real-world patterns. This paper provides an overview of synthetic data research, discussing its applications, challenges, and future directions. We present empirical evidence from prior art to demonstrate its effectiveness and highlight the importance of ensuring its factuality, fidelity, and unbiasedness. We emphasize the need for responsible use of synthetic data to build more powerful, inclusive, and trustworthy language models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.07503v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ruibo Liu, Jerry Wei, Fangyu Liu, Chenglei Si, Yanzhe Zhang, Jinmeng Rao, Steven Zheng, Daiyi Peng, Diyi Yang, Denny Zhou, Andrew M. Dai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DESTEIN: Navigating Detoxification of Language Models via Universal Steering Pairs and Head-wise Activation Fusion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.10464</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.10464v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Despite the remarkable achievements of language models (LMs) across a broad spectrum of tasks, their propensity for generating toxic outputs remains a prevalent concern. Current solutions involving finetuning or auxiliary models usually require extensive computational resources, hindering their practicality in large language models (LLMs). In this paper, we propose DeStein, a novel method that detoxifies LMs by applying representation engineering in activation spaces with lower resource and time costs. Specifically, we derive detoxification vectors from self-induced, universal steering pairs through arithmetic operations in activation spaces. During inference, detoxification is achieved by fusing the detoxification vectors with the original representations in a head-wise manner. Empirical results demonstrate that our method significantly outperforms previous state-of-the-art approaches on various metrics, while also maintaining satisfactory generation quality and diversity. We further validate the practicality and scalability of DeStein with a series of white-box LLMs. The method is open-sourced at https://github.com/LizLizLi/DeStein. Warning: Some example model outputs may contain highly offensive or disturbing text.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.10464v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yu Li, Han Jiang, Chuanyang Gong, Zhihua Wei</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unsupervised Parsing by Searching for Frequent Word Sequences among Sentences with Equivalent Predicate-Argument Structures</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.12059</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.12059v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Unsupervised constituency parsing focuses on identifying word sequences that form a syntactic unit (i.e., constituents) in target sentences. Linguists identify the constituent by evaluating a set of Predicate-Argument Structure (PAS) equivalent sentences where we find the constituent appears more frequently than non-constituents (i.e., the constituent corresponds to a frequent word sequence within the sentence set). However, such frequency information is unavailable in previous parsing methods that identify the constituent by observing sentences with diverse PAS. In this study, we empirically show that constituents correspond to frequent word sequences in the PAS-equivalent sentence set. We propose a frequency-based parser span-overlap that (1) computes the span-overlap score as the word sequence's frequency in the PAS-equivalent sentence set and (2) identifies the constituent structure by finding a constituent tree with the maximum span-overlap score. The parser achieves state-of-the-art level parsing accuracy, outperforming existing unsupervised parsers in eight out of ten languages. Additionally, we discover a multilingual phenomenon: participant-denoting constituents tend to have higher span-overlap scores than equal-length event-denoting constituents, meaning that the former tend to appear more frequently in the PAS-equivalent sentence set than the latter. The phenomenon indicates a statistical difference between the two constituent types, laying the foundation for future labeled unsupervised parsing research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.12059v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junjie Chen, Xiangheng He, Danushka Bollegala, Yusuke Miyao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LEGENT: Open Platform for Embodied Agents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.18243</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.18243v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Despite advancements in Large Language Models (LLMs) and Large Multimodal Models (LMMs), their integration into language-grounded, human-like embodied agents remains incomplete, hindering complex real-life task performance in physical environments. Existing integrations often feature limited open sourcing, challenging collective progress in this field. We introduce LEGENT, an open, scalable platform for developing embodied agents using LLMs and LMMs. LEGENT offers a dual approach: a rich, interactive 3D environment with communicable and actionable agents, paired with a user-friendly interface, and a sophisticated data generation pipeline utilizing advanced algorithms to exploit supervision from simulated worlds at scale. In our experiments, an embryonic vision-language-action model trained on LEGENT-generated data surpasses GPT-4V in embodied tasks, showcasing promising generalization capabilities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.18243v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhili Cheng, Zhitong Wang, Jinyi Hu, Shengding Hu, An Liu, Yuge Tu, Pengkai Li, Lei Shi, Zhiyuan Liu, Maosong Sun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AdaMoLE: Fine-Tuning Large Language Models with Adaptive Mixture of Low-Rank Adaptation Experts</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.00361</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.00361v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We introduce AdaMoLE, a novel method for fine-tuning large language models (LLMs) through an Adaptive Mixture of Low-Rank Adaptation (LoRA) Experts. Moving beyond conventional methods that employ a static top-k strategy for activating experts, AdaMoLE dynamically adjusts the activation threshold using a dedicated threshold network, adaptively responding to the varying complexities of different tasks. By replacing a single LoRA in a layer with multiple LoRA experts and integrating a gating function with the threshold mechanism, AdaMoLE effectively selects and activates the most appropriate experts based on the input context. Our extensive evaluations across a variety of commonsense reasoning and natural language processing tasks show that AdaMoLE exceeds baseline performance. This enhancement highlights the advantages of AdaMoLE's adaptive selection of LoRA experts, improving model effectiveness without a corresponding increase in the expert count. The experimental validation not only confirms AdaMoLE as a robust approach for enhancing LLMs but also suggests valuable directions for future research in adaptive expert selection mechanisms, potentially broadening the scope for optimizing model performance across diverse language processing tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.00361v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zefang Liu, Jiahua Luo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PolygloToxicityPrompts: Multilingual Evaluation of Neural Toxic Degeneration in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.09373</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.09373v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advances in large language models (LLMs) have led to their extensive global deployment, and ensuring their safety calls for comprehensive and multilingual toxicity evaluations. However, existing toxicity benchmarks are overwhelmingly focused on English, posing serious risks to deploying LLMs in other languages. We address this by introducing PolygloToxicityPrompts (PTP), the first large-scale multilingual toxicity evaluation benchmark of 425K naturally occurring prompts spanning 17 languages. We overcome the scarcity of naturally occurring toxicity in web-text and ensure coverage across languages with varying resources by automatically scraping over 100M web-text documents. Using PTP, we investigate research questions to study the impact of model size, prompt language, and instruction and preference-tuning methods on toxicity by benchmarking over 60 LLMs. Notably, we find that toxicity increases as language resources decrease or model size increases. Although instruction- and preference-tuning reduce toxicity, the choice of preference-tuning method does not have any significant impact. Our findings shed light on crucial shortcomings of LLM safeguarding and highlight areas for future research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.09373v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Devansh Jain, Priyanshu Kumar, Samuel Gehman, Xuhui Zhou, Thomas Hartvigsen, Maarten Sap</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Text Generation: A Systematic Literature Review of Tasks, Evaluation, and Challenges</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.15604</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.15604v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Text generation has become more accessible than ever, and the increasing interest in these systems, especially those using large language models, has spurred an increasing number of related publications. We provide a systematic literature review comprising 244 selected papers between 2017 and 2024. This review categorizes works in text generation into five main tasks: open-ended text generation, summarization, translation, paraphrasing, and question answering. For each task, we review their relevant characteristics, sub-tasks, and specific challenges (e.g., missing datasets for multi-document summarization, coherence in story generation, and complex reasoning for question answering). Additionally, we assess current approaches for evaluating text generation systems and ascertain problems with current metrics. Our investigation shows nine prominent challenges common to all tasks and sub-tasks in recent text generation publications: bias, reasoning, hallucinations, misuse, privacy, interpretability, transparency, datasets, and computing. We provide a detailed analysis of these challenges, their potential solutions, and which gaps still require further engagement from the community. This systematic literature review targets two main audiences: early career researchers in natural language processing looking for an overview of the field and promising research directions, as well as experienced researchers seeking a detailed view of tasks, evaluation methodologies, open challenges, and recent mitigation strategies.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.15604v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jonas Becker, Jan Philip Wahle, Bela Gipp, Terry Ruas</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Multi-scale Contextualized Information for Byte-based Neural Machine Translation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.19290</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.19290v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Subword tokenization is a common method for vocabulary building in Neural Machine Translation (NMT) models. However, increasingly complex tasks have revealed its disadvantages. First, a vocabulary cannot be modified once it is learned, making it hard to adapt to new words. Second, in multilingual translation, the imbalance in data volumes across different languages spreads to the vocabulary, exacerbating translations involving low-resource languages. While byte-based tokenization addresses these issues, byte-based models struggle with the low information density inherent in UTF-8 byte sequences. Previous works enhance token semantics through local contextualization but fail to select an appropriate contextualizing scope based on the input. Consequently, we propose the Multi-Scale Contextualization (MSC) method, which learns contextualized information of varying scales across different hidden state dimensions. It then leverages the attention module to dynamically integrate the multi-scale contextualized information. Experiments show that MSC significantly outperforms subword-based and other byte-based methods in both multilingual and out-of-domain scenarios. Code can be found in https://github.com/ictnlp/Multiscale-Contextualization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.19290v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Langlin Huang, Yang Feng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FineRadScore: A Radiology Report Line-by-Line Evaluation Technique Generating Corrections with Severity Scores</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.20613</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.20613v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The current gold standard for evaluating generated chest x-ray (CXR) reports is through radiologist annotations. However, this process can be extremely time-consuming and costly, especially when evaluating large numbers of reports. In this work, we present FineRadScore, a Large Language Model (LLM)-based automated evaluation metric for generated CXR reports. Given a candidate report and a ground-truth report, FineRadScore gives the minimum number of line-by-line corrections required to go from the candidate to the ground-truth report. Additionally, FineRadScore provides an error severity rating with each correction and generates comments explaining why the correction was needed. We demonstrate that FineRadScore's corrections and error severity scores align with radiologist opinions. We also show that, when used to judge the quality of the report as a whole, FineRadScore aligns with radiologists as well as current state-of-the-art automated CXR evaluation metrics. Finally, we analyze FineRadScore's shortcomings to provide suggestions for future improvements.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.20613v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alyssa Huang, Oishi Banerjee, Kay Wu, Eduardo Pontes Reis, Pranav Rajpurkar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are language models rational? The case of coherence norms and belief revision</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.03442</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.03442v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Do norms of rationality apply to machine learning models, in particular language models? In this paper we investigate this question by focusing on a special subset of rational norms: coherence norms. We consider both logical coherence norms as well as coherence norms tied to the strength of belief. To make sense of the latter, we introduce the Minimal Assent Connection (MAC) and propose a new account of credence, which captures the strength of belief in language models. This proposal uniformly assigns strength of belief simply on the basis of model internal next token probabilities. We argue that rational norms tied to coherence do apply to some language models, but not to others. This issue is significant since rationality is closely tied to predicting and explaining behavior, and thus it is connected to considerations about AI safety and alignment, as well as understanding model behavior more generally.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.03442v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Thomas Hofweber, Peter Hase, Elias Stengel-Eskin, Mohit Bansal</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semisupervised Neural Proto-Language Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.05930</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.05930v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Existing work implementing comparative reconstruction of ancestral languages (proto-languages) has usually required full supervision. However, historical reconstruction models are only of practical value if they can be trained with a limited amount of labeled data. We propose a semisupervised historical reconstruction task in which the model is trained on only a small amount of labeled data (cognate sets with proto-forms) and a large amount of unlabeled data (cognate sets without proto-forms). We propose a neural architecture for comparative reconstruction (DPD-BiReconstructor) incorporating an essential insight from linguists' comparative method: that reconstructed words should not only be reconstructable from their daughter words, but also deterministically transformable back into their daughter words. We show that this architecture is able to leverage unlabeled cognate sets to outperform strong semisupervised baselines on this novel task.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.05930v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Liang Lu, Peirong Xie, David R. Mortensen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Judging the Judges: A Systematic Investigation of Position Bias in Pairwise Comparative Assessments by LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07791</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.07791v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: LLM-as-a-Judge offers a promising alternative to human judges across various tasks, yet inherent biases, particularly position bias - a systematic preference for answers based on their position in the prompt - compromise its effectiveness. Our study investigates this issue by developing a framework to systematically study and quantify position bias using metrics such as repetitional consistency, positional consistency, and positional fairness. We conduct experiments with 9 judge models across 22 tasks from the MTBench and DevBench benchmarks and nearly 40 answer-generating models, generating approximately 80,000 evaluation instances. This comprehensive assessment reveals significant variations in bias across judges and tasks. Although GPT-4 often excels in positional consistency and fairness, some more cost-effective models perform comparably or even better in specific tasks, highlighting essential trade-offs between consistency, fairness, and cost. Our results also demonstrate high consistency of judgment across repetitions, confirming that position bias is not due to random variations. This research significantly contributes to the field by introducing new concepts for understanding position bias and providing a multi-dimensional framework for evaluation. These insights guide the selection of optimal judge models, enhance benchmark design, and lay the foundation for future research into effective debiasing strategies, ultimately enhancing the reliability of LLM evaluators.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.07791v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lin Shi, Weicheng Ma, Soroush Vosoughi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Language Model Tokenizer Bias: A Case Study and Solution on GPT-4o</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.11214</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.11214v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advancements in large language models (LLMs), such as GPT-4 and GPT-4o, have shown exceptional performance, especially in languages with abundant resources like English, thanks to extensive datasets that ensure robust training. Conversely, these models exhibit limitations when processing under-resourced languages such as Chinese and Korean, where issues including hallucinatory responses remain prevalent. This paper traces the roots of these disparities to the tokenization process inherent to these models. Specifically, it explores how the tokenizer vocabulary, often used to speed up the tokenization process and reduce tokens but constructed independently of the actual model training data, inadequately represents non-English languages. This misrepresentation results in the propagation of 'under-trained' or 'untrained' tokens, which perpetuate biases and pose serious concerns related to data security and ethical standards. We aim to dissect the tokenization mechanics of GPT-4o, illustrating how its simplified token-handling methods amplify these risks and offer strategic solutions to mitigate associated security and ethical issues. Through this study, we emphasize the critical need to rethink tokenization frameworks to foster more equitable and secure AI technologies.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.11214v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jin Yang, Zhiqiang Wang, Yanbin Lin, Zunduo Zhao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQLFixAgent: Towards Semantic-Accurate Text-to-SQL Parsing via Consistency-Enhanced Multi-Agent Collaboration</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.13408</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.13408v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: While fine-tuned large language models (LLMs) excel in generating grammatically valid SQL in Text-to-SQL parsing, they often struggle to ensure semantic accuracy in queries, leading to user confusion and diminished system usability. To tackle this challenge, we introduce SQLFixAgent, a new consistency-enhanced multi-agent collaborative framework designed for detecting and repairing erroneous SQL. Our framework comprises a core agent, SQLRefiner, alongside two auxiliary agents: SQLReviewer and QueryCrafter. The SQLReviewer agent employs the rubber duck debugging method to identify potential semantic mismatches between SQL and user query. If the error is detected, the QueryCrafter agent generates multiple SQL as candidate repairs using a fine-tuned SQLTool. Subsequently, leveraging similar repair retrieval and failure memory reflection, the SQLRefiner agent selects the most fitting SQL statement from the candidates as the final repair. We evaluated our proposed framework on five Text-to-SQL benchmarks. The experimental results show that our method consistently enhances the performance of the baseline model, specifically achieving an execution accuracy improvement of over 3\% on the Bird benchmark. Our framework also has a higher token efficiency compared to other advanced methods, making it more competitive.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.13408v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jipeng Cen, Jiaxin Liu, Zhixu Li, Jingjing Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI-native Memory: A Pathway from LLMs Towards AGI</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.18312</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.18312v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated the world with the sparks of artificial general intelligence (AGI). One opinion, especially from some startups working on LLMs, argues that an LLM with nearly unlimited context length can realize AGI. However, they might be too optimistic about the long-context capability of (existing) LLMs -- (1) Recent literature has shown that their effective context length is significantly smaller than their claimed context length; and (2) Our reasoning-in-a-haystack experiments further demonstrate that simultaneously finding the relevant information from a long context and conducting (simple) reasoning is nearly impossible. In this paper, we envision a pathway from LLMs to AGI through the integration of \emph{memory}. We believe that AGI should be a system where LLMs serve as core processors. In addition to raw data, the memory in this system would store a large number of important conclusions derived from reasoning processes. Compared with retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) that merely processing raw data, this approach not only connects semantically related information closer, but also simplifies complex inferences at the time of querying. As an intermediate stage, the memory will likely be in the form of natural language descriptions, which can be directly consumed by users too. Ultimately, every agent/person should have its own large personal model, a deep neural network model (thus \emph{AI-native}) that parameterizes and compresses all types of memory, even the ones cannot be described by natural languages. Finally, we discuss the significant potential of AI-native memory as the transformative infrastructure for (proactive) engagement, personalization, distribution, and social in the AGI era, as well as the incurred privacy and security challenges with preliminary solutions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.18312v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jingbo Shang, Zai Zheng, Jiale Wei, Xiang Ying, Felix Tao, Mindverse Team</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It's Morphing Time: Unleashing the Potential of Multiple LLMs via Multi-objective Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.00487</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.00487v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this paper, we introduce a novel approach for large language model merging via black-box multi-objective optimization algorithms. The goal of model merging is to combine multiple models, each excelling in different tasks, into a single model that outperforms any of the individual source models. However, model merging faces two significant challenges: First, existing methods rely heavily on human intuition and customized strategies to tackle multiple tasks. Second, it's difficult to search for the great model merging configuration in limited evaluations. To address these challenges, we propose a multi-objective optimization based model merging method named MM-MO. The proposed method can automatically search merging configurations for multiple tasks with multi-objective optimization algorithms. Moreover, to obtain high-quality model merging configurations within a limited number of evaluation iterations, we have made several improvements to multi-objective Bayesian optimization specifically for model merging scenarios. First, we introduced a weak-to-strong method to improve the acquisition strategy. Second, we employed Fisher information to select configurations, further increasing the chances of discovering superior model merging configurations. Third, we designed a sparsity metric as an additional optimization objective to enhance the model's generalization performance across different tasks. We conducted comprehensive experiments with other mainstream model merging methods, demonstrating that our method consistently outperforms them. Moreover, performance improvements are observed even on the tasks not explicitly targeted as optimization objectives, indicating that our method enhances the overall potential of the model. ...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.00487v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bingdong Li, Zixiang Di, Yanting Yang, Hong Qian, Peng Yang, Hao Hao, Ke Tang, Aimin Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tamil Language Computing: the Present and the Future</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.08618</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.08618v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper delves into the text processing aspects of Language Computing, which enables computers to understand, interpret, and generate human language. Focusing on tasks such as speech recognition, machine translation, sentiment analysis, text summarization, and language modelling, language computing integrates disciplines including linguistics, computer science, and cognitive psychology to create meaningful human-computer interactions. Recent advancements in deep learning have made computers more accessible and capable of independent learning and adaptation. In examining the landscape of language computing, the paper emphasises foundational work like encoding, where Tamil transitioned from ASCII to Unicode, enhancing digital communication. It discusses the development of computational resources, including raw data, dictionaries, glossaries, annotated data, and computational grammars, necessary for effective language processing. The challenges of linguistic annotation, the creation of treebanks, and the training of large language models are also covered, emphasising the need for high-quality, annotated data and advanced language models. The paper underscores the importance of building practical applications for languages like Tamil to address everyday communication needs, highlighting gaps in current technology. It calls for increased research collaboration, digitization of historical texts, and fostering digital usage to ensure the comprehensive development of Tamil language processing, ultimately enhancing global communication and access to digital services.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.08618v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Sarveswaran, K. (2024). Tamil Language Computing: the Present and the Future. Proceedings of Jaffna Science Association, Vol30(2),27-37</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Kengatharaiyer Sarveswaran</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cohesive Conversations: Enhancing Authenticity in Multi-Agent Simulated Dialogues</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.09897</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.09897v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper investigates the quality of multi-agent dialogues in simulations powered by Large Language Models (LLMs). Analyzing dialogues and memory over multiple sessions revealed significant issues such as repetition, inconsistency, and hallucination, exacerbated by the propagation of erroneous information. To combat these challenges, we propose a novel Screening, Diagnosis, and Regeneration (SDR) framework that detects and corrects utterance errors through a comprehensive process involving immediate issue identification, evidence gathering from past dialogues, and LLM analysis for utterance revision. By incorporating our SDR framework to Generative Agents (Park et al., 2023), we enhance the diversity, consistency, and factualness of the generated dialogues. This work presents a pioneering approach to enhancing dialogue quality in multi-agent simulations, establishing a new standard for future research in the field.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.09897v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>KuanChao Chu, Yi-Pei Chen, Hideki Nakayama</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SELF-GUIDE: Better Task-Specific Instruction Following via Self-Synthetic Finetuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.12874</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.12874v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) hold the promise of solving diverse tasks when provided with appropriate natural language prompts. However, prompting often leads models to make predictions with lower accuracy compared to finetuning a model with ample training data. On the other hand, while finetuning LLMs on task-specific data generally improves their performance, abundant annotated datasets are not available for all tasks. Previous work has explored generating task-specific data from state-of-the-art LLMs and using this data to finetune smaller models, but this approach requires access to a language model other than the one being trained, which introduces cost, scalability challenges, and legal hurdles associated with continuously relying on more powerful LLMs. In response to these, we propose SELF-GUIDE, a multi-stage mechanism in which we synthesize task-specific input-output pairs from the student LLM, then use these input-output pairs to finetune the student LLM itself. In our empirical evaluation of the Natural Instructions V2 benchmark, we find that SELF-GUIDE improves the performance of LLM by a substantial margin. Specifically, we report an absolute improvement of approximately 15% for classification tasks and 18% for generation tasks in the benchmark's metrics. This sheds light on the promise of self-synthesized data guiding LLMs towards becoming task-specific experts without any external learning signals.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.12874v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chenyang Zhao, Xueying Jia, Vijay Viswanathan, Tongshuang Wu, Graham Neubig</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Survey on Employing Large Language Models for Text-to-SQL Tasks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.15186</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.15186v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The increasing volume of data stored in relational databases has led to the need for efficient querying and utilization of this data in various sectors. However, writing SQL queries requires specialized knowledge, which poses a challenge for non-professional users trying to access and query databases. Text-to-SQL parsing solves this issue by converting natural language queries into SQL queries, thus making database access more accessible for non-expert users. To take advantage of the recent developments in Large Language Models (LLMs), a range of new methods have emerged, with a primary focus on prompt engineering and fine-tuning. This survey provides a comprehensive overview of LLMs in text-to-SQL tasks, discussing benchmark datasets, prompt engineering, fine-tuning methods, and future research directions. We hope this review will enable readers to gain a broader understanding of the recent advances in this field and offer some insights into its future trajectory.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.15186v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Liang Shi, Zhengju Tang, Nan Zhang, Xiaotong Zhang, Zhi Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Large Language Models Have Compositional Ability? An Investigation into Limitations and Scalability</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.15720</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.15720v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have emerged as powerful tools for many AI problems and exhibit remarkable in-context learning (ICL) capabilities. Compositional ability, solving unseen complex tasks that combine two or more simple tasks, is an essential reasoning ability for Artificial General Intelligence. Despite the tremendous success of LLMs, how they approach composite tasks, especially those not encountered during the pretraining phase, remains an open and largely underexplored question. In this study, we delve into the ICL capabilities of LLMs on composite tasks, with only simple tasks as in-context examples. We develop a test suite of composite tasks including linguistic and logical challenges and perform empirical studies across different LLM families. We observe that models exhibit divergent behaviors: (1) For simpler composite tasks that apply distinct mapping mechanisms to different input segments, the models demonstrate decent compositional ability, while scaling up the model enhances this ability; (2) for more complex composite tasks involving reasoning multiple steps, where each step represents one task, models typically underperform, and scaling up generally provides no improvements. We offer theoretical analysis in a simplified setting, explaining that models exhibit compositional capability when the task handles different input parts separately. We believe our work sheds new light on the capabilities of LLMs in solving composite tasks regarding the nature of the tasks and model scale. Our dataset and code are available at {\url{https://github.com/OliverXUZY/LLM_Compose}}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.15720v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhuoyan Xu, Zhenmei Shi, Yingyu Liang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time Matters: Examine Temporal Effects on Biomedical Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.17638</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.17638v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Time roots in applying language models for biomedical applications: models are trained on historical data and will be deployed for new or future data, which may vary from training data. While increasing biomedical tasks have employed state-of-the-art language models, there are very few studies have examined temporal effects on biomedical models when data usually shifts across development and deployment. This study fills the gap by statistically probing relations between language model performance and data shifts across three biomedical tasks. We deploy diverse metrics to evaluate model performance, distance methods to measure data drifts, and statistical methods to quantify temporal effects on biomedical language models. Our study shows that time matters for deploying biomedical language models, while the degree of performance degradation varies by biomedical tasks and statistical quantification approaches. We believe this study can establish a solid benchmark to evaluate and assess temporal effects on deploying biomedical language models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.17638v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weisi Liu, Zhe He, Xiaolei Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synth-Empathy: Towards High-Quality Synthetic Empathy Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.21669</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.21669v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In recent years, with the rapid advancements in large language models (LLMs), achieving excellent empathetic response capabilities has become a crucial prerequisite. Consequently, managing and understanding empathetic datasets have gained increasing significance. However, empathetic data are typically human-labeled, leading to insufficient datasets and wasted human labor. In this work, we present Synth-Empathy, an LLM-based data generation and quality and diversity selection pipeline that automatically generates high-quality empathetic data while discarding low-quality data. With the data generated from a low empathetic model, we are able to further improve empathetic response performance and achieve state-of-the-art (SoTA) results across multiple benchmarks. Moreover, our model achieves SoTA performance on various human evaluation benchmarks, demonstrating its effectiveness and robustness in real-world applications. Furthermore, we show the trade-off between data quantity and quality, providing insights into empathetic data generation and selection.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.21669v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hao Liang, Linzhuang Sun, Jingxuan Wei, Xijie Huang, Linkun Sun, Bihui Yu, Conghui He, Wentao Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNER: A Unified Prediction Head for Named Entity Recognition in Visually-rich Documents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.01038</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.01038v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The recognition of named entities in visually-rich documents (VrD-NER) plays a critical role in various real-world scenarios and applications. However, the research in VrD-NER faces three major challenges: complex document layouts, incorrect reading orders, and unsuitable task formulations. To address these challenges, we propose a query-aware entity extraction head, namely UNER, to collaborate with existing multi-modal document transformers to develop more robust VrD-NER models. The UNER head considers the VrD-NER task as a combination of sequence labeling and reading order prediction, effectively addressing the issues of discontinuous entities in documents. Experimental evaluations on diverse datasets demonstrate the effectiveness of UNER in improving entity extraction performance. Moreover, the UNER head enables a supervised pre-training stage on various VrD-NER datasets to enhance the document transformer backbones and exhibits substantial knowledge transfer from the pre-training stage to the fine-tuning stage. By incorporating universal layout understanding, a pre-trained UNER-based model demonstrates significant advantages in few-shot and cross-linguistic scenarios and exhibits zero-shot entity extraction abilities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.01038v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yi Tu, Chong Zhang, Ya Guo, Huan Chen, Jinyang Tang, Huijia Zhu, Qi Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging Information Gaps in Dialogues With Grounded Exchanges Using Knowledge Graphs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.01088</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.01088v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Knowledge models are fundamental to dialogue systems for enabling conversational interactions, which require handling domain-specific knowledge. Ensuring effective communication in information-providing conversations entails aligning user understanding with the knowledge available to the system. However, dialogue systems often face challenges arising from semantic inconsistencies in how information is expressed in natural language compared to how it is represented within the system's internal knowledge. To address this problem, we study the potential of large language models for conversational grounding, a mechanism to bridge information gaps by establishing shared knowledge between dialogue participants. Our approach involves annotating human conversations across five knowledge domains to create a new dialogue corpus called BridgeKG. Through a series of experiments on this dataset, we empirically evaluate the capabilities of large language models in classifying grounding acts and identifying grounded information items within a knowledge graph structure. Our findings offer insights into how these models use in-context learning for conversational grounding tasks and common prediction errors, which we illustrate with examples from challenging dialogues. We discuss how the models handle knowledge graphs as a semantic layer between unstructured dialogue utterances and structured information items.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.01088v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Phillip Schneider, Nektarios Machner, Kristiina Jokinen, Florian Matthes</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Language Model Math Reasoning via Grounding in Educational Curricula</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.04226</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.04226v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Our work presents a novel angle for evaluating language models' (LMs) mathematical abilities, by investigating whether they can discern skills and concepts enabled by math content. We contribute two datasets: one consisting of 385 fine-grained descriptions of K-12 math skills and concepts, or standards, from Achieve the Core (ATC), and another of 9.9K problems labeled with these standards (MathFish). Working with experienced teachers, we find that LMs struggle to tag and verify standards linked to problems, and instead predict labels that are close to ground truth, but differ in subtle ways. We also show that LMs often generate problems that do not fully align with standards described in prompts. Finally, we categorize problems in GSM8k using math standards, allowing us to better understand why some problems are more difficult to solve for models than others.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.04226v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Li Lucy, Tal August, Rose E. Wang, Luca Soldaini, Courtney Allison, Kyle Lo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Resilient and Efficient LLMs: A Comparative Study of Efficiency, Performance, and Adversarial Robustness</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.04585</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.04585v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: With the increasing demand for practical applications of Large Language Models (LLMs), many attention-efficient models have been developed to balance performance and computational cost. However, the adversarial robustness of these models remains under-explored. In this work, we design a framework to investigate the trade-off between efficiency, performance, and adversarial robustness of LLMs by comparing three prominent models with varying levels of complexity and efficiency -- Transformer++, Gated Linear Attention (GLA) Transformer, and MatMul-Free LM -- utilizing the GLUE and AdvGLUE datasets. The AdvGLUE dataset extends the GLUE dataset with adversarial samples designed to challenge model robustness. Our results show that while the GLA Transformer and MatMul-Free LM achieve slightly lower accuracy on GLUE tasks, they demonstrate higher efficiency and either superior or comparative robustness on AdvGLUE tasks compared to Transformer++ across different attack levels. These findings highlight the potential of simplified architectures to achieve a compelling balance between efficiency, performance, and adversarial robustness, offering valuable insights for applications where resource constraints and resilience to adversarial attacks are critical.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.04585v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaojing Fan, Chunliang Tao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strong and weak alignment of large language models with human values</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.04655</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.04655v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Minimizing negative impacts of Artificial Intelligent (AI) systems on human societies without human supervision requires them to be able to align with human values. However, most current work only addresses this issue from a technical point of view, e.g., improving current methods relying on reinforcement learning from human feedback, neglecting what it means and is required for alignment to occur. Here, we propose to distinguish strong and weak value alignment. Strong alignment requires cognitive abilities (either human-like or different from humans) such as understanding and reasoning about agents' intentions and their ability to causally produce desired effects. We argue that this is required for AI systems like large language models (LLMs) to be able to recognize situations presenting a risk that human values may be flouted. To illustrate this distinction, we present a series of prompts showing ChatGPT's, Gemini's and Copilot's failures to recognize some of these situations. We moreover analyze word embeddings to show that the nearest neighbors of some human values in LLMs differ from humans' semantic representations. We then propose a new thought experiment that we call "the Chinese room with a word transition dictionary", in extension of John Searle's famous proposal. We finally mention current promising research directions towards a weak alignment, which could produce statistically satisfying answers in a number of common situations, however so far without ensuring any truth value.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.04655v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mehdi Khamassi, Marceau Nahon, Raja Chatila</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XMainframe: A Large Language Model for Mainframe Modernization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.04660</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.04660v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Mainframe operating systems, despite their inception in the 1940s, continue to support critical sectors like finance and government. However, these systems are often viewed as outdated, requiring extensive maintenance and modernization. Addressing this challenge necessitates innovative tools that can understand and interact with legacy codebases. To this end, we introduce XMainframe, a state-of-the-art large language model (LLM) specifically designed with knowledge of mainframe legacy systems and COBOL codebases. Our solution involves the creation of an extensive data collection pipeline to produce high-quality training datasets, enhancing XMainframe's performance in this specialized domain. Additionally, we present MainframeBench, a comprehensive benchmark for assessing mainframe knowledge, including multiple-choice questions, question answering, and COBOL code summarization. Our empirical evaluations demonstrate that XMainframe consistently outperforms existing state-of-the-art LLMs across these tasks. Specifically, XMainframe achieves 30% higher accuracy than DeepSeek-Coder on multiple-choice questions, doubles the BLEU score of Mixtral-Instruct 8x7B on question answering, and scores six times higher than GPT-3.5 on COBOL summarization. Our work highlights the potential of XMainframe to drive significant advancements in managing and modernizing legacy systems, thereby enhancing productivity and saving time for software developers.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.04660v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Anh T. V. Dau, Hieu Trung Dao, Anh Tuan Nguyen, Hieu Trung Tran, Phong X. Nguyen, Nghi D. Q. Bui</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>reCSE: Portable Reshaping Features for Sentence Embedding in Self-supervised Contrastive Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.04975</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.04975v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We propose reCSE, a self supervised contrastive learning sentence representation framework based on feature reshaping. This framework is different from the current advanced models that use discrete data augmentation methods, but instead reshapes the input features of the original sentence, aggregates the global information of each token in the sentence, and alleviates the common problems of representation polarity and GPU memory consumption linear increase in current advanced models. In addition, our reCSE has achieved competitive performance in semantic similarity tasks. And the experiment proves that our proposed feature reshaping method has strong universality, which can be transplanted to other self supervised contrastive learning frameworks and enhance their representation ability, even achieving state-of-the-art performance. Our code is available at https://github.com/heavenhellchen/reCSE.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.04975v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fufangchen Zhao, Gao Jian, Danfeng Yan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MMICT: Boosting Multi-Modal Fine-Tuning with In-Context Examples</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.06363</link>
      <description>arXiv:2312.06363v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Although In-Context Learning (ICL) brings remarkable performance gains to Large Language Models (LLMs), the improvements remain lower than fine-tuning on downstream tasks. This paper introduces Multi-Modal In-Context Tuning (MMICT), a novel multi-modal fine-tuning paradigm that boosts multi-modal fine-tuning by fully leveraging the promising ICL capability of multi-modal LLMs (MM-LLMs). We propose the Multi-Modal Hub (M-Hub), a unified module that captures various multi-modal features according to different inputs and objectives. Based on M-Hub, MMICT enables MM-LLMs to learn from in-context visual-guided textual features and subsequently generate outputs conditioned on the textual-guided visual features. Moreover, leveraging the flexibility of M-Hub, we design a variety of in-context demonstrations. Extensive experiments on a diverse range of downstream multi-modal tasks demonstrate that MMICT significantly outperforms traditional fine-tuning strategy and the vanilla ICT method that directly takes the concatenation of all information from different modalities as input. Our implementation is available at: https://github.com/KDEGroup/MMICT.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2312.06363v3</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tao Chen, Enwei Zhang, Yuting Gao, Ke Li, Xing Sun, Yan Zhang, Hui Li, Rongrong Ji</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Private Fine-tuning of Large Language Models with Zeroth-order Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04343</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.04343v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Differentially private stochastic gradient descent (DP-SGD) allows models to be trained in a privacy-preserving manner, but has proven difficult to scale to the era of foundation models. We introduce DP-ZO, a private fine-tuning framework for large language models by privatizing zeroth order optimization methods. A key insight into the design of our method is that the direction of the gradient in the zeroth-order optimization we use is random and the only information from training data is the step size, i.e., a scalar. Therefore, we only need to privatize the scalar step size, which is memory-efficient. DP-ZO provides a strong privacy-utility trade-off across different tasks, and model sizes that are comparable to DP-SGD in $(\varepsilon,\delta)$-DP. Notably, DP-ZO possesses significant advantages over DP-SGD in memory efficiency, and obtains higher utility in $\varepsilon$-DP when using the Laplace mechanism.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.04343v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xinyu Tang, Ashwinee Panda, Milad Nasr, Saeed Mahloujifar, Prateek Mittal</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Formal-LLM: Integrating Formal Language and Natural Language for Controllable LLM-based Agents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.00798</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.00798v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Recent advancements on Large Language Models (LLMs) enable AI Agents to automatically generate and execute multi-step plans to solve complex tasks. However, since LLM's content generation process is hardly controllable, current LLM-based agents frequently generate invalid or non-executable plans, which jeopardizes the performance of the generated plans and corrupts users' trust in LLM-based agents. In response, this paper proposes a novel "Formal-LLM" framework for LLM-based agents by integrating the expressiveness of natural language and the precision of formal language. Specifically, the framework allows agent developers to express their requirements or constraints for the planning process as an automaton. A stack-based LLM plan generation process is then conducted under the supervision of the automaton to ensure that the generated plan satisfies the constraints, making the planning process controllable. We conduct experiments on both benchmark tasks and practical real-life tasks, and our framework achieves over 50% overall performance increase, which validates the feasibility and effectiveness of employing Formal-LLM to guide the plan generation of agents, preventing the agents from generating invalid and unsuccessful plans. Further, more controllable LLM-based agents can facilitate the broader utilization of LLM in application scenarios where high validity of planning is essential. The source code of this work is available at https://github.com/agiresearch/Formal-LLM.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.00798v4</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.FL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zelong Li, Wenyue Hua, Hao Wang, He Zhu, Yongfeng Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoding Speculative Decoding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.01528</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.01528v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Speculative Decoding is a widely used technique to speed up inference for Large Language Models (LLMs) without sacrificing quality. When performing inference, speculative decoding uses a smaller draft model to generate speculative tokens and then uses the target LLM to verify those draft tokens. The speedup provided by speculative decoding heavily depends on the choice of the draft model. In this work, we perform a detailed study comprising over 350 experiments with LLaMA-65B and OPT-66B using speculative decoding and delineate the factors that affect the performance gain provided by speculative decoding. Our experiments indicate that the performance of speculative decoding depends heavily on the latency of the draft model, and the draft model's capability in language modeling does not correlate strongly with its performance in speculative decoding. Based on these insights we explore a new design space for draft models and design hardware-efficient draft models for speculative decoding. Our newly designed draft model for LLaMA-65B can provide 111% higher throughput than existing draft models and can generalize further to the LLaMA-2 model family and supervised fine-tuned models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.01528v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Minghao Yan, Saurabh Agarwal, Shivaram Venkataraman</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LlaSMol: Advancing Large Language Models for Chemistry with a Large-Scale, Comprehensive, High-Quality Instruction Tuning Dataset</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09391</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.09391v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Chemistry plays a crucial role in many domains, such as drug discovery and material science. While large language models (LLMs) such as GPT-4 exhibit remarkable capabilities on natural language processing tasks, existing research indicates that their performance on chemistry tasks is discouragingly low. In this paper, however, we demonstrate that our developed LLMs can achieve very strong results on a comprehensive set of chemistry tasks, outperforming the most advanced GPT-4 and Claude 3 Opus by a substantial margin. To accomplish this, we propose SMolInstruct, a large-scale, comprehensive, and high-quality dataset for instruction tuning. It contains 14 selected chemistry tasks and over three million samples, laying a solid foundation for training and evaluating LLMs for chemistry. Using SMolInstruct, we fine-tune a set of open-source LLMs, among which, we find that Mistral serves as the best base model for chemistry tasks. Our analysis further demonstrates the critical role of the proposed dataset in driving the performance improvements.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.09391v4</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CE</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Botao Yu, Frazier N. Baker, Ziqi Chen, Xia Ning, Huan Sun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XLAVS-R: Cross-Lingual Audio-Visual Speech Representation Learning for Noise-Robust Speech Perception</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.14402</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.14402v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Speech recognition and translation systems perform poorly on noisy inputs, which are frequent in realistic environments. Augmenting these systems with visual signals has the potential to improve robustness to noise. However, audio-visual (AV) data is only available in limited amounts and for fewer languages than audio-only resources. To address this gap, we present XLAVS-R, a cross-lingual audio-visual speech representation model for noise-robust speech recognition and translation in over 100 languages. It is designed to maximize the benefits of limited multilingual AV pre-training data, by building on top of audio-only multilingual pre-training and simplifying existing pre-training schemes. Extensive evaluation on the MuAViC benchmark shows the strength of XLAVS-R on downstream audio-visual speech recognition and translation tasks, where it outperforms the previous state of the art by up to 18.5% WER and 4.7 BLEU given noisy AV inputs, and enables strong zero-shot audio-visual ability with audio-only fine-tuning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.14402v2</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>HyoJung Han, Mohamed Anwar, Juan Pino, Wei-Ning Hsu, Marine Carpuat, Bowen Shi, Changhan Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moderating Illicit Online Image Promotion for Unsafe User-Generated Content Games Using Large Vision-Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.18957</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.18957v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Online user generated content games (UGCGs) are increasingly popular among children and adolescents for social interaction and more creative online entertainment. However, they pose a heightened risk of exposure to explicit content, raising growing concerns for the online safety of children and adolescents. Despite these concerns, few studies have addressed the issue of illicit image-based promotions of unsafe UGCGs on social media, which can inadvertently attract young users. This challenge arises from the difficulty of obtaining comprehensive training data for UGCG images and the unique nature of these images, which differ from traditional unsafe content. In this work, we take the first step towards studying the threat of illicit promotions of unsafe UGCGs. We collect a real-world dataset comprising 2,924 images that display diverse sexually explicit and violent content used to promote UGCGs by their game creators. Our in-depth studies reveal a new understanding of this problem and the urgent need for automatically flagging illicit UGCG promotions. We additionally create a cutting-edge system, UGCG-Guard, designed to aid social media platforms in effectively identifying images used for illicit UGCG promotions. This system leverages recently introduced large vision-language models (VLMs) and employs a novel conditional prompting strategy for zero-shot domain adaptation, along with chain-of-thought (CoT) reasoning for contextual identification. UGCG-Guard achieves outstanding results, with an accuracy rate of 94% in detecting these images used for the illicit promotion of such games in real-world scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.18957v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Keyan Guo, Ayush Utkarsh, Wenbo Ding, Isabelle Ondracek, Ziming Zhao, Guo Freeman, Nishant Vishwamitra, Hongxin Hu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prompt-prompted Adaptive Structured Pruning for Efficient LLM Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.01365</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.01365v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: With the development of transformer-based large language models (LLMs), they have been applied to many fields due to their remarkable utility, but this comes at a considerable computational cost at deployment. Fortunately, some methods such as pruning or constructing a mixture of experts (MoE) aim at exploiting sparsity in transformer feedforward (FF) blocks to gain boosts in speed and reduction in memory requirements. However, these techniques can be very costly and inflexible in practice, as they often require training or are restricted to specific types of architectures. To address this, we introduce GRIFFIN, a novel training-free and calibration-free method that selects unique FF experts at the sequence level for efficient generation across a plethora of LLMs with different non-ReLU activation functions. This is possible due to a critical observation that many trained LLMs naturally produce highly structured FF activation patterns within a sequence, which we call flocking. Despite our method's simplicity, we show with 50% of the FF parameters, GRIFFIN maintains the original model's performance with little to no degradation on a variety of classification and generation tasks, all while improving latency (e.g. 1.29$\times$ and 1.25$\times$ speed-ups in Gemma 7B and Llama 2 13B, respectively, on an NVIDIA L40). Code is available at https://github.com/hdong920/GRIFFIN.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.01365v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Harry Dong, Beidi Chen, Yuejie Chi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fakes of Varying Shades: How Warning Affects Human Perception and Engagement Regarding LLM Hallucinations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03745</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03745v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The widespread adoption and transformative effects of large language models (LLMs) have sparked concerns regarding their capacity to produce inaccurate and fictitious content, referred to as `hallucinations'. Given the potential risks associated with hallucinations, humans should be able to identify them. This research aims to understand the human perception of LLM hallucinations by systematically varying the degree of hallucination (genuine, minor hallucination, major hallucination) and examining its interaction with warning (i.e., a warning of potential inaccuracies: absent vs. present). Participants (N=419) from Prolific rated the perceived accuracy and engaged with content (e.g., like, dislike, share) in a Q/A format. Participants ranked content as truthful in the order of genuine, minor hallucination, and major hallucination, and user engagement behaviors mirrored this pattern. More importantly, we observed that warning improved the detection of hallucination without significantly affecting the perceived truthfulness of genuine content. We conclude by offering insights for future tools to aid human detection of hallucinations. All survey materials, demographic questions, and post-session questions are available at: https://github.com/MahjabinNahar/fakes-of-varying-shades-survey-materials</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03745v3</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mahjabin Nahar, Haeseung Seo, Eun-Ju Lee, Aiping Xiong, Dongwon Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MC-GPT: Empowering Vision-and-Language Navigation with Memory Map and Reasoning Chains</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.10620</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.10620v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In the Vision-and-Language Navigation (VLN) task, the agent is required to navigate to a destination following a natural language instruction. While learning-based approaches have been a major solution to the task, they suffer from high training costs and lack of interpretability. Recently, Large Language Models (LLMs) have emerged as a promising tool for VLN due to their strong generalization capabilities. However, existing LLM-based methods face limitations in memory construction and diversity of navigation strategies. To address these challenges, we propose a suite of techniques. Firstly, we introduce a method to maintain a topological map that stores navigation history, retaining information about viewpoints, objects, and their spatial relationships. This map also serves as a global action space. Additionally, we present a Navigation Chain of Thoughts module, leveraging human navigation examples to enrich navigation strategy diversity. Finally, we establish a pipeline that integrates navigational memory and strategies with perception and action prediction modules. Experimental results on the REVERIE and R2R datasets show that our method effectively enhances the navigation ability of the LLM and improves the interpretability of navigation reasoning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.10620v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhaohuan Zhan, Lisha Yu, Sijie Yu, Guang Tan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parrot: Multilingual Visual Instruction Tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.02539</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.02539v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The rapid development of Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) like GPT-4V has marked a significant step towards artificial general intelligence. Existing methods mainly focus on aligning vision encoders with LLMs through supervised fine-tuning (SFT) to endow LLMs with multimodal abilities, making MLLMs' inherent ability to react to multiple languages progressively deteriorate as the training process evolves. We empirically find that the imbalanced SFT datasets, primarily composed of English-centric image-text pairs, lead to significantly reduced performance in non-English languages. This is due to the failure of aligning the vision encoder and LLM with multilingual tokens during the SFT process. In this paper, we introduce Parrot, a novel method that utilizes textual guidance to drive visual token alignment at the language level. Parrot makes the visual tokens condition on diverse language inputs and uses Mixture-of-Experts (MoE) to promote the alignment of multilingual tokens. Specifically, to enhance non-English visual tokens alignment, we compute the cross-attention using the initial visual features and textual embeddings, the result of which is then fed into the MoE router to select the most relevant experts. The selected experts subsequently convert the initial visual tokens into language-specific visual tokens. Moreover, considering the current lack of benchmarks for evaluating multilingual capabilities within the field, we collect and make available a Massive Multilingual Multimodal Benchmark which includes 6 languages, 15 categories, and 12,000 questions, named as MMMB. Our method not only demonstrates state-of-the-art performance on multilingual MMBench and MMMB, but also excels across a broad range of multimodal tasks. Both the source code and the training dataset of Parrot will be made publicly available. Code is available at: https://github.com/AIDC-AI/Parrot.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.02539v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hai-Long Sun, Da-Wei Zhou, Yang Li, Shiyin Lu, Chao Yi, Qing-Guo Chen, Zhao Xu, Weihua Luo, Kaifu Zhang, De-Chuan Zhan, Han-Jia Ye</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Representation Learning with Conditional Information Flow Maximization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.05510</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.05510v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: This paper proposes an information-theoretic representation learning framework, named conditional information flow maximization, to extract noise-invariant sufficient representations for the input data and target task. It promotes the learned representations have good feature uniformity and sufficient predictive ability, which can enhance the generalization of pre-trained language models (PLMs) for the target task. Firstly, an information flow maximization principle is proposed to learn more sufficient representations for the input and target by simultaneously maximizing both input-representation and representation-label mutual information. Unlike the information bottleneck, we handle the input-representation information in an opposite way to avoid the over-compression issue of latent representations. Besides, to mitigate the negative effect of potential redundant features from the input, we design a conditional information minimization principle to eliminate negative redundant features while preserve noise-invariant features. Experiments on 13 language understanding benchmarks demonstrate that our method effectively improves the performance of PLMs for classification and regression. Extensive experiments show that the learned representations are more sufficient, robust and transferable.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.05510v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dou Hu, Lingwei Wei, Wei Zhou, Songlin Hu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Bidirectional Human-AI Alignment: A Systematic Review for Clarifications, Framework, and Future Directions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09264</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09264v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Recent advancements in general-purpose AI have highlighted the importance of guiding AI systems towards the intended goals, ethical principles, and values of individuals and groups, a concept broadly recognized as alignment. However, the lack of clarified definitions and scopes of human-AI alignment poses a significant obstacle, hampering collaborative efforts across research domains to achieve this alignment. In particular, ML- and philosophy-oriented alignment research often views AI alignment as a static, unidirectional process (i.e., aiming to ensure that AI systems' objectives match humans) rather than an ongoing, mutual alignment problem. This perspective largely neglects the long-term interaction and dynamic changes of alignment. To understand these gaps, we introduce a systematic review of over 400 papers published between 2019 and January 2024, spanning multiple domains such as Human-Computer Interaction (HCI), Natural Language Processing (NLP), Machine Learning (ML). We characterize, define and scope human-AI alignment. From this, we present a conceptual framework of "Bidirectional Human-AI Alignment" to organize the literature from a human-centered perspective. This framework encompasses both 1) conventional studies of aligning AI to humans that ensures AI produces the intended outcomes determined by humans, and 2) a proposed concept of aligning humans to AI, which aims to help individuals and society adjust to AI advancements both cognitively and behaviorally. Additionally, we articulate the key findings derived from literature analysis, including literature gaps and trends, human values, and interaction techniques. To pave the way for future studies, we envision three key challenges and give recommendations for future research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09264v3</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hua Shen, Tiffany Knearem, Reshmi Ghosh, Kenan Alkiek, Kundan Krishna, Yachuan Liu, Ziqiao Ma, Savvas Petridis, Yi-Hao Peng, Li Qiwei, Sushrita Rakshit, Chenglei Si, Yutong Xie, Jeffrey P. Bigham, Frank Bentley, Joyce Chai, Zachary Lipton, Qiaozhu Mei, Rada Mihalcea, Michael Terry, Diyi Yang, Meredith Ringel Morris, Paul Resnick, David Jurgens</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Universal Approximation Theory: The basic theory for large language models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.00958</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.00958v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Language models have emerged as a critical area of focus in artificial intelligence, particularly with the introduction of groundbreaking innovations like ChatGPT. Large-scale Transformer networks have quickly become the leading approach for advancing natural language processing algorithms. Built on the Transformer architecture, these models enable interactions that closely mimic human communication and, equipped with extensive knowledge, can even assist in guiding human tasks. Despite their impressive capabilities and growing complexity, a key question remains-the theoretical foundations of large language models (LLMs). What makes Transformer so effective for powering intelligent language applications, such as translation and coding? What underlies LLMs' ability for In-Context Learning (ICL)? How does the LoRA scheme enhance the fine-tuning of LLMs? And what supports the practicality of pruning LLMs? To address these critical questions and explore the technological strategies within LLMs, we leverage the Universal Approximation Theory (UAT) to offer a theoretical backdrop, shedding light on the mechanisms that underpin these advancements.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.00958v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wei Wang, Qing Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KeyVideoLLM: Towards Large-scale Video Keyframe Selection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.03104</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.03104v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Recently, with the rise of web videos, managing and understanding large-scale video datasets has become increasingly important. Video Large Language Models (VideoLLMs) have emerged in recent years due to their strong video understanding capabilities. However, training and inference processes for VideoLLMs demand vast amounts of data, presenting significant challenges to data management, particularly regarding efficiency, robustness, and effectiveness. In this work, we present KeyVideoLLM, a text-video frame similarity-based keyframe selection method designed to manage VideoLLM data efficiently, robustly, and effectively. Specifically, KeyVideoLLM achieves a remarkable data compression rate of up to 60.9 times, substantially lowering disk space requirements, which proves its high efficiency. Additionally, it maintains a 100% selection success rate across all video formats and scales, enhances processing speed by up to 200 times compared to existing keyframe selection methods, and does not require hyperparameter tuning. Beyond its outstanding efficiency and robustness, KeyVideoLLM further improves model performance in video question-answering tasks during both training and inference stages. Notably, it consistently achieved the state-of-the-art (SoTA) experimental results on diverse datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.03104v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hao Liang, Jiapeng Li, Tianyi Bai, Xijie Huang, Linzhuang Sun, Zhengren Wang, Conghui He, Bin Cui, Chong Chen, Wentao Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning to (Learn at Test Time): RNNs with Expressive Hidden States</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.04620</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.04620v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Self-attention performs well in long context but has quadratic complexity. Existing RNN layers have linear complexity, but their performance in long context is limited by the expressive power of their hidden state. We propose a new class of sequence modeling layers with linear complexity and an expressive hidden state. The key idea is to make the hidden state a machine learning model itself, and the update rule a step of self-supervised learning. Since the hidden state is updated by training even on test sequences, our layers are called Test-Time Training (TTT) layers. We consider two instantiations: TTT-Linear and TTT-MLP, whose hidden state is a linear model and a two-layer MLP respectively. We evaluate our instantiations at the scale of 125M to 1.3B parameters, comparing with a strong Transformer and Mamba, a modern RNN. Both TTT-Linear and TTT-MLP match or exceed the baselines. Similar to Transformer, they can keep reducing perplexity by conditioning on more tokens, while Mamba cannot after 16k context. With preliminary systems optimization, TTT-Linear is already faster than Transformer at 8k context and matches Mamba in wall-clock time. TTT-MLP still faces challenges in memory I/O, but shows larger potential in long context, pointing to a promising direction for future research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.04620v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yu Sun, Xinhao Li, Karan Dalal, Jiarui Xu, Arjun Vikram, Genghan Zhang, Yann Dubois, Xinlei Chen, Xiaolong Wang, Sanmi Koyejo, Tatsunori Hashimoto, Carlos Guestrin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Survey on LoRA of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.11046</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.11046v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Low-Rank Adaptation~(LoRA), which updates the dense neural network layers with pluggable low-rank matrices, is one of the best performed parameter efficient fine-tuning paradigms. Furthermore, it has significant advantages in cross-task generalization and privacy-preserving. Hence, LoRA has gained much attention recently, and the number of related literature demonstrates exponential growth. It is necessary to conduct a comprehensive overview of the current progress on LoRA. This survey categorizes and reviews the progress from the perspectives of (1) downstream adaptation improving variants that improve LoRA's performance on downstream tasks; (2) cross-task generalization methods that mix multiple LoRA plugins to achieve cross-task generalization; (3) efficiency-improving methods that boost the computation-efficiency of LoRA; (4) data privacy-preserving methods that use LoRA in federated learning; (5) application. Besides, this survey also discusses the future directions in this field. At last, we provide a Github page~\footnote{\href{https://github.com/ZJU-LLMs/Awesome-LoRAs.git}{https://github.com/ZJU-LLMs/Awesome-LoRAs.git}} for readers to check the updates and initiate discussions on this survey paper.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.11046v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuren Mao, Yuhang Ge, Yijiang Fan, Wenyi Xu, Yu Mi, Zhonghao Hu, Yunjun Gao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Across Platforms and Languages: Dutch Influencers and Legal Disclosures on Instagram, YouTube and TikTok</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.12451</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.12451v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Content monetization on social media fuels a growing influencer economy. Influencer marketing remains largely undisclosed or inappropriately disclosed on social media. Non-disclosure issues have become a priority for national and supranational authorities worldwide, who are starting to impose increasingly harsher sanctions on them. This paper proposes a transparent methodology for measuring whether and how influencers comply with disclosures based on legal standards. We introduce a novel distinction between disclosures that are legally sufficient (green) and legally insufficient (yellow). We apply this methodology to an original dataset reflecting the content of 150 Dutch influencers publicly registered with the Dutch Media Authority based on recently introduced registration obligations. The dataset consists of 292,315 posts and is multi-language (English and Dutch) and cross-platform (Instagram, YouTube and TikTok). We find that influencer marketing remains generally underdisclosed on social media, and that bigger influencers are not necessarily more compliant with disclosure standards.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.12451v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haoyang Gui, Thales Bertaglia, Catalina Goanta, Sybe de Vries, Gerasimos Spanakis</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thought-Like-Pro: Enhancing Reasoning of Large Language Models through Self-Driven Prolog-based Chain-of-Thought</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.14562</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.14562v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have shown exceptional performance as general-purpose assistants, excelling across a variety of reasoning tasks. This achievement represents a significant step toward achieving artificial general intelligence (AGI). Despite these advancements, the effectiveness of LLMs often hinges on the specific prompting strategies employed, and there remains a lack of a robust framework to facilitate learning and generalization across diverse reasoning tasks. To address these challenges, we introduce a novel learning framework, THOUGHT-LIKE-PRO In this framework, we utilize imitation learning to imitate the Chain-of-Thought (CoT) process which is verified and translated from reasoning trajectories generated by a symbolic Prolog logic engine. This framework proceeds in a self-driven manner, that enables LLMs to formulate rules and statements from given instructions and leverage the symbolic Prolog engine to derive results. Subsequently, LLMs convert Prolog-derived successive reasoning trajectories into natural language CoT for imitation learning. Our empirical findings indicate that our proposed approach substantially enhances the reasoning abilities of LLMs and demonstrates robust generalization across out-of-distribution reasoning tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.14562v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoyu Tan (INF Technology), Yongxin Deng (Shanghai University of Engineering Science), Xihe Qiu (Shanghai University of Engineering Science), Weidi Xu (INF Technology), Chao Qu (INF Technology), Wei Chu (INF Technology), Yinghui Xu (Fudan University), Yuan Qi (Fudan University)</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficiently and Effectively: A Two-stage Approach to Balance Plaintext and Encrypted Text for Traffic Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.19687</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.19687v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Encrypted traffic classification is the task of identifying the application or service associated with encrypted network traffic. One effective approach for this task is to use deep learning methods to encode the raw traffic bytes directly and automatically extract features for classification (byte-based models). However, current byte-based models input raw traffic bytes, whether plaintext or encrypted text, for automated feature extraction, neglecting the distinct impacts of plaintext and encrypted text on downstream tasks. Additionally, these models primarily focus on improving classification accuracy, with little emphasis on the efficiency of models. In this paper, for the first time, we analyze the impact of plaintext and encrypted text on the model's effectiveness and efficiency. Based on our observations and findings, we propose a two-phase approach to balance the trade-off between plaintext and encrypted text in traffic classification. Specifically, Stage one is to Determine whether the Plain text is enough to be accurately Classified (DPC) using the proposed DPC Selector. This stage quickly identifies samples that can be classified using plaintext, leveraging explicit byte features in plaintext to enhance model's efficiency. Stage two aims to adaptively make a classification with the result from stage one. This stage incorporates encrypted text information for samples that cannot be classified using plaintext alone, ensuring the model's effectiveness on traffic classification tasks. Experiments on two datasets demonstrate that our proposed model achieves state-of-the-art results in both effectiveness and efficiency.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.19687v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wei Peng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SynthVLM: High-Efficiency and High-Quality Synthetic Data for Vision Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.20756</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.20756v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Recently, with the rise of web images, managing and understanding large-scale image datasets has become increasingly important. Vision Large Language Models (VLLMs) have recently emerged due to their robust vision-understanding capabilities. However, training these models requires vast amounts of data, posing challenges to efficiency, effectiveness, data quality, and privacy. In this paper, we introduce SynthVLM, a novel data synthesis pipeline for VLLMs. Unlike existing methods that generate captions from images, SynthVLM employs advanced diffusion models and high-quality captions to automatically generate and select high-resolution images from captions, creating precisely aligned image-text pairs. Leveraging these pairs, we achieve state-of-the-art (SoTA) performance on various vision question answering tasks, maintaining high alignment quality and preserving advanced language abilities. Moreover, SynthVLM surpasses traditional GPT-4 Vision-based caption generation methods in performance while significantly reducing computational overhead. Crucially, our method's reliance on purely generated data ensures the preservation of privacy, achieving SoTA performance with just 100k data points (only 18% of the official dataset size).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.20756v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zheng Liu, Hao Liang, Xijie Huang, Wentao Xiong, Qinhan Yu, Linzhuang Sun, Chong Chen, Conghui He, Bin Cui, Wentao Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CodexGraph: Bridging Large Language Models and Code Repositories via Code Graph Databases</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03910</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03910v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) excel in stand-alone code tasks like HumanEval and MBPP, but struggle with handling entire code repositories. This challenge has prompted research on enhancing LLM-codebase interaction at a repository scale. Current solutions rely on similarity-based retrieval or manual tools and APIs, each with notable drawbacks. Similarity-based retrieval often has low recall in complex tasks, while manual tools and APIs are typically task-specific and require expert knowledge, reducing their generalizability across diverse code tasks and real-world applications. To mitigate these limitations, we introduce CodexGraph, a system that integrates LLM agents with graph database interfaces extracted from code repositories. By leveraging the structural properties of graph databases and the flexibility of the graph query language, CodexGraph enables the LLM agent to construct and execute queries, allowing for precise, code structure-aware context retrieval and code navigation. We assess CodexGraph using three benchmarks: CrossCodeEval, SWE-bench, and EvoCodeBench. Additionally, we develop five real-world coding applications. With a unified graph database schema, CodexGraph demonstrates competitive performance and potential in both academic and real-world environments, showcasing its versatility and efficacy in software engineering. Our application demo: https://github.com/modelscope/modelscope-agent/tree/master/apps/codexgraph_agent.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03910v2</guid>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiangyan Liu, Bo Lan, Zhiyuan Hu, Yang Liu, Zhicheng Zhang, Fei Wang, Michael Shieh, Wenmeng Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
