<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Computer Science -- Computation and Language (cs.CL) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2024-01-16T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Computer Science -- Computation and Language</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2102.00225" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2102.01223" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2105.00815" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.13288" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.11326" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.08604" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.13709" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.04391" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.04511" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.11593" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.13310" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.10005" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.10818" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.11554" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.16801" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.17547" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.17727" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.18342" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2306.04746" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2306.05323" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2307.10443" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2307.13304" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2308.07272" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.04041" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.09552" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.12689" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.14324" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.16349" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.16540" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.00100" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.05378" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.05628" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.05782" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.08279" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.10788" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.10803" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.11454" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.12798" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.14053" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.18341" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.19680" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.20501" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.03220" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.04076" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.04131" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.08724" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.09812" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12275" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.13708" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.15565" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.16522" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.16989" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.04350" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.06355" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09211" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.10048" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11193" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12108" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.14033" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.17267" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.17482" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.00165" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.00741" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.01326" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.01699" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02330" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02333" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02987" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03642" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04658" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04925" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05561" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05596" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2102.00225">
<title>Learning From How Humans Correct. (arXiv:2102.00225v19 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2102.00225</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In industry NLP application, our manually labeled data has a certain number
of noisy data. We present a simple method to find the noisy data and relabel
them manually, meanwhile we collect the correction information. Then we present
novel method to incorporate the human correction information into deep learning
model. Human know how to correct noisy data. So the correction information can
be inject into deep learning model. We do the experiment on our own text
classification dataset, which is manually labeled, because we need to relabel
the noisy data in our dataset for our industry application. The experiment
result shows that our learn-on-correction method improve the classification
accuracy from 91.7% to 92.5% in test dataset. The 91.7% accuracy is trained on
the corrected dataset, which improve the baseline from 83.3% to 91.7% in test
dataset. The accuracy under human evaluation achieves more than 97%.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Guo_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tong Guo&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2102.01223">
<title>Inducing Meaningful Units from Character Sequences with Dynamic Capacity Slot Attention. (arXiv:2102.01223v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2102.01223</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Characters do not convey meaning, but sequences of characters do. We propose
an unsupervised distributional method to learn the abstract meaningful units in
a sequence of characters. Rather than segmenting the sequence, our Dynamic
Capacity Slot Attention model discovers continuous representations of the
objects in the sequence, extending an architecture for object discovery in
images. We train our model on different languages and evaluate the quality of
the obtained representations with forward and reverse probing classifiers.
These experiments show that our model succeeds in discovering units which are
similar to those proposed previously in form, content and level of abstraction,
and which show promise for capturing meaningful information at a higher level
of abstraction.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Behjati_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Melika Behjati&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Henderson_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;James Henderson&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2105.00815">
<title>Representation Learning for Weakly Supervised Relation Extraction. (arXiv:2105.00815v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2105.00815</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Recent years have seen rapid development in Information Extraction, as well
as its subtask, Relation Extraction. Relation Extraction is able to detect
semantic relations between entities in sentences. Currently, many efficient
approaches have been applied to relation extraction tasks. Supervised learning
approaches especially have good performance. However, there are still many
difficult challenges. One of the most serious problems is that manually labeled
data is difficult to acquire. In most cases, limited data for supervised
approaches equals lousy performance. Thus here, under the situation with only
limited training data, we focus on how to improve the performance of our
supervised baseline system with unsupervised pre-training. Feature is one of
the key components in improving the supervised approaches. Traditional
approaches usually apply hand-crafted features, which require expert knowledge
and expensive human labor. However, this type of feature might suffer from data
sparsity: when the training set size is small, the model parameters might be
poorly estimated. In this thesis, we present several novel unsupervised
pre-training models to learn the distributed text representation features,
which are encoded with rich syntactic-semantic patterns of relation
expressions. The experiments have demonstrated that this type of feature,
combine with the traditional hand-crafted features, could improve the
performance of the logistic classification model for relation extraction,
especially on the classification of relations with only minor training
instances.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhuang Li&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.13288">
<title>Discovering Salient Neurons in Deep NLP Models. (arXiv:2206.13288v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.13288</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;While a lot of work has been done in understanding representations learned
within deep NLP models and what knowledge they capture, little attention has
been paid towards individual neurons. We present a technique called as
Linguistic Correlation Analysis to extract salient neurons in the model, with
respect to any extrinsic property - with the goal of understanding how such a
knowledge is preserved within neurons. We carry out a fine-grained analysis to
answer the following questions: (i) can we identify subsets of neurons in the
network that capture specific linguistic properties? (ii) how localized or
distributed neurons are across the network? iii) how redundantly is the
information preserved? iv) how fine-tuning pre-trained models towards
downstream NLP tasks, impacts the learned linguistic knowledge? iv) how do
architectures vary in learning different linguistic properties? Our
data-driven, quantitative analysis illuminates interesting findings: (i) we
found small subsets of neurons that can predict different linguistic tasks, ii)
with neurons capturing basic lexical information (such as suffixation)
localized in lower most layers, iii) while those learning complex concepts
(such as syntactic role) predominantly in middle and higher layers, iii) that
salient linguistic neurons are relocated from higher to lower layers during
transfer learning, as the network preserve the higher layers for task specific
information, iv) we found interesting differences across pre-trained models,
with respect to how linguistic information is preserved within, and v) we found
that concept exhibit similar neuron distribution across different languages in
the multilingual transformer models. Our code is publicly available as part of
the NeuroX toolkit.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Durrani_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nadir Durrani&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Dalvi_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fahim Dalvi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sajjad_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hassan Sajjad&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.11326">
<title>Towards Faithful Model Explanation in NLP: A Survey. (arXiv:2209.11326v4 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.11326</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;End-to-end neural Natural Language Processing (NLP) models are notoriously
difficult to understand. This has given rise to numerous efforts towards model
explainability in recent years. One desideratum of model explanation is
faithfulness, i.e. an explanation should accurately represent the reasoning
process behind the model&apos;s prediction. In this survey, we review over 110 model
explanation methods in NLP through the lens of faithfulness. We first discuss
the definition and evaluation of faithfulness, as well as its significance for
explainability. We then introduce recent advances in faithful explanation,
grouping existing approaches into five categories: similarity-based methods,
analysis of model-internal structures, backpropagation-based methods,
counterfactual intervention, and self-explanatory models. For each category, we
synthesize its representative studies, strengths, and weaknesses. Finally, we
summarize their common virtues and remaining challenges, and reflect on future
work directions towards faithful explainability in NLP.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lyu_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qing Lyu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Apidianaki_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marianna Apidianaki&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Callison_Burch_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chris Callison-Burch&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.08604">
<title>NormSAGE: Multi-Lingual Multi-Cultural Norm Discovery from Conversations On-the-Fly. (arXiv:2210.08604v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.08604</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Norm discovery is important for understanding and reasoning about the
acceptable behaviors and potential violations in human communication and
interactions. We introduce NormSage, a framework for addressing the novel task
of conversation-grounded multi-lingual, multi-cultural norm discovery, based on
language model prompting and self-verification. NormSAGE leverages the
expressiveness and implicit knowledge of the pretrained GPT-3 language model
backbone, to elicit knowledge about norms through directed questions
representing the norm discovery task and conversation context. It further
addresses the risk of language model hallucination with a self-verification
mechanism ensuring that the norms discovered are correct and are substantially
grounded to their source conversations. Evaluation results show that our
approach discovers significantly more relevant and insightful norms for
conversations on-the-fly compared to baselines (&amp;gt;10+% in Likert scale rating).
The norms discovered from Chinese conversation are also comparable to the norms
discovered from English conversation in terms of insightfulness and correctness
(&amp;lt;3% difference). In addition, the culture-specific norms are promising
quality, allowing for 80% accuracy in culture pair human identification.
Finally, our grounding process in norm discovery self-verification can be
extended for instantiating the adherence and violation of any norm for a given
conversation on-the-fly, with explainability and transparency. NormSAGE
achieves an AUC of 95.4% in grounding, with natural language explanation
matching human-written quality.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Fung_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yi R. Fung&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chakraborty_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tuhin Chakraborty&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Guo_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hao Guo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Rambow_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Owen Rambow&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Muresan_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Smaranda Muresan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ji_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Heng Ji&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.13709">
<title>Undesirable Biases in NLP: Addressing Challenges of Measurement. (arXiv:2211.13709v4 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.13709</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;As Large Language Models and Natural Language Processing (NLP) technology
rapidly develop and spread into daily life, it becomes crucial to anticipate
how their use could harm people. One problem that has received a lot of
attention in recent years is that this technology has displayed harmful biases,
from generating derogatory stereotypes to producing disparate outcomes for
different social groups. Although a lot of effort has been invested in
assessing and mitigating these biases, our methods of measuring the biases of
NLP models have serious problems and it is often unclear what they actually
measure. In this paper, we provide an interdisciplinary approach to discussing
the issue of NLP model bias by adopting the lens of psychometrics -- a field
specialized in the measurement of concepts like bias that are not directly
observable. In particular, we will explore two central notions from
psychometrics, the construct validity and the reliability of measurement tools,
and discuss how they can be applied in the context of measuring model bias. Our
goal is to provide NLP practitioners with methodological tools for designing
better bias measures, and to inspire them more generally to explore tools from
psychometrics when working on bias measurement tools.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wal_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Oskar van der Wal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bachmann_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dominik Bachmann&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Leidinger_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alina Leidinger&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Maanen_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Leendert van Maanen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zuidema_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Willem Zuidema&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Schulz_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Katrin Schulz&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.04391">
<title>The Re-Label Method For Data-Centric Machine Learning. (arXiv:2302.04391v7 [cs.LG] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.04391</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In industry deep learning application, our manually labeled data has a
certain number of noisy data. To solve this problem and achieve more than 90
score in dev dataset, we present a simple method to find the noisy data and
re-label the noisy data by human, given the model predictions as references in
human labeling. In this paper, we illustrate our idea for a broad set of deep
learning tasks, includes classification, sequence tagging, object detection,
sequence generation, click-through rate prediction. The dev dataset evaluation
results and human evaluation results verify our idea.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Guo_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tong Guo&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.04511">
<title>A Large-Scale Analysis of Persian Tweets Regarding Covid-19 Vaccination. (arXiv:2302.04511v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.04511</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The Covid-19 pandemic had an enormous effect on our lives, especially on
people&apos;s interactions. By introducing Covid-19 vaccines, both positive and
negative opinions were raised over the subject of taking vaccines or not. In
this paper, using data gathered from Twitter, including tweets and user
profiles, we offer a comprehensive analysis of public opinion in Iran about the
Coronavirus vaccines. For this purpose, we applied a search query technique
combined with a topic modeling approach to extract vaccine-related tweets. We
utilized transformer-based models to classify the content of the tweets and
extract themes revolving around vaccination. We also conducted an emotion
analysis to evaluate the public happiness and anger around this topic. Our
results demonstrate that Covid-19 vaccination has attracted considerable
attention from different angles, such as governmental issues, safety or
hesitancy, and side effects. Moreover, Coronavirus-relevant phenomena like
public vaccination and the rate of infection deeply impacted public emotional
status and users&apos; interactions.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+ShabaniMirzaei_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Taha ShabaniMirzaei&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chamani_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Houmaan Chamani&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Abaskohi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Amirhossein Abaskohi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zadeh_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhivar Sourati Hassan Zadeh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bahrak_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Behnam Bahrak&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.11593">
<title>Difficulty in chirality recognition for Transformer architectures learning chemical structures from string. (arXiv:2303.11593v4 [cs.LG] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.11593</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Recent years have seen rapid development of descriptor generation based on
representation learning of extremely diverse molecules, especially those that
apply natural language processing (NLP) models to SMILES, a literal
representation of molecular structure. However, little research has been done
on how these models understand chemical structure. To address this black box,
we investigated the relationship between the learning progress of SMILES and
chemical structure using a representative NLP model, the Transformer. We show
that while the Transformer learns partial structures of molecules quickly, it
requires extended training to understand overall structures. Consistently, the
accuracy of molecular property predictions using descriptors generated from
models at different learning steps was similar from the beginning to the end of
training. Furthermore, we found that the Transformer requires particularly long
training to learn chirality and sometimes stagnates with low performance due to
misunderstanding of enantiomers. These findings are expected to deepen the
understanding of NLP models in chemistry.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yoshikai_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yasuhiro Yoshikai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Mizuno_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tadahaya Mizuno&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Nemoto_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shumpei Nemoto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kusuhara_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hiroyuki Kusuhara&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.13310">
<title>SwissBERT: The Multilingual Language Model for Switzerland. (arXiv:2303.13310v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.13310</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present SwissBERT, a masked language model created specifically for
processing Switzerland-related text. SwissBERT is a pre-trained model that we
adapted to news articles written in the national languages of Switzerland --
German, French, Italian, and Romansh. We evaluate SwissBERT on natural language
understanding tasks related to Switzerland and find that it tends to outperform
previous models on these tasks, especially when processing contemporary news
and/or Romansh Grischun. Since SwissBERT uses language adapters, it may be
extended to Swiss German dialects in future work. The model and our open-source
code are publicly released at https://github.com/ZurichNLP/swissbert.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Vamvas_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jannis Vamvas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Graen_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Johannes Gra&amp;#xeb;n&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sennrich_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rico Sennrich&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.10005">
<title>DinoSR: Self-Distillation and Online Clustering for Self-supervised Speech Representation Learning. (arXiv:2305.10005v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.10005</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we introduce self-distillation and online clustering for
self-supervised speech representation learning (DinoSR) which combines masked
language modeling, self-distillation, and online clustering. We show that these
concepts complement each other and result in a strong representation learning
model for speech. DinoSR first extracts contextualized embeddings from the
input audio with a teacher network, then runs an online clustering system on
the embeddings to yield a machine-discovered phone inventory, and finally uses
the discretized tokens to guide a student network. We show that DinoSR
surpasses previous state-of-the-art performance in several downstream tasks,
and provide a detailed analysis of the model and the learned discrete units.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alexander H. Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chang_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Heng-Jui Chang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Auli_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michael Auli&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hsu_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei-Ning Hsu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Glass_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;James R. Glass&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.10818">
<title>Diffusion Language Models Generation Can Be Halted Early. (arXiv:2305.10818v2 [cs.LG] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.10818</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Diffusion Language models (DLMs) are a promising avenue for text generation
due to their practical properties on tractable controllable generation. They
also have the advantage of not having to predict text autoregressively.
However, despite these notable features, DLMs have not yet reached the
performance levels of their Autoregressive counterparts. One of the ways to
reduce the performance gap between these two types of language models is to
speed up the generation of DLMs. Therefore, we propose a pioneering methodology
to address this issue in this work. It enables the execution of more generation
steps within a given time frame, potentially leading to higher-quality outputs.
Specifically, our methods estimate DLMs completeness of text generation and
allow adaptive halting of the generation process. We test and refine our
methods on Plaid, SSD, and CDCD DLMs and create a cohesive perspective on their
generation workflows. Finally, we confirm that our methods allow halting Plaid,
SSD, and CDCD models and decrease the generation time by $10$-$40$% without a
drop in the quality of model samples.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Vaina_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sofia Maria Lo Cicero Vaina&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Balagansky_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nikita Balagansky&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gavrilov_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniil Gavrilov&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.11554">
<title>ToolkenGPT: Augmenting Frozen Language Models with Massive Tools via Tool Embeddings. (arXiv:2305.11554v4 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.11554</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Augmenting large language models (LLMs) with external tools has emerged as a
promising approach to solving complex problems. However, traditional methods,
which finetune LLMs with tool demonstration data, can be both costly and
restricted to a predefined set of tools. Recent in-context learning paradigm
alleviates these issues, but the limited context length only allows for a few
shots of demonstrations, leading to suboptimal understandings of the tools.
Moreover, when there are numerous tools to choose from, in-context learning
could completely fail to work. In this paper, we propose an alternative
approach, $\textbf{ToolkenGPT}$, which combines the benefits of both sides. Our
approach represents each $\underline{tool}$ as a to$\underline{ken}$
($\textit{toolken}$) and learns an embedding for it, enabling tool calls in the
same way as generating a regular word token. Once a toolken is triggered, the
LLM is prompted to complete arguments for the tool to execute. ToolkenGPT
offers the flexibility to plug in an arbitrary number of tools by expanding the
set of toolkens on the fly. In addition, it improves tool use by allowing
extensive demonstration data for learning the toolken embeddings. In diverse
domains, including numerical reasoning, knowledge-based question answering, and
embodied plan generation, our approach effectively augments LLMs with tools and
substantially outperforms various latest baselines. ToolkenGPT demonstrates the
promising ability to use relevant tools from a large tool set in complex
scenarios.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hao_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shibo Hao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tianyang Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhen Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hu_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhiting Hu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.16801">
<title>Motion-Based Sign Language Video Summarization using Curvature and Torsion. (arXiv:2305.16801v3 [cs.CV] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.16801</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;An interesting problem in many video-based applications is the generation of
short synopses by selecting the most informative frames, a procedure which is
known as video summarization. For sign language videos the benefits of using
the $t$-parameterized counterpart of the curvature of the 2-D signer&apos;s wrist
trajectory to identify keyframes, have been recently reported in the
literature. In this paper we extend these ideas by modeling the 3-D hand motion
that is extracted from each frame of the video. To this end we propose a new
informative function based on the $t$-parameterized curvature and torsion of
the 3-D trajectory. The method to characterize video frames as keyframes
depends on whether the motion occurs in 2-D or 3-D space. Specifically, in the
case of 3-D motion we look for the maxima of the harmonic mean of the curvature
and torsion of the target&apos;s trajectory; in the planar motion case we seek for
the maxima of the trajectory&apos;s curvature. The proposed 3-D feature is
experimentally evaluated in applications of sign language videos on (1)
objective measures using ground-truth keyframe annotations, (2) human-based
evaluation of understanding, and (3) gloss classification and the results
obtained are promising.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sartinas_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Evangelos G. Sartinas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Psarakis_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Emmanouil Z. Psarakis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kosmopoulos_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dimitrios I. Kosmopoulos&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.17547">
<title>Translatotron 3: Speech to Speech Translation with Monolingual Data. (arXiv:2305.17547v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.17547</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This paper presents Translatotron 3, a novel approach to unsupervised direct
speech-to-speech translation from monolingual speech-text datasets by combining
masked autoencoder, unsupervised embedding mapping, and back-translation.
Experimental results in speech-to-speech translation tasks between Spanish and
English show that Translatotron 3 outperforms a baseline cascade system,
reporting $18.14$ BLEU points improvement on the synthesized
Unpaired-Conversational dataset. In contrast to supervised approaches that
necessitate real paired data, or specialized modeling to replicate
para-/non-linguistic information such as pauses, speaking rates, and speaker
identity, Translatotron 3 showcases its capability to retain it. Audio samples
can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;http://google-research.github.io/lingvo-lab/translatotron3&quot;&gt;this http URL&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Nachmani_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Eliya Nachmani&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Levkovitch_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alon Levkovitch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ding_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yifan Ding&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Asawaroengchai_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chulayuth Asawaroengchai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zen_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Heiga Zen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ramanovich_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michelle Tadmor Ramanovich&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.17727">
<title>Learning a Structural Causal Model for Intuition Reasoning in Conversation. (arXiv:2305.17727v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.17727</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Reasoning, a crucial aspect of NLP research, has not been adequately
addressed by prevailing models including Large Language Model. Conversation
reasoning, as a critical component of it, remains largely unexplored due to the
absence of a well-designed cognitive model. In this paper, inspired by
intuition theory on conversation cognition, we develop a conversation cognitive
model (CCM) that explains how each utterance receives and activates channels of
information recursively. Besides, we algebraically transformed CCM into a
structural causal model (SCM) under some mild assumptions, rendering it
compatible with various causal discovery methods. We further propose a
probabilistic implementation of the SCM for utterance-level relation reasoning.
By leveraging variational inference, it explores substitutes for implicit
causes, addresses the issue of their unobservability, and reconstructs the
causal representations of utterances through the evidence lower bounds.
Moreover, we constructed synthetic and simulated datasets incorporating
implicit causes and complete cause labels, alleviating the current situation
where all available datasets are implicit-causes-agnostic. Extensive
experiments demonstrate that our proposed method significantly outperforms
existing methods on synthetic, simulated, and real-world datasets. Finally, we
analyze the performance of CCM under latent confounders and propose theoretical
ideas for addressing this currently unresolved issue.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hang Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liao_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bingyu Liao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Luo_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jing Luo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhu_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wenjing Zhu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yang_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xinyu Yang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.18342">
<title>Neural Task Synthesis for Visual Programming. (arXiv:2305.18342v3 [cs.LG] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.18342</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Generative neural models hold great promise in enhancing programming
education by synthesizing new content. We seek to design neural models that can
automatically generate programming tasks for a given specification in the
context of visual programming domains. Despite the recent successes of large
generative models like GPT-4, our initial results show that these models are
ineffective in synthesizing visual programming tasks and struggle with logical
and spatial reasoning. We propose a novel neuro-symbolic technique,
NeurTaskSyn, that can synthesize programming tasks for a specification given in
the form of desired programming concepts exercised by its solution code and
constraints on the visual task. NeurTaskSyn has two components: the first
component is trained via imitation learning procedure to generate possible
solution codes, and the second component is trained via reinforcement learning
procedure to guide an underlying symbolic execution engine that generates
visual tasks for these codes. We demonstrate the effectiveness of NeurTaskSyn
through an extensive empirical evaluation and a qualitative study on reference
tasks taken from the Hour of Code: Classic Maze challenge by Code-dot-org and
the Intro to Programming with Karel course by CodeHS-dot-com.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Padurean_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Victor-Alexandru P&amp;#x103;durean&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tzannetos_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Georgios Tzannetos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Singla_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Adish Singla&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2306.04746">
<title>Using Imperfect Surrogates for Downstream Inference: Design-based Supervised Learning for Social Science Applications of Large Language Models. (arXiv:2306.04746v3 [stat.ME] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2306.04746</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In computational social science (CSS), researchers analyze documents to
explain social and political phenomena. In most scenarios, CSS researchers
first obtain labels for documents and then explain labels using interpretable
regression analyses in the second step. One increasingly common way to annotate
documents cheaply at scale is through large language models (LLMs). However,
like other scalable ways of producing annotations, such surrogate labels are
often imperfect and biased. We present a new algorithm for using imperfect
annotation surrogates for downstream statistical analyses while guaranteeing
statistical properties -- like asymptotic unbiasedness and proper uncertainty
quantification -- which are fundamental to CSS research. We show that direct
use of surrogate labels in downstream statistical analyses leads to substantial
bias and invalid confidence intervals, even with high surrogate accuracy of
80-90%. To address this, we build on debiased machine learning to propose the
design-based supervised learning (DSL) estimator. DSL employs a doubly-robust
procedure to combine surrogate labels with a smaller number of high-quality,
gold-standard labels. Our approach guarantees valid inference for downstream
statistical analyses, even when surrogates are arbitrarily biased and without
requiring stringent assumptions, by controlling the probability of sampling
documents for gold-standard labeling. Both our theoretical analysis and
experimental results show that DSL provides valid statistical inference while
achieving root mean squared errors comparable to existing alternatives that
focus only on prediction without inferential guarantees.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Egami_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Naoki Egami&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Hinck_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Musashi Hinck&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Stewart_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Brandon M. Stewart&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Wei_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hanying Wei&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2306.05323">
<title>Advancing Italian Biomedical Information Extraction with Transformers-based Models: Methodological Insights and Multicenter Practical Application. (arXiv:2306.05323v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2306.05323</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The introduction of computerized medical records in hospitals has reduced
burdensome activities like manual writing and information fetching. However,
the data contained in medical records are still far underutilized, primarily
because extracting data from unstructured textual medical records takes time
and effort. Information Extraction, a subfield of Natural Language Processing,
can help clinical practitioners overcome this limitation by using automated
text-mining pipelines. In this work, we created the first Italian
neuropsychiatric Named Entity Recognition dataset, PsyNIT, and used it to
develop a Transformers-based model. Moreover, we collected and leveraged three
external independent datasets to implement an effective multicenter model, with
overall F1-score 84.77%, Precision 83.16%, Recall 86.44%. The lessons learned
are: (i) the crucial role of a consistent annotation process and (ii) a
fine-tuning strategy that combines classical methods with a &quot;low-resource&quot;
approach. This allowed us to establish methodological guidelines that pave the
way for Natural Language Processing studies in less-resourced languages.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Crema_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Claudio Crema&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Buonocore_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tommaso Mario Buonocore&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Fostinelli_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Silvia Fostinelli&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Parimbelli_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Enea Parimbelli&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Verde_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Federico Verde&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Fundaro_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Cira Fundar&amp;#xf2;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Manera_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marina Manera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ramusino_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Matteo Cotta Ramusino&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Capelli_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marco Capelli&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Costa_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alfredo Costa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Binetti_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Giuliano Binetti&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bellazzi_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Riccardo Bellazzi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Redolfi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alberto Redolfi&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2307.10443">
<title>Integrating a Heterogeneous Graph with Entity-aware Self-attention using Relative Position Labels for Reading Comprehension Model. (arXiv:2307.10443v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2307.10443</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Despite the significant progress made by transformer models in machine
reading comprehension tasks, they still fall short in handling complex
reasoning tasks due to the absence of explicit knowledge in the input sequence.
To address this limitation, many recent works have proposed injecting external
knowledge into the model. However, selecting relevant external knowledge,
ensuring its availability, and requiring additional processing steps remain
challenging. In this paper, we introduce a novel attention pattern that
integrates reasoning knowledge derived from a heterogeneous graph into the
transformer architecture without relying on external knowledge. The proposed
attention pattern comprises three key elements: global-local attention for word
tokens, graph attention for entity tokens that exhibit strong attention towards
tokens connected in the graph as opposed to those unconnected, and the
consideration of the type of relationship between each entity token and word
token. This results in optimized attention between the two if a relationship
exists. The pattern is coupled with special relative position labels, allowing
it to integrate with LUKE&apos;s entity-aware self-attention mechanism. The
experimental findings corroborate that our model outperforms both the
cutting-edge LUKE-Graph and the baseline LUKE model across two distinct
datasets: ReCoRD, emphasizing commonsense reasoning, and WikiHop, focusing on
multi-hop reasoning challenges.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Foolad_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shima Foolad&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kiani_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kourosh Kiani&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2307.13304">
<title>QuIP: 2-Bit Quantization of Large Language Models With Guarantees. (arXiv:2307.13304v2 [cs.LG] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2307.13304</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This work studies post-training parameter quantization in large language
models (LLMs). We introduce quantization with incoherence processing (QuIP), a
new method based on the insight that quantization benefits from
$\textit{incoherent}$ weight and Hessian matrices, i.e., from the weights being
even in magnitude and the directions in which it is important to round them
accurately being unaligned with the coordinate axes. QuIP consists of two
steps: (1) an adaptive rounding procedure minimizing a quadratic proxy
objective; (2) efficient pre- and post-processing that ensures weight and
Hessian incoherence via multiplication by random orthogonal matrices. We
complement QuIP with the first theoretical analysis for an LLM-scale
quantization algorithm, and show that our theory also applies to an existing
method, OPTQ. Empirically, we find that our incoherence preprocessing improves
several existing quantization algorithms and yields the first LLM quantization
methods that produce viable results using only two bits per weight. Our code
can be found at https://github.com/Cornell-RelaxML/QuIP.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chee_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jerry Chee&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cai_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yaohui Cai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kuleshov_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Volodymyr Kuleshov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sa_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Christopher De Sa&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2308.07272">
<title>Dialogue for Prompting: a Policy-Gradient-Based Discrete Prompt Generation for Few-shot Learning. (arXiv:2308.07272v2 [cs.LG] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2308.07272</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Prompt-based pre-trained language models (PLMs) paradigm have succeeded
substantially in few-shot natural language processing (NLP) tasks. However,
prior discrete prompt optimization methods require expert knowledge to design
the base prompt set and identify high-quality prompts, which is costly,
inefficient, and subjective. Meanwhile, existing continuous prompt optimization
methods improve the performance by learning the ideal prompts through the
gradient information of PLMs, whose high computational cost, and low
readability and generalizability are often concerning. To address the research
gap, we propose a Dialogue-comprised Policy-gradient-based Discrete Prompt
Optimization ($DP_2O$) method. We first design a multi-round dialogue alignment
strategy for readability prompt set generation based on GPT-4. Furthermore, we
propose an efficient prompt screening metric to identify high-quality prompts
with linear complexity. Finally, we construct a reinforcement learning (RL)
framework based on policy gradients to match the prompts to inputs optimally.
By training a policy network with only 0.67% of the PLM parameter size on the
tasks in the few-shot setting, $DP_2O$ outperforms the state-of-the-art (SOTA)
method by 1.52% in accuracy on average on four open-source datasets. Moreover,
subsequent experiments also demonstrate that $DP_2O$ has good universality,
robustness, and generalization ability.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chengzhengxu Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaoming Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yichen Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Duyi Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lan_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yu Lan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shen_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chao Shen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.04041">
<title>Evaluation and Enhancement of Semantic Grounding in Large Vision-Language Models. (arXiv:2309.04041v2 [cs.CV] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.04041</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Large Vision-Language Models (LVLMs) offer remarkable benefits for a variety
of vision-language tasks. However, a challenge hindering their application in
real-world scenarios, particularly regarding safety, robustness, and
reliability, is their constrained semantic grounding ability, which pertains to
connecting language to the physical-world entities or concepts referenced in
images. Therefore, a crucial need arises for a comprehensive study to assess
the semantic grounding ability of widely used LVLMs. Despite the significance,
sufficient investigation in this direction is currently lacking. Our work
bridges this gap by designing a pipeline for generating large-scale evaluation
datasets covering fine-grained semantic information, such as color, number,
material, etc., along with a thorough assessment of seven popular LVLMs&apos;
semantic grounding ability. Results highlight prevalent misgrounding across
various aspects and degrees. To address this issue, we propose a data-centric
enhancement method that aims to improve LVLMs&apos; semantic grounding ability
through multimodal instruction tuning on fine-grained conversations.
Experiments on enhanced LVLMs demonstrate notable improvements in addressing
misgrounding issues.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiaying Lu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Rao_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jinmeng Rao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kezhen Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Guo_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaoyuan Guo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yawen Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sun_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Baochen Sun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yang_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Carl Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yang_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jie Yang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.09552">
<title>CB-Whisper: Contextual Biasing Whisper using Open-Vocabulary Keyword-Spotting. (arXiv:2309.09552v2 [cs.AI] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.09552</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;End-to-end automatic speech recognition (ASR) systems often struggle to
recognize rare name entities, such as personal names, organizations, and
terminologies not frequently encountered in the training data. This paper
presents Contextual Biasing Whisper (CB-Whisper), a novel ASR system based on
OpenAI&apos;s Whisper model that can recognize user-defined name entities by
performing open-vocabulary keyword-spotting (OV-KWS) using the hidden states of
Whisper encoder. The recognized entities are used as prompts for the Whisper
decoder. We first propose a multitask training approach with OV-KWS and ASR
tasks to optimize the model. Experiments show that this approach substantially
improves the entity recalls compared to the original Whisper model on Chinese
Aishell hot word subsets and two internal code-switch test sets. However, we
observed a slight increase in mixed-error-rate (MER) on internal test sets due
to catastrophic forgetting. To address this problem and use different sizes of
the Whisper model without finetuning, we propose to use OV-KWS as a separate
module and construct a spoken form prompt to prevent hallucination. The OV-KWS
module consistently improves MER and Entity Recall for whisper-small, medium,
and large models.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuang Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yinglu Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Min Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Su_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chang Su&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ren_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mengxin Ren&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Qiao_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaosong Qiao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhao_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaofeng Zhao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Piao_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mengyao Piao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiawei Yu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lv_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xinglin Lv&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ma_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Miaomiao Ma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhao_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yanqing Zhao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yang_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hao Yang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.12689">
<title>AMPLIFY:Attention-based Mixup for Performance Improvement and Label Smoothing in Transformer. (arXiv:2309.12689v2 [cs.LG] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.12689</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Mixup is an effective data augmentation method that generates new augmented
samples by aggregating linear combinations of different original samples.
However, if there are noises or aberrant features in the original samples,
Mixup may propagate them to the augmented samples, leading to over-sensitivity
of the model to these outliers . To solve this problem, this paper proposes a
new Mixup method called AMPLIFY. This method uses the Attention mechanism of
Transformer itself to reduce the influence of noises and aberrant values in the
original samples on the prediction results, without increasing additional
trainable parameters, and the computational cost is very low, thereby avoiding
the problem of high resource consumption in common Mixup methods such as
Sentence Mixup . The experimental results show that, under a smaller
computational resource cost, AMPLIFY outperforms other Mixup methods in text
classification tasks on 7 benchmark datasets, providing new ideas and new ways
to further improve the performance of pre-trained models based on the Attention
mechanism, such as BERT, ALBERT, RoBERTa, and GPT. Our code can be obtained at
https://github.com/kiwi-lilo/AMPLIFY.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yang_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Leixin Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xiang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yu Xiang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.14324">
<title>Towards General-Purpose Text-Instruction-Guided Voice Conversion. (arXiv:2309.14324v2 [eess.AS] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.14324</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This paper introduces a novel voice conversion (VC) model, guided by text
instructions such as &quot;articulate slowly with a deep tone&quot; or &quot;speak in a
cheerful boyish voice&quot;. Unlike traditional methods that rely on reference
utterances to determine the attributes of the converted speech, our model adds
versatility and specificity to voice conversion. The proposed VC model is a
neural codec language model which processes a sequence of discrete codes,
resulting in the code sequence of converted speech. It utilizes text
instructions as style prompts to modify the prosody and emotional information
of the given speech. In contrast to previous approaches, which often rely on
employing separate encoders like prosody and content encoders to handle
different aspects of the source speech, our model handles various information
of speech in an end-to-end manner. Experiments have demonstrated the impressive
capabilities of our model in comprehending instructions and delivering
reasonable results.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Kuan_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chun-Yi Kuan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Li_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chen An Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Hsu_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tsu-Yuan Hsu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Lin_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tse-Yang Lin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Chung_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ho-Lam Chung&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Chang_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kai-Wei Chang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Chang_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shuo-yiin Chang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Lee_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hung-yi Lee&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.16349">
<title>Human Feedback is not Gold Standard. (arXiv:2309.16349v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.16349</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Human feedback has become the de facto standard for evaluating the
performance of Large Language Models, and is increasingly being used as a
training objective. However, it is not clear which properties of a generated
output this single `preference&apos; score captures. We hypothesise that preference
scores are subjective and open to undesirable biases. We critically analyse the
use of human feedback for both training and evaluation, to verify whether it
fully captures a range of crucial error criteria. We find that while preference
scores have fairly good coverage, they under-represent important aspects like
factuality. We further hypothesise that both preference scores and error
annotation may be affected by confounders, and leverage instruction-tuned
models to generate outputs that vary along two possible confounding dimensions:
assertiveness and complexity. We find that the assertiveness of an output skews
the perceived rate of factuality errors, indicating that human annotations are
not a fully reliable evaluation metric or training objective. Finally, we offer
preliminary evidence that using human feedback as a training objective
disproportionately increases the assertiveness of model outputs. We encourage
future work to carefully consider whether preference scores are well aligned
with the desired objective.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hosking_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tom Hosking&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Blunsom_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Phil Blunsom&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bartolo_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Max Bartolo&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.16540">
<title>Unsupervised Pretraining for Fact Verification by Language Model Distillation. (arXiv:2309.16540v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2309.16540</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Fact verification aims to verify a claim using evidence from a trustworthy
knowledge base. To address this challenge, algorithms must produce features for
every claim that are both semantically meaningful, and compact enough to find a
semantic alignment with the source information. In contrast to previous work,
which tackled the alignment problem by learning over annotated corpora of
claims and their corresponding labels, we propose SFAVEL (Self-supervised Fact
Verification via Language Model Distillation), a novel unsupervised pretraining
framework that leverages pre-trained language models to distil self-supervised
features into high-quality claim-fact alignments without the need for
annotations. This is enabled by a novel contrastive loss function that
encourages features to attain high-quality claim and evidence alignments whilst
preserving the semantic relationships across the corpora. Notably, we present
results that achieve a new state-of-the-art on FB15k-237 (+5.3% Hits@1) and
FEVER (+8% accuracy) with linear evaluation.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bazaga_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Adri&amp;#xe1;n Bazaga&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lio_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pietro Li&amp;#xf2;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Micklem_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gos Micklem&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.00100">
<title>Multilingual Natural Language Processing Model for Radiology Reports -- The Summary is all you need!. (arXiv:2310.00100v4 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.00100</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The impression section of a radiology report summarizes important radiology
findings and plays a critical role in communicating these findings to
physicians. However, the preparation of these summaries is time-consuming and
error-prone for radiologists. Recently, numerous models for radiology report
summarization have been developed. Nevertheless, there is currently no model
that can summarize these reports in multiple languages. Such a model could
greatly improve future research and the development of Deep Learning models
that incorporate data from patients with different ethnic backgrounds. In this
study, the generation of radiology impressions in different languages was
automated by fine-tuning a model, publicly available, based on a multilingual
text-to-text Transformer to summarize findings available in English,
Portuguese, and German radiology reports. In a blind test, two board-certified
radiologists indicated that for at least 70% of the system-generated summaries,
the quality matched or exceeded the corresponding human-written summaries,
suggesting substantial clinical reliability. Furthermore, this study showed
that the multilingual model outperformed other models that specialized in
summarizing radiology reports in only one language, as well as models that were
not specifically designed for summarizing radiology reports, such as ChatGPT.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lindo_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mariana Lindo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Santos_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ana Sofia Santos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ferreira_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andr&amp;#xe9; Ferreira&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jianning Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Luijten_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gijs Luijten&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Correia_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gustavo Correia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kim_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Moon Kim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Schaarschmidt_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Benedikt Michael Schaarschmidt&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Deuschl_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Cornelius Deuschl&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Haubold_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Johannes Haubold&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kleesiek_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jens Kleesiek&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Egger_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jan Egger&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Alves_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Victor Alves&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.05378">
<title>Transcending the Attention Paradigm: Representation Learning from Geospatial Social Media Data. (arXiv:2310.05378v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.05378</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;While transformers have pioneered attention-driven architectures as a
cornerstone of language modeling, their dependence on explicitly contextual
information underscores limitations in their abilities to tacitly learn
overarching textual themes. This study challenges the heuristic paradigm of
performance benchmarking by investigating social media data as a source of
distributed patterns. In stark contrast to networks that rely on capturing
complex long-term dependencies, models of online data inherently lack structure
and are forced to detect latent structures in the aggregate. To properly
represent these abstract relationships, this research dissects empirical social
media corpora into their elemental components, analyzing over two billion
tweets across population-dense locations. We create Bag-of-Word embedding
specific to each city and compare their respective representations. This finds
that even amidst noisy data, geographic location has a considerable influence
on online communication, and that hidden insights can be uncovered without the
crutch of advanced algorithms. This evidence presents valuable geospatial
implications in social science and challenges the notion that intricate models
are prerequisites for pattern recognition in natural language. This aligns with
the evolving landscape that questions the embrace of absolute interpretability
over abstract understanding and bridges the divide between sophisticated
frameworks and intangible relationships.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+DiSanto_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nick DiSanto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Corso_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Anthony Corso&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sanders_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Benjamin Sanders&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Harding_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gavin Harding&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.05628">
<title>Glitter or Gold? Deriving Structured Insights from Sustainability Reports via Large Language Models. (arXiv:2310.05628v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.05628</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Over the last decade, several regulatory bodies have started requiring the
disclosure of non-financial information from publicly listed companies, in
light of the investors&apos; increasing attention to Environmental, Social, and
Governance (ESG) issues. Publicly released information on sustainability
practices is often disclosed in diverse, unstructured, and multi-modal
documentation. This poses a challenge in efficiently gathering and aligning the
data into a unified framework to derive insights related to Corporate Social
Responsibility (CSR). Thus, using Information Extraction (IE) methods becomes
an intuitive choice for delivering insightful and actionable data to
stakeholders. In this study, we employ Large Language Models (LLMs), In-Context
Learning, and the Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) paradigm to extract
structured insights related to ESG aspects from companies&apos; sustainability
reports. We then leverage graph-based representations to conduct statistical
analyses concerning the extracted insights. These analyses revealed that ESG
criteria cover a wide range of topics, exceeding 500, often beyond those
considered in existing categorizations, and are addressed by companies through
a variety of initiatives. Moreover, disclosure similarities emerged among
companies from the same region or sector, validating ongoing hypotheses in the
ESG literature. Lastly, by incorporating additional company attributes into our
analyses, we investigated which factors impact the most on companies&apos; ESG
ratings, showing that ESG disclosure affects the obtained ratings more than
other financial or company data.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bronzini_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marco Bronzini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Nicolini_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Carlo Nicolini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lepri_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bruno Lepri&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Passerini_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrea Passerini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Staiano_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jacopo Staiano&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.05782">
<title>Aligning Language Models with Human Preferences via a Bayesian Approach. (arXiv:2310.05782v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.05782</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In the quest to advance human-centric natural language generation (NLG)
systems, ensuring alignment between NLG models and human preferences is
crucial. For this alignment, current popular methods leverage a reinforcement
learning (RL) approach with a reward model trained on feedback from humans.
However, inherent disagreements due to the subjective nature of human
preferences pose a significant challenge for training the reward model,
resulting in a deterioration of the NLG performance. To tackle this issue,
previous approaches typically rely on majority voting or averaging to
consolidate multiple inconsistent preferences into a merged one. Although
straightforward to understand and execute, such methods suffer from an
inability to capture the nuanced degrees of disaggregation among humans and may
only represent a specialized subset of individuals, thereby lacking the ability
to quantitatively disclose the universality of human preferences. To address
this challenge, this paper proposes a novel approach, which employs a Bayesian
framework to account for the distribution of disagreements among human
preferences as training a preference model, and names it as d-PM. Besides,
considering the RL strategy&apos;s inefficient and complex training process over the
training efficiency, we further propose utilizing the contrastive learning
strategy to train the NLG model with the preference scores derived from the
d-PM model. Extensive experiments on two human-centric NLG tasks, i.e.,
emotional support conversation and integrity &quot;Rule-of-Thumb&quot; generation, show
that our method consistently exceeds previous SOTA models in both automatic and
human evaluations.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiashuo Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Haozhao Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sun_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shichao Sun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wenjie Li&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.08279">
<title>Can Text-based Knowledge Graph Completion Benefit From Zero-Shot Large Language Models?. (arXiv:2310.08279v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.08279</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Text-based knowledge graph completion (KGC) methods, leveraging textual
entity descriptions are at the research forefront. The efficacy of these models
hinges on the quality of the textual data. This study explores whether enriched
or more efficient textual descriptions can amplify model performance. Recently,
Large Language Models (LLMs) have shown remarkable improvements in NLP tasks,
attributed to their sophisticated text generation and conversational
capabilities. LLMs assimilate linguistic patterns and integrate knowledge from
their training data. Compared to traditional databases like Wikipedia, LLMs
provide several advantages, facilitating broader information querying and
content augmentation. We hypothesize that LLMs, without fine-tuning, can refine
entity descriptions, serving as an auxiliary knowledge source. An in-depth
analysis was conducted to verify this hypothesis. We found that (1) without
fine-tuning, LLMs have the capability to further improve the quality of entity
text descriptions. We validated this through experiments on the FB15K-237 and
WN18RR datasets. (2) LLMs exhibit text generation hallucination issues and
selectively output words with multiple meanings. This was mitigated by
contextualizing prompts to constrain LLM outputs. (3) Larger model sizes do not
necessarily guarantee better performance; even the 7B model can achieve
optimized results in this comparative task. These findings underscore the
untapped potential of large models in text-based KGC, which is a promising
direction for further research in KGC. The code and datasets are accessible at
\href{https://github.com/sjlmg/CP-KGC}.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yang_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rui Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Fang_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Li Fang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhou_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yi Zhou&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.10788">
<title>Self-Supervised Models of Speech Infer Universal Articulatory Kinematics. (arXiv:2310.10788v2 [eess.AS] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.10788</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Self-Supervised Learning (SSL) based models of speech have shown remarkable
performance on a range of downstream tasks. These state-of-the-art models have
remained blackboxes, but many recent studies have begun &quot;probing&quot; models like
HuBERT, to correlate their internal representations to different aspects of
speech. In this paper, we show &quot;inference of articulatory kinematics&quot; as
fundamental property of SSL models, i.e., the ability of these models to
transform acoustics into the causal articulatory dynamics underlying the speech
signal. We also show that this abstraction is largely overlapping across the
language of the data used to train the model, with preference to the language
with similar phonological system. Furthermore, we show that with simple affine
transformations, Acoustic-to-Articulatory inversion (AAI) is transferrable
across speakers, even across genders, languages, and dialects, showing the
generalizability of this property. Together, these results shed new light on
the internals of SSL models that are critical to their superior performance,
and open up new avenues into language-agnostic universal models for speech
engineering, that are interpretable and grounded in speech science.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Cho_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Cheol Jun Cho&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Mohamed_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Abdelrahman Mohamed&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Black_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alan W Black&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Anumanchipalli_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gopala K. Anumanchipalli&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.10803">
<title>SD-HuBERT: Sentence-Level Self-Distillation Induces Syllabic Organization in HuBERT. (arXiv:2310.10803v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.10803</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Data-driven unit discovery in self-supervised learning (SSL) of speech has
embarked on a new era of spoken language processing. Yet, the discovered units
often remain in phonetic space and the units beyond phonemes are largely
underexplored. Here, we demonstrate that a syllabic organization emerges in
learning sentence-level representation of speech. In particular, we adopt
&quot;self-distillation&quot; objective to fine-tune the pretrained HuBERT with an
aggregator token that summarizes the entire sentence. Without any supervision,
the resulting model draws definite boundaries in speech, and the
representations across frames exhibit salient syllabic structures. We
demonstrate that this emergent structure largely corresponds to the ground
truth syllables. Furthermore, we propose a new benchmark task, Spoken Speech
ABX, for evaluating sentence-level representation of speech. When compared to
previous models, our model outperforms in both unsupervised syllable discovery
and learning sentence-level representation. Together, we demonstrate that the
self-distillation of HuBERT gives rise to syllabic organization without relying
on external labels or modalities, and potentially provides novel data-driven
units for spoken language modeling.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cho_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Cheol Jun Cho&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Mohamed_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Abdelrahman Mohamed&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shang-Wen Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Black_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alan W Black&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Anumanchipalli_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gopala K. Anumanchipalli&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.11454">
<title>VeRA: Vector-based Random Matrix Adaptation. (arXiv:2310.11454v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.11454</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Low-rank adapation (LoRA) is a popular method that reduces the number of
trainable parameters when finetuning large language models, but still faces
acute storage challenges when scaling to even larger models or deploying
numerous per-user or per-task adapted models. In this work, we present
Vector-based Random Matrix Adaptation (VeRA), which significantly reduces the
number of trainable parameters compared to LoRA, yet maintains the same
performance. It achieves this by using a single pair of low-rank matrices
shared across all layers and learning small scaling vectors instead. We
demonstrate its effectiveness on the GLUE and E2E benchmarks, image
classification tasks, and show its application in instruction-tuning of 7B and
13B language models.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kopiczko_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dawid J. Kopiczko&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Blankevoort_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tijmen Blankevoort&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Asano_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuki M. Asano&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.12798">
<title>MolCA: Molecular Graph-Language Modeling with Cross-Modal Projector and Uni-Modal Adapter. (arXiv:2310.12798v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.12798</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Language Models (LMs) have demonstrated impressive molecule understanding
ability on various 1D text-related tasks. However, they inherently lack 2D
graph perception - a critical ability of human professionals in comprehending
molecules&apos; topological structures. To bridge this gap, we propose MolCA:
Molecular Graph-Language Modeling with Cross-Modal Projector and Uni-Modal
Adapter. MolCA enables an LM (e.g., Galactica) to understand both text- and
graph-based molecular contents via the cross-modal projector. Specifically, the
cross-modal projector is implemented as a Q-Former to connect a graph encoder&apos;s
representation space and an LM&apos;s text space. Further, MolCA employs a uni-modal
adapter (i.e., LoRA) for the LM&apos;s efficient adaptation to downstream tasks.
Unlike previous studies that couple an LM with a graph encoder via cross-modal
contrastive learning, MolCA retains the LM&apos;s ability of open-ended text
generation and augments it with 2D graph information. To showcase its
effectiveness, we extensively benchmark MolCA on tasks of molecule captioning,
IUPAC name prediction, and molecule-text retrieval, on which MolCA
significantly outperforms the baselines. Our codes and checkpoints can be found
at https://github.com/acharkq/MolCA.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhiyuan Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sihang Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Luo_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yanchen Luo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Fei_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hao Fei&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cao_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yixin Cao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kawaguchi_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kenji Kawaguchi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiang Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chua_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tat-Seng Chua&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.14053">
<title>Beyond Accuracy: Evaluating Self-Consistency of Code Large Language Models with IdentityChain. (arXiv:2310.14053v2 [cs.LG] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.14053</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Code Large Language Models (Code LLMs) are being increasingly employed in
real-life applications, so evaluating them is critical. While the conventional
accuracy evaluates the performance of Code LLMs on a set of individual tasks,
their self-consistency across different tasks is overlooked. Intuitively, a
trustworthy model should be self-consistent when generating natural language
specifications for its own code and generating code for its own specifications.
Failure to preserve self-consistency reveals a lack of understanding of the
shared semantics underlying natural language and programming language, and
therefore undermines the trustworthiness of a model. In this paper, we first
formally define the self-consistency of Code LLMs and then design a framework,
IdentityChain, which effectively and efficiently evaluates the self-consistency
and conventional accuracy of a model at the same time. We study eleven Code
LLMs and show that they fail to preserve self-consistency, which is indeed a
distinct aspect from conventional accuracy. Furthermore, we show that
IdentityChain can be used as a model debugging tool to expose weaknesses of
Code LLMs by demonstrating three major weaknesses that we identify in current
models using IdentityChain. Our code is available at
https://github.com/marcusm117/IdentityChain.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Min_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marcus J. Min&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ding_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yangruibo Ding&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Buratti_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Luca Buratti&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Pujar_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Saurabh Pujar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kaiser_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gail Kaiser&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jana_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Suman Jana&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ray_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Baishakhi Ray&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.18341">
<title>CXR-LLAVA: a multimodal large language model for interpreting chest X-ray images. (arXiv:2310.18341v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.18341</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Purpose: This study aimed to develop an open-source multimodal large language
model (CXR-LLAVA) for interpreting chest X-ray images (CXRs), leveraging recent
advances in large language models (LLMs) to potentially replicate the image
interpretation skills of human radiologists Materials and Methods: For
training, we collected 592,580 publicly available CXRs, of which 374,881 had
labels for certain radiographic abnormalities (Dataset 1) and 217,699 provided
free-text radiology reports (Dataset 2). After pre-training a vision
transformer with Dataset 1, we integrated it with an LLM influenced by the
LLAVA network. Then, the model was fine-tuned, primarily using Dataset 2. The
model&apos;s diagnostic performance for major pathological findings was evaluated,
along with the acceptability of radiologic reports by human radiologists, to
gauge its potential for autonomous reporting. Results: The model demonstrated
impressive performance in test sets, achieving an average F1 score of 0.81 for
six major pathological findings in the MIMIC internal test set and 0.62 for
seven major pathological findings in the external test set. The model&apos;s F1
scores surpassed those of GPT-4-vision and Gemini-Pro-Vision in both test sets.
In human radiologist evaluations of the external test set, the model achieved a
72.7% success rate in autonomous reporting, slightly below the 84.0% rate of
ground truth reports. Conclusion: This study highlights the significant
potential of multimodal LLMs for CXR interpretation, while also acknowledging
the performance limitations. Despite these challenges, we believe that making
our model open-source will catalyze further research, expanding its
effectiveness and applicability in various clinical contexts. CXR-LLAVA is
available at https://github.com/ECOFRI/CXR_LLAVA.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lee_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Seowoo Lee&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Youn_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiwon Youn&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kim_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hyungjin Kim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kim_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mansu Kim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yoon_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Soon Ho Yoon&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.19680">
<title>Integrating Pre-trained Language Model into Neural Machine Translation. (arXiv:2310.19680v4 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.19680</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Neural Machine Translation (NMT) has become a significant technology in
natural language processing through extensive research and development.
However, the deficiency of high-quality bilingual language pair data still
poses a major challenge to improving NMT performance. Recent studies have been
exploring the use of contextual information from pre-trained language model
(PLM) to address this problem. Yet, the issue of incompatibility between PLM
and NMT model remains unresolved. This study proposes PLM-integrated NMT
(PiNMT) model to overcome the identified problems. PiNMT model consists of
three critical components, PLM Multi Layer Converter, Embedding Fusion, and
Cosine Alignment, each playing a vital role in providing effective PLM
information to NMT. Furthermore, two training strategies, Separate Learning
Rates and Dual Step Training, are also introduced in this paper. By
implementing the proposed PiNMT model and training strategy, we achieve
state-of-the-art performance on the IWSLT&apos;14 En$\leftrightarrow$De dataset.
This study&apos;s outcomes are noteworthy as they demonstrate a novel approach for
efficiently integrating PLM with NMT to overcome incompatibility and enhance
performance.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hwang_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Soon-Jae Hwang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jeong_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chang-Sung Jeong&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.20501">
<title>LLMs may Dominate Information Access: Neural Retrievers are Biased Towards LLM-Generated Texts. (arXiv:2310.20501v2 [cs.IR] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.20501</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Recently, the emergence of large language models (LLMs) has revolutionized
the paradigm of information retrieval (IR) applications, especially in web
search. With their remarkable capabilities in generating human-like texts, LLMs
have created enormous texts on the Internet. As a result, IR systems in the
LLMs era are facing a new challenge: the indexed documents now are not only
written by human beings but also automatically generated by the LLMs. How these
LLM-generated documents influence the IR systems is a pressing and still
unexplored question. In this work, we conduct a quantitative evaluation of
different IR models in scenarios where both human-written and LLM-generated
texts are involved. Surprisingly, our findings indicate that neural retrieval
models tend to rank LLM-generated documents higher. We refer to this category
of biases in neural retrieval models towards the LLM-generated text as the
\textbf{source bias}. Moreover, we discover that this bias is not confined to
the first-stage neural retrievers, but extends to the second-stage neural
re-rankers. Then, we provide an in-depth analysis from the perspective of text
compression and observe that neural models can better understand the semantic
information of LLM-generated text, which is further substantiated by our
theoretical analysis. To mitigate the source bias, we also propose a
plug-and-play debiased constraint for the optimization objective, and
experimental results show the effectiveness. Finally, we discuss the potential
severe concerns stemming from the observed source bias and hope our findings
can serve as a critical wake-up call to the IR community and beyond. To
facilitate future explorations of IR in the LLM era, the constructed two new
benchmarks and codes will later be available at
\url{https://github.com/KID-22/LLM4IR-Bias}.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Dai_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sunhao Dai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhou_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuqi Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Pang_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Liang Pang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Weihao Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hu_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaolin Hu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yong Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiao Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gang Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jun Xu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.03220">
<title>ALYMPICS: LLM Agents Meet Game Theory -- Exploring Strategic Decision-Making with AI Agents. (arXiv:2311.03220v4 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.03220</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This paper introduces Alympics (Olympics for Agents), a systematic simulation
framework utilizing Large Language Model (LLM) agents for game theory research.
Alympics creates a versatile platform for studying complex game theory
problems, bridging the gap between theoretical game theory and empirical
investigations by providing a controlled environment for simulating human-like
strategic interactions with LLM agents. In our pilot case study, the &quot;Water
Allocation Challenge,&quot; we explore Alympics through a challenging strategic game
focused on the multi-round auction on scarce survival resources. This study
demonstrates the framework&apos;s ability to qualitatively and quantitatively
analyze game determinants, strategies, and outcomes. Additionally, we conduct a
comprehensive human assessment and an in-depth evaluation of LLM agents in
strategic decision-making scenarios. Our findings not only expand the
understanding of LLM agents&apos; proficiency in emulating human strategic behavior
but also highlight their potential in advancing game theory knowledge, thereby
enriching our understanding of both game theory and empowering further research
into strategic decision-making domains with LLM agents. Codes, prompts, and all
related resources are available at https://github.com/microsoft/Alympics.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Mao_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shaoguang Mao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cai_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuzhe Cai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xia_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yan Xia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wu_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wenshan Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xun Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fengyi Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ge_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tao Ge&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wei_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Furu Wei&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.04076">
<title>Do LLMs exhibit human-like response biases? A case study in survey design. (arXiv:2311.04076v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.04076</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;As large language models (LLMs) become more capable, there is growing
excitement about the possibility of using LLMs as proxies for humans in
real-world tasks where subjective labels are desired, such as in surveys and
opinion polling. One widely-cited barrier to the adoption of LLMs is their
sensitivity to prompt wording - but interestingly, humans also display
sensitivities to instruction changes in the form of response biases. As such,
we argue that if LLMs are going to be used to approximate human opinions, it is
necessary to investigate the extent to which LLMs also reflect human response
biases, if at all. In this work, we use survey design as a case study, where
human response biases caused by permutations in wordings of &quot;prompts&quot; have been
extensively studied. Drawing from prior work in social psychology, we design a
dataset and propose a framework to evaluate whether LLMs exhibit human-like
response biases in survey questionnaires. Our comprehensive evaluation of nine
models shows that popular open and commercial LLMs generally fail to reflect
human-like behavior. These inconsistencies tend to be more prominent in models
that have been instruction fine-tuned. Furthermore, even if a model shows a
significant change in the same direction as humans, we find that perturbations
that are not meant to elicit significant changes in humans may also result in a
similar change. These results highlight the potential pitfalls of using LLMs to
substitute humans in parts of the annotation pipeline, and further underscore
the importance of finer-grained characterizations of model behavior. Our code,
dataset, and collected samples are available at
https://github.com/lindiatjuatja/BiasMonkey
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tjuatja_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lindia Tjuatja&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Valerie Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wu_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sherry Tongshuang Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Talwalkar_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ameet Talwalkar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Neubig_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Graham Neubig&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.04131">
<title>Locating Cross-Task Sequence Continuation Circuits in Transformers. (arXiv:2311.04131v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.04131</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;While transformer models exhibit strong capabilities on linguistic tasks,
their complex architectures make them difficult to interpret. Recent work has
aimed to reverse engineer transformer models into human-readable
representations called circuits that implement algorithmic functions. We extend
this research by analyzing and comparing circuits for similar sequence
continuation tasks, which include increasing sequences of digits, number words,
and months. Through the application of circuit analysis techniques, we identify
key sub-circuits responsible for detecting sequence members and for predicting
the next member in a sequence. Our analysis reveals that semantically related
sequences rely on shared circuit subgraphs with analogous roles. Overall,
documenting shared computational structures enables better prediction of model
behaviors, identification of errors, and safer editing procedures. This
mechanistic understanding of transformers is a critical step towards building
more robust, aligned, and interpretable language models.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lan_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michael Lan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Barez_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fazl Barez&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.08724">
<title>Knowledge Graph Construction in Power Distribution Networks. (arXiv:2311.08724v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.08724</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we propose a method for knowledge graph construction in power
distribution networks. This method leverages entity features, which involve
their semantic, phonetic, and syntactic characteristics, in both the knowledge
graph of distribution network and the dispatching texts. An enhanced model
based on Convolutional Neural Network, is utilized for effectively matching
dispatch text entities with those in the knowledge graph. The effectiveness of
this model is evaluated through experiments in real-world power distribution
dispatch scenarios. The results indicate that, compared with the baselines, the
proposed model excels in linking a variety of entity types, demonstrating high
overall accuracy in power distribution knowledge graph construction task.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiang Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Che Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bing Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hao Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sizhe Li&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.09812">
<title>Large Language Models for Propaganda Span Annotation. (arXiv:2311.09812v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.09812</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The use of propagandistic techniques in online contents has increased in
recent years aiming to manipulate online audiences. Efforts to automatically
detect and debunk such content have been made addressing various modeling
scenarios. These include determining whether the content (text, image, or
multimodal) (i) is propagandistic, (ii) employs one or more propagandistic
techniques, and (iii) includes techniques with identifiable spans. Significant
research efforts have been devoted to the first two scenarios compared to the
latter. Therefore, in this study, we focus on the task of detecting
propagandistic textual spans. Specifically, we investigate whether large
language models (LLMs), such as GPT-4, can effectively perform the task.
Moreover, we study the potential of employing the model to collect more
cost-effective annotations. Our experiments use a large-scale in-house dataset
consisting of annotations from human annotators with varying expertise levels.
The results suggest that providing more information to the model as prompts
improves its performance compared to human annotations. Moreover, our work is
the first to show the potential of utilizing LLMs to develop annotated datasets
for this specific task, prompting it with annotations from human annotators
with limited expertise. We plan to make the collected span-level labels from
multiple annotators, including GPT-4, available for the community.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hasanain_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Maram Hasanain&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ahmed_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fatema Ahmed&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Alam_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Firoj Alam&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12275">
<title>Enabling On-Device Large Language Model Personalization with Self-Supervised Data Selection and Synthesis. (arXiv:2311.12275v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12275</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;After a large language model (LLM) is deployed on edge devices, it is
desirable for these devices to learn from user-generated conversation data to
generate user-specific and personalized responses in real-time. However,
user-generated data usually contains sensitive and private information, and
uploading such data to the cloud for annotation is not preferred if not
prohibited. While it is possible to obtain annotation locally by directly
asking users to provide preferred responses, such annotations have to be sparse
to not affect user experience. In addition, the storage of edge devices is
usually too limited to enable large-scale fine-tuning with full user-generated
data. It remains an open question how to enable on-device LLM personalization,
considering sparse annotation and limited on-device storage. In this paper, we
propose a novel framework to select and store the most representative data
online in a self-supervised way. Such data has a small memory footprint and
allows infrequent requests of user annotations for further fine-tuning. To
enhance fine-tuning quality, multiple semantically similar pairs of question
texts and expected responses are generated using the LLM. Our experiments show
that the proposed framework achieves the best user-specific content-generating
capability (accuracy) and fine-tuning speed (performance) compared with vanilla
baselines. To the best of our knowledge, this is the very first on-device LLM
personalization framework.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Qin_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ruiyang Qin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xia_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jun Xia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jia_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhenge Jia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jiang_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Meng Jiang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Abbasi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ahmed Abbasi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhou_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Peipei Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jingtong Hu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shi_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yiyu Shi&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.13708">
<title>Dynamic Fault Analysis in Substations Based on Knowledge Graphs. (arXiv:2311.13708v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.13708</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;To address the challenge of identifying hidden danger in substations from
unstructured text, a novel dynamic analysis method is proposed. We first
extract relevant information from the unstructured text, and then leverages a
flexible distributed search engine built on Elastic-Search to handle the data.
Following this, the hidden Markov model is employed to train the data within
the engine. The Viterbi algorithm is integrated to decipher the hidden state
sequences, facilitating the segmentation and labeling of entities related to
hidden dangers. The final step involves using the Neo4j graph database to
dynamically create a knowledge graph that visualizes hidden dangers in the
substation. The effectiveness of the proposed method is demonstrated through a
case analysis from a specific substation with hidden dangers revealed in the
text records.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Weiwei Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xing Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lu Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sizhe Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Fan_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hui Fan&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.15565">
<title>Evaluating the Efficacy of Hybrid Deep Learning Models in Distinguishing AI-Generated Text. (arXiv:2311.15565v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.15565</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;My research investigates the use of cutting-edge hybrid deep learning models
to accurately differentiate between AI-generated text and human writing. I
applied a robust methodology, utilising a carefully selected dataset comprising
AI and human texts from various sources, each tagged with instructions.
Advanced natural language processing techniques facilitated the analysis of
textual features. Combining sophisticated neural networks, the custom model
enabled it to detect nuanced differences between AI and human content.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Oketunji_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Abiodun Finbarrs Oketunji&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.16522">
<title>Dynamic Fault Characteristics Evaluation in Power Grid. (arXiv:2311.16522v2 [cs.LG] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.16522</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;To enhance the intelligence degree in operation and maintenance, a novel
method for fault detection in power grids is proposed. The proposed GNN-based
approach first identifies fault nodes through a specialized feature extraction
method coupled with a knowledge graph. By incorporating temporal data, the
method leverages the status of nodes from preceding and subsequent time periods
to help current fault detection. To validate the effectiveness of the node
features, a correlation analysis of the output features from each node was
conducted. The results from experiments show that this method can accurately
locate fault nodes in simulation scenarios with a remarkable accuracy.
Additionally, the graph neural network based feature modeling allows for a
qualitative examination of how faults spread across nodes, which provides
valuable insights for analyzing fault nodes.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Pei_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hao Pei&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lin_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Si Lin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chuanfu Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Che Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Haoming Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sizhe Li&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.16989">
<title>ChatGPT&apos;s One-year Anniversary: Are Open-Source Large Language Models Catching up?. (arXiv:2311.16989v4 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.16989</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Upon its release in late 2022, ChatGPT has brought a seismic shift in the
entire landscape of AI, both in research and commerce. Through
instruction-tuning a large language model (LLM) with supervised fine-tuning and
reinforcement learning from human feedback, it showed that a model could answer
human questions and follow instructions on a broad panel of tasks. Following
this success, interests in LLMs have intensified, with new LLMs flourishing at
frequent interval across academia and industry, including many start-ups
focused on LLMs. While closed-source LLMs (e.g., OpenAI&apos;s GPT, Anthropic&apos;s
Claude) generally outperform their open-source counterparts, the progress on
the latter has been rapid with claims of achieving parity or even better on
certain tasks. This has crucial implications not only on research but also on
business. In this work, on the first anniversary of ChatGPT, we provide an
exhaustive overview of this success, surveying all tasks where an open-source
LLM has claimed to be on par or better than ChatGPT.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hailin Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jiao_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fangkai Jiao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xingxuan Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Qin_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chengwei Qin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ravaut_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mathieu Ravaut&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhao_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ruochen Zhao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xiong_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Caiming Xiong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Joty_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shafiq Joty&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.04350">
<title>CLadder: A Benchmark to Assess Causal Reasoning Capabilities of Language Models. (arXiv:2312.04350v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.04350</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The ability to perform causal reasoning is widely considered a core feature
of intelligence. In this work, we investigate whether large language models
(LLMs) can coherently reason about causality. Much of the existing work in
natural language processing (NLP) focuses on evaluating commonsense causal
reasoning in LLMs, thus failing to assess whether a model can perform causal
inference in accordance with a set of well-defined formal rules. To address
this, we propose a new NLP task, causal inference in natural language, inspired
by the &quot;causal inference engine&quot; postulated by Judea Pearl et al. We compose a
large dataset, CLadder, with 10K samples: based on a collection of causal
graphs and queries (associational, interventional, and counterfactual), we
obtain symbolic questions and ground-truth answers, through an oracle causal
inference engine. These are then translated into natural language. We evaluate
multiple LLMs on our dataset, and we introduce and evaluate a bespoke
chain-of-thought prompting strategy, CausalCoT. We show that our task is highly
challenging for LLMs, and we conduct an in-depth analysis to gain deeper
insights into the causal reasoning abilities of LLMs. Our data is open-sourced
at https://huggingface.co/datasets/causalNLP/cladder, and our code can be found
at https://github.com/causalNLP/cladder.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jin_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhijing Jin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuen Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Leeb_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Felix Leeb&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gresele_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Luigi Gresele&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kamal_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ojasv Kamal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lyu_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhiheng Lyu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Blin_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kevin Blin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Adauto_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fernando Gonzalez Adauto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kleiman_Weiner_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Max Kleiman-Weiner&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sachan_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mrinmaya Sachan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Scholkopf_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bernhard Sch&amp;#xf6;lkopf&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.06355">
<title>Linguistic and Structural Basis of Engineering Design Knowledge. (arXiv:2312.06355v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.06355</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Artefact descriptions are the primary carriers of engineering design
knowledge that is both an outcome and a driver of the design process. While an
artefact could be described in different connotations, the design process
requires a description to embody engineering design knowledge, which is
expressed in the text through intricate placement of entities and
relationships. As large-language models learn from all kinds of text merely as
a sequence of characters/tokens, these are yet to generate text that embodies
explicit engineering design facts. Existing ontological design theories are
less likely to guide the large-language models whose applications are currently
limited to ideation and learning purposes. In this article, we explicate
engineering design knowledge as knowledge graphs from a large sample of 33,881
patent documents. We examine the constituents of these knowledge graphs to
understand the linguistic and structural basis of engineering design knowledge.
In terms of linguistic basis, we observe that entities and relationships could
be generalised to 64 and 24 linguistic syntaxes. While relationships mainly
capture attributes (&apos;of&apos;), structure (&apos;in&apos;, &apos;with&apos;), purpose (&apos;to&apos;, &apos;for&apos;),
hierarchy (&apos;include&apos;), exemplification (&apos;such as&apos;), and behaviour (&apos;to&apos;,
&apos;from&apos;), the hierarchical relationships could specifically be identified using
75 unique syntaxes. To understand the structural basis, we draw inspiration
from various studies on biological/ecological networks and discover motifs from
patent knowledge graphs. We identify four 3-node and four 4-node patterns that
could further be converged and simplified into sequence [-&amp;gt;...-&amp;gt;], aggregation
[-&amp;gt;...&amp;lt;-], and hierarchy [&amp;lt;-...-&amp;gt;]. Expected to guide large-language model
based design tools, we propose few regulatory precepts for concretising
abstract entities and relationships within subgraphs, while explicating
hierarchical structures.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Siddharth_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;L. Siddharth&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Luo_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jianxi Luo&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09211">
<title>Mitigating Outlier Activations in Low-Precision Fine-Tuning of Language Models. (arXiv:2312.09211v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09211</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Low-precision fine-tuning of language models has gained prominence as a
cost-effective and energy-efficient approach to deploying large-scale models in
various applications. However, this approach is susceptible to the existence of
outlier values in activation. The outlier values in the activation can
negatively affect the performance of fine-tuning language models in the
low-precision regime since they affect the scaling factor and thus make
representing smaller values harder. This paper investigates techniques for
mitigating outlier activation in low-precision integer fine-tuning of the
language models. Our proposed novel approach enables us to represent the
outlier activation values in 8-bit integers instead of floating-point (FP16)
values. The benefit of using integers for outlier values is that it enables us
to use operator tiling to avoid performing 16-bit integer matrix multiplication
to address this problem effectively. We provide theoretical analysis and
supporting experiments to demonstrate the effectiveness of our approach in
improving the robustness and performance of low-precision fine-tuned language
models.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ghaffari_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alireza Ghaffari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Justin Yu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Nejad_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mahsa Ghazvini Nejad&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Asgharian_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Masoud Asgharian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Boxing Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Nia_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vahid Partovi Nia&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.10048">
<title>Knowledge Graph Enhanced Aspect-Level Sentiment Analysis. (arXiv:2312.10048v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.10048</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we propose a novel method to enhance sentiment analysis by
addressing the challenge of context-specific word meanings. It combines the
advantages of a BERT model with a knowledge graph based synonym data. This
synergy leverages a dynamic attention mechanism to develop a knowledge-driven
state vector. For classifying sentiments linked to specific aspects, the
approach constructs a memory bank integrating positional data. The data are
then analyzed using a DCGRU to pinpoint sentiment characteristics related to
specific aspect terms. Experiments on three widely used datasets demonstrate
the superior performance of our method in sentiment classification.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sharma_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kavita Sharma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Patel_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ritu Patel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Iyer_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sunita Iyer&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11193">
<title>&quot;Paraphrasing The Original Text&quot; Makes High Accuracy Long-Context QA. (arXiv:2312.11193v7 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11193</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Most open-source generative language models currently have a context window
of no more than 4k, limiting their ability when facing long text. Many previous
efforts have tried to extend the context window of models, but their actual
effects have been found to be very limited. To address this issue, we
theoretically analyze the effectiveness of the long-context training data and
find that long-context training requires &quot;effective&quot; data rather than simply
&quot;long&quot; data, which is rarely noticed in previous studies. Thus, we propose
adding &quot;original text paraphrasing&quot; to enhance the effectiveness of the data.
The model trained on our re-fined dataset obtains excellent long-context
capabilities and achieves state-of-the-art accuracy on multi-document retrieval
and QA tasks among models of comparable scales. The model and training data
have been made available on
HuggingFace(https://huggingface.co/yuyijiong/Qwen-14b-chat-yarn-32k) and
WiseModel(https://wisemodel.cn/models/yuyijiong/Qwen-14b-chat-yarn-32k).
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yijiong Yu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12108">
<title>Knowledge Graph Error Detection with Contrastive Confidence Adaption. (arXiv:2312.12108v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12108</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Knowledge graphs (KGs) often contain various errors. Previous works on
detecting errors in KGs mainly rely on triplet embedding from graph structure.
We conduct an empirical study and find that these works struggle to
discriminate noise from semantically-similar correct triplets. In this paper,
we propose a KG error detection model CCA to integrate both textual and graph
structural information from triplet reconstruction for better distinguishing
semantics. We design interactive contrastive learning to capture the
differences between textual and structural patterns. Furthermore, we construct
realistic datasets with semantically-similar noise and adversarial noise.
Experimental results demonstrate that CCA outperforms state-of-the-art
baselines, especially in detecting semantically-similar noise and adversarial
noise.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiangyu Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yang Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hu_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei Hu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.14033">
<title>T-Eval: Evaluating the Tool Utilization Capability of Large Language Models Step by Step. (arXiv:2312.14033v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.14033</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Large language models (LLM) have achieved remarkable performance on various
NLP tasks and are augmented by tools for broader applications. Yet, how to
evaluate and analyze the tool-utilization capability of LLMs is still
under-explored. In contrast to previous works that evaluate models
holistically, we comprehensively decompose the tool utilization into multiple
sub-processes, including instruction following, planning, reasoning, retrieval,
understanding, and review. Based on that, we further introduce T-Eval to
evaluate the tool utilization capability step by step. T-Eval disentangles the
tool utilization evaluation into several sub-domains along model capabilities,
facilitating the inner understanding of both holistic and isolated competency
of LLMs. We conduct extensive experiments on T-Eval and in-depth analysis of
various LLMs. T-Eval not only exhibits consistency with the outcome-oriented
evaluation but also provides a more fine-grained analysis of the capabilities
of LLMs, providing a new perspective in LLM evaluation on tool-utilization
ability. The benchmark will be available at
https://github.com/open-compass/T-Eval.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zehui Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Du_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Weihua Du&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wenwei Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kuikun Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiangning Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zheng_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Miao Zheng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhuo_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jingming Zhuo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Songyang Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lin_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dahua Lin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kai Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhao_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Feng Zhao&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.17267">
<title>Improving Low-resource Prompt-based Relation Representation with Multi-view Decoupling Learning. (arXiv:2312.17267v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.17267</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Recently, prompt-tuning with pre-trained language models (PLMs) has
demonstrated the significantly enhancing ability of relation extraction (RE)
tasks. However, in low-resource scenarios, where the available training data is
scarce, previous prompt-based methods may still perform poorly for prompt-based
representation learning due to a superficial understanding of the relation. To
this end, we highlight the importance of learning high-quality relation
representation in low-resource scenarios for RE, and propose a novel
prompt-based relation representation method, named MVRE
(\underline{M}ulti-\underline{V}iew \underline{R}elation
\underline{E}xtraction), to better leverage the capacity of PLMs to improve the
performance of RE within the low-resource prompt-tuning paradigm. Specifically,
MVRE decouples each relation into different perspectives to encompass
multi-view relation representations for maximizing the likelihood during
relation inference. Furthermore, we also design a Global-Local loss and a
Dynamic-Initialization method for better alignment of the multi-view
relation-representing virtual words, containing the semantics of relation
labels during the optimization learning process and initialization. Extensive
experiments on three benchmark datasets show that our method can achieve
state-of-the-art in low-resource settings.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Fan_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chenghao Fan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wei_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei Wei&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Qu_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaoye Qu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lu_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhenyi Lu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xie_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wenfeng Xie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cheng_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yu Cheng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dangyang Chen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.17482">
<title>MosaicBERT: A Bidirectional Encoder Optimized for Fast Pretraining. (arXiv:2312.17482v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.17482</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Although BERT-style encoder models are heavily used in NLP research, many
researchers do not pretrain their own BERTs from scratch due to the high cost
of training. In the past half-decade since BERT first rose to prominence, many
advances have been made with other transformer architectures and training
configurations that have yet to be systematically incorporated into BERT. Here,
we introduce MosaicBERT, a BERT-style encoder architecture and training recipe
that is empirically optimized for fast pretraining. This efficient architecture
incorporates FlashAttention, Attention with Linear Biases (ALiBi), Gated Linear
Units (GLU), a module to dynamically remove padded tokens, and low precision
LayerNorm into the classic transformer encoder block. The training recipe
includes a 30% masking ratio for the Masked Language Modeling (MLM) objective,
bfloat16 precision, and vocabulary size optimized for GPU throughput, in
addition to best-practices from RoBERTa and other encoder models. When
pretrained from scratch on the C4 dataset, this base model achieves a
downstream average GLUE (dev) score of 79.6 in 1.13 hours on 8 A100 80 GB GPUs
at a cost of roughly $20. We plot extensive accuracy vs. pretraining speed
Pareto curves and show that MosaicBERT base and large are consistently Pareto
optimal when compared to a competitive BERT base and large. This empirical
speed up in pretraining enables researchers and engineers to pretrain custom
BERT-style models at low cost instead of finetune on existing generic models.
We open source our model weights and code.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Portes_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jacob Portes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Trott_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alex Trott&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Havens_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sam Havens&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+King_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniel King&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Venigalla_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Abhinav Venigalla&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Nadeem_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Moin Nadeem&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sardana_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nikhil Sardana&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Khudia_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daya Khudia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Frankle_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jonathan Frankle&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.00165">
<title>Mitigating the Impact of False Negatives in Dense Retrieval with Contrastive Confidence Regularization. (arXiv:2401.00165v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.00165</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In open-domain Question Answering (QA), dense retrieval is crucial for
finding relevant passages for answer generation. Typically, contrastive
learning is used to train a retrieval model that maps passages and queries to
the same semantic space. The objective is to make similar ones closer and
dissimilar ones further apart. However, training such a system is challenging
due to the false negative issue, where relevant passages may be missed during
data annotation. Hard negative sampling, which is commonly used to improve
contrastive learning, can introduce more noise in training. This is because
hard negatives are those closer to a given query, and thus more likely to be
false negatives. To address this issue, we propose a novel contrastive
confidence regularizer for Noise Contrastive Estimation (NCE) loss, a commonly
used loss for dense retrieval. Our analysis shows that the regularizer helps
dense retrieval models be more robust against false negatives with a
theoretical guarantee. Additionally, we propose a model-agnostic method to
filter out noisy negative passages in the dataset, improving any downstream
dense retrieval models. Through experiments on three datasets, we demonstrate
that our method achieves better retrieval performance in comparison to existing
state-of-the-art dense retrieval systems.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shiqi Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yeqin Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Nguyen_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Cam-Tu Nguyen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.00741">
<title>ToolEyes: Fine-Grained Evaluation for Tool Learning Capabilities of Large Language Models in Real-world Scenarios. (arXiv:2401.00741v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.00741</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Existing evaluations of tool learning primarily focus on validating the
alignment of selected tools for large language models (LLMs) with expected
outcomes. However, these approaches rely on a limited set of scenarios where
answers can be pre-determined, diverging from genuine needs. Furthermore, a
sole emphasis on outcomes disregards the intricate capabilities essential for
LLMs to effectively utilize tools. To tackle this issue, we propose ToolEyes, a
fine-grained system tailored for the evaluation of the LLMs&apos; tool learning
capabilities in authentic scenarios. The system meticulously examines seven
real-world scenarios, analyzing five dimensions crucial to LLMs in tool
learning: format alignment, intent comprehension, behavior planning, tool
selection, and answer organization. Additionally, ToolEyes incorporates a tool
library boasting approximately 600 tools, serving as an intermediary between
LLMs and the physical world. Evaluations involving ten LLMs across three
categories reveal a preference for specific scenarios and limited cognitive
abilities in tool learning. Intriguingly, expanding the model size even
exacerbates the hindrance to tool learning. These findings offer instructive
insights aimed at advancing the field of tool learning. The data is available
att https://github.com/Junjie-Ye/ToolEyes.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ye_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Junjie Ye&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Guanyu Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gao_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Songyang Gao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Huang_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Caishuang Huang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yilong Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sixian Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Fan_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaoran Fan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Dou_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shihan Dou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qi Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gui_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tao Gui&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Huang_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xuanjing Huang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.01326">
<title>An Autoregressive Text-to-Graph Framework for Joint Entity and Relation Extraction. (arXiv:2401.01326v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.01326</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we propose a novel method for joint entity and relation
extraction from unstructured text by framing it as a conditional sequence
generation problem. In contrast to conventional generative information
extraction models that are left-to-right token-level generators, our approach
is \textit{span-based}. It generates a linearized graph where nodes represent
text spans and edges represent relation triplets. Our method employs a
transformer encoder-decoder architecture with pointing mechanism on a dynamic
vocabulary of spans and relation types. Our model can capture the structural
characteristics and boundaries of entities and relations through span
representations while simultaneously grounding the generated output in the
original text thanks to the pointing mechanism. Evaluation on benchmark
datasets validates the effectiveness of our approach, demonstrating competitive
results. Code is available at https://github.com/urchade/ATG.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zaratiana_U/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Urchade Zaratiana&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tomeh_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nadi Tomeh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Holat_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pierre Holat&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Charnois_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thierry Charnois&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.01699">
<title>WordArt Designer API: User-Driven Artistic Typography Synthesis with Large Language Models on ModelScope. (arXiv:2401.01699v2 [cs.CV] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.01699</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This paper introduces the WordArt Designer API, a novel framework for
user-driven artistic typography synthesis utilizing Large Language Models
(LLMs) on ModelScope. We address the challenge of simplifying artistic
typography for non-professionals by offering a dynamic, adaptive, and
computationally efficient alternative to traditional rigid templates. Our
approach leverages the power of LLMs to understand and interpret user input,
facilitating a more intuitive design process. We demonstrate through various
case studies how users can articulate their aesthetic preferences and
functional requirements, which the system then translates into unique and
creative typographic designs. Our evaluations indicate significant improvements
in user satisfaction, design flexibility, and creative expression over existing
systems. The WordArt Designer API not only democratizes the art of typography
but also opens up new possibilities for personalized digital communication and
design.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+He_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jun-Yan He&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cheng_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhi-Qi Cheng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chenyang Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sun_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jingdong Sun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xiang_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wangmeng Xiang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yusen Hu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lin_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xianhui Lin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kang_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaoyang Kang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jin_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zengke Jin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Luo_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bin Luo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Geng_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yifeng Geng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xie_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xuansong Xie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhou_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jingren Zhou&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02330">
<title>LLaVA-Phi: Efficient Multi-Modal Assistant with Small Language Model. (arXiv:2401.02330v2 [cs.CV] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02330</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we introduce LLaVA-$\phi$ (LLaVA-Phi), an efficient
multi-modal assistant that harnesses the power of the recently advanced small
language model, Phi-2, to facilitate multi-modal dialogues. LLaVA-Phi marks a
notable advancement in the realm of compact multi-modal models. It demonstrates
that even smaller language models, with as few as 2.7B parameters, can
effectively engage in intricate dialogues that integrate both textual and
visual elements, provided they are trained with high-quality corpora. Our model
delivers commendable performance on publicly available benchmarks that
encompass visual comprehension, reasoning, and knowledge-based perception.
Beyond its remarkable performance in multi-modal dialogue tasks, our model
opens new avenues for applications in time-sensitive environments and systems
that require real-time interaction, such as embodied agents. It highlights the
potential of smaller language models to achieve sophisticated levels of
understanding and interaction, while maintaining greater resource
efficiency.The project is available at {https://github.com/zhuyiche/llava-phi}.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yichen Zhu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhu_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Minjie Zhu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ning Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ou_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhicai Ou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Mou_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaofeng Mou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tang_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jian Tang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02333">
<title>Beyond Extraction: Contextualising Tabular Data for Efficient Summarisation by Language Models. (arXiv:2401.02333v2 [cs.LG] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02333</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The conventional use of the Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) architecture
has proven effective for retrieving information from diverse documents.
However, challenges arise in handling complex table queries, especially within
PDF documents containing intricate tabular structures.This research introduces
an innovative approach to enhance the accuracy of complex table queries in
RAG-based systems. Our methodology involves storing PDFs in the retrieval
database and extracting tabular content separately. The extracted tables
undergo a process of context enrichment, concatenating headers with
corresponding values. To ensure a comprehensive understanding of the enriched
data, we employ a fine-tuned version of the Llama-2-chat language model for
summarisation within the RAG architecture. Furthermore, we augment the tabular
data with contextual sense using the ChatGPT 3.5 API through a one-shot prompt.
This enriched data is then fed into the retrieval database alongside other
PDFs. Our approach aims to significantly improve the precision of complex table
queries, offering a promising solution to a longstanding challenge in
information retrieval.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Allu_U/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Uday Allu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ahmed_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Biddwan Ahmed&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tripathi_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vishesh Tripathi&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02987">
<title>Has Your Pretrained Model Improved? A Multi-head Posterior Based Approach. (arXiv:2401.02987v3 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02987</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The emergence of pretrained models has significantly impacted Natural
Language Processing (NLP) and Computer Vision to relational datasets.
Traditionally, these models are assessed through fine-tuned downstream tasks.
However, this raises the question of how to evaluate these models more
efficiently and more effectively. In this study, we explore a novel approach
where we leverage the meta features associated with each entity as a source of
worldly knowledge and employ entity representations from the models. We propose
using the consistency between these representations and the meta features as a
metric for evaluating pretrained models. Our method&apos;s effectiveness is
demonstrated across various domains, including models with relational datasets,
large language models and image models.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Aboagye_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Prince Aboagye&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zheng_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yan Zheng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Junpeng Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Saini_U/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Uday Singh Saini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Dai_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xin Dai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yeh_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michael Yeh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Fan_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yujie Fan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhuang_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhongfang Zhuang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jain_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shubham Jain&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Liang Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei Zhang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03642">
<title>A Content-Based Novelty Measure for Scholarly Publications: A Proof of Concept. (arXiv:2401.03642v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03642</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Novelty, akin to gene mutation in evolution, opens possibilities for
scholarly advancement. Although peer review remains the gold standard for
evaluating novelty in scholarly communication and resource allocation, the vast
volume of submissions necessitates an automated measure of scholarly novelty.
Adopting a perspective that views novelty as the atypical combination of
existing knowledge, we introduce an information-theoretic measure of novelty in
scholarly publications. This measure quantifies the degree of &apos;surprise&apos;
perceived by a language model that represents the word distribution of
scholarly discourse. The proposed measure is accompanied by face and construct
validity evidence; the former demonstrates correspondence to scientific common
sense, and the latter is endorsed through alignment with novelty evaluations
from a select panel of domain experts. Additionally, characterized by its
interpretability, fine granularity, and accessibility, this measure addresses
gaps prevalent in existing methods. We believe this measure holds great
potential to benefit editors, stakeholders, and policymakers, and it provides a
reliable lens for examining the relationship between novelty and academic
dynamics such as creativity, interdisciplinarity, and scientific advances.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Haining Wang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04658">
<title>Lightning Attention-2: A Free Lunch for Handling Unlimited Sequence Lengths in Large Language Models. (arXiv:2401.04658v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04658</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Linear attention is an efficient attention mechanism that has recently
emerged as a promising alternative to conventional softmax attention. With its
ability to process tokens in linear computational complexities, linear
attention, in theory, can handle sequences of unlimited length without
sacrificing speed, i.e., maintaining a constant training speed for various
sequence lengths with a fixed memory consumption. However, due to the issue
with cumulative summation (cumsum), current linear attention algorithms cannot
demonstrate their theoretical advantage in a causal setting. In this paper, we
present Lightning Attention-2, the first linear attention implementation that
enables linear attention to realize its theoretical computational benefits. To
achieve this, we leverage the thought of tiling, separately handling the
intra-block and inter-block components in linear attention calculation.
Specifically, we utilize the conventional attention computation mechanism for
the intra-blocks and apply linear attention kernel tricks for the inter-blocks.
A tiling technique is adopted through both forward and backward procedures to
take full advantage of the GPU hardware. We implement our algorithm in Triton
to make it IO-aware and hardware-friendly. Various experiments are conducted on
different model sizes and sequence lengths. Lightning Attention-2 retains
consistent training and inference speed regardless of input sequence length and
is significantly faster than other attention mechanisms. The source code is
available at https://github.com/OpenNLPLab/lightning-attention.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Qin_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhen Qin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sun_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Weigao Sun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dong Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shen_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xuyang Shen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sun_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Weixuan Sun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhong_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yiran Zhong&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04925">
<title>The Impact of Reasoning Step Length on Large Language Models. (arXiv:2401.04925v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04925</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Chain of Thought (CoT) is significant in improving the reasoning abilities of
large language models (LLMs). However, the correlation between the
effectiveness of CoT and the length of reasoning steps in prompts remains
largely unknown. To shed light on this, we have conducted several empirical
experiments to explore the relations. Specifically, we design experiments that
expand and compress the rationale reasoning steps within CoT demonstrations,
while keeping all other factors constant. We have the following key findings.
First, the results indicate that lengthening the reasoning steps in prompts,
even without adding new information into the prompt, considerably enhances
LLMs&apos; reasoning abilities across multiple datasets. Alternatively, shortening
the reasoning steps, even while preserving the key information, significantly
diminishes the reasoning abilities of models. This finding highlights the
importance of the number of steps in CoT prompts and provides practical
guidance to make better use of LLMs&apos; potential in complex problem-solving
scenarios. Second, we also investigated the relationship between the
performance of CoT and the rationales used in demonstrations. Surprisingly, the
result shows that even incorrect rationales can yield favorable outcomes if
they maintain the requisite length of inference. Third, we observed that the
advantages of increasing reasoning steps are task-dependent: simpler tasks
require fewer steps, whereas complex tasks gain significantly from longer
inference sequences.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jin_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mingyu Jin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yu_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qinkai Yu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+shu_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dong shu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhao_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Haiyan Zhao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hua_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wenyue Hua&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Meng_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yanda Meng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yongfeng Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Du_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mengnan Du&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05561">
<title>TrustLLM: Trustworthiness in Large Language Models. (arXiv:2401.05561v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05561</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Large language models (LLMs), exemplified by ChatGPT, have gained
considerable attention for their excellent natural language processing
capabilities. Nonetheless, these LLMs present many challenges, particularly in
the realm of trustworthiness. Therefore, ensuring the trustworthiness of LLMs
emerges as an important topic. This paper introduces TrustLLM, a comprehensive
study of trustworthiness in LLMs, including principles for different dimensions
of trustworthiness, established benchmark, evaluation, and analysis of
trustworthiness for mainstream LLMs, and discussion of open challenges and
future directions. Specifically, we first propose a set of principles for
trustworthy LLMs that span eight different dimensions. Based on these
principles, we further establish a benchmark across six dimensions including
truthfulness, safety, fairness, robustness, privacy, and machine ethics. We
then present a study evaluating 16 mainstream LLMs in TrustLLM, consisting of
over 30 datasets. Our findings firstly show that in general trustworthiness and
utility (i.e., functional effectiveness) are positively related. Secondly, our
observations reveal that proprietary LLMs generally outperform most open-source
counterparts in terms of trustworthiness, raising concerns about the potential
risks of widely accessible open-source LLMs. However, a few open-source LLMs
come very close to proprietary ones. Thirdly, it is important to note that some
LLMs may be overly calibrated towards exhibiting trustworthiness, to the extent
that they compromise their utility by mistakenly treating benign prompts as
harmful and consequently not responding. Finally, we emphasize the importance
of ensuring transparency not only in the models themselves but also in the
technologies that underpin trustworthiness. Knowing the specific trustworthy
technologies that have been employed is crucial for analyzing their
effectiveness.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sun_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lichao Sun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Huang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yue Huang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Haoran Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wu_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Siyuan Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qihui Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gao_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chujie Gao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Huang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yixin Huang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lyu_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wenhan Lyu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yixuan Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiner Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhengliang Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yixin Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yijue Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhikun Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kailkhura_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bhavya Kailkhura&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xiong_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Caiming Xiong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xiao_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chaowei Xiao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chunyuan Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xing_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Eric Xing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Huang_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Furong Huang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hao Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ji_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Heng Ji&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hongyi Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Huan Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yao_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Huaxiu Yao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kellis_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Manolis Kellis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zitnik_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marinka Zitnik&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jiang_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Meng Jiang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bansal_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mohit Bansal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zou_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;James Zou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Pei_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jian Pei&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jian Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gao_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jianfeng Gao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Han_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiawei Han&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhao_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jieyu Zhao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tang_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiliang Tang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jindong Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Mitchell_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;John Mitchell&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shu_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kai Shu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xu_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kaidi Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chang_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kai-Wei Chang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+He_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lifang He&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Huang_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lifu Huang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Backes_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michael Backes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gong_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Neil Zhenqiang Gong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yu_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Philip S. Yu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pin-Yu Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gu_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Quanquan Gu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xu_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ran Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ying_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rex Ying&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ji_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shuiwang Ji&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jana_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Suman Jana&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tianlong Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tianming Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhou_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tianyi Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Willian Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiang Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiangliang Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiao Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xie_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xing Xie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xun Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xuyu Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yan Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ye_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yanfang Ye&lt;/a&gt;, et al. (3 additional authors not shown)</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05596">
<title>POMP: Probability-driven Meta-graph Prompter for LLMs in Low-resource Unsupervised Neural Machine Translation. (arXiv:2401.05596v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05596</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Low-resource languages (LRLs) face challenges in supervised neural machine
translation due to limited parallel data, prompting research into unsupervised
methods. Unsupervised neural machine translation (UNMT) methods, including
back-translation, transfer learning, and pivot-based translation, offer
practical solutions for LRL translation, but they are hindered by issues like
synthetic data noise, language bias, and error propagation, which can
potentially be mitigated by Large Language Models (LLMs). LLMs have advanced
NMT with in-context learning (ICL) and supervised fine-tuning methods, but
insufficient training data results in poor performance in LRLs. We argue that
LLMs can mitigate the linguistic noise with auxiliary languages to improve
translations in LRLs. In this paper, we propose Probability-driven Meta-graph
Prompter (POMP), a novel approach employing a dynamic, sampling-based graph of
multiple auxiliary languages to enhance LLMs&apos; translation capabilities for
LRLs. POMP involves constructing a directed acyclic meta-graph for each source
language, from which we dynamically sample multiple paths to prompt LLMs to
mitigate the linguistic noise and improve translations during training. We use
the BLEURT metric to evaluate the translations and back-propagate rewards,
estimated by scores, to update the probabilities of auxiliary languages in the
paths. Our experiments show significant improvements in the translation quality
of three LRLs, demonstrating the effectiveness of our approach.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Pan_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shilong Pan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tian_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhiliang Tian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ding_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Liang Ding&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Huang_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhen Huang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wen_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhihua Wen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dongsheng Li&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>