<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CV updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CV</link>
    <description>cs.CV updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CV" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 04:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Saturday</day>
      <day>Sunday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>Reconstruction of the shape of irregular rough particles from their interferometric images using a convolutional neural network</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03327</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03327v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We have developed a convolutional neural network (CNN) to reconstruct the shape of irregular rough particles from their interferometric images. The CNN is based on a UNET architecture with residual block modules. The database has been constructed using the experimental patterns generated by perfectly known pseudo-particles programmed on a Digital Micromirror Device (DMD) and under laser illumination. The CNN has been trained on a basis of 18000 experimental interferometric images using the AUSTRAL super computer (at CRIANN in Normandy). The CNN is tested in the case of centrosymmetric (stick, cross, dendrite) and non-centrosymmetric (like T, Y or L) particles. The size and the 3D orientation of the programmed particles are random. The different shapes are reconstructed by the CNN with good accuracy. Using three angles of view, the 3D reconstruction of particles from three reconstructed faces can be further done.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03327v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>21st International Symposium on the Application of Laser and Imaging Techniques to Fluid Mechanics?LISBON | PORTUGAL ?JULY 8 -- 11, 2024, Jul 2024, Lisbonne, Portugal</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Alexis Abad (CORIA), Alexandre Poux (CORIA), Alexis Boulet (CORIA), Marc Brunel (CORIA)</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>InLUT3D: Challenging real indoor dataset for point cloud analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03338</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03338v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this paper, we introduce the InLUT3D point cloud dataset, a comprehensive resource designed to advance the field of scene understanding in indoor environments. The dataset covers diverse spaces within the W7 faculty buildings of Lodz University of Technology, characterised by high-resolution laser-based point clouds and manual labelling. Alongside the dataset, we propose metrics and benchmarking guidelines essential for ensuring trustworthy and reproducible results in algorithm evaluation. We anticipate that the introduction of the InLUT3D dataset and its associated benchmarks will catalyse future advancements in 3D scene understanding, facilitating methodological rigour and inspiring new approaches in the field.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03338v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jakub Walczak</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FastEdit: Fast Text-Guided Single-Image Editing via Semantic-Aware Diffusion Fine-Tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03355</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03355v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Conventional Text-guided single-image editing approaches require a two-step process, including fine-tuning the target text embedding for over 1K iterations and the generative model for another 1.5K iterations. Although it ensures that the resulting image closely aligns with both the input image and the target text, this process often requires 7 minutes per image, posing a challenge for practical application due to its time-intensive nature. To address this bottleneck, we introduce FastEdit, a fast text-guided single-image editing method with semantic-aware diffusion fine-tuning, dramatically accelerating the editing process to only 17 seconds. FastEdit streamlines the generative model's fine-tuning phase, reducing it from 1.5K to a mere 50 iterations. For diffusion fine-tuning, we adopt certain time step values based on the semantic discrepancy between the input image and target text. Furthermore, FastEdit circumvents the initial fine-tuning step by utilizing an image-to-image model that conditions on the feature space, rather than the text embedding space. It can effectively align the target text prompt and input image within the same feature space and save substantial processing time. Additionally, we apply the parameter-efficient fine-tuning technique LoRA to U-net. With LoRA, FastEdit minimizes the model's trainable parameters to only 0.37\% of the original size. At the same time, we can achieve comparable editing outcomes with significantly reduced computational overhead. We conduct extensive experiments to validate the editing performance of our approach and show promising editing capabilities, including content addition, style transfer, background replacement, and posture manipulation, etc.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03355v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhi Chen, Zecheng Zhao, Yadan Luo, Zi Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RayGauss: Volumetric Gaussian-Based Ray Casting for Photorealistic Novel View Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03356</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03356v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Differentiable volumetric rendering-based methods made significant progress in novel view synthesis. On one hand, innovative methods have replaced the Neural Radiance Fields (NeRF) network with locally parameterized structures, enabling high-quality renderings in a reasonable time. On the other hand, approaches have used differentiable splatting instead of NeRF's ray casting to optimize radiance fields rapidly using Gaussian kernels, allowing for fine adaptation to the scene. However, differentiable ray casting of irregularly spaced kernels has been scarcely explored, while splatting, despite enabling fast rendering times, is susceptible to clearly visible artifacts.
  Our work closes this gap by providing a physically consistent formulation of the emitted radiance c and density {\sigma}, decomposed with Gaussian functions associated with Spherical Gaussians/Harmonics for all-frequency colorimetric representation. We also introduce a method enabling differentiable ray casting of irregularly distributed Gaussians using an algorithm that integrates radiance fields slab by slab and leverages a BVH structure. This allows our approach to finely adapt to the scene while avoiding splatting artifacts. As a result, we achieve superior rendering quality compared to the state-of-the-art while maintaining reasonable training times and achieving inference speeds of 25 FPS on the Blender dataset. Project page with videos and code: https://raygauss.github.io/</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03356v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hugo Blanc, Jean-Emmanuel Deschaud, Alexis Paljic</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Set2Seq Transformer: Learning Permutation Aware Set Representations of Artistic Sequences</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03404</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03404v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We propose Set2Seq Transformer, a novel sequential multiple instance architecture, that learns to rank permutation aware set representations of sequences. First, we illustrate that learning temporal position-aware representations of discrete timesteps can greatly improve static visual multiple instance learning methods that do not regard temporality and concentrate almost exclusively on visual content analysis. We further demonstrate the significant advantages of end-to-end sequential multiple instance learning, integrating visual content and temporal information in a multimodal manner. As application we focus on fine art analysis related tasks. To that end, we show that our Set2Seq Transformer can leverage visual set and temporal position-aware representations for modelling visual artists' oeuvres for predicting artistic success. Finally, through extensive quantitative and qualitative evaluation using a novel dataset, WikiArt-Seq2Rank, and a visual learning-to-rank downstream task, we show that our Set2Seq Transformer captures essential temporal information improving the performance of strong static and sequential multiple instance learning methods for predicting artistic success.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03404v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Athanasios Efthymiou, Stevan Rudinac, Monika Kackovic, Nachoem Wijnberg, Marcel Worring</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid diffusion models: combining supervised and generative pretraining for label-efficient fine-tuning of segmentation models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03433</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03433v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We are considering in this paper the task of label-efficient fine-tuning of segmentation models: We assume that a large labeled dataset is available and allows to train an accurate segmentation model in one domain, and that we have to adapt this model on a related domain where only a few samples are available. We observe that this adaptation can be done using two distinct methods: The first method, supervised pretraining, is simply to take the model trained on the first domain using classical supervised learning, and fine-tune it on the second domain with the available labeled samples. The second method is to perform self-supervised pretraining on the first domain using a generic pretext task in order to get high-quality representations which can then be used to train a model on the second domain in a label-efficient way. We propose in this paper to fuse these two approaches by introducing a new pretext task, which is to perform simultaneously image denoising and mask prediction on the first domain. We motivate this choice by showing that in the same way that an image denoiser conditioned on the noise level can be considered as a generative model for the unlabeled image distribution using the theory of diffusion models, a model trained using this new pretext task can be considered as a generative model for the joint distribution of images and segmentation masks under the assumption that the mapping from images to segmentation masks is deterministic. We then empirically show on several datasets that fine-tuning a model pretrained using this approach leads to better results than fine-tuning a similar model trained using either supervised or unsupervised pretraining only.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03433v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bruno Sauvalle, Mathieu Salzmann</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Foundation Models in Remote Sensing: A Survey</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03464</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03464v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Artificial Intelligence (AI) technologies have profoundly transformed the field of remote sensing, revolutionizing data collection, processing, and analysis. Traditionally reliant on manual interpretation and task-specific models, remote sensing has been significantly enhanced by the advent of foundation models--large-scale, pre-trained AI models capable of performing a wide array of tasks with unprecedented accuracy and efficiency. This paper provides a comprehensive survey of foundation models in the remote sensing domain, covering models released between June 2021 and June 2024. We categorize these models based on their applications in computer vision and domain-specific tasks, offering insights into their architectures, pre-training datasets, and methodologies. Through detailed performance comparisons, we highlight emerging trends and the significant advancements achieved by these foundation models. Additionally, we discuss the technical challenges, practical implications, and future research directions, addressing the need for high-quality data, computational resources, and improved model generalization. Our research also finds that pre-training methods, particularly self-supervised learning techniques like contrastive learning and masked autoencoders, significantly enhance the performance and robustness of foundation models in remote sensing tasks such as scene classification, object detection, and other applications. This survey aims to serve as a resource for researchers and practitioners by providing a panorama of advances and promising pathways for continued development and application of foundation models in remote sensing.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03464v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Siqi Lu, Junlin Guo, James R Zimmer-Dauphinee, Jordan M Nieusma, Xiao Wang, Parker VanValkenburgh, Steven A Wernke, Yuankai Huo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FacialPulse: An Efficient RNN-based Depression Detection via Temporal Facial Landmarks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03499</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03499v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Depression is a prevalent mental health disorder that significantly impacts individuals' lives and well-being. Early detection and intervention are crucial for effective treatment and management of depression. Recently, there are many end-to-end deep learning methods leveraging the facial expression features for automatic depression detection. However, most current methods overlook the temporal dynamics of facial expressions. Although very recent 3DCNN methods remedy this gap, they introduce more computational cost due to the selection of CNN-based backbones and redundant facial features.
  To address the above limitations, by considering the timing correlation of facial expressions, we propose a novel framework called FacialPulse, which recognizes depression with high accuracy and speed. By harnessing the bidirectional nature and proficiently addressing long-term dependencies, the Facial Motion Modeling Module (FMMM) is designed in FacialPulse to fully capture temporal features. Since the proposed FMMM has parallel processing capabilities and has the gate mechanism to mitigate gradient vanishing, this module can also significantly boost the training speed.
  Besides, to effectively use facial landmarks to replace original images to decrease information redundancy, a Facial Landmark Calibration Module (FLCM) is designed to eliminate facial landmark errors to further improve recognition accuracy. Extensive experiments on the AVEC2014 dataset and MMDA dataset (a depression dataset) demonstrate the superiority of FacialPulse on recognition accuracy and speed, with the average MAE (Mean Absolute Error) decreased by 21% compared to baselines, and the recognition speed increased by 100% compared to state-of-the-art methods. Codes are released at https://github.com/volatileee/FacialPulse.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03499v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ruiqi Wang, Jinyang Huang, Jie Zhang, Xin Liu, Xiang Zhang, Zhi Liu, Peng Zhao, Sigui Chen, Xiao Sun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>e-Health CSIRO at RRG24: Entropy-Augmented Self-Critical Sequence Training for Radiology Report Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03500</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03500v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The Shared Task on Large-Scale Radiology Report Generation (RRG24) aims to expedite the development of assistive systems for interpreting and reporting on chest X-ray (CXR) images. This task challenges participants to develop models that generate the findings and impression sections of radiology reports from CXRs from a patient's study, using five different datasets. This paper outlines the e-Health CSIRO team's approach, which achieved multiple first-place finishes in RRG24. The core novelty of our approach lies in the addition of entropy regularisation to self-critical sequence training, to maintain a higher entropy in the token distribution. This prevents overfitting to common phrases and ensures a broader exploration of the vocabulary during training, essential for handling the diversity of the radiology reports in the RRG24 datasets. Our model is available on Hugging Face https://huggingface.co/aehrc/cxrmate-rrg24.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03500v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aaron Nicolson, Jinghui Liu, Jason Dowling, Anthony Nguyen, Bevan Koopman</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opening the Black Box of 3D Reconstruction Error Analysis with VECTOR</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03503</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03503v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Reconstruction of 3D scenes from 2D images is a technical challenge that impacts domains from Earth and planetary sciences and space exploration to augmented and virtual reality. Typically, reconstruction algorithms first identify common features across images and then minimize reconstruction errors after estimating the shape of the terrain. This bundle adjustment (BA) step optimizes around a single, simplifying scalar value that obfuscates many possible causes of reconstruction errors (e.g., initial estimate of the position and orientation of the camera, lighting conditions, ease of feature detection in the terrain). Reconstruction errors can lead to inaccurate scientific inferences or endanger a spacecraft exploring a remote environment. To address this challenge, we present VECTOR, a visual analysis tool that improves error inspection for stereo reconstruction BA. VECTOR provides analysts with previously unavailable visibility into feature locations, camera pose, and computed 3D points. VECTOR was developed in partnership with the Perseverance Mars Rover and Ingenuity Mars Helicopter terrain reconstruction team at the NASA Jet Propulsion Laboratory. We report on how this tool was used to debug and improve terrain reconstruction for the Mars 2020 mission.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03503v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Racquel Fygenson, Kazi Jawad, Isabel Li, Francois Ayoub, Robert G. Deen, Scott Davidoff, Dominik Moritz, Mauricio Hess-Flores</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GUI Element Detection Using SOTA YOLO Deep Learning Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03507</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03507v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Detection of Graphical User Interface (GUI) elements is a crucial task for automatic code generation from images and sketches, GUI testing, and GUI search. Recent studies have leveraged both old-fashioned and modern computer vision (CV) techniques. Oldfashioned methods utilize classic image processing algorithms (e.g. edge detection and contour detection) and modern methods use mature deep learning solutions for general object detection tasks. GUI element detection, however, is a domain-specific case of object detection, in which objects overlap more often, and are located very close to each other, plus the number of object classes is considerably lower, yet there are more objects in the images compared to natural images. Hence, the studies that have been carried out on comparing various object detection models, might not apply to GUI element detection. In this study, we evaluate the performance of the four most recent successful YOLO models for general object detection tasks on GUI element detection and investigate their accuracy performance in detecting various GUI elements.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03507v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Seyed Shayan Daneshvar, Shaowei Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MoExtend: Tuning New Experts for Modality and Task Extension</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03511</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03511v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) excel in various tasks but are primarily trained on text data, limiting their application scope. Expanding LLM capabilities to include vision-language understanding is vital, yet training them on multimodal data from scratch is challenging and costly. Existing instruction tuning methods, e.g., LLAVA, often connects a pretrained CLIP vision encoder and LLMs via fully fine-tuning LLMs to bridge the modality gap. However, full fine-tuning is plagued by catastrophic forgetting, i.e., forgetting previous knowledge, and high training costs particularly in the era of increasing tasks and modalities. To solve this issue, we introduce MoExtend, an effective framework designed to streamline the modality adaptation and extension of Mixture-of-Experts (MoE) models. MoExtend seamlessly integrates new experts into pre-trained MoE models, endowing them with novel knowledge without the need to tune pretrained models such as MoE and vision encoders. This approach enables rapid adaptation and extension to new modal data or tasks, effectively addressing the challenge of accommodating new modalities within LLMs. Furthermore, MoExtend avoids tuning pretrained models, thus mitigating the risk of catastrophic forgetting. Experimental results demonstrate the efficacy and efficiency of MoExtend in enhancing the multimodal capabilities of LLMs, contributing to advancements in multimodal AI research. Code: https://github.com/zhongshsh/MoExtend.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03511v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shanshan Zhong, Shanghua Gao, Zhongzhan Huang, Wushao Wen, Marinka Zitnik, Pan Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging LLMs for Enhanced Open-Vocabulary 3D Scene Understanding in Autonomous Driving</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03516</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03516v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper introduces a novel method for open-vocabulary 3D scene understanding in autonomous driving by combining Language Embedded 3D Gaussians with Large Language Models (LLMs) for enhanced inference. We propose utilizing LLMs to generate contextually relevant canonical phrases for segmentation and scene interpretation. Our method leverages the contextual and semantic capabilities of LLMs to produce a set of canonical phrases, which are then compared with the language features embedded in the 3D Gaussians. This LLM-guided approach significantly improves zero-shot scene understanding and detection of objects of interest, even in the most challenging or unfamiliar environments. Experimental results on the WayveScenes101 dataset demonstrate that our approach surpasses state-of-the-art methods in terms of accuracy and flexibility for open-vocabulary object detection and segmentation. This work represents a significant advancement towards more intelligent, context-aware autonomous driving systems, effectively bridging 3D scene representation with high-level semantic understanding.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03516v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Amirhosein Chahe, Lifeng Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SwinShadow: Shifted Window for Ambiguous Adjacent Shadow Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03521</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03521v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Shadow detection is a fundamental and challenging task in many computer vision applications. Intuitively, most shadows come from the occlusion of light by the object itself, resulting in the object and its shadow being contiguous (referred to as the adjacent shadow in this paper). In this case, when the color of the object is similar to that of the shadow, existing methods struggle to achieve accurate detection. To address this problem, we present SwinShadow, a transformer-based architecture that fully utilizes the powerful shifted window mechanism for detecting adjacent shadows. The mechanism operates in two steps. Initially, it applies local self-attention within a single window, enabling the network to focus on local details. Subsequently, it shifts the attention windows to facilitate inter-window attention, enabling the capture of a broader range of adjacent information. These combined steps significantly improve the network's capacity to distinguish shadows from nearby objects. And the whole process can be divided into three parts: encoder, decoder, and feature integration. During encoding, we adopt Swin Transformer to acquire hierarchical features. Then during decoding, for shallow layers, we propose a deep supervision (DS) module to suppress the false positives and boost the representation capability of shadow features for subsequent processing, while for deep layers, we leverage a double attention (DA) module to integrate local and shifted window in one stage to achieve a larger receptive field and enhance the continuity of information. Ultimately, a new multi-level aggregation (MLA) mechanism is applied to fuse the decoded features for mask prediction. Extensive experiments on three shadow detection benchmark datasets, SBU, UCF, and ISTD, demonstrate that our network achieves good performance in terms of balance error rate (BER).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03521v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yonghui Wang, Shaokai Liu, Li Li, Wengang Zhou, Houqiang Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PRTGS: Precomputed Radiance Transfer of Gaussian Splats for Real-Time High-Quality Relighting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03538</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03538v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We proposed Precomputed RadianceTransfer of GaussianSplats (PRTGS), a real-time high-quality relighting method for Gaussian splats in low-frequency lighting environments that captures soft shadows and interreflections by precomputing 3D Gaussian splats' radiance transfer. Existing studies have demonstrated that 3D Gaussian splatting (3DGS) outperforms neural fields' efficiency for dynamic lighting scenarios. However, the current relighting method based on 3DGS still struggles to compute high-quality shadow and indirect illumination in real time for dynamic light, leading to unrealistic rendering results. We solve this problem by precomputing the expensive transport simulations required for complex transfer functions like shadowing, the resulting transfer functions are represented as dense sets of vectors or matrices for every Gaussian splat. We introduce distinct precomputing methods tailored for training and rendering stages, along with unique ray tracing and indirect lighting precomputation techniques for 3D Gaussian splats to accelerate training speed and compute accurate indirect lighting related to environment light. Experimental analyses demonstrate that our approach achieves state-of-the-art visual quality while maintaining competitive training times and allows high-quality real-time (30+ fps) relighting for dynamic light and relatively complex scenes at 1080p resolution.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03538v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yijia Guo, Yuanxi Bai, Liwen Hu, Ziyi Guo, Mianzhi Liu, Yu Cai, Tiejun Huang, Lei Ma</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PoseMamba: Monocular 3D Human Pose Estimation with Bidirectional Global-Local Spatio-Temporal State Space Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03540</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03540v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Transformers have significantly advanced the field of 3D human pose estimation (HPE). However, existing transformer-based methods primarily use self-attention mechanisms for spatio-temporal modeling, leading to a quadratic complexity, unidirectional modeling of spatio-temporal relationships, and insufficient learning of spatial-temporal correlations. Recently, the Mamba architecture, utilizing the state space model (SSM), has exhibited superior long-range modeling capabilities in a variety of vision tasks with linear complexity. In this paper, we propose PoseMamba, a novel purely SSM-based approach with linear complexity for 3D human pose estimation in monocular video. Specifically, we propose a bidirectional global-local spatio-temporal SSM block that comprehensively models human joint relations within individual frames as well as temporal correlations across frames. Within this bidirectional global-local spatio-temporal SSM block, we introduce a reordering strategy to enhance the local modeling capability of the SSM. This strategy provides a more logical geometric scanning order and integrates it with the global SSM, resulting in a combined global-local spatial scan. We have quantitatively and qualitatively evaluated our approach using two benchmark datasets: Human3.6M and MPI-INF-3DHP. Extensive experiments demonstrate that PoseMamba achieves state-of-the-art performance on both datasets while maintaining a smaller model size and reducing computational costs. The code and models will be released.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03540v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yunlong Huang, Junshuo Liu, Ke Xian, Robert Caiming Qiu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automatic identification of the area covered by acorn trees in the dehesa (pastureland) Extremadura of Spain</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03542</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03542v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The acorn is the fruit of the oak and is an important crop in the Spanish dehesa extreme\~na, especially for the value it provides in the Iberian pig food to obtain the "acorn" certification. For this reason, we want to maximise the production of Iberian pigs with the appropriate weight. Hence the need to know the area covered by the crowns of the acorn trees, to determine the covered wooded area (CWA, from the Spanish Superficie Arbolada Cubierta SAC) and thereby estimate the number of Iberian pigs that can be released per hectare, as indicated by the royal decree 4/2014. In this work, we propose the automatic estimation of the CWA, through aerial digital images (orthophotos) of the pastureland of Extremadura, and with this, to offer the possibility of determining the number of Iberian pigs to be released in a specific plot of land. Among the main issues for automatic detection are, first, the correct identification of acorn trees, secondly, correctly discriminating the shades of the acorn trees and, finally, detect the arbuscles (young acorn trees not yet productive, or shrubs that are not oaks). These difficulties represent a real challenge, both for the automatic segmentation process and for manual segmentation. In this work, the proposed method for automatic segmentation is based on the clustering algorithm proposed by Gustafson-Kessel (GK) but the modified version of Babuska (GK-B) and on the use of real orthophotos. The obtained results are promising both in their comparison with the real images and when compared with the images segmented by hand. The whole set of orthophotos used in this work correspond to an approximate area of 142 hectares, and the results are of great interest to producers of certified "acorn" pork.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03542v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1016/j.compag.2020.105289</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Computers and Electronics in Agriculture, Volume 172, 2020, 105289, ISSN 0168-1699</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Ojeda-Maga\~na Benjamin, Ruelas Ruben, Quintanilla-Dominguez Joel, Gomez-Barba Leopoldo, Lopez de Herrera Juan, Robledo-Hernandez Jose, Tarquis Ana</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CLIP-based Point Cloud Classification via Point Cloud to Image Translation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03545</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03545v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Point cloud understanding is an inherently challenging problem because of the sparse and unordered structure of the point cloud in the 3D space. Recently, Contrastive Vision-Language Pre-training (CLIP) based point cloud classification model i.e. PointCLIP has added a new direction in the point cloud classification research domain. In this method, at first multi-view depth maps are extracted from the point cloud and passed through the CLIP visual encoder. To transfer the 3D knowledge to the network, a small network called an adapter is fine-tuned on top of the CLIP visual encoder. PointCLIP has two limitations. Firstly, the point cloud depth maps lack image information which is essential for tasks like classification and recognition. Secondly, the adapter only relies on the global representation of the multi-view features. Motivated by this observation, we propose a Pretrained Point Cloud to Image Translation Network (PPCITNet) that produces generalized colored images along with additional salient visual cues to the point cloud depth maps so that it can achieve promising performance on point cloud classification and understanding. In addition, we propose a novel viewpoint adapter that combines the view feature processed by each viewpoint as well as the global intertwined knowledge that exists across the multi-view features. The experimental results demonstrate the superior performance of the proposed model over existing state-of-the-art CLIP-based models on ModelNet10, ModelNet40, and ScanobjectNN datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03545v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shuvozit Ghose, Manyi Li, Yiming Qian, Yang Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VPOcc: Exploiting Vanishing Point for Monocular 3D Semantic Occupancy Prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03551</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03551v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Monocular 3D semantic occupancy prediction is becoming important in robot vision due to the compactness of using a single RGB camera. However, existing methods often do not adequately account for camera perspective geometry, resulting in information imbalance along the depth range of the image. To address this issue, we propose a vanishing point (VP) guided monocular 3D semantic occupancy prediction framework named VPOcc. Our framework consists of three novel modules utilizing VP. First, in the VPZoomer module, we initially utilize VP in feature extraction to achieve information balanced feature extraction across the scene by generating a zoom-in image based on VP. Second, we perform perspective geometry-aware feature aggregation by sampling points towards VP using a VP-guided cross-attention (VPCA) module. Finally, we create an information-balanced feature volume by effectively fusing original and zoom-in voxel feature volumes with a balanced feature volume fusion (BVFV) module. Experiments demonstrate that our method achieves state-of-the-art performance for both IoU and mIoU on SemanticKITTI and SSCBench-KITTI360. These results are obtained by effectively addressing the information imbalance in images through the utilization of VP. Our code will be available at www.github.com/anonymous.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03551v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junsu Kim, Junhee Lee, Ukcheol Shin, Jean Oh, Kyungdon Joo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>D2Styler: Advancing Arbitrary Style Transfer with Discrete Diffusion Methods</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03558</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03558v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In image processing, one of the most challenging tasks is to render an image's semantic meaning using a variety of artistic approaches. Existing techniques for arbitrary style transfer (AST) frequently experience mode-collapse, over-stylization, or under-stylization due to a disparity between the style and content images. We propose a novel framework called D$^2$Styler (Discrete Diffusion Styler) that leverages the discrete representational capability of VQ-GANs and the advantages of discrete diffusion, including stable training and avoidance of mode collapse. Our method uses Adaptive Instance Normalization (AdaIN) features as a context guide for the reverse diffusion process. This makes it easy to move features from the style image to the content image without bias. The proposed method substantially enhances the visual quality of style-transferred images, allowing the combination of content and style in a visually appealing manner. We take style images from the WikiArt dataset and content images from the COCO dataset. Experimental results demonstrate that D$^2$Styler produces high-quality style-transferred images and outperforms twelve existing methods on nearly all the metrics. The qualitative results and ablation studies provide further insights into the efficacy of our technique. The code is available at https://github.com/Onkarsus13/D2Styler.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03558v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Onkar Susladkar, Gayatri Deshmukh, Sparsh Mittal, Parth Shastri</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring of Hermit Crabs Using drone-captured imagery and Deep Learning based Super-Resolution Reconstruction and Improved YOLOv8</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03559</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03559v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Hermit crabs play a crucial role in coastal ecosystems by dispersing seeds, cleaning up debris, and disturbing soil. They serve as vital indicators of marine environmental health, responding to climate change and pollution. Traditional survey methods, like quadrat sampling, are labor-intensive, time-consuming, and environmentally dependent. This study presents an innovative approach combining UAV-based remote sensing with Super-Resolution Reconstruction (SRR) and the CRAB-YOLO detection network, a modification of YOLOv8s, to monitor hermit crabs. SRR enhances image quality by addressing issues such as motion blur and insufficient resolution, significantly improving detection accuracy over conventional low-resolution fuzzy images. The CRAB-YOLO network integrates three improvements for detection accuracy, hermit crab characteristics, and computational efficiency, achieving state-of-the-art (SOTA) performance compared to other mainstream detection models. The RDN networks demonstrated the best image reconstruction performance, and CRAB-YOLO achieved a mean average precision (mAP) of 69.5% on the SRR test set, a 40% improvement over the conventional Bicubic method with a magnification factor of 4. These results indicate that the proposed method is effective in detecting hermit crabs, offering a cost-effective and automated solution for extensive hermit crab monitoring, thereby aiding coastal benthos conservation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03559v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fan Zhao, Yijia Chen, Dianhan Xi, Yongying Liu, Jiaqi Wang, Shigeru Tabeta, Katsunori Mizuno</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Underwater litter monitoring using consumer-grade aerial-aquatic speedy scanner (AASS) and deep learning based super-resolution reconstruction and detection network</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03564</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03564v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Underwater litter is widely spread across aquatic environments such as lakes, rivers, and oceans, significantly impacting natural ecosystems. Current monitoring technologies for detecting underwater litter face limitations in survey efficiency, cost, and environmental conditions, highlighting the need for efficient, consumer-grade technologies for automatic detection. This research introduces the Aerial-Aquatic Speedy Scanner (AASS) combined with Super-Resolution Reconstruction (SRR) and an improved YOLOv8 detection network. AASS enhances data acquisition efficiency over traditional methods, capturing high-quality images that accurately identify underwater waste. SRR improves image-resolution by mitigating motion blur and insufficient resolution, thereby enhancing detection tasks. Specifically, the RCAN model achieved the highest mean average precision (mAP) of 78.6% for detection accuracy on reconstructed images among the tested SRR models. With a magnification factor of 4, the SRR test set shows an improved mAP compared to the conventional bicubic set. These results demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed method in detecting underwater litter.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03564v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fan Zhao, Yongying Liu, Jiaqi Wang, Yijia Chen, Dianhan Xi, Xinlei Shao, Shigeru Tabeta, Katsunori Mizuno</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking Exocentric Video-Language Data for Egocentric Video Representation Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03567</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03567v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present EMBED (Egocentric Models Built with Exocentric Data), a method designed to transform exocentric video-language data for egocentric video representation learning. Large-scale exocentric data covers diverse activities with significant potential for egocentric learning, but inherent disparities between egocentric and exocentric data pose challenges in utilizing one view for the other seamlessly. Egocentric videos predominantly feature close-up hand-object interactions, whereas exocentric videos offer a broader perspective on human activities. Additionally, narratives in egocentric datasets are typically more action-centric and closely linked with the visual content, in contrast to the narrative styles found in exocentric datasets. To address these challenges, we employ a data transformation framework to adapt exocentric data for egocentric training, focusing on identifying specific video clips that emphasize hand-object interactions and transforming narration styles to align with egocentric perspectives. By applying both vision and language style transfer, our framework creates a new egocentric dataset derived from exocentric video-language data. Through extensive evaluations, we demonstrate the effectiveness of EMBED, achieving state-of-the-art results across various egocentric downstream tasks, including an absolute improvement of 4.7% on the Epic-Kitchens-100 multi-instance retrieval and 6.2% on the EGTEA classification benchmarks in zero-shot settings. Furthermore, EMBED enables egocentric video-language models to perform competitively in exocentric tasks. Finally, we showcase EMBED's application across various exocentric datasets, exhibiting strong generalization capabilities when applied to different exocentric datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03567v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zi-Yi Dou, Xitong Yang, Tushar Nagarajan, Huiyu Wang, Jing Huang, Nanyun Peng, Kris Kitani, Fu-Jen Chu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A comparative study of generative adversarial networks for image recognition algorithms based on deep learning and traditional methods</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03568</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03568v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this paper, an image recognition algorithm based on the combination of deep learning and generative adversarial network (GAN) is studied, and compared with traditional image recognition methods. The purpose of this study is to evaluate the advantages and application prospects of deep learning technology, especially GAN, in the field of image recognition. Firstly, this paper reviews the basic principles and techniques of traditional image recognition methods, including the classical algorithms based on feature extraction such as SIFT, HOG and their combination with support vector machine (SVM), random forest, and other classifiers. Then, the working principle, network structure, and unique advantages of GAN in image generation and recognition are introduced. In order to verify the effectiveness of GAN in image recognition, a series of experiments are designed and carried out using multiple public image data sets for training and testing. The experimental results show that compared with traditional methods, GAN has excellent performance in processing complex images, recognition accuracy, and anti-noise ability. Specifically, Gans are better able to capture high-dimensional features and details of images, significantly improving recognition performance. In addition, Gans shows unique advantages in dealing with image noise, partial missing information, and generating high-quality images.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03568v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yihao Zhong, Yijing Wei, Yingbin Liang, Xiqing Liu, Rongwei Ji, Yiru Cang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teach CLIP to Develop a Number Sense for Ordinal Regression</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03574</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03574v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Ordinal regression is a fundamental problem within the field of computer vision, with customised well-trained models on specific tasks. While pre-trained vision-language models (VLMs) have exhibited impressive performance on various vision tasks, their potential for ordinal regression has received less exploration. In this study, we first investigate CLIP's potential for ordinal regression, from which we expect the model could generalise to different ordinal regression tasks and scenarios. Unfortunately, vanilla CLIP fails on this task, since current VLMs have a well-documented limitation of encapsulating compositional concepts such as number sense. We propose a simple yet effective method called NumCLIP to improve the quantitative understanding of VLMs. We disassemble the exact image to number-specific text matching problem into coarse classification and fine prediction stages. We discretize and phrase each numerical bin with common language concept to better leverage the available pre-trained alignment in CLIP. To consider the inherent continuous property of ordinal regression, we propose a novel fine-grained cross-modal ranking-based regularisation loss specifically designed to keep both semantic and ordinal alignment in CLIP's feature space. Experimental results on three general ordinal regression tasks demonstrate the effectiveness of NumCLIP, with 10% and 3.83% accuracy improvement on historical image dating and image aesthetics assessment task, respectively. Code is publicly available at https://github.com/xmed-lab/NumCLIP.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03574v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yao Du, Qiang Zhai, Weihang Dai, Xiaomeng Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Focal Depth Estimation: A Calibration-Free, Subject- and Daytime Invariant Approach</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03591</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03591v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In an era where personalized technology is increasingly intertwined with daily life, traditional eye-tracking systems and autofocal glasses face a significant challenge: the need for frequent, user-specific calibration, which impedes their practicality. This study introduces a groundbreaking calibration-free method for estimating focal depth, leveraging machine learning techniques to analyze eye movement features within short sequences. Our approach, distinguished by its innovative use of LSTM networks and domain-specific feature engineering, achieves a mean absolute error (MAE) of less than 10 cm, setting a new focal depth estimation accuracy standard. This advancement promises to enhance the usability of autofocal glasses and pave the way for their seamless integration into extended reality environments, marking a significant leap forward in personalized visual technology.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03591v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>eess.SP</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Benedikt W. Hosp, Bj\"orn Severitt, Rajat Agarwala, Evgenia Rusak, Yannick Sauer, Siegfried Wahl</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PRISM: PRogressive dependency maxImization for Scale-invariant image Matching</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03598</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03598v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Image matching aims at identifying corresponding points between a pair of images. Currently, detector-free methods have shown impressive performance in challenging scenarios, thanks to their capability of generating dense matches and global receptive field. However, performing feature interaction and proposing matches across the entire image is unnecessary, because not all image regions contribute to the matching process. Interacting and matching in unmatchable areas can introduce errors, reducing matching accuracy and efficiency. Meanwhile, the scale discrepancy issue still troubles existing methods. To address above issues, we propose PRogressive dependency maxImization for Scale-invariant image Matching (PRISM), which jointly prunes irrelevant patch features and tackles the scale discrepancy. To do this, we firstly present a Multi-scale Pruning Module (MPM) to adaptively prune irrelevant features by maximizing the dependency between the two feature sets. Moreover, we design the Scale-Aware Dynamic Pruning Attention (SADPA) to aggregate information from different scales via a hierarchical design. Our method's superior matching performance and generalization capability are confirmed by leading accuracy across various evaluation benchmarks and downstream tasks. The code is publicly available at https://github.com/Master-cai/PRISM.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03598v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3664647.3681209</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Xudong Cai, Yongcai Wang, Lun Luo, Minhang Wang, Deying Li, Jintao Xu, Weihao Gu, Rui Ai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JARViS: Detecting Actions in Video Using Unified Actor-Scene Context Relation Modeling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03612</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03612v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Video action detection (VAD) is a formidable vision task that involves the localization and classification of actions within the spatial and temporal dimensions of a video clip. Among the myriad VAD architectures, two-stage VAD methods utilize a pre-trained person detector to extract the region of interest features, subsequently employing these features for action detection. However, the performance of two-stage VAD methods has been limited as they depend solely on localized actor features to infer action semantics. In this study, we propose a new two-stage VAD framework called Joint Actor-scene context Relation modeling based on Visual Semantics (JARViS), which effectively consolidates cross-modal action semantics distributed globally across spatial and temporal dimensions using Transformer attention. JARViS employs a person detector to produce densely sampled actor features from a keyframe. Concurrently, it uses a video backbone to create spatio-temporal scene features from a video clip. Finally, the fine-grained interactions between actors and scenes are modeled through a Unified Action-Scene Context Transformer to directly output the final set of actions in parallel. Our experimental results demonstrate that JARViS outperforms existing methods by significant margins and achieves state-of-the-art performance on three popular VAD datasets, including AVA, UCF101-24, and JHMDB51-21.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03612v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Seok Hwan Lee, Taein Son, Soo Won Seo, Jisong Kim, Jun Won Choi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AgentsCoMerge: Large Language Model Empowered Collaborative Decision Making for Ramp Merging</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03624</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03624v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Ramp merging is one of the bottlenecks in traffic systems, which commonly cause traffic congestion, accidents, and severe carbon emissions. In order to address this essential issue and enhance the safety and efficiency of connected and autonomous vehicles (CAVs) at multi-lane merging zones, we propose a novel collaborative decision-making framework, named AgentsCoMerge, to leverage large language models (LLMs). Specifically, we first design a scene observation and understanding module to allow an agent to capture the traffic environment. Then we propose a hierarchical planning module to enable the agent to make decisions and plan trajectories based on the observation and the agent's own state. In addition, in order to facilitate collaboration among multiple agents, we introduce a communication module to enable the surrounding agents to exchange necessary information and coordinate their actions. Finally, we develop a reinforcement reflection guided training paradigm to further enhance the decision-making capability of the framework. Extensive experiments are conducted to evaluate the performance of our proposed method, demonstrating its superior efficiency and effectiveness for multi-agent collaborative decision-making under various ramp merging scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03624v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Senkang Hu, Zhengru Fang, Zihan Fang, Yiqin Deng, Xianhao Chen, Yuguang Fang, Sam Kwong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weakly Contrastive Learning via Batch Instance Discrimination and Feature Clustering for Small Sample SAR ATR</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03627</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03627v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In recent years, impressive performance of deep learning technology has been recognized in Synthetic Aperture Radar (SAR) Automatic Target Recognition (ATR). Since a large amount of annotated data is required in this technique, it poses a trenchant challenge to the issue of obtaining a high recognition rate through less labeled data. To overcome this problem, inspired by the contrastive learning, we proposed a novel framework named Batch Instance Discrimination and Feature Clustering (BIDFC). In this framework, different from that of the objective of general contrastive learning methods, embedding distance between samples should be moderate because of the high similarity between samples in the SAR images. Consequently, our flexible framework is equipped with adjustable distance between embedding, which we term as weakly contrastive learning. Technically, instance labels are assigned to the unlabeled data in per batch and random augmentation and training are performed few times on these augmented data. Meanwhile, a novel Dynamic-Weighted Variance loss (DWV loss) function is also posed to cluster the embedding of enhanced versions for each sample. Experimental results on the moving and stationary target acquisition and recognition (MSTAR) database indicate a 91.25% classification accuracy of our method fine-tuned on only 3.13% training data. Even though a linear evaluation is performed on the same training data, the accuracy can still reach 90.13%. We also verified the effectiveness of BIDFC in OpenSarShip database, indicating that our method can be generalized to other datasets. Our code is avaliable at: https://github.com/Wenlve-Zhou/BIDFC-master.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03627v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1109/TGRS.2021.3066195</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Yikui Zhai, Wenlve Zhou, Bing Sun, Jingwen Li, Qirui Ke, Zilu Ying, Junying Gan, Chaoyun Mai, Ruggero Donida Labati, Vincenzo Piuri, Fabio Scotti</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Concept Conductor: Orchestrating Multiple Personalized Concepts in Text-to-Image Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03632</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03632v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The customization of text-to-image models has seen significant advancements, yet generating multiple personalized concepts remains a challenging task. Current methods struggle with attribute leakage and layout confusion when handling multiple concepts, leading to reduced concept fidelity and semantic consistency. In this work, we introduce a novel training-free framework, Concept Conductor, designed to ensure visual fidelity and correct layout in multi-concept customization. Concept Conductor isolates the sampling processes of multiple custom models to prevent attribute leakage between different concepts and corrects erroneous layouts through self-attention-based spatial guidance. Additionally, we present a concept injection technique that employs shape-aware masks to specify the generation area for each concept. This technique injects the structure and appearance of personalized concepts through feature fusion in the attention layers, ensuring harmony in the final image. Extensive qualitative and quantitative experiments demonstrate that Concept Conductor can consistently generate composite images with accurate layouts while preserving the visual details of each concept. Compared to existing baselines, Concept Conductor shows significant performance improvements. Our method supports the combination of any number of concepts and maintains high fidelity even when dealing with visually similar concepts. The code and models are available at https://github.com/Nihukat/Concept-Conductor.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03632v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zebin Yao, Fangxiang Feng, Ruifan Li, Xiaojie Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TALE: Training-free Cross-domain Image Composition via Adaptive Latent Manipulation and Energy-guided Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03637</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03637v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present TALE, a novel training-free framework harnessing the generative capabilities of text-to-image diffusion models to address the cross-domain image composition task that focuses on flawlessly incorporating user-specified objects into a designated visual contexts regardless of domain disparity. Previous methods often involve either training auxiliary networks or finetuning diffusion models on customized datasets, which are expensive and may undermine the robust textual and visual priors of pre-trained diffusion models. Some recent works attempt to break the barrier by proposing training-free workarounds that rely on manipulating attention maps to tame the denoising process implicitly. However, composing via attention maps does not necessarily yield desired compositional outcomes. These approaches could only retain some semantic information and usually fall short in preserving identity characteristics of input objects or exhibit limited background-object style adaptation in generated images. In contrast, TALE is a novel method that operates directly on latent space to provide explicit and effective guidance for the composition process to resolve these problems. Specifically, we equip TALE with two mechanisms dubbed Adaptive Latent Manipulation and Energy-guided Latent Optimization. The former formulates noisy latents conducive to initiating and steering the composition process by directly leveraging background and foreground latents at corresponding timesteps, and the latter exploits designated energy functions to further optimize intermediate latents conforming to specific conditions that complement the former to generate desired final results. Our experiments demonstrate that TALE surpasses prior baselines and attains state-of-the-art performance in image-guided composition across various photorealistic and artistic domains.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03637v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3664647.3681079</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Kien T. Pham, Jingye Chen, Qifeng Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PHOCUS: Physics-Based Deconvolution for Ultrasound Resolution Enhancement</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03657</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03657v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Ultrasound is widely used in medical diagnostics allowing for accessible and powerful imaging but suffers from resolution limitations due to diffraction and the finite aperture of the imaging system, which restricts diagnostic use. The impulse function of an ultrasound imaging system is called the point spread function (PSF), which is convolved with the spatial distribution of reflectors in the image formation process. Recovering high-resolution reflector distributions by removing image distortions induced by the convolution process improves image clarity and detail. Conventionally, deconvolution techniques attempt to rectify the imaging system's dependent PSF, working directly on the radio-frequency (RF) data. However, RF data is often not readily accessible. Therefore, we introduce a physics-based deconvolution process using a modeled PSF, working directly on the more commonly available B-mode images. By leveraging Implicit Neural Representations (INRs), we learn a continuous mapping from spatial locations to their respective echogenicity values, effectively compensating for the discretized image space. Our contribution consists of a novel methodology for retrieving a continuous echogenicity map directly from a B-mode image through a differentiable physics-based rendering pipeline for ultrasound resolution enhancement. We qualitatively and quantitatively evaluate our approach on synthetic data, demonstrating improvements over traditional methods in metrics such as PSNR and SSIM. Furthermore, we show qualitative enhancements on an ultrasound phantom and an in-vivo acquisition of a carotid artery.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03657v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Felix Duelmer, Walter Simson, Mohammad Farid Azampour, Magdalena Wysocki, Angelos Karlas, Nassir Navab</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing Extremely Memory-Efficient CNNs for On-device Vision Tasks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03663</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03663v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this paper, we introduce a memory-efficient CNN (convolutional neural network), which enables resource-constrained low-end embedded and IoT devices to perform on-device vision tasks, such as image classification and object detection, using extremely low memory, i.e., only 63 KB on ImageNet classification. Based on the bottleneck block of MobileNet, we propose three design principles that significantly curtail the peak memory usage of a CNN so that it can fit the limited KB memory of the low-end device. First, 'input segmentation' divides an input image into a set of patches, including the central patch overlapped with the others, reducing the size (and memory requirement) of a large input image. Second, 'patch tunneling' builds independent tunnel-like paths consisting of multiple bottleneck blocks per patch, penetrating through the entire model from an input patch to the last layer of the network, maintaining lightweight memory usage throughout the whole network. Lastly, 'bottleneck reordering' rearranges the execution order of convolution operations inside the bottleneck block such that the memory usage remains constant regardless of the size of the convolution output channels. The experiment result shows that the proposed network classifies ImageNet with extremely low memory (i.e., 63 KB) while achieving competitive top-1 accuracy (i.e., 61.58\%). To the best of our knowledge, the memory usage of the proposed network is far smaller than state-of-the-art memory-efficient networks, i.e., up to 89x and 3.1x smaller than MobileNet (i.e., 5.6 MB) and MCUNet (i.e., 196 KB), respectively.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03663v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jaewook Lee, Yoel Park, Seulki Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>L4DR: LiDAR-4DRadar Fusion for Weather-Robust 3D Object Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03677</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03677v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: LiDAR-based vision systems are integral for 3D object detection, which is crucial for autonomous navigation. However, they suffer from performance degradation in adverse weather conditions due to the quality deterioration of LiDAR point clouds. Fusing LiDAR with the weather-robust 4D radar sensor is expected to solve this problem. However, the fusion of LiDAR and 4D radar is challenging because they differ significantly in terms of data quality and the degree of degradation in adverse weather. To address these issues, we introduce L4DR, a weather-robust 3D object detection method that effectively achieves LiDAR and 4D Radar fusion. Our L4DR includes Multi-Modal Encoding (MME) and Foreground-Aware Denoising (FAD) technique to reconcile sensor gaps, which is the first exploration of the complementarity of early fusion between LiDAR and 4D radar. Additionally, we design an Inter-Modal and Intra-Modal ({IM}2 ) parallel feature extraction backbone coupled with a Multi-Scale Gated Fusion (MSGF) module to counteract the varying degrees of sensor degradation under adverse weather conditions. Experimental evaluation on a VoD dataset with simulated fog proves that L4DR is more adaptable to changing weather conditions. It delivers a significant performance increase under different fog levels, improving the 3D mAP by up to 18.17% over the traditional LiDAR-only approach. Moreover, the results on the K-Radar dataset validate the consistent performance improvement of L4DR in real-world adverse weather conditions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03677v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xun Huang, Ziyu Xu, Hai Wu, Jinlong Wang, Qiming Xia, Yan Xia, Jonathan Li, Kyle Gao, Chenglu Wen, Cheng Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Openstory++: A Large-scale Dataset and Benchmark for Instance-aware Open-domain Visual Storytelling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03695</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03695v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent image generation models excel at creating high-quality images from brief captions. However, they fail to maintain consistency of multiple instances across images when encountering lengthy contexts. This inconsistency is largely due to in existing training datasets the absence of granular instance feature labeling in existing training datasets. To tackle these issues, we introduce Openstory++, a large-scale dataset combining additional instance-level annotations with both images and text. Furthermore, we develop a training methodology that emphasizes entity-centric image-text generation, ensuring that the models learn to effectively interweave visual and textual information. Specifically, Openstory++ streamlines the process of keyframe extraction from open-domain videos, employing vision-language models to generate captions that are then polished by a large language model for narrative continuity. It surpasses previous datasets by offering a more expansive open-domain resource, which incorporates automated captioning, high-resolution imagery tailored for instance count, and extensive frame sequences for temporal consistency. Additionally, we present Cohere-Bench, a pioneering benchmark framework for evaluating the image generation tasks when long multimodal context is provided, including the ability to keep the background, style, instances in the given context coherent. Compared to existing benchmarks, our work fills critical gaps in multi-modal generation, propelling the development of models that can adeptly generate and interpret complex narratives in open-domain environments. Experiments conducted within Cohere-Bench confirm the superiority of Openstory++ in nurturing high-quality visual storytelling models, enhancing their ability to address open-domain generation tasks. More details can be found at https://openstorypp.github.io/</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03695v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zilyu Ye, Jinxiu Liu, Ruotian Peng, Jinjin Cao, Zhiyang Chen, Yiyang Zhang, Ziwei Xuan, Mingyuan Zhou, Xiaoqian Shen, Mohamed Elhoseiny, Qi Liu, Guo-Jun Qi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CAS-ViT: Convolutional Additive Self-attention Vision Transformers for Efficient Mobile Applications</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03703</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03703v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Vision Transformers (ViTs) mark a revolutionary advance in neural networks with their token mixer's powerful global context capability. However, the pairwise token affinity and complex matrix operations limit its deployment on resource-constrained scenarios and real-time applications, such as mobile devices, although considerable efforts have been made in previous works. In this paper, we introduce CAS-ViT: Convolutional Additive Self-attention Vision Transformers, to achieve a balance between efficiency and performance in mobile applications. Firstly, we argue that the capability of token mixers to obtain global contextual information hinges on multiple information interactions, such as spatial and channel domains. Subsequently, we construct a novel additive similarity function following this paradigm and present an efficient implementation named Convolutional Additive Token Mixer (CATM). This simplification leads to a significant reduction in computational overhead. We evaluate CAS-ViT across a variety of vision tasks, including image classification, object detection, instance segmentation, and semantic segmentation. Our experiments, conducted on GPUs, ONNX, and iPhones, demonstrate that CAS-ViT achieves a competitive performance when compared to other state-of-the-art backbones, establishing it as a viable option for efficient mobile vision applications. Our code and model are available at: \url{https://github.com/Tianfang-Zhang/CAS-ViT}</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03703v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tianfang Zhang, Lei Li, Yang Zhou, Wentao Liu, Chen Qian, Xiangyang Ji</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pick of the Bunch: Detecting Infrared Small Targets Beyond Hit-Miss Trade-Offs via Selective Rank-Aware Attention</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03717</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03717v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Infrared small target detection faces the inherent challenge of precisely localizing dim targets amidst complex background clutter. Traditional approaches struggle to balance detection precision and false alarm rates. To break this dilemma, we propose SeRankDet, a deep network that achieves high accuracy beyond the conventional hit-miss trade-off, by following the ``Pick of the Bunch'' principle. At its core lies our Selective Rank-Aware Attention (SeRank) module, employing a non-linear Top-K selection process that preserves the most salient responses, preventing target signal dilution while maintaining constant complexity. Furthermore, we replace the static concatenation typical in U-Net structures with our Large Selective Feature Fusion (LSFF) module, a dynamic fusion strategy that empowers SeRankDet with adaptive feature integration, enhancing its ability to discriminate true targets from false alarms. The network's discernment is further refined by our Dilated Difference Convolution (DDC) module, which merges differential convolution aimed at amplifying subtle target characteristics with dilated convolution to expand the receptive field, thereby substantially improving target-background separation. Despite its lightweight architecture, the proposed SeRankDet sets new benchmarks in state-of-the-art performance across multiple public datasets. The code is available at https://github.com/GrokCV/SeRankDet.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03717v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yimian Dai, Peiwen Pan, Yulei Qian, Yuxuan Li, Xiang Li, Jian Yang, Huan Wan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Soft-Hard Attention U-Net Model and Benchmark Dataset for Multiscale Image Shadow Removal</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03734</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03734v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Effective shadow removal is pivotal in enhancing the visual quality of images in various applications, ranging from computer vision to digital photography. During the last decades physics and machine learning -based methodologies have been proposed; however, most of them have limited capacity in capturing complex shadow patterns due to restrictive model assumptions, neglecting the fact that shadows usually appear at different scales. Also, current datasets used for benchmarking shadow removal are composed of a limited number of images with simple scenes containing mainly uniform shadows cast by single objects, whereas only a few of them include both manual shadow annotations and paired shadow-free images. Aiming to address all these limitations in the context of natural scene imaging, including urban environments with complex scenes, the contribution of this study is twofold: a) it proposes a novel deep learning architecture, named Soft-Hard Attention U-net (SHAU), focusing on multiscale shadow removal; b) it provides a novel synthetic dataset, named Multiscale Shadow Removal Dataset (MSRD), containing complex shadow patterns of multiple scales, aiming to serve as a privacy-preserving dataset for a more comprehensive benchmarking of future shadow removal methodologies. Key architectural components of SHAU are the soft and hard attention modules, which along with multiscale feature extraction blocks enable effective shadow removal of different scales and intensities. The results demonstrate the effectiveness of SHAU over the relevant state-of-the-art shadow removal methods across various benchmark datasets, improving the Peak Signal-to-Noise Ratio and Root Mean Square Error for the shadow area by 25.1% and 61.3%, respectively.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03734v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Eirini Cholopoulou, Dimitrios E. Diamantis, Dimitra-Christina C. Koutsiou, Dimitris K. Iakovidis</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing Multimodal Large Language Models with Quantization-Aware Scale Learning for Efficient Adaptation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03735</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03735v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper presents the first study to explore the potential of parameter quantization for multimodal large language models to alleviate the significant resource constraint encountered during vision-language instruction tuning. We introduce a Quantization-aware Scale LeArning method based on multimodal Warmup, termed QSLAW. This method is grounded in two key innovations: (1) The learning of group-wise scale factors for quantized LLM weights to mitigate the quantization error arising from activation outliers and achieve more effective vision-language instruction tuning; (2) The implementation of a multimodal warmup that progressively integrates linguistic and multimodal training samples, thereby preventing overfitting of the quantized model to multimodal data while ensuring stable adaptation of multimodal large language models to downstream vision-language tasks. Extensive experiments demonstrate that models quantized by QSLAW perform on par with, or even surpass, their full-precision counterparts, while facilitating up to 1.4 times reduction in VL tuning time and GPU consumption. Our code is released at https://github.com/xjjxmu/QSLAW.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03735v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jingjing Xie, Yuxin Zhang, Mingbao Lin, Liujuan Cao, Rongrong Ji</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intuitionistic Fuzzy Cognitive Maps for Interpretable Image Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03745</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03745v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The interpretability of machine learning models is critical, as users may be reluctant to rely on their inferences. Intuitionistic FCMs (iFCMs) have been proposed as an extension of FCMs offering a natural mechanism to assess the quality of their output through the estimation of hesitancy, a concept resembling to human hesitation in decision making. To address the challenge of interpretable image classification, this paper introduces a novel framework, named Interpretable Intuitionistic FCM (I2FCM) which is domain-independent, simple to implement, and can be applied on Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) models, rendering them interpretable. To the best of our knowledge this is the first time iFCMs are applied for image classification. Further novel contributions include: a feature extraction process focusing on the most informative image regions; a learning algorithm for data-driven determination of the intuitionistic fuzzy interconnections of the iFCM; an inherently interpretable classification approach based on image contents. In the context of image classification, hesitancy is considered as a degree of inconfidence with which an image is categorized to a class. The constructed iFCM model distinguishes the most representative image semantics and analyses them utilizing cause-and-effect relations. The effectiveness of the introduced framework is evaluated on publicly available datasets, and the experimental results confirm that it can provide enhanced classification performance, while providing interpretable inferences.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03745v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Georgia Sovatzidi, Michael D. Vasilakakis, Dimitris K. Iakovidis</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Generation Scheme for Thermal Modality with Edge-Guided Adversarial Conditional Diffusion Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03748</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03748v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In challenging low light and adverse weather conditions,thermal vision algorithms,especially object detection,have exhibited remarkable potential,contrasting with the frequent struggles encountered by visible vision algorithms. Nevertheless,the efficacy of thermal vision algorithms driven by deep learning models remains constrained by the paucity of available training data samples. To this end,this paper introduces a novel approach termed the edge guided conditional diffusion model. This framework aims to produce meticulously aligned pseudo thermal images at the pixel level,leveraging edge information extracted from visible images. By utilizing edges as contextual cues from the visible domain,the diffusion model achieves meticulous control over the delineation of objects within the generated images. To alleviate the impacts of those visible-specific edge information that should not appear in the thermal domain,a two-stage modality adversarial training strategy is proposed to filter them out from the generated images by differentiating the visible and thermal modality. Extensive experiments on LLVIP demonstrate ECDM s superiority over existing state-of-the-art approaches in terms of image generation quality.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03748v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Guoqing Zhu, Honghu Pan, Qiang Wang, Chao Tian, Chao Yang, Zhenyu He</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3iGS: Factorised Tensorial Illumination for 3D Gaussian Splatting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03753</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03753v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The use of 3D Gaussians as representation of radiance fields has enabled high quality novel view synthesis at real-time rendering speed. However, the choice of optimising the outgoing radiance of each Gaussian independently as spherical harmonics results in unsatisfactory view dependent effects. In response to these limitations, our work, Factorised Tensorial Illumination for 3D Gaussian Splatting, or 3iGS, improves upon 3D Gaussian Splatting (3DGS) rendering quality. Instead of optimising a single outgoing radiance parameter, 3iGS enhances 3DGS view-dependent effects by expressing the outgoing radiance as a function of a local illumination field and Bidirectional Reflectance Distribution Function (BRDF) features. We optimise a continuous incident illumination field through a Tensorial Factorisation representation, while separately fine-tuning the BRDF features of each 3D Gaussian relative to this illumination field. Our methodology significantly enhances the rendering quality of specular view-dependent effects of 3DGS, while maintaining rapid training and rendering speeds.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03753v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhe Jun Tang, Tat-Jen Cham</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MMSummary: Multimodal Summary Generation for Fetal Ultrasound Video</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03761</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03761v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present the first automated multimodal summary generation system, MMSummary, for medical imaging video, particularly with a focus on fetal ultrasound analysis. Imitating the examination process performed by a human sonographer, MMSummary is designed as a three-stage pipeline, progressing from keyframe detection to keyframe captioning and finally anatomy segmentation and measurement. In the keyframe detection stage, an innovative automated workflow is proposed to progressively select a concise set of keyframes, preserving sufficient video information without redundancy. Subsequently, we adapt a large language model to generate meaningful captions for fetal ultrasound keyframes in the keyframe captioning stage. If a keyframe is captioned as fetal biometry, the segmentation and measurement stage estimates biometric parameters by segmenting the region of interest according to the textual prior. The MMSummary system provides comprehensive summaries for fetal ultrasound examinations and based on reported experiments is estimated to reduce scanning time by approximately 31.5%, thereby suggesting the potential to enhance clinical workflow efficiency.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03761v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoqing Guo, Qianhui Men, J. Alison Noble</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Methodological Explainability Evaluation of an Interpretable Deep Learning Model for Post-Hepatectomy Liver Failure Prediction Incorporating Counterfactual Explanations and Layerwise Relevance Propagation: A Prospective In Silico Trial</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03771</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03771v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Artificial intelligence (AI)-based decision support systems have demonstrated value in predicting post-hepatectomy liver failure (PHLF) in hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC). However, they often lack transparency, and the impact of model explanations on clinicians' decisions has not been thoroughly evaluated. Building on prior research, we developed a variational autoencoder-multilayer perceptron (VAE-MLP) model for preoperative PHLF prediction. This model integrated counterfactuals and layerwise relevance propagation (LRP) to provide insights into its decision-making mechanism. Additionally, we proposed a methodological framework for evaluating the explainability of AI systems. This framework includes qualitative and quantitative assessments of explanations against recognized biomarkers, usability evaluations, and an in silico clinical trial. Our evaluations demonstrated that the model's explanation correlated with established biomarkers and exhibited high usability at both the case and system levels. Furthermore, results from the three-track in silico clinical trial showed that clinicians' prediction accuracy and confidence increased when AI explanations were provided.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03771v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xian Zhong, Zohaib Salahuddin, Yi Chen, Henry C Woodruff, Haiyi Long, Jianyun Peng, Nuwan Udawatte, Roberto Casale, Ayoub Mokhtari, Xiaoer Zhang, Jiayao Huang, Qingyu Wu, Li Tan, Lili Chen, Dongming Li, Xiaoyan Xie, Manxia Lin, Philippe Lambin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vision-Language Guidance for LiDAR-based Unsupervised 3D Object Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03790</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03790v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Accurate 3D object detection in LiDAR point clouds is crucial for autonomous driving systems. To achieve state-of-the-art performance, the supervised training of detectors requires large amounts of human-annotated data, which is expensive to obtain and restricted to predefined object categories. To mitigate manual labeling efforts, recent unsupervised object detection approaches generate class-agnostic pseudo-labels for moving objects, subsequently serving as supervision signal to bootstrap a detector. Despite promising results, these approaches do not provide class labels or generalize well to static objects. Furthermore, they are mostly restricted to data containing multiple drives from the same scene or images from a precisely calibrated and synchronized camera setup. To overcome these limitations, we propose a vision-language-guided unsupervised 3D detection approach that operates exclusively on LiDAR point clouds. We transfer CLIP knowledge to classify point clusters of static and moving objects, which we discover by exploiting the inherent spatio-temporal information of LiDAR point clouds for clustering, tracking, as well as box and label refinement. Our approach outperforms state-of-the-art unsupervised 3D object detectors on the Waymo Open Dataset ($+23~\text{AP}_{3D}$) and Argoverse 2 ($+7.9~\text{AP}_{3D}$) and provides class labels not solely based on object size assumptions, marking a significant advancement in the field.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03790v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Christian Fruhwirth-Reisinger, Wei Lin, Du\v{s}an Mali\'c, Horst Bischof, Horst Possegger</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compact 3D Gaussian Splatting for Static and Dynamic Radiance Fields</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03822</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03822v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: 3D Gaussian splatting (3DGS) has recently emerged as an alternative representation that leverages a 3D Gaussian-based representation and introduces an approximated volumetric rendering, achieving very fast rendering speed and promising image quality. Furthermore, subsequent studies have successfully extended 3DGS to dynamic 3D scenes, demonstrating its wide range of applications. However, a significant drawback arises as 3DGS and its following methods entail a substantial number of Gaussians to maintain the high fidelity of the rendered images, which requires a large amount of memory and storage. To address this critical issue, we place a specific emphasis on two key objectives: reducing the number of Gaussian points without sacrificing performance and compressing the Gaussian attributes, such as view-dependent color and covariance. To this end, we propose a learnable mask strategy that significantly reduces the number of Gaussians while preserving high performance. In addition, we propose a compact but effective representation of view-dependent color by employing a grid-based neural field rather than relying on spherical harmonics. Finally, we learn codebooks to compactly represent the geometric and temporal attributes by residual vector quantization. With model compression techniques such as quantization and entropy coding, we consistently show over 25x reduced storage and enhanced rendering speed compared to 3DGS for static scenes, while maintaining the quality of the scene representation. For dynamic scenes, our approach achieves more than 12x storage efficiency and retains a high-quality reconstruction compared to the existing state-of-the-art methods. Our work provides a comprehensive framework for 3D scene representation, achieving high performance, fast training, compactness, and real-time rendering. Our project page is available at https://maincold2.github.io/c3dgs/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03822v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Joo Chan Lee, Daniel Rho, Xiangyu Sun, Jong Hwan Ko, Eunbyung Park</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Target Prompting for Information Extraction with Vision Language Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03834</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03834v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The recent trend in the Large Vision and Language model has brought a new change in how information extraction systems are built. VLMs have set a new benchmark with their State-of-the-art techniques in understanding documents and building question-answering systems across various industries. They are significantly better at generating text from document images and providing accurate answers to questions. However, there are still some challenges in effectively utilizing these models to build a precise conversational system. General prompting techniques used with large language models are often not suitable for these specially designed vision language models. The output generated by such generic input prompts is ordinary and may contain information gaps when compared with the actual content of the document. To obtain more accurate and specific answers, a well-targeted prompt is required by the vision language model, along with the document image. In this paper, a technique is discussed called Target prompting, which focuses on explicitly targeting parts of document images and generating related answers from those specific regions only. The paper also covers the evaluation of response for each prompting technique using different user queries and input prompts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03834v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dipankar Medhi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bi-Level Spatial and Channel-aware Transformer for Learned Image Compression</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03842</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03842v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent advancements in learned image compression (LIC) methods have demonstrated superior performance over traditional hand-crafted codecs. These learning-based methods often employ convolutional neural networks (CNNs) or Transformer-based architectures. However, these nonlinear approaches frequently overlook the frequency characteristics of images, which limits their compression efficiency. To address this issue, we propose a novel Transformer-based image compression method that enhances the transformation stage by considering frequency components within the feature map. Our method integrates a novel Hybrid Spatial-Channel Attention Transformer Block (HSCATB), where a spatial-based branch independently handles high and low frequencies at the attention layer, and a Channel-aware Self-Attention (CaSA) module captures information across channels, significantly improving compression performance. Additionally, we introduce a Mixed Local-Global Feed Forward Network (MLGFFN) within the Transformer block to enhance the extraction of diverse and rich information, which is crucial for effective compression. These innovations collectively improve the transformation's ability to project data into a more decorrelated latent space, thereby boosting overall compression efficiency. Experimental results demonstrate that our framework surpasses state-of-the-art LIC methods in rate-distortion performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03842v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.IT</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>math.IT</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hamidreza Soltani, Erfan Ghasemi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surgformer: Surgical Transformer with Hierarchical Temporal Attention for Surgical Phase Recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03867</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03867v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Existing state-of-the-art methods for surgical phase recognition either rely on the extraction of spatial-temporal features at a short-range temporal resolution or adopt the sequential extraction of the spatial and temporal features across the entire temporal resolution. However, these methods have limitations in modeling spatial-temporal dependency and addressing spatial-temporal redundancy: 1) These methods fail to effectively model spatial-temporal dependency, due to the lack of long-range information or joint spatial-temporal modeling. 2) These methods utilize dense spatial features across the entire temporal resolution, resulting in significant spatial-temporal redundancy. In this paper, we propose the Surgical Transformer (Surgformer) to address the issues of spatial-temporal modeling and redundancy in an end-to-end manner, which employs divided spatial-temporal attention and takes a limited set of sparse frames as input. Moreover, we propose a novel Hierarchical Temporal Attention (HTA) to capture both global and local information within varied temporal resolutions from a target frame-centric perspective. Distinct from conventional temporal attention that primarily emphasizes dense long-range similarity, HTA not only captures long-term information but also considers local latent consistency among informative frames. HTA then employs pyramid feature aggregation to effectively utilize temporal information across diverse temporal resolutions, thereby enhancing the overall temporal representation. Extensive experiments on two challenging benchmark datasets verify that our proposed Surgformer performs favorably against the state-of-the-art methods. The code is released at https://github.com/isyangshu/Surgformer.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03867v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shu Yang, Luyang Luo, Qiong Wang, Hao Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global-Local Progressive Integration Network for Blind Image Quality Assessment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03885</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03885v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Vision transformers (ViTs) excel in computer vision for modeling long-term dependencies, yet face two key challenges for image quality assessment (IQA): discarding fine details during patch embedding, and requiring extensive training data due to lack of inductive biases. In this study, we propose a Global-Local progressive INTegration network for IQA, called GlintIQA, to address these issues through three key components: 1) Hybrid feature extraction combines ViT-based global feature extractor (VGFE) and convolutional neural networks (CNNs)-based local feature extractor (CLFE) to capture global coarse-grained features and local fine-grained features, respectively. The incorporation of CNNs mitigates the patch-level information loss and inductive bias constraints inherent to ViT architectures. 2) Progressive feature integration leverages diverse kernel sizes in embedding to spatially align coarse- and fine-grained features, and progressively aggregate these features by interactively stacking channel-wise attention and spatial enhancement modules to build effective quality-aware representations. 3) Content similarity-based labeling approach is proposed that automatically assigns quality labels to images with diverse content based on subjective quality scores. This addresses the scarcity of labeled training data in synthetic datasets and bolsters model generalization. The experimental results demonstrate the efficacy of our approach, yielding 5.04% average SROCC gains on cross-authentic dataset evaluations. Moreover, our model and its counterpart pre-trained on the proposed dataset respectively exhibited 5.40% and 13.23% improvements on across-synthetic datasets evaluation. The codes and proposed dataset will be released at https://github.com/XiaoqiWang/GlintIQA.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03885v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoqi Wang, Yun Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual-Modeling Decouple Distillation for Unsupervised Anomaly Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03888</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03888v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Knowledge distillation based on student-teacher network is one of the mainstream solution paradigms for the challenging unsupervised Anomaly Detection task, utilizing the difference in representation capabilities of the teacher and student networks to implement anomaly localization. However, over-generalization of the student network to the teacher network may lead to negligible differences in representation capabilities of anomaly, thus affecting the detection effectiveness. Existing methods address the possible over-generalization by using differentiated students and teachers from the structural perspective or explicitly expanding distilled information from the content perspective, which inevitably result in an increased likelihood of underfitting of the student network and poor anomaly detection capabilities in anomaly center or edge. In this paper, we propose Dual-Modeling Decouple Distillation (DMDD) for the unsupervised anomaly detection. In DMDD, a Decouple Student-Teacher Network is proposed to decouple the initial student features into normality and abnormality features. We further introduce Dual-Modeling Distillation based on normal-anomaly image pairs, fitting normality features of anomalous image and the teacher features of the corresponding normal image, widening the distance between abnormality features and the teacher features in anomalous regions. Synthesizing these two distillation ideas, we achieve anomaly detection which focuses on both edge and center of anomaly. Finally, a Multi-perception Segmentation Network is proposed to achieve focused anomaly map fusion based on multiple attention. Experimental results on MVTec AD show that DMDD surpasses SOTA localization performance of previous knowledge distillation-based methods, reaching 98.85% on pixel-level AUC and 96.13% on PRO.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03888v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3664647.3681669</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Xinyue Liu, Jianyuan Wang, Biao Leng, Shuo Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AdapMTL: Adaptive Pruning Framework for Multitask Learning Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03913</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03913v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In the domain of multimedia and multimodal processing, the efficient handling of diverse data streams such as images, video, and sensor data is paramount. Model compression and multitask learning (MTL) are crucial in this field, offering the potential to address the resource-intensive demands of processing and interpreting multiple forms of media simultaneously. However, effectively compressing a multitask model presents significant challenges due to the complexities of balancing sparsity allocation and accuracy performance across multiple tasks. To tackle these challenges, we propose AdapMTL, an adaptive pruning framework for MTL models. AdapMTL leverages multiple learnable soft thresholds independently assigned to the shared backbone and the task-specific heads to capture the nuances in different components' sensitivity to pruning. During training, it co-optimizes the soft thresholds and MTL model weights to automatically determine the suitable sparsity level at each component to achieve both high task accuracy and high overall sparsity. It further incorporates an adaptive weighting mechanism that dynamically adjusts the importance of task-specific losses based on each task's robustness to pruning. We demonstrate the effectiveness of AdapMTL through comprehensive experiments on popular multitask datasets, namely NYU-v2 and Tiny-Taskonomy, with different architectures, showcasing superior performance compared to state-of-the-art pruning methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03913v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3664647.3681426</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Mingcan Xiang, Steven Jiaxun Tang, Qizheng Yang, Hui Guan, Tongping Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FMiFood: Multi-modal Contrastive Learning for Food Image Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03922</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03922v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Food image classification is the fundamental step in image-based dietary assessment, which aims to estimate participants' nutrient intake from eating occasion images. A common challenge of food images is the intra-class diversity and inter-class similarity, which can significantly hinder classification performance. To address this issue, we introduce a novel multi-modal contrastive learning framework called FMiFood, which learns more discriminative features by integrating additional contextual information, such as food category text descriptions, to enhance classification accuracy. Specifically, we propose a flexible matching technique that improves the similarity matching between text and image embeddings to focus on multiple key information. Furthermore, we incorporate the classification objectives into the framework and explore the use of GPT-4 to enrich the text descriptions and provide more detailed context. Our method demonstrates improved performance on both the UPMC-101 and VFN datasets compared to existing methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03922v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xinyue Pan, Jiangpeng He, Fengqing Zhu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fast Sprite Decomposition from Animated Graphics</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03923</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03923v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper presents an approach to decomposing animated graphics into sprites, a set of basic elements or layers. Our approach builds on the optimization of sprite parameters to fit the raster video. For efficiency, we assume static textures for sprites to reduce the search space while preventing artifacts using a texture prior model. To further speed up the optimization, we introduce the initialization of the sprite parameters utilizing a pre-trained video object segmentation model and user input of single frame annotations. For our study, we construct the Crello Animation dataset from an online design service and define quantitative metrics to measure the quality of the extracted sprites. Experiments show that our method significantly outperforms baselines for similar decomposition tasks in terms of the quality/efficiency tradeoff.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03923v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tomoyuki Suzuki, Kotaro Kikuchi, Kota Yamaguchi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Well Can Vision Language Models See Image Details?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03940</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03940v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Model-based Vision-Language Models (LLM-based VLMs) have demonstrated impressive results in various vision-language understanding tasks. However, how well these VLMs can see image detail beyond the semantic level remains unclear. In our study, we introduce a pixel value prediction task (PVP) to explore "How Well Can Vision Language Models See Image Details?" and to assist VLMs in perceiving more details. Typically, these models comprise a frozen CLIP visual encoder, a large language model, and a connecting module. After fine-tuning VLMs on the PVP task, we find: 1) existing VLMs struggle to predict precise pixel values by only fine-tuning the connection module and LLM; and 2) prediction precision is significantly improved when the vision encoder is also adapted. Additionally, our research reveals that incorporating pixel value prediction as one of the VLM pre-training tasks and vision encoder adaptation markedly boosts VLM performance on downstream image-language understanding tasks requiring detailed image perception, such as referring image segmentation (with an average +10.19 cIoU improvement) and video game decision making (with average score improvements of +80.34 and +70.54 on two games, respectively).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03940v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chenhui Gou, Abdulwahab Felemban, Faizan Farooq Khan, Deyao Zhu, Jianfei Cai, Hamid Rezatofighi, Mohamed Elhoseiny</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Empirical Comparison of Video Frame Sampling Methods for Multi-Modal RAG Retrieval</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03340</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03340v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Numerous video frame sampling methodologies detailed in the literature present a significant challenge in determining the optimal video frame method for Video RAG pattern without a comparative side-by-side analysis. In this work, we investigate the trade-offs in frame sampling methods for Video &amp; Frame Retrieval using natural language questions. We explore the balance between the quantity of sampled frames and the retrieval recall score, aiming to identify efficient video frame sampling strategies that maintain high retrieval efficacy with reduced storage and processing demands. Our study focuses on the storage and retrieval of image data (video frames) within a vector database required by Video RAG pattern, comparing the effectiveness of various frame sampling techniques. Our investigation indicates that the recall@k metric for both text-to-video and text-to-frame retrieval tasks using various methods covered as part of this work is comparable to or exceeds that of storing each frame from the video. Our findings are intended to inform the selection of frame sampling methods for practical Video RAG implementations, serving as a springboard for innovative research in this domain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03340v1</guid>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mahesh Kandhare, Thibault Gisselbrecht</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IVISIT: An Interactive Visual Simulation Tool for system simulation, visualization, optimization, and parameter management</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03341</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03341v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: IVISIT is a generic interactive visual simulation tool that is based on Python/Numpy and can be used for system simulation, parameter optimization, parameter management, and visualization of system dynamics as required, for example,for developing neural network simulations, machine learning applications, or computer vision systems. It provides classes for rapid prototyping of applications and visualization and manipulation of system properties using interactive GUI elements like sliders, images, textboxes, option lists, checkboxes and buttons based on Tkinter and Matplotlib. Parameters and simulation configurations can be stored and managed based on SQLite database functions. This technical report describes the main architecture and functions of IVISIT, and provides easy examples how to rapidly implement interactive applications and manage parameter settings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03341v1</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Andreas Knoblauch</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GMAI-MMBench: A Comprehensive Multimodal Evaluation Benchmark Towards General Medical AI</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03361</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03361v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large Vision-Language Models (LVLMs) are capable of handling diverse data types such as imaging, text, and physiological signals, and can be applied in various fields. In the medical field, LVLMs have a high potential to offer substantial assistance for diagnosis and treatment. Before that, it is crucial to develop benchmarks to evaluate LVLMs' effectiveness in various medical applications. Current benchmarks are often built upon specific academic literature, mainly focusing on a single domain, and lacking varying perceptual granularities. Thus, they face specific challenges, including limited clinical relevance, incomplete evaluations, and insufficient guidance for interactive LVLMs. To address these limitations, we developed the GMAI-MMBench, the most comprehensive general medical AI benchmark with well-categorized data structure and multi-perceptual granularity to date. It is constructed from 285 datasets across 39 medical image modalities, 18 clinical-related tasks, 18 departments, and 4 perceptual granularities in a Visual Question Answering (VQA) format. Additionally, we implemented a lexical tree structure that allows users to customize evaluation tasks, accommodating various assessment needs and substantially supporting medical AI research and applications. We evaluated 50 LVLMs, and the results show that even the advanced GPT-4o only achieves an accuracy of 52\%, indicating significant room for improvement. Moreover, we identified five key insufficiencies in current cutting-edge LVLMs that need to be addressed to advance the development of better medical applications. We believe that GMAI-MMBench will stimulate the community to build the next generation of LVLMs toward GMAI.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03361v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Pengcheng Chen, Jin Ye, Guoan Wang, Yanjun Li, Zhongying Deng, Wei Li, Tianbin Li, Haodong Duan, Ziyan Huang, Yanzhou Su, Benyou Wang, Shaoting Zhang, Bin Fu, Jianfei Cai, Bohan Zhuang, Eric J Seibel, Junjun He, Yu Qiao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Non-negative VAE:the Generalized Gamma Belief Network</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03388</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03388v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The gamma belief network (GBN), often regarded as a deep topic model, has demonstrated its potential for uncovering multi-layer interpretable latent representations in text data. Its notable capability to acquire interpretable latent factors is partially attributed to sparse and non-negative gamma-distributed latent variables. However, the existing GBN and its variations are constrained by the linear generative model, thereby limiting their expressiveness and applicability. To address this limitation, we introduce the generalized gamma belief network (Generalized GBN) in this paper, which extends the original linear generative model to a more expressive non-linear generative model. Since the parameters of the Generalized GBN no longer possess an analytic conditional posterior, we further propose an upward-downward Weibull inference network to approximate the posterior distribution of the latent variables. The parameters of both the generative model and the inference network are jointly trained within the variational inference framework. Finally, we conduct comprehensive experiments on both expressivity and disentangled representation learning tasks to evaluate the performance of the Generalized GBN against state-of-the-art Gaussian variational autoencoders serving as baselines.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03388v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhibin Duan, Tiansheng Wen, Muyao Wang, Bo Chen, Mingyuan Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biomedical Image Segmentation: A Systematic Literature Review of Deep Learning Based Object Detection Methods</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03393</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03393v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Biomedical image segmentation plays a vital role in diagnosis of diseases across various organs. Deep learning-based object detection methods are commonly used for such segmentation. There exists an extensive research in this topic. However, there is no standard review on this topic. Existing surveys often lack a standardized approach or focus on broader segmentation techniques. In this paper, we conducted a systematic literature review (SLR), collected and analysed 148 articles that explore deep learning object detection methods for biomedical image segmentation. We critically analyzed these methods, identified the key challenges, and discussed the future directions. From the selected articles we extracted the results including the deep learning models, targeted imaging modalities, targeted diseases, and the metrics for the analysis of the methods. The results have been presented in tabular and/or charted forms. The results are presented in three major categories including two stage detection models, one stage detection models and point-based detection models. Each article is individually analyzed along with its pros and cons. Finally, we discuss open challenges, potential benefits, and future research directions. This SLR aims to provide the research community with a quick yet deeper understanding of these segmentation models, ultimately facilitating the development of more powerful solutions for biomedical image analysis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03393v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fazli Wahid, Yingliang Ma, Dawar Khan, Muhammad Aamir, Syed U. K. Bukhari</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post-Mortem Human Iris Segmentation Analysis with Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03448</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03448v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Iris recognition is widely used in several fields such as mobile phones, financial transactions, identification cards, airport security, international border control, voter registration for living persons. However, the possibility of identifying deceased individuals based on their iris patterns has emerged recently as a supplementary or alternative method valuable in forensic analysis. Simultaneously, it poses numerous new technological challenges and one of the most challenging among them is the image segmentation stage as conventional iris recognition approaches have struggled to reliably execute it. This paper presents and compares Deep Learning (DL) models designed for segmenting iris images collected from the deceased subjects, by training SegNet and DeepLabV3+ semantic segmentation methods where using VGG19, ResNet18, ResNet50, MobileNetv2, Xception, or InceptionResNetv2 as backbones. In this study, our experiments demonstrate that our proposed method effectively learns and identifies specific deformations inherent in post-mortem samples and providing a significant improvement in accuracy. By employing our novel method MobileNetv2 as the backbone of DeepLabV3+ and replacing the final layer with a hybrid loss function combining Boundary and Dice loss, we achieve Mean Intersection over Union of 95.54% on the Warsaw-BioBase-PostMortem-Iris-v1 dataset. To the best of our knowledge, this study provides the most extensive evaluation of DL models for post-mortem iris segmentation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03448v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Afzal Hossain, Tipu Sultan, Stephanie Schuckers</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MultiHateClip: A Multilingual Benchmark Dataset for Hateful Video Detection on YouTube and Bilibili</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03468</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03468v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Hate speech is a pressing issue in modern society, with significant effects both online and offline. Recent research in hate speech detection has primarily centered on text-based media, largely overlooking multimodal content such as videos. Existing studies on hateful video datasets have predominantly focused on English content within a Western context and have been limited to binary labels (hateful or non-hateful), lacking detailed contextual information. This study presents MultiHateClip1 , an novel multilingual dataset created through hate lexicons and human annotation. It aims to enhance the detection of hateful videos on platforms such as YouTube and Bilibili, including content in both English and Chinese languages. Comprising 2,000 videos annotated for hatefulness, offensiveness, and normalcy, this dataset provides a cross-cultural perspective on gender-based hate speech. Through a detailed examination of human annotation results, we discuss the differences between Chinese and English hateful videos and underscore the importance of different modalities in hateful and offensive video analysis. Evaluations of state-of-the-art video classification models, such as VLM, GPT-4V and Qwen-VL, on MultiHateClip highlight the existing challenges in accurately distinguishing between hateful and offensive content and the urgent need for models that are both multimodally and culturally nuanced. MultiHateClip represents a foundational advance in enhancing hateful video detection by underscoring the necessity of a multimodal and culturally sensitive approach in combating online hate speech.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03468v1</guid>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3664647.3681521</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Han Wang, Tan Rui Yang, Usman Naseem, Roy Ka-Wei Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HistoSPACE: Histology-Inspired Spatial Transcriptome Prediction And Characterization Engine</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03592</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03592v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Spatial transcriptomics (ST) enables the visualization of gene expression within the context of tissue morphology. This emerging discipline has the potential to serve as a foundation for developing tools to design precision medicines. However, due to the higher costs and expertise required for such experiments, its translation into a regular clinical practice might be challenging. Despite the implementation of modern deep learning to enhance information obtained from histological images using AI, efforts have been constrained by limitations in the diversity of information. In this paper, we developed a model, HistoSPACE that explore the diversity of histological images available with ST data to extract molecular insights from tissue image. Our proposed study built an image encoder derived from universal image autoencoder. This image encoder was connected to convolution blocks to built the final model. It was further fine tuned with the help of ST-Data. This model is notably lightweight in compared to traditional histological models. Our developed model demonstrates significant efficiency compared to contemporary algorithms, revealing a correlation of 0.56 in leave-one-out cross-validation. Finally, its robustness was validated through an independent dataset, showing a well matched preditction with predefined disease pathology.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03592v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shivam Kumar, Samrat Chatterjee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Quantum Control Gates for Functional MRI Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03596</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03596v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Quantum computing has emerged as a powerful tool for solving complex problems intractable for classical computers, particularly in popular fields such as cryptography, optimization, and neurocomputing. In this paper, we present a new quantum-based approach named the Hierarchical Quantum Control Gates (HQCG) method for efficient understanding of Functional Magnetic Resonance Imaging (fMRI) data. This approach includes two novel modules: the Local Quantum Control Gate (LQCG) and the Global Quantum Control Gate (GQCG), which are designed to extract local and global features of fMRI signals, respectively. Our method operates end-to-end on a quantum machine, leveraging quantum mechanics to learn patterns within extremely high-dimensional fMRI signals, such as 30,000 samples which is a challenge for classical computers. Empirical results demonstrate that our approach significantly outperforms classical methods. Additionally, we found that the proposed quantum model is more stable and less prone to overfitting than the classical methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03596v1</guid>
      <category>quant-ph</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xuan-Bac Nguyen, Hoang-Quan Nguyen, Hugh Churchill, Samee U. Khan, Khoa Luu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>InPer: Whole-Process Domain Generalization via Causal Intervention and Perturbation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03608</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03608v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Despite the considerable advancements achieved by deep neural networks, their performance tends to degenerate when the test environment diverges from the training ones. Domain generalization (DG) solves this issue by learning representations independent of domain-related information, thus facilitating extrapolation to unseen environments. Existing approaches typically focus on formulating tailored training objectives to extract shared features from the source data. However, the disjointed training and testing procedures may compromise robustness, particularly in the face of unforeseen variations during deployment. In this paper, we propose a novel and holistic framework based on causality, named InPer, designed to enhance model generalization by incorporating causal intervention during training and causal perturbation during testing. Specifically, during the training phase, we employ entropy-based causal intervention (EnIn) to refine the selection of causal variables. To identify samples with anti-interference causal variables from the target domain, we propose a novel metric, homeostatic score, through causal perturbation (HoPer) to construct a prototype classifier in test time. Experimental results across multiple cross-domain tasks confirm the efficacy of InPer.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03608v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>stat.ME</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Luyao Tang, Yuxuan Yuan, Chaoqi Chen, Xinghao Ding, Yue Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distillation Learning Guided by Image Reconstruction for One-Shot Medical Image Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03616</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03616v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Traditional one-shot medical image segmentation (MIS) methods use registration networks to propagate labels from a reference atlas or rely on comprehensive sampling strategies to generate synthetic labeled data for training. However, these methods often struggle with registration errors and low-quality synthetic images, leading to poor performance and generalization. To overcome this, we introduce a novel one-shot MIS framework based on knowledge distillation, which allows the network to directly 'see' real images through a distillation process guided by image reconstruction. It focuses on anatomical structures in a single labeled image and a few unlabeled ones. A registration-based data augmentation network creates realistic, labeled samples, while a feature distillation module helps the student network learn segmentation from these samples, guided by the teacher network. During inference, the streamlined student network accurately segments new images. Evaluations on three public datasets (OASIS for T1 brain MRI, BCV for abdomen CT, and VerSe for vertebrae CT) show superior segmentation performance and generalization across different medical image datasets and modalities compared to leading methods. Our code is available at https://github.com/NoviceFodder/OS-MedSeg.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03616v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Feng Zhou, Yanjie Zhou, Longjie Wang, Yun Peng, David E. Carlson, Liyun Tu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAM2-PATH: A better segment anything model for semantic segmentation in digital pathology</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03651</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03651v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The semantic segmentation task in pathology plays an indispensable role in assisting physicians in determining the condition of tissue lesions. Foundation models, such as the SAM (Segment Anything Model) and SAM2, exhibit exceptional performance in instance segmentation within everyday natural scenes. SAM-PATH has also achieved impressive results in semantic segmentation within the field of pathology. However, in computational pathology, the models mentioned above still have the following limitations. The pre-trained encoder models suffer from a scarcity of pathology image data; SAM and SAM2 are not suitable for semantic segmentation. In this paper, we have designed a trainable Kolmogorov-Arnold Networks(KAN) classification module within the SAM2 workflow, and we have introduced the largest pretrained vision encoder for histopathology (UNI) to date. Our proposed framework, SAM2-PATH, augments SAM2's capability to perform semantic segmentation in digital pathology autonomously, eliminating the need for human provided input prompts. The experimental results demonstrate that, after fine-tuning the KAN classification module and decoder, Our dataset has achieved competitive results on publicly available pathology data. The code has been open-sourced and can be found at the following address: https://github.com/simzhangbest/SAM2PATH.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03651v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mingya Zhang, Liang Wang, Limei Gu, Zhao Li, Yaohui Wang, Tingshen Ling, Xianping Tao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unsupervised Detection of Fetal Brain Anomalies using Denoising Diffusion Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03654</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03654v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Congenital malformations of the brain are among the most common fetal abnormalities that impact fetal development. Previous anomaly detection methods on ultrasound images are based on supervised learning, rely on manual annotations, and risk missing underrepresented categories. In this work, we frame fetal brain anomaly detection as an unsupervised task using diffusion models. To this end, we employ an inpainting-based Noise Agnostic Anomaly Detection approach that identifies the abnormality using diffusion-reconstructed fetal brain images from multiple noise levels. Our approach only requires normal fetal brain ultrasound images for training, addressing the limited availability of abnormal data. Our experiments on a real-world clinical dataset show the potential of using unsupervised methods for fetal brain anomaly detection. Additionally, we comprehensively evaluate how different noise types affect diffusion models in the fetal anomaly detection domain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03654v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Markus Ditlev Sj{\o}gren Olsen, Jakob Ambsdorf, Manxi Lin, Caroline Taks{\o}e-Vester, Morten Bo S{\o}ndergaard Svendsen, Anders Nymark Christensen, Mads Nielsen, Martin Gr{\o}nneb{\ae}k Tolsgaard, Aasa Feragen, Paraskevas Pegios</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Counterfactuals and Uncertainty-Based Explainable Paradigm for the Automated Detection and Segmentation of Renal Cysts in Computed Tomography Images: A Multi-Center Study</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03789</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03789v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Routine computed tomography (CT) scans often detect a wide range of renal cysts, some of which may be malignant. Early and precise localization of these cysts can significantly aid quantitative image analysis. Current segmentation methods, however, do not offer sufficient interpretability at the feature and pixel levels, emphasizing the necessity for an explainable framework that can detect and rectify model inaccuracies. We developed an interpretable segmentation framework and validated it on a multi-centric dataset. A Variational Autoencoder Generative Adversarial Network (VAE-GAN) was employed to learn the latent representation of 3D input patches and reconstruct input images. Modifications in the latent representation using the gradient of the segmentation model generated counterfactual explanations for varying dice similarity coefficients (DSC). Radiomics features extracted from these counterfactual images, using a ground truth cyst mask, were analyzed to determine their correlation with segmentation performance. The DSCs for the original and VAE-GAN reconstructed images for counterfactual image generation showed no significant differences. Counterfactual explanations highlighted how variations in cyst image features influence segmentation outcomes and showed model discrepancies. Radiomics features correlating positively and negatively with dice scores were identified. The uncertainty of the predicted segmentation masks was estimated using posterior sampling of the weight space. The combination of counterfactual explanations and uncertainty maps provided a deeper understanding of the image features within the segmented renal cysts that lead to high uncertainty. The proposed segmentation framework not only achieved high segmentation accuracy but also increased interpretability regarding how image features impact segmentation performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03789v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zohaib Salahuddin, Abdalla Ibrahim, Sheng Kuang, Yousif Widaatalla, Razvan L. Miclea, Oliver Morin, Spencer Behr, Marnix P. M. Kop, Tom Marcelissen, Patricia Zondervan, Auke Jager, Philippe Lambin, Henry C Woodruff</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Real-Time Gaussian Splatting: Accelerating 3DGS through Photometric SLAM</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03825</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03825v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Initial applications of 3D Gaussian Splatting (3DGS) in Visual Simultaneous Localization and Mapping (VSLAM) demonstrate the generation of high-quality volumetric reconstructions from monocular video streams. However, despite these promising advancements, current 3DGS integrations have reduced tracking performance and lower operating speeds compared to traditional VSLAM. To address these issues, we propose integrating 3DGS with Direct Sparse Odometry, a monocular photometric SLAM system. We have done preliminary experiments showing that using Direct Sparse Odometry point cloud outputs, as opposed to standard structure-from-motion methods, significantly shortens the training time needed to achieve high-quality renders. Reducing 3DGS training time enables the development of 3DGS-integrated SLAM systems that operate in real-time on mobile hardware. These promising initial findings suggest further exploration is warranted in combining traditional VSLAM systems with 3DGS.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03825v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yan Song Hu, Dayou Mao, Yuhao Chen, John Zelek</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using a Distance Sensor to Detect Deviations in a Planar Surface</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03838</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03838v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We investigate methods for determining if a planar surface contains geometric deviations (e.g., protrusions, objects, divots, or cliffs) using only an instantaneous measurement from a miniature optical time-of-flight sensor. The key to our method is to utilize the entirety of information encoded in raw time-of-flight data captured by off-the-shelf distance sensors. We provide an analysis of the problem in which we identify the key ambiguity between geometry and surface photometrics. To overcome this challenging ambiguity, we fit a Gaussian mixture model to a small dataset of planar surface measurements. This model implicitly captures the expected geometry and distribution of photometrics of the planar surface and is used to identify measurements that are likely to contain deviations. We characterize our method on a variety of surfaces and planar deviations across a range of scenarios. We find that our method utilizing raw time-of-flight data outperforms baselines which use only derived distance estimates. We build an example application in which our method enables mobile robot obstacle and cliff avoidance over a wide field-of-view.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03838v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Carter Sifferman, William Sun, Mohit Gupta, Michael Gleicher</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lightweight Video Denoising Using a Classic Bayesian Backbone</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03904</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03904v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In recent years, state-of-the-art image and video denoising networks have become increasingly large, requiring millions of trainable parameters to achieve best-in-class performance. Improved denoising quality has come at the cost of denoising speed, where modern transformer networks are far slower to run than smaller denoising networks such as FastDVDnet and classic Bayesian denoisers such as the Wiener filter.
  In this paper, we implement a hybrid Wiener filter which leverages small ancillary networks to increase the original denoiser performance, while retaining fast denoising speeds. These networks are used to refine the Wiener coring estimate, optimise windowing functions and estimate the unknown noise profile. Using these methods, we outperform several popular denoisers and remain within 0.2 dB, on average, of the popular VRT transformer. Our method was found to be over x10 faster than the transformer method, with a far lower parameter cost.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03904v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.SP</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Cl\'ement Bled, Fran\c{c}ois Piti\'e</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum Learning for ab initio Deep Learned Refractive Optics</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2302.01089</link>
      <description>arXiv:2302.01089v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Deep optical optimization has recently emerged as a new paradigm for designing computational imaging systems using only the output image as the objective. However, it has been limited to either simple optical systems consisting of a single element such as a diffractive optical element (DOE) or metalens, or the fine-tuning of compound lenses from good initial designs. Here we present a DeepLens design method based on curriculum learning, which is able to learn optical designs of compound lenses ab initio from randomly initialized surfaces without human intervention, therefore overcoming the need for a good initial design. We demonstrate the effectiveness of our approach by fully automatically designing both classical imaging lenses and a large field-of-view extended depth-of-field computational lens in a cellphone-style form factor, with highly aspheric surfaces and a short back focal length.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2302.01089v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>physics.optics</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1038/s41467-024-50835-7</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Nat Commun 15, 6572 (2024)</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Xinge Yang, Qiang Fu, Wolfgang Heidrich</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RCA: Region Conditioned Adaptation for Visual Abductive Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2303.10428</link>
      <description>arXiv:2303.10428v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Visual abductive reasoning aims to make likely explanations for visual observations. We propose a simple yet effective Region Conditioned Adaptation, a hybrid parameter-efficient fine-tuning method that equips the frozen CLIP with the ability to infer explanations from local visual cues. We encode ``local hints'' and ``global contexts'' into visual prompts of the CLIP model separately at fine and coarse-grained levels. Adapters are used for fine-tuning CLIP models for downstream tasks and we design a new attention adapter, that directly steers the focus of the attention map with trainable query and key projections of a frozen CLIP model. Finally, we train our new model with a modified contrastive loss to regress the visual feature simultaneously toward features of literal description and plausible explanations. The loss enables CLIP to maintain both perception and reasoning abilities. Experiments on the Sherlock visual abductive reasoning benchmark show that the RCA significantly outstands previous SOTAs, ranking the \nth{1} on the leaderboards (e.g., Human Acc: RCA 31.74 \textit{vs} CPT-CLIP 29.58, higher =better). We also validate the RCA is generalizable to local perception benchmarks like RefCOCO. We open-source our project at \textit{\color{magenta}{\url{https://github.com/LUNAProject22/RPA}}}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2303.10428v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hao Zhang, Yeo Keat Ee, Basura Fernando</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASR: Attention-alike Structural Re-parameterization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2304.06345</link>
      <description>arXiv:2304.06345v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The structural re-parameterization (SRP) technique is a novel deep learning technique that achieves interconversion between different network architectures through equivalent parameter transformations. This technique enables the mitigation of the extra costs for performance improvement during training, such as parameter size and inference time, through these transformations during inference, and therefore SRP has great potential for industrial and practical applications. The existing SRP methods have successfully considered many commonly used architectures, such as normalizations, pooling methods, and multi-branch convolution. However, the widely used attention modules which drastically slow inference speed cannot be directly implemented by SRP due to these modules usually act on the backbone network in a multiplicative manner and the modules' output is input-dependent during inference, which limits the application scenarios of SRP. In this paper, we conduct extensive experiments from a statistical perspective and discover an interesting phenomenon Stripe Observation, which reveals that channel attention values quickly approach some constant vectors during training. This observation inspires us to propose a simple-yet-effective attention-alike structural re-parameterization (ASR) that allows us to achieve SRP for a given network while enjoying the effectiveness of the attention mechanism. Extensive experiments conducted on several standard benchmarks demonstrate the effectiveness of ASR in generally improving the performance of existing backbone networks, attention modules, and SRP methods without any elaborated model crafting. We also analyze the limitations and provide experimental and theoretical evidence for the strong robustness of the proposed ASR.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2304.06345v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shanshan Zhong, Zhongzhan Huang, Wushao Wen, Jinghui Qin, Liang Lin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spatial-Frequency Discriminability for Revealing Adversarial Perturbations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2305.10856</link>
      <description>arXiv:2305.10856v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The vulnerability of deep neural networks to adversarial perturbations has been widely perceived in the computer vision community. From a security perspective, it poses a critical risk for modern vision systems, e.g., the popular Deep Learning as a Service (DLaaS) frameworks. For protecting deep models while not modifying them, current algorithms typically detect adversarial patterns through discriminative decomposition for natural and adversarial data. However, these decompositions are either biased towards frequency resolution or spatial resolution, thus failing to capture adversarial patterns comprehensively. Also, when the detector relies on few fixed features, it is practical for an adversary to fool the model while evading the detector (i.e., defense-aware attack). Motivated by such facts, we propose a discriminative detector relying on a spatial-frequency Krawtchouk decomposition. It expands the above works from two aspects: 1) the introduced Krawtchouk basis provides better spatial-frequency discriminability, capturing the differences between natural and adversarial data comprehensively in both spatial and frequency distributions, w.r.t. the common trigonometric or wavelet basis; 2) the extensive features formed by the Krawtchouk decomposition allows for adaptive feature selection and secrecy mechanism, significantly increasing the difficulty of the defense-aware attack, w.r.t. the detector with few fixed features. Theoretical and numerical analyses demonstrate the uniqueness and usefulness of our detector, exhibiting competitive scores on several deep models and image sets against a variety of adversarial attacks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2305.10856v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1109/TCSVT.2024.3432932</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems for Video Technology, 2024</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Chao Wang, Shuren Qi, Zhiqiu Huang, Yushu Zhang, Rushi Lan, Xiaochun Cao, Feng-Lei Fan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semantic-guided modeling of spatial relation and object co-occurrence for indoor scene recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2305.12661</link>
      <description>arXiv:2305.12661v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Exploring the semantic context in scene images is essential for indoor scene recognition. However, due to the diverse intra-class spatial layouts and the coexisting inter-class objects, modeling contextual relationships to adapt various image characteristics is a great challenge. Existing contextual modeling methods for scene recognition exhibit two limitations: 1) They typically model only one type of spatial relationship (order or metric) among objects within scenes, with limited exploration of diverse spatial layouts. 2) They often overlook the differences in coexisting objects across different scenes, suppressing scene recognition performance. To overcome these limitations, we propose SpaCoNet, which simultaneously models Spatial relation and Co-occurrence of objects guided by semantic segmentation. Firstly, the Semantic Spatial Relation Module (SSRM) is constructed to model scene spatial features. With the help of semantic segmentation, this module decouples spatial information from the scene image and thoroughly explores all spatial relationships among objects in an end-to-end manner, thereby obtaining semantic-based spatial features. Secondly, both spatial features from the SSRM and deep features from the Image Feature Extraction Module are allocated to each object, so as to distinguish the coexisting object across different scenes. Finally, utilizing the discriminative features above, we design a Global-Local Dependency Module to explore the long-range co-occurrence among objects, and further generate a semantic-guided feature representation for indoor scene recognition. Experimental results on three widely used scene datasets demonstrate the effectiveness and generality of the proposed method.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2305.12661v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chuanxin Song, Hanbo Wu, Xin Ma</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BASED: Bundle-Adjusting Surgical Endoscopic Dynamic Video Reconstruction using Neural Radiance Fields</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2309.15329</link>
      <description>arXiv:2309.15329v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Reconstruction of deformable scenes from endoscopic videos is important for many applications such as intraoperative navigation, surgical visual perception, and robotic surgery. It is a foundational requirement for realizing autonomous robotic interventions for minimally invasive surgery. However, previous approaches in this domain have been limited by their modular nature and are confined to specific camera and scene settings. Our work adopts the Neural Radiance Fields (NeRF) approach to learning 3D implicit representations of scenes that are both dynamic and deformable over time, and furthermore with unknown camera poses. We demonstrate this approach on endoscopic surgical scenes from robotic surgery. This work removes the constraints of known camera poses and overcomes the drawbacks of the state-of-the-art unstructured dynamic scene reconstruction technique, which relies on the static part of the scene for accurate reconstruction. Through several experimental datasets, we demonstrate the versatility of our proposed model to adapt to diverse camera and scene settings, and show its promise for both current and future robotic surgical systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2309.15329v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shreya Saha, Zekai Liang, Shan Lin, Jingpei Lu, Michael Yip, Sainan Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Every Dataset Counts: Scaling up Monocular 3D Object Detection with Joint Datasets Training</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.00920</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.00920v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Monocular 3D object detection plays a crucial role in autonomous driving. However, existing monocular 3D detection algorithms depend on 3D labels derived from LiDAR measurements, which are costly to acquire for new datasets and challenging to deploy in novel environments. Specifically, this study investigates the pipeline for training a monocular 3D object detection model on a diverse collection of 3D and 2D datasets. The proposed framework comprises three components: (1) a robust monocular 3D model capable of functioning across various camera settings, (2) a selective-training strategy to accommodate datasets with differing class annotations, and (3) a pseudo 3D training approach using 2D labels to enhance detection performance in scenes containing only 2D labels. With this framework, we could train models on a joint set of various open 3D/2D datasets to obtain models with significantly stronger generalization capability and enhanced performance on new dataset with only 2D labels. We conduct extensive experiments on KITTI/nuScenes/ONCE/Cityscapes/BDD100K datasets to demonstrate the scaling ability of the proposed method.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.00920v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fulong Ma, Xiaoyang Yan, Guoyang Zhao, Xiaojie Xu, Yuxuan Liu, Ming Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supervised domain adaptation for building extraction from off-nadir aerial images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.03867</link>
      <description>arXiv:2311.03867v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Building extraction $-$ needed for inventory management and planning of urban environment $-$ is affected by the misalignment between labels and off-nadir source imagery in training data. Teacher-Student learning of noise-tolerant convolutional neural networks (CNNs) is the existing solution, but the Student networks typically have lower accuracy and cannot surpass the Teacher's performance. This paper proposes a supervised domain adaptation (SDA) of encoder-decoder networks (EDNs) between noisy and clean datasets to tackle the problem. EDNs are configured with high-performing lightweight encoders such as EfficientNet, ResNeSt, and MobileViT. The proposed method is compared against the existing Teacher-Student learning methods like knowledge distillation (KD) and deep mutual learning (DML) with three newly developed datasets. The methods are evaluated for different urban buildings (low-rise, mid-rise, high-rise, and skyscrapers), where misalignment increases with the increase in building height and spatial resolution. For a robust experimental design, 43 lightweight CNNs, five optimisers, nine loss functions, and seven EDNs are benchmarked to obtain the best-performing EDN for SDA. The SDA of the best-performing EDN from our study significantly outperformed KD and DML with up to 0.943, 0.868, 0.912, and 0.697 F1 scores in the low-rise, mid-rise, high-rise, and skyscrapers respectively. The proposed method and the experimental findings will be beneficial in training robust CNNs for building extraction.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2311.03867v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bipul Neupane, Jagannath Aryal, Abbas Rajabifard</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Efficacy of Text-Based Input Modalities for Action Anticipation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12972</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.12972v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Anticipating future actions is a highly challenging task due to the diversity and scale of potential future actions; yet, information from different modalities help narrow down plausible action choices. Each modality can provide diverse and often complementary context for the model to learn from. While previous multi-modal methods leverage information from modalities such as video and audio, we primarily explore how text descriptions of actions and objects can also lead to more accurate action anticipation by providing additional contextual cues, e.g., about the environment and its contents. We propose a Multi-modal Contrastive Anticipative Transformer (M-CAT), a video transformer architecture that jointly learns from multi-modal features and text descriptions of actions and objects. We train our model in two stages, where the model first learns to align video clips with descriptions of future actions, and is subsequently fine-tuned to predict future actions. Compared to existing methods, M-CAT has the advantage of learning additional context from two types of text inputs: rich descriptions of future actions during pre-training, and, text descriptions for detected objects and actions during modality feature fusion. Through extensive experimental evaluation, we demonstrate that our model outperforms previous methods on the EpicKitchens datasets, and show that using simple text descriptions of actions and objects aid in more effective action anticipation. In addition, we examine the impact of object and action information obtained via text, and perform extensive ablations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.12972v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Apoorva Beedu, Karan Samel, Irfan Essa</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S^2Former-OR: Single-Stage Bi-Modal Transformer for Scene Graph Generation in OR</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.14461</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.14461v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Scene graph generation (SGG) of surgical procedures is crucial in enhancing holistically cognitive intelligence in the operating room (OR). However, previous works have primarily relied on multi-stage learning, where the generated semantic scene graphs depend on intermediate processes with pose estimation and object detection. This pipeline may potentially compromise the flexibility of learning multimodal representations, consequently constraining the overall effectiveness. In this study, we introduce a novel single-stage bi-modal transformer framework for SGG in the OR, termed S^2Former-OR, aimed to complementally leverage multi-view 2D scenes and 3D point clouds for SGG in an end-to-end manner. Concretely, our model embraces a View-Sync Transfusion scheme to encourage multi-view visual information interaction. Concurrently, a Geometry-Visual Cohesion operation is designed to integrate the synergic 2D semantic features into 3D point cloud features. Moreover, based on the augmented feature, we propose a novel relation-sensitive transformer decoder that embeds dynamic entity-pair queries and relational trait priors, which enables the direct prediction of entity-pair relations for graph generation without intermediate steps. Extensive experiments have validated the superior SGG performance and lower computational cost of S^2Former-OR on 4D-OR benchmark, compared with current OR-SGG methods, e.g., 3 percentage points Precision increase and 24.2M reduction in model parameters. We further compared our method with generic single-stage SGG methods with broader metrics for a comprehensive evaluation, with consistently better performance achieved.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.14461v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jialun Pei, Diandian Guo, Jingyang Zhang, Manxi Lin, Yueming Jin, Pheng-Ann Heng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meta-Prompting for Automating Zero-shot Visual Recognition with LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.11755</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.11755v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Prompt ensembling of Large Language Model (LLM) generated category-specific prompts has emerged as an effective method to enhance zero-shot recognition ability of Vision-Language Models (VLMs). To obtain these category-specific prompts, the present methods rely on hand-crafting the prompts to the LLMs for generating VLM prompts for the downstream tasks. However, this requires manually composing these task-specific prompts and still, they might not cover the diverse set of visual concepts and task-specific styles associated with the categories of interest. To effectively take humans out of the loop and completely automate the prompt generation process for zero-shot recognition, we propose Meta-Prompting for Visual Recognition (MPVR). Taking as input only minimal information about the target task, in the form of its short natural language description, and a list of associated class labels, MPVR automatically produces a diverse set of category-specific prompts resulting in a strong zero-shot classifier. MPVR generalizes effectively across various popular zero-shot image recognition benchmarks belonging to widely different domains when tested with multiple LLMs and VLMs. For example, MPVR obtains a zero-shot recognition improvement over CLIP by up to 19.8% and 18.2% (5.0% and 4.5% on average over 20 datasets) leveraging GPT and Mixtral LLMs, respectively</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.11755v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>M. Jehanzeb Mirza, Leonid Karlinsky, Wei Lin, Sivan Doveh, Jakub Micorek, Mateusz Kozinski, Hilde Kuehne, Horst Possegger</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Subjective-Aligned Dataset and Metric for Text-to-Video Quality Assessment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.11956</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.11956v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: With the rapid development of generative models, Artificial Intelligence-Generated Contents (AIGC) have exponentially increased in daily lives. Among them, Text-to-Video (T2V) generation has received widespread attention. Though many T2V models have been released for generating high perceptual quality videos, there is still lack of a method to evaluate the quality of these videos quantitatively. To solve this issue, we establish the largest-scale Text-to-Video Quality Assessment DataBase (T2VQA-DB) to date. The dataset is composed of 10,000 videos generated by 9 different T2V models. We also conduct a subjective study to obtain each video's corresponding mean opinion score. Based on T2VQA-DB, we propose a novel transformer-based model for subjective-aligned Text-to-Video Quality Assessment (T2VQA). The model extracts features from text-video alignment and video fidelity perspectives, then it leverages the ability of a large language model to give the prediction score. Experimental results show that T2VQA outperforms existing T2V metrics and SOTA video quality assessment models. Quantitative analysis indicates that T2VQA is capable of giving subjective-align predictions, validating its effectiveness. The dataset and code will be released at https://github.com/QMME/T2VQA.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.11956v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tengchuan Kou, Xiaohong Liu, Zicheng Zhang, Chunyi Li, Haoning Wu, Xiongkuo Min, Guangtao Zhai, Ning Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pose-Aware Self-Supervised Learning with Viewpoint Trajectory Regularization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.14973</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.14973v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Learning visual features from unlabeled images has proven successful for semantic categorization, often by mapping different $views$ of the same object to the same feature to achieve recognition invariance. However, visual recognition involves not only identifying $what$ an object is but also understanding $how$ it is presented. For example, seeing a car from the side versus head-on is crucial for deciding whether to stay put or jump out of the way. While unsupervised feature learning for downstream viewpoint reasoning is important, it remains under-explored, partly due to the lack of a standardized evaluation method and benchmarks.
  We introduce a new dataset of adjacent image triplets obtained from a viewpoint trajectory, without any semantic or pose labels. We benchmark both semantic classification and pose estimation accuracies on the same visual feature. Additionally, we propose a viewpoint trajectory regularization loss for learning features from unlabeled image triplets. Our experiments demonstrate that this approach helps develop a visual representation that encodes object identity and organizes objects by their poses, retaining semantic classification accuracy while achieving emergent global pose awareness and better generalization to novel objects. Our dataset and code are available at http://pwang.pw/trajSSL/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.14973v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiayun Wang, Yubei Chen, Stella X. Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UniTraj: A Unified Framework for Scalable Vehicle Trajectory Prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.15098</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.15098v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Vehicle trajectory prediction has increasingly relied on data-driven solutions, but their ability to scale to different data domains and the impact of larger dataset sizes on their generalization remain under-explored. While these questions can be studied by employing multiple datasets, it is challenging due to several discrepancies, e.g., in data formats, map resolution, and semantic annotation types. To address these challenges, we introduce UniTraj, a comprehensive framework that unifies various datasets, models, and evaluation criteria, presenting new opportunities for the vehicle trajectory prediction field. In particular, using UniTraj, we conduct extensive experiments and find that model performance significantly drops when transferred to other datasets. However, enlarging data size and diversity can substantially improve performance, leading to a new state-of-the-art result for the nuScenes dataset. We provide insights into dataset characteristics to explain these findings. The code can be found here: https://github.com/vita-epfl/UniTraj</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.15098v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lan Feng, Mohammadhossein Bahari, Kaouther Messaoud Ben Amor, \'Eloi Zablocki, Matthieu Cord, Alexandre Alahi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EgoNav: Egocentric Scene-aware Human Trajectory Prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.19026</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.19026v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Wearable collaborative robots stand to assist human wearers who need fall prevention assistance or wear exoskeletons. Such a robot needs to be able to constantly adapt to the surrounding scene based on egocentric vision, and predict the ego motion of the wearer. In this work, we leveraged body-mounted cameras and sensors to anticipate the trajectory of human wearers through complex surroundings. To facilitate research in ego-motion prediction, we have collected a comprehensive walking scene navigation dataset centered on the user's perspective. We then present a method to predict human motion conditioning on the surrounding static scene. Our method leverages a diffusion model to produce a distribution of potential future trajectories, taking into account the user's observation of the environment. To that end, we introduce a compact representation to encode the user's visual memory of the surroundings, as well as an efficient sample-generating technique to speed up real-time inference of a diffusion model. We ablate our model and compare it to baselines, and results show that our model outperforms existing methods on key metrics of collision avoidance and trajectory mode coverage.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.19026v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weizhuo Wang, C. Karen Liu, Monroe Kennedy III</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DenseNets Reloaded: Paradigm Shift Beyond ResNets and ViTs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.19588</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.19588v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper revives Densely Connected Convolutional Networks (DenseNets) and reveals the underrated effectiveness over predominant ResNet-style architectures. We believe DenseNets' potential was overlooked due to untouched training methods and traditional design elements not fully revealing their capabilities. Our pilot study shows dense connections through concatenation are strong, demonstrating that DenseNets can be revitalized to compete with modern architectures. We methodically refine suboptimal components - architectural adjustments, block redesign, and improved training recipes towards widening DenseNets and boosting memory efficiency while keeping concatenation shortcuts. Our models, employing simple architectural elements, ultimately surpass Swin Transformer, ConvNeXt, and DeiT-III - key architectures in the residual learning lineage. Furthermore, our models exhibit near state-of-the-art performance on ImageNet-1K, competing with the very recent models and downstream tasks, ADE20k semantic segmentation, and COCO object detection/instance segmentation. Finally, we provide empirical analyses that uncover the merits of the concatenation over additive shortcuts, steering a renewed preference towards DenseNet-style designs. Our code is available at https://github.com/naver-ai/rdnet.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.19588v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.NE</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Donghyun Kim, Byeongho Heo, Dongyoon Han</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ENet-21: An Optimized light CNN Structure for Lane Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.19782</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.19782v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Lane detection for autonomous vehicles is an important concept, yet it is a challenging issue of driver assistance systems in modern vehicles. The emergence of deep learning leads to significant progress in self-driving cars. Conventional deep learning-based methods handle lane detection problems as a binary segmentation task and determine whether a pixel belongs to a line. These methods rely on the assumption of a fixed number of lanes, which does not always work. This study aims to develop an optimal structure for the lane detection problem, offering a promising solution for driver assistance features in modern vehicles by utilizing a machine learning method consisting of binary segmentation and Affinity Fields that can manage varying numbers of lanes and lane change scenarios. In this approach, the Convolutional Neural Network (CNN), is selected as a feature extractor, and the final output is obtained through clustering of the semantic segmentation and Affinity Field outputs. Our method uses less complex CNN architecture than existing ones. Experiments on the TuSimple dataset support the effectiveness of the proposed method.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.19782v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Seyed Rasoul Hosseini, Hamid Taheri, Mohammad Teshnehlab</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DPA-Net: Structured 3D Abstraction from Sparse Views via Differentiable Primitive Assembly</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.00875</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.00875v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We present a differentiable rendering framework to learn structured 3D abstractions in the form of primitive assemblies from sparse RGB images capturing a 3D object. By leveraging differentiable volume rendering, our method does not require 3D supervision. Architecturally, our network follows the general pipeline of an image-conditioned neural radiance field (NeRF) exemplified by pixelNeRF for color prediction. As our core contribution, we introduce differential primitive assembly (DPA) into NeRF to output a 3D occupancy field in place of density prediction, where the predicted occupancies serve as opacity values for volume rendering. Our network, coined DPA-Net, produces a union of convexes, each as an intersection of convex quadric primitives, to approximate the target 3D object, subject to an abstraction loss and a masking loss, both defined in the image space upon volume rendering. With test-time adaptation and additional sampling and loss designs aimed at improving the accuracy and compactness of the obtained assemblies, our method demonstrates superior performance over state-of-the-art alternatives for 3D primitive abstraction from sparse views.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.00875v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fenggen Yu, Yiming Qian, Xu Zhang, Francisca Gil-Ureta, Brian Jackson, Eric Bennett, Hao Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RoadBEV: Road Surface Reconstruction in Bird's Eye View</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.06605</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.06605v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Road surface conditions, especially geometry profiles, enormously affect driving performance of autonomous vehicles. Vision-based online road reconstruction promisingly captures road information in advance. Existing solutions like monocular depth estimation and stereo matching suffer from modest performance. The recent technique of Bird's-Eye-View (BEV) perception provides immense potential to more reliable and accurate reconstruction. This paper uniformly proposes two simple yet effective models for road elevation reconstruction in BEV named RoadBEV-mono and RoadBEV-stereo, which estimate road elevation with monocular and stereo images, respectively. The former directly fits elevation values based on voxel features queried from image view, while the latter efficiently recognizes road elevation patterns based on BEV volume representing correlation between left and right voxel features. Insightful analyses reveal their consistence and difference with the perspective view. Experiments on real-world dataset verify the models' effectiveness and superiority. Elevation errors of RoadBEV-mono and RoadBEV-stereo achieve 1.83 cm and 0.50 cm, respectively. Our models are promising for practical road preview, providing essential information for promoting safety and comfort of autonomous vehicles. The code is released at https://github.com/ztsrxh/RoadBEV</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.06605v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tong Zhao, Lei Yang, Yichen Xie, Mingyu Ding, Masayoshi Tomizuka, Yintao Wei</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Composed Image Retrieval via Contrastive Learning with Scaling Positives and Negatives</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.11317</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.11317v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The Composed Image Retrieval (CIR) task aims to retrieve target images using a composed query consisting of a reference image and a modified text. Advanced methods often utilize contrastive learning as the optimization objective, which benefits from adequate positive and negative examples. However, the triplet for CIR incurs high manual annotation costs, resulting in limited positive examples. Furthermore, existing methods commonly use in-batch negative sampling, which reduces the negative number available for the model. To address the problem of lack of positives, we propose a data generation method by leveraging a multi-modal large language model to construct triplets for CIR. To introduce more negatives during fine-tuning, we design a two-stage fine-tuning framework for CIR, whose second stage introduces plenty of static representations of negatives to optimize the representation space rapidly. The above two improvements can be effectively stacked and designed to be plug-and-play, easily applied to existing CIR models without changing their original architectures. Extensive experiments and ablation analysis demonstrate that our method effectively scales positives and negatives and achieves state-of-the-art results on both FashionIQ and CIRR datasets. In addition, our method also performs well in zero-shot composed image retrieval, providing a new CIR solution for the low-resources scenario. Our code and data are released at https://github.com/BUAADreamer/SPN4CIR.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.11317v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhangchi Feng, Richong Zhang, Zhijie Nie</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrossMatch: Enhance Semi-Supervised Medical Image Segmentation with Perturbation Strategies and Knowledge Distillation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.00354</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.00354v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Semi-supervised learning for medical image segmentation presents a unique challenge of efficiently using limited labeled data while leveraging abundant unlabeled data. Despite advancements, existing methods often do not fully exploit the potential of the unlabeled data for enhancing model robustness and accuracy. In this paper, we introduce CrossMatch, a novel framework that integrates knowledge distillation with dual perturbation strategies-image-level and feature-level-to improve the model's learning from both labeled and unlabeled data. CrossMatch employs multiple encoders and decoders to generate diverse data streams, which undergo self-knowledge distillation to enhance consistency and reliability of predictions across varied perturbations. Our method significantly surpasses other state-of-the-art techniques in standard benchmarks by effectively minimizing the gap between training on labeled and unlabeled data and improving edge accuracy and generalization in medical image segmentation. The efficacy of CrossMatch is demonstrated through extensive experimental validations, showing remarkable performance improvements without increasing computational costs. Code for this implementation is made available at https://github.com/AiEson/CrossMatch.git.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.00354v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bin Zhao, Chunshi Wang, Shuxue Ding</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compression-Realized Deep Structural Network for Video Quality Enhancement</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.06342</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.06342v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper focuses on the task of quality enhancement for compressed videos. Although deep network-based video restorers achieve impressive progress, most of the existing methods lack a structured design to optimally leverage the priors within compression codecs. Since the quality degradation of the video is primarily induced by the compression algorithm, a new paradigm is urgently needed for a more ``conscious'' process of quality enhancement. As a result, we propose the Compression-Realized Deep Structural Network (CRDS), introducing three inductive biases aligned with the three primary processes in the classic compression codec, merging the strengths of classical encoder architecture with deep network capabilities. Inspired by the residual extraction and domain transformation process in the codec, a pre-trained Latent Degradation Residual Auto-Encoder is proposed to transform video frames into a latent feature space, and the mutual neighborhood attention mechanism is integrated for precise motion estimation and residual extraction. Furthermore, drawing inspiration from the quantization noise distribution of the codec, CRDS proposes a novel Progressive Denoising framework with intermediate supervision that decomposes the quality enhancement into a series of simpler denoising sub-tasks. Experimental results on datasets like LDV 2.0 and MFQE 2.0 indicate our approach surpasses state-of-the-art models. Codes are available at https://github.com/shc15522/CRDS.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.06342v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hanchi Sun, Xiaohong Liu, Xinyang Jiang, Yifei Shen, Dongsheng Li, Xiongkuo Min, Guangtao Zhai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FA-Depth: Toward Fast and Accurate Self-supervised Monocular Depth Estimation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.10885</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.10885v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Most existing methods often rely on complex models to predict scene depth with high accuracy, resulting in slow inference that is not conducive to deployment. To better balance precision and speed, we first designed SmallDepth based on sparsity. Second, to enhance the feature representation ability of SmallDepth during training under the condition of equal complexity during inference, we propose an equivalent transformation module(ETM). Third, to improve the ability of each layer in the case of a fixed SmallDepth to perceive different context information and improve the robustness of SmallDepth to the left-right direction and illumination changes, we propose pyramid loss. Fourth, to further improve the accuracy of SmallDepth, we utilized the proposed function approximation loss (APX) to transfer knowledge in the pretrained HQDecv2, obtained by optimizing the previous HQDec to address grid artifacts in some regions, to SmallDepth. Extensive experiments demonstrate that each proposed component improves the precision of SmallDepth without changing the complexity of SmallDepth during inference, and the developed approach achieves state-of-the-art results on KITTI at an inference speed of more than 500 frames per second and with approximately 2 M parameters. The code and models will be publicly available at https://github.com/fwucas/FA-Depth.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.10885v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fei Wang, Jun Cheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Capsule Network Projectors are Equivariant and Invariant Learners</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.14386</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.14386v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Learning invariant representations has been the longstanding approach to self-supervised learning. However, recently progress has been made in preserving equivariant properties in representations, yet do so with highly prescribed architectures. In this work, we propose an invariant-equivariant self-supervised architecture that employs Capsule Networks (CapsNets) which have been shown to capture equivariance with respect to novel viewpoints. We demonstrate that the use of CapsNets in equivariant self-supervised architectures achieves improved downstream performance on equivariant tasks with higher efficiency and fewer network parameters. To accommodate the architectural changes of CapsNets, we introduce a new objective function based on entropy minimisation. This approach which we name CapsIE (Capsule Invariant Equivariant Network) achieves state-of-the-art performance across invariant and equivariant tasks on the 3DIEBench dataset compared to prior equivariant SSL methods, while outperforming supervised baselines. Our results demonstrate the ability of CapsNets to learn complex and generalised representations for large-scale, multi-task datasets compared to previous CapsNet benchmarks. Code is available at https://github.com/AberdeenML/CapsIE.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.14386v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Miles Everett, Aiden Durrant, Mingjun Zhong, Georgios Leontidis</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visualize and Paint GAN Activations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.15636</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.15636v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We investigate how generated structures of GANs correlate with their activations in hidden layers, with the purpose of better understanding the inner workings of those models and being able to paint structures with unconditionally trained GANs. This gives us more control over the generated images, allowing to generate them from a semantic segmentation map while not requiring such a segmentation in the training data. To this end we introduce the concept of tileable features, allowing us to identify activations that work well for painting.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.15636v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rudolf Herdt, Peter Maass</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FourierMamba: Fourier Learning Integration with State Space Models for Image Deraining</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.19450</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.19450v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Image deraining aims to remove rain streaks from rainy images and restore clear backgrounds. Currently, some research that employs the Fourier transform has proved to be effective for image deraining, due to it acting as an effective frequency prior for capturing rain streaks. However, despite there exists dependency of low frequency and high frequency in images, these Fourier-based methods rarely exploit the correlation of different frequencies for conjuncting their learning procedures, limiting the full utilization of frequency information for image deraining. Alternatively, the recently emerged Mamba technique depicts its effectiveness and efficiency for modeling correlation in various domains (e.g., spatial, temporal), and we argue that introducing Mamba into its unexplored Fourier spaces to correlate different frequencies would help improve image deraining. This motivates us to propose a new framework termed FourierMamba, which performs image deraining with Mamba in the Fourier space. Owning to the unique arrangement of frequency orders in Fourier space, the core of FourierMamba lies in the scanning encoding of different frequencies, where the low-high frequency order formats exhibit differently in the spatial dimension (unarranged in axis) and channel dimension (arranged in axis). Therefore, we design FourierMamba that correlates Fourier space information in the spatial and channel dimensions with distinct designs. Specifically, in the spatial dimension Fourier space, we introduce the zigzag coding to scan the frequencies to rearrange the orders from low to high frequencies, thereby orderly correlating the connections between frequencies; in the channel dimension Fourier space with arranged orders of frequencies in axis, we can directly use Mamba to perform frequency correlation and improve the channel information representation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.19450v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dong Li, Yidi Liu, Xueyang Fu, Senyan Xu, Zheng-Jun Zha</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>QClusformer: A Quantum Transformer-based Framework for Unsupervised Visual Clustering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.19722</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.19722v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Unsupervised vision clustering, a cornerstone in computer vision, has been studied for decades, yielding significant outcomes across numerous vision tasks. However, these algorithms involve substantial computational demands when confronted with vast amounts of unlabeled data. Conversely, quantum computing holds promise in expediting unsupervised algorithms when handling large-scale databases. In this study, we introduce QClusformer, a pioneering Transformer-based framework leveraging quantum machines to tackle unsupervised vision clustering challenges. Specifically, we design the Transformer architecture, including the self-attention module and transformer blocks, from a quantum perspective to enable execution on quantum hardware. In addition, we present QClusformer, a variant based on the Transformer architecture, tailored for unsupervised vision clustering tasks. By integrating these elements into an end-to-end framework, QClusformer consistently outperforms previous methods running on classical computers. Empirical evaluations across diverse benchmarks, including MS-Celeb-1M and DeepFashion, underscore the superior performance of QClusformer compared to state-of-the-art methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.19722v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xuan-Bac Nguyen, Hoang-Quan Nguyen, Samuel Yen-Chi Chen, Samee U. Khan, Hugh Churchill, Khoa Luu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bilateral Guided Radiance Field Processing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.00448</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.00448v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Neural Radiance Fields (NeRF) achieves unprecedented performance in synthesizing novel view synthesis, utilizing multi-view consistency. When capturing multiple inputs, image signal processing (ISP) in modern cameras will independently enhance them, including exposure adjustment, color correction, local tone mapping, etc. While these processings greatly improve image quality, they often break the multi-view consistency assumption, leading to "floaters" in the reconstructed radiance fields. To address this concern without compromising visual aesthetics, we aim to first disentangle the enhancement by ISP at the NeRF training stage and re-apply user-desired enhancements to the reconstructed radiance fields at the finishing stage. Furthermore, to make the re-applied enhancements consistent between novel views, we need to perform imaging signal processing in 3D space (i.e. "3D ISP"). For this goal, we adopt the bilateral grid, a locally-affine model, as a generalized representation of ISP processing. Specifically, we optimize per-view 3D bilateral grids with radiance fields to approximate the effects of camera pipelines for each input view. To achieve user-adjustable 3D finishing, we propose to learn a low-rank 4D bilateral grid from a given single view edit, lifting photo enhancements to the whole 3D scene. We demonstrate our approach can boost the visual quality of novel view synthesis by effectively removing floaters and performing enhancements from user retouching. The source code and our data are available at: https://bilarfpro.github.io.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.00448v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuehao Wang, Chaoyi Wang, Bingchen Gong, Tianfan Xue</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Classifying Dry Eye Disease Patients from Healthy Controls Using Machine Learning and Metabolomics Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.14068</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.14068v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Dry eye disease is a common disorder of the ocular surface, leading patients to seek eye care. Clinical signs and symptoms are currently used to diagnose dry eye disease. Metabolomics, a method for analyzing biological systems, has been found helpful in identifying distinct metabolites in patients and in detecting metabolic profiles that may indicate dry eye disease at early stages. In this study, we explored using machine learning and metabolomics information to identify which cataract patients suffered from dry eye disease. As there is no one-size-fits-all machine learning model for metabolomics data, choosing the most suitable model can significantly affect the quality of predictions and subsequent metabolomics analyses. To address this challenge, we conducted a comparative analysis of nine machine learning models on three metabolomics data sets from cataract patients with and without dry eye disease. The models were evaluated and optimized using nested k-fold cross-validation. To assess the performance of these models, we selected a set of suitable evaluation metrics tailored to the data set's challenges. The logistic regression model overall performed the best, achieving the highest area under the curve score of 0.8378, balanced accuracy of 0.735, Matthew's correlation coefficient of 0.5147, an F1-score of 0.8513, and a specificity of 0.5667. Additionally, following the logistic regression, the XGBoost and Random Forest models also demonstrated good performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.14068v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sajad Amouei Sheshkal, Morten Gundersen, Michael Alexander Riegler, {\O}ygunn Aass Utheim, Kjell Gunnar Gundersen, Hugo Lewi Hammer</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating and Defending Shortcut Learning in Personalized Diffusion Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.18944</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.18944v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Personalized diffusion models have gained popularity for adapting pre-trained text-to-image models to generate images of specific topics with minimal training data. However, these models are vulnerable to minor adversarial perturbations, leading to degraded performance on corrupted datasets. Such vulnerabilities are further exploited to craft protective perturbations on sensitive images like portraits that prevent unauthorized generation. In response, diffusion-based purification methods have been proposed to remove these perturbations and retain generation performance. However, existing works turn to over-purifying the images, which causes information loss. In this paper, we take a closer look at the fine-tuning process of personalized diffusion models through the lens of shortcut learning. And we propose a hypothesis explaining the manipulation mechanisms of existing perturbation methods, demonstrating that perturbed images significantly deviate from their original prompts in the CLIP-based latent space. This misalignment during fine-tuning causes models to associate noisy patterns with identifiers, resulting in performance degradation. Based on these insights, we introduce a systematic approach to maintain training performance through purification. Our method first purifies the images to realign them with their original semantic meanings in latent space. Then, we introduce contrastive learning with negative tokens to decouple the learning of clean identities from noisy patterns, which shows a strong potential capacity against adaptive perturbation. Our study uncovers shortcut learning vulnerabilities in personalized diffusion models and provides a firm evaluation framework for future protective perturbation research. Code is available at https://github.com/liuyixin-louis/DiffShortcut.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.18944v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yixin Liu, Ruoxi Chen, Lichao Sun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MobileFlow: A Multimodal LLM For Mobile GUI Agent</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.04346</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.04346v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Currently, the integration of mobile Graphical User Interfaces (GUIs) is ubiquitous in most people's daily lives. And the ongoing evolution of multimodal large-scale models, such as GPT-4v, Qwen-VL-Max, has significantly bolstered the capabilities of GUI comprehension and user action analysis, showcasing the potentiality of intelligent GUI assistants. However, current GUI Agents often need to access page layout information through calling system APIs, which may pose privacy risks. Fixing GUI (such as mobile interfaces) to a certain low resolution might result in the loss of fine-grained image details. At the same time, the multimodal large models built for GUI Agents currently have poor understanding and decision-making abilities for Chinese GUI interfaces, making them difficult to apply to a large number of Chinese apps. This paper introduces MobileFlow, a multimodal large language model meticulously crafted for mobile GUI agents. Transforming from the open-source model Qwen-VL-Chat into GUI domain, MobileFlow contains approximately 21 billion parameters and is equipped with novel hybrid visual encoders, making it possible for variable resolutions of image inputs and good support for multilingual GUI. By incorporating Mixture of Experts (MoE) expansions and pioneering alignment training strategies, MobileFlow has the capacity to fully interpret image data and comprehend user instructions for GUI interaction tasks. Finally, MobileFlow outperforms Qwen-VL-Max and GPT-4v in terms of task execution by GUI agents on both public and our proposed evaluation metrics, and has been successfully deployed in real-world business contexts, proving its effectiveness for practical applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.04346v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Songqin Nong, Jiali Zhu, Rui Wu, Jiongchao Jin, Shuo Shan, Xiutian Huang, Wenhao Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HyperKAN: Kolmogorov-Arnold Networks make Hyperspectral Image Classificators Smarter</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.05278</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.05278v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In traditional neural network architectures, a multilayer perceptron (MLP) is typically employed as a classification block following the feature extraction stage. However, the Kolmogorov-Arnold Network (KAN) presents a promising alternative to MLP, offering the potential to enhance prediction accuracy. In this paper, we propose the replacement of linear and convolutional layers of traditional networks with KAN-based counterparts. These modifications allowed us to significantly increase the per-pixel classification accuracy for hyperspectral remote-sensing images. We modified seven different neural network architectures for hyperspectral image classification and observed a substantial improvement in the classification accuracy across all the networks. The architectures considered in the paper include baseline MLP, state-of-the-art 1D (1DCNN) and 3D convolutional (two different 3DCNN, NM3DCNN), and transformer (SSFTT) architectures, as well as newly proposed M1DCNN. The greatest effect was achieved for convolutional networks working exclusively on spectral data, and the best classification quality was achieved using a KAN-based transformer architecture. All the experiments were conducted using seven openly available hyperspectral datasets. Our code is available at https://github.com/f-neumann77/HyperKAN.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.05278v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Valeriy Lobanov, Nikita Firsov, Evgeny Myasnikov, Roman Khabibullin, Artem Nikonorov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-times Monte Carlo Rendering for Inter-reflection Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.05771</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.05771v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Inverse rendering methods have achieved remarkable performance in reconstructing high-fidelity 3D objects with disentangled geometries, materials, and environmental light. However, they still face huge challenges in reflective surface reconstruction. Although recent methods model the light trace to learn specularity, the ignorance of indirect illumination makes it hard to handle inter-reflections among multiple smooth objects. In this work, we propose Ref-MC2 that introduces the multi-time Monte Carlo sampling which comprehensively computes the environmental illumination and meanwhile considers the reflective light from object surfaces. To address the computation challenge as the times of Monte Carlo sampling grow, we propose a specularity-adaptive sampling strategy, significantly reducing the computational complexity. Besides the computational resource, higher geometry accuracy is also required because geometric errors accumulate multiple times. Therefore, we further introduce a reflection-aware surface model to initialize the geometry and refine it during inverse rendering. We construct a challenging dataset containing scenes with multiple objects and inter-reflections. Experiments show that our method outperforms other inverse rendering methods on various object groups. We also show downstream applications, e.g., relighting and material editing, to illustrate the disentanglement ability of our method.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.05771v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tengjie Zhu, Zhuo Chen, Jingnan Gao, Yichao Yan, Xiaokang Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CCVA-FL: Cross-Client Variations Adaptive Federated Learning for Medical Imaging</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.11652</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.11652v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Federated Learning (FL) offers a privacy-preserving approach to train models on decentralized data. Its potential in healthcare is significant, but challenges arise due to cross-client variations in medical image data, exacerbated by limited annotations. This paper introduces Cross-Client Variations Adaptive Federated Learning (CCVA-FL) to address these issues. CCVA-FL aims to minimize cross-client variations by transforming images into a common feature space. It involves expert annotation of a subset of images from each client, followed by the selection of a client with the least data complexity as the target. Synthetic medical images are then generated using Scalable Diffusion Models with Transformers (DiT) based on the target client's annotated images. These synthetic images, capturing diversity and representing the original data, are shared with other clients. Each client then translates its local images into the target image space using image-to-image translation. The translated images are subsequently used in a federated learning setting to develop a server model. Our results demonstrate that CCVA-FL outperforms Vanilla Federated Averaging by effectively addressing data distribution differences across clients without compromising privacy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.11652v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sunny Gupta, Amit Sethi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermal Imaging and Radar for Remote Sleep Monitoring of Breathing and Apnea</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.11936</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.11936v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Polysomnography (PSG), the current gold standard method for monitoring and detecting sleep disorders, is cumbersome and costly. At-home testing solutions, known as home sleep apnea testing (HSAT), exist. However, they are contact-based, a feature which limits the ability of some patient populations to tolerate testing and discourages widespread deployment. Previous work on non-contact sleep monitoring for sleep apnea detection either estimates respiratory effort using radar or nasal airflow using a thermal camera, but has not compared the two or used them together. We conducted a study on 10 participants, ages 34 - 78, with suspected sleep disorders using a hardware setup with a synchronized radar and thermal camera. We show the first comparison of radar and thermal imaging for sleep monitoring, and find that our thermal imaging method outperforms radar significantly. Our thermal imaging method detects apneas with an accuracy of 0.99, a precision of 0.68, a recall of 0.74, an F1 score of 0.71, and an intra-class correlation of 0.70; our radar method detects apneas with an accuracy of 0.83, a precision of 0.13, a recall of 0.86, an F1 score of 0.22, and an intra-class correlation of 0.13. We also present a novel proposal for classifying obstructive and central sleep apnea by leveraging a multimodal setup. This method could be used accurately detect and classify apneas during sleep with non-contact sensors, thereby improving diagnostic capacities in patient populations unable to tolerate current technology.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.11936v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kai Del Regno, Alexander Vilesov, Adnan Armouti, Anirudh Bindiganavale Harish, Selim Emir Can, Ashley Kita, Achuta Kadambi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CLIP with Generative Latent Replay: a Strong Baseline for Incremental Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.15793</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.15793v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: With the emergence of Transformers and Vision-Language Models (VLMs) such as CLIP, large pre-trained models have become a common strategy to enhance performance in Continual Learning scenarios. This led to the development of numerous prompting strategies to effectively fine-tune transformer-based models without succumbing to catastrophic forgetting. However, these methods struggle to specialize the model on domains significantly deviating from the pre-training and preserving its zero-shot capabilities. In this work, we propose Continual Generative training for Incremental prompt-Learning, a novel approach to mitigate forgetting while adapting a VLM, which exploits generative replay to align prompts to tasks. We also introduce a new metric to evaluate zero-shot capabilities within CL benchmarks. Through extensive experiments on different domains, we demonstrate the effectiveness of our framework in adapting to new tasks while improving zero-shot capabilities. Further analysis reveals that our approach can bridge the gap with joint prompt tuning. The codebase is available at https://github.com/aimagelab/mammoth.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.15793v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Emanuele Frascaroli, Aniello Panariello, Pietro Buzzega, Lorenzo Bonicelli, Angelo Porrello, Simone Calderara</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MMInstruct: A High-Quality Multi-Modal Instruction Tuning Dataset with Extensive Diversity</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.15838</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.15838v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Despite the effectiveness of vision-language supervised fine-tuning in enhancing the performance of Vision Large Language Models (VLLMs). However, existing visual instruction tuning datasets include the following limitations: (1) Instruction annotation quality: despite existing VLLMs exhibiting strong performance, instructions generated by those advanced VLLMs may still suffer from inaccuracies, such as hallucinations. (2) Instructions and image diversity: the limited range of instruction types and the lack of diversity in image data may impact the model's ability to generate diversified and closer to real-world scenarios outputs. To address these challenges, we construct a high-quality, diverse visual instruction tuning dataset MMInstruct, which consists of 973K instructions from 24 domains. There are four instruction types: Judgement, Multiple-Choice, Long Visual Question Answering and Short Visual Question Answering. To construct MMInstruct, we propose an instruction generation data engine that leverages GPT-4V, GPT-3.5, and manual correction. Our instruction generation engine enables semi-automatic, low-cost, and multi-domain instruction generation at 1/6 the cost of manual construction. Through extensive experiment validation and ablation experiments, we demonstrate that MMInstruct could significantly improve the performance of VLLMs, e.g., the model fine-tuning on MMInstruct achieves new state-of-the-art performance on 10 out of 12 benchmarks. The code and data shall be available at https://github.com/yuecao0119/MMInstruct.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.15838v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yangzhou Liu, Yue Cao, Zhangwei Gao, Weiyun Wang, Zhe Chen, Wenhai Wang, Hao Tian, Lewei Lu, Xizhou Zhu, Tong Lu, Yu Qiao, Jifeng Dai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Text-Region Matching for Multi-Label Image Recognition with Missing Labels</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.18520</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.18520v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recently, large-scale visual language pre-trained (VLP) models have demonstrated impressive performance across various downstream tasks. Motivated by these advancements, pioneering efforts have emerged in multi-label image recognition with missing labels, leveraging VLP prompt-tuning technology. However, they usually cannot match text and vision features well, due to complicated semantics gaps and missing labels in a multi-label image. To tackle this challenge, we propose \textbf{T}ext-\textbf{R}egion \textbf{M}atching for optimizing \textbf{M}ulti-\textbf{L}abel prompt tuning, namely TRM-ML, a novel method for enhancing meaningful cross-modal matching. Compared to existing methods, we advocate exploring the information of category-aware regions rather than the entire image or pixels, which contributes to bridging the semantic gap between textual and visual representations in a one-to-one matching manner. Concurrently, we further introduce multimodal contrastive learning to narrow the semantic gap between textual and visual modalities and establish intra-class and inter-class relationships. Additionally, to deal with missing labels, we propose a multimodal category prototype that leverages intra- and inter-category semantic relationships to estimate unknown labels, facilitating pseudo-label generation. Extensive experiments on the MS-COCO, PASCAL VOC, Visual Genome, NUS-WIDE, and CUB-200-211 benchmark datasets demonstrate that our proposed framework outperforms the state-of-the-art methods by a significant margin. Our code is available here\href{https://github.com/yu-gi-oh-leilei/TRM-ML}{\raisebox{-1pt}{\faGithub}}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.18520v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3664647.3680815</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Leilei Ma, Hongxing Xie, Lei Wang, Yanping Fu, Dengdi Sun, Haifeng Zhao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisit Self-supervised Depth Estimation with Local Structure-from-Motion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.19166</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.19166v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Both self-supervised depth estimation and Structure-from-Motion (SfM) recover scene depth from RGB videos. Despite sharing a similar objective, the two approaches are disconnected. Prior works of self-supervision backpropagate losses defined within immediate neighboring frames. Instead of learning-through-loss, this work proposes an alternative scheme by performing local SfM. First, with calibrated RGB or RGB-D images, we employ a depth and correspondence estimator to infer depthmaps and pair-wise correspondence maps. Then, a novel bundle-RANSAC-adjustment algorithm jointly optimizes camera poses and one depth adjustment for each depthmap. Finally, we fix camera poses and employ a NeRF, however, without a neural network, for dense triangulation and geometric verification. Poses, depth adjustments, and triangulated sparse depths are our outputs. For the first time, we show self-supervision within $5$ frames already benefits SoTA supervised depth and correspondence models. The project page is held in the link (https://shngjz.github.io/SSfM.github.io/).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.19166v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shengjie Zhu, Xiaoming Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Tree Type Detection in Forest Fire Risk Assessment: Multi-Stage Approach and Color Encoding with Forest Fire Risk Evaluation Framework for UAV Imagery</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.19184</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.19184v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Forest fires pose a significant threat to ecosystems, economies, and human health worldwide. Early detection and assessment of forest fires are crucial for effective management and conservation efforts. Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs) equipped with advanced computer vision algorithms offer a promising solution for forest fire detection and assessment. In this paper, we optimize an integrated forest fire risk assessment framework using UAVs and multi-stage object detection algorithms. We introduce improvements to our previous framework, including the adoption of Faster R-CNN, Grid R-CNN, Sparse R-CNN, Cascade R-CNN, Dynamic R-CNN, and Libra R-CNN detectors, and explore optimizations such as CBAM for attention enhancement, random erasing for preprocessing, and different color space representations. We evaluate these enhancements through extensive experimentation using aerial image footage from various regions in British Columbia, Canada. Our findings demonstrate the effectiveness of multi-stage detectors and optimizations in improving the accuracy of forest fire risk assessment. This research contributes to the advancement of UAV-based forest fire detection and assessment systems, enhancing their efficiency and effectiveness in supporting sustainable forest management and conservation efforts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.19184v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jinda Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GP-VLS: A general-purpose vision language model for surgery</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.19305</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.19305v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Surgery requires comprehensive medical knowledge, visual assessment skills, and procedural expertise. While recent surgical AI models have focused on solving task-specific problems, there is a need for general-purpose systems that can understand surgical scenes and interact through natural language. This paper introduces GP-VLS, a general-purpose vision language model for surgery that integrates medical and surgical knowledge with visual scene understanding. For comprehensively evaluating general-purpose surgical models, we propose SurgiQual, which evaluates across medical and surgical knowledge benchmarks as well as surgical vision-language questions. To train GP-VLS, we develop six new datasets spanning medical knowledge, surgical textbooks, and vision-language pairs for tasks like phase recognition and tool identification. We show that GP-VLS significantly outperforms existing open- and closed-source models on surgical vision-language tasks, with 8-21% improvements in accuracy across SurgiQual benchmarks. GP-VLS also demonstrates strong performance on medical and surgical knowledge tests compared to open-source alternatives. Overall, GP-VLS provides an open-source foundation for developing AI assistants to support surgeons across a wide range of tasks and scenarios. The code and data for this work is publicly available at gpvls-surgery-vlm.github.io.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.19305v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>q-bio.TO</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Samuel Schmidgall, Joseph Cho, Cyril Zakka, William Hiesinger</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing Prompt Learning through an External Layer</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.19674</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.19674v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Prompt learning represents a promising method for adapting pre-trained vision-language models (VLMs) to various downstream tasks by learning a set of text embeddings. One challenge inherent to these methods is the poor generalization performance due to the invalidity of the learned text embeddings for unseen tasks. A straightforward approach to bridge this gap is to freeze the text embeddings in prompts, which results in a lack of capacity to adapt VLMs for downstream tasks. To address this dilemma, we propose a paradigm called EnPrompt with a novel External Layer (EnLa). Specifically, we propose a textual external layer and learnable visual embeddings for adapting VLMs to downstream tasks. The learnable external layer is built upon valid embeddings of pre-trained CLIP. This design considers the balance of learning capabilities between the two branches. To align the textual and visual features, we propose a novel two-pronged approach: i) we introduce the optimal transport as the discrepancy metric to align the vision and text modalities, and ii) we introduce a novel strengthening feature to enhance the interaction between these two modalities. Four representative experiments (i.e., base-to-novel generalization, few-shot learning, cross-dataset generalization, domain shifts generalization) across 15 datasets demonstrate that our method outperforms the existing prompt learning method.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.19674v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3664647.3680953</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Fangming Cui, Xun Yang, Chao Wu, Liang Xiao, Xinmei Tian</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IG-SLAM: Instant Gaussian SLAM</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.01126</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.01126v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: 3D Gaussian Splatting has recently shown promising results as an alternative scene representation in SLAM systems to neural implicit representations. However, current methods either lack dense depth maps to supervise the mapping process or detailed training designs that consider the scale of the environment. To address these drawbacks, we present IG-SLAM, a dense RGB-only SLAM system that employs robust Dense-SLAM methods for tracking and combines them with Gaussian Splatting. A 3D map of the environment is constructed using accurate pose and dense depth provided by tracking. Additionally, we utilize depth uncertainty in map optimization to improve 3D reconstruction. Our decay strategy in map optimization enhances convergence and allows the system to run at 10 fps in a single process. We demonstrate competitive performance with state-of-the-art RGB-only SLAM systems while achieving faster operation speeds. We present our experiments on the Replica, TUM-RGBD, ScanNet, and EuRoC datasets. The system achieves photo-realistic 3D reconstruction in large-scale sequences, particularly in the EuRoC dataset.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.01126v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>F. Aykut Sarikamis, A. Aydin Alatan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SynopGround: A Large-Scale Dataset for Multi-Paragraph Video Grounding from TV Dramas and Synopses</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.01669</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.01669v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Video grounding is a fundamental problem in multimodal content understanding, aiming to localize specific natural language queries in an untrimmed video. However, current video grounding datasets merely focus on simple events and are either limited to shorter videos or brief sentences, which hinders the model from evolving toward stronger multimodal understanding capabilities. To address these limitations, we present a large-scale video grounding dataset named SynopGround, in which more than 2800 hours of videos are sourced from popular TV dramas and are paired with accurately localized human-written synopses. Each paragraph in the synopsis serves as a language query and is manually annotated with precise temporal boundaries in the long video. These paragraph queries are tightly correlated to each other and contain a wealth of abstract expressions summarizing video storylines and specific descriptions portraying event details, which enables the model to learn multimodal perception on more intricate concepts over longer context dependencies. Based on the dataset, we further introduce a more complex setting of video grounding dubbed Multi-Paragraph Video Grounding (MPVG), which takes as input multiple paragraphs and a long video for grounding each paragraph query to its temporal interval. In addition, we propose a novel Local-Global Multimodal Reasoner (LGMR) to explicitly model the local-global structures of long-term multimodal inputs for MPVG. Our method provides an effective baseline solution to the multi-paragraph video grounding problem. Extensive experiments verify the proposed model's effectiveness as well as its superiority in long-term multi-paragraph video grounding over prior state-of-the-arts. Dataset and code are publicly available. Project page: https://synopground.github.io/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.01669v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chaolei Tan, Zihang Lin, Junfu Pu, Zhongang Qi, Wei-Yi Pei, Zhi Qu, Yexin Wang, Ying Shan, Wei-Shi Zheng, Jian-Fang Hu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unleashing the Power of Data Tsunami: A Comprehensive Survey on Data Assessment and Selection for Instruction Tuning of Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02085</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.02085v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Instruction tuning plays a critical role in aligning large language models (LLMs) with human preference. Despite the vast amount of open instruction datasets, naively training a LLM on all existing instructions may not be optimal and practical. To pinpoint the most beneficial datapoints, data assessment and selection methods have been proposed in the fields of natural language processing (NLP) and deep learning. However, under the context of instruction tuning, there still exists a gap in knowledge on what kind of data evaluation metrics can be employed and how they can be integrated into the selection mechanism. To bridge this gap, we present a comprehensive review on existing literature of data assessment and selection especially for instruction tuning of LLMs. We systematically categorize all applicable methods into quality-based, diversity-based, and importance-based ones where a unified, fine-grained taxonomy is structured. For each category, representative methods are elaborated to describe the landscape of relevant research. In addition, comparison between latest methods is conducted on their officially reported results to provide in-depth discussions on their limitations. Finally, we summarize the open challenges and propose the promosing avenues for future studies. All related contents are available at https://github.com/yuleiqin/fantastic-data-engineering.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.02085v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>eess.SP</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yulei Qin, Yuncheng Yang, Pengcheng Guo, Gang Li, Hang Shao, Yuchen Shi, Zihan Xu, Yun Gu, Ke Li, Xing Sun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RICA2: Rubric-Informed, Calibrated Assessment of Actions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02138</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.02138v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The ability to quantify how well an action is carried out, also known as action quality assessment (AQA), has attracted recent interest in the vision community. Unfortunately, prior methods often ignore the score rubric used by human experts and fall short of quantifying the uncertainty of the model prediction. To bridge the gap, we present RICA^2 - a deep probabilistic model that integrates score rubric and accounts for prediction uncertainty for AQA. Central to our method lies in stochastic embeddings of action steps, defined on a graph structure that encodes the score rubric. The embeddings spread probabilistic density in the latent space and allow our method to represent model uncertainty. The graph encodes the scoring criteria, based on which the quality scores can be decoded. We demonstrate that our method establishes new state of the art on public benchmarks, including FineDiving, MTL-AQA, and JIGSAWS, with superior performance in score prediction and uncertainty calibration. Our code is available at https://abrarmajeedi.github.io/rica2_aqa/</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.02138v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Abrar Majeedi, Viswanatha Reddy Gajjala, Satya Sai Srinath Namburi GNVV, Yin Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Affect Analysis: A Protocol for Ensuring Fairness and Consistency</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02164</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.02164v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Evaluating affect analysis methods presents challenges due to inconsistencies in database partitioning and evaluation protocols, leading to unfair and biased results. Previous studies claim continuous performance improvements, but our findings challenge such assertions. Using these insights, we propose a unified protocol for database partitioning that ensures fairness and comparability. We provide detailed demographic annotations (in terms of race, gender and age), evaluation metrics, and a common framework for expression recognition, action unit detection and valence-arousal estimation. We also rerun the methods with the new protocol and introduce a new leaderboards to encourage future research in affect recognition with a fairer comparison. Our annotations, code, and pre-trained models are available on \hyperlink{https://github.com/dkollias/Fair-Consistent-Affect-Analysis}{Github}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.02164v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Guanyu Hu, Dimitrios Kollias, Eleni Papadopoulou, Paraskevi Tzouveli, Jie Wei, Xinyu Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ProCreate, Don't Reproduce! Propulsive Energy Diffusion for Creative Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02226</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.02226v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this paper, we propose ProCreate, a simple and easy-to-implement method to improve sample diversity and creativity of diffusion-based image generative models and to prevent training data reproduction. ProCreate operates on a set of reference images and actively propels the generated image embedding away from the reference embeddings during the generation process. We propose FSCG-8 (Few-Shot Creative Generation 8), a few-shot creative generation dataset on eight different categories -- encompassing different concepts, styles, and settings -- in which ProCreate achieves the highest sample diversity and fidelity. Furthermore, we show that ProCreate is effective at preventing replicating training data in a large-scale evaluation using training text prompts. Code and FSCG-8 are available at https://github.com/Agentic-Learning-AI-Lab/procreate-diffusion-public. The project page is available at https://procreate-diffusion.github.io.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.02226v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jack Lu, Ryan Teehan, Mengye Ren</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pose Magic: Efficient and Temporally Consistent Human Pose Estimation with a Hybrid Mamba-GCN Network</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02922</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.02922v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Current state-of-the-art (SOTA) methods in 3D Human Pose Estimation (HPE) are primarily based on Transformers. However, existing Transformer-based 3D HPE backbones often encounter a trade-off between accuracy and computational efficiency. To resolve the above dilemma, in this work, we leverage recent advances in state space models and utilize Mamba for high-quality and efficient long-range modeling. Nonetheless, Mamba still faces challenges in precisely exploiting local dependencies between joints. To address these issues, we propose a new attention-free hybrid spatiotemporal architecture named Hybrid Mamba-GCN (Pose Magic). This architecture introduces local enhancement with GCN by capturing relationships between neighboring joints, thus producing new representations to complement Mamba's outputs. By adaptively fusing representations from Mamba and GCN, Pose Magic demonstrates superior capability in learning the underlying 3D structure. To meet the requirements of real-time inference, we also provide a fully causal version. Extensive experiments show that Pose Magic achieves new SOTA results ($\downarrow 0.9 mm$) while saving $74.1\%$ FLOPs. In addition, Pose Magic exhibits optimal motion consistency and the ability to generalize to unseen sequence lengths.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.02922v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xinyi Zhang, Qiqi Bao, Qinpeng Cui, Wenming Yang, Qingmin Liao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fingerprinting Image-to-Image Generative Adversarial Networks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2106.11760</link>
      <description>arXiv:2106.11760v5 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs) have been widely used in various application scenarios. Since the production of a commercial GAN requires substantial computational and human resources, the copyright protection of GANs is urgently needed. This paper presents a novel fingerprinting scheme for the Intellectual Property (IP) protection of image-to-image GANs based on a trusted third party. We break through the stealthiness and robustness bottlenecks suffered by previous fingerprinting methods for classification models being naively transferred to GANs. Specifically, we innovatively construct a composite deep learning model from the target GAN and a classifier. Then we generate fingerprint samples from this composite model, and embed them in the classifier for effective ownership verification. This scheme inspires some concrete methodologies to practically protect the modern image-to-image translation GANs. Theoretical analysis proves that these methods can satisfy different security requirements necessary for IP protection. We also conduct extensive experiments to show that our solutions outperform existing strategies.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2106.11760v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Guanlin Li, Guowen Xu, Han Qiu, Shangwei Guo, Run Wang, Jiwei Li, Tianwei Zhang, Rongxing Lu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Face of Populism: Examining Differences in Facial Emotional Expressions of Political Leaders Using Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2304.09914</link>
      <description>arXiv:2304.09914v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Populist rhetoric employed on online media is characterized as deeply impassioned and often imbued with strong emotions. The aim of this paper is to empirically investigate the differences in affective nonverbal communication of political leaders. We use a deep-learning approach to process a sample of 220 YouTube videos of political leaders from 15 different countries, analyze their facial expressions of emotion and then examine differences in average emotion scores representing the relative presence of 6 emotional states (anger, disgust, fear, happiness, sadness, and surprise) and a neutral expression for each frame of the YouTube video. Based on a sample of manually coded images, we find that this deep-learning approach has 53-60\% agreement with human labels. We observe statistically significant differences in the average score of negative emotions between groups of leaders with varying degrees of populist rhetoric.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2304.09914v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <category>physics.soc-ph</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sara Major, Aleksandar Toma\v{s}evi\'c</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distill Gold from Massive Ores: Bi-level Data Pruning towards Efficient Dataset Distillation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2305.18381</link>
      <description>arXiv:2305.18381v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Data-efficient learning has garnered significant attention, especially given the current trend of large multi-modal models. Recently, dataset distillation has become an effective approach by synthesizing data samples that are essential for network training. However, it remains to be explored which samples are essential for the dataset distillation process itself. In this work, we study the data efficiency and selection for the dataset distillation task. By re-formulating the dynamics of distillation, we provide insight into the inherent redundancy in the real dataset, both theoretically and empirically. We propose to use the empirical loss value as a static data pruning criterion. To further compensate for the variation of the data value in training, we find the most contributing samples based on their causal effects on the distillation. The proposed selection strategy can efficiently exploit the training dataset, outperform the previous SOTA distillation algorithms, and consistently enhance the distillation algorithms, even on much larger-scale and more heterogeneous datasets, e.g., full ImageNet-1K and Kinetics-400. We believe this paradigm will open up new avenues in the dynamics of distillation and pave the way for efficient dataset distillation. Our code is available on https://github.com/silicx/GoldFromOres-BiLP.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2305.18381v4</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yue Xu, Yong-Lu Li, Kaitong Cui, Ziyu Wang, Cewu Lu, Yu-Wing Tai, Chi-Keung Tang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LoRAPrune: Structured Pruning Meets Low-Rank Parameter-Efficient Fine-Tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2305.18403</link>
      <description>arXiv:2305.18403v5 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs), such as LLaMA and T5, have shown exceptional performance across various tasks through fine-tuning. Although low-rank adaption (LoRA) has emerged to cheaply fine-tune these LLMs on downstream tasks, their deployment is still hindered by the vast model scale and computational costs. Post-training model pruning offers a way to compress LLMs. However, the current pruning methods designed for LLMs are not compatible with LoRA. This is due to their utilization of unstructured pruning on LLMs, impeding the merging of LoRA weights, or their dependence on the gradients of pre-trained weights to guide pruning, which can impose significant memory overhead. To this end, we propose LoRAPrune, a new framework that delivers an accurate structured pruned model in a highly memory-efficient manner. Specifically, we first design a LoRA-guided pruning criterion, which uses the weights and gradients of LoRA, rather than the gradients of pre-trained weights for importance estimation. We subsequently integrate this criterion into an iterative pruning process, effectively removing redundant channels and heads. Extensive experimental results demonstrate the superior performance of our LoRAPrune over existing approaches on the LLaMA series models. At a 50\% compression rate, LoRAPrune demonstrates superior performance over LLM-Pruner, achieving a reduction in perplexity by 4.81 on WikiText2 and 3.46 on PTB, while also decreasing memory usage by 52.6%. Besides, LoRAPrune also matches semi-structural pruning across multiple LLMs, proving its wide applicability. The code is available at https://github.com/aim-uofa/LoRAPrune.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2305.18403v5</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mingyang Zhang, Hao Chen, Chunhua Shen, Zhen Yang, Linlin Ou, Xinyi Yu, Bohan Zhuang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehensive Augmentation Framework for Anomaly Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2308.15068</link>
      <description>arXiv:2308.15068v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Data augmentation methods are commonly integrated into the training of anomaly detection models. Previous approaches have primarily focused on replicating real-world anomalies or enhancing diversity, without considering that the standard of anomaly varies across different classes, potentially leading to a biased training distribution.This paper analyzes crucial traits of simulated anomalies that contribute to the training of reconstructive networks and condenses them into several methods, thus creating a comprehensive framework by selectively utilizing appropriate combinations.Furthermore, we integrate this framework with a reconstruction-based approach and concurrently propose a split training strategy that alleviates the issue of overfitting while avoiding introducing interference to the reconstruction process. The evaluations conducted on the MVTec anomaly detection dataset demonstrate that our method outperforms the previous state-of-the-art approach, particularly in terms of object classes. To evaluate generalizability, we generate a simulated dataset comprising anomalies with diverse characteristics since the original test samples only include specific types of anomalies and may lead to biased evaluations. Experimental results demonstrate that our approach exhibits promising potential for generalizing effectively to various unforeseen anomalies encountered in real-world scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2308.15068v4</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiang Lin, Yaping Yan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robustness of Deep Learning for Accelerated MRI: Benefits of Diverse Training Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.10271</link>
      <description>arXiv:2312.10271v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Deep learning based methods for image reconstruction are state-of-the-art for a variety of imaging tasks. However, neural networks often perform worse if the training data differs significantly from the data they are applied to. For example, a model trained for accelerated magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) on one scanner performs worse on another scanner. In this work, we investigate the impact of the training data on a model's performance and robustness for accelerated MRI. We find that models trained on the combination of various data distributions, such as those obtained from different MRI scanners and anatomies, exhibit robustness equal or superior to models trained on the best single distribution for a specific target distribution. Thus training on such diverse data tends to improve robustness. Furthermore, training on such a diverse dataset does not compromise in-distribution performance, i.e., a model trained on diverse data yields in-distribution performance at least as good as models trained on the more narrow individual distributions. Our results suggest that training a model for imaging on a variety of distributions tends to yield a more effective and robust model than maintaining separate models for individual distributions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2312.10271v2</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kang Lin, Reinhard Heckel</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAFE-SIM: Safety-Critical Closed-Loop Traffic Simulation with Diffusion-Controllable Adversaries</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.00391</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.00391v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Evaluating the performance of autonomous vehicle planning algorithms necessitates simulating long-tail safety-critical traffic scenarios. However, traditional methods for generating such scenarios often fall short in terms of controllability and realism; they also neglect the dynamics of agent interactions. To address these limitations, we introduce SAFE-SIM, a novel diffusion-based controllable closed-loop safety-critical simulation framework. Our approach yields two distinct advantages: 1) generating realistic long-tail safety-critical scenarios that closely reflect real-world conditions, and 2) providing controllable adversarial behavior for more comprehensive and interactive evaluations. We develop a novel approach to simulate safety-critical scenarios through an adversarial term in the denoising process of diffusion models, which allows an adversarial agent to challenge a planner with plausible maneuvers while all agents in the scene exhibit reactive and realistic behaviors. Furthermore, we propose novel guidance objectives and a partial diffusion process that enables users to control key aspects of the scenarios, such as the collision type and aggressiveness of the adversarial agent, while maintaining the realism of the behavior. We validate our framework empirically using the nuScenes and nuPlan datasets across multiple planners, demonstrating improvements in both realism and controllability. These findings affirm that diffusion models provide a robust and versatile foundation for safety-critical, interactive traffic simulation, extending their utility across the broader autonomous driving landscape. Project website: https://safe-sim.github.io/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.00391v3</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wei-Jer Chang, Francesco Pittaluga, Masayoshi Tomizuka, Wei Zhan, Manmohan Chandraker</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Job, New Gender? Measuring the Social Bias in Image Generation Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.00763</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.00763v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Image generation models can generate or edit images from a given text. Recent advancements in image generation technology, exemplified by DALL-E and Midjourney, have been groundbreaking. These advanced models, despite their impressive capabilities, are often trained on massive Internet datasets, making them susceptible to generating content that perpetuates social stereotypes and biases, which can lead to severe consequences. Prior research on assessing bias within image generation models suffers from several shortcomings, including limited accuracy, reliance on extensive human labor, and lack of comprehensive analysis. In this paper, we propose BiasPainter, a novel evaluation framework that can accurately, automatically and comprehensively trigger social bias in image generation models. BiasPainter uses a diverse range of seed images of individuals and prompts the image generation models to edit these images using gender, race, and age-neutral queries. These queries span 62 professions, 39 activities, 57 types of objects, and 70 personality traits. The framework then compares the edited images to the original seed images, focusing on the significant changes related to gender, race, and age. BiasPainter adopts a key insight that these characteristics should not be modified when subjected to neutral prompts. Built upon this design, BiasPainter can trigger the social bias and evaluate the fairness of image generation models. We use BiasPainter to evaluate six widely-used image generation models, such as stable diffusion and Midjourney. Experimental results show that BiasPainter can successfully trigger social bias in image generation models. According to our human evaluation, BiasPainter can achieve 90.8% accuracy on automatic bias detection, which is significantly higher than the results reported in previous work.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.00763v2</guid>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenxuan Wang, Haonan Bai, Jen-tse Huang, Yuxuan Wan, Youliang Yuan, Haoyi Qiu, Nanyun Peng, Michael R. Lyu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Driving Animatronic Robot Facial Expression From Speech</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.12670</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.12670v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Animatronic robots hold the promise of enabling natural human-robot interaction through lifelike facial expressions. However, generating realistic, speech-synchronized robot expressions poses significant challenges due to the complexities of facial biomechanics and the need for responsive motion synthesis. This paper introduces a novel, skinning-centric approach to drive animatronic robot facial expressions from speech input. At its core, the proposed approach employs linear blend skinning (LBS) as a unifying representation, guiding innovations in both embodiment design and motion synthesis. LBS informs the actuation topology, facilitates human expression retargeting, and enables efficient speech-driven facial motion generation. This approach demonstrates the capability to produce highly realistic facial expressions on an animatronic face in real-time at over 4000 fps on a single Nvidia RTX 4090, significantly advancing robots' ability to replicate nuanced human expressions for natural interaction. To foster further research and development in this field, the code has been made publicly available at: \url{https://github.com/library87/OpenRoboExp}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.12670v3</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Boren Li, Hang Li, Hangxin Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Detection Based on Blood Test Parameters using Various Artificial Intelligence Methods</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.02348</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.02348v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In 2019, the world faced a new challenge: a COVID-19 disease caused by the novel coronavirus, SARS-CoV-2. The virus rapidly spread across the globe, leading to a high rate of mortality, which prompted health organizations to take measures to control its transmission. Early disease detection is crucial in the treatment process, and computer-based automatic detection systems have been developed to aid in this effort. These systems often rely on artificial intelligence (AI) approaches such as machine learning, neural networks, fuzzy systems, and deep learning to classify diseases. This study aimed to differentiate COVID-19 patients from others using self-categorizing classifiers and employing various AI methods. This study used two datasets: the blood test samples and radiography images. The best results for the blood test samples obtained from San Raphael Hospital, which include two classes of individuals, those with COVID-19 and those with non-COVID diseases, were achieved through the use of the Ensemble method (a combination of a neural network and two machines learning methods). The results showed that this approach for COVID-19 diagnosis is cost-effective and provides results in a shorter amount of time than other methods. The proposed model achieved an accuracy of 94.09% on the dataset used. Secondly, the radiographic images were divided into four classes: normal, viral pneumonia, ground glass opacity, and COVID-19 infection. These were used for segmentation and classification. The lung lobes were extracted from the images and then categorized into specific classes. We achieved an accuracy of 91.1% on the image dataset. Generally, this study highlights the potential of AI in detecting and managing COVID-19 and underscores the importance of continued research and development in this field.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.02348v3</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kavian Khanjani, Seyed Rasoul Hosseini, Hamid Taheri, Shahrzad Shashaani, Mohammad Teshnehlab</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diffusion-based Human Motion Style Transfer with Semantic Guidance</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.06646</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.06646v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: 3D Human motion style transfer is a fundamental problem in computer graphic and animation processing. Existing AdaIN- based methods necessitate datasets with balanced style distribution and content/style labels to train the clustered latent space. However, we may encounter a single unseen style example in practical scenarios, but not in sufficient quantity to constitute a style cluster for AdaIN-based methods. Therefore, in this paper, we propose a novel two-stage framework for few-shot style transfer learning based on the diffusion model. Specifically, in the first stage, we pre-train a diffusion-based text-to-motion model as a generative prior so that it can cope with various content motion inputs. In the second stage, based on the single style example, we fine-tune the pre-trained diffusion model in a few-shot manner to make it capable of style transfer. The key idea is regarding the reverse process of diffusion as a motion-style translation process since the motion styles can be viewed as special motion variations. During the fine-tuning for style transfer, a simple yet effective semantic-guided style transfer loss coordinated with style example reconstruction loss is introduced to supervise the style transfer in CLIP semantic space. The qualitative and quantitative evaluations demonstrate that our method can achieve state-of-the-art performance and has practical applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.06646v2</guid>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lei Hu, Zihao Zhang, Yongjing Ye, Yiwen Xu, Shihong Xia</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cascaded Multi-path Shortcut Diffusion Model for Medical Image Translation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.12223</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.12223v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Image-to-image translation is a vital component in medical imaging processing, with many uses in a wide range of imaging modalities and clinical scenarios. Previous methods include Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs) and Diffusion Models (DMs), which offer realism but suffer from instability and lack uncertainty estimation. Even though both GAN and DM methods have individually exhibited their capability in medical image translation tasks, the potential of combining a GAN and DM to further improve translation performance and to enable uncertainty estimation remains largely unexplored. In this work, we address these challenges by proposing a Cascade Multi-path Shortcut Diffusion Model (CMDM) for high-quality medical image translation and uncertainty estimation. To reduce the required number of iterations and ensure robust performance, our method first obtains a conditional GAN-generated prior image that will be used for the efficient reverse translation with a DM in the subsequent step. Additionally, a multi-path shortcut diffusion strategy is employed to refine translation results and estimate uncertainty. A cascaded pipeline further enhances translation quality, incorporating residual averaging between cascades. We collected three different medical image datasets with two sub-tasks for each dataset to test the generalizability of our approach. Our experimental results found that CMDM can produce high-quality translations comparable to state-of-the-art methods while providing reasonable uncertainty estimations that correlate well with the translation error.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.12223v2</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yinchi Zhou, Tianqi Chen, Jun Hou, Huidong Xie, Nicha C. Dvornek, S. Kevin Zhou, David L. Wilson, James S. Duncan, Chi Liu, Bo Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SeamPose: Repurposing Seams as Capacitive Sensors in a Shirt for Upper-Body Pose Tracking</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.11645</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.11645v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Seams are areas of overlapping fabric formed by stitching two or more pieces of fabric together in the cut-and-sew apparel manufacturing process. In SeamPose, we repurposed seams as capacitive sensors in a shirt for continuous upper-body pose estimation. Compared to previous all-textile motion-capturing garments that place the electrodes on the clothing surface, our solution leverages existing seams inside of a shirt by machine-sewing insulated conductive threads over the seams. The unique invisibilities and placements of the seams afford the sensing shirt to look and wear similarly as a conventional shirt while providing exciting pose-tracking capabilities. To validate this approach, we implemented a proof-of-concept untethered shirt with 8 capacitive sensing seams. With a 12-participant user study, our customized deep-learning pipeline accurately estimates the relative (to the pelvis) upper-body 3D joint positions with a mean per joint position error (MPJPE) of 6.0 cm. SeamPose represents a step towards unobtrusive integration of smart clothing for everyday pose estimation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.11645v2</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tianhong Catherine Yu, Manru Mary Zhang, Peter He, Chi-Jung Lee, Cassidy Cheesman, Saif Mahmud, Ruidong Zhang, Fran\c{c}ois Guimbreti\`ere, Cheng Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Imperative Learning: A Self-supervised Neural-Symbolic Learning Framework for Robot Autonomy</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.16087</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.16087v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Data-driven methods such as reinforcement and imitation learning have achieved remarkable success in robot autonomy. However, their data-centric nature still hinders them from generalizing well to ever-changing environments. Moreover, collecting large datasets for robotic tasks is often impractical and expensive. To overcome these challenges, we introduce a new self-supervised neural-symbolic (NeSy) computational framework, imperative learning (IL), for robot autonomy, leveraging the generalization abilities of symbolic reasoning. The framework of IL consists of three primary components: a neural module, a reasoning engine, and a memory system. We formulate IL as a special bilevel optimization (BLO), which enables reciprocal learning over the three modules. This overcomes the label-intensive obstacles associated with data-driven approaches and takes advantage of symbolic reasoning concerning logical reasoning, physical principles, geometric analysis, etc. We discuss several optimization techniques for IL and verify their effectiveness in five distinct robot autonomy tasks including path planning, rule induction, optimal control, visual odometry, and multi-robot routing. Through various experiments, we show that IL can significantly enhance robot autonomy capabilities and we anticipate that it will catalyze further research across diverse domains.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.16087v4</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chen Wang, Kaiyi Ji, Junyi Geng, Zhongqiang Ren, Taimeng Fu, Fan Yang, Yifan Guo, Haonan He, Xiangyu Chen, Zitong Zhan, Qiwei Du, Shaoshu Su, Bowen Li, Yuheng Qiu, Yi Du, Qihang Li, Yifan Yang, Xiao Lin, Zhipeng Zhao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ESP-MedSAM: Efficient Self-Prompting SAM for Universal Image Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.14153</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.14153v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The Segment Anything Model (SAM) has demonstrated outstanding adaptation to medical image segmentation but still faces three major challenges. Firstly, the huge computational costs of SAM limit its real-world applicability. Secondly, SAM depends on manual annotations (e.g., points, boxes) as prompts, which are laborious and impractical in clinical scenarios. Thirdly, SAM handles all segmentation targets equally, which is suboptimal for diverse medical modalities with inherent heterogeneity. To address these issues, we propose an Efficient Self-Prompting SAM for universal medical image segmentation, named ESP-MedSAM. We devise a Multi-Modal Decoupled Knowledge Distillation (MMDKD) strategy to distil common image knowledge and domain-specific medical knowledge from the foundation model to train a lightweight image encoder and a modality controller. Further, they combine with the additionally introduced Self-Patch Prompt Generator (SPPG) and Query-Decoupled Modality Decoder (QDMD) to construct ESP-MedSAM. Specifically, SPPG aims to generate a set of patch prompts automatically and QDMD leverages a one-to-one strategy to provide an independent decoding channel for every modality. Extensive experiments indicate that ESP-MedSAM outperforms state-of-the-arts in diverse medical imaging segmentation takes, displaying superior zero-shot learning and modality transfer ability. Especially, our framework uses only 31.4% parameters compared to SAM-Base.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.14153v2</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qing Xu, Jiaxuan Li, Xiangjian He, Ziyu Liu, Zhen Chen, Wenting Duan, Chenxin Li, Maggie M. He, Fiseha B. Tesema, Wooi P. Cheah, Yi Wang, Rong Qu, Jonathan M. Garibaldi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Backbone for Long-Horizon Robot Task Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.01334</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.01334v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: End-to-end robot learning, particularly for long-horizon tasks, often results in unpredictable outcomes and poor generalization. To address these challenges, we propose a novel Therblig-based Backbone Framework (TBBF) to enhance robot task understanding and transferability. This framework uses therbligs (basic action elements) as the backbone to decompose high-level robot tasks into elemental robot configurations, which are then integrated with current foundation models to improve task understanding. The approach consists of two stages: offline training and online testing. During the offline training stage, we developed the Meta-RGate SynerFusion (MGSF) network for accurate therblig segmentation across various tasks. In the online testing stage, after a one-shot demonstration of a new task is collected, our MGSF network extracts high-level knowledge, which is then encoded into the image using Action Registration (ActionREG). Additionally, the Large Language Model (LLM)-Alignment Policy for Visual Correction (LAP-VC) is employed to ensure precise action execution, facilitating trajectory transfer in novel robot scenarios. Experimental results validate these methods, achieving 94.37% recall in therblig segmentation and success rates of 94.4% and 80% in real-world online robot testing for simple and complex scenarios, respectively. Supplementary material is available at: https://sites.google.com/view/therbligsbasedbackbone/home</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.01334v2</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoshuai Chen, Wei Chen, Dongmyoung Lee, Yukun Ge, Nicolas Rojas, Petar Kormushev</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contextual Cross-Modal Attention for Audio-Visual Deepfake Detection and Localization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.01532</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.01532v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In the digital age, the emergence of deepfakes and synthetic media presents a significant threat to societal and political integrity. Deepfakes based on multi-modal manipulation, such as audio-visual, are more realistic and pose a greater threat. Current multi-modal deepfake detectors are often based on the attention-based fusion of heterogeneous data streams from multiple modalities. However, the heterogeneous nature of the data (such as audio and visual signals) creates a distributional modality gap and poses a significant challenge in effective fusion and hence multi-modal deepfake detection. In this paper, we propose a novel multi-modal attention framework based on recurrent neural networks (RNNs) that leverages contextual information for audio-visual deepfake detection. The proposed approach applies attention to multi-modal multi-sequence representations and learns the contributing features among them for deepfake detection and localization. Thorough experimental validations on audio-visual deepfake datasets, namely FakeAVCeleb, AV-Deepfake1M, TVIL, and LAV-DF datasets, demonstrate the efficacy of our approach. Cross-comparison with the published studies demonstrates superior performance of our approach with an improved accuracy and precision by 3.47% and 2.05% in deepfake detection and localization, respectively. Thus, obtaining state-of-the-art performance. To facilitate reproducibility, the code and the datasets information is available at https://github.com/vcbsl/audiovisual-deepfake/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.01532v2</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Vinaya Sree Katamneni, Ajita Rattani</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EqvAfford: SE(3) Equivariance for Point-Level Affordance Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.01953</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.01953v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Humans perceive and interact with the world with the awareness of equivariance, facilitating us in manipulating different objects in diverse poses. For robotic manipulation, such equivariance also exists in many scenarios. For example, no matter what the pose of a drawer is (translation, rotation and tilt), the manipulation strategy is consistent (grasp the handle and pull in a line). While traditional models usually do not have the awareness of equivariance for robotic manipulation, which might result in more data for training and poor performance in novel object poses, we propose our EqvAfford framework, with novel designs to guarantee the equivariance in point-level affordance learning for downstream robotic manipulation, with great performance and generalization ability on representative tasks on objects in diverse poses.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.01953v2</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yue Chen, Chenrui Tie, Ruihai Wu, Hao Dong</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
