<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL</link>
    <description>cs.CL updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 05:00:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Saturday</day>
      <day>Sunday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>CoCoP: Enhancing Text Classification with LLM through Code Completion Prompt</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.08979</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.08979v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Text classification is a fundamental task in natural language processing (NLP), and large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated their capability to perform this task across various domains. However, the performance of LLMs heavily depends on the quality of their input prompts. Recent studies have also shown that LLMs exhibit remarkable results in code-related tasks. To leverage the capabilities of LLMs in text classification, we propose the Code Completion Prompt (CoCoP) method, which transforms the text classification problem into a code completion task. CoCoP significantly improves text classification performance across diverse datasets by utilizing LLMs' code-completion capability. For instance, CoCoP enhances the accuracy of the SST2 dataset by more than 20%. Moreover, when CoCoP integrated with LLMs specifically designed for code-related tasks (code models), such as CodeLLaMA, this method demonstrates better or comparable performance to few-shot learning techniques while using only one-tenth of the model size. The source code of our proposed method will be available to the public upon the acceptance of the paper.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.08979v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mohammad Mahdi Mohajeri, Mohammad Javad Dousti, Majid Nili Ahmadabadi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Code-mixed LLM: Improve Large Language Models' Capability to Handle Code-Mixing through Reinforcement Learning from AI Feedback</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09073</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09073v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Code-mixing(CM) or code-switching(CSW) refers to the juxtaposition of linguistic units from two or more languages during the conversation or sometimes even a single utterance. Code-mixing introduces unique challenges in daily life, such as syntactic mismatches and semantic blending, that are rarely encountered in monolingual settings. Large language models (LLMs) have revolutionized the field of natural language processing (NLP) by offering unprecedented capabilities in understanding human languages. However, the effectiveness of current state-of-the-art multilingual LLMs has not yet been fully explored in the CM scenario. To fill this gap, we first benchmark the performance of multilingual LLMs on various code-mixing NLP tasks. Then we propose to improve the multilingual LLMs' ability to understand code-mixing through reinforcement learning from human feedback (RLHF) and code-mixed machine translation tasks. Given the high-cost and time-consuming preference labeling procedure, we improve this by utilizing LLMs as annotators to perform the reinforcement learning from AI feedback (RLAIF). The experiments show the effectiveness of the proposed method.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09073v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenbo Zhang, Aditya Majumdar, Amulya Yadav</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personalized Help for Optimizing Low-Skilled Users' Strategy</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09109</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09109v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: AIs can beat humans in game environments; however, how helpful those agents are to human remains understudied. We augment CICERO, a natural language agent that demonstrates superhuman performance in Diplomacy, to generate both move and message advice based on player intentions. A dozen Diplomacy games with novice and experienced players, with varying advice settings, show that some of the generated advice is beneficial. It helps novices compete with experienced players and in some instances even surpass them. The mere presence of advice can be advantageous, even if players do not follow it.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09109v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Feng Gu, Wichayaporn Wongkamjan, Jordan Lee Boyd-Graber, Jonathan K. Kummerfeld, Denis Peskoff, Jonathan May</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>P-MMEval: A Parallel Multilingual Multitask Benchmark for Consistent Evaluation of LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09116</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09116v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent advancements in large language models (LLMs) showcase varied multilingual capabilities across tasks like translation, code generation, and reasoning. Previous assessments often limited their scope to fundamental natural language processing (NLP) or isolated capability-specific tasks. To alleviate this drawback, we aim to present a comprehensive multilingual multitask benchmark. First, we present a pipeline for selecting available and reasonable benchmarks from massive ones, addressing the oversight in previous work regarding the utility of these benchmarks, i.e., their ability to differentiate between models being evaluated. Leveraging this pipeline, we introduce P-MMEval, a large-scale benchmark covering effective fundamental and capability-specialized datasets. Furthermore, P-MMEval delivers consistent language coverage across various datasets and provides parallel samples. Finally, we conduct extensive experiments on representative multilingual model series to compare performances across models, analyze dataset effectiveness, examine prompt impacts on model performances, and explore the relationship between multilingual performances and factors such as tasks, model sizes, and languages. These insights offer valuable guidance for future research. The dataset is available at https://huggingface.co/datasets/Qwen/P-MMEval.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09116v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yidan Zhang, Boyi Deng, Yu Wan, Baosong Yang, Haoran Wei, Fei Huang, Bowen Yu, Junyang Lin, Fei Huang, Jingren Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DROJ: A Prompt-Driven Attack against Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09125</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09125v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated exceptional capabilities across various natural language processing tasks. Due to their training on internet-sourced datasets, LLMs can sometimes generate objectionable content, necessitating extensive alignment with human feedback to avoid such outputs. Despite massive alignment efforts, LLMs remain susceptible to adversarial jailbreak attacks, which usually are manipulated prompts designed to circumvent safety mechanisms and elicit harmful responses. Here, we introduce a novel approach, Directed Rrepresentation Optimization Jailbreak (DROJ), which optimizes jailbreak prompts at the embedding level to shift the hidden representations of harmful queries towards directions that are more likely to elicit affirmative responses from the model. Our evaluations on LLaMA-2-7b-chat model show that DROJ achieves a 100\% keyword-based Attack Success Rate (ASR), effectively preventing direct refusals. However, the model occasionally produces repetitive and non-informative responses. To mitigate this, we introduce a helpfulness system prompt that enhances the utility of the model's responses. Our code is available at https://github.com/Leon-Leyang/LLM-Safeguard.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09125v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Leyang Hu, Boran Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unstructured Text Enhanced Open-domain Dialogue System: A Systematic Survey</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09166</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09166v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Incorporating external knowledge into dialogue generation has been proven to benefit the performance of an open-domain Dialogue System (DS), such as generating informative or stylized responses, controlling conversation topics. In this article, we study the open-domain DS that uses unstructured text as external knowledge sources (\textbf{U}nstructured \textbf{T}ext \textbf{E}nhanced \textbf{D}ialogue \textbf{S}ystem, \textbf{UTEDS}). The existence of unstructured text entails distinctions between UTEDS and traditional data-driven DS and we aim to analyze these differences. We first give the definition of the UTEDS related concepts, then summarize the recently released datasets and models. We categorize UTEDS into Retrieval and Generative models and introduce them from the perspective of model components. The retrieval models consist of Fusion, Matching, and Ranking modules, while the generative models comprise Dialogue and Knowledge Encoding, Knowledge Selection, and Response Generation modules. We further summarize the evaluation methods utilized in UTEDS and analyze the current models' performance. At last, we discuss the future development trends of UTEDS, hoping to inspire new research in this field.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09166v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3464377</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>ACM Transactions on Information Systems 40(1): 9:1-9:44 (2022)</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Longxuan Ma, Mingda Li, Weinan Zhang, Jiapeng Li, Ting Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive and Practical Evaluation of Retrieval-Augmented Generation Systems for Medical Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09213</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09213v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) has emerged as a promising approach to enhance the performance of large language models (LLMs) in knowledge-intensive tasks such as those from medical domain. However, the sensitive nature of the medical domain necessitates a completely accurate and trustworthy system. While existing RAG benchmarks primarily focus on the standard retrieve-answer setting, they overlook many practical scenarios that measure crucial aspects of a reliable medical system. This paper addresses this gap by providing a comprehensive evaluation framework for medical question-answering (QA) systems in a RAG setting for these situations, including sufficiency, integration, and robustness. We introduce Medical Retrieval-Augmented Generation Benchmark (MedRGB) that provides various supplementary elements to four medical QA datasets for testing LLMs' ability to handle these specific scenarios. Utilizing MedRGB, we conduct extensive evaluations of both state-of-the-art commercial LLMs and open-source models across multiple retrieval conditions. Our experimental results reveals current models' limited ability to handle noise and misinformation in the retrieved documents. We further analyze the LLMs' reasoning processes to provides valuable insights and future directions for developing RAG systems in this critical medical domain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09213v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nghia Trung Ngo, Chien Van Nguyen, Franck Dernoncourt, Thien Huu Nguyen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HateGPT: Unleashing GPT-3.5 Turbo to Combat Hate Speech on X</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09214</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09214v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The widespread use of social media platforms like Twitter and Facebook has enabled people of all ages to share their thoughts and experiences, leading to an immense accumulation of user-generated content. However, alongside the benefits, these platforms also face the challenge of managing hate speech and offensive content, which can undermine rational discourse and threaten democratic values. As a result, there is a growing need for automated methods to detect and mitigate such content, especially given the complexity of conversations that may require contextual analysis across multiple languages, including code-mixed languages like Hinglish, German-English, and Bangla. We participated in the English task where we have to classify English tweets into two categories namely Hate and Offensive and Non Hate-Offensive. In this work, we experiment with state-of-the-art large language models like GPT-3.5 Turbo via prompting to classify tweets into Hate and Offensive or Non Hate-Offensive. In this study, we evaluate the performance of a classification model using Macro-F1 scores across three distinct runs. The Macro-F1 score, which balances precision and recall across all classes, is used as the primary metric for model evaluation. The scores obtained are 0.756 for run 1, 0.751 for run 2, and 0.754 for run 3, indicating a high level of performance with minimal variance among the runs. The results suggest that the model consistently performs well in terms of precision and recall, with run 1 showing the highest performance. These findings highlight the robustness and reliability of the model across different runs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09214v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aniket Deroy, Subhankar Maity</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Financial Domain Adaptation of Language Models via Model Augmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09249</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09249v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The domain adaptation of language models, including large language models (LLMs), has become increasingly important as the use of such models continues to expand. This study demonstrates the effectiveness of Composition to Augment Language Models (CALM) in adapting to the financial domain. CALM is a model to extend the capabilities of existing models by introducing cross-attention between two LLMs with different functions. In our experiments, we developed a CALM to enhance the financial performance of an LLM with strong response capabilities by leveraging a financial-specialized LLM. Notably, the CALM was trained using a financial dataset different from the one used to train the financial-specialized LLM, confirming CALM's ability to adapt to various datasets. The models were evaluated through quantitative Japanese financial benchmarks and qualitative response comparisons, demonstrating that CALM enables superior responses with higher scores than the original models and baselines. Additionally, comparative experiments on connection points revealed that connecting the middle layers of the models is most effective in facilitating adaptation to the financial domain. These findings confirm that CALM is a practical approach for adapting LLMs to the financial domain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09249v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kota Tanabe, Masanori Hirano, Kazuki Matoya, Kentaro Imajo, Hiroki Sakaji, Itsuki Noda</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DAHL: Domain-specific Automated Hallucination Evaluation of Long-Form Text through a Benchmark Dataset in Biomedicine</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09255</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09255v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We introduce DAHL, a benchmark dataset and automated evaluation system designed to assess hallucination in long-form text generation, specifically within the biomedical domain. Our benchmark dataset, meticulously curated from biomedical research papers, consists of 8,573 questions across 29 categories. DAHL evaluates fact-conflicting hallucinations in Large Language Models (LLMs) by deconstructing responses into atomic units, each representing a single piece of information. The accuracy of these responses is averaged to produce the DAHL Score, offering a more in-depth evaluation of hallucinations compared to previous methods that rely on multiple-choice tasks. We conduct experiments with 8 different models, finding that larger models tend to hallucinate less; however, beyond a model size of 7 to 8 billion parameters, further scaling does not significantly improve factual accuracy. The DAHL Score holds potential as an efficient alternative to human-annotated preference labels, being able to be expanded to other specialized domains. We release the dataset and code in public.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09255v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jean Seo, Jongwon Lim, Dongjun Jang, Hyopil Shin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cross-Modal Consistency in Multimodal Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09273</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09273v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent developments in multimodal methodologies have marked the beginning of an exciting era for models adept at processing diverse data types, encompassing text, audio, and visual content. Models like GPT-4V, which merge computer vision with advanced language processing, exhibit extraordinary proficiency in handling intricate tasks that require a simultaneous understanding of both textual and visual information. Prior research efforts have meticulously evaluated the efficacy of these Vision Large Language Models (VLLMs) in various domains, including object detection, image captioning, and other related fields. However, existing analyses have often suffered from limitations, primarily centering on the isolated evaluation of each modality's performance while neglecting to explore their intricate cross-modal interactions. Specifically, the question of whether these models achieve the same level of accuracy when confronted with identical task instances across different modalities remains unanswered. In this study, we take the initiative to delve into the interaction and comparison among these modalities of interest by introducing a novel concept termed cross-modal consistency. Furthermore, we propose a quantitative evaluation framework founded on this concept. Our experimental findings, drawn from a curated collection of parallel vision-language datasets developed by us, unveil a pronounced inconsistency between the vision and language modalities within GPT-4V, despite its portrayal as a unified multimodal model. Our research yields insights into the appropriate utilization of such models and hints at potential avenues for enhancing their design.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09273v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiang Zhang, Senyu Li, Ning Shi, Bradley Hauer, Zijun Wu, Grzegorz Kondrak, Muhammad Abdul-Mageed, Laks V. S. Lakshmanan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>StreamAdapter: Efficient Test Time Adaptation from Contextual Streams</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09289</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09289v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In-context learning (ICL) allows large language models (LLMs) to adapt to new tasks directly from the given demonstrations without requiring gradient updates. While recent advances have expanded context windows to accommodate more demonstrations, this approach increases inference costs without necessarily improving performance. To mitigate these issues, We propose StreamAdapter, a novel approach that directly updates model parameters from context at test time, eliminating the need for explicit in-context demonstrations. StreamAdapter employs context mapping and weight absorption mechanisms to dynamically transform ICL demonstrations into parameter updates with minimal additional parameters. By reducing reliance on numerous in-context examples, StreamAdapter significantly reduce inference costs and allows for efficient inference with constant time complexity, regardless of demonstration count. Extensive experiments across diverse tasks and model architectures demonstrate that StreamAdapter achieves comparable or superior adaptation capability to ICL while requiring significantly fewer demonstrations. The superior task adaptation and context encoding capabilities of StreamAdapter on both language understanding and generation tasks provides a new perspective for adapting LLMs at test time using context, allowing for more efficient adaptation across scenarios and more cost-effective inference</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09289v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dilxat Muhtar, Yelong Shen, Yaming Yang, Xiaodong Liu, Yadong Lu, Jianfeng Liu, Yuefeng Zhan, Hao Sun, Weiwei Deng, Feng Sun, Xueliang Zhang, Jianfeng Gao, Weizhu Chen, Qi Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DTELS: Towards Dynamic Granularity of Timeline Summarization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09297</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09297v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The rapid proliferation of online news has posed significant challenges in tracking the continuous development of news topics. Traditional timeline summarization constructs a chronological summary of the events but often lacks the flexibility to meet the diverse granularity needs. To overcome this limitation, we introduce a new paradigm, Dynamic-granularity TimELine Summarization, (DTELS), which aims to construct adaptive timelines based on user instructions or requirements. This paper establishes a comprehensive benchmark for DTLES that includes: (1) an evaluation framework grounded in journalistic standards to assess the timeline quality across four dimensions: Informativeness, Granular Consistency, Factuality, and Coherence; (2) a large-scale, multi-source dataset with multiple granularity timeline annotations based on a consensus process to facilitate authority; (3) extensive experiments and analysis with two proposed solutions based on Large Language Models (LLMs) and existing state-of-the-art TLS methods. The experimental results demonstrate the effectiveness of LLM-based solutions. However, even the most advanced LLMs struggle to consistently generate timelines that are both informative and granularly consistent, highlighting the challenges of the DTELS task.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09297v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chenlong Zhang, Tong Zhou, Pengfei Cao, Zhuoran Jin, Yubo Chen, Kang Liu, Jun Zhao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DriveThru: a Document Extraction Platform and Benchmark Datasets for Indonesian Local Language Archives</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09318</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09318v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Indonesia is one of the most diverse countries linguistically. However, despite this linguistic diversity, Indonesian languages remain underrepresented in Natural Language Processing (NLP) research and technologies. In the past two years, several efforts have been conducted to construct NLP resources for Indonesian languages. However, most of these efforts have been focused on creating manual resources thus difficult to scale to more languages. Although many Indonesian languages do not have a web presence, locally there are resources that document these languages well in printed forms such as books, magazines, and newspapers. Digitizing these existing resources will enable scaling of Indonesian language resource construction to many more languages. In this paper, we propose an alternative method of creating datasets by digitizing documents, which have not previously been used to build digital language resources in Indonesia. DriveThru is a platform for extracting document content utilizing Optical Character Recognition (OCR) techniques in its system to provide language resource building with less manual effort and cost. This paper also studies the utility of current state-of-the-art LLM for post-OCR correction to show the capability of increasing the character accuracy rate (CAR) and word accuracy rate (WAR) compared to off-the-shelf OCR.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09318v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>MohammadRifqi Farhansyah, Muhammad Zuhdi Fikri Johari, Afinzaki Amiral, Ayu Purwarianti, Kumara Ari Yuana, Derry Tanti Wijaya</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everyone deserves their voice to be heard: Analyzing Predictive Gender Bias in ASR Models Applied to Dutch Speech Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09431</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09431v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent research has shown that state-of-the-art (SotA) Automatic Speech Recognition (ASR) systems, such as Whisper, often exhibit predictive biases that disproportionately affect various demographic groups. This study focuses on identifying the performance disparities of Whisper models on Dutch speech data from the Common Voice dataset and the Dutch National Public Broadcasting organisation. We analyzed the word error rate, character error rate and a BERT-based semantic similarity across gender groups. We used the moral framework of Weerts et al. (2022) to assess quality of service harms and fairness, and to provide a nuanced discussion on the implications of these biases, particularly for automatic subtitling. Our findings reveal substantial disparities in word error rate (WER) among gender groups across all model sizes, with bias identified through statistical testing.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09431v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rik Raes, Saskia Lensink, Mykola Pechenizkiy</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MM-Eval: A Hierarchical Benchmark for Modern Mongolian Evaluation in LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09492</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09492v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) excel in high-resource languages but face notable challenges in low-resource languages like Mongolian. This paper addresses these challenges by categorizing capabilities into language abilities (syntax and semantics) and cognitive abilities (knowledge and reasoning). To systematically evaluate these areas, we developed MM-Eval, a specialized dataset based on Modern Mongolian Language Textbook I and enriched with WebQSP and MGSM datasets.
  Preliminary experiments on models including Qwen2-7B-Instruct, GLM4-9b-chat, Llama3.1-8B-Instruct, GPT-4, and DeepseekV2.5 revealed that: 1) all models performed better on syntactic tasks than semantic tasks, highlighting a gap in deeper language understanding; and 2) knowledge tasks showed a moderate decline, suggesting that models can transfer general knowledge from high-resource to low-resource contexts.
  The release of MM-Eval, comprising 569 syntax, 677 semantics, 344 knowledge, and 250 reasoning tasks, offers valuable insights for advancing NLP and LLMs in low-resource languages like Mongolian. The dataset is available at https://github.com/joenahm/MM-Eval.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09492v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mengyuan Zhang, Ruihui Wang, Bo Xia, Yuan Sun, Xiaobing Zhao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Use of Readability Metrics in Legal Text: A Systematic Literature Review</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09497</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09497v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Understanding the text in legal documents can be challenging due to their complex structure and the inclusion of domain-specific jargon. Laws and regulations are often crafted in such a manner that engagement with them requires formal training, potentially leading to vastly different interpretations of the same texts. Linguistic complexity is an important contributor to the difficulties experienced by readers. Simplifying texts could enhance comprehension across a broader audience, not just among trained professionals. Various metrics have been developed to measure document readability. Therefore, we adopted a systematic review approach to examine the linguistic and readability metrics currently employed for legal and regulatory texts. A total of 3566 initial papers were screened, with 34 relevant studies found and further assessed. Our primary objective was to identify which current metrics were applied for evaluating readability within the legal field. Sixteen different metrics were identified, with the Flesch-Kincaid Grade Level being the most frequently used method. The majority of studies (73.5%) were found in the domain of "informed consent forms". From the analysis, it is clear that not all legal domains are well represented in terms of readability metrics and that there is a further need to develop more consensus on which metrics should be applied for legal documents.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09497v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yu Han, Aaron Ceross, Jeroen H. M. Bergmann</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Practical Guide to Fine-tuning Language Models with Limited Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09539</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09539v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Employing pre-trained Large Language Models (LLMs) has become the de facto standard in Natural Language Processing (NLP) despite their extensive data requirements. Motivated by the recent surge in research focused on training LLMs with limited data, particularly in low-resource domains and languages, this paper surveys recent transfer learning approaches to optimize model performance in downstream tasks where data is scarce. We first address initial and continued pre-training strategies to better leverage prior knowledge in unseen domains and languages. We then examine how to maximize the utility of limited data during fine-tuning and few-shot learning. The final section takes a task-specific perspective, reviewing models and methods suited for different levels of data scarcity. Our goal is to provide practitioners with practical guidelines for overcoming the challenges posed by constrained data while also highlighting promising directions for future research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09539v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>M\'arton Sz\'ep, Daniel Rueckert, R\"udiger von Eisenhart-Rothe, Florian Hinterwimmer</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Piecing It All Together: Verifying Multi-Hop Multimodal Claims</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09547</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09547v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Existing claim verification datasets often do not require systems to perform complex reasoning or effectively interpret multimodal evidence. To address this, we introduce a new task: multi-hop multimodal claim verification. This task challenges models to reason over multiple pieces of evidence from diverse sources, including text, images, and tables, and determine whether the combined multimodal evidence supports or refutes a given claim. To study this task, we construct MMCV, a large-scale dataset comprising 16k multi-hop claims paired with multimodal evidence, generated and refined using large language models, with additional input from human feedback. We show that MMCV is challenging even for the latest state-of-the-art multimodal large language models, especially as the number of reasoning hops increases. Additionally, we establish a human performance benchmark on a subset of MMCV. We hope this dataset and its evaluation task will encourage future research in multimodal multi-hop claim verification.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09547v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haoran Wang, Aman Rangapur, Xiongxiao Xu, Yueqing Liang, Haroon Gharwi, Carl Yang, Kai Shu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BabyLM Challenge: Exploring the Effect of Variation Sets on Language Model Training Efficiency</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09587</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09587v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: While current large language models have achieved a remarkable success, their data efficiency remains a challenge to overcome. Recently it has been suggested that child-directed speech (CDS) can improve training data efficiency of modern language models based on Transformer neural networks. However, it is not yet understood which specific properties of CDS are effective for training these models. In the context of the BabyLM Challenge, we focus on Variation Sets (VSs), sets of consecutive utterances expressing a similar intent with slightly different words and structures, which are ubiquitous in CDS. To assess the impact of VSs on training data efficiency, we augment CDS data with different proportions of artificial VSs and use these datasets to train an auto-regressive model, GPT-2. We find that the best proportion of VSs depends on the evaluation benchmark: BLiMP and GLUE scores benefit from the presence of VSs, but EWOK scores do not. Additionally, the results vary depending on multiple factors such as the number of epochs and the order of utterance presentation. Taken together, these findings suggest that VSs can have a beneficial influence on language models, while leaving room for further investigation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09587v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Akari Haga, Akiyo Fukatsu, Miyu Oba, Arianna Bisazza, Yohei Oseki</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Moral Foundations Weibo Corpus</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09612</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09612v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Moral sentiments expressed in natural language significantly influence both online and offline environments, shaping behavioral styles and interaction patterns, including social media selfpresentation, cyberbullying, adherence to social norms, and ethical decision-making. To effectively measure moral sentiments in natural language processing texts, it is crucial to utilize large, annotated datasets that provide nuanced understanding for accurate analysis and modeltraining. However, existing corpora, while valuable, often face linguistic limitations. To address this gap in the Chinese language domain,we introduce the Moral Foundation Weibo Corpus. This corpus consists of 25,671 Chinese comments on Weibo, encompassing six diverse topic areas. Each comment is manually annotated by at least three systematically trained annotators based on ten moral categories derived from a grounded theory of morality. To assess annotator reliability, we present the kappa testresults, a gold standard for measuring consistency. Additionally, we apply several the latest large language models to supplement the manual annotations, conducting analytical experiments to compare their performance and report baseline results for moral sentiment classification.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09612v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Renjie Cao, Miaoyan Hu, Jiahan Wei, Baha Ihnaini</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PTR: Precision-Driven Tool Recommendation for Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09613</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09613v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: By augmenting Large Language Models (LLMs) with external tools, their capacity to solve complex problems has been significantly enhanced. However, despite ongoing advancements in the parsing capabilities of LLMs, incorporating all available tools simultaneously in the prompt remains impractical due to the vast number of external tools. Consequently, it is essential to provide LLMs with a precise set of tools tailored to the specific task, considering both quantity and quality. Current tool retrieval methods primarily focus on refining the ranking list of tools and directly packaging a fixed number of top-ranked tools as the tool set. However, these approaches often fail to equip LLMs with the optimal set of tools prior to execution, since the optimal number of tools for different tasks could be different, resulting in inefficiencies such as redundant or unsuitable tools, which impede immediate access to the most relevant tools. This paper addresses the challenge of recommending precise toolsets for LLMs. We introduce the problem of tool recommendation, define its scope, and propose a novel Precision-driven Tool Recommendation (PTR) approach. PTR captures an initial, concise set of tools by leveraging historical tool bundle usage and dynamically adjusts the tool set by performing tool matching, culminating in a multi-view-based tool addition. Additionally, we present a new dataset, RecTools, and a metric, TRACC, designed to evaluate the effectiveness of tool recommendation for LLMs. We further validate our design choices through comprehensive experiments, demonstrating promising accuracy across two open benchmarks and our RecTools dataset.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09613v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hang Gao, Yongfeng Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive Decoding via Latent Preference Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09661</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09661v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: During language model decoding, it is known that using higher temperature sampling gives more creative responses, while lower temperatures are more factually accurate. However, such models are commonly applied to general instruction following, which involves both creative and fact seeking tasks, using a single fixed temperature across all examples and tokens. In this work, we introduce Adaptive Decoding, a layer added to the model to select the sampling temperature dynamically at inference time, at either the token or example level, in order to optimize performance. To learn its parameters we introduce Latent Preference Optimization (LPO) a general approach to train discrete latent variables such as choices of temperature. Our method outperforms all fixed decoding temperatures across a range of tasks that require different temperatures, including UltraFeedback, Creative Story Writing, and GSM8K.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09661v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shehzaad Dhuliawala, Ilia Kulikov, Ping Yu, Asli Celikyilmaz, Jason Weston, Sainbayar Sukhbaatar, Jack Lanchantin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Squeezed Attention: Accelerating Long Context Length LLM Inference</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09688</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09688v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Emerging Large Language Model (LLM) applications require long input prompts to perform complex downstream tasks like document analysis and code generation. For these long context length applications, the length of the input prompt poses a significant challenge in terms of inference efficiency since the inference costs increase linearly with sequence length. However, for many of these applications, much of the context in the prompt is fixed across different user inputs, thereby providing the opportunity to perform offline optimizations to process user inputs quickly, as they are received. In this work, we propose Squeezed Attention as a mechanism to accelerate LLM applications where a large portion of the input prompt is fixed. We first leverage K-means clustering offline to group the keys for the fixed context based on semantic similarity and represent each cluster with a single centroid value. During inference, we compare query tokens from the user input with the centroids to predict which of the keys from the fixed context are semantically relevant and need to be loaded during inference. We then compute exact attention using only these important keys from the fixed context, thereby reducing bandwidth and computational costs. We also extend our method to use a hierarchical centroid lookup to identify important keys, which can reduce the complexity of attention from linear to logarithmic with respect to the context length. We implement optimized Triton kernels for centroid comparison and sparse FlashAttention with important keys, achieving more than 4x speedups during both the prefill and generation phases for long-context inference. Furthermore, we have extensively evaluated our method on various long-context benchmarks including LongBench, where it achieves a 3x reduction in KV cache budget without accuracy loss and up to an 8x reduction with &lt;0.5 point accuracy gap for various models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09688v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Coleman Hooper, Sehoon Kim, Hiva Mohammadzadeh, Monishwaran Maheswaran, June Paik, Michael W. Mahoney, Kurt Keutzer, Amir Gholami</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Bayesian Optimization Approach to Machine Translation Reranking</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09694</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09694v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Reranking a list of candidates from a machine translation system with an external scoring model and returning the highest-scoring candidate remains a simple and effective method for improving the overall output quality. Translation scoring models continue to grow in size, with the best models being comparable to generation models. Thus, reranking can add substantial computational cost to the translation pipeline. In this work, we pose reranking as a Bayesian optimization (BayesOpt) problem. By strategically selecting candidates to score based on a balance of exploration and exploitation, we show that it is possible to find top-scoring candidates when scoring only a fraction of the candidate list. For instance, our method achieves the same CometKiwi score using only 70 scoring evaluations compared a baseline system using 180. We present a multi-fidelity setting for BayesOpt, where the candidates are first scored with a cheaper but noisier proxy scoring model, which further improves the cost-performance tradeoff when using smaller but well-trained distilled proxy scorers.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09694v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Julius Cheng, Maike Z\"ufle, Vil\'em Zouhar, Andreas Vlachos</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying Risk Propensities of Large Language Models: Ethical Focus and Bias Detection through Role-Play</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.08884</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.08884v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: As Large Language Models (LLMs) become more prevalent, concerns about their safety, ethics, and potential biases have risen. Systematically evaluating LLMs' risk decision-making tendencies and attitudes, particularly in the ethical domain, has become crucial. This study innovatively applies the Domain-Specific Risk-Taking (DOSPERT) scale from cognitive science to LLMs and proposes a novel Ethical Decision-Making Risk Attitude Scale (EDRAS) to assess LLMs' ethical risk attitudes in depth. We further propose a novel approach integrating risk scales and role-playing to quantitatively evaluate systematic biases in LLMs. Through systematic evaluation and analysis of multiple mainstream LLMs, we assessed the "risk personalities" of LLMs across multiple domains, with a particular focus on the ethical domain, and revealed and quantified LLMs' systematic biases towards different groups. This research helps understand LLMs' risk decision-making and ensure their safe and reliable application. Our approach provides a tool for identifying and mitigating biases, contributing to fairer and more trustworthy AI systems. The code and data are available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.08884v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yifan Zeng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sparse Upcycling: Inference Inefficient Finetuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.08968</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.08968v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Small, highly trained, open-source large language models are widely used due to their inference efficiency, but further improving their quality remains a challenge. Sparse upcycling is a promising approach that transforms a pretrained dense model into a Mixture-of-Experts (MoE) architecture, increasing the model's parameter count and quality. In this work, we compare the effectiveness of sparse upcycling against continued pretraining (CPT) across different model sizes, compute budgets, and pretraining durations. Our experiments show that sparse upcycling can achieve better quality, with improvements of over 20% relative to CPT in certain scenarios. However, this comes with a significant inference cost, leading to 40% slowdowns in high-demand inference settings for larger models. Our findings highlight the trade-off between model quality and inference efficiency, offering insights for practitioners seeking to balance model quality and deployment constraints.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.08968v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sasha Doubov, Nikhil Sardana, Vitaliy Chiley</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Refusal in LLMs is an Affine Function</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09003</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09003v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We propose affine concept editing (ACE) as an approach for steering language models' behavior by intervening directly in activations. We begin with an affine decomposition of model activation vectors and show that prior methods for steering model behavior correspond to subsets of terms of this decomposition. We then provide a derivation of ACE and test it on refusal using Llama 3 8B and Hermes Eagle RWKV v5. ACE ultimately combines affine subspace projection and activation addition to reliably control the model's refusal responses across prompt types. We evaluate the results using LLM-based scoring on a collection of harmful and harmless prompts. Our experiments demonstrate that ACE consistently achieves more precise control over model behavior and generalizes to models where directional ablation via affine subspace projection alone produces incoherent outputs. Code for reproducing our results is available at https://github.com/EleutherAI/steering-llama3 .</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09003v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Thomas Marshall, Adam Scherlis, Nora Belrose</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cut Your Losses in Large-Vocabulary Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09009</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09009v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: As language models grow ever larger, so do their vocabularies. This has shifted the memory footprint of LLMs during training disproportionately to one single layer: the cross-entropy in the loss computation. Cross-entropy builds up a logit matrix with entries for each pair of input tokens and vocabulary items and, for small models, consumes an order of magnitude more memory than the rest of the LLM combined. We propose Cut Cross-Entropy (CCE), a method that computes the cross-entropy loss without materializing the logits for all tokens into global memory. Rather, CCE only computes the logit for the correct token and evaluates the log-sum-exp over all logits on the fly. We implement a custom kernel that performs the matrix multiplications and the log-sum-exp reduction over the vocabulary in flash memory, making global memory consumption for the cross-entropy computation negligible. This has a dramatic effect. Taking the Gemma 2 (2B) model as an example, CCE reduces the memory footprint of the loss computation from 24 GB to 1 MB, and the total training-time memory consumption of the classifier head from 28 GB to 1 GB. To improve the throughput of CCE, we leverage the inherent sparsity of softmax and propose to skip elements of the gradient computation that have a negligible (i.e., below numerical precision) contribution to the gradient. Experiments demonstrate that the dramatic reduction in memory consumption is accomplished without sacrificing training speed or convergence.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09009v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Erik Wijmans, Brody Huval, Alexander Hertzberg, Vladlen Koltun, Philipp Kr\"ahenb\"uhl</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the Visual Gap: Fine-Tuning Multimodal Models with Knowledge-Adapted Captions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09018</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09018v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recent research increasingly focuses on training vision-language models (VLMs) with long, detailed image captions. However, small-scale VLMs often struggle to balance the richness of these captions with the risk of hallucinating content during fine-tuning. In this paper, we explore how well VLMs adapt to such captions. To quantify caption quality, we propose Decomposed NLI (DNLI), an evaluation framework that breaks down generated captions into individual propositions, assessing each in isolation. This fine-grained analysis reveals a critical balance between capturing descriptive details and preventing hallucinations. Our findings show that simply reducing caption complexity or employing standard data curation techniques does not effectively resolve this issue. To tackle this challenge, we introduce Knowledge Adapted (KnowAda) fine-tuning, a data-centric approach that automatically adapts training data with the model's existing knowledge and visual understanding. KnowAda minimizes hallucinations while preserving high descriptiveness. We validate this approach across several small-scale VLMs (up to 7B parameters) and dense caption datasets, demonstrating that KnowAda effectively balances hallucination reduction and descriptiveness. Our results show that KnowAda outperforms various baselines in both automatic metrics and human evaluations. We will release our code and models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09018v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Moran Yanuka, Assaf Ben Kish, Yonatan Bitton, Idan Szpektor, Raja Giryes</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jailbreak Attacks and Defenses against Multimodal Generative Models: A Survey</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09259</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09259v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The rapid evolution of multimodal foundation models has led to significant advancements in cross-modal understanding and generation across diverse modalities, including text, images, audio, and video. However, these models remain susceptible to jailbreak attacks, which can bypass built-in safety mechanisms and induce the production of potentially harmful content. Consequently, understanding the methods of jailbreak attacks and existing defense mechanisms is essential to ensure the safe deployment of multimodal generative models in real-world scenarios, particularly in security-sensitive applications. To provide comprehensive insight into this topic, this survey reviews jailbreak and defense in multimodal generative models. First, given the generalized lifecycle of multimodal jailbreak, we systematically explore attacks and corresponding defense strategies across four levels: input, encoder, generator, and output. Based on this analysis, we present a detailed taxonomy of attack methods, defense mechanisms, and evaluation frameworks specific to multimodal generative models. Additionally, we cover a wide range of input-output configurations, including modalities such as Any-to-Text, Any-to-Vision, and Any-to-Any within generative systems. Finally, we highlight current research challenges and propose potential directions for future research.The open-source repository corresponding to this work can be found at https://github.com/liuxuannan/Awesome-Multimodal-Jailbreak.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09259v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xuannan Liu, Xing Cui, Peipei Li, Zekun Li, Huaibo Huang, Shuhan Xia, Miaoxuan Zhang, Yueying Zou, Ran He</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Re-Parameterization of Lightweight Transformer for On-Device Speech Emotion Recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09339</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09339v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: With the increasing implementation of machine learning models on edge or Internet-of-Things (IoT) devices, deploying advanced models on resource-constrained IoT devices remains challenging. Transformer models, a currently dominant neural architecture, have achieved great success in broad domains but their complexity hinders its deployment on IoT devices with limited computation capability and storage size. Although many model compression approaches have been explored, they often suffer from notorious performance degradation. To address this issue, we introduce a new method, namely Transformer Re-parameterization, to boost the performance of lightweight Transformer models. It consists of two processes: the High-Rank Factorization (HRF) process in the training stage and the deHigh-Rank Factorization (deHRF) process in the inference stage. In the former process, we insert an additional linear layer before the Feed-Forward Network (FFN) of the lightweight Transformer. It is supposed that the inserted HRF layers can enhance the model learning capability. In the later process, the auxiliary HRF layer will be merged together with the following FFN layer into one linear layer and thus recover the original structure of the lightweight model. To examine the effectiveness of the proposed method, we evaluate it on three widely used Transformer variants, i.e., ConvTransformer, Conformer, and SpeechFormer networks, in the application of speech emotion recognition on the IEMOCAP, M3ED and DAIC-WOZ datasets. Experimental results show that our proposed method consistently improves the performance of lightweight Transformers, even making them comparable to large models. The proposed re-parameterization approach enables advanced Transformer models to be deployed on resource-constrained IoT devices.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09339v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zixing Zhang, Zhongren Dong, Weixiang Xu, Jing Han</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Less is More: Unseen Domain Fake News Detection via Causal Propagation Substructures</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09389</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09389v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The spread of fake news on social media poses significant threats to individuals and society. Text-based and graph-based models have been employed for fake news detection by analysing news content and propagation networks, showing promising results in specific scenarios. However, these data-driven models heavily rely on pre-existing in-distribution data for training, limiting their performance when confronted with fake news from emerging or previously unseen domains, known as out-of-distribution (OOD) data. Tackling OOD fake news is a challenging yet critical task. In this paper, we introduce the Causal Subgraph-oriented Domain Adaptive Fake News Detection (CSDA) model, designed to enhance zero-shot fake news detection by extracting causal substructures from propagation graphs using in-distribution data and generalising this approach to OOD data. The model employs a graph neural network based mask generation process to identify dominant nodes and edges within the propagation graph, using these substructures for fake news detection. Additionally, the performance of CSDA is further improved through contrastive learning in few-shot scenarios, where a limited amount of OOD data is available for training. Extensive experiments on public social media datasets demonstrate that CSDA effectively handles OOD fake news detection, achieving a 7 to 16 percents accuracy improvement over other state-of-the-art models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09389v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shuzhi Gong, Richard O. Sinnott, Jianzhong Qi, Cecile Paris</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robot Tasks with Fuzzy Time Requirements from Natural Language Instructions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09436</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09436v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Natural language allows robot programming to be accessible to everyone. However, the inherent fuzziness in natural language poses challenges for inflexible, traditional robot systems. We focus on instructions with fuzzy time requirements (e.g., "start in a few minutes"). Building on previous robotics research, we introduce fuzzy skills. These define an execution by the robot with so-called satisfaction functions representing vague execution time requirements. Such functions express a user's satisfaction over potential starting times for skill execution. When the robot handles multiple fuzzy skills, the satisfaction function provides a temporal tolerance window for execution, thus, enabling optimal scheduling based on satisfaction. We generalized such functions based on individual user expectations with a user study. The participants rated their satisfaction with an instruction's execution at various times. Our investigations reveal that trapezoidal functions best approximate the users' satisfaction. Additionally, the results suggest that users are more lenient if the execution is specified further into the future.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09436v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sascha Sucker, Michael Neubauer, Dominik Henrich</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Communication Compression for Tensor Parallel LLM Inference</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09510</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09510v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have pushed the frontier of artificial intelligence but are comprised of hundreds of billions of parameters and operations. For faster inference latency, LLMs are deployed on multiple hardware accelerators through various Model Parallelism strategies. Our paper looks into the details on one such strategy - Tensor Parallel - and proposes to reduce latency by compressing inter-accelerator communication. We leverage fine grained quantization techniques to compress selected activations by 3.5 - 4.5x. Our proposed method leads up to 2x reduction of time-to-first-token (TTFT) with negligible model performance degradation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09510v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jan Hansen-Palmus, Michael Truong-Le, Oliver Hausd\"orfer, Alok Verma</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLaMA-Mesh: Unifying 3D Mesh Generation with Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09595</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09595v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This work explores expanding the capabilities of large language models (LLMs) pretrained on text to generate 3D meshes within a unified model. This offers key advantages of (1) leveraging spatial knowledge already embedded in LLMs, derived from textual sources like 3D tutorials, and (2) enabling conversational 3D generation and mesh understanding. A primary challenge is effectively tokenizing 3D mesh data into discrete tokens that LLMs can process seamlessly. To address this, we introduce LLaMA-Mesh, a novel approach that represents the vertex coordinates and face definitions of 3D meshes as plain text, allowing direct integration with LLMs without expanding the vocabulary. We construct a supervised fine-tuning (SFT) dataset enabling pretrained LLMs to (1) generate 3D meshes from text prompts, (2) produce interleaved text and 3D mesh outputs as required, and (3) understand and interpret 3D meshes. Our work is the first to demonstrate that LLMs can be fine-tuned to acquire complex spatial knowledge for 3D mesh generation in a text-based format, effectively unifying the 3D and text modalities. LLaMA-Mesh achieves mesh generation quality on par with models trained from scratch while maintaining strong text generation performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09595v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhengyi Wang, Jonathan Lorraine, Yikai Wang, Hang Su, Jun Zhu, Sanja Fidler, Xiaohui Zeng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Initial Nugget Evaluation Results for the TREC 2024 RAG Track with the AutoNuggetizer Framework</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09607</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09607v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This report provides an initial look at partial results from the TREC 2024 Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) Track. We have identified RAG evaluation as a barrier to continued progress in information access (and more broadly, natural language processing and artificial intelligence), and it is our hope that we can contribute to tackling the many challenges in this space. The central hypothesis we explore in this work is that the nugget evaluation methodology, originally developed for the TREC Question Answering Track in 2003, provides a solid foundation for evaluating RAG systems. As such, our efforts have focused on "refactoring" this methodology, specifically applying large language models to both automatically create nuggets and to automatically assign nuggets to system answers. We call this the AutoNuggetizer framework. Within the TREC setup, we are able to calibrate our fully automatic process against a manual process whereby nuggets are created by human assessors semi-manually and then assigned manually to system answers. Based on initial results across 21 topics from 45 runs, we observe a strong correlation between scores derived from a fully automatic nugget evaluation and a (mostly) manual nugget evaluation by human assessors. This suggests that our fully automatic evaluation process can be used to guide future iterations of RAG systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09607v1</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ronak Pradeep, Nandan Thakur, Shivani Upadhyay, Daniel Campos, Nick Craswell, Jimmy Lin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Limits of Language Generation: Trade-Offs Between Hallucination and Mode Collapse</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09642</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09642v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Specifying all desirable properties of a language model is challenging, but certain requirements seem essential. Given samples from an unknown language, the trained model should produce valid strings not seen in training and be expressive enough to capture the language's full richness. Otherwise, outputting invalid strings constitutes "hallucination," and failing to capture the full range leads to "mode collapse." We ask if a language model can meet both requirements.
  We investigate this within a statistical language generation setting building on Gold and Angluin. Here, the model receives random samples from a distribution over an unknown language K, which belongs to a possibly infinite collection of languages. The goal is to generate unseen strings from K. We say the model generates from K with consistency and breadth if, as training size increases, its output converges to all unseen strings in K.
  Kleinberg and Mullainathan [KM24] asked if consistency and breadth in language generation are possible. We answer this negatively: for a large class of language models, including next-token prediction models, this is impossible for most collections of candidate languages. This contrasts with [KM24]'s result, showing consistent generation without breadth is possible for any countable collection of languages. Our finding highlights that generation with breadth fundamentally differs from generation without breadth.
  As a byproduct, we establish near-tight bounds on the number of samples needed for generation with or without breadth.
  Finally, our results offer hope: consistent generation with breadth is achievable for any countable collection of languages when negative examples (strings outside K) are available alongside positive ones. This suggests that post-training feedback, which encodes negative examples, can be crucial in reducing hallucinations while limiting mode collapse.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09642v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.DS</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alkis Kalavasis, Anay Mehrotra, Grigoris Velegkas</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM Hallucination Reasoning with Zero-shot Knowledge Test</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09689</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09689v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: LLM hallucination, where LLMs occasionally generate unfaithful text, poses significant challenges for their practical applications. Most existing detection methods rely on external knowledge, LLM fine-tuning, or hallucination-labeled datasets, and they do not distinguish between different types of hallucinations, which are crucial for improving detection performance. We introduce a new task, Hallucination Reasoning, which classifies LLM-generated text into one of three categories: aligned, misaligned, and fabricated. Our novel zero-shot method assesses whether LLM has enough knowledge about a given prompt and text. Our experiments conducted on new datasets demonstrate the effectiveness of our method in hallucination reasoning and underscore its importance for enhancing detection performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09689v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Seongmin Lee, Hsiang Hsu, Chun-Fu Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Rating as Reliable Human Evaluation of Simultaneous Speech Translation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2203.02458</link>
      <description>arXiv:2203.02458v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Simultaneous speech translation (SST) can be evaluated on simulated online events where human evaluators watch subtitled videos and continuously express their satisfaction by pressing buttons (so called Continuous Rating). Continuous Rating is easy to collect, but little is known about its reliability, or relation to comprehension of foreign language document by SST users. In this paper, we contrast Continuous Rating with factual questionnaires on judges with different levels of source language knowledge. Our results show that Continuous Rating is easy and reliable SST quality assessment if the judges have at least limited knowledge of the source language. Our study indicates users' preferences on subtitle layout and presentation style and, most importantly, provides a significant evidence that users with advanced source language knowledge prefer low latency over fewer re-translations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2203.02458v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>D\'avid Javorsk\'y, Dominik Mach\'a\v{c}ek, Ond\v{r}ej Bojar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unsupervised Summarization Re-ranking</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2212.09593</link>
      <description>arXiv:2212.09593v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: With the rise of task-specific pre-training objectives, abstractive summarization models like PEGASUS offer appealing zero-shot performance on downstream summarization tasks. However, the performance of such unsupervised models still lags significantly behind their supervised counterparts. Similarly to the supervised setup, we notice a very high variance in quality among summary candidates from these models while only one candidate is kept as the summary output. In this paper, we propose to re-rank summary candidates in an unsupervised manner, aiming to close the performance gap between unsupervised and supervised models. Our approach improves the unsupervised PEGASUS by up to 7.27% and ChatGPT by up to 6.86% relative mean ROUGE across four widely-adopted summarization benchmarks ; and achieves relative gains of 7.51% (up to 23.73% from XSum to WikiHow) averaged over 30 zero-shot transfer setups (finetuning on a dataset, evaluating on another).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2212.09593v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mathieu Ravaut, Shafiq Joty, Nancy Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Language Models Encode the Value of Numbers Linearly</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03735</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.03735v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have exhibited impressive competence in various tasks, but their internal mechanisms on mathematical problems are still under-explored. In this paper, we study a fundamental question: how language models encode the value of numbers, a basic element in math. To study the question, we construct a synthetic dataset comprising addition problems and utilize linear probes to read out input numbers from the hidden states. Experimental results support the existence of encoded number values in LLMs on different layers, and these values can be extracted via linear probes. Further experiments show that LLMs store their calculation results in a similar manner, and we can intervene the output via simple vector additions, proving the causal connection between encoded numbers and language model outputs. Our research provides evidence that LLMs encode the value of numbers linearly, offering insights for better exploring, designing, and utilizing numeric information in LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.03735v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fangwei Zhu, Damai Dai, Zhifang Sui</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can LLMs Recognize Toxicity? A Structured Investigation Framework and Toxicity Metric</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.06900</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.06900v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In the pursuit of developing Large Language Models (LLMs) that adhere to societal standards, it is imperative to detect the toxicity in the generated text. The majority of existing toxicity metrics rely on encoder models trained on specific toxicity datasets, which are susceptible to out-of-distribution (OOD) problems and depend on the dataset's definition of toxicity. In this paper, we introduce a robust metric grounded on LLMs to flexibly measure toxicity according to the given definition. We first analyze the toxicity factors, followed by an examination of the intrinsic toxic attributes of LLMs to ascertain their suitability as evaluators. Finally, we evaluate the performance of our metric with detailed analysis. Our empirical results demonstrate outstanding performance in measuring toxicity within verified factors, improving on conventional metrics by 12 points in the F1 score. Our findings also indicate that upstream toxicity significantly influences downstream metrics, suggesting that LLMs are unsuitable for toxicity evaluations within unverified factors.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.06900v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>EMNLP2024 findings</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Hyukhun Koh, Dohyung Kim, Minwoo Lee, Kyomin Jung</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Verifiable by Design: Aligning Language Models to Quote from Pre-Training Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03862</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03862v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: To trust the fluent generations of large language models (LLMs), humans must be able to verify their correctness against trusted, external sources. Recent efforts, such as providing citations via retrieved documents or post-hoc provenance, enhance verifiability but provide no guarantees on their correctness. To address these limitations, we tackle the verifiability goal with a different philosophy: trivializing the verification process by developing models that quote verbatim statements from trusted sources in their pre-training data. We propose Quote-Tuning, which demonstrates the feasibility of aligning models to quote. The core of Quote-Tuning is a fast membership inference function that efficiently verifies text against trusted corpora. We leverage this tool to design a reward function to quantify quotes in model responses, and curate datasets for preference learning. Experiments show that Quote-Tuning significantly increases verbatim quotes from high-quality documents by up to 130% relative to base models while maintaining response quality. Quote-Tuning is applicable in different tasks, generalizes to out-of-domain data and diverse model families, and provides additional benefits to truthfulness. Our method not only serves as a hassle-free method to increase quoting but also opens up avenues for improving LLM trustworthiness through better verifiability.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03862v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jingyu Zhang, Marc Marone, Tianjian Li, Benjamin Van Durme, Daniel Khashabi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Potential of Multimodal LLM with Knowledge-Intensive Multimodal ASR</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10880</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10880v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advancements in multimodal large language models (MLLMs) have made significant progress in integrating information across various modalities, yet real-world applications in educational and scientific domains remain challenging. This paper introduces the Multimodal Scientific ASR (MS-ASR) task, which focuses on transcribing scientific conference videos by leveraging visual information from slides to enhance the accuracy of technical terminologies. Realized that traditional metrics like WER fall short in assessing performance accurately, prompting the proposal of severity-aware WER (SWER) that considers the content type and severity of ASR errors. We propose the Scientific Vision Augmented ASR (SciVASR) framework as a baseline method, enabling MLLMs to improve transcript quality through post-editing. Evaluations of state-of-the-art MLLMs, including GPT-4o, show a 45% improvement over speech-only baselines, highlighting the importance of multimodal information integration.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10880v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Minghan Wang, Yuxia Wang, Thuy-Trang Vu, Ehsan Shareghi, Gholamreza Haffari</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problematic Tokens: Tokenizer Bias in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.11214</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.11214v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advancements in large language models(LLMs), such as GPT-4 and GPT-4o, have shown exceptional performance, especially in languages with abundant resources like English, thanks to extensive datasets that ensure robust training. Conversely, these models exhibit limitations when processing under-resourced languages such as Chinese and Korean, where issues including hallucinatory responses remain prevalent. This paper traces the roots of these disparities to the tokenization process inherent to these models. Specifically, it explores how the tokenizers vocabulary, often used to speed up the tokenization process and reduce tokens but constructed independently of the actual model training data, inadequately represents non-English languages. This misrepresentation results in the propagation of under-trained or untrained tokens, which perpetuate biases and pose serious concerns related to data security and ethical standards. We aim to dissect the tokenization mechanics of GPT-4o, illustrating how its simplified token-handling methods amplify these risks and offer strategic solutions to mitigate associated security and ethical issues. Through this study, we emphasize the critical need to rethink tokenization frameworks to foster more equitable and secure AI technologies. The code and data are available at https://github.com/yeyimilk/LLMGPT4o</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.11214v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jin Yang, Zhiqiang Wang, Yanbin Lin, Zunduo Zhao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Instance Training to Instruction Learning: Task Adapters Generation from Instructions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.12382</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.12382v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have acquired the ability to solve general tasks by utilizing instruction finetuning (IFT). However, IFT still relies heavily on instance training of extensive task data, which greatly limits the adaptability of LLMs to real-world scenarios where labeled task instances are scarce and broader task generalization becomes paramount. Contrary to LLMs, humans acquire skills and complete tasks not merely through repeated practice but also by understanding and following instructional guidelines. This paper is dedicated to simulating human learning to address the shortcomings of instance training, focusing on instruction learning to enhance cross-task generalization. Within this context, we introduce Task Adapters Generation from Instructions (TAGI), which automatically constructs the task-specific model in a parameter generation manner based on the given task instructions without retraining for unseen tasks. Specifically, we utilize knowledge distillation to enhance the consistency between TAGI developed through Learning with Instruction and task-specific models developed through Training with Instance, by aligning the labels, output logits, and adapter parameters between them. TAGI is endowed with cross-task generalization capabilities through a two-stage training process that includes hypernetwork pretraining and finetuning. We evaluate TAGI on the Super-Natural Instructions and P3 datasets. The experimental results demonstrate that TAGI can match or even outperform traditional meta-trained models and other hypernetwork models, while significantly reducing computational requirements.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.12382v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Huanxuan Liao, Shizhu He, Yao Xu, Yuanzhe Zhang, Yanchao Hao, Shengping Liu, Kang Liu, Jun Zhao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IRCAN: Mitigating Knowledge Conflicts in LLM Generation via Identifying and Reweighting Context-Aware Neurons</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.18406</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.18406v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: It is widely acknowledged that large language models (LLMs) encode a vast reservoir of knowledge after being trained on mass data. Recent studies disclose knowledge conflicts in LLM generation, wherein outdated or incorrect parametric knowledge (i.e., encoded knowledge) contradicts new knowledge provided in the context. To mitigate such knowledge conflicts, we propose a novel framework, IRCAN (Identifying and Reweighting Context-Aware Neurons) to capitalize on neurons that are crucial in processing contextual cues. Specifically, IRCAN first identifies neurons that significantly contribute to context processing, utilizing a context-aware attribution score derived from integrated gradients. Subsequently, the identified context-aware neurons are strengthened via reweighting. In doing so, we steer LLMs to generate context-sensitive outputs with respect to the new knowledge provided in the context. Extensive experiments conducted across a variety of models and tasks demonstrate that IRCAN not only achieves remarkable improvements in handling knowledge conflicts but also offers a scalable, plug-and-play solution that can be integrated seamlessly with existing models. Our codes are released at https://github.com/danshi777/IRCAN.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.18406v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dan Shi, Renren Jin, Tianhao Shen, Weilong Dong, Xinwei Wu, Deyi Xiong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Language Models for Power Scheduling: A User-Centric Approach</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.00476</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.00476v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: While traditional optimization and scheduling schemes are designed to meet fixed, predefined system requirements, future systems are moving toward user-driven approaches and personalized services, aiming to achieve high quality-of-experience (QoE) and flexibility. This challenge is particularly pronounced in wireless and digitalized energy networks, where users' requirements have largely not been taken into consideration due to the lack of a common language between users and machines. The emergence of powerful large language models (LLMs) marks a radical departure from traditional system-centric methods into more advanced user-centric approaches by providing a natural communication interface between users and devices. In this paper, for the first time, we introduce a novel architecture for resource scheduling problems by constructing three LLM agents to convert an arbitrary user's voice request (VRQ) into a resource allocation vector. Specifically, we design an LLM intent recognition agent to translate the request into an optimization problem (OP), an LLM OP parameter identification agent, and an LLM OP solving agent. To evaluate system performance, we construct a database of typical VRQs in the context of electric vehicle (EV) charging. As a proof of concept, we primarily use Llama 3 8B. Through testing with different prompt engineering scenarios, the obtained results demonstrate the efficiency of the proposed architecture. The conducted performance analysis allows key insights to be extracted. For instance, having a larger set of candidate OPs to model the real-world problem might degrade the final performance because of a higher recognition/OP classification noise level. All results and codes are open source.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.00476v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SY</category>
      <category>eess.SY</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Thomas Mongaillard, Samson Lasaulce, Othman Hicheur, Chao Zhang, Lina Bariah, Vineeth S. Varma, Hang Zou, Qiyang Zhao, Merouane Debbah</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Small Language Models Learn, Unlearn, and Retain Noise Patterns?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.00996</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.00996v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Small Language Models (SLMs) are generally considered more compact versions of large language models (LLMs). This study investigates the ability of SLMs with parameters between 1 and 3 billion to learn, retain, and subsequently eliminate different types of noise present in the data. Four pre-trained SLMs were utilized for this: Olmo 1B, Qwen1.5 1.8B, Gemma 2B, and Phi2 2.7B. The models were instruction-tuned on noise-free data and tested using in-context examples to determine if they could learn noise through examples. Subsequently, noise patterns were introduced in instruction tuning to evaluate the noise learning, unlearning, and retention capabilities of the models. Olmo, the smallest model, was highly sensitive to noise, quickly adapting to noisy patterns. Phi2 resisted learning character-level and transliteration noise, likely due to its carefully curated, structured, and high-quality pretraining data. Gemma excelled with transliteration noise, likely benefiting from its multilingual pretraining. The findings can be used to develop robust training strategies for SLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.00996v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nicy Scaria, Silvester John Joseph Kennedy, Deepak Subramani</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SLIMER-IT: Zero-Shot NER on Italian Language</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.15933</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.15933v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Traditional approaches to Named Entity Recognition (NER) frame the task into a BIO sequence labeling problem. Although these systems often excel in the downstream task at hand, they require extensive annotated data and struggle to generalize to out-of-distribution input domains and unseen entity types. On the contrary, Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated strong zero-shot capabilities. While several works address Zero-Shot NER in English, little has been done in other languages. In this paper, we define an evaluation framework for Zero-Shot NER, applying it to the Italian language. Furthermore, we introduce SLIMER-IT, the Italian version of SLIMER, an instruction-tuning approach for zero-shot NER leveraging prompts enriched with definition and guidelines. Comparisons with other state-of-the-art models, demonstrate the superiority of SLIMER-IT on never-seen-before entity tags.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.15933v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Andrew Zamai, Leonardo Rigutini, Marco Maggini, Andrea Zugarini</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Value Residual Learning For Alleviating Attention Concentration In Transformers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.17897</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.17897v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Transformers can capture long-range dependencies using self-attention, allowing tokens to attend to all others directly. However, stacking multiple attention layers leads to attention concentration. One natural way to address this issue is to use cross-layer attention, allowing information from earlier layers to be directly accessible to later layers. However, this approach is computationally expensive. To address this problem, we propose Transformer with residual value (ResFormer) which approximates cross-layer attention through adding a residual connection from the values of the the first layer to all subsequent layers. Based on this method, one variant is the Transformer with single layer value (SVFormer), where all layers share the same value embedding from first layer, reducing the $KV$ cache by nearly 50\%. Comprehensive empirical evidence demonstrates that ResFormer mitigates attention concentration problem in deeper layers and enhances representation across most layers, outperforming the vanilla Transformer, DenseFormer, and NeuTRENO in training error as well as downstream tasks. Further visualization results suggest that Resformer alleviates attention sinks through avoiding value-state drains. SVFormer trains significantly faster than the vanilla Transformer and performs better than other methods like GQA and CLA, with performance influenced by sequence length and cumulative learning rate.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.17897v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhanchao Zhou, Tianyi Wu, Zhiyun Jiang, Zhenzhong Lan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Not All Heads Matter: A Head-Level KV Cache Compression Method with Integrated Retrieval and Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.19258</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.19258v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Key-Value (KV) caching is a common technique to enhance the computational efficiency of Large Language Models (LLMs), but its memory overhead grows rapidly with input length. Prior work has shown that not all tokens are equally important for text generation, proposing layer-level KV cache compression to selectively retain key information. Recognizing the distinct roles of attention heads in generation, we propose HeadKV, a head-level KV cache compression method, and HeadKV-R2, which leverages a novel contextual reasoning ability estimation for compression. Our approach operates at the level of individual heads, estimating their importance for contextual QA tasks that require both retrieval and reasoning capabilities. Extensive experiments across diverse benchmarks (LongBench, LooGLE), model architectures (e.g., Llama-3-8B-Instruct, Mistral-7B-Instruct), and long-context abilities tests demonstrate that our head-level KV cache compression significantly outperforms strong baselines, particularly in low-resource settings (KV size = 64 &amp; 128). Notably, our method retains just 1.5% of the KV cache while achieving 97% of the performance of the full KV cache on the contextual question answering benchmark.Codes are available at https://github.com/FYYFU/HeadKV</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.19258v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yu Fu, Zefan Cai, Abedelkadir Asi, Wayne Xiong, Yue Dong, Wen Xiao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MDCure: A Scalable Pipeline for Multi-Document Instruction-Following</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.23463</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.23463v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Multi-document (MD) processing is crucial for LLMs to handle real-world tasks such as summarization and question-answering across large sets of documents. While LLMs have improved at processing long inputs, MD contexts still present challenges, such as managing inter-document dependencies, redundancy, and incoherent structures. We introduce MDCure, a scalable and effective fine-tuning pipeline to enhance the MD capabilities of LLMs without the computational cost of pre-training or reliance on human annotated data. MDCure is based on generation of high-quality synthetic MD instruction data from sets of related articles via targeted prompts. We further introduce MDCureRM, a multi-objective reward model which filters generated data based on their training utility for MD settings. With MDCure, we fine-tune a variety of LLMs, from the FlanT5, Qwen2, and LLAMA3.1 model families, up to 70B parameters in size. Extensive evaluations on a wide range of MD and long-context benchmarks spanning various tasks show MDCure consistently improves performance over pre-trained baselines and over corresponding base models by up to 75.5%. Our code, datasets, and models are available at https://github.com/yale-nlp/MDCure.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.23463v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gabrielle Kaili-May Liu, Bowen Shi, Avi Caciularu, Idan Szpektor, Arman Cohan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative Assessment of Intersectional Empathetic Bias and Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.05777</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.05777v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: A growing amount of literature critiques the current operationalizations of empathy based on loose definitions of the construct. Such definitions negatively affect dataset quality, model robustness, and evaluation reliability. We propose an empathy evaluation framework that operationalizes empathy close to its psychological origins. The framework measures the variance in responses of LLMs to prompts using existing metrics for empathy and emotional valence. The variance is introduced through the controlled generation of the prompts by varying social biases affecting context understanding, thus impacting empathetic understanding. The control over generation ensures high theoretical validity of the constructs in the prompt dataset. Also, it makes high-quality translation, especially into languages that currently have little-to-no way of evaluating empathy or bias, such as the Slavonic family, more manageable. Using chosen LLMs and various prompt types, we demonstrate the empathy evaluation with the framework, including multiple-choice answers and free generation. The variance in our initial evaluation sample is small and we were unable to measure convincing differences between the empathetic understanding in contexts given by different social groups. However, the results are promising because the models showed significant alterations their reasoning chains needed to capture the relatively subtle changes in the prompts. This provides the basis for future research into the construction of the evaluation sample and statistical methods for measuring the results.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.05777v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Vojtech Formanek, Ondrej Sotolar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More Expressive Attention with Negative Weights</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.07176</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.07176v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We propose a novel attention mechanism, named Cog Attention, that enables attention weights to be negative for enhanced expressiveness, which stems from two key factors: (1) Cog Attention can shift the token deletion and copying function from a static OV matrix to dynamic QK inner products, with the OV matrix now focusing more on refinement or modification. The attention head can simultaneously delete, copy, or retain tokens by assigning them negative, positive, or minimal attention weights, respectively. As a result, a single attention head becomes more flexible and expressive. (2) Cog Attention improves the model's robustness against representational collapse, which can occur when earlier tokens are over-squashed into later positions, leading to homogeneous representations. Negative weights reduce effective information paths from earlier to later tokens, helping to mitigate this issue. We develop Transformer-like models which use Cog Attention as attention modules, including decoder-only models for language modeling and U-ViT diffusion models for image generation. Experiments show that models using Cog Attention exhibit superior performance compared to those employing traditional softmax attention modules. Our approach suggests a promising research direction for rethinking and breaking the entrenched constraints of traditional softmax attention, such as the requirement for non-negative weights.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.07176v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ang Lv, Ruobing Xie, Shuaipeng Li, Jiayi Liao, Xingwu Sun, Zhanhui Kang, Di Wang, Rui Yan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trustful LLMs: Customizing and Grounding Text Generation with Knowledge Bases and Dual Decoders</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.07870</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.07870v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Although people are impressed by the content generation skills of large language models, the use of LLMs, such as ChatGPT, is limited by the domain grounding of the content. The correctness and groundedness of the generated content need to be based on a verified context, such as results from Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG). One important issue when adapting LLMs to a customized domain is that the generated responses are often incomplete, or the additions are not verified and may even be hallucinated. Prior studies on hallucination detection have focused on evaluation metrics, which are not easily adaptable to dynamic domains and can be vulnerable to attacks like jail-breaking. In this work, we propose 1) a post-processing algorithm that leverages knowledge triplets in RAG context to correct hallucinations and 2) a dual-decoder model that fuses RAG context to guide the generation process.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.07870v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>EMNLP CustomNLP4U 2024</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Xiaofeng Zhu, Jaya Krishna Mandivarapu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Bases in Support of Large Language Models for Processing Web News</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.08278</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.08278v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have received considerable interest in wide applications lately. During pre-training via massive datasets, such a model implicitly memorizes the factual knowledge of trained datasets in its hidden parameters. However, knowledge held implicitly in parameters often makes its use by downstream applications ineffective due to the lack of common-sense reasoning. In this article, we introduce a general framework that permits to build knowledge bases with an aid of LLMs, tailored for processing Web news. The framework applies a rule-based News Information Extractor (NewsIE) to news items for extracting their relational tuples, referred to as knowledge bases, which are then graph-convoluted with the implicit knowledge facts of news items obtained by LLMs, for their classification. It involves two lightweight components: 1) NewsIE: for extracting the structural information of every news item, in the form of relational tuples; 2) BERTGraph: for graph convoluting the implicit knowledge facts with relational tuples extracted by NewsIE. We have evaluated our framework under different news-related datasets for news category classification, with promising experimental results.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.08278v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yihe Zhang, Nabin Pakka, Nian-Feng Tzeng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Objective and Unbiased Decision Assessments with LLM-Enhanced Hierarchical Attention Networks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.08504</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.08504v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: How objective and unbiased are we while making decisions? This work investigates cognitive bias identification in high-stake decision making process by human experts, questioning its effectiveness in real-world settings, such as candidates assessments for university admission. We begin with a statistical analysis assessing correlations among different decision points among in the current process, which discovers discrepancies that imply cognitive bias and inconsistency in decisions. This motivates our exploration of bias-aware AI-augmented workflow that surpass human judgment. We propose BGM-HAN, an enhanced Hierarchical Attention Network with Byte-Pair Encoding, Gated Residual Connections and Multi-Head Attention. Using it as a backbone model, we further propose a Shortlist-Analyse-Recommend (SAR) agentic workflow, which simulate real-world decision-making. In our experiments, both the proposed model and the agentic workflow significantly improves on both human judgment and alternative models, validated with real-world data.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.08504v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junhua Liu, Kwan Hui Lim, Roy Ka-Wei Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Rewarding with Prompt Optimization Enables Tuning-free Self-Alignment of Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.08733</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.08733v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Aligning Large Language Models (LLMs) traditionally relies on costly training and human preference annotations. Self-alignment seeks to reduce these expenses by enabling models to align themselves. To further lower costs and achieve alignment without any expensive tuning or annotations, we introduce a new tuning-free approach for self-alignment, Dynamic Rewarding with Prompt Optimization (DRPO). Our approach leverages a search-based optimization framework that allows LLMs to iteratively self-improve and craft the optimal alignment instructions, all without additional training or human intervention. The core of DRPO is a dynamic rewarding mechanism, which identifies and rectifies model-specific alignment weaknesses, allowing LLMs to adapt efficiently to diverse alignment challenges. Empirical evaluations on eight recent LLMs, both open- and closed-sourced, demonstrate that DRPO significantly enhances alignment performance, with base models outperforming their SFT/RLHF-tuned counterparts. Moreover, the prompts automatically optimized by DRPO surpass those curated by human experts, further validating the effectiveness of our approach. Our findings highlight the great potential of current LLMs to achieve adaptive self-alignment through inference-time optimization, complementing tuning-based alignment methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.08733v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Somanshu Singla, Zhen Wang, Tianyang Liu, Abdullah Ashfaq, Zhiting Hu, Eric P. Xing</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AutoDefense: Multi-Agent LLM Defense against Jailbreak Attacks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.04783</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.04783v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Despite extensive pre-training in moral alignment to prevent generating harmful information, large language models (LLMs) remain vulnerable to jailbreak attacks. In this paper, we propose AutoDefense, a multi-agent defense framework that filters harmful responses from LLMs. With the response-filtering mechanism, our framework is robust against different jailbreak attack prompts, and can be used to defend different victim models. AutoDefense assigns different roles to LLM agents and employs them to complete the defense task collaboratively. The division in tasks enhances the overall instruction-following of LLMs and enables the integration of other defense components as tools. With AutoDefense, small open-source LMs can serve as agents and defend larger models against jailbreak attacks. Our experiments show that AutoDefense can effectively defense against different jailbreak attacks, while maintaining the performance at normal user request. For example, we reduce the attack success rate on GPT-3.5 from 55.74% to 7.95% using LLaMA-2-13b with a 3-agent system. Our code and data are publicly available at https://github.com/XHMY/AutoDefense.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.04783v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yifan Zeng, Yiran Wu, Xiao Zhang, Huazheng Wang, Qingyun Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VRSD: Rethinking Similarity and Diversity for Retrieval in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.04573</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.04573v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Vector retrieval algorithms are essential for semantic queries within the rapidly evolving landscape of Large Language Models (LLMs). The ability to retrieve vectors that satisfy both similarity and diversity criteria substantially enhances the performance of LLMs. Although Maximal Marginal Relevance (MMR) is widely employed in retrieval scenarios requiring relevance and diversity, variations in the parameter $\lambda$ lead to fluctuations that complicate the optimization trajectory in vector spaces. This obscures the direction of improvement and highlights the lack of a robust theoretical analysis regarding similarity and diversity constraints in retrieval processes. To address these challenges, this paper introduces a novel approach that characterizes both constraints through the relationship between the sum vector and the query vector. The proximity of these vectors ensures the similarity constraint, while requiring individual vectors within the sum vector to diverge in their alignment with the query vector satisfies the diversity constraint. We first formulate a new combinatorial optimization problem, selecting k vectors from a candidate set such that their sum vector maximally aligns with the query vector, and demonstrate that this problem is NP-complete. This result underscores the inherent difficulty of simultaneously achieving similarity and diversity in vector retrieval, thereby providing a theoretical foundation for future research. Subsequently, we present the heuristic algorithm Vectors Retrieval with Similarity and Diversity, VRSD, which features a clear optimization objective and eliminates the need for preset parameters. VRSD also achieves a modest reduction in time complexity compared to MMR. Empirical validation confirms that VRSD significantly outperforms MMR across various datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.04573v2</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hang Gao, Yongfeng Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characterization of Political Polarized Users Attacked by Language Toxicity on Twitter</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.12471</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.12471v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Understanding the dynamics of language toxicity on social media is important for us to investigate the propagation of misinformation and the development of echo chambers for political scenarios such as U.S. presidential elections. Recent research has used large-scale data to investigate the dynamics across social media platforms. However, research on the toxicity dynamics is not enough. This study aims to provide a first exploration of the potential language toxicity flow among Left, Right and Center users. Specifically, we aim to examine whether Left users were easier to be attacked by language toxicity. In this study, more than 500M Twitter posts were examined. It was discovered that Left users received much more toxic replies than Right and Center users.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.12471v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3678884.3681849</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>In Companion Publication of the 2024 Conference on Computer-Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing (CSCW Companion 24). Association for Computing Machinery, New York, NY, USA, 185-189</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Wentao Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Arabic Multi-Label Emotion Classification using Stacked Embeddings and Hybrid Loss Function</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.03979</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.03979v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In multi-label emotion classification, particularly for low-resource languages like Arabic, the challenges of class imbalance and label correlation hinder model performance, especially in accurately predicting minority emotions. To address these issues, this study proposes a novel approach that combines stacked embeddings, meta-learning, and a hybrid loss function to enhance multi-label emotion classification for the Arabic language. The study extracts contextual embeddings from three fine-tuned language models-ArabicBERT, MarBERT, and AraBERT-which are then stacked to form enriched embeddings. A meta-learner is trained on these stacked embeddings, and the resulting concatenated representations are provided as input to a Bi-LSTM model, followed by a fully connected neural network for multi-label classification. To further improve performance, a hybrid loss function is introduced, incorporating class weighting, label correlation matrix, and contrastive learning, effectively addressing class imbalances and improving the handling of label correlations. Extensive experiments validate the proposed model's performance across key metrics such as Precision, Recall, F1-Score, Jaccard Accuracy, and Hamming Loss. The class-wise performance analysis demonstrates the hybrid loss function's ability to significantly reduce disparities between majority and minority classes, resulting in a more balanced emotion classification. An ablation study highlights the contribution of each component, showing the superiority of the model compared to baseline approaches and other loss functions. This study not only advances multi-label emotion classification for Arabic but also presents a generalizable framework that can be adapted to other languages and domains, providing a significant step forward in addressing the challenges of low-resource emotion classification tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.03979v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Muhammad Azeem Aslam, Wang Jun, Nisar Ahmed, Muhammad Imran Zaman, Li Yanan, Hu Hongfei, Wang Shiyu, Xin Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Large Language Models Truly Grasp Mathematics? An Empirical Exploration From Cognitive Psychology</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.14979</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.14979v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The cognitive mechanism by which Large Language Models (LLMs) solve mathematical problems remains a widely debated and unresolved issue. Currently, there is little interpretable experimental evidence that connects LLMs' problem-solving with human cognitive psychology.To determine if LLMs possess human-like mathematical reasoning, we modified the problems used in the human Cognitive Reflection Test (CRT). Our results show that, even with the use of Chains of Thought (CoT) prompts, mainstream LLMs, including the latest o1 model (noted for its reasoning capabilities), have a high error rate when solving these modified CRT problems. Specifically, the average accuracy rate dropped by up to 50% compared to the original questions.Further analysis of LLMs' incorrect answers suggests that they primarily rely on pattern matching from their training data, which aligns more with human intuition (System 1 thinking) rather than with human-like reasoning (System 2 thinking). This finding challenges the belief that LLMs have genuine mathematical reasoning abilities comparable to humans. As a result, this work may adjust overly optimistic views on LLMs' progress towards artificial general intelligence.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.14979v4</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wei Xie, Shuoyoucheng Ma, Zhenhua Wang, Enze Wang, Kai Chen, Xiaobing Sun, Baosheng Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM2CLIP: Powerful Language Model Unlocks Richer Visual Representation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.04997</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.04997v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: CLIP is one of the most important multimodal foundational models today. What powers CLIP's capabilities? The rich supervision signals provided by natural language, the carrier of human knowledge, shape a powerful cross-modal representation space. However, with the rapid advancements in large language models LLMs like GPT-4 and LLaMA, the boundaries of language comprehension and generation are continually being pushed. This raises an intriguing question: can the capabilities of LLMs be harnessed to further improve multimodal representation learning? The potential benefits of incorporating LLMs into CLIP are clear. LLMs' strong textual understanding can fundamentally improve CLIP's ability to handle image captions, drastically enhancing its ability to process long and complex texts, a well-known limitation of vanilla CLIP. Moreover, LLMs are trained on a vast corpus of text, possessing open-world knowledge. This allows them to expand on caption information during training, increasing the efficiency of the learning process. In this paper, we propose LLM2CLIP, a novel approach that embraces the power of LLMs to unlock CLIP's potential. By fine-tuning the LLM in the caption space with contrastive learning, we extract its textual capabilities into the output embeddings, significantly improving the output layer's textual discriminability. We then design an efficient training process where the fine-tuned LLM acts as a powerful teacher for CLIP's visual encoder. Thanks to the LLM's presence, we can now incorporate longer and more complex captions without being restricted by vanilla CLIP's text encoder's context window and ability limitations. Our experiments demonstrate that this approach brings substantial improvements in cross-modal tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.04997v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weiquan Huang, Aoqi Wu, Yifan Yang, Xufang Luo, Yuqing Yang, Liang Hu, Qi Dai, Xiyang Dai, Dongdong Chen, Chong Luo, Lili Qiu</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
