<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL</link>
    <description>cs.CL updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 05:28:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Sunday</day>
      <day>Saturday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>The use of large language models to enhance cancer clinical trial educational materials</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.01955</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.01955v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Cancer clinical trials often face challenges in recruitment and engagement due to a lack of participant-facing informational and educational resources. This study investigated the potential of Large Language Models (LLMs), specifically GPT4, in generating patient-friendly educational content from clinical trial informed consent forms. Using data from ClinicalTrials.gov, we employed zero-shot learning for creating trial summaries and one-shot learning for developing multiple-choice questions, evaluating their effectiveness through patient surveys and crowdsourced annotation. Results showed that GPT4-generated summaries were both readable and comprehensive, and may improve patients' understanding and interest in clinical trials. The multiple-choice questions demonstrated high accuracy and agreement with crowdsourced annotators. For both resource types, hallucinations were identified that require ongoing human oversight. The findings demonstrate the potential of LLMs "out-of-the-box" to support the generation of clinical trial education materials with minimal trial-specific engineering, but implementation with a human-in-the-loop is still needed to avoid misinformation risks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.01955v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mingye Gao, Aman Varshney, Shan Chen, Vikram Goddla, Jack Gallifant, Patrick Doyle, Claire Novack, Maeve Dillon-Martin, Teresia Perkins, Xinrong Correia, Erik Duhaime, Howard Isenstein, Elad Sharon, Lisa Soleymani Lehmann, David Kozono, Brian Anthony, Dmitriy Dligach, Danielle S. Bitterman</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Real-Time Multilingual Sign Language Processing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.01991</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.01991v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Sign Language Processing (SLP) is an interdisciplinary field comprised of Natural Language Processing (NLP) and Computer Vision. It is focused on the computational understanding, translation, and production of signed languages. Traditional approaches have often been constrained by the use of gloss-based systems that are both language-specific and inadequate for capturing the multidimensional nature of sign language. These limitations have hindered the development of technology capable of processing signed languages effectively.
  This thesis aims to revolutionize the field of SLP by proposing a simple paradigm that can bridge this existing technological gap. We propose the use of SignWiring, a universal sign language transcription notation system, to serve as an intermediary link between the visual-gestural modality of signed languages and text-based linguistic representations.
  We contribute foundational libraries and resources to the SLP community, thereby setting the stage for a more in-depth exploration of the tasks of sign language translation and production. These tasks encompass the translation of sign language from video to spoken language text and vice versa. Through empirical evaluations, we establish the efficacy of our transcription method as a pivot for enabling faster, more targeted research, that can lead to more natural and accurate translations across a range of languages.
  The universal nature of our transcription-based paradigm also paves the way for real-time, multilingual applications in SLP, thereby offering a more inclusive and accessible approach to language technology. This is a significant step toward universal accessibility, enabling a wider reach of AI-driven language technologies to include the deaf and hard-of-hearing community.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.01991v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Amit Moryossef</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Multi-way Parallel Named Entity Annotated Corpus for English, Tamil and Sinhala</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02056</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02056v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper presents a multi-way parallel English-Tamil-Sinhala corpus annotated with Named Entities (NEs), where Sinhala and Tamil are low-resource languages. Using pre-trained multilingual Language Models (mLMs), we establish new benchmark Named Entity Recognition (NER) results on this dataset for Sinhala and Tamil. We also carry out a detailed investigation on the NER capabilities of different types of mLMs. Finally, we demonstrate the utility of our NER system on a low-resource Neural Machine Translation (NMT) task. Our dataset is publicly released: https://github.com/suralk/multiNER.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02056v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Surangika Ranathunga, Asanka Ranasinghea, Janaka Shamala, Ayodya Dandeniyaa, Rashmi Galappaththia, Malithi Samaraweeraa</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BN-AuthProf: Benchmarking Machine Learning for Bangla Author Profiling on Social Media Texts</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02058</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02058v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Author profiling, the analysis of texts to uncover attributes such as gender and age of the author, has become essential with the widespread use of social media platforms. This paper focuses on author profiling in the Bangla language, aiming to extract valuable insights about anonymous authors based on their writing style on social media. The primary objective is to introduce and benchmark the performance of machine learning approaches on a newly created Bangla Author Profiling dataset, BN-AuthProf. The dataset comprises 30,131 social media posts from 300 authors, labeled by their age and gender. Authors' identities and sensitive information were anonymized to ensure privacy. Various classical machine learning and deep learning techniques were employed to evaluate the dataset. For gender classification, the best accuracy achieved was 80% using Support Vector Machine (SVM), while a Multinomial Naive Bayes (MNB) classifier achieved the best F1 score of 0.756. For age classification, MNB attained a maximum accuracy score of 91% with an F1 score of 0.905. This research highlights the effectiveness of machine learning in gender and age classification for Bangla author profiling, with practical implications spanning marketing, security, forensic linguistics, education, and criminal investigations, considering privacy and biases.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02058v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Raisa Tasnim, Mehanaz Chowdhury, Md Ataur Rahman</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let's Think Var-by-Var: Large Language Models Enable Ad Hoc Probabilistic Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02081</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02081v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: A hallmark of intelligence is the ability to flesh out underspecified situations using "common sense." We propose to extract that common sense from large language models (LLMs), in a form that can feed into probabilistic inference. We focus our investigation on $\textit{guesstimation}$ questions such as "How much are Airbnb listings in Newark, NJ?" Formulating a sensible answer without access to data requires drawing on, and integrating, bits of common knowledge about how $\texttt{Price}$ and $\texttt{Location}$ may relate to other variables, such as $\texttt{Property Type}$. Our framework answers such a question by synthesizing an $\textit{ad hoc}$ probabilistic model. First we prompt an LLM to propose a set of random variables relevant to the question, followed by moment constraints on their joint distribution. We then optimize the joint distribution $p$ within a log-linear family to maximize the overall constraint satisfaction. Our experiments show that LLMs can successfully be prompted to propose reasonable variables, and while the proposed numerical constraints can be noisy, jointly optimizing for their satisfaction reconciles them. When evaluated on probabilistic questions derived from three real-world tabular datasets, we find that our framework performs comparably to a direct prompting baseline in terms of total variation distance from the dataset distribution, and is similarly robust to noise.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02081v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shepard Xia, Brian Lu, Jason Eisner</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Language Transfer Capability of Decoder-only Architecture in Multilingual Neural Machine Translation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02101</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02101v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Existing multilingual neural machine translation (MNMT) approaches mainly focus on improving models with the encoder-decoder architecture to translate multiple languages. However, decoder-only architecture has been explored less in MNMT due to its underperformance when trained on parallel data solely. In this work, we attribute the issue of the decoder-only architecture to its lack of language transfer capability. Specifically, the decoder-only architecture is insufficient in encoding source tokens with the target language features. We propose dividing the decoding process into two stages so that target tokens are explicitly excluded in the first stage to implicitly boost the transfer capability across languages. Additionally, we impose contrastive learning on translation instructions, resulting in improved performance in zero-shot translation. We conduct experiments on TED-19 and OPUS-100 datasets, considering both training from scratch and fine-tuning scenarios. Experimental results show that, compared to the encoder-decoder architecture, our methods not only perform competitively in supervised translations but also achieve improvements of up to 3.39 BLEU, 6.99 chrF++, 3.22 BERTScore, and 4.81 COMET in zero-shot translations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02101v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhi Qu, Yiran Wang, Chenchen Ding, Hideki Tanaka, Masao Utiyama, Taro Watanabe</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explainable and Interpretable Multimodal Large Language Models: A Comprehensive Survey</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02104</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02104v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The rapid development of Artificial Intelligence (AI) has revolutionized numerous fields, with large language models (LLMs) and computer vision (CV) systems driving advancements in natural language understanding and visual processing, respectively. The convergence of these technologies has catalyzed the rise of multimodal AI, enabling richer, cross-modal understanding that spans text, vision, audio, and video modalities. Multimodal large language models (MLLMs), in particular, have emerged as a powerful framework, demonstrating impressive capabilities in tasks like image-text generation, visual question answering, and cross-modal retrieval. Despite these advancements, the complexity and scale of MLLMs introduce significant challenges in interpretability and explainability, essential for establishing transparency, trustworthiness, and reliability in high-stakes applications. This paper provides a comprehensive survey on the interpretability and explainability of MLLMs, proposing a novel framework that categorizes existing research across three perspectives: (I) Data, (II) Model, (III) Training \&amp; Inference. We systematically analyze interpretability from token-level to embedding-level representations, assess approaches related to both architecture analysis and design, and explore training and inference strategies that enhance transparency. By comparing various methodologies, we identify their strengths and limitations and propose future research directions to address unresolved challenges in multimodal explainability. This survey offers a foundational resource for advancing interpretability and transparency in MLLMs, guiding researchers and practitioners toward developing more accountable and robust multimodal AI systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02104v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yunkai Dang, Kaichen Huang, Jiahao Huo, Yibo Yan, Sirui Huang, Dongrui Liu, Mengxi Gao, Jie Zhang, Chen Qian, Kun Wang, Yong Liu, Jing Shao, Hui Xiong, Xuming Hu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Misalignment of Semantic Relation Knowledge between WordNet and Human Intuition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02138</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02138v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: WordNet provides a carefully constructed repository of semantic relations, created by specialists. But there is another source of information on semantic relations, the intuition of language users. We present the first systematic study of the degree to which these two sources are aligned. Investigating the cases of misalignment could make proper use of WordNet and facilitate its improvement. Our analysis which uses templates to elicit responses from human participants, reveals a general misalignment of semantic relation knowledge between WordNet and human intuition. Further analyses find a systematic pattern of mismatch among synonymy and taxonomic relations~(hypernymy and hyponymy), together with the fact that WordNet path length does not serve as a reliable indicator of human intuition regarding hypernymy or hyponymy relations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02138v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhihan Cao, Hiroaki Yamada, Simone Teufel, Takenobu Tokunaga</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Large Language Models for Comparative Literature Summarization with Reflective Incremental Mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02149</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02149v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this paper, we introduce ChatCite, a novel method leveraging large language models (LLMs) for generating comparative literature summaries. The ability to summarize research papers with a focus on key comparisons between studies is an essential task in academic research. Existing summarization models, while effective at generating concise summaries, fail to provide deep comparative insights. ChatCite addresses this limitation by incorporating a multi-step reasoning mechanism that extracts critical elements from papers, incrementally builds a comparative summary, and refines the output through a reflective memory process. We evaluate ChatCite on a custom dataset, CompLit-LongContext, consisting of 1000 research papers with annotated comparative summaries. Experimental results show that ChatCite outperforms several baseline methods, including GPT-4, BART, T5, and CoT, across various automatic evaluation metrics such as ROUGE and the newly proposed G-Score. Human evaluation further confirms that ChatCite generates more coherent, insightful, and fluent summaries compared to these baseline models. Our method provides a significant advancement in automatic literature review generation, offering researchers a powerful tool for efficiently comparing and synthesizing scientific research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02149v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fernando Gabriela Garcia, Spencer Burns, Harrison Fuller</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BANER: Boundary-Aware LLMs for Few-Shot Named Entity Recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02228</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02228v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Despite the recent success of two-stage prototypical networks in few-shot named entity recognition (NER), challenges such as over/under-detected false spans in the span detection stage and unaligned entity prototypes in the type classification stage persist. Additionally, LLMs have not proven to be effective few-shot information extractors in general. In this paper, we propose an approach called Boundary-Aware LLMs for Few-Shot Named Entity Recognition to address these issues. We introduce a boundary-aware contrastive learning strategy to enhance the LLM's ability to perceive entity boundaries for generalized entity spans. Additionally, we utilize LoRAHub to align information from the target domain to the source domain, thereby enhancing adaptive cross-domain classification capabilities. Extensive experiments across various benchmarks demonstrate that our framework outperforms prior methods, validating its effectiveness. In particular, the proposed strategies demonstrate effectiveness across a range of LLM architectures. The code and data are released on https://github.com/UESTC-GQJ/BANER.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02228v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Quanjiang Guo, Yihong Dong, Ling Tian, Zhao Kang, Yu Zhang, Sijie Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compressing KV Cache for Long-Context LLM Inference with Inter-Layer Attention Similarity</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02252</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02252v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The increasing context window size in Large Language Models (LLMs), such as the GPT and LLaMA series, has improved their ability to tackle complex, long-text tasks, but at the cost of inference efficiency, particularly regarding memory and computational complexity. Existing methods, including selective token retention and window-based attention, improve efficiency but risk discarding important tokens needed for future text generation. In this paper, we propose an approach that enhances LLM efficiency without token loss by reducing the memory and computational load of less important tokens, rather than discarding them.We address two challenges: 1) investigating the distribution of important tokens in the context, discovering recent tokens are more important than distant tokens in context, and 2) optimizing resources for distant tokens by sharing attention scores across layers. The experiments show that our method saves $35\%$ KV cache without compromising the performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02252v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Da Ma, Lu Chen, Situo Zhang, Yuxun Miao, Su Zhu, Zhi Chen, Hongshen Xu, Hanqi Li, Shuai Fan, Lei Pan, Kai Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MediaSpin: Exploring Media Bias Through Fine-Grained Analysis of News Headlines</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02271</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02271v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this paper, we introduce the MediaSpin dataset aiming to help in the development of models that can detect different forms of media bias present in news headlines, developed through human-supervised and -validated Large Language Model (LLM) labeling of media bias. This corpus comprises 78,910 pairs of news headlines and annotations with explanations of the 13 distinct types of media bias categories assigned. We demonstrate the usefulness of our dataset for automated bias detection in news edits.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02271v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Preetika Verma, Kokil Jaidka</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehensive Evaluation of Large Language Models on Aspect-Based Sentiment Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02279</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02279v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recently, Large Language Models (LLMs) have garnered increasing attention in the field of natural language processing, revolutionizing numerous downstream tasks with powerful reasoning and generation abilities. For example, In-Context Learning (ICL) introduces a fine-tuning-free paradigm, allowing out-of-the-box LLMs to execute downstream tasks by analogy learning without any fine-tuning. Besides, in a fine-tuning-dependent paradigm where substantial training data exists, Parameter-Efficient Fine-Tuning (PEFT), as the cost-effective methods, enable LLMs to achieve excellent performance comparable to full fine-tuning.
  However, these fascinating techniques employed by LLMs have not been fully exploited in the ABSA field. Previous works probe LLMs in ABSA by merely using randomly selected input-output pairs as demonstrations in ICL, resulting in an incomplete and superficial evaluation. In this paper, we shed light on a comprehensive evaluation of LLMs in the ABSA field, involving 13 datasets, 8 ABSA subtasks, and 6 LLMs. Specifically, we design a unified task formulation to unify ``multiple LLMs for multiple ABSA subtasks in multiple paradigms.'' For the fine-tuning-dependent paradigm, we efficiently fine-tune LLMs using instruction-based multi-task learning. For the fine-tuning-free paradigm, we propose 3 demonstration selection strategies to stimulate the few-shot abilities of LLMs. Our extensive experiments demonstrate that LLMs achieve a new state-of-the-art performance compared to fine-tuned Small Language Models (SLMs) in the fine-tuning-dependent paradigm. More importantly, in the fine-tuning-free paradigm where SLMs are ineffective, LLMs with ICL still showcase impressive potential and even compete with fine-tuned SLMs on some ABSA subtasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02279v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Changzhi Zhou, Dandan Song, Yuhang Tian, Zhijing Wu, Hao Wang, Xinyu Zhang, Jun Yang, Ziyi Yang, Shuhao Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pay Attention to the Robustness of Chinese Minority Language Models! Syllable-level Textual Adversarial Attack on Tibetan Script</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02323</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02323v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The textual adversarial attack refers to an attack method in which the attacker adds imperceptible perturbations to the original texts by elaborate design so that the NLP (natural language processing) model produces false judgments. This method is also used to evaluate the robustness of NLP models. Currently, most of the research in this field focuses on English, and there is also a certain amount of research on Chinese. However, to the best of our knowledge, there is little research targeting Chinese minority languages. Textual adversarial attacks are a new challenge for the information processing of Chinese minority languages. In response to this situation, we propose a Tibetan syllable-level black-box textual adversarial attack called TSAttacker based on syllable cosine distance and scoring mechanism. And then, we conduct TSAttacker on six models generated by fine-tuning two PLMs (pre-trained language models) for three downstream tasks. The experiment results show that TSAttacker is effective and generates high-quality adversarial samples. In addition, the robustness of the involved models still has much room for improvement.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02323v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.18653/v1/2023.trustnlp-1.4</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Proceedings of the 3rd Workshop on Trustworthy Natural Language Processing (TrustNLP 2023)</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Xi Cao, Dolma Dawa, Nuo Qun, Trashi Nyima</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Granularity Tibetan Textual Adversarial Attack Method Based on Masked Language Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02343</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02343v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In social media, neural network models have been applied to hate speech detection, sentiment analysis, etc., but neural network models are susceptible to adversarial attacks. For instance, in a text classification task, the attacker elaborately introduces perturbations to the original texts that hardly alter the original semantics in order to trick the model into making different predictions. By studying textual adversarial attack methods, the robustness of language models can be evaluated and then improved. Currently, most of the research in this field focuses on English, and there is also a certain amount of research on Chinese. However, there is little research targeting Chinese minority languages. With the rapid development of artificial intelligence technology and the emergence of Chinese minority language models, textual adversarial attacks become a new challenge for the information processing of Chinese minority languages. In response to this situation, we propose a multi-granularity Tibetan textual adversarial attack method based on masked language models called TSTricker. We utilize the masked language models to generate candidate substitution syllables or words, adopt the scoring mechanism to determine the substitution order, and then conduct the attack method on several fine-tuned victim models. The experimental results show that TSTricker reduces the accuracy of the classification models by more than 28.70% and makes the classification models change the predictions of more than 90.60% of the samples, which has an evidently higher attack effect than the baseline method.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02343v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3589335.3652503</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Companion Proceedings of the ACM Web Conference 2024</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Xi Cao, Nuo Qun, Quzong Gesang, Yulei Zhu, Trashi Nyima</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Featuring Comments in Online Discussions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02369</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02369v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: A widespread moderation strategy by online news platforms is to feature what the platform deems high quality comments, usually called editor picks or featured comments. In this paper, we compare online discussions of news articles in which certain comments are featured, versus discussions in which no comments are featured. We measure the impact of featuring comments on the discussion, by estimating and comparing the quality of discussions from the perspective of the user base and the platform itself. Our analysis shows that the impact on discussion quality is limited. However, we do observe an increase in discussion activity after the first comments are featured by moderators, suggesting that the moderation strategy might be used to increase user engagement and to postpone the natural decline in user activity over time.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02369v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Cedric Waterschoot, Ernst van den Hemel, Antal van den Bosch</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TSCheater: Generating High-Quality Tibetan Adversarial Texts via Visual Similarity</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02371</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02371v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Language models based on deep neural networks are vulnerable to textual adversarial attacks. While rich-resource languages like English are receiving focused attention, Tibetan, a cross-border language, is gradually being studied due to its abundant ancient literature and critical language strategy. Currently, there are several Tibetan adversarial text generation methods, but they do not fully consider the textual features of Tibetan script and overestimate the quality of generated adversarial texts. To address this issue, we propose a novel Tibetan adversarial text generation method called TSCheater, which considers the characteristic of Tibetan encoding and the feature that visually similar syllables have similar semantics. This method can also be transferred to other abugidas, such as Devanagari script. We utilize a self-constructed Tibetan syllable visual similarity database called TSVSDB to generate substitution candidates and adopt a greedy algorithm-based scoring mechanism to determine substitution order. After that, we conduct the method on eight victim language models. Experimentally, TSCheater outperforms existing methods in attack effectiveness, perturbation magnitude, semantic similarity, visual similarity, and human acceptance. Finally, we construct the first Tibetan adversarial robustness evaluation benchmark called AdvTS, which is generated by existing methods and proofread by humans.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02371v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xi Cao, Quzong Gesang, Yuan Sun, Nuo Qun, Tashi Nyima</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GerPS-Compare: Comparing NER methods for legal norm analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02427</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02427v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We apply NER to a particular sub-genre of legal texts in German: the genre of legal norms regulating administrative processes in public service administration. The analysis of such texts involves identifying stretches of text that instantiate one of ten classes identified by public service administration professionals. We investigate and compare three methods for performing Named Entity Recognition (NER) to detect these classes: a Rule-based system, deep discriminative models, and a deep generative model. Our results show that Deep Discriminative models outperform both the Rule-based system as well as the Deep Generative model, the latter two roughly performing equally well, outperforming each other in different classes. The main cause for this somewhat surprising result is arguably the fact that the classes used in the analysis are semantically and syntactically heterogeneous, in contrast to the classes used in more standard NER tasks. Deep Discriminative models appear to be better equipped for dealing with this heterogenerity than both generic LLMs and human linguists designing rule-based NER systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02427v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sarah T. Bachinger, Christoph Unger, Robin Erd, Leila Feddoul, Clara Lachenmaier, Sina Zarrie{\ss}, Birgitta K\"onig-Ries</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gracefully Filtering Backdoor Samples for Generative Large Language Models without Retraining</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02454</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02454v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Backdoor attacks remain significant security threats to generative large language models (LLMs). Since generative LLMs output sequences of high-dimensional token logits instead of low-dimensional classification logits, most existing backdoor defense methods designed for discriminative models like BERT are ineffective for generative LLMs. Inspired by the observed differences in learning behavior between backdoor and clean mapping in the frequency space, we transform gradients of each training sample, directly influencing parameter updates, into the frequency space. Our findings reveal a distinct separation between the gradients of backdoor and clean samples in the frequency space. Based on this phenomenon, we propose Gradient Clustering in the Frequency Space for Backdoor Sample Filtering (GraCeFul), which leverages sample-wise gradients in the frequency space to effectively identify backdoor samples without requiring retraining LLMs. Experimental results show that GraCeFul outperforms baselines significantly. Notably, GraCeFul exhibits remarkable computational efficiency, achieving nearly 100% recall and F1 scores in identifying backdoor samples, reducing the average success rate of various backdoor attacks to 0% with negligible drops in clean accuracy across multiple free-style question answering datasets. Additionally, GraCeFul generalizes to Llama-2 and Vicuna. The codes are publicly available at https://github.com/ZrW00/GraceFul.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02454v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zongru Wu, Pengzhou Cheng, Lingyong Fang, Zhuosheng Zhang, Gongshen Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can ChatGPT capture swearing nuances? Evidence from translating Arabic oaths</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02466</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02466v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This study sets out to answer one major question: Can ChatGPT capture swearing nuances? It presents an empirical study on the ability of ChatGPT to translate Arabic oath expressions into English. 30 Arabic oath expressions were collected from the literature. These 30 oaths were first translated via ChatGPT and then analyzed and compared to the human translation in terms of types of gaps left unfulfilled by ChatGPT. Specifically, the gaps involved are: religious gap, cultural gap, both religious and cultural gaps, no gap, using non-oath particles, redundancy and noncapturing of Arabic script diacritics. It concludes that ChatGPT translation of oaths is still much unsatisfactory, unveiling the need of further developments of ChatGPT, and the inclusion of Arabic data on which ChatGPT should be trained including oath expressions, oath nuances, rituals, and practices.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02466v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mohammed Q. Shormani</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patent-CR: A Dataset for Patent Claim Revision</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02549</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02549v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper presents Patent-CR, the first dataset created for the patent claim revision task in English. It includes both initial patent applications rejected by patent examiners and the final granted versions. Unlike normal text revision tasks that predominantly focus on enhancing sentence quality, such as grammar correction and coherence improvement, patent claim revision aims at ensuring the claims meet stringent legal criteria. These criteria are beyond novelty and inventiveness, including clarity of scope, technical accuracy, language precision, and legal robustness. We assess various large language models (LLMs) through professional human evaluation, including general LLMs with different sizes and architectures, text revision models, and domain-specific models. Our results indicate that LLMs often bring ineffective edits that deviate from the target revisions. In addition, domain-specific models and the method of fine-tuning show promising results. Notably, GPT-4 outperforms other tested LLMs, but further revisions are still necessary to reach the examination standard. Furthermore, we demonstrate the inconsistency between automated and human evaluation results, suggesting that GPT-4-based automated evaluation has the highest correlation with human judgment. This dataset, along with our preliminary empirical research, offers invaluable insights for further exploration in patent claim revision.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02549v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lekang Jiang, Pascal A Scherz, Stephan Goetz</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Tokens in Retrieval Augmented Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02563</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02563v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) architectures have recently garnered significant attention for their ability to improve truth grounding and coherence in natural language processing tasks. However, the reliability of RAG systems in producing accurate answers diminishes as the volume of data they access increases. Even with smaller datasets, these systems occasionally fail to address simple queries. This issue arises from their dependence on state-of-the-art large language models (LLMs), which can introduce uncertainty into the system's outputs. In this work, I propose a novel Comparative RAG system that introduces an evaluator module to bridge the gap between probabilistic RAG systems and deterministically verifiable responses. The evaluator compares external recommendations with the retrieved document chunks, adding a decision-making layer that enhances the system's reliability. This approach ensures that the chunks retrieved are both semantically relevant and logically consistent with deterministic insights, thereby improving the accuracy and overall efficiency of RAG systems. This framework paves the way for more reliable and scalable question-answering applications in domains requiring high precision and verifiability.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02563v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Joel Suro</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nemotron-CC: Transforming Common Crawl into a Refined Long-Horizon Pretraining Dataset</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02595</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02595v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent English Common Crawl datasets like FineWeb-Edu and DCLM achieved significant benchmark gains via aggressive model-based filtering, but at the cost of removing 90% of data. This limits their suitability for long token horizon training, such as 15T tokens for Llama 3.1. In this paper, we show how to achieve better trade-offs between accuracy and data quantity by a combination of classifier ensembling, synthetic data rephrasing, and reduced reliance on heuristic filters. When training 8B parameter models for 1T tokens, using a high-quality subset of our data improves MMLU by 5.6 over DCLM, demonstrating the efficacy of our methods for boosting accuracies over a relatively short token horizon. Furthermore, our full 6.3T token dataset matches DCLM on MMLU, but contains four times more unique real tokens than DCLM. This unlocks state-of-the-art training over a long token horizon: an 8B parameter model trained for 15T tokens, of which 7.2T came from our dataset, is better than the Llama 3.1 8B model: +5 on MMLU, +3.1 on ARC-Challenge, and +0.5 on average across ten diverse tasks. The dataset is available at https://data.commoncrawl.org/contrib/Nemotron/Nemotron-CC/index.html</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02595v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dan Su, Kezhi Kong, Ying Lin, Joseph Jennings, Brandon Norick, Markus Kliegl, Mostofa Patwary, Mohammad Shoeybi, Bryan Catanzaro</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CEGI: Measuring the trade-off between efficiency and carbon emissions for SLMs and VLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02602</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02602v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper analyzes the performance of Small Language Models (SLMs) and Vision Language Models (VLMs) and evaluates the trade-off between model performance and carbon emissions across 4 essential tasks: Image Captioning, Visual Question Answering (VQA), Dialogue Summarization and Text-to-SQL conversion. Various SLMs and VLMs belonging to the Qwen and LLaMA architecture family are chosen and variants based on model size in terms of the number of parameters, quantization level and fine-tuning parameters are evaluated. The model variant's performance and carbon emissions are calculated. To quantify the trade-off between model performance and carbon emissions, we introduce a novel metric called CEGI (Carbon Efficient Gain Index). This metric represents the carbon emission per unit percentage gain per million trainable parameters . This metric provides a normalized measure to compare model's efficiency in terms of performance improvement relative to their environmental cost. The experiment's outcome demonstrates that fine-tuning SLMs and VLMs can achieve performance levels comparable to Large Language Models (LLMs) while producing significantly less carbon emissions. Our findings suggest that the marginal gains in accuracy from larger models do not justify the substantial increase in carbon emissions. Leveraging lower-bit quantization levels, the proposed metric further enhances energy efficiency without compromising performance. This study highlights balancing high performance and environmental sustainability. It offers a valuable metric for selecting models suitable for environmentally-friendly AI development.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02602v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Abhas Kumar, Kapil Pathak, Rajesh Kavuru, Prabhakar Srinivasan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interpretable Company Similarity with Sparse Autoencoders</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02605</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02605v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Determining company similarity is a vital task in finance, underpinning hedging, risk management, portfolio diversification, and more. Practitioners often rely on sector and industry classifications to gauge similarity, such as SIC-codes and GICS-codes, the former being used by the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), and the latter widely used by the investment community. Clustering embeddings of company descriptions has been proposed as a potential technique for determining company similarity, but the lack of interpretability in token embeddings poses a significant barrier to adoption in high-stakes contexts. Sparse Autoencoders have shown promise in enhancing the interpretability of Large Language Models by decomposing LLM activations into interpretable features. In this paper, we explore the use of SAE features in measuring company similarity and benchmark them against (1) SIC codes and (2) Major Group codes. We conclude that SAE features can reproduce and even surpass sector classifications in quantifying fundamental characteristics of companies, evaluated by the correlation of monthly returns, a proxy for similarity, and PnL from cointegration.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02605v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>econ.GN</category>
      <category>q-fin.EC</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Marco Molinari, Vladimir Tregubiak, Victor Shao, Abhimanyu Pandey, Mateusz Mikolajczak, Sebasti\~ao Kuznetsov Ryder Torres Pereira</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GLM-4-Voice: Towards Intelligent and Human-Like End-to-End Spoken Chatbot</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02612</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02612v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We introduce GLM-4-Voice, an intelligent and human-like end-to-end spoken chatbot. It supports both Chinese and English, engages in real-time voice conversations, and varies vocal nuances such as emotion, intonation, speech rate, and dialect according to user instructions. GLM-4-Voice uses an ultra-low bitrate (175bps), single-codebook speech tokenizer with 12.5Hz frame rate derived from an automatic speech recognition (ASR) model by incorporating a vector-quantized bottleneck into the encoder. To efficiently transfer knowledge from text to speech modalities, we synthesize speech-text interleaved data from existing text pre-training corpora using a text-to-token model. We continue pre-training from the pre-trained text language model GLM-4-9B with a combination of unsupervised speech data, interleaved speech-text data, and supervised speech-text data, scaling up to 1 trillion tokens, achieving state-of-the-art performance in both speech language modeling and spoken question answering. We then fine-tune the pre-trained model with high-quality conversational speech data, achieving superior performance compared to existing baselines in both conversational ability and speech quality. The open models can be accessed through https://github.com/THUDM/GLM-4-Voice and https://huggingface.co/THUDM/glm-4-voice-9b.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02612v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aohan Zeng, Zhengxiao Du, Mingdao Liu, Kedong Wang, Shengmin Jiang, Lei Zhao, Yuxiao Dong, Jie Tang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time-Reversal Provides Unsupervised Feedback to LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02626</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02626v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) are typically trained to predict in the forward direction of time. However, recent works have shown that prompting these models to look back and critique their own generations can produce useful feedback. Motivated by this, we explore the question of whether LLMs can be empowered to think (predict and score) backwards to provide unsupervised feedback that complements forward LLMs. Towards this, we introduce Time Reversed Language Models (TRLMs), which can score and generate queries when conditioned on responses, effectively functioning in the reverse direction of time. Further, to effectively infer in the response to query direction, we pre-train and fine-tune a language model (TRLM-Ba) in the reverse token order from scratch. We show empirically (and theoretically in a stylized setting) that time-reversed models can indeed complement forward model predictions when used to score the query given response for re-ranking multiple forward generations. We obtain up to 5\% improvement on the widely used AlpacaEval Leaderboard over the competent baseline of best-of-N re-ranking using self log-perplexity scores. We further show that TRLM scoring outperforms conventional forward scoring of response given query, resulting in significant gains in applications such as citation generation and passage retrieval. We next leverage the generative ability of TRLM to augment or provide unsupervised feedback to input safety filters of LLMs, demonstrating a drastic reduction in false negative rate with negligible impact on false positive rates against several attacks published on the popular JailbreakBench leaderboard.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02626v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Varun, Y., Madhavan, R., Addepalli, S., Suggala, A., Shanmugam, K., &amp; Jain, P. Time-Reversal Provides Unsupervised Feedback to LLMs. In The Thirty-Eighth Annual Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2024</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Yerram Varun, Rahul Madhavan, Sravanti Addepalli, Arun Suggala, Karthikeyan Shanmugam, Prateek Jain</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Words and Action: Modeling Linguistic Leadership in #BlackLivesMatter Communities</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02637</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02637v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this project, we describe a method of modeling semantic leadership across a set of communities associated with the #BlackLivesMatter movement, which has been informed by qualitative research on the structure of social media and Black Twitter in particular. We describe our bespoke approaches to time-binning, community clustering, and connecting communities over time, as well as our adaptation of state-of-the-art approaches to semantic change detection and semantic leadership induction. We find substantial evidence of the leadership role of BLM activists and progressives, as well as Black celebrities. We also find evidence of the sustained engagement of the conservative community with this discourse, suggesting an alternative explanation for how we arrived at the present moment, in which "anti-woke" and "anti-CRT" bills are being enacted nationwide.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02637v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dani Roytburg, Deborah Olorunisola, Sandeep Soni, Lauren Klein</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>QA-TOOLBOX: Conversational Question-Answering for process task guidance in manufacturing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02638</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02638v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this work we explore utilizing LLMs for data augmentation for manufacturing task guidance system. The dataset consists of representative samples of interactions with technicians working in an advanced manufacturing setting. The purpose of this work to explore the task, data augmentation for the supported tasks and evaluating the performance of the existing LLMs. We observe that that task is complex requiring understanding from procedure specification documents, actions and objects sequenced temporally. The dataset consists of 200,000+ question/answer pairs that refer to the spec document and are grounded in narrations and/or video demonstrations. We compared the performance of several popular open-sourced LLMs by developing a baseline using each LLM and then compared the responses in a reference-free setting using LLM-as-a-judge and compared the ratings with crowd-workers whilst validating the ratings with experts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02638v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ramesh Manuvinakurike, Elizabeth Watkins, Celal Savur, Anthony Rhodes, Sovan Biswas, Gesem Gudino Mejia, Richard Beckwith, Saurav Sahay, Giuseppe Raffa, Lama Nachman</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Probing the statistical properties of enriched co-occurrence networks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02664</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02664v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent studies have explored the addition of virtual edges to word co-occurrence networks using word embeddings to enhance graph representations, particularly for short texts. While these enriched networks have demonstrated some success, the impact of incorporating semantic edges into traditional co-occurrence networks remains uncertain. This study investigates two key statistical properties of text-based network models. First, we assess whether network metrics can effectively distinguish between meaningless and meaningful texts. Second, we analyze whether these metrics are more sensitive to syntactic or semantic aspects of the text. Our results show that incorporating virtual edges can have positive and negative effects, depending on the specific network metric. For instance, the informativeness of the average shortest path and closeness centrality improves in short texts, while the clustering coefficient's informativeness decreases as more virtual edges are added. Additionally, we found that including stopwords affects the statistical properties of enriched networks. Our results can serve as a guideline for determining which network metrics are most appropriate for specific applications, depending on the typical text size and the nature of the problem.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02664v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Diego R. Amancio, Jeaneth Machicao, Laura V. C. Quispe</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mind the Gap: Examining the Self-Improvement Capabilities of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02674</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02674v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Self-improvement is a mechanism in Large Language Model (LLM) pre-training, post-training and test-time inference. We explore a framework where the model verifies its own outputs, filters or reweights data based on this verification, and distills the filtered data. Despite several empirical successes, a fundamental understanding is still lacking. In this work, we initiate a comprehensive, modular and controlled study on LLM self-improvement. We provide a mathematical formulation for self-improvement, which is largely governed by a quantity which we formalize as the generation-verification gap. Through experiments with various model families and tasks, we discover a scaling phenomenon of self-improvement -- a variant of the generation-verification gap scales monotonically with the model pre-training flops. We also examine when self-improvement is possible, an iterative self-improvement procedure, and ways to improve its performance. Our findings not only advance understanding of LLM self-improvement with practical implications, but also open numerous avenues for future research into its capabilities and boundaries.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02674v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuda Song, Hanlin Zhang, Carson Eisenach, Sham Kakade, Dean Foster, Udaya Ghai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>T-REG: Preference Optimization with Token-Level Reward Regularization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02685</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02685v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Reinforcement learning from human feedback (RLHF) has been crucial in aligning large language models (LLMs) with human values. Traditionally, RLHF involves generating responses to a query and using a reward model to assign a reward to the entire response. However, this approach faces challenges due to its reliance on a single, sparse reward, which makes it challenging for the model to identify which parts of the sequence contribute most significantly to the final reward. Recent methods have attempted to address this limitation by introducing token-level rewards. However, these methods often rely on either a trained credit assignment model or AI annotators, raising concerns about the quality and reliability of the rewards. In this paper, we propose token-level reward regularization (T-REG), a novel approach that leverages both sequence-level and token-level rewards for preference optimization. Harnessing the self-refinement capabilities of LLMs, our method uses contrastive prompting to enable LLMs to self-generate token-level rewards. These self-generated rewards then act as reward regularization, guiding the model to more effectively distribute sequence-level rewards across tokens. This facilitates better token-level credit assignment and enhances alignment performance. Experiments on the instruction following benchmarks, including Alpaca Eval 2 and Arena-Hard, show that our method consistently outperforms baseline methods by up to 3.8% and 4.4%, respectively. We will release the code and models at https://github.com/wzhouad/T-REG.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02685v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenxuan Zhou, Shujian Zhang, Lingxiao Zhao, Tao Meng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scaling BERT Models for Turkish Automatic Punctuation and Capitalization Correction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02698</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02698v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper investigates the effectiveness of BERT based models for automated punctuation and capitalization corrections in Turkish texts across five distinct model sizes. The models are designated as Tiny, Mini, Small, Medium, and Base. The design and capabilities of each model are tailored to address the specific challenges of the Turkish language, with a focus on optimizing performance while minimizing computational overhead. The study presents a systematic comparison of the performance metrics precision, recall, and F1 score of each model, offering insights into their applicability in diverse operational contexts. The results demonstrate a significant improvement in text readability and accuracy as model size increases, with the Base model achieving the highest correction precision. This research provides a comprehensive guide for selecting the appropriate model size based on specific user needs and computational resources, establishing a framework for deploying these models in real-world applications to enhance the quality of written Turkish.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02698v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1109/ASYU62119.2024.10757039</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>2024 Innovations in Intelligent Systems and Applications Conference (ASYU) published in IEEE Xplore</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Abdulkader Saoud, Mahmut Alomeyr, Himmet Toprak Kesgin, Mehmet Fatih Amasyali</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Composition of Experts: A Modular Compound AI System Leveraging Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.01868</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.01868v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have achieved remarkable advancements, but their monolithic nature presents challenges in terms of scalability, cost, and customization. This paper introduces the Composition of Experts (CoE), a modular compound AI system leveraging multiple expert LLMs. CoE leverages a router to dynamically select the most appropriate expert for a given input, enabling efficient utilization of resources and improved performance. We formulate the general problem of training a CoE and discuss inherent complexities associated with it. We propose a two-step routing approach to address these complexities that first uses a router to classify the input into distinct categories followed by a category-to-expert mapping to obtain desired experts. CoE offers a flexible and cost-effective solution to build compound AI systems. Our empirical evaluation demonstrates the effectiveness of CoE in achieving superior performance with reduced computational overhead. Given that CoE comprises of many expert LLMs it has unique system requirements for cost-effective serving. We present an efficient implementation of CoE leveraging SambaNova SN40L RDUs unique three-tiered memory architecture. CoEs obtained using open weight LLMs Qwen/Qwen2-7B-Instruct, google/gemma-2-9b-it, google/gemma-2-27b-it, meta-llama/Llama-3.1-70B-Instruct and Qwen/Qwen2-72B-Instruct achieve a score of $59.4$ with merely $31$ billion average active parameters on Arena-Hard and a score of $9.06$ with $54$ billion average active parameters on MT-Bench.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.01868v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Swayambhoo Jain, Ravi Raju, Bo Li, Zoltan Csaki, Jonathan Li, Kaizhao Liang, Guoyao Feng, Urmish Thakkar, Anand Sampat, Raghu Prabhakar, Sumati Jairath</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Improvement in Language Models: The Sharpening Mechanism</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.01951</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.01951v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recent work in language modeling has raised the possibility of self-improvement, where a language models evaluates and refines its own generations to achieve higher performance without external feedback. It is impossible for this self-improvement to create information that is not already in the model, so why should we expect that this will lead to improved capabilities? We offer a new perspective on the capabilities of self-improvement through a lens we refer to as sharpening. Motivated by the observation that language models are often better at verifying response quality than they are at generating correct responses, we formalize self-improvement as using the model itself as a verifier during post-training in order to ``sharpen'' the model to one placing large mass on high-quality sequences, thereby amortizing the expensive inference-time computation of generating good sequences. We begin by introducing a new statistical framework for sharpening in which the learner aims to sharpen a pre-trained base policy via sample access, and establish fundamental limits. Then we analyze two natural families of self-improvement algorithms based on SFT and RLHF.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.01951v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Audrey Huang, Adam Block, Dylan J. Foster, Dhruv Rohatgi, Cyril Zhang, Max Simchowitz, Jordan T. Ash, Akshay Krishnamurthy</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free Process Rewards without Process Labels</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.01981</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.01981v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Different from its counterpart outcome reward models (ORMs), which evaluate the entire responses, a process reward model (PRM) scores a reasoning trajectory step by step, providing denser and more fine grained rewards. However, training a PRM requires labels annotated at every intermediate step, presenting significant challenges for both manual and automatic data collection. This paper aims to address this challenge. Both theoretically and empirically, we show that an \textit{implicit PRM} can be obtained at no additional cost, by simply training an ORM on the cheaper response-level labels. The only assumption is to parameterize the outcome reward as the log-likelihood ratios of the policy and reference models, which can be optimized regardless of the specific choice of loss objectives. In experiments, we instantiate our implicit PRMs with various objectives and evaluate their performance on MATH. We show that our implicit PRM outperforms a strong MCTS-based baseline \textit{\'a la} Math-Shepherd using less than $1/38$ of the training data. Its performance can be further improved with majority voting. We further find that scaling up instructions and responses benefits our implicit PRM, and the latter brings a larger gain. Particularly, we find that our implicit PRM, when instantiated with the cross-entropy (CE) loss, is more data-efficient and can keep improving generation models even when trained with only one response per instruction, the setup that suffers from extreme data scarcity and imbalance. Further, instructions should be relevant to downstream tasks while the diversity of responses does not bring gains. Surprisingly, training on extra Math-Shepherd step labels brings no further improvements to our implicit PRM trained on only outcome data. We hope that our work will encourage a rethinking of PRM training approaches and contribute to making training PRMs more accessible.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.01981v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lifan Yuan, Wendi Li, Huayu Chen, Ganqu Cui, Ning Ding, Kaiyan Zhang, Bowen Zhou, Zhiyuan Liu, Hao Peng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Data Snooping on Deep Learning Models for Locating Vulnerabilities in Lifted Code</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02048</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02048v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This study examines the impact of data snooping on neural networks for vulnerability detection in lifted code, building on previous research which used word2vec, and unidirectional and bidirectional transformer-based embeddings. The research specifically focuses on how model performance is affected when embedding models are trained on datasets, including samples also used for neural network training and validation. The results show that introducing data snooping did not significantly alter model performance, suggesting that data snooping had a minimal impact or that samples randomly dropped as part of the methodology contained hidden features critical to achieving optimal performance. In addition, the findings reinforce the conclusions of previous research, which found that models trained with GPT-2 embeddings consistently outperformed neural networks trained with other embeddings. The fact that this holds even when data snooping is introduced into the embedding model indicates GPT-2's robustness in representing complex code features, even under less-than-ideal conditions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02048v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gary A. McCully, John D. Hastings, Shengjie Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WSI-LLaVA: A Multimodal Large Language Model for Whole Slide Image</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02141</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02141v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recent advancements in computational pathology have produced patch-level Multi-modal Large Language Models (MLLMs), but these models are limited by their inability to analyze whole slide images (WSIs) comprehensively and their tendency to bypass crucial morphological features that pathologists rely on for diagnosis. To address these challenges, we first introduce WSI-Bench, a large-scale morphology-aware benchmark containing 180k VQA pairs from 9,850 WSIs across 30 cancer types, designed to evaluate MLLMs' understanding of morphological characteristics crucial for accurate diagnosis. Building upon this benchmark, we present WSI-LLaVA, a novel framework for gigapixel WSI understanding that employs a three-stage training approach: WSI-text alignment, feature space alignment, and task-specific instruction tuning. To better assess model performance in pathological contexts, we develop two specialized WSI metrics: WSI-Precision and WSI-Relevance. Experimental results demonstrate that WSI-LLaVA outperforms existing models across all capability dimensions, with a significant improvement in morphological analysis, establishing a clear correlation between morphological understanding and diagnostic accuracy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02141v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuci Liang, Xinheng Lyu, Meidan Ding, Wenting Chen, Jipeng Zhang, Yuexiang Ren, Xiangjian He, Song Wu, Sen Yang, Xiyue Wang, Xiaohan Xing, Linlin Shen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personalized Multimodal Large Language Models: A Survey</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02142</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02142v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) have become increasingly important due to their state-of-the-art performance and ability to integrate multiple data modalities, such as text, images, and audio, to perform complex tasks with high accuracy. This paper presents a comprehensive survey on personalized multimodal large language models, focusing on their architecture, training methods, and applications. We propose an intuitive taxonomy for categorizing the techniques used to personalize MLLMs to individual users, and discuss the techniques accordingly. Furthermore, we discuss how such techniques can be combined or adapted when appropriate, highlighting their advantages and underlying rationale. We also provide a succinct summary of personalization tasks investigated in existing research, along with the evaluation metrics commonly used. Additionally, we summarize the datasets that are useful for benchmarking personalized MLLMs. Finally, we outline critical open challenges. This survey aims to serve as a valuable resource for researchers and practitioners seeking to understand and advance the development of personalized multimodal large language models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02142v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junda Wu, Hanjia Lyu, Yu Xia, Zhehao Zhang, Joe Barrow, Ishita Kumar, Mehrnoosh Mirtaheri, Hongjie Chen, Ryan A. Rossi, Franck Dernoncourt, Tong Yu, Ruiyi Zhang, Jiuxiang Gu, Nesreen K. Ahmed, Yu Wang, Xiang Chen, Hanieh Deilamsalehy, Namyong Park, Sungchul Kim, Huanrui Yang, Subrata Mitra, Zhengmian Hu, Nedim Lipka, Dang Nguyen, Yue Zhao, Jiebo Luo, Julian McAuley</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jailbreak Defense in a Narrow Domain: Limitations of Existing Methods and a New Transcript-Classifier Approach</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02159</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02159v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Defending large language models against jailbreaks so that they never engage in a broadly-defined set of forbidden behaviors is an open problem. In this paper, we investigate the difficulty of jailbreak-defense when we only want to forbid a narrowly-defined set of behaviors. As a case study, we focus on preventing an LLM from helping a user make a bomb. We find that popular defenses such as safety training, adversarial training, and input/output classifiers are unable to fully solve this problem. In pursuit of a better solution, we develop a transcript-classifier defense which outperforms the baseline defenses we test. However, our classifier defense still fails in some circumstances, which highlights the difficulty of jailbreak-defense even in a narrow domain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02159v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tony T. Wang, John Hughes, Henry Sleight, Rylan Schaeffer, Rajashree Agrawal, Fazl Barez, Mrinank Sharma, Jesse Mu, Nir Shavit, Ethan Perez</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Theoretical Framework for Acoustic Neighbor Embeddings</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02164</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02164v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This paper provides a theoretical framework for interpreting acoustic neighbor embeddings, which are representations of the phonetic content of variable-width audio or text in a fixed-dimensional embedding space. A probabilistic interpretation of the distances between embeddings is proposed, based on a general quantitative definition of phonetic similarity between words. This provides us a framework for understanding and applying the embeddings in a principled manner. Theoretical and empirical evidence to support an approximation of uniform cluster-wise isotropy are shown, which allows us to reduce the distances to simple Euclidean distances. Four experiments that validate the framework and demonstrate how it can be applied to diverse problems are described. Nearest-neighbor search between audio and text embeddings can give isolated word classification accuracy that is identical to that of finite state transducers (FSTs) for vocabularies as large as 500k. Embedding distances give accuracy with 0.5% point difference compared to phone edit distances in out-of-vocabulary word recovery, as well as producing clustering hierarchies identical to those derived from human listening experiments in English dialect clustering. The theoretical framework also allows us to use the embeddings to predict the expected confusion of device wake-up words. All source code and pretrained models are provided.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02164v1</guid>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Woojay Jeon</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VISCO: Benchmarking Fine-Grained Critique and Correction Towards Self-Improvement in Visual Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02172</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02172v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The ability of large vision-language models (LVLMs) to critique and correct their reasoning is an essential building block towards their self-improvement. However, a systematic analysis of such capabilities in LVLMs is still lacking. We propose VISCO, the first benchmark to extensively analyze the fine-grained critique and correction capabilities of LVLMs. Compared to existing work that uses a single scalar value to critique the entire reasoning [4], VISCO features dense and fine-grained critique, requiring LVLMs to evaluate the correctness of each step in the chain-of-thought and provide natural language explanations to support their judgments. Extensive evaluation of 24 LVLMs demonstrates that human-written critiques significantly enhance the performance after correction, showcasing the potential of the self-improvement strategy. However, the model-generated critiques are less helpful and sometimes detrimental to the performance, suggesting that critique is the crucial bottleneck. We identified three common patterns in critique failures: failure to critique visual perception, reluctance to "say no", and exaggerated assumption of error propagation. To address these issues, we propose an effective LookBack strategy that revisits the image to verify each piece of information in the initial reasoning. LookBack significantly improves critique and correction performance by up to 13.5%.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02172v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xueqing Wu, Yuheng Ding, Bingxuan Li, Pan Lu, Da Yin, Kai-Wei Chang, Nanyun Peng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DataLab: A Unifed Platform for LLM-Powered Business Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02205</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02205v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Business intelligence (BI) transforms large volumes of data within modern organizations into actionable insights for informed decision-making. Recently, large language model (LLM)-based agents have streamlined the BI workflow by automatically performing task planning, reasoning, and actions in executable environments based on natural language (NL) queries. However, existing approaches primarily focus on individual BI tasks such as NL2SQL and NL2VIS. The fragmentation of tasks across different data roles and tools lead to inefficiencies and potential errors due to the iterative and collaborative nature of BI. In this paper, we introduce DataLab, a unified BI platform that integrates a one-stop LLM-based agent framework with an augmented computational notebook interface. DataLab supports a wide range of BI tasks for different data roles by seamlessly combining LLM assistance with user customization within a single environment. To achieve this unification, we design a domain knowledge incorporation module tailored for enterprise-specific BI tasks, an inter-agent communication mechanism to facilitate information sharing across the BI workflow, and a cell-based context management strategy to enhance context utilization efficiency in BI notebooks. Extensive experiments demonstrate that DataLab achieves state-of-the-art performance on various BI tasks across popular research benchmarks. Moreover, DataLab maintains high effectiveness and efficiency on real-world datasets from Tencent, achieving up to a 58.58% increase in accuracy and a 61.65% reduction in token cost on enterprise-specific BI tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02205v1</guid>
      <category>cs.DB</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Luoxuan Weng, Yinghao Tang, Yingchaojie Feng, Zhuo Chang, Peng Chen, Ruiqin Chen, Haozhe Feng, Chen Hou, Danqing Huang, Yang Li, Huaming Rao, Haonan Wang, Canshi Wei, Xiaofeng Yang, Yuhui Zhang, Yifeng Zheng, Xiuqi Huang, Minfeng Zhu, Yuxin Ma, Bin Cui, Wei Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characterizing Information Shared by Participants to Coding Challenges: The Case of Advent of Code</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02290</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02290v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Advent of Code (AoC from now on) is a popular coding challenge requiring to solve programming puzzles for a variety of skill sets and levels. AoC follows the advent calendar, therefore it is an annual challenge that lasts for 25 days. AoC participants usually post their solutions on social networks and discuss them online. These challenges are interesting to study since they could highlight the adoption of new tools, the evolution of the developer community, or the technological requirements of well-known companies. For these reasons, we first create a dataset of the 2019-2021 AoC editions containing the discussion threads made on the subreddit {\tt /r/adventofcode}. Then, we propose a model based on stream graphs to best study this context, where we represent its most important actors through time: participants, comments, and programming languages. Thanks to our model, we investigate user participation, adoption of new programming languages during a challenge and between two of them, and resiliency of programming languages based on a Stack Overflow survey. We find that the top-used programming languages are almost the same in the three years, pointing out their importance. Moreover, participants tend to keep the same programming language for the whole challenge, while the ones attending two AoCs usually change it in the next one. Finally, we observe interesting results about the programming languages that are ``Popular'' or ``Loved'' according to the Stack Overflow survey. Firstly, these are the ones adopted for the longest time in an AoC edition, thanks to which users have a high chance of reaching the end of the challenge. Secondly, they are the most chosen when a participant decides to change programming language during the same challenge.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02290v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Francesco Cauteruccio, Enrico Corradini, Luca Virgili</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Multimodal Agents for Accurate Phishing Detection with Enhanced Token Optimization and Cost Reduction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02301</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02301v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: With the rise of sophisticated phishing attacks, there is a growing need for effective and economical detection solutions. This paper explores the use of large multimodal agents, specifically Gemini 1.5 Flash and GPT-4o mini, to analyze both URLs and webpage screenshots via APIs, thus avoiding the complexities of training and maintaining AI systems. Our findings indicate that integrating these two data types substantially enhances detection performance over using either type alone. However, API usage incurs costs per query that depend on the number of input and output tokens. To address this, we propose a two-tiered agentic approach: initially, one agent assesses the URL, and if inconclusive, a second agent evaluates both the URL and the screenshot. This method not only maintains robust detection performance but also significantly reduces API costs by minimizing unnecessary multi-input queries. Cost analysis shows that with the agentic approach, GPT-4o mini can process about 4.2 times as many websites per $100 compared to the multimodal approach (107,440 vs. 25,626), and Gemini 1.5 Flash can process about 2.6 times more websites (2,232,142 vs. 862,068). These findings underscore the significant economic benefits of the agentic approach over the multimodal method, providing a viable solution for organizations aiming to leverage advanced AI for phishing detection while controlling expenses.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02301v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fouad Trad, Ali Chehab</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ScImage: How Good Are Multimodal Large Language Models at Scientific Text-to-Image Generation?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02368</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02368v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Multimodal large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated impressive capabilities in generating high-quality images from textual instructions. However, their performance in generating scientific images--a critical application for accelerating scientific progress--remains underexplored. In this work, we address this gap by introducing ScImage, a benchmark designed to evaluate the multimodal capabilities of LLMs in generating scientific images from textual descriptions. ScImage assesses three key dimensions of understanding: spatial, numeric, and attribute comprehension, as well as their combinations, focusing on the relationships between scientific objects (e.g., squares, circles). We evaluate five models, GPT-4o, Llama, AutomaTikZ, Dall-E, and StableDiffusion, using two modes of output generation: code-based outputs (Python, TikZ) and direct raster image generation. Additionally, we examine four different input languages: English, German, Farsi, and Chinese. Our evaluation, conducted with 11 scientists across three criteria (correctness, relevance, and scientific accuracy), reveals that while GPT-4o produces outputs of decent quality for simpler prompts involving individual dimensions such as spatial, numeric, or attribute understanding in isolation, all models face challenges in this task, especially for more complex prompts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02368v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Leixin Zhang, Steffen Eger, Yinjie Cheng, Weihe Zhai, Jonas Belouadi, Christoph Leiter, Simone Paolo Ponzetto, Fahimeh Moafian, Zhixue Zhao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Four Guiding Principles for Modeling Causal Domain Knowledge: A Case Study on Brainstorming Approaches for Urban Blight Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02400</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02400v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Urban blight is a problem of high interest for planning and policy making. Researchers frequently propose theories about the relationships between urban blight indicators, focusing on relationships reflecting causality. In this paper, we improve on the integration of domain knowledge in the analysis of urban blight by introducing four rules for effective modeling of causal domain knowledge. The findings of this study reveal significant deviation from causal modeling guidelines by investigating cognitive maps developed for urban blight analysis. These findings provide valuable insights that will inform future work on urban blight, ultimately enhancing our understanding of urban blight complex interactions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02400v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CE</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Houssam Razouk, Michael Leitner, Roman Kern</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial Expert Intelligence through PAC-reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02441</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02441v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Artificial Expert Intelligence (AEI) seeks to transcend the limitations of both Artificial General Intelligence (AGI) and narrow AI by integrating domain-specific expertise with critical, precise reasoning capabilities akin to those of top human experts. Existing AI systems often excel at predefined tasks but struggle with adaptability and precision in novel problem-solving. To overcome this, AEI introduces a framework for ``Probably Approximately Correct (PAC) Reasoning". This paradigm provides robust theoretical guarantees for reliably decomposing complex problems, with a practical mechanism for controlling reasoning precision. In reference to the division of human thought into System 1 for intuitive thinking and System 2 for reflective reasoning~\citep{tversky1974judgment}, we refer to this new type of reasoning as System 3 for precise reasoning, inspired by the rigor of the scientific method. AEI thus establishes a foundation for error-bounded, inference-time learning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02441v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shai Shalev-Shwartz, Amnon Shashua, Gal Beniamini, Yoav Levine, Or Sharir, Noam Wies, Ido Ben-Shaul, Tomer Nussbaum, Shir Granot Peled</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DP-2Stage: Adapting Language Models as Differentially Private Tabular Data Generators</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02467</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02467v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Generating tabular data under differential privacy (DP) protection ensures theoretical privacy guarantees but poses challenges for training machine learning models, primarily due to the need to capture complex structures under noisy supervision signals. Recently, pre-trained Large Language Models (LLMs) -- even those at the scale of GPT-2 -- have demonstrated great potential in synthesizing tabular data. However, their applications under DP constraints remain largely unexplored. In this work, we address this gap by applying DP techniques to the generation of synthetic tabular data. Our findings shows that LLMs face difficulties in generating coherent text when fine-tuned with DP, as privacy budgets are inefficiently allocated to non-private elements like table structures. To overcome this, we propose \ours, a two-stage fine-tuning framework for differentially private tabular data generation. The first stage involves non-private fine-tuning on a pseudo dataset, followed by DP fine-tuning on a private dataset. Our empirical results show that this approach improves performance across various settings and metrics compared to directly fine-tuned LLMs in DP contexts. We release our code and setup at https://github.com/tejuafonja/DP-2Stage.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02467v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tejumade Afonja, Hui-Po Wang, Raouf Kerkouche, Mario Fritz</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLMForecaster: Improving Seasonal Event Forecasts with Unstructured Textual Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02525</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02525v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Modern time-series forecasting models often fail to make full use of rich unstructured information about the time series themselves. This lack of proper conditioning can lead to obvious model failures; for example, models may be unaware of the details of a particular product, and hence fail to anticipate seasonal surges in customer demand in the lead up to major exogenous events like holidays for clearly relevant products. To address this shortcoming, this paper introduces a novel forecast post-processor -- which we call LLMForecaster -- that fine-tunes large language models (LLMs) to incorporate unstructured semantic and contextual information and historical data to improve the forecasts from an existing demand forecasting pipeline. In an industry-scale retail application, we demonstrate that our technique yields statistically significantly forecast improvements across several sets of products subject to holiday-driven demand surges.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02525v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hanyu Zhang, Chuck Arvin, Dmitry Efimov, Michael W. Mahoney, Dominique Perrault-Joncas, Shankar Ramasubramanian, Andrew Gordon Wilson, Malcolm Wolff</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AV-Odyssey Bench: Can Your Multimodal LLMs Really Understand Audio-Visual Information?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02611</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02611v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recently, multimodal large language models (MLLMs), such as GPT-4o, Gemini 1.5 Pro, and Reka Core, have expanded their capabilities to include vision and audio modalities. While these models demonstrate impressive performance across a wide range of audio-visual applications, our proposed DeafTest reveals that MLLMs often struggle with simple tasks humans find trivial: 1) determining which of two sounds is louder, and 2) determining which of two sounds has a higher pitch. Motivated by these observations, we introduce AV-Odyssey Bench, a comprehensive audio-visual benchmark designed to assess whether those MLLMs can truly understand the audio-visual information. This benchmark encompasses 4,555 carefully crafted problems, each incorporating text, visual, and audio components. To successfully infer answers, models must effectively leverage clues from both visual and audio inputs. To ensure precise and objective evaluation of MLLM responses, we have structured the questions as multiple-choice, eliminating the need for human evaluation or LLM-assisted assessment. We benchmark a series of closed-source and open-source models and summarize the observations. By revealing the limitations of current models, we aim to provide useful insight for future dataset collection and model development.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02611v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kaixiong Gong, Kaituo Feng, Bohao Li, Yibing Wang, Mofan Cheng, Shijia Yang, Jiaming Han, Benyou Wang, Yutong Bai, Zhuoran Yang, Xiangyu Yue</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sibyl: Empowering Empathetic Dialogue Generation in Large Language Models via Sensible and Visionary Commonsense Inference</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.15316</link>
      <description>arXiv:2311.15316v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recently, there has been a heightened interest in building chatbots based on Large Language Models (LLMs) to emulate human-like qualities in multi-turn conversations. Despite having access to commonsense knowledge to better understand the psychological aspects and causality of dialogue context, even these powerful LLMs struggle to achieve the goals of empathy and emotional support. Current commonsense knowledge derived from dialogue contexts is inherently limited and often fails to adequately anticipate the future course of a dialogue. This lack of foresight can mislead LLMs and hinder their ability to provide effective support. In response to this challenge, we present an innovative framework named Sensible and Visionary Commonsense Knowledge (Sibyl). Designed to concentrate on the immediately succeeding dialogue, this paradigm equips LLMs with the capability to uncover the implicit requirements of the conversation, aiming to elicit more empathetic responses. Experimental results demonstrate that incorporating our paradigm for acquiring commonsense knowledge into LLMs comprehensively enhances the quality of their responses.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2311.15316v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lanrui Wang, Jiangnan Li, Chenxu Yang, Zheng Lin, Hongyin Tang, Huan Liu, Yanan Cao, Jingang Wang, Weiping Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CultureLLM: Incorporating Cultural Differences into Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.10946</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.10946v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are reported to be partial to certain cultures owing to the training data dominance from the English corpora. Since multilingual cultural data are often expensive to collect, existing efforts handle this by prompt engineering or culture-specific pre-training. However, they might overlook the knowledge deficiency of low-resource culture and require extensive computing resources. In this paper, we propose CultureLLM, a cost-effective solution to incorporate cultural differences into LLMs. CultureLLM adopts World Value Survey (WVS) as seed data and generates semantically equivalent training data via the proposed semantic data augmentation. Using only 50 seed samples from WVS with augmented data, we fine-tune culture-specific LLMs and one unified model (CultureLLM-One) for 9 cultures covering rich and low-resource languages. Extensive experiments on 60 culture-related datasets demonstrate that CultureLLM significantly outperforms various counterparts such as GPT-3.5 (by 8.1%) and Gemini Pro (by 9.5%) with comparable performance to GPT-4 or even better. Our human study shows that the generated samples are semantically equivalent to the original samples, providing an effective solution for LLMs augmentation. Code is released at https://github.com/Scarelette/CultureLLM.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.10946v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Cheng Li, Mengzhou Chen, Jindong Wang, Sunayana Sitaram, Xing Xie</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EVOR: Evolving Retrieval for Code Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12317</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.12317v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recently the retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) has been successfully applied in code generation. However, existing pipelines for retrieval-augmented code generation (RACG) employ static knowledge bases with a single source, limiting the adaptation capabilities of Large Language Models (LLMs) to domains they have insufficient knowledge of. In this work, we develop a novel pipeline, EVOR, that employs the synchronous evolution of both queries and diverse knowledge bases. On two realistic settings where the external knowledge is required to solve code generation tasks, we compile four new datasets associated with frequently updated libraries and long-tail programming languages, named EVOR-BENCH. Extensive experiments demonstrate that EVOR achieves two to four times of execution accuracy compared to other methods such as Reflexion (Shinn et al., 2024), DocPrompting (Zhou et al., 2023), etc. We demonstrate that EVOR is flexible and can be easily combined with them to achieve further improvement. Further analysis reveals that EVOR benefits from the synchronous evolution of queries and documents and the diverse information sources in the knowledge base. We hope that our studies will inspire more insights into the design of advanced RACG pipelines in future research. Our model, code, and data are available at https://arks-codegen.github.io.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.12317v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hongjin Su, Shuyang Jiang, Yuhang Lai, Haoyuan Wu, Boao Shi, Che Liu, Qian Liu, Tao Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Language Models for Data Annotation and Synthesis: A Survey</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.13446</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.13446v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Data annotation and synthesis generally refers to the labeling or generating of raw data with relevant information, which could be used for improving the efficacy of machine learning models. The process, however, is labor-intensive and costly. The emergence of advanced Large Language Models (LLMs), exemplified by GPT-4, presents an unprecedented opportunity to automate the complicated process of data annotation and synthesis. While existing surveys have extensively covered LLM architecture, training, and general applications, we uniquely focus on their specific utility for data annotation. This survey contributes to three core aspects: LLM-Based Annotation Generation, LLM-Generated Annotations Assessment, and LLM-Generated Annotations Utilization. Furthermore, this survey includes an in-depth taxonomy of data types that LLMs can annotate, a comprehensive review of learning strategies for models utilizing LLM-generated annotations, and a detailed discussion of the primary challenges and limitations associated with using LLMs for data annotation and synthesis. Serving as a key guide, this survey aims to assist researchers and practitioners in exploring the potential of the latest LLMs for data annotation, thereby fostering future advancements in this critical field.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.13446v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhen Tan, Dawei Li, Song Wang, Alimohammad Beigi, Bohan Jiang, Amrita Bhattacharjee, Mansooreh Karami, Jundong Li, Lu Cheng, Huan Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AutoGuide: Automated Generation and Selection of Context-Aware Guidelines for Large Language Model Agents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.08978</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.08978v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advances in large language models (LLMs) have empowered AI agents capable of performing various sequential decision-making tasks. However, effectively guiding LLMs to perform well in unfamiliar domains like web navigation, where they lack sufficient knowledge, has proven to be difficult with the demonstration-based in-context learning paradigm. In this paper, we introduce a novel framework, called AutoGuide, which addresses this limitation by automatically generating context-aware guidelines from offline experiences. Importantly, each context-aware guideline is expressed in concise natural language and follows a conditional structure, clearly describing the context where it is applicable. As a result, our guidelines facilitate the provision of relevant knowledge for the agent's current decision-making process, overcoming the limitations of the conventional demonstration-based learning paradigm. Our evaluation demonstrates that AutoGuide significantly outperforms competitive baselines in complex benchmark domains, including real-world web navigation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.08978v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yao Fu, Dong-Ki Kim, Jaekyeom Kim, Sungryull Sohn, Lajanugen Logeswaran, Kyunghoon Bae, Honglak Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Text Clustering with Large Language Model Embeddings</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.15112</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.15112v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Text clustering is an important method for organising the increasing volume of digital content, aiding in the structuring and discovery of hidden patterns in uncategorised data. The effectiveness of text clustering largely depends on the selection of textual embeddings and clustering algorithms. This study argues that recent advancements in large language models (LLMs) have the potential to enhance this task. The research investigates how different textual embeddings, particularly those utilised in LLMs, and various clustering algorithms influence the clustering of text datasets. A series of experiments were conducted to evaluate the impact of embeddings on clustering results, the role of dimensionality reduction through summarisation, and the adjustment of model size. The findings indicate that LLM embeddings are superior at capturing subtleties in structured language. OpenAI's GPT-3.5 Turbo model yields better results in three out of five clustering metrics across most tested datasets. Most LLM embeddings show improvements in cluster purity and provide a more informative silhouette score, reflecting a refined structural understanding of text data compared to traditional methods. Among the more lightweight models, BERT demonstrates leading performance. Additionally, it was observed that increasing model dimensionality and employing summarisation techniques do not consistently enhance clustering efficiency, suggesting that these strategies require careful consideration for practical application. These results highlight a complex balance between the need for refined text representation and computational feasibility in text clustering applications. This study extends traditional text clustering frameworks by integrating embeddings from LLMs, offering improved methodologies and suggesting new avenues for future research in various types of textual analysis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.15112v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1016/j.ijcce.2024.09.005</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>International Journal of Cognitive Computing in Engineering, 6, pp. 100-108, 2025</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Alina Petukhova, Jo\~ao P. Matos-Carvalho, Nuno Fachada</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The PRISM Alignment Dataset: What Participatory, Representative and Individualised Human Feedback Reveals About the Subjective and Multicultural Alignment of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.16019</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.16019v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Human feedback is central to the alignment of Large Language Models (LLMs). However, open questions remain about methods (how), domains (where), people (who) and objectives (to what end) of feedback processes. To navigate these questions, we introduce PRISM, a dataset that maps the sociodemographics and stated preferences of 1,500 diverse participants from 75 countries, to their contextual preferences and fine-grained feedback in 8,011 live conversations with 21 LLMs. With PRISM, we contribute (i) wider geographic and demographic participation in feedback; (ii) census-representative samples for two countries (UK, US); and (iii) individualised ratings that link to detailed participant profiles, permitting personalisation and attribution of sample artefacts. We target subjective and multicultural perspectives on value-laden and controversial issues, where we expect interpersonal and cross-cultural disagreement. We use PRISM in three case studies to demonstrate the need for careful consideration of which humans provide what alignment data.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.16019v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>The Thirty-eight Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems Datasets and Benchmarks Track (2024)</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Hannah Rose Kirk, Alexander Whitefield, Paul R\"ottger, Andrew Bean, Katerina Margatina, Juan Ciro, Rafael Mosquera, Max Bartolo, Adina Williams, He He, Bertie Vidgen, Scott A. Hale</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Distributed Representations for Multi-Level Lexical Semantics: A Research Proposal</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.00751</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.00751v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Modern neural networks (NNs), trained on extensive raw sentence data, construct distributed representations by compressing individual words into dense, continuous, high-dimensional vectors. These representations are expected to capture multi-level lexical meaning. In this thesis, our objective is to examine the efficacy of distributed representations from NNs in encoding lexical meaning. Initially, we identify and formalize three levels of lexical semantics: \textit{local}, \textit{global}, and \textit{mixed} levels. Then, for each level, we evaluate language models by collecting or constructing multilingual datasets, leveraging various language models, and employing linguistic analysis theories. This thesis builds a bridge between computational models and lexical semantics, aiming to complement each other.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.00751v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhu Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samba: Simple Hybrid State Space Models for Efficient Unlimited Context Language Modeling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07522</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.07522v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Efficiently modeling sequences with infinite context length has long been a challenging problem. Previous approaches have either suffered from quadratic computational complexity or limited extrapolation ability in length generalization. In this work, we present Samba, a simple hybrid architecture that layer-wise combines Mamba, a selective State Space Model (SSM), with Sliding Window Attention (SWA). Samba selectively compresses a given sequence into recurrent hidden states while still maintaining the ability to precisely recall recent memories with the attention mechanism. We scale Samba up to 3.8B parameters with 3.2T training tokens and demonstrate that it significantly outperforms state-of-the-art models across a variety of benchmarks. Pretrained on sequences of 4K length, Samba shows improved perplexity in context lengths of up to 1M in zero-shot. When finetuned on 4K-length sequences, Samba efficiently extrapolates to a 256K context length with perfect memory recall on the Passkey Retrieval task, and exhibits superior retrieval extrapolation on the challenging Phonebook task compared to full-attention models. As a linear-time sequence model, Samba achieves a 3.73x higher throughput compared to Transformers with grouped-query attention for user prompts of 128K length, and a 3.64x speedup when generating 64K tokens with unlimited streaming. Our code for training on open source data is publicly available at https://github.com/microsoft/Samba.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.07522v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Liliang Ren, Yang Liu, Yadong Lu, Yelong Shen, Chen Liang, Weizhu Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discovering influential text using convolutional neural networks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10086</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10086v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Experimental methods for estimating the impacts of text on human evaluation have been widely used in the social sciences. However, researchers in experimental settings are usually limited to testing a small number of pre-specified text treatments. While efforts to mine unstructured texts for features that causally affect outcomes have been ongoing in recent years, these models have primarily focused on the topics or specific words of text, which may not always be the mechanism of the effect. We connect these efforts with NLP interpretability techniques and present a method for flexibly discovering clusters of similar text phrases that are predictive of human reactions to texts using convolutional neural networks. When used in an experimental setting, this method can identify text treatments and their effects under certain assumptions. We apply the method to two datasets. The first enables direct validation of the model's ability to detect phrases known to cause the outcome. The second demonstrates its ability to flexibly discover text treatments with varying textual structures. In both cases, the model learns a greater variety of text treatments compared to benchmark methods, and these text features quantitatively meet or exceed the ability of benchmark methods to predict the outcome.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10086v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>stat.ME</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Megan Ayers, Luke Sanford, Margaret Roberts, Eddie Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Understanding Jailbreak Attacks in LLMs: A Representation Space Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10794</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10794v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are susceptible to a type of attack known as jailbreaking, which misleads LLMs to output harmful contents. Although there are diverse jailbreak attack strategies, there is no unified understanding on why some methods succeed and others fail. This paper explores the behavior of harmful and harmless prompts in the LLM's representation space to investigate the intrinsic properties of successful jailbreak attacks. We hypothesize that successful attacks share some similar properties: They are effective in moving the representation of the harmful prompt towards the direction to the harmless prompts. We leverage hidden representations into the objective of existing jailbreak attacks to move the attacks along the acceptance direction, and conduct experiments to validate the above hypothesis using the proposed objective. We hope this study provides new insights into understanding how LLMs understand harmfulness information.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10794v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuping Lin, Pengfei He, Han Xu, Yue Xing, Makoto Yamada, Hui Liu, Jiliang Tang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing Story: Case Studies of Generative AI's Use in Journalism</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.13706</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.13706v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Journalists are among the many users of large language models (LLMs). To better understand the journalist-AI interactions, we conduct a study of LLM usage by two news agencies through browsing the WildChat dataset, identifying candidate interactions, and verifying them by matching to online published articles. Our analysis uncovers instances where journalists provide sensitive material such as confidential correspondence with sources or articles from other agencies to the LLM as stimuli and prompt it to generate articles, and publish these machine-generated articles with limited intervention (median output-publication ROUGE-L of 0.62). Based on our findings, we call for further research into what constitutes responsible use of AI, and the establishment of clear guidelines and best practices on using LLMs in a journalistic context.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.13706v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Natalie Grace Brigham, Chongjiu Gao, Tadayoshi Kohno, Franziska Roesner, Niloofar Mireshghallah</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AdaZeta: Adaptive Zeroth-Order Tensor-Train Adaption for Memory-Efficient Large Language Models Fine-Tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.18060</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.18060v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Fine-tuning large language models (LLMs) has achieved remarkable performance across various natural language processing tasks, yet it demands more and more memory as model sizes keep growing. To address this issue, the recently proposed Memory-efficient Zeroth-order (MeZO) methods attempt to fine-tune LLMs using only forward passes, thereby avoiding the need for a backpropagation graph. However, significant performance drops and a high risk of divergence have limited their widespread adoption. In this paper, we propose the Adaptive Zeroth-order Tensor-Train Adaption (AdaZeta) framework, specifically designed to improve the performance and convergence of the ZO methods. To enhance dimension-dependent ZO estimation accuracy, we introduce a fast-forward, low-parameter tensorized adapter. To tackle the frequently observed divergence issue in large-scale ZO fine-tuning tasks, we propose an adaptive query number schedule that guarantees convergence. Detailed theoretical analysis and extensive experimental results on Roberta-Large and Llama-2-7B models substantiate the efficacy of our AdaZeta framework in terms of accuracy, memory efficiency, and convergence speed.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.18060v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yifan Yang, Kai Zhen, Ershad Banijamal, Athanasios Mouchtaris, Zheng Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stress-Testing Long-Context Language Models with Lifelong ICL and Task Haystack</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.16695</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.16695v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We introduce Lifelong ICL, a problem setting that challenges long-context language models (LMs) to learn a sequence of language tasks through in-context learning (ICL). We further introduce Task Haystack, an evaluation suite dedicated to assessing and diagnosing how long-context LMs utilizes contexts in Lifelong ICL. When given a task instruction and test inputs, long-context LMs are expected to leverage the relevant demonstrations in the Lifelong ICL prompt, avoid distraction and interference from other tasks, and achieve test accuracies that are not significantly worse than those of the Single-task ICL baseline.
  Task Haystack draws inspiration from the widely-adopted "needle-in-a-haystack" (NIAH) evaluation, but presents distinct new challenges. It requires models (1) to utilize the contexts at a deeper level, rather than resorting to simple copying and pasting; (2) to navigate through long streams of evolving topics and tasks, proxying the complexities and dynamism of contexts in real-world scenarios. Additionally, Task Haystack inherits the controllability of NIAH, providing model developers with tools and visualizations to identify model vulnerabilities effectively.
  We benchmark 14 long-context LMs using Task Haystack, finding that frontier models like GPT-4o still struggle with the setting, failing on 15% of cases on average. Most open-weight models further lack behind by a large margin, with failure rates reaching up to 61%. In our controlled analysis, we identify factors such as distraction and recency bias as contributors to these failure cases. Further, performance declines when task instructions are paraphrased at test time or when ICL demonstrations are repeated excessively, raising concerns about the robustness, instruction understanding, and true context utilization of long-context LMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.16695v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoyue Xu, Qinyuan Ye, Xiang Ren</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GSIFN: A Graph-Structured and Interlaced-Masked Multimodal Transformer-based Fusion Network for Multimodal Sentiment Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14809</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14809v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Multimodal Sentiment Analysis (MSA) leverages multiple data modals to analyze human sentiment. Existing MSA models generally employ cutting-edge multimodal fusion and representation learning-based methods to promote MSA capability. However, there are two key challenges: (i) in existing multimodal fusion methods, the decoupling of modal combinations and tremendous parameter redundancy, lead to insufficient fusion performance and efficiency; (ii) a challenging trade-off exists between representation capability and computational overhead in unimodal feature extractors and encoders. Our proposed GSIFN incorporates two main components to solve these problems: (i) a graph-structured and interlaced-masked multimodal Transformer. It adopts the Interlaced Mask mechanism to construct robust multimodal graph embedding, achieve all-modal-in-one Transformer-based fusion, and greatly reduce the computational overhead; (ii) a self-supervised learning framework with low computational overhead and high performance, which utilizes a parallelized LSTM with matrix memory to enhance non-verbal modal features for unimodal label generation. Evaluated on the MSA datasets CMU-MOSI, CMU-MOSEI, and CH-SIMS, GSIFN demonstrates superior performance with significantly lower computational overhead compared with previous state-of-the-art models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14809v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yijie Jin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Salient Information Prompting to Steer Content in Prompt-based Abstractive Summarization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.02741</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.02741v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) can generate fluent summaries across domains using prompting techniques, reducing the need to train models for summarization applications. However, crafting effective prompts that guide LLMs to generate summaries with the appropriate level of detail and writing style remains a challenge. In this paper, we explore the use of salient information extracted from the source document to enhance summarization prompts. We show that adding keyphrases in prompts can improve ROUGE F1 and recall, making the generated summaries more similar to the reference and more complete. The number of keyphrases can control the precision-recall trade-off. Furthermore, our analysis reveals that incorporating phrase-level salient information is superior to word- or sentence-level. However, the impact on hallucination is not universally positive across LLMs. To conduct this analysis, we introduce Keyphrase Signal Extractor (SigExt), a lightweight model that can be finetuned to extract salient keyphrases. By using SigExt, we achieve consistent ROUGE improvements across datasets and open-weight and proprietary LLMs without any LLM customization. Our findings provide insights into leveraging salient information in building prompt-based summarization systems. We release our code at \url{https://github.com/amazon-science/SigExt}</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.02741v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lei Xu, Mohammed Asad Karim, Saket Dingliwal, Aparna Elangovan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VibeCheck: Discover and Quantify Qualitative Differences in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.12851</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.12851v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) often exhibit subtle yet distinctive characteristics in their outputs that users intuitively recognize, but struggle to quantify. These "vibes" -- such as tone, formatting, or writing style -- influence user preferences, yet traditional evaluations focus primarily on the singular axis of correctness. We introduce VibeCheck, a system for automatically comparing a pair of LLMs by discovering identifying traits of a model (vibes) that are well-defined, differentiating, and user-aligned. VibeCheck iteratively discovers vibes from model outputs and then utilizes a panel of LLM judges to quantitatively measure the utility of each vibe. We validate that the vibes generated by VibeCheck align with those found in human discovery and run VibeCheck on pairwise preference data from real-world user conversations with Llama-3-70b vs GPT-4. VibeCheck reveals that Llama has a friendly, funny, and somewhat controversial vibe. These vibes predict model identity with 80% accuracy and human preference with 61% accuracy. Lastly, we run VibeCheck on a variety of models and tasks including summarization, math, and captioning to provide insight into differences in model behavior. VibeCheck discovers vibes like Command X prefers to add concrete intros and conclusions when summarizing in comparison to TNGL, Llama-405b often overexplains its thought process on math problems compared to GPT-4o, and GPT-4 prefers to focus on the mood and emotions of the scene when captioning compared to Gemini-1.5-Flash. Code can be found at https://github.com/lisadunlap/VibeCheck</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.12851v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lisa Dunlap, Krishna Mandal, Trevor Darrell, Jacob Steinhardt, Joseph E Gonzalez</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Isolated Conversations to Hierarchical Schemas: Dynamic Tree Memory Representation for LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.14052</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.14052v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advancements in large language models have significantly improved their context windows, yet challenges in effective long-term memory management remain. We introduce MemTree, an algorithm that leverages a dynamic, tree-structured memory representation to optimize the organization, retrieval, and integration of information, akin to human cognitive schemas. MemTree organizes memory hierarchically, with each node encapsulating aggregated textual content, corresponding semantic embeddings, and varying abstraction levels across the tree's depths. Our algorithm dynamically adapts this memory structure by computing and comparing semantic embeddings of new and existing information to enrich the model's context-awareness. This approach allows MemTree to handle complex reasoning and extended interactions more effectively than traditional memory augmentation methods, which often rely on flat lookup tables. Evaluations on benchmarks for multi-turn dialogue understanding and document question answering show that MemTree significantly enhances performance in scenarios that demand structured memory management.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.14052v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alireza Rezazadeh, Zichao Li, Wei Wei, Yujia Bao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Value Residual Learning For Alleviating Attention Concentration In Transformers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.17897</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.17897v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Transformers can capture long-range dependencies using self-attention, allowing tokens to attend to all others directly. However, stacking multiple attention layers leads to attention concentration. One natural way to address this issue is to use cross-layer attention, allowing information from earlier layers to be directly accessible to later layers. However, this approach is computationally expensive. To address this problem, we propose Transformer with residual value (ResFormer) which approximates cross-layer attention through adding a residual connection from the values of the the first layer to all subsequent layers. Based on this method, one variant is the Transformer with single layer value (SVFormer), where all layers share the same value embedding from first layer. Comprehensive empirical evidence demonstrates ResFormer achieves equivalent validation loss with 10.4% fewer model parameters and 13.6% less training data compared to Transformer, while maintaining similar memory usage and computational cost. Besides, SVFormer reduces KV cache size by nearly half with only a small performance penalty and can be integrated with other KV-efficient methods, yielding further reductions in KV cache, with performance influenced by sequence length and cumulative learning rate. Further visualization results suggest that Resformer and SVFormer alleviate attention concentration in deeper layers through avoiding value-state drains and enhance representation across most layers.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.17897v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhanchao Zhou, Tianyi Wu, Zhiyun Jiang, Zhenzhong Lan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Nobel Prize Literature with Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.18142</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.18142v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This study examines the capabilities of advanced Large Language Models (LLMs), particularly the o1 model, in the context of literary analysis. The outputs of these models are compared directly to those produced by graduate-level human participants. By focusing on two Nobel Prize-winning short stories, 'Nine Chapters' by Han Kang, the 2024 laureate, and 'Friendship' by Jon Fosse, the 2023 laureate, the research explores the extent to which AI can engage with complex literary elements such as thematic analysis, intertextuality, cultural and historical contexts, linguistic and structural innovations, and character development. Given the Nobel Prize's prestige and its emphasis on cultural, historical, and linguistic richness, applying LLMs to these works provides a deeper understanding of both human and AI approaches to interpretation. The study uses qualitative and quantitative evaluations of coherence, creativity, and fidelity to the text, revealing the strengths and limitations of AI in tasks typically reserved for human expertise. While LLMs demonstrate strong analytical capabilities, particularly in structured tasks, they often fall short in emotional nuance and coherence, areas where human interpretation excels. This research underscores the potential for human-AI collaboration in the humanities, opening new opportunities in literary studies and beyond.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.18142v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhenyuan Yang, Zhengliang Liu, Jing Zhang, Cen Lu, Jiaxin Tai, Tianyang Zhong, Yiwei Li, Siyan Zhao, Teng Yao, Qing Liu, Jinlin Yang, Qixin Liu, Zhaowei Li, Kexin Wang, Longjun Ma, Dajiang Zhu, Yudan Ren, Bao Ge, Wei Zhang, Ning Qiang, Tuo Zhang, Tianming Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WebRL: Training LLM Web Agents via Self-Evolving Online Curriculum Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.02337</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.02337v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have shown remarkable potential as autonomous agents, particularly in web-based tasks. However, existing LLM web agents heavily rely on expensive proprietary LLM APIs, while open LLMs lack the necessary decision-making capabilities. This paper introduces WebRL, a self-evolving online curriculum reinforcement learning framework designed to train high-performance web agents using open LLMs. WebRL addresses three key challenges in building LLM web agents, including the scarcity of training tasks, sparse feedback signals, and policy distribution drift in online learning. Specifically, WebRL incorporates 1) a self-evolving curriculum that generates new tasks from unsuccessful attempts, 2) a robust outcome-supervised reward model (ORM), and 3) adaptive reinforcement learning strategies to ensure consistent improvements. We apply WebRL to transform open Llama-3.1 and GLM-4 models into proficient web agents. On WebArena-Lite, WebRL improves the success rate of Llama-3.1-8B from 4.8% to 42.4%, and from 6.1% to 43% for GLM-4-9B. These open models significantly surpass the performance of GPT-4-Turbo (17.6%) and GPT-4o (13.9%) and outperform previous state-of-the-art web agents trained on open LLMs (AutoWebGLM, 18.2%). Our findings demonstrate WebRL's effectiveness in bridging the gap between open and proprietary LLM-based web agents, paving the way for more accessible and powerful autonomous web interaction systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.02337v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zehan Qi, Xiao Liu, Iat Long Iong, Hanyu Lai, Xueqiao Sun, Wenyi Zhao, Yu Yang, Xinyue Yang, Jiadai Sun, Shuntian Yao, Tianjie Zhang, Wei Xu, Jie Tang, Yuxiao Dong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trustful LLMs: Customizing and Grounding Text Generation with Knowledge Bases and Dual Decoders</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.07870</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.07870v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Although people are impressed by the content generation skills of large language models, the use of LLMs, such as ChatGPT, is limited by the domain grounding of the content. The correctness and groundedness of the generated content need to be based on a verified context, such as results from Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG). One important issue when adapting LLMs to a customized domain is that the generated responses are often incomplete, or the additions are not verified and may even be hallucinated. Prior studies on hallucination detection have focused on evaluation metrics, which are not easily adaptable to dynamic domains and can be vulnerable to attacks like jail-breaking. In this work, we propose 1) a post-processing algorithm that leverages knowledge triplets in RAG context to correct hallucinations and 2) a dual-decoder model that fuses RAG context to guide the generation process.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.07870v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>EMNLP CustomNLP4U 2024</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Xiaofeng Zhu, Jaya Krishna Mandivarapu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Text Classification (HTC) vs. eXtreme Multilabel Classification (XML): Two Sides of the Same Medal</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.13687</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.13687v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Assigning a subset of labels from a fixed pool of labels to a given input text is a text classification problem with many real-world applications, such as in recommender systems. Two separate research streams address this issue. Hierarchical Text Classification (HTC) focuses on datasets with smaller label pools of hundreds of entries, accompanied by a semantic label hierarchy. In contrast, eXtreme Multi-Label Text Classification (XML) considers very large label pools with up to millions of entries, in which the labels are not arranged in any particular manner. However, in XML, a common approach is to construct an artificial hierarchy without any semantic information before or during the training process. Here, we investigate how state-of-the-art models from one domain perform when trained and tested on datasets from the other domain. The HBGL and HGLCR models from the HTC domain are trained and tested on the datasets Wiki10-31K, AmazonCat-13K, and Amazon-670K from the XML domain. On the other side, the XML models CascadeXML and XR-Transformer are trained and tested on the datasets Web of Science, The New York Times Annotated Corpus, and RCV1-V2 from the HTC domain. HTC models, on the other hand, are not equipped to handle the size of XML datasets and achieve poor transfer results. The code and numerous files that are needed to reproduce our results can be obtained from https://github.com/FloHauss/XMC_HTC</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.13687v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nerijus Bertalis, Paul Granse, Ferhat G\"ul, Florian Hauss, Leon Menkel, David Sch\"uler, Tom Speier, Lukas Galke, Ansgar Scherp</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BayLing 2: A Multilingual Large Language Model with Efficient Language Alignment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.16300</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.16300v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs), with their powerful generative capabilities and vast knowledge, empower various tasks in everyday life. However, these abilities are primarily concentrated in high-resource languages, leaving low-resource languages with weaker generative capabilities and relatively limited knowledge. Enhancing the multilingual capabilities of LLMs is therefore crucial for serving over 100 linguistic communities worldwide. An intuitive approach to enhance the multilingual capabilities would be to construct instruction data for various languages, but constructing instruction data for over 100 languages is prohibitively costly. In this paper, we introduce BayLing 2, which efficiently transfers generative capabilities and knowledge from high-resource languages to low-resource languages through language alignment. To achieve this, we constructed a dataset of 3.2 million instructions, comprising high-resource language instructions (Chinese and English) and cross-lingual instructions for 100+ languages and performed instruction tuning based on the dataset to facilitate the capability transfer between languages. Using Llama as the foundation model, we developed BayLing-2-7B, BayLing-2-13B, and BayLing-2-8B, and conducted a comprehensive evaluation of BayLing. For multilingual translation across 100+ languages, BayLing shows superior performance compared to open-source models of similar scale. For multilingual knowledge and understanding benchmarks, BayLing achieves significant improvements across over 20 low-resource languages, demonstrating its capability of effective knowledge transfer from high-resource to low-resource languages. Furthermore, results on English benchmarks indicate that BayLing maintains high performance in highresource languages while enhancing the performance in low-resource languages. Demo, homepage, code and models of BayLing are available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.16300v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shaolei Zhang, Kehao Zhang, Qingkai Fang, Shoutao Guo, Yan Zhou, Xiaodong Liu, Yang Feng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AtomR: Atomic Operator-Empowered Large Language Models for Heterogeneous Knowledge Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.16495</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.16495v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advancements in large language models (LLMs) have led to significant improvements in various natural language processing tasks, but it is still challenging for LLMs to perform knowledge-intensive complex question answering due to LLMs' inefficacy in reasoning planning and the hallucination problem. A typical solution is to employ retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) coupled with chain-of-thought (CoT) reasoning, which decomposes complex questions into chain-like sub-questions and applies iterative RAG at each sub-question. However, prior works exhibit sub-optimal reasoning planning and overlook dynamic knowledge retrieval from heterogeneous sources. In this paper, we propose AtomR, a novel heterogeneous knowledge reasoning framework that conducts multi-source reasoning at the atomic level. Drawing inspiration from the graph modeling of knowledge, AtomR leverages large language models (LLMs) to decompose complex questions into combinations of three atomic knowledge operators, significantly enhancing the reasoning process at both the planning and execution stages. We also introduce BlendQA, a novel evaluation benchmark tailored to assess complex heterogeneous knowledge reasoning. Experiments show that AtomR significantly outperforms state-of-the-art baselines across three single-source and two multi-source reasoning benchmarks, with notable performance gains of 9.4% on 2WikiMultihop and 9.5% on BlendQA.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.16495v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Amy Xin, Jinxin Liu, Zijun Yao, Zhicheng Lee, Shulin Cao, Lei Hou, Juanzi Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>N\"ushuRescue: Revitalization of the endangered N\"ushu Language with AI</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.00218</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.00218v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The preservation and revitalization of endangered and extinct languages is a meaningful endeavor, conserving cultural heritage while enriching fields like linguistics and anthropology. However, these languages are typically low-resource, making their reconstruction labor-intensive and costly. This challenge is exemplified by N\"ushu, a rare script historically used by Yao women in China for self-expression within a patriarchal society. To address this challenge, we introduce N\"ushuRescue, an AI-driven framework designed to train large language models (LLMs) on endangered languages with minimal data. N\"ushuRescue automates evaluation and expands target corpora to accelerate linguistic revitalization. As a foundational component, we developed NCGold, a 500-sentence N\"ushu-Chinese parallel corpus, the first publicly available dataset of its kind. Leveraging GPT-4-Turbo, with no prior exposure to N\"ushu and only 35 short examples from NCGold, N\"ushuRescue achieved 48.69\% translation accuracy on 50 withheld sentences and generated NCSilver, a set of 98 newly translated modern Chinese sentences of varying lengths. A sample of both NCGold and NCSilver is included in the Supplementary Materials. Additionally, we developed FastText-based and Seq2Seq models to further support research on N\"ushu. N\"ushuRescue provides a versatile and scalable tool for the revitalization of endangered languages, minimizing the need for extensive human input.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.00218v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ivory Yang, Weicheng Ma, Soroush Vosoughi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing Speech Language Models by Scaling Supervised Fine-Tuning with Over 60,000 Hours of Synthetic Speech Dialogue Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.01078</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.01078v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The GPT-4o represents a significant milestone in enabling real-time interaction with large language models (LLMs) through speech, its remarkable low latency and high fluency not only capture attention but also stimulate research interest in the field. This real-time speech interaction is particularly valuable in scenarios requiring rapid feedback and immediate responses, dramatically enhancing user experience. However, there is a notable lack of research focused on real-time large speech language models, particularly for Chinese. In this work, we present KE-Omni, a seamless large speech language model built upon Ke-SpeechChat, a large-scale high-quality synthetic speech interaction dataset consisting of 7 million Chinese and English conversations, featuring 42,002 speakers, and totaling over 60,000 hours, This contributes significantly to the advancement of research and development in this field. The demos can be accessed at \url{https://huggingface.co/spaces/KE-Team/KE-Omni}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.01078v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shuaijiang Zhao, Tingwei Guo, Bajian Xiang, Tongtang Wan, Qiang Niu, Wei Zou, Xiangang Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yi-Lightning Technical Report</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.01253</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.01253v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This technical report presents Yi-Lightning, our latest flagship large language model (LLM). It achieves exceptional performance, ranking 6th overall on Chatbot Arena, with particularly strong results (2nd to 4th place) in specialized categories including Chinese, Math, Coding, and Hard Prompts. Yi-Lightning leverages an enhanced Mixture-of-Experts (MoE) architecture, featuring advanced expert segmentation and routing mechanisms coupled with optimized KV-caching techniques. Our development process encompasses comprehensive pre-training, supervised fine-tuning (SFT), and reinforcement learning from human feedback (RLHF), where we devise deliberate strategies for multi-stage training, synthetic data construction, and reward modeling. Furthermore, we implement RAISE (Responsible AI Safety Engine), a four-component framework to address safety issues across pre-training, post-training, and serving phases. Empowered by our scalable super-computing infrastructure, all these innovations substantially reduce training, deployment and inference costs while maintaining high-performance standards. With further evaluations on public academic benchmarks, Yi-Lightning demonstrates competitive performance against top-tier LLMs, while we observe a notable disparity between traditional, static benchmark results and real-world, dynamic human preferences. This observation prompts a critical reassessment of conventional benchmarks' utility in guiding the development of more intelligent and powerful AI systems for practical applications. Yi-Lightning is now available through our developer platform at https://platform.lingyiwanwu.com.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.01253v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>01. AI,  :, Alan Wake, Albert Wang, Bei Chen, C. X. Lv, Chao Li, Chengen Huang, Chenglin Cai, Chujie Zheng, Daniel Cooper, Ethan Dai, Fan Zhou, Feng Hu, Heng Ji, Howard Qiu, Jiangcheng Zhu, Jun Tian, Katherine Su, Lihuan Zhang, Liying Li, Ming Song, Mou Li, Peng Liu, Qichen Hu, Shawn Wang, Shijun Zhou, Shiyong Li, Tianhang Zhu, Wen Xie, Xiang He, Xiaobo Chen, Xiaohui Hu, Xiaoyi Ren, Xinyao Niu, Yanpeng Li, Yongke Zhao, Yongzhen Luo, Yuchi Xu, Yuxuan Sha, Zhaodong Yan, Zhiyuan Liu, Zirui Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Cross-Lingual Audio Abuse Detection in Low-Resource Settings with Few-Shot Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.01408</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.01408v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Online abusive content detection, particularly in low-resource settings and within the audio modality, remains underexplored. We investigate the potential of pre-trained audio representations for detecting abusive language in low-resource languages, in this case, in Indian languages using Few Shot Learning (FSL). Leveraging powerful representations from models such as Wav2Vec and Whisper, we explore cross-lingual abuse detection using the ADIMA dataset with FSL. Our approach integrates these representations within the Model-Agnostic Meta-Learning (MAML) framework to classify abusive language in 10 languages. We experiment with various shot sizes (50-200) evaluating the impact of limited data on performance. Additionally, a feature visualization study was conducted to better understand model behaviour. This study highlights the generalization ability of pre-trained models in low-resource scenarios and offers valuable insights into detecting abusive language in multilingual contexts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.01408v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aditya Narayan Sankaran, Reza Farahbakhsh, Noel Crespi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impromptu Cybercrime Euphemism Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.01413</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.01413v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Detecting euphemisms is essential for content security on various social media platforms, but existing methods designed for detecting euphemisms are ineffective in impromptu euphemisms. In this work, we make a first attempt to an exploration of impromptu euphemism detection and introduce the Impromptu Cybercrime Euphemisms Detection (ICED) dataset. Moreover, we propose a detection framework tailored to this problem, which employs context augmentation modeling and multi-round iterative training. Our detection framework mainly consists of a coarse-grained and a fine-grained classification model. The coarse-grained classification model removes most of the harmless content in the corpus to be detected. The fine-grained model, impromptu euphemisms detector, integrates context augmentation and multi-round iterations training to better predicts the actual meaning of a masked token. In addition, we leverage ChatGPT to evaluate the mode's capability. Experimental results demonstrate that our approach achieves a remarkable 76-fold improvement compared to the previous state-of-the-art euphemism detector.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.01413v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiang Li, Yucheng Zhou, Laiping Zhao, Jing Li, Fangming Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enabling Efficient Attack Investigation via Human-in-the-Loop Security Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2211.05403</link>
      <description>arXiv:2211.05403v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: System auditing is a vital technique for collecting system call events as system provenance and investigating complex multi-step attacks such as Advanced Persistent Threats. However, existing attack investigation methods struggle to uncover long attack sequences due to the massive volume of system provenance data and their inability to focus on attack-relevant parts. In this paper, we present Raptor, a defense system that enables human analysts to effectively analyze large-scale system provenance to reveal multi-step attack sequences. Raptor introduces an expressive domain-specific language, ProvQL, that offers essential primitives for various types of attack analyses (e.g., attack pattern search, attack dependency tracking) with user-defined constraints, enabling analysts to focus on attack-relevant parts and iteratively sift through the large provenance data. Moreover, Raptor provides an optimized execution engine for efficient language execution. Our extensive evaluations on a wide range of attack scenarios demonstrate the practical effectiveness of Raptor in facilitating timely attack investigation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2211.05403v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.DB</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xinyu Yang, Haoyuan Liu, Saimon Amanuel Tsegai, Peng Gao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Filtered Direct Preference Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.13846</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.13846v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Reinforcement learning from human feedback (RLHF) plays a crucial role in aligning language models with human preferences. While the significance of dataset quality is generally recognized, explicit investigations into its impact within the RLHF framework, to our knowledge, have been limited. This paper addresses the issue of text quality within the preference dataset by focusing on direct preference optimization (DPO), an increasingly adopted reward-model-free RLHF method. We confirm that text quality significantly influences the performance of models optimized with DPO more than those optimized with reward-model-based RLHF. Building on this new insight, we propose an extension of DPO, termed filtered direct preference optimization (fDPO). fDPO uses a trained reward model to monitor the quality of texts within the preference dataset during DPO training. Samples of lower quality are discarded based on comparisons with texts generated by the model being optimized, resulting in a more accurate dataset. Experimental results demonstrate that fDPO enhances the final model performance. Our code is available at https://github.com/CyberAgentAILab/filtered-dpo.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.13846v4</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tetsuro Morimura, Mitsuki Sakamoto, Yuu Jinnai, Kenshi Abe, Kaito Ariu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intelligent Go-Explore: Standing on the Shoulders of Giant Foundation Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.15143</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.15143v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Go-Explore is a powerful family of algorithms designed to solve hard-exploration problems built on the principle of archiving discovered states, and iteratively returning to and exploring from the most promising states. This approach has led to superhuman performance across a wide variety of challenging problems including Atari games and robotic control, but requires manually designing heuristics to guide exploration (i.e., determine which states to save and explore from, and what actions to consider next), which is time-consuming and infeasible in general. To resolve this, we propose Intelligent Go-Explore (IGE) which greatly extends the scope of the original Go-Explore by replacing these handcrafted heuristics with the intelligence and internalized human notions of interestingness captured by giant pretrained foundation models (FMs). This provides IGE with a human-like ability to instinctively identify how interesting or promising any new state is (e.g., discovering new objects, locations, or behaviors), even in complex environments where heuristics are hard to define. Moreover, IGE offers the exciting opportunity to recognize and capitalize on serendipitous discoveries-states encountered during exploration that are valuable in terms of exploration, yet where what makes them interesting was not anticipated by the human user. We evaluate our algorithm on a diverse range of language and vision-based tasks that require search and exploration. Across these tasks, IGE strongly exceeds classic reinforcement learning and graph search baselines, and also succeeds where prior state-of-the-art FM agents like Reflexion completely fail. Overall, Intelligent Go-Explore combines the tremendous strengths of FMs and the powerful Go-Explore algorithm, opening up a new frontier of research into creating more generally capable agents with impressive exploration capabilities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.15143v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Cong Lu, Shengran Hu, Jeff Clune</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Language Model-empowered multimodal strain sensory system for shape recognition, monitoring, and human interaction of tensegrity</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10264</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10264v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: A tensegrity-based system is a promising approach for dynamic exploration of uneven and unpredictable environments, particularly, space exploration. However, implementing such systems presents challenges in terms of intelligent aspects: state recognition, wireless monitoring, human interaction, and smart analyzing and advising function. Here, we introduce a 6-strut tensegrity integrate with 24 multimodal strain sensors by leveraging both deep learning model and large language models to realize smart tensegrity. Using conductive flexible tendons assisted by long short-term memory model, the tensegrity achieves the self-shape reconstruction without extern sensors. Through integrating the flask server and gpt-3.5-turbo model, the tensegrity autonomously enables to send data to iPhone for wireless monitoring and provides data analysis, explanation, prediction, and suggestions to human for decision making. Finally, human interaction system of the tensegrity helps human obtain necessary information of tensegrity from the aspect of human language. Overall, this intelligent tensegrity-based system with self-sensing tendons showcases potential for future exploration, making it a versatile tool for real-world applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10264v2</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1109/LRA.2024.3469811</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Zebing Mao, Ryota Kobayashi, Hiroyuki Nabae, Koichi Suzumori</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying Language Model Forgetting with Low-rank Example Associations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.14026</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.14026v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large Language models (LLMs) suffer from forgetting of upstream data when fine-tuned. Despite efforts on mitigating forgetting, few have investigated whether, and how forgotten upstream examples are dependent on and associated with newly learned tasks. Insights on such associations enable efficient and targeted mitigation of forgetting. In this paper, we empirically analyze forgetting (measured in log-perplexity increase) that occurs in $N$ upstream examples of language modeling or instruction-tuning after fine-tuning LLMs on one of $M$ new tasks, visualized in $M\times N$ matrices. We demonstrate that the matrices display simple low-rank patterns, often well-approximated with multiplicative scalar effects of upstream examples and newly learned tasks. We also examine fine-grained associations with visualization and statistics. Leveraging the low-rank nature of the associations, we predict forgetting of upstream examples when fine-tuning on unseen tasks with matrix completion over the empirical associations. This enables fast identification of most forgotten examples without expensive inference on the entire upstream data. The approach, despite simplicity, outperforms prior approaches that learn semantic relationships of learned tasks and upstream examples with LMs for predicting forgetting. We demonstrate the practical utility of our analysis by showing statistically significantly reduced forgetting as we upweight predicted examples for replay at fine-tuning. Project page: https://inklab.usc.edu/lm-forgetting-prediction/</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.14026v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xisen Jin, Xiang Ren</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Warmup-Stable-Decay Learning Rates: A River Valley Loss Landscape Perspective</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.05192</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.05192v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Training language models currently requires pre-determining a fixed compute budget because the typical cosine learning rate schedule depends on the total number of steps. In contrast, the Warmup-Stable-Decay (WSD) schedule uses a constant learning rate to produce a main branch of iterates that can in principle continue indefinitely without a pre-specified compute budget. Then, given any compute budget, one can branch out from the main branch at a proper time with a rapidly decaying learning rate to produce a strong model. Empirically, WSD generates a non-traditional loss curve: the loss remains elevated during the stable phase but sharply declines during the decay phase. Towards explaining this phenomenon, we conjecture that pretraining loss exhibits a river valley landscape, which resembles a deep valley with a river at its bottom. Under this assumption, we show that during the stable phase, the iterate undergoes large oscillations due to the high learning rate, yet it progresses swiftly along the river. During the decay phase, the rapidly dropping learning rate minimizes the iterate's oscillations, moving it closer to the river and revealing true optimization progress. Therefore, the sustained high learning rate phase and fast decaying phase are responsible for progress in the river and the mountain directions respectively, and are both critical. Our analysis predicts phenomenons consistent with empirical observations and shows that this landscape can emerge from pretraining on a simple bi-gram dataset. Inspired by the theory, we introduce WSD-S, a variant of WSD that reuses previous checkpoints' decay phases and keeps only one main branch, where we resume from a decayed checkpoint. WSD-S empirically outperforms WSD and Cyclic-Cosine in obtaining multiple language model checkpoints across various compute budgets in a single run for parameters scaling from 0.1B to 1.2B.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.05192v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kaiyue Wen, Zhiyuan Li, Jason Wang, David Hall, Percy Liang, Tengyu Ma</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proactive Agent: Shifting LLM Agents from Reactive Responses to Active Assistance</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.12361</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.12361v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Agents powered by large language models have shown remarkable abilities in solving complex tasks. However, most agent systems remain reactive, limiting their effectiveness in scenarios requiring foresight and autonomous decision-making. In this paper, we tackle the challenge of developing proactive agents capable of anticipating and initiating tasks without explicit human instructions. We propose a novel data-driven approach for this problem. Firstly, we collect real-world human activities to generate proactive task predictions. These predictions are then labeled by human annotators as either accepted or rejected. The labeled data is used to train a reward model that simulates human judgment and serves as an automatic evaluator of the proactiveness of LLM agents. Building on this, we develop a comprehensive data generation pipeline to create a diverse dataset, ProactiveBench, containing 6,790 events. Finally, we demonstrate that fine-tuning models with the proposed ProactiveBench can significantly elicit the proactiveness of LLM agents. Experimental results show that our fine-tuned model achieves an F1-Score of 66.47% in proactively offering assistance, outperforming all open-source and close-source models. These results highlight the potential of our method in creating more proactive and effective agent systems, paving the way for future advancements in human-agent collaboration.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.12361v3</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yaxi Lu, Shenzhi Yang, Cheng Qian, Guirong Chen, Qinyu Luo, Yesai Wu, Huadong Wang, Xin Cong, Zhong Zhang, Yankai Lin, Weiwen Liu, Yasheng Wang, Zhiyuan Liu, Fangming Liu, Maosong Sun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Model Editing for LLMs4Code: How Far are We?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.06638</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.06638v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large Language Models for Code (LLMs4Code) have been found to exhibit outstanding performance in the software engineering domain, especially the remarkable performance in coding tasks. However, even the most advanced LLMs4Code can inevitably contain incorrect or outdated code knowledge. Due to the high cost of training LLMs4Code, it is impractical to re-train the models for fixing these problematic code knowledge. Model editing is a new technical field for effectively and efficiently correcting erroneous knowledge in LLMs, where various model editing techniques and benchmarks have been proposed recently. Despite that, a comprehensive study that thoroughly compares and analyzes the performance of the state-of-the-art model editing techniques for adapting the knowledge within LLMs4Code across various code-related tasks is notably absent. To bridge this gap, we perform the first systematic study on applying state-of-the-art model editing approaches to repair the inaccuracy of LLMs4Code. To that end, we introduce a benchmark named CLMEEval, which consists of two datasets, i.e., CoNaLa-Edit (CNLE) with 21K+ code generation samples and CodeSearchNet-Edit (CSNE) with 16K+ code summarization samples. With the help of CLMEEval, we evaluate six advanced model editing techniques on three LLMs4Code: CodeLlama (7B), CodeQwen1.5 (7B), and Stable-Code (3B). Our findings include that the external memorization-based GRACE approach achieves the best knowledge editing effectiveness and specificity (the editing does not influence untargeted knowledge), while generalization (whether the editing can generalize to other semantically-identical inputs) is a universal challenge for existing techniques. Furthermore, building on in-depth case analysis, we introduce an enhanced version of GRACE called A-GRACE, which incorporates contrastive learning to better capture the semantics of the inputs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.06638v2</guid>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaopeng Li, Shangwen Wang, Shasha Li, Jun Ma, Jie Yu, Xiaodong Liu, Jing Wang, Bin Ji, Weimin Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Re-examining learning linear functions in context</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.11465</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.11465v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In context learning (ICL) is an attractive method of solving a wide range of problems. Inspired by Garg et al. (2022), we look closely at ICL in a variety of train and test settings for several transformer models of different sizes trained from scratch. Our study complements prior work by pointing out several systematic failures of these models to generalize to data not in the training distribution, thereby showing some limitations of ICL. We find that models adopt a strategy for this task that is very different from standard solutions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.11465v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Omar Naim, Guilhem Fouilh\'e, Nicholas Asher</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cautious Optimizers: Improving Training with One Line of Code</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.16085</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.16085v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: AdamW has been the default optimizer for transformer pretraining. For many years, our community searches for faster and more stable optimizers with only constraint positive outcomes. In this work, we propose a \textbf{single-line modification in Pytorch} to any momentum-based optimizer, which we rename Cautious Optimizer, e.g. C-AdamW and C-Lion. Our theoretical result shows that this modification preserves Adam's Hamiltonian function and it does not break the convergence guarantee under the Lyapunov analysis. In addition, a whole new family of optimizers is revealed by our theoretical insight. Among them, we pick the simplest one for empirical experiments, showing speed-up on Llama and MAE pretraining up to $1.47\times$. Code is available at https://github.com/kyleliang919/C-Optim</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.16085v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.DM</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kaizhao Liang, Lizhang Chen, Bo Liu, Qiang Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BPP-Search: Enhancing Tree of Thought Reasoning for Mathematical Modeling Problem Solving</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.17404</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.17404v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: LLMs exhibit advanced reasoning capabilities, offering the potential to transform natural language questions into mathematical models. However, existing open-source datasets in operations research domain lack detailed annotations of the modeling process, such as variable definitions, focusing solely on objective values, which hinders reinforcement learning applications. To address this, we release the StructuredOR dataset, annotated with comprehensive labels that capture the complete mathematical modeling process. We further propose BPP-Search, a algorithm that integrates reinforcement learning into a tree-of-thought structure using Beam search, a Process reward model, and a pairwise Preference algorithm. This approach enables efficient exploration of tree structures, avoiding exhaustive search while improving accuracy. Extensive experiments on StructuredOR, NL4OPT, and MAMO-ComplexLP datasets show that BPP-Search significantly outperforms state-of-the-art methods. In tree-based reasoning, BPP-Search excels in accuracy and efficiency, enabling faster retrieval of correct solutions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.17404v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Teng Wang, Wing-Yin Yu, Zhenqi He, Zehua Liu, Xiongwei Han, Hailei Gong, Han Wu, Wei Shi, Ruifeng She, Fangzhou Zhu, Tao Zhong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Language Model-Brained GUI Agents: A Survey</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.18279</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.18279v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: GUIs have long been central to human-computer interaction, providing an intuitive and visually-driven way to access and interact with digital systems. The advent of LLMs, particularly multimodal models, has ushered in a new era of GUI automation. They have demonstrated exceptional capabilities in natural language understanding, code generation, and visual processing. This has paved the way for a new generation of LLM-brained GUI agents capable of interpreting complex GUI elements and autonomously executing actions based on natural language instructions. These agents represent a paradigm shift, enabling users to perform intricate, multi-step tasks through simple conversational commands. Their applications span across web navigation, mobile app interactions, and desktop automation, offering a transformative user experience that revolutionizes how individuals interact with software. This emerging field is rapidly advancing, with significant progress in both research and industry.
  To provide a structured understanding of this trend, this paper presents a comprehensive survey of LLM-brained GUI agents, exploring their historical evolution, core components, and advanced techniques. We address research questions such as existing GUI agent frameworks, the collection and utilization of data for training specialized GUI agents, the development of large action models tailored for GUI tasks, and the evaluation metrics and benchmarks necessary to assess their effectiveness. Additionally, we examine emerging applications powered by these agents. Through a detailed analysis, this survey identifies key research gaps and outlines a roadmap for future advancements in the field. By consolidating foundational knowledge and state-of-the-art developments, this work aims to guide both researchers and practitioners in overcoming challenges and unlocking the full potential of LLM-brained GUI agents.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.18279v3</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chaoyun Zhang, Shilin He, Jiaxu Qian, Bowen Li, Liqun Li, Si Qin, Yu Kang, Minghua Ma, Guyue Liu, Qingwei Lin, Saravan Rajmohan, Dongmei Zhang, Qi Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MATATA: a weak-supervised MAthematical Tool-Assisted reasoning for Tabular Applications</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.18915</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.18915v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Mathematical reasoning capabilities are increasing with tool-augmented language agents, but methods often rely either on closed-source or large models, external data, or extensive prompt engineering. This work introduces MATATA, a novel cost-effective method to train LLM agents for tabular data problems through reasoning, planning, and tool use. With a progressive self-improvement paradigm and an iterative weak supervision, it empowers 3.8B/8B Small Language Models (SLMs), particularly suited for local hosting and sensitive business contexts where data privacy is crucial. By employing a flexible and reusable tools across different datasets, it achieves robust performance with effective scalability across shared tasks. Experiments show that MATATA reaches state-of-the-art performances on FinQA and TAT-QA among reasoning frameworks based on open-source models. Moreover, MATATA models compete with GPT-4 based frameworks on TabMWP, while being SLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.18915v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Vishnou Vinayagame, Gregory Senay, Luis Mart\'i</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic-LLaVA: Efficient Multimodal Large Language Models via Dynamic Vision-language Context Sparsification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.00876</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.00876v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) have achieved remarkable success in vision understanding, reasoning, and interaction. However, the inference computation and memory increase progressively with the generation of output tokens during decoding, directly affecting the efficacy of MLLMs. Existing methods attempt to reduce the vision context redundancy to achieve efficient MLLMs. Unfortunately, the efficiency benefits of the vision context reduction in the prefill stage gradually diminish during the decoding stage. To address this problem, we proposed a dynamic vision-language context sparsification framework Dynamic-LLaVA, which dynamically reduces the redundancy of vision context in the prefill stage and decreases the memory and computation overhead of the generated language context during decoding. Dynamic-LLaVA designs a tailored sparsification inference scheme for different inference modes, i.e., prefill, decoding with and without KV cache, to achieve efficient inference of MLLMs. In practice, Dynamic-LLaVA can reduce computation consumption by $\sim$75\% in the prefill stage. Meanwhile, throughout the entire generation process of MLLMs, Dynamic-LLaVA reduces the $\sim$50\% computation consumption under decoding without KV cache, while saving $\sim$50\% GPU memory overhead when decoding with KV cache, due to the vision-language context sparsification. Extensive experiments also demonstrate that Dynamic-LLaVA achieves efficient inference for MLLMs with negligible understanding and generation ability degradation or even performance gains compared to the full-context inference baselines. Code is available at https://github.com/Osilly/dynamic_llava .</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.00876v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenxuan Huang, Zijie Zhai, Yunhang Shen, Shaoshen Cao, Fei Zhao, Xiangfeng Xu, Zheyu Ye, Shaohui Lin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CPRM: A LLM-based Continual Pre-training Framework for Relevance Modeling in Commercial Search</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.01269</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.01269v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Relevance modeling between queries and items stands as a pivotal component in commercial search engines, directly affecting the user experience. Given the remarkable achievements of large language models (LLMs) in various natural language processing (NLP) tasks, LLM-based relevance modeling is gradually being adopted within industrial search systems. Nevertheless, foundational LLMs lack domain-specific knowledge and do not fully exploit the potential of in-context learning. Furthermore, structured item text remains underutilized, and there is a shortage in the supply of corresponding queries and background knowledge. We thereby propose CPRM (Continual Pre-training for Relevance Modeling), a framework designed for the continual pre-training of LLMs to address these issues. Our CPRM framework includes three modules: 1) employing both queries and multi-field item to jointly pre-train for enhancing domain knowledge, 2) applying in-context pre-training, a novel approach where LLMs are pre-trained on a sequence of related queries or items, and 3) conducting reading comprehension on items to produce associated domain knowledge and background information (e.g., generating summaries and corresponding queries) to further strengthen LLMs. Results on offline experiments and online A/B testing demonstrate that our model achieves convincing performance compared to strong baselines.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.01269v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kaixin Wu, Yixin Ji, Zeyuan Chen, Qiang Wang, Cunxiang Wang, Hong Liu, Baijun Ji, Jia Xu, Zhongyi Liu, Jinjie Gu, Yuan Zhou, Linjian Mo</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
