<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL</link>
    <description>cs.CL updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 04:00:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Sunday</day>
      <day>Saturday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Traffic Crash Narratives in Jordan Using Text Mining Analytics</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09438</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09438v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This study explores traffic crash narratives in an attempt to inform and enhance effective traffic safety policies using text-mining analytics. Text mining techniques are employed to unravel key themes and trends within the narratives, aiming to provide a deeper understanding of the factors contributing to traffic crashes. This study collected crash data from five major freeways in Jordan that cover narratives of 7,587 records from 2018-2022. An unsupervised learning method was adopted to learn the pattern from crash data. Various text mining techniques, such as topic modeling, keyword extraction, and Word Co-Occurrence Network, were also used to reveal the co-occurrence of crash patterns. Results show that text mining analytics is a promising method and underscore the multifactorial nature of traffic crashes, including intertwining human decisions and vehicular conditions. The recurrent themes across all analyses highlight the need for a balanced approach to road safety, merging both proactive and reactive measures. Emphasis on driver education and awareness around animal-related incidents is paramount.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09438v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shadi Jaradat, Taqwa I. Alhadidi, Huthaifa I. Ashqar, Ahmed Hossain, Mohammed Elhenawy</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing High Resolution Vision-Language Models in Biomedicine</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09454</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09454v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Multi-modal learning has significantly advanced generative AI, especially in vision-language modeling. Innovations like GPT-4V and open-source projects such as LLaVA have enabled robust conversational agents capable of zero-shot task completions. However, applying these technologies in the biomedical field presents unique challenges. Recent initiatives like LLaVA-Med have started to adapt instruction-tuning for biomedical contexts using large datasets such as PMC-15M. Our research offers three key contributions: (i) we present a new instruct dataset enriched with medical image-text pairs from Claude3-Opus and LLaMA3 70B, (ii) we propose a novel image encoding strategy using hierarchical representations to improve fine-grained biomedical visual comprehension, and (iii) we develop the Llama3-Med model, which achieves state-of-the-art zero-shot performance on biomedical visual question answering benchmarks, with an average performance improvement of over 10% compared to previous methods. These advancements provide more accurate and reliable tools for medical professionals, bridging gaps in current multi-modal conversational assistants and promoting further innovations in medical AI.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09454v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>q-bio.QM</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zekai Chen, Arda Pekis, Kevin Brown</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Newswire: A Large-Scale Structured Database of a Century of Historical News</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09490</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09490v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In the U.S. historically, local newspapers drew their content largely from newswires like the Associated Press. Historians argue that newswires played a pivotal role in creating a national identity and shared understanding of the world, but there is no comprehensive archive of the content sent over newswires. We reconstruct such an archive by applying a customized deep learning pipeline to hundreds of terabytes of raw image scans from thousands of local newspapers. The resulting dataset contains 2.7 million unique public domain U.S. newswire articles, written between 1878 and 1977. Locations in these articles are georeferenced, topics are tagged using customized neural topic classification, named entities are recognized, and individuals are disambiguated to Wikipedia using a novel entity disambiguation model. To construct the Newswire dataset, we first recognize newspaper layouts and transcribe around 138 millions structured article texts from raw image scans. We then use a customized neural bi-encoder model to de-duplicate reproduced articles, in the presence of considerable abridgement and noise, quantifying how widely each article was reproduced. A text classifier is used to ensure that we only include newswire articles, which historically are in the public domain. The structured data that accompany the texts provide rich information about the who (disambiguated individuals), what (topics), and where (georeferencing) of the news that millions of Americans read over the course of a century. We also include Library of Congress metadata information about the newspapers that ran the articles on their front pages. The Newswire dataset is useful both for large language modeling - expanding training data beyond what is available from modern web texts - and for studying a diversity of questions in computational linguistics, social science, and the digital humanities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09490v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>econ.GN</category>
      <category>q-fin.EC</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Emily Silcock, Abhishek Arora, Luca D'Amico-Wong, Melissa Dell</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Talking Heads: Understanding Inter-layer Communication in Transformer Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09519</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09519v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Although it is known that transformer language models (LMs) pass features from early layers to later layers, it is not well understood how this information is represented and routed by the model. By analyzing particular mechanism LMs use to accomplish this, we find that it is also used to recall items from a list, and show that this mechanism can explain an otherwise arbitrary-seeming sensitivity of the model to the order of items in the prompt. Specifically, we find that models write into low-rank subspaces of the residual stream to represent features which are then read out by specific later layers, forming low-rank communication channels between layers. By decomposing attention head weight matrices with the Singular Value Decomposition (SVD), we find that previously described interactions between heads separated by one or more layers can be predicted via analysis of their weight matrices. We show that it is possible to manipulate the internal model representations as well as edit model weights based on the mechanism we discover in order to significantly improve performance on our synthetic Laundry List task, which requires recall from a list, often improving task accuracy by over 20%. Our analysis reveals a surprisingly intricate interpretable structure learned from language model pretraining, and helps us understand why sophisticated LMs sometimes fail in simple domains, facilitating future analysis of more complex behaviors.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09519v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jack Merullo, Carsten Eickhoff, Ellie Pavlick</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Syntactic Patterns in Urdu: A Deep Dive into Dependency Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09549</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09549v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Parsing is the process of breaking a sentence into its grammatical components and identifying the syntactic structure of the sentence. The syntactically correct sentence structure is achieved by assigning grammatical labels to its constituents using lexicon and syntactic rules. In linguistics, parser is extremely useful due to the number of different applications like name entity recognition, QA systems and information extraction, etc. The two most common techniques used for parsing are phrase structure and dependency Structure. Because Urdu is a low-resource language, there has been little progress in building an Urdu parser. A comparison of several parsers revealed that the dependency parsing approach is better suited for order-free languages such as Urdu. We have made significant progress in parsing Urdu, a South Asian language with a complex morphology. For Urdu dependency parsing, a basic feature model consisting of word location, word head, and dependency relation is employed as a starting point, followed by more complex feature models. The dependency tagset is designed after careful consideration of the complex morphological structure of the Urdu language, word order variation, and lexical ambiguity and it contains 22 tags. Our dataset comprises of sentences from news articles, and we tried to include sentences of different complexity (which is quite challenging), to get reliable results. All experiments are performed using MaltParser, exploring all 9 algorithms and classifiers. We have achieved a 70 percent overall best-labeled accuracy (LA), as well as an 84 percent overall best-unlabeled attachment score (UAS) using the Nivreeager algorithm. The comparison of output data with treebank test data that has been manually parsed is then used to carry out error assessment and to identify the errors produced by the parser.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09549v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nudrat Habib</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoding the Diversity: A Review of the Indic AI Research Landscape</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09559</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09559v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This review paper provides a comprehensive overview of large language model (LLM) research directions within Indic languages. Indic languages are those spoken in the Indian subcontinent, including India, Pakistan, Bangladesh, Sri Lanka, Nepal, and Bhutan, among others. These languages have a rich cultural and linguistic heritage and are spoken by over 1.5 billion people worldwide. With the tremendous market potential and growing demand for natural language processing (NLP) based applications in diverse languages, generative applications for Indic languages pose unique challenges and opportunities for research. Our paper deep dives into the recent advancements in Indic generative modeling, contributing with a taxonomy of research directions, tabulating 84 recent publications. Research directions surveyed in this paper include LLM development, fine-tuning existing LLMs, development of corpora, benchmarking and evaluation, as well as publications around specific techniques, tools, and applications. We found that researchers across the publications emphasize the challenges associated with limited data availability, lack of standardization, and the peculiar linguistic complexities of Indic languages. This work aims to serve as a valuable resource for researchers and practitioners working in the field of NLP, particularly those focused on Indic languages, and contributes to the development of more accurate and efficient LLM applications for these languages.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09559v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sankalp KJ, Vinija Jain, Sreyoshi Bhaduri, Tamoghna Roy, Aman Chadha</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speech ReaLLM -- Real-time Streaming Speech Recognition with Multimodal LLMs by Teaching the Flow of Time</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09569</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09569v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We introduce Speech ReaLLM, a new ASR architecture that marries "decoder-only" ASR with the RNN-T to make multimodal LLM architectures capable of real-time streaming. This is the first "decoder-only" ASR architecture designed to handle continuous audio without explicit end-pointing. Speech ReaLLM is a special case of the more general ReaLLM ("real-time LLM") approach, also introduced here for the first time. The idea is inspired by RNN-T: Instead of generating a response only at the end of a user prompt, generate after every input token received in real time (it is often empty). On Librispeech "test", an 80M Speech ReaLLM achieves WERs of 3.0% and 7.4% in real time (without an external LM or auxiliary loss). This is only slightly above a 3x larger Attention-Encoder-Decoder baseline. We also show that this way, an LLM architecture can learn to represent and reproduce the flow of time; and that a pre-trained 7B LLM can be fine-tuned to do reasonably well on this task.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09569v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Frank Seide, Morrie Doulaty, Yangyang Shi, Yashesh Gaur, Junteng Jia, Chunyang Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Gender Polarity in Short Social Media Texts with BERT: The Role of Emojis and Emoticons</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09573</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09573v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this effort we fine tuned different models based on BERT to detect the gender polarity of twitter accounts. We specially focused on analyzing the effect of using emojis and emoticons in performance of our model in classifying task. We were able to demonstrate that the use of these none word inputs alongside the mention of other accounts in a short text format like tweet has an impact in detecting the account holder's gender.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09573v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.13140/RG.2.2.15772.50568</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Saba Yousefian Jazi, Amir Mirzaeinia, Sina Yousefian Jazi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multimodal Large Language Models with Fusion Low Rank Adaptation for Device Directed Speech Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09617</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09617v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Although Large Language Models (LLMs) have shown promise for human-like conversations, they are primarily pre-trained on text data. Incorporating audio or video improves performance, but collecting large-scale multimodal data and pre-training multimodal LLMs is challenging. To this end, we propose a Fusion Low Rank Adaptation (FLoRA) technique that efficiently adapts a pre-trained unimodal LLM to consume new, previously unseen modalities via low rank adaptation. For device-directed speech detection, using FLoRA, the multimodal LLM achieves 22% relative reduction in equal error rate (EER) over the text-only approach and attains performance parity with its full fine-tuning (FFT) counterpart while needing to tune only a fraction of its parameters. Furthermore, with the newly introduced adapter dropout, FLoRA is robust to missing data, improving over FFT by 20% lower EER and 56% lower false accept rate. The proposed approach scales well for model sizes from 16M to 3B parameters.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09617v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shruti Palaskar, Oggi Rudovic, Sameer Dharur, Florian Pesce, Gautam Krishna, Aswin Sivaraman, Jack Berkowitz, Ahmed Hussen Abdelaziz, Saurabh Adya, Ahmed Tewfik</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Modal Retrieval For Large Language Model Based Speech Recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09618</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09618v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Retrieval is a widely adopted approach for improving language models leveraging external information. As the field moves towards multi-modal large language models, it is important to extend the pure text based methods to incorporate other modalities in retrieval as well for applications across the wide spectrum of machine learning tasks and data types. In this work, we propose multi-modal retrieval with two approaches: kNN-LM and cross-attention techniques. We demonstrate the effectiveness of our retrieval approaches empirically by applying them to automatic speech recognition tasks with access to external information. Under this setting, we show that speech-based multi-modal retrieval outperforms text based retrieval, and yields up to 50 % improvement in word error rate over the multi-modal language model baseline. Furthermore, we achieve state-of-the-art recognition results on the Spoken-Squad question answering dataset.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09618v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jari Kolehmainen, Aditya Gourav, Prashanth Gurunath Shivakumar, Yile Gu, Ankur Gandhe, Ariya Rastrow, Grant Strimel, Ivan Bulyko</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Language Structures through Grounding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09662</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09662v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Language is highly structured, with syntactic and semantic structures, to some extent, agreed upon by speakers of the same language. With implicit or explicit awareness of such structures, humans can learn and use language efficiently and generalize to sentences that contain unseen words. Motivated by human language learning, in this dissertation, we consider a family of machine learning tasks that aim to learn language structures through grounding. We seek distant supervision from other data sources (i.e., grounds), including but not limited to other modalities (e.g., vision), execution results of programs, and other languages.
  We demonstrate the potential of this task formulation and advocate for its adoption through three schemes. In Part I, we consider learning syntactic parses through visual grounding. We propose the task of visually grounded grammar induction, present the first models to induce syntactic structures from visually grounded text and speech, and find that the visual grounding signals can help improve the parsing quality over language-only models. As a side contribution, we propose a novel evaluation metric that enables the evaluation of speech parsing without text or automatic speech recognition systems involved. In Part II, we propose two execution-aware methods to map sentences into corresponding semantic structures (i.e., programs), significantly improving compositional generalization and few-shot program synthesis. In Part III, we propose methods that learn language structures from annotations in other languages. Specifically, we propose a method that sets a new state of the art on cross-lingual word alignment. We then leverage the learned word alignments to improve the performance of zero-shot cross-lingual dependency parsing, by proposing a novel substructure-based projection method that preserves structural knowledge learned from the source language.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09662v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Freda Shi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FreeCtrl: Constructing Control Centers with Feedforward Layers for Learning-Free Controllable Text Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09688</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09688v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Controllable text generation (CTG) seeks to craft texts adhering to specific attributes, traditionally employing learning-based techniques such as training, fine-tuning, or prefix-tuning with attribute-specific datasets. These approaches, while effective, demand extensive computational and data resources. In contrast, some proposed learning-free alternatives circumvent learning but often yield inferior results, exemplifying the fundamental machine learning trade-off between computational expense and model efficacy. To overcome these limitations, we propose FreeCtrl, a learning-free approach that dynamically adjusts the weights of selected feedforward neural network (FFN) vectors to steer the outputs of large language models (LLMs). FreeCtrl hinges on the principle that the weights of different FFN vectors influence the likelihood of different tokens appearing in the output. By identifying and adaptively adjusting the weights of attribute-related FFN vectors, FreeCtrl can control the output likelihood of attribute keywords in the generated content. Extensive experiments on single- and multi-attribute control reveal that the learning-free FreeCtrl outperforms other learning-free and learning-based methods, successfully resolving the dilemma between learning costs and model performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09688v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zijian Feng, Hanzhang Zhou, Zixiao Zhu, Kezhi Mao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Detecting Response Generation Not Requiring Factual Judgment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09702</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09702v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: With the remarkable development of large language models (LLMs), ensuring the factuality of output has become a challenge. However, having all the contents of the response with given knowledge or facts is not necessarily a good thing in dialogues. This study aimed to achieve both attractiveness and factuality in a dialogue response for which a task was set to predict sentences that do not require factual correctness judgment such as agreeing, or personal opinions/feelings. We created a dataset, dialogue dataset annotated with fact-check-needed label (DDFC), for this task via crowdsourcing, and classification tasks were performed on several models using this dataset. The model with the highest classification accuracy could yield about 88% accurate classification results.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09702v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ryohei Kamei, Daiki Shiono, Reina Akama, Jun Suzuki</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UniBridge: A Unified Approach to Cross-Lingual Transfer Learning for Low-Resource Languages</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09717</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09717v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this paper, we introduce UniBridge (Cross-Lingual Transfer Learning with Optimized Embeddings and Vocabulary), a comprehensive approach developed to improve the effectiveness of Cross-Lingual Transfer Learning, particularly in languages with limited resources. Our approach tackles two essential elements of a language model: the initialization of embeddings and the optimal vocabulary size. Specifically, we propose a novel embedding initialization method that leverages both lexical and semantic alignment for a language. In addition, we present a method for systematically searching for the optimal vocabulary size, ensuring a balance between model complexity and linguistic coverage. Our experiments across multilingual datasets show that our approach greatly improves the F1-Score in several languages. UniBridge is a robust and adaptable solution for cross-lingual systems in various languages, highlighting the significance of initializing embeddings and choosing the right vocabulary size in cross-lingual environments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09717v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Trinh Pham, Khoi M. Le, Luu Anh Tuan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Knowledge Distillation for Learning Ambiguity</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09719</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09719v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent language models have shown remarkable performance on natural language understanding (NLU) tasks. However, they are often sub-optimal when faced with ambiguous samples that can be interpreted in multiple ways, over-confidently predicting a single label without consideration for its correctness. To address this issue, we propose a novel self-knowledge distillation method that enables models to learn label distributions more accurately by leveraging knowledge distilled from their lower layers. This approach also includes a learning phase that re-calibrates the unnecessarily strengthened confidence for training samples judged as extremely ambiguous based on the distilled distribution knowledge. We validate our method on diverse NLU benchmark datasets and the experimental results demonstrate its effectiveness in producing better label distributions. Particularly, through the process of re-calibrating the confidence for highly ambiguous samples, the issue of over-confidence when predictions for unseen samples do not match with their ground-truth labels has been significantly alleviated. This has been shown to contribute to generating better distributions than the existing state-of-the-art method. Moreover, our method is more efficient in training the models compared to the existing method, as it does not involve additional training processes to refine label distributions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09719v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hancheol Park, Soyeong Jeong, Sukmin Cho, Jong C. Park</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bootstrapping Language Models with DPO Implicit Rewards</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09760</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09760v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Human alignment in large language models (LLMs) is an active area of research. A recent groundbreaking work, direct preference optimization (DPO), has greatly simplified the process from past work in reinforcement learning from human feedback (RLHF) by bypassing the reward learning stage in RLHF. DPO, after training, provides an implicit reward model. In this work, we make a novel observation that this implicit reward model can by itself be used in a bootstrapping fashion to further align the LLM. Our approach is to use the rewards from a current LLM model to construct a preference dataset, which is then used in subsequent DPO rounds. We incorporate refinements that debias the length of the responses and improve the quality of the preference dataset to further improve our approach. Our approach, named self-alignment with DPO ImpliCit rEwards (DICE), shows great improvements in alignment and achieves superior performance than Gemini Pro on AlpacaEval 2, reaching 27.55% length-controlled win rate against GPT-4 Turbo, but with only 8B parameters and no external feedback. Our code is available at https://github.com/sail-sg/dice.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09760v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Changyu Chen, Zichen Liu, Chao Du, Tianyu Pang, Qian Liu, Arunesh Sinha, Pradeep Varakantham, Min Lin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pcc-tuning: Breaking the Contrastive Learning Ceiling in Semantic Textual Similarity</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09790</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09790v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Semantic Textual Similarity (STS) constitutes a critical research direction in computational linguistics and serves as a key indicator of the encoding capabilities of embedding models. Driven by advances in pre-trained language models and contrastive learning techniques, leading sentence representation methods can already achieved average Spearman's correlation scores of approximately 86 across seven STS benchmarks in SentEval. However, further improvements have become increasingly marginal, with no existing method attaining an average score higher than 87 on these tasks. This paper conducts an in-depth analysis of this phenomenon and concludes that the upper limit for Spearman's correlation scores using contrastive learning is 87.5. To transcend this ceiling, we propose an innovative approach termed Pcc-tuning, which employs Pearson's correlation coefficient as a loss function to refine model performance beyond contrastive learning. Experimental results demonstrate that Pcc-tuning markedly surpasses previous state-of-the-art strategies, raising the Spearman's correlation score to above 90.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09790v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bowen Zhang, Chunping Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retrieval Augmented Fact Verification by Synthesizing Contrastive Arguments</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09815</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09815v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The rapid propagation of misinformation poses substantial risks to public interest. To combat misinformation, large language models (LLMs) are adapted to automatically verify claim credibility. Nevertheless, existing methods heavily rely on the embedded knowledge within LLMs and / or black-box APIs for evidence collection, leading to subpar performance with smaller LLMs or upon unreliable context. In this paper, we propose retrieval augmented fact verification through the synthesis of contrasting arguments (RAFTS). Upon input claims, RAFTS starts with evidence retrieval, where we design a retrieval pipeline to collect and re-rank relevant documents from verifiable sources. Then, RAFTS forms contrastive arguments (i.e., supporting or refuting) conditioned on the retrieved evidence. In addition, RAFTS leverages an embedding model to identify informative demonstrations, followed by in-context prompting to generate the prediction and explanation. Our method effectively retrieves relevant documents as evidence and evaluates arguments from varying perspectives, incorporating nuanced information for fine-grained decision-making. Combined with informative in-context examples as prior, RAFTS achieves significant improvements to supervised and LLM baselines without complex prompts. We demonstrate the effectiveness of our method through extensive experiments, where RAFTS can outperform GPT-based methods with a significantly smaller 7B LLM.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09815v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhenrui Yue, Huimin Zeng, Lanyu Shang, Yifan Liu, Yang Zhang, Dong Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HiP Attention: Sparse Sub-Quadratic Attention with Hierarchical Attention Pruning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09827</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09827v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In modern large language models (LLMs), increasing sequence lengths is a crucial challenge for enhancing their comprehension and coherence in handling complex tasks such as multi-modal question answering. However, handling long context sequences with LLMs is prohibitively costly due to the conventional attention mechanism's quadratic time and space complexity, and the context window size is limited by the GPU memory. Although recent works have proposed linear and sparse attention mechanisms to address this issue, their real-world applicability is often limited by the need to re-train pre-trained models. In response, we propose a novel approach, Hierarchically Pruned Attention (HiP), which simultaneously reduces the training and inference time complexity from $O(T^2)$ to $O(T \log T)$ and the space complexity from $O(T^2)$ to $O(T)$. To this end, we devise a dynamic sparse attention mechanism that generates an attention mask through a novel tree-search-like algorithm for a given query on the fly. HiP is training-free as it only utilizes the pre-trained attention scores to spot the positions of the top-$k$ most significant elements for each query. Moreover, it ensures that no token is overlooked, unlike the sliding window-based sub-quadratic attention methods, such as StreamingLLM. Extensive experiments on diverse real-world benchmarks demonstrate that HiP significantly reduces prompt (i.e., prefill) and decoding latency and memory usage while maintaining high generation performance with little or no degradation. As HiP allows pretrained LLMs to scale to millions of tokens on commodity GPUs with no additional engineering due to its easy plug-and-play deployment, we believe that our work will have a large practical impact, opening up the possibility to many long-context LLM applications previously infeasible.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09827v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.DC</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Heejun Lee, Geon Park, Youngwan Lee, Jina Kim, Wonyoung Jeong, Myeongjae Jeon, Sung Ju Hwang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapport-Driven Virtual Agent: Rapport Building Dialogue Strategy for Improving User Experience at First Meeting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09839</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09839v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Rapport is known as a conversational aspect focusing on relationship building, which influences outcomes in collaborative tasks. This study aims to establish human-agent rapport through small talk by using a rapport-building strategy. We implemented this strategy for the virtual agents based on dialogue strategies by prompting a large language model (LLM). In particular, we utilized two dialogue strategies-predefined sequence and free-form-to guide the dialogue generation framework. We conducted analyses based on human evaluations, examining correlations between total turn, utterance characters, rapport score, and user experience variables: naturalness, satisfaction, interest, engagement, and usability. We investigated correlations between rapport score and naturalness, satisfaction, engagement, and conversation flow. Our experimental results also indicated that using free-form to prompt the rapport-building strategy performed the best in subjective scores.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09839v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Muhammad Yeza Baihaqi, Angel Garc\'ia Contreras, Seiya Kawano, Koichiro Yoshino</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Encoding of Gender in Transformer-based ASR Representations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09855</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09855v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: While existing literature relies on performance differences to uncover gender biases in ASR models, a deeper analysis is essential to understand how gender is encoded and utilized during transcript generation. This work investigates the encoding and utilization of gender in the latent representations of two transformer-based ASR models, Wav2Vec2 and HuBERT. Using linear erasure, we demonstrate the feasibility of removing gender information from each layer of an ASR model and show that such an intervention has minimal impacts on the ASR performance. Additionally, our analysis reveals a concentration of gender information within the first and last frames in the final layers, explaining the ease of erasing gender in these layers. Our findings suggest the prospect of creating gender-neutral embeddings that can be integrated into ASR frameworks without compromising their efficacy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09855v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aravind Krishnan, Badr M. Abdullah, Dietrich Klakow</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Unified Data Augmentation Framework for Low-Resource Multi-Domain Dialogue Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09881</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09881v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Current state-of-the-art dialogue systems heavily rely on extensive training datasets. However, challenges arise in domains where domain-specific training datasets are insufficient or entirely absent. To tackle this challenge, we propose a novel data \textbf{A}ugmentation framework for \textbf{M}ulti-\textbf{D}omain \textbf{D}ialogue \textbf{G}eneration, referred to as \textbf{AMD$^2$G}. The AMD$^2$G framework consists of a data augmentation process and a two-stage training approach: domain-agnostic training and domain adaptation training. We posit that domain corpora are a blend of domain-agnostic and domain-specific features, with certain representation patterns shared among diverse domains. Domain-agnostic training aims to enable models to learn these common expressive patterns. To construct domain-agnostic dialogue corpora, we employ a \textit{\textbf{de-domaining}} data processing technique used to remove domain-specific features. By mitigating the effects of domain-specific features, the model trained on the de-domained corpora can effectively learn common expression patterns in different domains. Subsequently, we adapt the learned domain-agnostic features to the target domain through domain adaptation training. We conduct experiments on Chinese dialogue datasets from five different domains and show that AMD$^2$G achieves superior performance compared to both direct training on the target domain corpus and collective training on all five domain corpora. Our work underscores AMD$^2$G as a viable alternative solution for low-resource multi-domain dialogue generation. Code and data associated with our work are available on GitHub repository$^{\text 1}$.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09881v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>2024 European Conference on Machine Learning and Principles and Practice of Knowledge Discovery in Databases</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Yongkang Liu, Ercong Nie, Zheng Hua, Zifeng Ding, Daling Wang, Yifei Zhang, Hinrich Sch\"utze</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3D-RPE: Enhancing Long-Context Modeling Through 3D Rotary Position Encoding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09897</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09897v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Inspired by the Bloch Sphere representation, we propose a novel rotary position encoding on a three-dimensional sphere, named 3D Rotary Position Encoding (3D-RPE). 3D-RPE is an advanced version of the widely used 2D Rotary Position Encoding (RoPE), with two major advantages for modeling long contexts: controllable long-term decay and improved position resolution. For controllable long-term decay, 3D-RPE allows for the regulation of long-term decay within the chunk size, ensuring the modeling of relative positional information between tokens at a distant relative position. For enhanced position resolution, 3D-RPE can mitigate the degradation of position resolution caused by position interpolation on RoPE. We have conducted experiments on long-context Natural Language Understanding (NLU) and long-sequence Language Modeling (LM) tasks. From the experimental results, 3D-RPE achieved performance improvements over RoPE, especially in long-context NLU tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09897v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xindian Ma, Wenyuan Liu, Peng Zhang, Nan Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GEB-1.3B: Open Lightweight Large Language Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09900</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09900v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recently developed large language models (LLMs) such as ChatGPT, Claude, and Llama have demonstrated impressive abilities, and even surpass human-level performance in several tasks. Despite their success, the resource-intensive demands of these models, requiring significant computational power for both training and inference, limit their deployment to high-performance servers. Additionally, the extensive calculation requirements of the models often lead to increased latency in response times. With the increasing need for LLMs to operate efficiently on CPUs, research about lightweight models that are optimized for CPU inference has emerged. In this work, we introduce GEB-1.3B, a lightweight LLM trained on 550 billion tokens in both Chinese and English languages. We employ novel training techniques, including ROPE, Group-Query-Attention, and FlashAttention-2, to accelerate training while maintaining model performance. Additionally, we fine-tune the model using 10 million samples of instruction data to enhance alignment. GEB-1.3B exhibits outstanding performance on general benchmarks such as MMLU, C-Eval, and CMMLU, outperforming comparative models such as MindLLM-1.3B and TinyLLaMA-1.1B. Notably, the FP32 version of GEB-1.3B achieves commendable inference times on CPUs, with ongoing efforts to further enhance speed through advanced quantization techniques. The release of GEB-1.3B as an open-source model marks a significant contribution to the development of lightweight LLMs, promising to foster further research and innovation in the field.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09900v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jie Wu, Yufeng Zhu, Lei Shen, Xuqing Lu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Editing in Language Models via Adapted Direct Preference Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09920</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09920v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) can become outdated over time as they may lack updated world knowledge, leading to factual knowledge errors and gaps. Knowledge Editing (KE) aims to overcome this challenge using weight updates that do not require expensive retraining. We propose treating KE as an LLM alignment problem. Toward this goal, we introduce Knowledge Direct Preference Optimization (KDPO), a variation of the Direct Preference Optimization (DPO) that is more effective for knowledge modifications. Our method is based on an online approach that continually updates the knowledge stored in the model. We use the current knowledge as a negative sample and the new knowledge we want to introduce as a positive sample in a process called DPO. We also use teacher-forcing for negative sample generation and optimize using the positive sample, which helps maintain localized changes. We tested our KE method on various datasets and models, comparing it to several cutting-edge methods, with 100 and 500 sequential edits. Additionally, we conducted an ablation study comparing our method to the standard DPO approach. Our experimental results show that our modified DPO method allows for more refined KE, achieving similar or better performance compared to previous methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09920v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Amit Rozner, Barak Battash, Lior Wolf, Ofir Lindenbaum</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CliBench: Multifaceted Evaluation of Large Language Models in Clinical Decisions on Diagnoses, Procedures, Lab Tests Orders and Prescriptions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09923</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09923v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The integration of Artificial Intelligence (AI), especially Large Language Models (LLMs), into the clinical diagnosis process offers significant potential to improve the efficiency and accessibility of medical care. While LLMs have shown some promise in the medical domain, their application in clinical diagnosis remains underexplored, especially in real-world clinical practice, where highly sophisticated, patient-specific decisions need to be made. Current evaluations of LLMs in this field are often narrow in scope, focusing on specific diseases or specialties and employing simplified diagnostic tasks. To bridge this gap, we introduce CliBench, a novel benchmark developed from the MIMIC IV dataset, offering a comprehensive and realistic assessment of LLMs' capabilities in clinical diagnosis. This benchmark not only covers diagnoses from a diverse range of medical cases across various specialties but also incorporates tasks of clinical significance: treatment procedure identification, lab test ordering and medication prescriptions. Supported by structured output ontologies, CliBench enables a precise and multi-granular evaluation, offering an in-depth understanding of LLM's capability on diverse clinical tasks of desired granularity. We conduct a zero-shot evaluation of leading LLMs to assess their proficiency in clinical decision-making. Our preliminary results shed light on the potential and limitations of current LLMs in clinical settings, providing valuable insights for future advancements in LLM-powered healthcare.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09923v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mingyu Derek Ma, Chenchen Ye, Yu Yan, Xiaoxuan Wang, Peipei Ping, Timothy S Chang, Wei Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experiments in News Bias Detection with Pre-Trained Neural Transformers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09938</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09938v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The World Wide Web provides unrivalled access to information globally, including factual news reporting and commentary. However, state actors and commercial players increasingly spread biased (distorted) or fake (non-factual) information to promote their agendas. We compare several large, pre-trained language models on the task of sentence-level news bias detection and sub-type classification, providing quantitative and qualitative results.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09938v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tim Menzner, Jochen L. Leidner</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BLEnD: A Benchmark for LLMs on Everyday Knowledge in Diverse Cultures and Languages</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09948</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09948v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) often lack culture-specific knowledge of daily life, especially across diverse regions and non-English languages. Existing benchmarks for evaluating LLMs' cultural sensitivities are limited to a single language or collected from online sources such as Wikipedia, which do not reflect the mundane everyday lifestyles of diverse regions. That is, information about the food people eat for their birthday celebrations, spices they typically use, musical instruments youngsters play, or the sports they practice in school is common cultural knowledge but uncommon in easily collected online sources, especially for underrepresented cultures. To address this issue, we introduce BLEnD, a hand-crafted benchmark designed to evaluate LLMs' everyday knowledge across diverse cultures and languages. BLEnD comprises 52.6k question-answer pairs from 16 countries/regions, in 13 different languages, including low-resource ones such as Amharic, Assamese, Azerbaijani, Hausa, and Sundanese. We construct the benchmark to include two formats of questions: short-answer and multiple-choice. We show that LLMs perform better for cultures that are highly represented online, with a maximum 57.34% difference in GPT-4, the best-performing model, in the short-answer format. For cultures represented by mid-to-high-resource languages, LLMs perform better in their local languages, but for cultures represented by low-resource languages, LLMs perform better in English than the local languages. We make our dataset publicly available at: https://github.com/nlee0212/BLEnD.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09948v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junho Myung, Nayeon Lee, Yi Zhou, Jiho Jin, Rifki Afina Putri, Dimosthenis Antypas, Hsuvas Borkakoty, Eunsu Kim, Carla Perez-Almendros, Abinew Ali Ayele, V\'ictor Guti\'errez-Basulto, Yazm\'in Ib\'a\~nez-Garc\'ia, Hwaran Lee, Shamsuddeen Hassan Muhammad, Kiwoong Park, Anar Sabuhi Rzayev, Nina White, Seid Muhie Yimam, Mohammad Taher Pilehvar, Nedjma Ousidhoum, Jose Camacho-Collados, Alice Oh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bag of Lies: Robustness in Continuous Pre-training BERT</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09967</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09967v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This study aims to acquire more insights into the continuous pre-training phase of BERT regarding entity knowledge, using the COVID-19 pandemic as a case study. Since the pandemic emerged after the last update of BERT's pre-training data, the model has little to no entity knowledge about COVID-19. Using continuous pre-training, we control what entity knowledge is available to the model. We compare the baseline BERT model with the further pre-trained variants on the fact-checking benchmark Check-COVID. To test the robustness of continuous pre-training, we experiment with several adversarial methods to manipulate the input data, such as training on misinformation and shuffling the word order until the input becomes nonsensical. Surprisingly, our findings reveal that these methods do not degrade, and sometimes even improve, the model's downstream performance. This suggests that continuous pre-training of BERT is robust against misinformation. Furthermore, we are releasing a new dataset, consisting of original texts from academic publications in the LitCovid repository and their AI-generated false counterparts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09967v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ine Gevers, Walter Daelemans</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Better LLM Evaluator for Text Generation: The Impact of Prompt Output Sequencing and Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09972</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09972v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This research investigates prompt designs of evaluating generated texts using large language models (LLMs). While LLMs are increasingly used for scoring various inputs, creating effective prompts for open-ended text evaluation remains challenging due to model sensitivity and subjectivity in evaluation of text generation. Our study experimented with different prompt structures, altering the sequence of output instructions and including explanatory reasons. We found that the order of presenting reasons and scores significantly influences LLMs' scoring, with a different level of rule understanding in the prompt. An additional optimization may enhance scoring alignment if sufficient data is available. This insight is crucial for improving the accuracy and consistency of LLM-based evaluations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09972v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>KuanChao Chu, Yi-Pei Chen, Hideki Nakayama</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disentangling Dialect from Social Bias via Multitask Learning to Improve Fairness</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09977</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09977v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Dialects introduce syntactic and lexical variations in language that occur in regional or social groups. Most NLP methods are not sensitive to such variations. This may lead to unfair behavior of the methods, conveying negative bias towards dialect speakers. While previous work has studied dialect-related fairness for aspects like hate speech, other aspects of biased language, such as lewdness, remain fully unexplored. To fill this gap, we investigate performance disparities between dialects in the detection of five aspects of biased language and how to mitigate them. To alleviate bias, we present a multitask learning approach that models dialect language as an auxiliary task to incorporate syntactic and lexical variations. In our experiments with African-American English dialect, we provide empirical evidence that complementing common learning approaches with dialect modeling improves their fairness. Furthermore, the results suggest that multitask learning achieves state-of-the-art performance and helps to detect properties of biased language more reliably.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09977v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Maximilian Splieth\"over, Sai Nikhil Menon, Henning Wachsmuth</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HIRO: Hierarchical Information Retrieval Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09979</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09979v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) excel in natural language tasks but face limitations due to static training datasets, resulting in outdated or contextually shallow responses. Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) addresses this by integrating real-time external knowledge, enhancing model accuracy and credibility, especially for knowledge-intensive tasks. However, RAG-enhanced LLMs struggle with long contexts, causing them to "choke" on information overload, compromising response quality. Recent RAG applications use hierarchical data structures for storing documents, organized at various levels of summarization and information density. In this context, we introduce HIRO (Hierarchical Information Retrieval Optimization), a novel querying approach for RAG applications using hierarchical structures for storing documents. HIRO employs DFS-based recursive similarity score calculation and branch pruning to minimize the context returned to the LLM without informational loss. HIRO outperforms existing querying mechanisms on the NarrativeQA dataset by an absolute performance gain of 10.85%.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09979v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Krish Goel, Mahek Chandak</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Precision Empowers, Excess Distracts: Visual Question Answering With Dynamically Infused Knowledge In Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09994</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09994v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In the realm of multimodal tasks, Visual Question Answering (VQA) plays a crucial role by addressing natural language questions grounded in visual content. Knowledge-Based Visual Question Answering (KBVQA) advances this concept by adding external knowledge along with images to respond to questions. We introduce an approach for KBVQA, augmenting the existing vision-language transformer encoder-decoder (OFA) model. Our main contribution involves enhancing questions by incorporating relevant external knowledge extracted from knowledge graphs, using a dynamic triple extraction method. We supply a flexible number of triples from the knowledge graph as context, tailored to meet the requirements for answering the question. Our model, enriched with knowledge, demonstrates an average improvement of 4.75\% in Exact Match Score over the state-of-the-art on three different KBVQA datasets. Through experiments and analysis, we demonstrate that furnishing variable triples for each question improves the reasoning capabilities of the language model in contrast to supplying a fixed number of triples. This is illustrated even for recent large language models. Additionally, we highlight the model's generalization capability by showcasing its SOTA-beating performance on a small dataset, achieved through straightforward fine-tuning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09994v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Manas Jhalani, Annervaz K M, Pushpak Bhattacharyya</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FZI-WIM at SemEval-2024 Task 2: Self-Consistent CoT for Complex NLI in Biomedical Domain</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10040</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10040v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper describes the inference system of FZI-WIM at the SemEval-2024 Task 2: Safe Biomedical Natural Language Inference for Clinical Trials. Our system utilizes the chain of thought (CoT) paradigm to tackle this complex reasoning problem and further improves the CoT performance with self-consistency. Instead of greedy decoding, we sample multiple reasoning chains with the same prompt and make the final verification with majority voting. The self-consistent CoT system achieves a baseline F1 score of 0.80 (1st), faithfulness score of 0.90 (3rd), and consistency score of 0.73 (12th). We release the code and data publicly https://github.com/jens5588/FZI-WIM-NLI4CT.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10040v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>The 18th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation (SemEval-2024)</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Jin Liu, Steffen Thoma</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Evaluation of Speech Foundation Models for Spoken Language Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10083</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10083v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The Spoken Language Understanding Evaluation (SLUE) suite of benchmark tasks was recently introduced to address the need for open resources and benchmarking of complex spoken language understanding (SLU) tasks, including both classification and sequence generation tasks, on natural speech. The benchmark has demonstrated preliminary success in using pre-trained speech foundation models (SFM) for these SLU tasks. However, the community still lacks a fine-grained understanding of the comparative utility of different SFMs. Inspired by this, we ask: which SFMs offer the most benefits for these complex SLU tasks, and what is the most effective approach for incorporating these SFMs? To answer this, we perform an extensive evaluation of multiple supervised and self-supervised SFMs using several evaluation protocols: (i) frozen SFMs with a lightweight prediction head, (ii) frozen SFMs with a complex prediction head, and (iii) fine-tuned SFMs with a lightweight prediction head. Although the supervised SFMs are pre-trained on much more speech recognition data (with labels), they do not always outperform self-supervised SFMs; the latter tend to perform at least as well as, and sometimes better than, supervised SFMs, especially on the sequence generation tasks in SLUE. While there is no universally optimal way of incorporating SFMs, the complex prediction head gives the best performance for most tasks, although it increases the inference time. We also introduce an open-source toolkit and performance leaderboard, SLUE-PERB, for these tasks and modeling strategies.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10083v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Siddhant Arora, Ankita Pasad, Chung-Ming Chien, Jionghao Han, Roshan Sharma, Jee-weon Jung, Hira Dhamyal, William Chen, Suwon Shon, Hung-yi Lee, Karen Livescu, Shinji Watanabe</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Question Answering on Charts Through Effective Pre-training Tasks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10085</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10085v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: To completely understand a document, the use of textual information is not enough. Understanding visual cues, such as layouts and charts, is also required. While the current state-of-the-art approaches for document understanding (both OCR-based and OCR-free) work well, a thorough analysis of their capabilities and limitations has not yet been performed. Therefore, in this work, we addresses the limitation of current VisualQA models when applied to charts and plots. To investigate shortcomings of the state-of-the-art models, we conduct a comprehensive behavioral analysis, using ChartQA as a case study. Our findings indicate that existing models particularly underperform in answering questions related to the chart's structural and visual context, as well as numerical information. To address these issues, we propose three simple pre-training tasks that enforce the existing model in terms of both structural-visual knowledge, as well as its understanding of numerical questions. We evaluate our pre-trained model (called MatCha-v2) on three chart datasets - both extractive and abstractive question datasets - and observe that it achieves an average improvement of 1.7% over the baseline model.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10085v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ashim Gupta, Vivek Gupta, Shuo Zhang, Yujie He, Ning Zhang, Shalin Shah</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discovering influential text using convolutional neural networks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10086</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10086v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Experimental methods for estimating the impacts of text on human evaluation have been widely used in the social sciences. However, researchers in experimental settings are usually limited to testing a small number of pre-specified text treatments. While efforts to mine unstructured texts for features that causally affect outcomes have been ongoing in recent years, these models have primarily focused on the topics or specific words of text, which may not always be the mechanism of the effect. We connect these efforts with NLP interpretability techniques and present a method for flexibly discovering clusters of similar text phrases that are predictive of human reactions to texts using convolutional neural networks. When used in an experimental setting, this method can identify text treatments and their effects under certain assumptions. We apply the method to two datasets. The first enables direct validation of the model's ability to detect phrases known to cause the outcome. The second demonstrates its ability to flexibly discover text treatments with varying textual structures. In both cases, the model learns a greater variety of text treatments compared to benchmark methods, and these text features quantitatively meet or exceed the ability of benchmark methods to predict the outcome.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10086v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>stat.ME</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Megan Ayers, Luke Sanford, Margaret Roberts, Eddie Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Correlation between Human and Machine Evaluation of Simultaneous Speech Translation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10091</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10091v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Assessing the performance of interpreting services is a complex task, given the nuanced nature of spoken language translation, the strategies that interpreters apply, and the diverse expectations of users. The complexity of this task become even more pronounced when automated evaluation methods are applied. This is particularly true because interpreted texts exhibit less linearity between the source and target languages due to the strategies employed by the interpreter.
  This study aims to assess the reliability of automatic metrics in evaluating simultaneous interpretations by analyzing their correlation with human evaluations. We focus on a particular feature of interpretation quality, namely translation accuracy or faithfulness. As a benchmark we use human assessments performed by language experts, and evaluate how well sentence embeddings and Large Language Models correlate with them. We quantify semantic similarity between the source and translated texts without relying on a reference translation. The results suggest GPT models, particularly GPT-3.5 with direct prompting, demonstrate the strongest correlation with human judgment in terms of semantic similarity between source and target texts, even when evaluating short textual segments. Additionally, the study reveals that the size of the context window has a notable impact on this correlation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10091v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoman Wang, Claudio Fantinuoli</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Know the Unknown: An Uncertainty-Sensitive Method for LLM Instruction Tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10099</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10099v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated remarkable capabilities across various tasks but still face challenges such as hallucinations. One potential reason for hallucinations is the lack of relevant knowledge or context. Thus, a promising solution to mitigate this issue involves instructing LLMs to respond with "I do not know" when a question falls outside their knowledge domain or the provided context. However, in this work, we observed that LLMs struggle to admit their lack of knowledge, primarily due to existing instruction datasets designed to encourage specific answers. To improve large language models' capability to recognize the boundaries of their knowledge, we propose a novel approach called uncertainty-sensitive tuning. This method involves two-stage training designed for uncertainty recognition and prompt-sensitive activation. In the first stage, we guide the LLM to reject unknown questions. In the second stage, we recover the decreased performance in QA tasks by incorporating designed causal instructions. By leveraging this method, we aim to enhance the model's ability to identify areas of uncertainty. The experimental results demonstrate that our proposed uncertainty-sensitive tuning method significantly improves the performance of the Llama2-chat-7B model. Specifically, it achieves a substantial 34.7% improvement in handling questions involving knowledge gaps compared to the original model. Moreover, our approach outperforms GPT-4, exhibiting a 9.4% increase in overall performance. We open-source the model and code on GitHub.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10099v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiaqi Li, Yixuan Tang, Yi Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SEACrowd: A Multilingual Multimodal Data Hub and Benchmark Suite for Southeast Asian Languages</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10118</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10118v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Southeast Asia (SEA) is a region rich in linguistic diversity and cultural variety, with over 1,300 indigenous languages and a population of 671 million people. However, prevailing AI models suffer from a significant lack of representation of texts, images, and audio datasets from SEA, compromising the quality of AI models for SEA languages. Evaluating models for SEA languages is challenging due to the scarcity of high-quality datasets, compounded by the dominance of English training data, raising concerns about potential cultural misrepresentation. To address these challenges, we introduce SEACrowd, a collaborative initiative that consolidates a comprehensive resource hub that fills the resource gap by providing standardized corpora in nearly 1,000 SEA languages across three modalities. Through our SEACrowd benchmarks, we assess the quality of AI models on 36 indigenous languages across 13 tasks, offering valuable insights into the current AI landscape in SEA. Furthermore, we propose strategies to facilitate greater AI advancements, maximizing potential utility and resource equity for the future of AI in SEA.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10118v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Holy Lovenia, Rahmad Mahendra, Salsabil Maulana Akbar, Lester James V. Miranda, Jennifer Santoso, Elyanah Aco, Akhdan Fadhilah, Jonibek Mansurov, Joseph Marvin Imperial, Onno P. Kampman, Joel Ruben Antony Moniz, Muhammad Ravi Shulthan Habibi, Frederikus Hudi, Railey Montalan, Ryan Ignatius, Joanito Agili Lopo, William Nixon, B\"orje F. Karlsson, James Jaya, Ryandito Diandaru, Yuze Gao, Patrick Amadeus, Bin Wang, Jan Christian Blaise Cruz, Chenxi Whitehouse, Ivan Halim Parmonangan, Maria Khelli, Wenyu Zhang, Lucky Susanto, Reynard Adha Ryanda, Sonny Lazuardi Hermawan, Dan John Velasco, Muhammad Dehan Al Kautsar, Willy Fitra Hendria, Yasmin Moslem, Noah Flynn, Muhammad Farid Adilazuarda, Haochen Li, Johanes Lee, R. Damanhuri, Shuo Sun, Muhammad Reza Qorib, Amirbek Djanibekov, Wei Qi Leong, Quyet V. Do, Niklas Muennighoff, Tanrada Pansuwan, Ilham Firdausi Putra, Yan Xu, Ngee Chia Tai, Ayu Purwarianti, Sebastian Ruder, William Tjhi, Peerat Limkonchotiwat, Alham Fikri Aji, Sedrick Keh, Genta Indra Winata, Ruochen Zhang, Fajri Koto, Zheng-Xin Yong, Samuel Cahyawijaya</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Devil is in the Neurons: Interpreting and Mitigating Social Biases in Pre-trained Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10130</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10130v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Pre-trained Language models (PLMs) have been acknowledged to contain harmful information, such as social biases, which may cause negative social impacts or even bring catastrophic results in application. Previous works on this problem mainly focused on using black-box methods such as probing to detect and quantify social biases in PLMs by observing model outputs. As a result, previous debiasing methods mainly finetune or even pre-train language models on newly constructed anti-stereotypical datasets, which are high-cost. In this work, we try to unveil the mystery of social bias inside language models by introducing the concept of {\sc Social Bias Neurons}. Specifically, we propose {\sc Integrated Gap Gradients (IG$^2$)} to accurately pinpoint units (i.e., neurons) in a language model that can be attributed to undesirable behavior, such as social bias. By formalizing undesirable behavior as a distributional property of language, we employ sentiment-bearing prompts to elicit classes of sensitive words (demographics) correlated with such sentiments. Our IG$^2$ thus attributes the uneven distribution for different demographics to specific Social Bias Neurons, which track the trail of unwanted behavior inside PLM units to achieve interoperability. Moreover, derived from our interpretable technique, {\sc Bias Neuron Suppression (BNS)} is further proposed to mitigate social biases. By studying BERT, RoBERTa, and their attributable differences from debiased FairBERTa, IG$^2$ allows us to locate and suppress identified neurons, and further mitigate undesired behaviors. As measured by prior metrics from StereoSet, our model achieves a higher degree of fairness while maintaining language modeling ability with low cost.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10130v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yan Liu, Yu Liu, Xiaokang Chen, Pin-Yu Chen, Daoguang Zan, Min-Yen Kan, Tsung-Yi Ho</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of Large Language Models: STEM education and Gender Stereotypes</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10133</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10133v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have an increasing impact on our lives with use cases such as chatbots, study support, coding support, ideation, writing assistance, and more. Previous studies have revealed linguistic biases in pronouns used to describe professions or adjectives used to describe men vs women. These issues have to some degree been addressed in updated LLM versions, at least to pass existing tests. However, biases may still be present in the models, and repeated use of gender stereotypical language may reinforce the underlying assumptions and are therefore important to examine further. This paper investigates gender biases in LLMs in relation to educational choices through an open-ended, true to user-case experimental design and a quantitative analysis. We investigate the biases in the context of four different cultures, languages, and educational systems (English/US/UK, Danish/DK, Catalan/ES, and Hindi/IN) for ages ranging from 10 to 16 years, corresponding to important educational transition points in the different countries. We find that there are significant and large differences in the ratio of STEM to non-STEM suggested education paths provided by chatGPT when using typical girl vs boy names to prompt lists of suggested things to become. There are generally fewer STEM suggestions in the Danish, Spanish, and Indian context compared to the English. We also find subtle differences in the suggested professions, which we categorise and report.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10133v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Smilla Due, Sneha Das, Marianne Andersen, Berta Plandolit L\'opez, Sniff Andersen Nex{\o}, Line Clemmensen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BABILong: Testing the Limits of LLMs with Long Context Reasoning-in-a-Haystack</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10149</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10149v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In recent years, the input context sizes of large language models (LLMs) have increased dramatically. However, existing evaluation methods have not kept pace, failing to comprehensively assess the efficiency of models in handling long contexts. To bridge this gap, we introduce the BABILong benchmark, designed to test language models' ability to reason across facts distributed in extremely long documents. BABILong includes a diverse set of 20 reasoning tasks, including fact chaining, simple induction, deduction, counting, and handling lists/sets. These tasks are challenging on their own, and even more demanding when the required facts are scattered across long natural text. Our evaluations show that popular LLMs effectively utilize only 10-20\% of the context and their performance declines sharply with increased reasoning complexity. Among alternatives to in-context reasoning, Retrieval-Augmented Generation methods achieve a modest 60\% accuracy on single-fact question answering, independent of context length. Among context extension methods, the highest performance is demonstrated by recurrent memory transformers, enabling the processing of lengths up to 11 million tokens. The BABILong benchmark is extendable to any length to support the evaluation of new upcoming models with increased capabilities, and we provide splits up to 1 million token lengths.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10149v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuri Kuratov, Aydar Bulatov, Petr Anokhin, Ivan Rodkin, Dmitry Sorokin, Artyom Sorokin, Mikhail Burtsev</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Datasets for Multilingual Answer Sentence Selection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10172</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10172v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Answer Sentence Selection (AS2) is a critical task for designing effective retrieval-based Question Answering (QA) systems. Most advancements in AS2 focus on English due to the scarcity of annotated datasets for other languages. This lack of resources prevents the training of effective AS2 models in different languages, creating a performance gap between QA systems in English and other locales. In this paper, we introduce new high-quality datasets for AS2 in five European languages (French, German, Italian, Portuguese, and Spanish), obtained through supervised Automatic Machine Translation (AMT) of existing English AS2 datasets such as ASNQ, WikiQA, and TREC-QA using a Large Language Model (LLM). We evaluated our approach and the quality of the translated datasets through multiple experiments with different Transformer architectures. The results indicate that our datasets are pivotal in producing robust and powerful multilingual AS2 models, significantly contributing to closing the performance gap between English and other languages.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10172v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Matteo Gabburo, Stefano Campese, Federico Agostini, Alessandro Moschitti</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IntentionQA: A Benchmark for Evaluating Purchase Intention Comprehension Abilities of Language Models in E-commerce</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10173</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10173v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Enhancing Language Models' (LMs) ability to understand purchase intentions in E-commerce scenarios is crucial for their effective assistance in various downstream tasks. However, previous approaches that distill intentions from LMs often fail to generate meaningful and human-centric intentions applicable in real-world E-commerce contexts. This raises concerns about the true comprehension and utilization of purchase intentions by LMs. In this paper, we present IntentionQA, a double-task multiple-choice question answering benchmark to evaluate LMs' comprehension of purchase intentions in E-commerce. Specifically, LMs are tasked to infer intentions based on purchased products and utilize them to predict additional purchases. IntentionQA consists of 4,360 carefully curated problems across three difficulty levels, constructed using an automated pipeline to ensure scalability on large E-commerce platforms. Human evaluations demonstrate the high quality and low false-negative rate of our benchmark. Extensive experiments across 19 language models show that they still struggle with certain scenarios, such as understanding products and intentions accurately, jointly reasoning with products and intentions, and more, in which they fall far behind human performances. Our code and data are publicly available at https://github.com/HKUST-KnowComp/IntentionQA.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10173v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenxuan Ding, Weiqi Wang, Sze Heng Douglas Kwok, Minghao Liu, Tianqing Fang, Jiaxin Bai, Junxian He, Yangqiu Song</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let the Poem Hit the Rhythm: Using a Byte-Based Transformer for Beat-Aligned Poetry Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10174</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10174v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The intersection between poetry and music provides an interesting case for computational creativity, yet remains relatively unexplored. This paper explores the integration of poetry and music through the lens of beat patterns, investigating whether a byte-based language model can generate words that fit specific beat patterns within the context of poetry. Drawing on earlier studies, we developed a method to train a byte-based transformer model, ByT5, to align poems with beat patterns. The results demonstrate a high level of beat alignment while maintaining semantic coherence. Future work will aim to improve the model's ability to create complete beat-aligned poems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10174v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mohamad Elzohbi, Richard Zhao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHIRON: Rich Character Representations in Long-Form Narratives</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10190</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10190v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Characters are integral to long-form narratives, but are poorly understood by existing story analysis and generation systems. While prior work has simplified characters via graph-based methods and brief character descriptions, we aim to better tackle the problem of representing complex characters by taking inspiration from advice given to professional writers. We propose CHIRON, a new `character sheet' based representation that organizes and filters textual information about characters. We construct CHIRON sheets in two steps: a Generation Module that prompts an LLM for character information via question-answering and a Validation Module that uses automated reasoning and a domain-specific entailment model to eliminate false facts about a character. We validate CHIRON via the downstream task of masked-character prediction, where our experiments show CHIRON is better and more flexible than comparable summary-based baselines. We also show that metrics derived from CHIRON can be used to automatically infer character-centricity in stories, and that these metrics align with human judgments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10190v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alexander Gurung, Mirella Lapata</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Fundamental Trade-off in Aligned Language Models and its Relation to Sampling Adaptors</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10203</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10203v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The relationship between the quality of a string and its probability $p(\boldsymbol{y})$ under a language model has been influential in the development of techniques to build good text generation systems. For example, several decoding algorithms have been motivated to manipulate $p(\boldsymbol{y})$ to produce higher-quality text. In this work, we examine the probability--quality relationship in language models explicitly aligned to human preferences, e.g., through Reinforcement Learning through Human Feedback (RLHF). We find that, given a general language model and its aligned version, for corpora sampled from an aligned language model, there exists a trade-off between the average reward and average log-likelihood of the strings under the general language model. We provide a formal treatment of this issue and demonstrate how a choice of sampling adaptor allows for a selection of how much likelihood we exchange for the reward.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10203v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Naaman Tan, Josef Valvoda, Anej Svete, Tianyu Liu, Yanxia Qin, Kan Min-Yen, Ryan Cotterell</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be like a Goldfish, Don't Memorize! Mitigating Memorization in Generative LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10209</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10209v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models can memorize and repeat their training data, causing privacy and copyright risks. To mitigate memorization, we introduce a subtle modification to the next-token training objective that we call the goldfish loss. During training, a randomly sampled subset of tokens are excluded from the loss computation. These dropped tokens are not memorized by the model, which prevents verbatim reproduction of a complete chain of tokens from the training set. We run extensive experiments training billion-scale Llama-2 models, both pre-trained and trained from scratch, and demonstrate significant reductions in extractable memorization with little to no impact on downstream benchmarks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10209v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Abhimanyu Hans, Yuxin Wen, Neel Jain, John Kirchenbauer, Hamid Kazemi, Prajwal Singhania, Siddharth Singh, Gowthami Somepalli, Jonas Geiping, Abhinav Bhatele, Tom Goldstein</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevBench: A multimodal developmental benchmark for language learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10215</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10215v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: How (dis)similar are the learning trajectories of vision-language models and children? Recent modeling work has attempted to understand the gap between models' and humans' data efficiency by constructing models trained on less data, especially multimodal naturalistic data. However, such models are often evaluated on adult-level benchmarks, with limited breadth in language abilities tested, and without direct comparison to behavioral data. We introduce DevBench, a multimodal benchmark comprising seven language evaluation tasks spanning the domains of lexical, syntactic, and semantic ability, with behavioral data from both children and adults. We evaluate a set of vision-language models on these tasks, comparing models and humans not only on accuracy but on their response patterns. Across tasks, models exhibit variation in their closeness to human response patterns, and models that perform better on a task also more closely resemble human behavioral responses. We also examine the developmental trajectory of OpenCLIP over training, finding that greater training results in closer approximations to adult response patterns. DevBench thus provides a benchmark for comparing models to human language development. These comparisons highlight ways in which model and human language learning processes diverge, providing insight into entry points for improving language models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10215v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alvin Wei Ming Tan, Sunny Yu, Bria Long, Wanjing Anya Ma, Tonya Murray, Rebecca D. Silverman, Jason D. Yeatman, Michael C. Frank</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regularizing Hidden States Enables Learning Generalizable Reward Model for LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10216</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10216v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Reward models trained on human preference data have been proven to be effective for aligning Large Language Models (LLMs) with human intent within the reinforcement learning from human feedback (RLHF) framework. However, the generalization capabilities of current reward models to unseen prompts and responses are limited. This limitation can lead to an unexpected phenomenon known as reward over-optimization, where excessive optimization of rewards results in a decline in actual performance. While previous research has advocated for constraining policy optimization, our study proposes a novel approach to enhance the reward model's generalization ability against distribution shifts by regularizing the hidden states. Specifically, we retain the base model's language model head and incorporate a suite of text-generation losses to preserve the hidden states' text generation capabilities, while concurrently learning a reward head behind the same hidden states. Our experimental results demonstrate that the introduced regularization technique markedly improves the accuracy of learned reward models across a variety of out-of-distribution (OOD) tasks and effectively alleviate the over-optimization issue in RLHF, offering a more reliable and robust preference learning paradigm.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10216v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rui Yang, Ruomeng Ding, Yong Lin, Huan Zhang, Tong Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pandora: Towards General World Model with Natural Language Actions and Video States</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09455</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09455v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: World models simulate future states of the world in response to different actions. They facilitate interactive content creation and provides a foundation for grounded, long-horizon reasoning. Current foundation models do not fully meet the capabilities of general world models: large language models (LLMs) are constrained by their reliance on language modality and their limited understanding of the physical world, while video models lack interactive action control over the world simulations. This paper makes a step towards building a general world model by introducing Pandora, a hybrid autoregressive-diffusion model that simulates world states by generating videos and allows real-time control with free-text actions. Pandora achieves domain generality, video consistency, and controllability through large-scale pretraining and instruction tuning. Crucially, Pandora bypasses the cost of training-from-scratch by integrating a pretrained LLM (7B) and a pretrained video model, requiring only additional lightweight finetuning. We illustrate extensive outputs by Pandora across diverse domains (indoor/outdoor, natural/urban, human/robot, 2D/3D, etc.). The results indicate great potential of building stronger general world models with larger-scale training.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09455v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiannan Xiang, Guangyi Liu, Yi Gu, Qiyue Gao, Yuting Ning, Yuheng Zha, Zeyu Feng, Tianhua Tao, Shibo Hao, Yemin Shi, Zhengzhong Liu, Eric P. Xing, Zhiting Hu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Updating CLIP to Prefer Descriptions Over Captions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09458</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09458v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Although CLIPScore is a powerful generic metric that captures the similarity between a text and an image, it fails to distinguish between a caption that is meant to complement the information in an image and a description that is meant to replace an image entirely, e.g., for accessibility. We address this shortcoming by updating the CLIP model with the Concadia dataset to assign higher scores to descriptions than captions using parameter efficient fine-tuning and a loss objective derived from work on causal interpretability. This model correlates with the judgements of blind and low-vision people while preserving transfer capabilities and has interpretable structure that sheds light on the caption--description distinction.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09458v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Amir Zur, Elisa Kreiss, Karel D'Oosterlinck, Christopher Potts, Atticus Geiger</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Systematic Review of Generative AI for Teaching and Learning Practice</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09520</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09520v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The use of generative artificial intelligence (GenAI) in academia is a subjective and hotly debated topic. Currently, there are no agreed guidelines towards the usage of GenAI systems in higher education (HE) and, thus, it is still unclear how to make effective use of the technology for teaching and learning practice. This paper provides an overview of the current state of research on GenAI for teaching and learning in HE. To this end, this study conducted a systematic review of relevant studies indexed by Scopus, using the preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses (PRISMA) guidelines. The search criteria revealed a total of 625 research papers, of which 355 met the final inclusion criteria. The findings from the review showed the current state and the future trends in documents, citations, document sources/authors, keywords, and co-authorship. The research gaps identified suggest that while some authors have looked at understanding the detection of AI-generated text, it may be beneficial to understand how GenAI can be incorporated into supporting the educational curriculum for assessments, teaching, and learning delivery. Furthermore, there is a need for additional interdisciplinary, multidimensional studies in HE through collaboration. This will strengthen the awareness and understanding of students, tutors, and other stakeholders, which will be instrumental in formulating guidelines, frameworks, and policies for GenAI usage.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09520v1</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.3390/educsci14060636</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Educ. Sci. 2024, 14, pp636</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Bayode Ogunleye, Kudirat Ibilola Zakariyyah, Oluwaseun Ajao, Olakunle Olayinka, Hemlata Sharma</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating ChatGPT-4 Vision on Brazil's National Undergraduate Computer Science Exam</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09671</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09671v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The recent integration of visual capabilities into Large Language Models (LLMs) has the potential to play a pivotal role in science and technology education, where visual elements such as diagrams, charts, and tables are commonly used to improve the learning experience. This study investigates the performance of ChatGPT-4 Vision, OpenAI's most advanced visual model at the time the study was conducted, on the Bachelor in Computer Science section of Brazil's 2021 National Undergraduate Exam (ENADE). By presenting the model with the exam's open and multiple-choice questions in their original image format and allowing for reassessment in response to differing answer keys, we were able to evaluate the model's reasoning and self-reflecting capabilities in a large-scale academic assessment involving textual and visual content. ChatGPT-4 Vision significantly outperformed the average exam participant, positioning itself within the top 10 best score percentile. While it excelled in questions that incorporated visual elements, it also encountered challenges with question interpretation, logical reasoning, and visual acuity. The involvement of an independent expert panel to review cases of disagreement between the model and the answer key revealed some poorly constructed questions containing vague or ambiguous statements, calling attention to the critical need for improved question design in future exams. Our findings suggest that while ChatGPT-4 Vision shows promise in multimodal academic evaluations, human oversight remains crucial for verifying the model's accuracy and ensuring the fairness of high-stakes educational exams. The paper's research materials are publicly available at https://github.com/nabormendonca/gpt-4v-enade-cs-2021.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09671v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>ACM Transactions on Computing Education, June 2024</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Nabor C. Mendon\c{c}a</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Byte-level Representation for End-to-end ASR</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09676</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09676v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We propose a novel approach to optimizing a byte-level representation for end-to-end automatic speech recognition (ASR). Byte-level representation is often used by large scale multilingual ASR systems when the character set of the supported languages is large. The compactness and universality of byte-level representation allow the ASR models to use smaller output vocabularies and therefore, provide more flexibility. UTF-8 is a commonly used byte-level representation for multilingual ASR, but it is not designed to optimize machine learning tasks directly. By using auto-encoder and vector quantization, we show that we can optimize a byte-level representation for ASR and achieve better accuracy. Our proposed framework can incorporate information from different modalities, and provides an error correction mechanism. In an English/Mandarin dictation task, we show that a bilingual ASR model built with this approach can outperform UTF-8 representation by 5% relative in error rate.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09676v1</guid>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Roger Hsiao, Liuhui Deng, Erik McDermott, Ruchir Travadi, Xiaodan Zhuang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application of Natural Language Processing in Financial Risk Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09765</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09765v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This paper explores the application of Natural Language Processing (NLP) in financial risk detection. By constructing an NLP-based financial risk detection model, this study aims to identify and predict potential risks in financial documents and communications. First, the fundamental concepts of NLP and its theoretical foundation, including text mining methods, NLP model design principles, and machine learning algorithms, are introduced. Second, the process of text data preprocessing and feature extraction is described. Finally, the effectiveness and predictive performance of the model are validated through empirical research. The results show that the NLP-based financial risk detection model performs excellently in risk identification and prediction, providing effective risk management tools for financial institutions. This study offers valuable references for the field of financial risk management, utilizing advanced NLP techniques to improve the accuracy and efficiency of financial risk detection.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09765v1</guid>
      <category>q-fin.RM</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Liyang Wang, Yu Cheng, Ao Xiang, Jingyu Zhang, Haowei Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OSPC: Detecting Harmful Memes with Large Language Model as a Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09779</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09779v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Memes, which rapidly disseminate personal opinions and positions across the internet, also pose significant challenges in propagating social bias and prejudice. This study presents a novel approach to detecting harmful memes, particularly within the multicultural and multilingual context of Singapore. Our methodology integrates image captioning, Optical Character Recognition (OCR), and Large Language Model (LLM) analysis to comprehensively understand and classify harmful memes. Utilizing the BLIP model for image captioning, PP-OCR and TrOCR for text recognition across multiple languages, and the Qwen LLM for nuanced language understanding, our system is capable of identifying harmful content in memes created in English, Chinese, Malay, and Tamil. To enhance the system's performance, we fine-tuned our approach by leveraging additional data labeled using GPT-4V, aiming to distill the understanding capability of GPT-4V for harmful memes to our system. Our framework achieves top-1 at the public leaderboard of the Online Safety Prize Challenge hosted by AI Singapore, with the AUROC as 0.7749 and accuracy as 0.7087, significantly ahead of the other teams. Notably, our approach outperforms previous benchmarks, with FLAVA achieving an AUROC of 0.5695 and VisualBERT an AUROC of 0.5561.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09779v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3589335.3665995</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Jingtao Cao, Zheng Zhang, Hongru Wang, Bin Liang, Hao Wang, Kam-Fai Wong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Federated Learning driven Large Language Models for Swarm Intelligence: A Survey</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09831</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09831v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Federated learning (FL) offers a compelling framework for training large language models (LLMs) while addressing data privacy and decentralization challenges. This paper surveys recent advancements in the federated learning of large language models, with a particular focus on machine unlearning, a crucial aspect for complying with privacy regulations like the Right to be Forgotten. Machine unlearning in the context of federated LLMs involves systematically and securely removing individual data contributions from the learned model without retraining from scratch. We explore various strategies that enable effective unlearning, such as perturbation techniques, model decomposition, and incremental learning, highlighting their implications for maintaining model performance and data privacy. Furthermore, we examine case studies and experimental results from recent literature to assess the effectiveness and efficiency of these approaches in real-world scenarios. Our survey reveals a growing interest in developing more robust and scalable federated unlearning methods, suggesting a vital area for future research in the intersection of AI ethics and distributed machine learning technologies.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09831v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.NE</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Youyang Qu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LUMA: A Benchmark Dataset for Learning from Uncertain and Multimodal Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09864</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09864v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Multimodal Deep Learning enhances decision-making by integrating diverse information sources, such as texts, images, audio, and videos. To develop trustworthy multimodal approaches, it is essential to understand how uncertainty impacts these models. We introduce LUMA, a unique benchmark dataset, featuring audio, image, and textual data from 50 classes, for learning from uncertain and multimodal data. It extends the well-known CIFAR 10/100 dataset with audio samples extracted from three audio corpora, and text data generated using the Gemma-7B Large Language Model (LLM). The LUMA dataset enables the controlled injection of varying types and degrees of uncertainty to achieve and tailor specific experiments and benchmarking initiatives. LUMA is also available as a Python package including the functions for generating multiple variants of the dataset with controlling the diversity of the data, the amount of noise for each modality, and adding out-of-distribution samples. A baseline pre-trained model is also provided alongside three uncertainty quantification methods: Monte-Carlo Dropout, Deep Ensemble, and Reliable Conflictive Multi-View Learning. This comprehensive dataset and its tools are intended to promote and support the development and benchmarking of trustworthy and robust multimodal deep learning approaches.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09864v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Grigor Bezirganyan, Sana Sellami, Laure Berti-\'Equille, S\'ebastien Fournier</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An efficient text augmentation approach for contextualized Mandarin speech recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09950</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09950v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Although contextualized automatic speech recognition (ASR) systems are commonly used to improve the recognition of uncommon words, their effectiveness is hindered by the inherent limitations of speech-text data availability. To address this challenge, our study proposes to leverage extensive text-only datasets and contextualize pre-trained ASR models using a straightforward text-augmentation (TA) technique, all while keeping computational costs minimal. In particular, to contextualize a pre-trained CIF-based ASR, we construct a codebook using limited speech-text data. By utilizing a simple codebook lookup process, we convert available text-only data into latent text embeddings. These embeddings then enhance the inputs for the contextualized ASR. Our experiments on diverse Mandarin test sets demonstrate that our TA approach significantly boosts recognition performance. The top-performing system shows relative CER improvements of up to 30% on rare words and 15% across all words in general.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09950v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Naijun Zheng, Xucheng Wan, Kai Liu, Ziqing Du, Zhou Huan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BiVLC: Extending Vision-Language Compositionality Evaluation with Text-to-Image Retrieval</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09952</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09952v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Existing Vision-Language Compositionality (VLC) benchmarks like SugarCrepe are formulated as image-to-text retrieval problems, where, given an image, the models need to select between the correct textual description and a synthetic hard negative text. In this work we present the Bidirectional Vision-Language Compositionality (BiVLC) dataset. The novelty of BiVLC is to add a synthetic hard negative image generated from the synthetic text, resulting in two image-to-text retrieval examples (one for each image) and, more importantly, two text-to-image retrieval examples (one for each text). Human annotators filter out ill-formed examples ensuring the validity of the benchmark. The experiments on BiVLC uncover a weakness of current multimodal models, as they perform poorly in the text-to-image direction. In fact, when considering both retrieval directions, the conclusions obtained in previous works change significantly. In addition to the benchmark, we show that a contrastive model trained using synthetic images and texts improves the state of the art in SugarCrepe and in BiVLC for both retrieval directions. The gap to human performance in BiVLC confirms that Vision-Language Compositionality is still a challenging problem. BiVLC and code are available at https://imirandam.github.io/BiVLC_project_page.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09952v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Imanol Miranda, Ander Salaberria, Eneko Agirre, Gorka Azkune</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChartMimic: Evaluating LMM's Cross-Modal Reasoning Capability via Chart-to-Code Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09961</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09961v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We introduce a new benchmark, ChartMimic, aimed at assessing the visually-grounded code generation capabilities of large multimodal models (LMMs). ChartMimic utilizes information-intensive visual charts and textual instructions as inputs, requiring LMMs to generate the corresponding code for chart rendering. ChartMimic includes 1,000 human-curated (figure, instruction, code) triplets, which represent the authentic chart use cases found in scientific papers across various domains(e.g., Physics, Computer Science, Economics, etc). These charts span 18 regular types and 4 advanced types, diversifying into 191 subcategories. Furthermore, we propose multi-level evaluation metrics to provide an automatic and thorough assessment of the output code and the rendered charts. Unlike existing code generation benchmarks, ChartMimic places emphasis on evaluating LMMs' capacity to harmonize a blend of cognitive capabilities, encompassing visual understanding, code generation, and cross-modal reasoning. The evaluation of 3 proprietary models and 11 open-weight models highlights the substantial challenges posed by ChartMimic. Even the advanced GPT-4V, Claude-3-opus only achieve an average score of 73.2 and 53.7, respectively, indicating significant room for improvement. We anticipate that ChartMimic will inspire the development of LMMs, advancing the pursuit of artificial general intelligence.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09961v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chufan Shi, Cheng Yang, Yaxin Liu, Bo Shui, Junjie Wang, Mohan Jing, Linran Xu, Xinyu Zhu, Siheng Li, Yuxiang Zhang, Gongye Liu, Xiaomei Nie, Deng Cai, Yujiu Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Details Make a Difference: Object State-Sensitive Neurorobotic Task Planning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09988</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09988v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The state of an object reflects its current status or condition and is important for a robot's task planning and manipulation. However, detecting an object's state and generating a state-sensitive plan for robots is challenging. Recently, pre-trained Large Language Models (LLMs) and Vision-Language Models (VLMs) have shown impressive capabilities in generating plans. However, to the best of our knowledge, there is hardly any investigation on whether LLMs or VLMs can also generate object state-sensitive plans. To study this, we introduce an Object State-Sensitive Agent (OSSA), a task-planning agent empowered by pre-trained neural networks. We propose two methods for OSSA: (i) a modular model consisting of a pre-trained vision processing module (dense captioning model, DCM) and a natural language processing model (LLM), and (ii) a monolithic model consisting only of a VLM. To quantitatively evaluate the performances of the two methods, we use tabletop scenarios where the task is to clear the table. We contribute a multimodal benchmark dataset that takes object states into consideration. Our results show that both methods can be used for object state-sensitive tasks, but the monolithic approach outperforms the modular approach. The code for OSSA is available at \url{https://github.com/Xiao-wen-Sun/OSSA}</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09988v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaowen Sun, Xufeng Zhao, Jae Hee Lee, Wenhao Lu, Matthias Kerzel, Stefan Wermter</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Group and Shuffle: Efficient Structured Orthogonal Parametrization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10019</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10019v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The increasing size of neural networks has led to a growing demand for methods of efficient fine-tuning. Recently, an orthogonal fine-tuning paradigm was introduced that uses orthogonal matrices for adapting the weights of a pretrained model. In this paper, we introduce a new class of structured matrices, which unifies and generalizes structured classes from previous works. We examine properties of this class and build a structured orthogonal parametrization upon it. We then use this parametrization to modify the orthogonal fine-tuning framework, improving parameter and computational efficiency. We empirically validate our method on different domains, including adapting of text-to-image diffusion models and downstream task fine-tuning in language modeling. Additionally, we adapt our construction for orthogonal convolutions and conduct experiments with 1-Lipschitz neural networks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10019v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.NA</category>
      <category>math.NA</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mikhail Gorbunov, Nikolay Yudin, Vera Soboleva, Aibek Alanov, Alexey Naumov, Maxim Rakhuba</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Bayesian Active Learning for Preference Modeling in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10023</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10023v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Leveraging human preferences for steering the behavior of Large Language Models (LLMs) has demonstrated notable success in recent years. Nonetheless, data selection and labeling are still a bottleneck for these systems, particularly at large scale. Hence, selecting the most informative points for acquiring human feedback may considerably reduce the cost of preference labeling and unleash the further development of LLMs. Bayesian Active Learning provides a principled framework for addressing this challenge and has demonstrated remarkable success in diverse settings. However, previous attempts to employ it for Preference Modeling did not meet such expectations. In this work, we identify that naive epistemic uncertainty estimation leads to the acquisition of redundant samples. We address this by proposing the Bayesian Active Learner for Preference Modeling (BAL-PM), a novel stochastic acquisition policy that not only targets points of high epistemic uncertainty according to the preference model but also seeks to maximize the entropy of the acquired prompt distribution in the feature space spanned by the employed LLM. Notably, our experiments demonstrate that BAL-PM requires 33% to 68% fewer preference labels in two popular human preference datasets and exceeds previous stochastic Bayesian acquisition policies.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10023v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Luckeciano C. Melo, Panagiotis Tigas, Alessandro Abate, Yarin Gal</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simul-Whisper: Attention-Guided Streaming Whisper with Truncation Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10052</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10052v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: As a robust and large-scale multilingual speech recognition model, Whisper has demonstrated impressive results in many low-resource and out-of-distribution scenarios. However, its encoder-decoder structure hinders its application to streaming speech recognition. In this paper, we introduce Simul-Whisper, which uses the time alignment embedded in Whisper's cross-attention to guide auto-regressive decoding and achieve chunk-based streaming ASR without any fine-tuning of the pre-trained model. Furthermore, we observe the negative effect of the truncated words at the chunk boundaries on the decoding results and propose an integrate-and-fire-based truncation detection model to address this issue. Experiments on multiple languages and Whisper architectures show that Simul-Whisper achieves an average absolute word error rate degradation of only 1.46% at a chunk size of 1 second, which significantly outperforms the current state-of-the-art baseline.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10052v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haoyu Wang, Guoqiang Hu, Guodong Lin, Wei-Qiang Zhang, Jian Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Detecting the terminality of speech-turn boundary for spoken interactions in French TV and Radio content</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10073</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10073v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Transition Relevance Places are defined as the end of an utterance where the interlocutor may take the floor without interrupting the current speaker --i.e., a place where the turn is terminal. Analyzing turn terminality is useful to study the dynamic of turn-taking in spontaneous conversations. This paper presents an automatic classification of spoken utterances as Terminal or Non-Terminal in multi-speaker settings. We compared audio, text, and fusions of both approaches on a French corpus of TV and Radio extracts annotated with turn-terminality information at each speaker change. Our models are based on pre-trained self-supervised representations. We report results for different fusion strategies and varying context sizes. This study also questions the problem of performance variability by analyzing the differences in results for multiple training runs with random initialization. The measured accuracy would allow the use of these models for large-scale analysis of turn-taking.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10073v1</guid>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>R\'emi Uro, Marie Tahon, David Doukhan, Antoine Laurent, Albert Rilliard</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sycophancy to Subterfuge: Investigating Reward-Tampering in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10162</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10162v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In reinforcement learning, specification gaming occurs when AI systems learn undesired behaviors that are highly rewarded due to misspecified training goals. Specification gaming can range from simple behaviors like sycophancy to sophisticated and pernicious behaviors like reward-tampering, where a model directly modifies its own reward mechanism. However, these more pernicious behaviors may be too complex to be discovered via exploration. In this paper, we study whether Large Language Model (LLM) assistants which find easily discovered forms of specification gaming will generalize to perform rarer and more blatant forms, up to and including reward-tampering. We construct a curriculum of increasingly sophisticated gameable environments and find that training on early-curriculum environments leads to more specification gaming on remaining environments. Strikingly, a small but non-negligible proportion of the time, LLM assistants trained on the full curriculum generalize zero-shot to directly rewriting their own reward function. Retraining an LLM not to game early-curriculum environments mitigates, but does not eliminate, reward-tampering in later environments. Moreover, adding harmlessness training to our gameable environments does not prevent reward-tampering. These results demonstrate that LLMs can generalize from common forms of specification gaming to more pernicious reward tampering and that such behavior may be nontrivial to remove.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10162v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Carson Denison, Monte MacDiarmid, Fazl Barez, David Duvenaud, Shauna Kravec, Samuel Marks, Nicholas Schiefer, Ryan Soklaski, Alex Tamkin, Jared Kaplan, Buck Shlegeris, Samuel R. Bowman, Ethan Perez, Evan Hubinger</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inclusive ASR for Disfluent Speech: Cascaded Large-Scale Self-Supervised Learning with Targeted Fine-Tuning and Data Augmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10177</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10177v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Automatic speech recognition (ASR) systems often falter while processing stuttering-related disfluencies -- such as involuntary blocks and word repetitions -- yielding inaccurate transcripts. A critical barrier to progress is the scarcity of large, annotated disfluent speech datasets. Therefore, we present an inclusive ASR design approach, leveraging large-scale self-supervised learning on standard speech followed by targeted fine-tuning and data augmentation on a smaller, curated dataset of disfluent speech. Our data augmentation technique enriches training datasets with various disfluencies, enhancing ASR processing of these speech patterns. Results show that fine-tuning wav2vec 2.0 with even a relatively small, labeled dataset, alongside data augmentation, can significantly reduce word error rates for disfluent speech. Our approach not only advances ASR inclusivity for people who stutter, but also paves the way for ASRs that can accommodate wider speech variations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10177v1</guid>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dena Mujtaba, Nihar R. Mahapatra, Megan Arney, J. Scott Yaruss, Caryn Herring, Jia Bin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Short Film Dataset (SFD): A Benchmark for Story-Level Video Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10221</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10221v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recent advances in vision-language models have significantly propelled video understanding. Existing datasets and tasks, however, have notable limitations. Most datasets are confined to short videos with limited events and narrow narratives. For example, datasets with instructional and egocentric videos often document the activities of one person in a single scene. Although some movie datasets offer richer content, they are often limited to short-term tasks, lack publicly available videos and frequently encounter data leakage given the use of movie forums and other resources in LLM training. To address the above limitations, we propose the Short Film Dataset (SFD) with 1,078 publicly available amateur movies, a wide variety of genres and minimal data leakage issues. SFD offers long-term story-oriented video tasks in the form of multiple-choice and open-ended question answering. Our extensive experiments emphasize the need for long-term reasoning to solve SFD tasks. Notably, we find strong signals in movie transcripts leading to the on-par performance of people and LLMs. We also show significantly lower performance of current models compared to people when using vision data alone.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10221v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ridouane Ghermi, Xi Wang, Vicky Kalogeiton, Ivan Laptev</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VEGA: Learning Interleaved Image-Text Comprehension in Vision-Language Large Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10228</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10228v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The swift progress of Multi-modal Large Models (MLLMs) has showcased their impressive ability to tackle tasks blending vision and language. Yet, most current models and benchmarks cater to scenarios with a narrow scope of visual and textual contexts. These models often fall short when faced with complex comprehension tasks, which involve navigating through a plethora of irrelevant and potentially misleading information in both text and image forms. To bridge this gap, we introduce a new, more demanding task known as Interleaved Image-Text Comprehension (IITC). This task challenges models to discern and disregard superfluous elements in both images and text to accurately answer questions and to follow intricate instructions to pinpoint the relevant image. In support of this task, we further craft a new VEGA dataset, tailored for the IITC task on scientific content, and devised a subtask, Image-Text Association (ITA), to refine image-text correlation skills. Our evaluation of four leading closed-source models, as well as various open-source models using VEGA, underscores the rigorous nature of IITC. Even the most advanced models, such as Gemini-1.5-pro and GPT4V, only achieved modest success. By employing a multi-task, multi-scale post-training strategy, we have set a robust baseline for MLLMs on the IITC task, attaining an $85.8\%$ accuracy rate in image association and a $0.508$ Rouge score. These results validate the effectiveness of our dataset in improving MLLMs capabilities for nuanced image-text comprehension.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10228v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chenyu Zhou, Mengdan Zhang, Peixian Chen, Chaoyou Fu, Yunhang Shen, Xiawu Zheng, Xing Sun, Rongrong Ji</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SDA: Simple Discrete Augmentation for Contrastive Sentence Representation Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2210.03963</link>
      <description>arXiv:2210.03963v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Contrastive learning has recently achieved compelling performance in unsupervised sentence representation. As an essential element, data augmentation protocols, however, have not been well explored. The pioneering work SimCSE resorting to a simple dropout mechanism (viewed as continuous augmentation) surprisingly dominates discrete augmentations such as cropping, word deletion, and synonym replacement as reported. To understand the underlying rationales, we revisit existing approaches and attempt to hypothesize the desiderata of reasonable data augmentation methods: balance of semantic consistency and expression diversity. We then develop three simple yet effective discrete sentence augmentation schemes: punctuation insertion, modal verbs, and double negation. They act as minimal noises at lexical level to produce diverse forms of sentences. Furthermore, standard negation is capitalized on to generate negative samples for alleviating feature suppression involved in contrastive learning. We experimented extensively with semantic textual similarity on diverse datasets. The results support the superiority of the proposed methods consistently. Our key code is available at https://github.com/Zhudongsheng75/SDA</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2210.03963v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dongsheng Zhu, Zhenyu Mao, Jinghui Lu, Rui Zhao, Fei Tan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multilingual Machine Translation with Large Language Models: Empirical Results and Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2304.04675</link>
      <description>arXiv:2304.04675v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated remarkable potential in handling multilingual machine translation (MMT). In this paper, we systematically investigate the advantages and challenges of LLMs for MMT by answering two questions: 1) How well do LLMs perform in translating massive languages? 2) Which factors affect LLMs' performance in translation? We thoroughly evaluate eight popular LLMs, including ChatGPT and GPT-4. Our empirical results show that translation capabilities of LLMs are continually involving. GPT-4 has beat the strong supervised baseline NLLB in 40.91% of translation directions but still faces a large gap towards the commercial translation system like Google Translate, especially on low-resource languages. Through further analysis, we discover that LLMs exhibit new working patterns when used for MMT. First, LLM can acquire translation ability in a resource-efficient way and generate moderate translation even on zero-resource languages. Second, instruction semantics can surprisingly be ignored when given in-context exemplars. Third, cross-lingual exemplars can provide better task guidance for low-resource translation than exemplars in the same language pairs. Code will be released at: https://github.com/NJUNLP/MMT-LLM.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2304.04675v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenhao Zhu, Hongyi Liu, Qingxiu Dong, Jingjing Xu, Shujian Huang, Lingpeng Kong, Jiajun Chen, Lei Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unsupervised extraction of local and global keywords from a single text</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2307.14005</link>
      <description>arXiv:2307.14005v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We propose an unsupervised, corpus-independent method to extract keywords from a single text. It is based on the spatial distribution of words and the response of this distribution to a random permutation of words. As compared to existing methods (such as e.g. YAKE) our method has three advantages. First, it is significantly more effective at extracting keywords from long texts. Second, it allows inference of two types of keywords: local and global. Third, it uncovers basic themes in texts. Additionally, our method is language-independent and applies to short texts. The results are obtained via human annotators with previous knowledge of texts from our database of classical literary works (the agreement between annotators is from moderate to substantial). Our results are supported via human-independent arguments based on the average length of extracted content words and on the average number of nouns in extracted words. We discuss relations of keywords with higher-order textual features and reveal a connection between keywords and chapter divisions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2307.14005v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.DL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lida Aleksanyan, Armen E. Allahverdyan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards the TopMost: A Topic Modeling System Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2309.06908</link>
      <description>arXiv:2309.06908v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Topic models have a rich history with various applications and have recently been reinvigorated by neural topic modeling. However, these numerous topic models adopt totally distinct datasets, implementations, and evaluations. This impedes quick utilization and fair comparisons, and thereby hinders their research progress and applications. To tackle this challenge, we in this paper propose a Topic Modeling System Toolkit (TopMost). Compared to existing toolkits, TopMost stands out by supporting more extensive features. It covers a broader spectrum of topic modeling scenarios with their complete lifecycles, including datasets, preprocessing, models, training, and evaluations. Thanks to its highly cohesive and decoupled modular design, TopMost enables rapid utilization, fair comparisons, and flexible extensions of diverse cutting-edge topic models. Our code, tutorials, and documentation are available at https://github.com/bobxwu/topmost.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2309.06908v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaobao Wu, Fengjun Pan, Anh Tuan Luu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Context Utilization in Summarization with Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.10570</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.10570v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) excel in abstractive summarization tasks, delivering fluent and pertinent summaries. Recent advancements have extended their capabilities to handle long-input contexts, exceeding 100k tokens. However, in question answering, language models exhibit uneven utilization of their input context. They tend to favor the initial and final segments, resulting in a U-shaped performance pattern concerning where the answer is located within the input. This bias raises concerns, particularly in summarization where crucial content may be dispersed throughout the source document(s). Besides, in summarization, mapping facts from the source to the summary is not trivial as salient content is usually re-phrased. In this paper, we conduct the first comprehensive study on context utilization and position bias in summarization. Our analysis encompasses 6 LLMs, 10 datasets, and 5 evaluation metrics. We introduce a new evaluation benchmark called MiddleSum on the which we benchmark two alternative inference methods to alleviate position bias: hierarchical summarization and incremental summarization. Our code and data can be found here: https://github.com/ntunlp/MiddleSum.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.10570v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mathieu Ravaut, Aixin Sun, Nancy F. Chen, Shafiq Joty</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COSMIC: Data Efficient Instruction-tuning For Speech In-Context Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.02248</link>
      <description>arXiv:2311.02248v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We present a cost-effective method to integrate speech into a large language model (LLM), resulting in a Contextual Speech Model with Instruction-following/in-context-learning Capabilities (COSMIC) multi-modal LLM. Using GPT-3.5, we generate Speech Comprehension Test Question-Answer (SQA) pairs from speech transcriptions for supervised instruction tuning. With under 30 million trainable parameters and only 450 hours of English speech data, COSMIC demonstrates emerging capabilities in instruction-following and in-context learning. Equipped with such capabilities, COSMIC achieves a maximum 33.18 BLEU score in 0-shot EN-to-X speech to text translation (S2TT) and a significant boost in the 1-shot setting. Additionally, there is an average 25.8\% relative Word Error Rate (WER) reduction for 1-shot cross-domain adaptation. COSMIC exhibits a significant automatic speech recognition (ASR) accuracy gain in contextual biasing tasks due to its instruction-following capability.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2311.02248v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jing Pan, Jian Wu, Yashesh Gaur, Sunit Sivasankaran, Zhuo Chen, Shujie Liu, Jinyu Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GRASP: A Disagreement Analysis Framework to Assess Group Associations in Perspectives</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.05074</link>
      <description>arXiv:2311.05074v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Human annotation plays a core role in machine learning -- annotations for supervised models, safety guardrails for generative models, and human feedback for reinforcement learning, to cite a few avenues. However, the fact that many of these human annotations are inherently subjective is often overlooked. Recent work has demonstrated that ignoring rater subjectivity (typically resulting in rater disagreement) is problematic within specific tasks and for specific subgroups. Generalizable methods to harness rater disagreement and thus understand the socio-cultural leanings of subjective tasks remain elusive. In this paper, we propose GRASP, a comprehensive disagreement analysis framework to measure group association in perspectives among different rater sub-groups, and demonstrate its utility in assessing the extent of systematic disagreements in two datasets: (1) safety annotations of human-chatbot conversations, and (2) offensiveness annotations of social media posts, both annotated by diverse rater pools across different socio-demographic axes. Our framework (based on disagreement metrics) reveals specific rater groups that have significantly different perspectives than others on certain tasks, and helps identify demographic axes that are crucial to consider in specific task contexts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2311.05074v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>2024 Annual Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Vinodkumar Prabhakaran, Christopher Homan, Lora Aroyo, Aida Mostafazadeh Davani, Alicia Parrish, Alex Taylor, Mark D\'iaz, Ding Wang, Gregory Serapio-Garc\'ia</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Authorship Attribution Models Distinguish Speakers in Speech Transcripts?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.07564</link>
      <description>arXiv:2311.07564v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Authorship verification is the task of determining if two distinct writing samples share the same author and is typically concerned with the attribution of written text. In this paper, we explore the attribution of transcribed speech, which poses novel challenges. The main challenge is that many stylistic features, such as punctuation and capitalization, are not informative in this setting. On the other hand, transcribed speech exhibits other patterns, such as filler words and backchannels (e.g., 'um', 'uh-huh'), which may be characteristic of different speakers. We propose a new benchmark for speaker attribution focused on human-transcribed conversational speech transcripts. To limit spurious associations of speakers with topic, we employ both conversation prompts and speakers participating in the same conversation to construct verification trials of varying difficulties. We establish the state of the art on this new benchmark by comparing a suite of neural and non-neural baselines, finding that although written text attribution models achieve surprisingly good performance in certain settings, they perform markedly worse as conversational topic is increasingly controlled. We present analyses of the impact of transcription style on performance as well as the ability of fine-tuning on speech transcripts to improve performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2311.07564v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Cristina Aggazzotti, Nicholas Andrews, Elizabeth Allyn Smith</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identifying Self-Disclosures of Use, Misuse and Addiction in Community-based Social Media Posts</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.09066</link>
      <description>arXiv:2311.09066v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In the last decade, the United States has lost more than 500,000 people from an overdose involving prescription and illicit opioids making it a national public health emergency (USDHHS, 2017). Medical practitioners require robust and timely tools that can effectively identify at-risk patients. Community-based social media platforms such as Reddit allow self-disclosure for users to discuss otherwise sensitive drug-related behaviors. We present a moderate size corpus of 2500 opioid-related posts from various subreddits labeled with six different phases of opioid use: Medical Use, Misuse, Addiction, Recovery, Relapse, Not Using. For every post, we annotate span-level extractive explanations and crucially study their role both in annotation quality and model development. We evaluate several state-of-the-art models in a supervised, few-shot, or zero-shot setting. Experimental results and error analysis show that identifying the phases of opioid use disorder is highly contextual and challenging. However, we find that using explanations during modeling leads to a significant boost in classification accuracy demonstrating their beneficial role in a high-stakes domain such as studying the opioid use disorder continuum.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2311.09066v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chenghao Yang, Tuhin Chakrabarty, Karli R Hochstatter, Melissa N Slavin, Nabila El-Bassel, Smaranda Muresan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Reversal Curse and Other Deductive Logical Reasoning in BERT and GPT-Based Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.03633</link>
      <description>arXiv:2312.03633v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The term "Reversal Curse" refers to the scenario where auto-regressive decoder large language models (LLMs), such as ChatGPT, trained on "A is B" fail to learn "B is A," assuming that B and A are distinct and can be uniquely identified from each other, demonstrating a basic failure of logical deduction. This raises a red flag in the use of GPT models for certain general tasks such as constructing knowledge graphs, considering their adherence to this symmetric principle. In our study, we examined a bidirectional LLM, BERT, and found that it is immune to the reversal curse. Driven by ongoing efforts to construct biomedical knowledge graphs with LLMs, we also embarked on evaluating more complex but essential deductive reasoning capabilities. This process included first training encoder and decoder language models to master the intersection and union operations on two sets and then moving on to assess their capability to infer different combinations of union and intersection operations on three newly created sets. The findings showed that while both encoder and decoder language models, trained for tasks involving two sets (union/intersection), were proficient in such scenarios, they encountered difficulties when dealing with operations that included three sets (various combinations of union and intersection). Our research highlights the distinct characteristics of encoder and decoder models in simple and complex logical reasoning. In practice, the choice between BERT and GPT should be guided by the specific requirements and nature of the task at hand, leveraging their respective strengths in bidirectional context comprehension and sequence prediction.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2312.03633v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Da Wu, Jingye Yang, Kai Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cross-Subject Data Splitting for Brain-to-Text Decoding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.10987</link>
      <description>arXiv:2312.10987v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent major milestones have successfully decoded non-invasive brain signals (e.g. functional Magnetic Resonance Imaging (fMRI) and electroencephalogram (EEG)) into natural language. Despite the progress in model design, how to split the datasets for training, validating, and testing still remains a matter of debate. Most of the prior researches applied subject-specific data splitting, where the decoding model is trained and evaluated per subject. Such splitting method poses challenges to the utilization efficiency of dataset as well as the generalization of models. In this study, we propose a cross-subject data splitting criterion for brain-to-text decoding on various types of cognitive dataset (fMRI, EEG), aiming to maximize dataset utilization and improve model generalization. We undertake a comprehensive analysis on existing cross-subject data splitting strategies and prove that all these methods suffer from data leakage, namely the leakage of test data to training set, which significantly leads to overfitting and overestimation of decoding models. The proposed cross-subject splitting method successfully addresses the data leakage problem and we re-evaluate some SOTA brain-to-text decoding models as baselines for further research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2312.10987v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Congchi Yin, Qian Yu, Zhiwei Fang, Jie He, Changping Peng, Zhangang Lin, Jingping Shao, Piji Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FinDABench: Benchmarking Financial Data Analysis Ability of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02982</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.02982v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated impressive capabilities across a wide range of tasks. However, their proficiency and reliability in the specialized domain of financial data analysis, particularly focusing on data-driven thinking, remain uncertain. To bridge this gap, we introduce \texttt{FinDABench}, a comprehensive benchmark designed to evaluate the financial data analysis capabilities of LLMs within this context. \texttt{FinDABench} assesses LLMs across three dimensions: 1) \textbf{Foundational Ability}, evaluating the models' ability to perform financial numerical calculation and corporate sentiment risk assessment; 2) \textbf{Reasoning Ability}, determining the models' ability to quickly comprehend textual information and analyze abnormal financial reports; and 3) \textbf{Technical Skill}, examining the models' use of technical knowledge to address real-world data analysis challenges involving analysis generation and charts visualization from multiple perspectives. We will release \texttt{FinDABench}, and the evaluation scripts at \url{https://github.com/cubenlp/BIBench}. \texttt{FinDABench} aims to provide a measure for in-depth analysis of LLM abilities and foster the advancement of LLMs in the field of financial data analysis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.02982v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shu Liu, Shangqing Zhao, Chenghao Jia, Xinlin Zhuang, Zhaoguang Long, Jie Zhou, Aimin Zhou, Man Lan, Qingquan Wu, Chong Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Proficient Are Large Language Models in Formal Languages? An In-Depth Insight for Knowledge Base Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05777</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.05777v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Knowledge Base Question Answering (KBQA) aims to answer natural language questions based on facts in knowledge bases. A typical approach to KBQA is semantic parsing, which translates a question into an executable logical form in a formal language. Recent works leverage the capabilities of large language models (LLMs) for logical form generation to improve performance. However, although it is validated that LLMs are capable of solving some KBQA problems, there has been little discussion on the differences in LLMs' proficiency in formal languages used in semantic parsing. In this work, we propose to evaluate the understanding and generation ability of LLMs to deal with differently structured logical forms by examining the inter-conversion of natural and formal language through in-context learning of LLMs. Extensive experiments with models of different sizes show that state-of-the-art LLMs can understand formal languages as well as humans, but generating correct logical forms given a few examples remains a challenge. Most importantly, our results also indicate that LLMs exhibit considerable sensitivity. In general, the formal language with a lower formalization level, i.e., the more similar it is to natural language, is more friendly to LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.05777v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jinxin Liu, Shulin Cao, Jiaxin Shi, Tingjian Zhang, Lunyiu Nie, Linmei Hu, Lei Hou, Juanzi Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quality Does Matter: A Detailed Look at the Quality and Utility of Web-Mined Parallel Corpora</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.07446</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.07446v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We conducted a detailed analysis on the quality of web-mined corpora for two low-resource languages (making three language pairs, English-Sinhala, English-Tamil and Sinhala-Tamil). We ranked each corpus according to a similarity measure and carried out an intrinsic and extrinsic evaluation on different portions of this ranked corpus. We show that there are significant quality differences between different portions of web-mined corpora and that the quality varies across languages and datasets. We also show that, for some web-mined datasets, Neural Machine Translation (NMT) models trained with their highest-ranked 25k portion can be on par with human-curated datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.07446v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Surangika Ranathunga, Nisansa de Silva, Menan Velayuthan, Aloka Fernando, Charitha Rathnayake</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>QuRating: Selecting High-Quality Data for Training Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09739</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.09739v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Selecting high-quality pre-training data is important for creating capable language models, but existing methods rely on simple heuristics. We introduce QuRating, a method for selecting pre-training data that can capture human intuitions about data quality. In this paper, we investigate four qualities - writing style, required expertise, facts &amp; trivia, and educational value - and find that LLMs are able to discern these qualities, especially when making pairwise judgments of texts. We train a QuRater model to learn scalar ratings from pairwise judgments, and use it to annotate a 260B training corpus with quality ratings for each of the four criteria. In our experiments, we select 30B tokens according to the different quality ratings and train 1.3B-parameter language models on the selected data. We find that it is important to balance quality and diversity. When we sample using quality ratings as logits over documents, our models obtain lower perplexity and stronger in-context learning performance than baselines. Our best model is based on educational value and performs similarly to a model trained with uniform sampling for 50% more steps. Beyond data selection, we use the quality ratings to construct a training curriculum which improves performance without changing the training dataset. We extensively analyze the quality ratings and discuss their characteristics, biases, and wider implications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.09739v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alexander Wettig, Aatmik Gupta, Saumya Malik, Danqi Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FinTral: A Family of GPT-4 Level Multimodal Financial Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.10986</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.10986v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We introduce FinTral, a suite of state-of-the-art multimodal large language models (LLMs) built upon the Mistral-7b model and tailored for financial analysis. FinTral integrates textual, numerical, tabular, and image data. We enhance FinTral with domain-specific pretraining, instruction fine-tuning, and RLAIF training by exploiting a large collection of textual and visual datasets we curate for this work. We also introduce an extensive benchmark featuring nine tasks and 25 datasets for evaluation, including hallucinations in the financial domain. Our FinTral model trained with direct preference optimization employing advanced Tools and Retrieval methods, dubbed FinTral-DPO-T&amp;R, demonstrates an exceptional zero-shot performance. It outperforms ChatGPT-3.5 in all tasks and surpasses GPT-4 in five out of nine tasks, marking a significant advancement in AI-driven financial technology. We also demonstrate that FinTral has the potential to excel in real-time analysis and decision-making in diverse financial contexts. The GitHub repository for FinTral is available at \url{https://github.com/UBC-NLP/fintral}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.10986v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gagan Bhatia, El Moatez Billah Nagoudi, Hasan Cavusoglu, Muhammad Abdul-Mageed</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MORE: Multi-mOdal REtrieval Augmented Generative Commonsense Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.13625</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.13625v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Since commonsense information has been recorded significantly less frequently than its existence, language models pre-trained by text generation have difficulty to learn sufficient commonsense knowledge. Several studies have leveraged text retrieval to augment the models' commonsense ability. Unlike text, images capture commonsense information inherently but little effort has been paid to effectively utilize them. In this work, we propose a novel Multi-mOdal REtrieval (MORE) augmentation framework, to leverage both text and images to enhance the commonsense ability of language models. Extensive experiments on the Common-Gen task have demonstrated the efficacy of MORE based on the pre-trained models of both single and multiple modalities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.13625v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wanqing Cui, Keping Bi, Jiafeng Guo, Xueqi Cheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Robust Instruction Tuning on Multimodal Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.14492</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.14492v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Fine-tuning large language models (LLMs) on multi-task instruction-following data has been proven to be a powerful learning paradigm for improving their zero-shot capabilities on new tasks. Recent works about high-quality instruction-following data generation and selection require amounts of human labor to conceive model-understandable instructions for the given tasks and carefully filter the LLM-generated data. In this work, we introduce an automatic instruction augmentation method named INSTRAUG in multimodal tasks. It starts from a handful of basic and straightforward meta instructions but can expand an instruction-following dataset by 30 times. Results on two popular multimodal instructionfollowing benchmarks MULTIINSTRUCT and InstructBLIP show that INSTRAUG can significantly improve the alignment of multimodal large language models (MLLMs) across 12 multimodal tasks, which is even equivalent to the benefits of scaling up training data multiple times.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.14492v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wei Han, Hui Chen, Soujanya Poria</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Large Language Models for Learning Complex Legal Concepts through Storytelling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.17019</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.17019v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Making legal knowledge accessible to non-experts is crucial for enhancing general legal literacy and encouraging civic participation in democracy. However, legal documents are often challenging to understand for people without legal backgrounds. In this paper, we present a novel application of large language models (LLMs) in legal education to help non-experts learn intricate legal concepts through storytelling, an effective pedagogical tool in conveying complex and abstract concepts. We also introduce a new dataset LegalStories, which consists of 294 complex legal doctrines, each accompanied by a story and a set of multiple-choice questions generated by LLMs. To construct the dataset, we experiment with various LLMs to generate legal stories explaining these concepts. Furthermore, we use an expert-in-the-loop approach to iteratively design multiple-choice questions. Then, we evaluate the effectiveness of storytelling with LLMs through randomized controlled trials (RCTs) with legal novices on 10 samples from the dataset. We find that LLM-generated stories enhance comprehension of legal concepts and interest in law among non-native speakers compared to only definitions. Moreover, stories consistently help participants relate legal concepts to their lives. Finally, we find that learning with stories shows a higher retention rate for non-native speakers in the follow-up assessment. Our work has strong implications for using LLMs in promoting teaching and learning in the legal field and beyond.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.17019v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hang Jiang, Xiajie Zhang, Robert Mahari, Daniel Kessler, Eric Ma, Tal August, Irene Li, Alex 'Sandy' Pentland, Yoon Kim, Jad Kabbara, Deb Roy</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EUROPA: A Legal Multilingual Keyphrase Generation Dataset</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.00252</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.00252v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Keyphrase generation has primarily been explored within the context of academic research articles, with a particular focus on scientific domains and the English language. In this work, we present EUROPA, a dataset for multilingual keyphrase generation in the legal domain. It is derived from legal judgments from the Court of Justice of the European Union (EU), and contains instances in all 24 EU official languages. We run multilingual models on our corpus and analyze the results, showing room for improvement on a domain-specific multilingual corpus such as the one we present.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.00252v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Olivier Sala\"un, Fr\'ed\'eric Piedboeuf, Guillaume Le Berre, David Alfonso Hermelo, Philippe Langlais</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Modular Approach for Multimodal Summarization of TV Shows</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.03823</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.03823v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this paper we address the task of summarizing television shows, which touches key areas in AI research: complex reasoning, multiple modalities, and long narratives. We present a modular approach where separate components perform specialized sub-tasks which we argue affords greater flexibility compared to end-to-end methods. Our modules involve detecting scene boundaries, reordering scenes so as to minimize the number of cuts between different events, converting visual information to text, summarizing the dialogue in each scene, and fusing the scene summaries into a final summary for the entire episode. We also present a new metric, PREFS (Precision and Recall Evaluation of Summary FactS), to measure both precision and recall of generated summaries, which we decompose into atomic facts. Tested on the recently released SummScreen3D dataset Papalampidi and Lapata (2023), our method produces higher quality summaries than comparison models, as measured with ROUGE and our new fact-based metric.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.03823v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Louis Mahon, Mirella Lapata</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gemini 1.5: Unlocking multimodal understanding across millions of tokens of context</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.05530</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.05530v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this report, we introduce the Gemini 1.5 family of models, representing the next generation of highly compute-efficient multimodal models capable of recalling and reasoning over fine-grained information from millions of tokens of context, including multiple long documents and hours of video and audio. The family includes two new models: (1) an updated Gemini 1.5 Pro, which exceeds the February version on the great majority of capabilities and benchmarks; (2) Gemini 1.5 Flash, a more lightweight variant designed for efficiency with minimal regression in quality. Gemini 1.5 models achieve near-perfect recall on long-context retrieval tasks across modalities, improve the state-of-the-art in long-document QA, long-video QA and long-context ASR, and match or surpass Gemini 1.0 Ultra's state-of-the-art performance across a broad set of benchmarks. Studying the limits of Gemini 1.5's long-context ability, we find continued improvement in next-token prediction and near-perfect retrieval (&gt;99%) up to at least 10M tokens, a generational leap over existing models such as Claude 3.0 (200k) and GPT-4 Turbo (128k). Finally, we highlight real-world use cases, such as Gemini 1.5 collaborating with professionals on completing their tasks achieving 26 to 75% time savings across 10 different job categories, as well as surprising new capabilities of large language models at the frontier; when given a grammar manual for Kalamang, a language with fewer than 200 speakers worldwide, the model learns to translate English to Kalamang at a similar level to a person who learned from the same content.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.05530v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator> Gemini Team, Petko Georgiev, Ving Ian Lei, Ryan Burnell, Libin Bai, Anmol Gulati, Garrett Tanzer, Damien Vincent, Zhufeng Pan, Shibo Wang, Soroosh Mariooryad, Yifan Ding, Xinyang Geng, Fred Alcober, Roy Frostig, Mark Omernick, Lexi Walker, Cosmin Paduraru, Christina Sorokin, Andrea Tacchetti, Colin Gaffney, Samira Daruki, Olcan Sercinoglu, Zach Gleicher, Juliette Love, Paul Voigtlaender, Rohan Jain, Gabriela Surita, Kareem Mohamed, Rory Blevins, Junwhan Ahn, Tao Zhu, Kornraphop Kawintiranon, Orhan Firat, Yiming Gu, Yujing Zhang, Matthew Rahtz, Manaal Faruqui, Natalie Clay, Justin Gilmer, JD Co-Reyes, Ivo Penchev, Rui Zhu, Nobuyuki Morioka, Kevin Hui, Krishna Haridasan, Victor Campos, Mahdis Mahdieh, Mandy Guo, Samer Hassan, Kevin Kilgour, Arpi Vezer, Heng-Tze Cheng, Raoul de Liedekerke, Siddharth Goyal, Paul Barham, DJ Strouse, Seb Noury, Jonas Adler, Mukund Sundararajan, Sharad Vikram, Dmitry Lepikhin, Michela Paganini, Xavier Garcia, Fan Yang, Dasha Valter, Maja Trebacz, Kiran Vodrahalli, Chulayuth Asawaroengchai, Roman Ring, Norbert Kalb, Livio Baldini Soares, Siddhartha Brahma, David Steiner, Tianhe Yu, Fabian Mentzer, Antoine He, Lucas Gonzalez, Bibo Xu, Raphael Lopez Kaufman, Laurent El Shafey, Junhyuk Oh, Tom Hennigan, George van den Driessche, Seth Odoom, Mario Lucic, Becca Roelofs, Sid Lall, Amit Marathe, Betty Chan, Santiago Ontanon, Luheng He, Denis Teplyashin, Jonathan Lai, Phil Crone, Bogdan Damoc, Lewis Ho, Sebastian Riedel, Karel Lenc, Chih-Kuan Yeh, Aakanksha Chowdhery, Yang Xu, Mehran Kazemi, Ehsan Amid, Anastasia Petrushkina, Kevin Swersky, Ali Khodaei, Gowoon Chen, Chris Larkin, Mario Pinto, Geng Yan, Adria Puigdomenech Badia, Piyush Patil, Steven Hansen, Dave Orr, Sebastien M. R. Arnold, Jordan Grimstad, Andrew Dai, Sholto Douglas, Rishika Sinha, Vikas Yadav, Xi Chen, Elena Gribovskaya, Jacob Austin, Jeffrey Zhao, Kaushal Patel, Paul Komarek, Sophia Austin, Sebastian Borgeaud, Linda Friso, Abhimanyu Goyal, Ben Caine, Kris Cao, Da-Woon Chung, Matthew Lamm, Gabe Barth-Maron, Thais Kagohara, Kate Olszewska, Mia Chen, Kaushik Shivakumar, Rishabh Agarwal, Harshal Godhia, Ravi Rajwar, Javier Snaider, Xerxes Dotiwalla, Yuan Liu, Aditya Barua, Victor Ungureanu, Yuan Zhang, Bat-Orgil Batsaikhan, Mateo Wirth, James Qin, Ivo Danihelka, Tulsee Doshi, Martin Chadwick, Jilin Chen, Sanil Jain, Quoc Le, Arjun Kar, Madhu Gurumurthy, Cheng Li, Ruoxin Sang, Fangyu Liu, Lampros Lamprou, Rich Munoz, Nathan Lintz, Harsh Mehta, Heidi Howard, Malcolm Reynolds, Lora Aroyo, Quan Wang, Lorenzo Blanco, Albin Cassirer, Jordan Griffith, Dipanjan Das, Stephan Lee, Jakub Sygnowski, Zach Fisher, James Besley, Richard Powell, Zafarali Ahmed, Dominik Paulus, David Reitter, Zalan Borsos, Rishabh Joshi, Aedan Pope, Steven Hand, Vittorio Selo, Vihan Jain, Nikhil Sethi, Megha Goel, Takaki Makino, Rhys May, Zhen Yang, Johan Schalkwyk, Christina Butterfield, Anja Hauth, Alex Goldin, Will Hawkins, Evan Senter, Sergey Brin, Oliver Woodman, Marvin Ritter, Eric Noland, Minh Giang, Vijay Bolina, Lisa Lee, Tim Blyth, Ian Mackinnon, Machel Reid, Obaid Sarvana, David Silver, Alexander Chen, Lily Wang, Loren Maggiore, Oscar Chang, Nithya Attaluri, Gregory Thornton, Chung-Cheng Chiu, Oskar Bunyan, Nir Levine, Timothy Chung, Evgenii Eltyshev, Xiance Si, Timothy Lillicrap, Demetra Brady, Vaibhav Aggarwal, Boxi Wu, Yuanzhong Xu, Ross McIlroy, Kartikeya Badola, Paramjit Sandhu, Erica Moreira, Wojciech Stokowiec, Ross Hemsley, Dong Li, Alex Tudor, Pranav Shyam, Elahe Rahimtoroghi, Salem Haykal, Pablo Sprechmann, Xiang Zhou, Diana Mincu, Yujia Li, Ravi Addanki, Kalpesh Krishna, Xiao Wu, Alexandre Frechette, Matan Eyal, Allan Dafoe, Dave Lacey, Jay Whang, Thi Avrahami, Ye Zhang, Emanuel Taropa, Hanzhao Lin, Daniel Toyama, Eliza Rutherford, Motoki Sano, HyunJeong Choe, Alex Tomala, Chalence Safranek-Shrader, Nora Kassner, Mantas Pajarskas, Matt Harvey, Sean Sechrist, Meire Fortunato, Christina Lyu, Gamaleldin Elsayed, Chenkai Kuang, James Lottes, Eric Chu, Chao Jia, Chih-Wei Chen, Peter Humphreys, Kate Baumli, Connie Tao, Rajkumar Samuel, Cicero Nogueira dos Santos, Anders Andreassen, Nemanja Raki\'cevi\'c, Dominik Grewe, Aviral Kumar, Stephanie Winkler, Jonathan Caton, Andrew Brock, Sid Dalmia, Hannah Sheahan, Iain Barr, Yingjie Miao, Paul Natsev, Jacob Devlin, Feryal Behbahani, Flavien Prost, Yanhua Sun, Artiom Myaskovsky, Thanumalayan Sankaranarayana Pillai, Dan Hurt, Angeliki Lazaridou, Xi Xiong, Ce Zheng, Fabio Pardo, Xiaowei Li, Dan Horgan, Joe Stanton, Moran Ambar, Fei Xia, Alejandro Lince, Mingqiu Wang, Basil Mustafa, Albert Webson, Hyo Lee, Rohan Anil, Martin Wicke, Timothy Dozat, Abhishek Sinha, Enrique Piqueras, Elahe Dabir, Shyam Upadhyay, Anudhyan Boral, Lisa Anne Hendricks, Corey Fry, Josip Djolonga, Yi Su, Jake Walker, Jane Labanowski, Ronny Huang, Vedant Misra, Jeremy Chen, RJ Skerry-Ryan, Avi Singh, Shruti Rijhwani, Dian Yu, Alex Castro-Ros, Beer Changpinyo, Romina Datta, Sumit Bagri, Arnar Mar Hrafnkelsson, Marcello Maggioni, Daniel Zheng, Yury Sulsky, Shaobo Hou, Tom Le Paine, Antoine Yang, Jason Riesa, Dominika Rogozinska, Dror Marcus, Dalia El Badawy, Qiao Zhang, Luyu Wang, Helen Miller, Jeremy Greer, Lars Lowe Sjos, Azade Nova, Heiga Zen, Rahma Chaabouni, Mihaela Rosca, Jiepu Jiang, Charlie Chen, Ruibo Liu, Tara Sainath, Maxim Krikun, Alex Polozov, Jean-Baptiste Lespiau, Josh Newlan, Zeyncep Cankara, Soo Kwak, Yunhan Xu, Phil Chen, Andy Coenen, Clemens Meyer, Katerina Tsihlas, Ada Ma, Juraj Gottweis, Jinwei Xing, Chenjie Gu, Jin Miao, Christian Frank, Zeynep Cankara, Sanjay Ganapathy, Ishita Dasgupta, Steph Hughes-Fitt, Heng Chen, David Reid, Keran Rong, Hongmin Fan, Joost van Amersfoort, Vincent Zhuang, Aaron Cohen, Shixiang Shane Gu, Anhad Mohananey, Anastasija Ilic, Taylor Tobin, John Wieting, Anna Bortsova, Phoebe Thacker, Emma Wang, Emily Caveness, Justin Chiu, Eren Sezener, Alex Kaskasoli, Steven Baker, Katie Millican, Mohamed Elhawaty, Kostas Aisopos, Carl Lebsack, Nathan Byrd, Hanjun Dai, Wenhao Jia, Matthew Wiethoff, Elnaz Davoodi, Albert Weston, Lakshman Yagati, Arun Ahuja, Isabel Gao, Golan Pundak, Susan Zhang, Michael Azzam, Khe Chai Sim, Sergi Caelles, James Keeling, Abhanshu Sharma, Andy Swing, YaGuang Li, Chenxi Liu, Carrie Grimes Bostock, Yamini Bansal, Zachary Nado, Ankesh Anand, Josh Lipschultz, Abhijit Karmarkar, Lev Proleev, Abe Ittycheriah, Soheil Hassas Yeganeh, George Polovets, Aleksandra Faust, Jiao Sun, Alban Rrustemi, Pen Li, Rakesh Shivanna, Jeremiah Liu, Chris Welty, Federico Lebron, Anirudh Baddepudi, Sebastian Krause, Emilio Parisotto, Radu Soricut, Zheng Xu, Dawn Bloxwich, Melvin Johnson, Behnam Neyshabur, Justin Mao-Jones, Renshen Wang, Vinay Ramasesh, Zaheer Abbas, Arthur Guez, Constant Segal, Duc Dung Nguyen, James Svensson, Le Hou, Sarah York, Kieran Milan, Sophie Bridgers, Wiktor Gworek, Marco Tagliasacchi, James Lee-Thorp, Michael Chang, Alexey Guseynov, Ale Jakse Hartman, Michael Kwong, Ruizhe Zhao, Sheleem Kashem, Elizabeth Cole, Antoine Miech, Richard Tanburn, Mary Phuong, Filip Pavetic, Sebastien Cevey, Ramona Comanescu, Richard Ives, Sherry Yang, Cosmo Du, Bo Li, Zizhao Zhang, Mariko Iinuma, Clara Huiyi Hu, Aurko Roy, Shaan Bijwadia, Zhenkai Zhu, Danilo Martins, Rachel Saputro, Anita Gergely, Steven Zheng, Dawei Jia, Ioannis Antonoglou, Adam Sadovsky, Shane Gu, Yingying Bi, Alek Andreev, Sina Samangooei, Mina Khan, Tomas Kocisky, Angelos Filos, Chintu Kumar, Colton Bishop, Adams Yu, Sarah Hodkinson, Sid Mittal, Premal Shah, Alexandre Moufarek, Yong Cheng, Adam Bloniarz, Jaehoon Lee, Pedram Pejman, Paul Michel, Stephen Spencer, Vladimir Feinberg, Xuehan Xiong, Nikolay Savinov, Charlotte Smith, Siamak Shakeri, Dustin Tran, Mary Chesus, Bernd Bohnet, George Tucker, Tamara von Glehn, Carrie Muir, Yiran Mao, Hideto Kazawa, Ambrose Slone, Kedar Soparkar, Disha Shrivastava, James Cobon-Kerr, Michael Sharman, Jay Pavagadhi, Carlos Araya, Karolis Misiunas, Nimesh Ghelani, Michael Laskin, David Barker, Qiujia Li, Anton Briukhov, Neil Houlsby, Mia Glaese, Balaji Lakshminarayanan, Nathan Schucher, Yunhao Tang, Eli Collins, Hyeontaek Lim, Fangxiaoyu Feng, Adria Recasens, Guangda Lai, Alberto Magni, Nicola De Cao, Aditya Siddhant, Zoe Ashwood, Jordi Orbay, Mostafa Dehghani, Jenny Brennan, Yifan He, Kelvin Xu, Yang Gao, Carl Saroufim, James Molloy, Xinyi Wu, Seb Arnold, Solomon Chang, Julian Schrittwieser, Elena Buchatskaya, Soroush Radpour, Martin Polacek, Skye Giordano, Ankur Bapna, Simon Tokumine, Vincent Hellendoorn, Thibault Sottiaux, Sarah Cogan, Aliaksei Severyn, Mohammad Saleh, Shantanu Thakoor, Laurent Shefey, Siyuan Qiao, Meenu Gaba, Shuo-yiin Chang, Craig Swanson, Biao Zhang, Benjamin Lee, Paul Kishan Rubenstein, Gan Song, Tom Kwiatkowski, Anna Koop, Ajay Kannan, David Kao, Parker Schuh, Axel Stjerngren, Golnaz Ghiasi, Gena Gibson, Luke Vilnis, Ye Yuan, Felipe Tiengo Ferreira, Aishwarya Kamath, Ted Klimenko, Ken Franko, Kefan Xiao, Indro Bhattacharya, Miteyan Patel, Rui Wang, Alex Morris, Robin Strudel, Vivek Sharma, Peter Choy, Sayed Hadi Hashemi, Jessica Landon, Mara Finkelstein, Priya Jhakra, Justin Frye, Megan Barnes, Matthew Mauger, Dennis Daun, Khuslen Baatarsukh, Matthew Tung, Wael Farhan, Henryk Michalewski, Fabio Viola, Felix de Chaumont Quitry, Charline Le Lan, Tom Hudson, Qingze Wang, Felix Fischer, Ivy Zheng, Elspeth White, Anca Dragan, Jean-baptiste Alayrac, Eric Ni, Alexander Pritzel, Adam Iwanicki, Michael Isard, Anna Bulanova, Lukas Zilka, Ethan Dyer, Devendra Sachan, Srivatsan Srinivasan, Hannah Muckenhirn, Honglong Cai, Amol Mandhane, Mukarram Tariq, Jack W. Rae, Gary Wang, Kareem Ayoub, Nicholas FitzGerald, Yao Zhao, Woohyun Han, Chris Alberti, Dan Garrette, Kashyap Krishnakumar, Mai Gimenez, Anselm Levskaya, Daniel Sohn, Josip Matak, Inaki Iturrate, Michael B. Chang, Jackie Xiang, Yuan Cao, Nishant Ranka, Geoff Brown, Adrian Hutter, Vahab Mirrokni, Nanxin Chen, Kaisheng Yao, Zoltan Egyed, Francois Galilee, Tyler Liechty, Praveen Kallakuri, Evan Palmer, Sanjay Ghemawat, Jasmine Liu, David Tao, Chloe Thornton, Tim Green, Mimi Jasarevic, Sharon Lin, Victor Cotruta, Yi-Xuan Tan, Noah Fiedel, Hongkun Yu, Ed Chi, Alexander Neitz, Jens Heitkaemper, Anu Sinha, Denny Zhou, Yi Sun, Charbel Kaed, Brice Hulse, Swaroop Mishra, Maria Georgaki, Sneha Kudugunta, Clement Farabet, Izhak Shafran, Daniel Vlasic, Anton Tsitsulin, Rajagopal Ananthanarayanan, Alen Carin, Guolong Su, Pei Sun, Shashank V, Gabriel Carvajal, Josef Broder, Iulia Comsa, Alena Repina, William Wong, Warren Weilun Chen, Peter Hawkins, Egor Filonov, Lucia Loher, Christoph Hirnschall, Weiyi Wang, Jingchen Ye, Andrea Burns, Hardie Cate, Diana Gage Wright, Federico Piccinini, Lei Zhang, Chu-Cheng Lin, Ionel Gog, Yana Kulizhskaya, Ashwin Sreevatsa, Shuang Song, Luis C. Cobo, Anand Iyer, Chetan Tekur, Guillermo Garrido, Zhuyun Xiao, Rupert Kemp, Huaixiu Steven Zheng, Hui Li, Ananth Agarwal, Christel Ngani, Kati Goshvadi, Rebeca Santamaria-Fernandez, Wojciech Fica, Xinyun Chen, Chris Gorgolewski, Sean Sun, Roopal Garg, Xinyu Ye, S. M. Ali Eslami, Nan Hua, Jon Simon, Pratik Joshi, Yelin Kim, Ian Tenney, Sahitya Potluri, Lam Nguyen Thiet, Quan Yuan, Florian Luisier, Alexandra Chronopoulou, Salvatore Scellato, Praveen Srinivasan, Minmin Chen, Vinod Koverkathu, Valentin Dalibard, Yaming Xu, Brennan Saeta, Keith Anderson, Thibault Sellam, Nick Fernando, Fantine Huot, Junehyuk Jung, Mani Varadarajan, Michael Quinn, Amit Raul, Maigo Le, Ruslan Habalov, Jon Clark, Komal Jalan, Kalesha Bullard, Achintya Singhal, Thang Luong, Boyu Wang, Sujeevan Rajayogam, Julian Eisenschlos, Johnson Jia, Daniel Finchelstein, Alex Yakubovich, Daniel Balle, Michael Fink, Sameer Agarwal, Jing Li, Dj Dvijotham, Shalini Pal, Kai Kang, Jaclyn Konzelmann, Jennifer Beattie, Olivier Dousse, Diane Wu, Remi Crocker, Chen Elkind, Siddhartha Reddy Jonnalagadda, Jong Lee, Dan Holtmann-Rice, Krystal Kallarackal, Rosanne Liu, Denis Vnukov, Neera Vats, Luca Invernizzi, Mohsen Jafari, Huanjie Zhou, Lilly Taylor, Jennifer Prendki, Marcus Wu, Tom Eccles, Tianqi Liu, Kavya Kopparapu, Francoise Beaufays, Christof Angermueller, Andreea Marzoca, Shourya Sarcar, Hilal Dib, Jeff Stanway, Frank Perbet, Nejc Trdin, Rachel Sterneck, Andrey Khorlin, Dinghua Li, Xihui Wu, Sonam Goenka, David Madras, Sasha Goldshtein, Willi Gierke, Tong Zhou, Yaxin Liu, Yannie Liang, Anais White, Yunjie Li, Shreya Singh, Sanaz Bahargam, Mark Epstein, Sujoy Basu, Li Lao, Adnan Ozturel, Carl Crous, Alex Zhai, Han Lu, Zora Tung, Neeraj Gaur, Alanna Walton, Lucas Dixon, Ming Zhang, Amir Globerson, Grant Uy, Andrew Bolt, Olivia Wiles, Milad Nasr, Ilia Shumailov, Marco Selvi, Francesco Piccinno, Ricardo Aguilar, Sara McCarthy, Misha Khalman, Mrinal Shukla, Vlado Galic, John Carpenter, Kevin Villela, Haibin Zhang, Harry Richardson, James Martens, Matko Bosnjak, Shreyas Rammohan Belle, Jeff Seibert, Mahmoud Alnahlawi, Brian McWilliams, Sankalp Singh, Annie Louis, Wen Ding, Dan Popovici, Lenin Simicich, Laura Knight, Pulkit Mehta, Nishesh Gupta, Chongyang Shi, Saaber Fatehi, Jovana Mitrovic, Alex Grills, Joseph Pagadora, Dessie Petrova, Danielle Eisenbud, Zhishuai Zhang, Damion Yates, Bhavishya Mittal, Nilesh Tripuraneni, Yannis Assael, Thomas Brovelli, Prateek Jain, Mihajlo Velimirovic, Canfer Akbulut, Jiaqi Mu, Wolfgang Macherey, Ravin Kumar, Jun Xu, Haroon Qureshi, Gheorghe Comanici, Jeremy Wiesner, Zhitao Gong, Anton Ruddock, Matthias Bauer, Nick Felt, Anirudh GP, Anurag Arnab, Dustin Zelle, Jonas Rothfuss, Bill Rosgen, Ashish Shenoy, Bryan Seybold, Xinjian Li, Jayaram Mudigonda, Goker Erdogan, Jiawei Xia, Jiri Simsa, Andrea Michi, Yi Yao, Christopher Yew, Steven Kan, Isaac Caswell, Carey Radebaugh, Andre Elisseeff, Pedro Valenzuela, Kay McKinney, Kim Paterson, Albert Cui, Eri Latorre-Chimoto, Solomon Kim, William Zeng, Ken Durden, Priya Ponnapalli, Tiberiu Sosea, Christopher A. Choquette-Choo, James Manyika, Brona Robenek, Harsha Vashisht, Sebastien Pereira, Hoi Lam, Marko Velic, Denese Owusu-Afriyie, Katherine Lee, Tolga Bolukbasi, Alicia Parrish, Shawn Lu, Jane Park, Balaji Venkatraman, Alice Talbert, Lambert Rosique, Yuchung Cheng, Andrei Sozanschi, Adam Paszke, Praveen Kumar, Jessica Austin, Lu Li, Khalid Salama, Wooyeol Kim, Nandita Dukkipati, Anthony Baryshnikov, Christos Kaplanis, XiangHai Sheng, Yuri Chervonyi, Caglar Unlu, Diego de Las Casas, Harry Askham, Kathryn Tunyasuvunakool, Felix Gimeno, Siim Poder, Chester Kwak, Matt Miecnikowski, Vahab Mirrokni, Alek Dimitriev, Aaron Parisi, Dangyi Liu, Tomy Tsai, Toby Shevlane, Christina Kouridi, Drew Garmon, Adrian Goedeckemeyer, Adam R. Brown, Anitha Vijayakumar, Ali Elqursh, Sadegh Jazayeri, Jin Huang, Sara Mc Carthy, Jay Hoover, Lucy Kim, Sandeep Kumar, Wei Chen, Courtney Biles, Garrett Bingham, Evan Rosen, Lisa Wang, Qijun Tan, David Engel, Francesco Pongetti, Dario de Cesare, Dongseong Hwang, Lily Yu, Jennifer Pullman, Srini Narayanan, Kyle Levin, Siddharth Gopal, Megan Li, Asaf Aharoni, Trieu Trinh, Jessica Lo, Norman Casagrande, Roopali Vij, Loic Matthey, Bramandia Ramadhana, Austin Matthews, CJ Carey, Matthew Johnson, Kremena Goranova, Rohin Shah, Shereen Ashraf, Kingshuk Dasgupta, Rasmus Larsen, Yicheng Wang, Manish Reddy Vuyyuru, Chong Jiang, Joana Ijazi, Kazuki Osawa, Celine Smith, Ramya Sree Boppana, Taylan Bilal, Yuma Koizumi, Ying Xu, Yasemin Altun, Nir Shabat, Ben Bariach, Alex Korchemniy, Kiam Choo, Olaf Ronneberger, Chimezie Iwuanyanwu, Shubin Zhao, David Soergel, Cho-Jui Hsieh, Irene Cai, Shariq Iqbal, Martin Sundermeyer, Zhe Chen, Elie Bursztein, Chaitanya Malaviya, Fadi Biadsy, Prakash Shroff, Inderjit Dhillon, Tejasi Latkar, Chris Dyer, Hannah Forbes, Massimo Nicosia, Vitaly Nikolaev, Somer Greene, Marin Georgiev, Pidong Wang, Nina Martin, Hanie Sedghi, John Zhang, Praseem Banzal, Doug Fritz, Vikram Rao, Xuezhi Wang, Jiageng Zhang, Viorica Patraucean, Dayou Du, Igor Mordatch, Ivan Jurin, Lewis Liu, Ayush Dubey, Abhi Mohan, Janek Nowakowski, Vlad-Doru Ion, Nan Wei, Reiko Tojo, Maria Abi Raad, Drew A. Hudson, Vaishakh Keshava, Shubham Agrawal, Kevin Ramirez, Zhichun Wu, Hoang Nguyen, Ji Liu, Madhavi Sewak, Bryce Petrini, DongHyun Choi, Ivan Philips, Ziyue Wang, Ioana Bica, Ankush Garg, Jarek Wilkiewicz, Priyanka Agrawal, Xiaowei Li, Danhao Guo, Emily Xue, Naseer Shaik, Andrew Leach, Sadh MNM Khan, Julia Wiesinger, Sammy Jerome, Abhishek Chakladar, Alek Wenjiao Wang, Tina Ornduff, Folake Abu, Alireza Ghaffarkhah, Marcus Wainwright, Mario Cortes, Frederick Liu, Joshua Maynez, Slav Petrov, Yonghui Wu, Demis Hassabis, Koray Kavukcuoglu, Jeffrey Dean, Oriol Vinyals</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>StableToolBench: Towards Stable Large-Scale Benchmarking on Tool Learning of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.07714</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.07714v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have witnessed remarkable advancements in recent years, prompting the exploration of tool learning, which integrates LLMs with external tools to address diverse real-world challenges. Assessing the capability of LLMs to utilise tools necessitates large-scale and stable benchmarks. However, previous works relied on either hand-crafted online tools with limited scale, or large-scale real online APIs suffering from instability of API status. To address this problem, we introduce StableToolBench, a benchmark evolving from ToolBench, proposing a virtual API server and stable evaluation system. The virtual API server contains a caching system and API simulators which are complementary to alleviate the change in API status. Meanwhile, the stable evaluation system designs solvable pass and win rates using GPT-4 as the automatic evaluator to eliminate the randomness during evaluation. Experimental results demonstrate the stability of StableToolBench, and further discuss the effectiveness of API simulators, the caching system, and the evaluator system.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.07714v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhicheng Guo, Sijie Cheng, Hao Wang, Shihao Liang, Yujia Qin, Peng Li, Zhiyuan Liu, Maosong Sun, Yang Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LimGen: Probing the LLMs for Generating Suggestive Limitations of Research Papers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.15529</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.15529v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Examining limitations is a crucial step in the scholarly research reviewing process, revealing aspects where a study might lack decisiveness or require enhancement. This aids readers in considering broader implications for further research. In this article, we present a novel and challenging task of Suggestive Limitation Generation (SLG) for research papers. We compile a dataset called \textbf{\textit{LimGen}}, encompassing 4068 research papers and their associated limitations from the ACL anthology. We investigate several approaches to harness large language models (LLMs) for producing suggestive limitations, by thoroughly examining the related challenges, practical insights, and potential opportunities. Our LimGen dataset and code can be accessed at \url{https://github.com/arbmf/LimGen}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.15529v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Abdur Rahman Bin Md Faizullah, Ashok Urlana, Rahul Mishra</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Survey on RAG Meeting LLMs: Towards Retrieval-Augmented Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.06211</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.06211v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: As one of the most advanced techniques in AI, Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) can offer reliable and up-to-date external knowledge, providing huge convenience for numerous tasks. Particularly in the era of AI-Generated Content (AIGC), the powerful capacity of retrieval in providing additional knowledge enables RAG to assist existing generative AI in producing high-quality outputs. Recently, Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated revolutionary abilities in language understanding and generation, while still facing inherent limitations, such as hallucinations and out-of-date internal knowledge. Given the powerful abilities of RAG in providing the latest and helpful auxiliary information, Retrieval-Augmented Large Language Models (RA-LLMs) have emerged to harness external and authoritative knowledge bases, rather than solely relying on the model's internal knowledge, to augment the generation quality of LLMs. In this survey, we comprehensively review existing research studies in RA-LLMs, covering three primary technical perspectives: architectures, training strategies, and applications. As the preliminary knowledge, we briefly introduce the foundations and recent advances of LLMs. Then, to illustrate the practical significance of RAG for LLMs, we systematically review mainstream relevant work by their architectures, training strategies, and application areas, detailing specifically the challenges of each and the corresponding capabilities of RA-LLMs. Finally, to deliver deeper insights, we discuss current limitations and several promising directions for future research. Updated information about this survey can be found at https://advanced-recommender-systems.github.io/RAG-Meets-LLMs/</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.06211v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenqi Fan, Yujuan Ding, Liangbo Ning, Shijie Wang, Hengyun Li, Dawei Yin, Tat-Seng Chua, Qing Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are EEG-to-Text Models Working?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.06459</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.06459v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This work critically analyzes existing models for open-vocabulary EEG-to-Text translation. We identify a crucial limitation: previous studies often employed implicit teacher-forcing during evaluation, artificially inflating performance metrics. Additionally, they lacked a critical benchmark - comparing model performance on pure noise inputs. We propose a methodology to differentiate between models that truly learn from EEG signals and those that simply memorize training data. Our analysis reveals that model performance on noise data can be comparable to that on EEG data. These findings highlight the need for stricter evaluation practices in EEG-to-Text research, emphasizing transparent reporting and rigorous benchmarking with noise inputs. This approach will lead to more reliable assessments of model capabilities and pave the way for robust EEG-to-Text communication systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.06459v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hyejeong Jo, Yiqian Yang, Juhyeok Han, Yiqun Duan, Hui Xiong, Won Hee Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RDRec: Rationale Distillation for LLM-based Recommendation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.10587</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.10587v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language model (LLM)-based recommender models that bridge users and items through textual prompts for effective semantic reasoning have gained considerable attention. However, few methods consider the underlying rationales behind interactions, such as user preferences and item attributes, limiting the reasoning capability of LLMs for recommendations. This paper proposes a rationale distillation recommender (RDRec), a compact model designed to learn rationales generated by a larger language model (LM). By leveraging rationales from reviews related to users and items, RDRec remarkably specifies their profiles for recommendations. Experiments show that RDRec achieves state-of-the-art (SOTA) performance in both top-N and sequential recommendations. Our source code is released at https://github.com/WangXFng/RDRec.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.10587v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xinfeng Wang, Jin Cui, Yoshimi Suzuki, Fumiyo Fukumoto</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decompose and Aggregate: A Step-by-Step Interpretable Evaluation Framework</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.15329</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.15329v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The acceleration of Large Language Models (LLMs) research has opened up new possibilities for evaluating generated texts. They serve as scalable and economical evaluators, but the question of how reliable these evaluators are has emerged as a crucial research question. Prior research efforts in the meta-evaluation of LLMs as judges limit the prompting of an LLM to a single use to obtain a final evaluation decision. They then compute the agreement between LLMs' outputs and human labels. This lacks interpretability in understanding the evaluation capability of LLMs. In light of this challenge, we propose Decompose and Aggregate, which breaks down the evaluation process into different stages based on pedagogical practices. Our experiments illustrate that it not only provides a more interpretable window for how well LLMs evaluate, but also leads to improvements up to 39.6% for different LLMs on a variety of meta-evaluation benchmarks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.15329v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Minzhi Li, Zhengyuan Liu, Shumin Deng, Shafiq Joty, Nancy F. Chen, Min-Yen Kan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Empowering Character-level Text Infilling by Eliminating Sub-Tokens</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.17103</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.17103v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In infilling tasks, sub-tokens, representing instances where a complete token is segmented into two parts, often emerge at the boundaries of prefixes, middles, and suffixes. Traditional methods focused on training models at the token level, leading to sub-optimal performance in character-level infilling tasks during the inference stage. Alternately, some approaches considered character-level infilling, but they relied on predicting sub-tokens in inference, yet this strategy diminished ability in character-level infilling tasks due to the large perplexity of the model on sub-tokens. In this paper, we introduce FIM-SE, which stands for Fill-In-the-Middle with both Starting and Ending character constraints. The proposed method addresses character-level infilling tasks by utilizing a line-level format to avoid predicting any sub-token in inference. In addition, we incorporate two special tokens to signify the rest of the incomplete lines, thereby enhancing generation guidance. Extensive experiments demonstrate that our proposed approach surpasses previous methods, offering a significant advantage. Code is available at https://github.com/SenseLLM/FIM-SE.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.17103v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Houxing Ren, Mingjie Zhan, Zhongyuan Wu, Hongsheng Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TS-Align: A Teacher-Student Collaborative Framework for Scalable Iterative Finetuning of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.20215</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.20215v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Mainstream approaches to aligning large language models (LLMs) heavily rely on human preference data, particularly when models require periodic updates. The standard process for iterative alignment of LLMs involves collecting new human feedback for each update. However, the data collection process is costly and challenging to scale. To address this issue, we introduce the "TS-Align" framework, which fine-tunes a policy model using pairwise feedback data automatically mined from its outputs. This automatic mining process is efficiently accomplished through the collaboration between a large-scale teacher model and a small-scale student model. The policy fine-tuning process can be iteratively repeated using on-policy generations within our proposed teacher-student collaborative framework. Through extensive experiments, we demonstrate that our final aligned policy outperforms the base policy model with an average win rate of 69.7% across seven conversational or instruction-following datasets. Furthermore, we show that the ranking capability of the teacher is effectively distilled into the student through our pipeline, resulting in a small-scale yet effective reward model for policy model alignment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.20215v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chen Zhang, Chengguang Tang, Dading Chong, Ke Shi, Guohua Tang, Feng Jiang, Haizhou Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scalable MatMul-free Language Modeling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.02528</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.02528v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Matrix multiplication (MatMul) typically dominates the overall computational cost of large language models (LLMs). This cost only grows as LLMs scale to larger embedding dimensions and context lengths. In this work, we show that MatMul operations can be completely eliminated from LLMs while maintaining strong performance at billion-parameter scales. Our experiments show that our proposed MatMul-free models achieve performance on-par with state-of-the-art Transformers that require far more memory during inference at a scale up to at least 2.7B parameters. We investigate the scaling laws and find that the performance gap between our MatMul-free models and full precision Transformers narrows as the model size increases. We also provide a GPU-efficient implementation of this model which reduces memory usage by up to 61% over an unoptimized baseline during training. By utilizing an optimized kernel during inference, our model's memory consumption can be reduced by more than 10x compared to unoptimized models. To properly quantify the efficiency of our architecture, we build a custom hardware solution on an FPGA which exploits lightweight operations beyond what GPUs are capable of. We processed billion-parameter scale models at 13W beyond human readable throughput, moving LLMs closer to brain-like efficiency. This work not only shows how far LLMs can be stripped back while still performing effectively, but also points at the types of operations future accelerators should be optimized for in processing the next generation of lightweight LLMs. Our code implementation is available at https://github.com/ridgerchu/matmulfreellm.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.02528v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rui-Jie Zhu, Yu Zhang, Ethan Sifferman, Tyler Sheaves, Yiqiao Wang, Dustin Richmond, Peng Zhou, Jason K. Eshraghian</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Zero-Shot Chinese-English Code-Switching ASR with kNN-CTC and Gated Monolingual Datastores</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.03814</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.03814v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The kNN-CTC model has proven to be effective for monolingual automatic speech recognition (ASR). However, its direct application to multilingual scenarios like code-switching, presents challenges. Although there is potential for performance improvement, a kNN-CTC model utilizing a single bilingual datastore can inadvertently introduce undesirable noise from the alternative language. To address this, we propose a novel kNN-CTC-based code-switching ASR (CS-ASR) framework that employs dual monolingual datastores and a gated datastore selection mechanism to reduce noise interference. Our method selects the appropriate datastore for decoding each frame, ensuring the injection of language-specific information into the ASR process. We apply this framework to cutting-edge CTC-based models, developing an advanced CS-ASR system. Extensive experiments demonstrate the remarkable effectiveness of our gated datastore mechanism in enhancing the performance of zero-shot Chinese-English CS-ASR.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.03814v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiaming Zhou, Shiwan Zhao, Hui Wang, Tian-Hao Zhang, Haoqin Sun, Xuechen Wang, Yong Qin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Underneath the Numbers: Quantitative and Qualitative Gender Fairness in LLMs for Depression Prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.08183</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.08183v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent studies show bias in many machine learning models for depression detection, but bias in LLMs for this task remains unexplored. This work presents the first attempt to investigate the degree of gender bias present in existing LLMs (ChatGPT, LLaMA 2, and Bard) using both quantitative and qualitative approaches. From our quantitative evaluation, we found that ChatGPT performs the best across various performance metrics and LLaMA 2 outperforms other LLMs in terms of group fairness metrics. As qualitative fairness evaluation remains an open research question we propose several strategies (e.g., word count, thematic analysis) to investigate whether and how a qualitative evaluation can provide valuable insights for bias analysis beyond what is possible with quantitative evaluation. We found that ChatGPT consistently provides a more comprehensive, well-reasoned explanation for its prediction compared to LLaMA 2. We have also identified several themes adopted by LLMs to qualitatively evaluate gender fairness. We hope our results can be used as a stepping stone towards future attempts at improving qualitative evaluation of fairness for LLMs especially for high-stakes tasks such as depression detection.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.08183v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Micol Spitale, Jiaee Cheong, Hatice Gunes</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AlignMMBench: Evaluating Chinese Multimodal Alignment in Large Vision-Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09295</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09295v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Evaluating the alignment capabilities of large Vision-Language Models (VLMs) is essential for determining their effectiveness as helpful assistants. However, existing benchmarks primarily focus on basic abilities using nonverbal methods, such as yes-no and multiple-choice questions. In this paper, we address this gap by introducing AlignMMBench, a comprehensive alignment benchmark specifically designed for emerging Chinese VLMs. This benchmark is meticulously curated from real-world scenarios and Chinese Internet sources, encompassing thirteen specific tasks across three categories, and includes both single-turn and multi-turn dialogue scenarios. Incorporating a prompt rewrite strategy, AlignMMBench encompasses 1,054 images and 4,978 question-answer pairs. To facilitate the evaluation pipeline, we propose CritiqueVLM, a rule-calibrated evaluator that exceeds GPT-4's evaluation ability. Finally, we report the performance of representative VLMs on AlignMMBench, offering insights into the capabilities and limitations of different VLM architectures. All evaluation codes and data are available on https://alignmmbench.github.io.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09295v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuhang Wu, Wenmeng Yu, Yean Cheng, Yan Wang, Xiaohan Zhang, Jiazheng Xu, Ming Ding, Yuxiao Dong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ProxyLM: Predicting Language Model Performance on Multilingual Tasks via Proxy Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09334</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.09334v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Performance prediction is a method to estimate the performance of Language Models (LMs) on various Natural Language Processing (NLP) tasks, mitigating computational costs associated with model capacity and data for fine-tuning. Our paper introduces ProxyLM, a scalable framework for predicting LM performance using proxy models in multilingual tasks. These proxy models act as surrogates, approximating the performance of the LM of interest. By leveraging proxy models, ProxyLM significantly reduces computational overhead on task evaluations, achieving up to a 37.08x speedup compared to traditional methods, even with our smallest proxy models. Additionally, our methodology showcases adaptability to previously unseen languages in pre-trained LMs, outperforming the state-of-the-art performance by 1.89x as measured by root-mean-square error (RMSE). This framework streamlines model selection, enabling efficient deployment and iterative LM enhancements without extensive computational resources.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.09334v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>David Anugraha, Genta Indra Winata, Chenyue Li, Patrick Amadeus Irawan, En-Shiun Annie Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating writing style as a contributor to gender gaps in science and technology</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2204.13805</link>
      <description>arXiv:2204.13805v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: A growing stream of research finds that scientific contributions are evaluated differently depending on the gender of the author. In this article, we consider whether gender differences in writing styles - how men and women communicate their work - may contribute to these observed gender gaps. We ground our investigation in a framework for characterizing the linguistic style of written text, with two sets of features - informational (i.e., features that emphasize facts) and involved (i.e., features that emphasize relationships). Using a large sample of academic papers and patents, we find significant differences in writing style by gender, with women using more involved features in their writing. Papers and patents with more involved features also tend to be cited more by women. Our findings suggest that scientific text is not devoid of personal character, which could contribute to bias in evaluation, thereby compromising the norm of universalism as a foundational principle of science.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2204.13805v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kara Kedrick, Ekaterina Levitskaya, Russell J. Funk</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning 6-DoF Fine-grained Grasp Detection Based on Part Affordance Grounding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2301.11564</link>
      <description>arXiv:2301.11564v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Robotic grasping is a fundamental ability for a robot to interact with the environment. Current methods focus on how to obtain a stable and reliable grasping pose in object level, while little work has been studied on part (shape)-wise grasping which is related to fine-grained grasping and robotic affordance. Parts can be seen as atomic elements to compose an object, which contains rich semantic knowledge and a strong correlation with affordance. However, lacking a large part-wise 3D robotic dataset limits the development of part representation learning and downstream applications. In this paper, we propose a new large Language-guided SHape grAsPing datasEt (named LangSHAPE) to promote 3D part-level affordance and grasping ability learning. From the perspective of robotic cognition, we design a two-stage fine-grained robotic grasping framework (named LangPartGPD), including a novel 3D part language grounding model and a part-aware grasp pose detection model, in which explicit language input from human or large language models (LLMs) could guide a robot to generate part-level 6-DoF grasping pose with textual explanation. Our method combines the advantages of human-robot collaboration and LLMs' planning ability using explicit language as a symbolic intermediate. To evaluate the effectiveness of our proposed method, we perform 3D part grounding and fine-grained grasp detection experiments on both simulation and physical robot settings, following language instructions across different degrees of textual complexity. Results show our method achieves competitive performance in 3D geometry fine-grained grounding, object affordance inference, and 3D part-aware grasping tasks. Our dataset and code are available on our project website https://sites.google.com/view/lang-shape</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2301.11564v2</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yaoxian Song, Penglei Sun, Piaopiao Jin, Yi Ren, Yu Zheng, Zhixu Li, Xiaowen Chu, Yue Zhang, Tiefeng Li, Jason Gu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrossGET: Cross-Guided Ensemble of Tokens for Accelerating Vision-Language Transformers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2305.17455</link>
      <description>arXiv:2305.17455v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Recent vision-language models have achieved tremendous advances. However, their computational costs are also escalating dramatically, making model acceleration exceedingly critical. To pursue more efficient vision-language Transformers, this paper introduces Cross-Guided Ensemble of Tokens (CrossGET), a general acceleration framework for vision-language Transformers. This framework adaptively combines tokens in real-time during inference, significantly reducing computational costs while maintaining high performance. CrossGET features two primary innovations: 1) Cross-Guided Matching and Ensemble. CrossGET leverages cross-modal guided token matching and ensemble to effectively utilize cross-modal information, achieving wider applicability across both modality-independent models, e.g., CLIP, and modality-dependent ones, e.g., BLIP2. 2) Complete-Graph Soft Matching. CrossGET introduces an algorithm for the token-matching mechanism, ensuring reliable matching results while facilitating parallelizability and high efficiency. Extensive experiments have been conducted on various vision-language tasks, such as image-text retrieval, visual reasoning, image captioning, and visual question answering. The performance on both classic multimodal architectures and emerging multimodal LLMs demonstrates the framework's effectiveness and versatility. The code is available at https://github.com/sdc17/CrossGET.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2305.17455v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dachuan Shi, Chaofan Tao, Anyi Rao, Zhendong Yang, Chun Yuan, Jiaqi Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LUNA: A Model-Based Universal Analysis Framework for Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.14211</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.14211v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Over the past decade, Artificial Intelligence (AI) has had great success recently and is being used in a wide range of academic and industrial fields. More recently, LLMs have made rapid advancements that have propelled AI to a new level, enabling even more diverse applications and industrial domains with intelligence, particularly in areas like software engineering and natural language processing. Nevertheless, a number of emerging trustworthiness concerns and issues exhibited in LLMs have already recently received much attention, without properly solving which the widespread adoption of LLMs could be greatly hindered in practice. The distinctive characteristics of LLMs, such as the self-attention mechanism, extremely large model scale, and autoregressive generation schema, differ from classic AI software based on CNNs and RNNs and present new challenges for quality analysis. Up to the present, it still lacks universal and systematic analysis techniques for LLMs despite the urgent industrial demand. Towards bridging this gap, we initiate an early exploratory study and propose a universal analysis framework for LLMs, LUNA, designed to be general and extensible, to enable versatile analysis of LLMs from multiple quality perspectives in a human-interpretable manner. In particular, we first leverage the data from desired trustworthiness perspectives to construct an abstract model as an auxiliary analysis asset, which is empowered by various abstract model construction methods. To assess the quality of the abstract model, we collect and define a number of evaluation metrics, aiming at both abstract model level and the semantics level. Then, the semantics, which is the degree of satisfaction of the LLM w.r.t. the trustworthiness perspective, is bound to and enriches the abstract model with semantics, which enables more detailed analysis applications for diverse purposes.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.14211v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Da Song, Xuan Xie, Jiayang Song, Derui Zhu, Yuheng Huang, Felix Juefei-Xu, Lei Ma</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Inter-Session Intentions via Complex Logical Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13866</link>
      <description>arXiv:2312.13866v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Understanding user intentions is essential for improving product recommendations, navigation suggestions, and query reformulations. However, user intentions can be intricate, involving multiple sessions and attribute requirements connected by logical operators such as And, Or, and Not. For instance, a user may search for Nike or Adidas running shoes across various sessions, with a preference for purple. In another example, a user may have purchased a mattress in a previous session and is now looking for a matching bed frame without intending to buy another mattress. Existing research on session understanding has not adequately addressed making product or attribute recommendations for such complex intentions. In this paper, we present the task of logical session complex query answering (LS-CQA), where sessions are treated as hyperedges of items, and we frame the problem of complex intention understanding as an LS-CQA task on an aggregated hypergraph of sessions, items, and attributes. This is a unique complex query answering task with sessions as ordered hyperedges. We also introduce a new model, the Logical Session Graph Transformer (LSGT), which captures interactions among items across different sessions and their logical connections using a transformer structure. We analyze the expressiveness of LSGT and prove the permutation invariance of the inputs for the logical operators. By evaluating LSGT on three datasets, we demonstrate that it achieves state-of-the-art results.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2312.13866v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiaxin Bai, Chen Luo, Zheng Li, Qingyu Yin, Yangqiu Song</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Changes by Butterflies: Farsighted Forecasting with Group Reservoir Transformer</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09573</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.09573v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In Chaos, a minor divergence between two initial conditions exhibits exponential amplification over time, leading to far-away outcomes, known as the butterfly effect. Thus, the distant future is full of uncertainty and hard to forecast. We introduce Group Reservoir Transformer to predict long-term events more accurately and robustly by overcoming two challenges in Chaos: (1) the extensive historical sequences and (2) the sensitivity to initial conditions. A reservoir is attached to a Transformer to efficiently handle arbitrarily long historical lengths, with an extension of a group of reservoirs to reduce the sensitivity to the initialization variations. Our architecture consistently outperforms state-of-the-art models in multivariate time series, including TimeLLM, GPT2TS, PatchTST, DLinear, TimeNet, and the baseline Transformer, with an error reduction of up to -59\% in various fields such as ETTh, ETTm, and air quality, demonstrating that an ensemble of butterfly learning can improve the adequacy and certainty of event prediction, despite of the traveling time to the unknown future.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.09573v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Md Kowsher, Abdul Rafae Khan, Jia Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Cognitive Evaluation Benchmark of Image Reasoning and Description for Large Vision-Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18409</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.18409v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large Vision-Language Models (LVLMs), despite their recent success, are hardly comprehensively tested for their cognitive abilities. Inspired by the prevalent use of the "Cookie Theft" task in human cognition test, we propose a novel evaluation benchmark to evaluate high-level cognitive ability of LVLMs using images with rich semantics. It defines eight reasoning capabilities and consists of an image description task and a visual question answering task. Our evaluation on well-known LVLMs shows that there is still a large gap in cognitive ability between LVLMs and humans.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.18409v3</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiujie Song, Mengyue Wu, Kenny Q. Zhu, Chunhao Zhang, Yanyi Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>L^2GC:Lorentzian Linear Graph Convolutional Networks for Node Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.06064</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.06064v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Linear Graph Convolutional Networks (GCNs) are used to classify the node in the graph data. However, we note that most existing linear GCN models perform neural network operations in Euclidean space, which do not explicitly capture the tree-like hierarchical structure exhibited in real-world datasets that modeled as graphs. In this paper, we attempt to introduce hyperbolic space into linear GCN and propose a novel framework for Lorentzian linear GCN. Specifically, we map the learned features of graph nodes into hyperbolic space, and then perform a Lorentzian linear feature transformation to capture the underlying tree-like structure of data. Experimental results on standard citation networks datasets with semi-supervised learning show that our approach yields new state-of-the-art results of accuracy 74.7$\%$ on Citeseer and 81.3$\%$ on PubMed datasets. Furthermore, we observe that our approach can be trained up to two orders of magnitude faster than other nonlinear GCN models on PubMed dataset. Our code is publicly available at https://github.com/llqy123/LLGC-master.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.06064v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qiuyu Liang, Weihua Wang, Feilong Bao, Guanglai Gao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eye-gaze Guided Multi-modal Alignment for Medical Representation Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.12416</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.12416v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In the medical multi-modal frameworks, the alignment of cross-modality features presents a significant challenge. However, existing works have learned features that are implicitly aligned from the data, without considering the explicit relationships in the medical context. This data-reliance may lead to low generalization of the learned alignment relationships. In this work, we propose the Eye-gaze Guided Multi-modal Alignment (EGMA) framework to harness eye-gaze data for better alignment of medical visual and textual features. We explore the natural auxiliary role of radiologists' eye-gaze data in aligning medical images and text, and introduce a novel approach by using eye-gaze data, collected synchronously by radiologists during diagnostic evaluations. We conduct downstream tasks of image classification and image-text retrieval on four medical datasets, where EGMA achieved state-of-the-art performance and stronger generalization across different datasets. Additionally, we explore the impact of varying amounts of eye-gaze data on model performance, highlighting the feasibility and utility of integrating this auxiliary data into multi-modal alignment framework.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.12416v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chong Ma, Hanqi Jiang, Wenting Chen, Yiwei Li, Zihao Wu, Xiaowei Yu, Zhengliang Liu, Lei Guo, Dajiang Zhu, Tuo Zhang, Dinggang Shen, Tianming Liu, Xiang Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VoiceCraft: Zero-Shot Speech Editing and Text-to-Speech in the Wild</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.16973</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.16973v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We introduce VoiceCraft, a token infilling neural codec language model, that achieves state-of-the-art performance on both speech editing and zero-shot text-to-speech (TTS) on audiobooks, internet videos, and podcasts. VoiceCraft employs a Transformer decoder architecture and introduces a token rearrangement procedure that combines causal masking and delayed stacking to enable generation within an existing sequence. On speech editing tasks, VoiceCraft produces edited speech that is nearly indistinguishable from unedited recordings in terms of naturalness, as evaluated by humans; for zero-shot TTS, our model outperforms prior SotA models including VALLE and the popular commercial model XTTS-v2. Crucially, the models are evaluated on challenging and realistic datasets, that consist of diverse accents, speaking styles, recording conditions, and background noise and music, and our model performs consistently well compared to other models and real recordings. In particular, for speech editing evaluation, we introduce a high quality, challenging, and realistic dataset named RealEdit. We encourage readers to listen to the demos at https://jasonppy.github.io/VoiceCraft_web.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.16973v3</guid>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Puyuan Peng, Po-Yao Huang, Shang-Wen Li, Abdelrahman Mohamed, David Harwath</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CausalChaos! Dataset for Comprehensive Causal Action Question Answering Over Longer Causal Chains Grounded in Dynamic Visual Scenes</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.01299</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.01299v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Causal video question answering (QA) has garnered increasing interest, yet existing datasets often lack depth in causal reasoning. To address this gap, we capitalize on the unique properties of cartoons and construct CausalChaos!, a novel, challenging causal Why-QA dataset built upon the iconic "Tom and Jerry" cartoon series. Cartoons use the principles of animation that allow animators to create expressive, unambiguous causal relationships between events to form a coherent storyline. Utilizing these properties, along with thought-provoking questions and multi-level answers (answer and detailed causal explanation), our questions involve causal chains that interconnect multiple dynamic interactions between characters and visual scenes. These factors demand models to solve more challenging, yet well-defined causal relationships. We also introduce hard incorrect answer mining, including a causally confusing version that is even more challenging. While models perform well, there is much room for improvement, especially, on open-ended answers. We identify more advanced/explicit causal relationship modeling &amp; joint modeling of vision and language as the immediate areas for future efforts to focus upon. Along with the other complementary datasets, our new challenging dataset will pave the way for these developments in the field.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.01299v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Paritosh Parmar, Eric Peh, Ruirui Chen, Ting En Lam, Yuhan Chen, Elston Tan, Basura Fernando</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Play Preference Optimization for Language Model Alignment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.00675</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.00675v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Traditional reinforcement learning from human feedback (RLHF) approaches relying on parametric models like the Bradley-Terry model fall short in capturing the intransitivity and irrationality in human preferences. Recent advancements suggest that directly working with preference probabilities can yield a more accurate reflection of human preferences, enabling more flexible and accurate language model alignment. In this paper, we propose a self-play-based method for language model alignment, which treats the problem as a constant-sum two-player game aimed at identifying the Nash equilibrium policy. Our approach, dubbed Self-Play Preference Optimization (SPPO), approximates the Nash equilibrium through iterative policy updates and enjoys a theoretical convergence guarantee. Our method can effectively increase the log-likelihood of the chosen response and decrease that of the rejected response, which cannot be trivially achieved by symmetric pairwise loss such as Direct Preference Optimization (DPO) and Identity Preference Optimization (IPO). In our experiments, using only 60k prompts (without responses) from the UltraFeedback dataset and without any prompt augmentation, by leveraging a pre-trained preference model PairRM with only 0.4B parameters, SPPO can obtain a model from fine-tuning Mistral-7B-Instruct-v0.2 that achieves the state-of-the-art length-controlled win-rate of 28.53% against GPT-4-Turbo on AlpacaEval 2.0. It also outperforms the (iterative) DPO and IPO on MT-Bench and the Open LLM Leaderboard. Starting from a stronger base model Llama-3-8B-Instruct, we are able to achieve a length-controlled win rate of 38.77%. Notably, the strong performance of SPPO is achieved without additional external supervision (e.g., responses, preferences, etc.) from GPT-4 or other stronger language models. Codes are available at https://github.com/uclaml/SPPO.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.00675v4</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yue Wu, Zhiqing Sun, Huizhuo Yuan, Kaixuan Ji, Yiming Yang, Quanquan Gu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sunnie: An Anthropomorphic LLM-Based Conversational Agent for Mental Well-Being Activity Recommendation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.13803</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.13803v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: A longstanding challenge in mental well-being support is the reluctance of people to adopt psychologically beneficial activities, often due to lack of motivation, low perceived trustworthiness, and limited personalization of recommendations. Chatbots have shown promise in promoting positive mental health practices, yet their rigid interaction flows and less human-like conversational experiences present significant limitations. In this work, we explore whether the anthropomorphic design (both LLM's persona design and conversational experience design) can enhance users' perception of the system and their willingness to adopt mental well-being activity recommendations. To this end, we introduce Sunnie, an anthropomorphic LLM-based conversational agent designed to offer personalized well-being support through multi-turn conversation and recommend practical actions grounded in positive psychology and social psychology. An empirical user study comparing the user experience with Sunnie and with a traditional survey-based activity recommendation system suggests that the anthropomorphic characteristics of Sunnie significantly enhance users' perception of the system and the overall usability; nevertheless, users' willingness to adopt activity recommendations did not change significantly.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.13803v2</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Siyi Wu, Feixue Han, Bingsheng Yao, Tianyi Xie, Xuan Zhao, Dakuo Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generalization Beyond Data Imbalance: A Controlled Study on CLIP for Transferable Insights</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.21070</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.21070v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Severe data imbalance naturally exists among web-scale vision-language datasets. Despite this, we find CLIP pre-trained thereupon exhibits notable robustness to the data imbalance compared to supervised learning, and demonstrates significant effectiveness in learning generalizable representations. With an aim to investigate the reasons behind this finding, we conduct controlled experiments to study various underlying factors, and reveal that CLIP's pretext task forms a dynamic classification problem wherein only a subset of classes is present in training. This isolates the bias from dominant classes and implicitly balances the learning signal. Furthermore, the robustness and discriminability of CLIP improve with more descriptive language supervision, larger data scale, and broader open-world concepts, which are inaccessible to supervised learning. Our study not only uncovers the mechanisms behind CLIP's generalizability beyond data imbalance but also provides transferable insights for the research community. The findings are validated in both supervised and self-supervised learning, enabling models trained on imbalanced data to achieve CLIP-level performance on diverse recognition tasks. Code and data are available at: https://github.com/CVMI-Lab/clip-beyond-tail.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.21070v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xin Wen, Bingchen Zhao, Yilun Chen, Jiangmiao Pang, Xiaojuan Qi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TimeCMA: Towards LLM-Empowered Time Series Forecasting via Cross-Modality Alignment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.01638</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.01638v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The widespread adoption of scalable mobile sensing has led to large amounts of time series data for real-world applications. A fundamental application is multivariate time series forecasting (MTSF), which aims to predict future time series values based on historical observations. Existing MTSF methods suffer from limited parameterization and small-scale training data. Recently, Large language models (LLMs) have been introduced in time series, which achieve promising forecasting performance but incur heavy computational costs. To solve these challenges, we propose TimeCMA, an LLM-empowered framework for time series forecasting with cross-modality alignment. We design a dual-modality encoding module with two branches, where the time series encoding branch extracts relatively low-quality yet pure embeddings of time series through an inverted Transformer. In addition, the LLM-empowered encoding branch wraps the same time series as prompts to obtain high-quality yet entangled prompt embeddings via a Pre-trained LLM. Then, we design a cross-modality alignment module to retrieve high-quality and pure time series embeddings from the prompt embeddings. Moreover, we develop a time series forecasting module to decode the aligned embeddings while capturing dependencies among multiple variables for forecasting. Notably, we tailor the prompt to encode sufficient temporal information into a last token and design the last token embedding storage to reduce computational costs. Extensive experiments on real data offer insight into the accuracy and efficiency of the proposed framework.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.01638v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chenxi Liu, Qianxiong Xu, Hao Miao, Sun Yang, Lingzheng Zhang, Cheng Long, Ziyue Li, Rui Zhao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FusionBench: A Comprehensive Benchmark of Deep Model Fusion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.03280</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.03280v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Deep model fusion is an emerging technique that unifies the predictions or parameters of several deep neural networks into a single model in a cost-effective and data-efficient manner. This enables the unified model to take advantage of the original models' strengths, potentially exceeding their performance. Although a variety of deep model fusion techniques have been introduced, their evaluations tend to be inconsistent and often inadequate to validate their effectiveness and robustness against distribution shifts. To address this issue, we introduce FusionBench, which is the first comprehensive benchmark dedicated to deep model fusion. FusionBench covers a wide range of tasks, including open-vocabulary image classification, text classification, and text-to-text generation. Each category includes up to eight tasks with corresponding task-specific models, featuring both full fine-tuning and LoRA fine-tuning, as well as models of different sizes, to ensure fair and balanced comparisons of various multi-task model fusion techniques across different tasks, model scales, and fine-tuning strategies. We implement and evaluate a broad spectrum of deep model fusion techniques. These techniques range from model ensemble methods, which combine the predictions to improve the overall performance, to model merging, which integrates different models into a single one, and model mixing methods, which upscale or recombine the components of the original models. FusionBench now contains 26 distinct tasks, 74 fine-tuned models, and 16 fusion techniques, and we are committed to consistently expanding the benchmark with more tasks, models, and fusion techniques. In addition, we offer a well-documented set of resources and guidelines to aid researchers in understanding and replicating the benchmark results. Homepage https://github.com/tanganke/fusion_bench</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.03280v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Anke Tang, Li Shen, Yong Luo, Han Hu, Bo Du, Dacheng Tao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>M3GIA: A Cognition Inspired Multilingual and Multimodal General Intelligence Ability Benchmark</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.05343</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.05343v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: As recent multi-modality large language models (MLLMs) have shown formidable proficiency on various complex tasks, there has been increasing attention on debating whether these models could eventually mirror human intelligence. However, existing benchmarks mainly focus on evaluating solely on task performance, such as the accuracy of identifying the attribute of an object. Combining well-developed cognitive science to understand the intelligence of MLLMs beyond superficial achievements remains largely unexplored. To this end, we introduce the first cognitive-driven multi-lingual and multi-modal benchmark to evaluate the general intelligence ability of MLLMs, dubbed M3GIA. Specifically, we identify five key cognitive factors based on the well-recognized Cattell-Horn-Carrol (CHC) model of intelligence and propose a novel evaluation metric. In addition, since most MLLMs are trained to perform in different languages, a natural question arises: is language a key factor influencing the cognitive ability of MLLMs? As such, we go beyond English to encompass other languages based on their popularity, including Chinese, French, Spanish, Portuguese and Korean, to construct our M3GIA. We make sure all the data relevant to the cultural backgrounds are collected from their native context to avoid English-centric bias. We collected a significant corpus of data from human participants, revealing that the most advanced MLLM reaches the lower boundary of human intelligence in English. Yet, there remains a pronounced disparity in the other five languages assessed. We also reveals an interesting winner takes all phenomenon that are aligned with the discovery in cognitive studies. Our benchmark will be open-sourced, with the aspiration of facilitating the enhancement of cognitive capabilities in MLLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.05343v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wei Song, Yadong Li, Jianhua Xu, Guowei Wu, Lingfeng Ming, Kexin Yi, Weihua Luo, Houyi Li, Yi Du, Fangda Guo, Kaicheng Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Large Language Model Pipeline for Breast Cancer Oncology</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.06455</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.06455v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated potential in the innovation of many disciplines. However, how they can best be developed for oncology remains underdeveloped. State-of-the-art OpenAI models were fine-tuned on a clinical dataset and clinical guidelines text corpus for two important cancer treatment factors, adjuvant radiation therapy and chemotherapy, using a novel Langchain prompt engineering pipeline. A high accuracy (0.85+) was achieved in the classification of adjuvant radiation therapy and chemotherapy for breast cancer patients. Furthermore, a confidence interval was formed from observational data on the quality of treatment from human oncologists to estimate the proportion of scenarios in which the model must outperform the original oncologist in its treatment prediction to be a better solution overall as 8.2% to 13.3%. Due to indeterminacy in the outcomes of cancer treatment decisions, future investigation, potentially a clinical trial, would be required to determine if this threshold was met by the models. Nevertheless, with 85% of U.S. cancer patients receiving treatment at local community facilities, these kinds of models could play an important part in expanding access to quality care with outcomes that lie, at minimum, close to a human oncologist.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.06455v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tristen Pool, Dennis Trujillo</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
