<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL</link>
    <description>cs.CL updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 05:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Sunday</day>
      <day>Saturday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>NERsocial: Efficient Named Entity Recognition Dataset Construction for Human-Robot Interaction Utilizing RapidNER</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09634</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09634v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Adapting named entity recognition (NER) methods to new domains poses significant challenges. We introduce RapidNER, a framework designed for the rapid deployment of NER systems through efficient dataset construction. RapidNER operates through three key steps: (1) extracting domain-specific sub-graphs and triples from a general knowledge graph, (2) collecting and leveraging texts from various sources to build the NERsocial dataset, which focuses on entities typical in human-robot interaction, and (3) implementing an annotation scheme using Elasticsearch (ES) to enhance efficiency. NERsocial, validated by human annotators, includes six entity types, 153K tokens, and 99.4K sentences, demonstrating RapidNER's capability to expedite dataset creation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09634v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jesse Atuhurra, Hidetaka Kamigaito, Hiroki Ouchi, Hiroyuki Shindo, Taro Watanabe</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GReaTer: Gradients over Reasoning Makes Smaller Language Models Strong Prompt Optimizers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09722</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09722v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The effectiveness of large language models (LLMs) is closely tied to the design of prompts, making prompt optimization essential for enhancing their performance across a wide range of tasks. Many existing approaches to automating prompt engineering rely exclusively on textual feedback, refining prompts based solely on inference errors identified by large, computationally expensive LLMs. Unfortunately, smaller models struggle to generate high-quality feedback, resulting in complete dependence on large LLM judgment. Moreover, these methods fail to leverage more direct and finer-grained information, such as gradients, due to operating purely in text space. To this end, we introduce GReaTer, a novel prompt optimization technique that directly incorporates gradient information over task-specific reasoning. By utilizing task loss gradients, GReaTer enables self-optimization of prompts for open-source, lightweight language models without the need for costly closed-source LLMs. This allows high-performance prompt optimization without dependence on massive LLMs, closing the gap between smaller models and the sophisticated reasoning often needed for prompt refinement. Extensive evaluations across diverse reasoning tasks including BBH, GSM8k, and FOLIO demonstrate that GReaTer consistently outperforms previous state-of-the-art prompt optimization methods, even those reliant on powerful LLMs. Additionally, GReaTer-optimized prompts frequently exhibit better transferability and, in some cases, boost task performance to levels comparable to or surpassing those achieved by larger language models, highlighting the effectiveness of prompt optimization guided by gradients over reasoning. Code of GReaTer is available at https://github.com/psunlpgroup/GreaTer.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09722v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sarkar Snigdha Sarathi Das, Ryo Kamoi, Bo Pang, Yusen Zhang, Caiming Xiong, Rui Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memory Layers at Scale</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09764</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09764v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Memory layers use a trainable key-value lookup mechanism to add extra parameters to a model without increasing FLOPs. Conceptually, sparsely activated memory layers complement compute-heavy dense feed-forward layers, providing dedicated capacity to store and retrieve information cheaply. This work takes memory layers beyond proof-of-concept, proving their utility at contemporary scale. On downstream tasks, language models augmented with our improved memory layer outperform dense models with more than twice the computation budget, as well as mixture-of-expert models when matched for both compute and parameters. We find gains are especially pronounced for factual tasks. We provide a fully parallelizable memory layer implementation, demonstrating scaling laws with up to 128B memory parameters, pretrained to 1 trillion tokens, comparing to base models with up to 8B parameters.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09764v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Vincent-Pierre Berges, Barlas O\u{g}uz, Daniel Haziza, Wen-tau Yih, Luke Zettlemoyer, Gargi Gosh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semi-IIN: Semi-supervised Intra-inter modal Interaction Learning Network for Multimodal Sentiment Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09784</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09784v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Despite multimodal sentiment analysis being a fertile research ground that merits further investigation, current approaches take up high annotation cost and suffer from label ambiguity, non-amicable to high-quality labeled data acquisition. Furthermore, choosing the right interactions is essential because the significance of intra- or inter-modal interactions can differ among various samples. To this end, we propose Semi-IIN, a Semi-supervised Intra-inter modal Interaction learning Network for multimodal sentiment analysis. Semi-IIN integrates masked attention and gating mechanisms, enabling effective dynamic selection after independently capturing intra- and inter-modal interactive information. Combined with the self-training approach, Semi-IIN fully utilizes the knowledge learned from unlabeled data. Experimental results on two public datasets, MOSI and MOSEI, demonstrate the effectiveness of Semi-IIN, establishing a new state-of-the-art on several metrics. Code is available at https://github.com/flow-ljh/Semi-IIN.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09784v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jinhao Lin, Yifei Wang, Yanwu Xu, Qi Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AutoPatent: A Multi-Agent Framework for Automatic Patent Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09796</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09796v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: As the capabilities of Large Language Models (LLMs) continue to advance, the field of patent processing has garnered increased attention within the natural language processing community. However, the majority of research has been concentrated on classification tasks, such as patent categorization and examination, or on short text generation tasks like patent summarization and patent quizzes. In this paper, we introduce a novel and practical task known as Draft2Patent, along with its corresponding D2P benchmark, which challenges LLMs to generate full-length patents averaging 17K tokens based on initial drafts. Patents present a significant challenge to LLMs due to their specialized nature, standardized terminology, and extensive length. We propose a multi-agent framework called AutoPatent which leverages the LLM-based planner agent, writer agents, and examiner agent with PGTree and RRAG to generate lengthy, intricate, and high-quality complete patent documents. The experimental results demonstrate that our AutoPatent framework significantly enhances the ability to generate comprehensive patents across various LLMs. Furthermore, we have discovered that patents generated solely with the AutoPatent framework based on the Qwen2.5-7B model outperform those produced by larger and more powerful LLMs, such as GPT-4o, Qwen2.5-72B, and LLAMA3.1-70B, in both objective metrics and human evaluations. We will make the data and code available upon acceptance at \url{https://github.com/QiYao-Wang/AutoPatent}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09796v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qiyao Wang, Shiwen Ni, Huaren Liu, Shule Lu, Guhong Chen, Xi Feng, Chi Wei, Qiang Qu, Hamid Alinejad-Rokny, Yuan Lin, Min Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM Distillation for Efficient Few-Shot Multiple Choice Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09807</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09807v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Multiple Choice Question Answering (MCQA) is an important problem with numerous real-world applications, such as medicine, law, and education. The high cost of building MCQA datasets makes few-shot learning pivotal in this domain. While Large Language Models (LLMs) can enable few-shot learning, their direct application in real-world scenarios is often hindered by their high computational cost. To address this challenge, we propose a simple yet effective approach that uses LLMs for data generation and scoring. Our approach utilizes LLMs to create MCQA data which contains questions and choices, and to assign probability scores to the generated choices. We then use the generated data and LLM-assigned scores to finetune a smaller and more efficient encoder-only model, DeBERTa-v3-base by leveraging distillation loss. Extensive experiments on the Massive Multitask Language Understanding (MMLU) benchmark demonstrate that our method improves accuracy from 28.9% to 39.3%, representing a gain of over 10% compared to a baseline finetuned directly on 5-shot examples. This shows the effectiveness of LLM-driven data generation and knowledge distillation for few-shot MCQA.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09807v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Patrick Sutanto, Joan Santoso</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ScaleOT: Privacy-utility-scalable Offsite-tuning with Dynamic LayerReplace and Selective Rank Compression</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09812</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09812v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Offsite-tuning is a privacy-preserving method for tuning large language models (LLMs) by sharing a lossy compressed emulator from the LLM owners with data owners for downstream task tuning. This approach protects the privacy of both the model and data owners. However, current offsite tuning methods often suffer from adaptation degradation, high computational costs, and limited protection strength due to uniformly dropping LLM layers or relying on expensive knowledge distillation. To address these issues, we propose ScaleOT, a novel privacy-utility-scalable offsite-tuning framework that effectively balances privacy and utility. ScaleOT introduces a novel layerwise lossy compression algorithm that uses reinforcement learning to obtain the importance of each layer. It employs lightweight networks, termed harmonizers, to replace the raw LLM layers. By combining important original LLM layers and harmonizers in different ratios, ScaleOT generates emulators tailored for optimal performance with various model scales for enhanced privacy protection. Additionally, we present a rank reduction method to further compress the original LLM layers, significantly enhancing privacy with negligible impact on utility. Comprehensive experiments show that ScaleOT can achieve nearly lossless offsite tuning performance compared with full fine-tuning while obtaining better model privacy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09812v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kai Yao, Zhaorui Tan, Tiandi Ye, Lichun Li, Yuan Zhao, Wenyan Liu, Wei Wang, Jianke Zhu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MERaLiON-AudioLLM: Technical Report</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09818</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09818v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We introduce MERaLiON-AudioLLM (Multimodal Empathetic Reasoning and Learning in One Network), the first speech-text model tailored for Singapore's multilingual and multicultural landscape. Developed under the National Large Language Models Funding Initiative, Singapore, MERaLiON-AudioLLM integrates advanced speech and text processing to address the diverse linguistic nuances of local accents and dialects, enhancing accessibility and usability in complex, multilingual environments. Our results demonstrate improvements in both speech recognition and task-specific understanding, positioning MERaLiON-AudioLLM as a pioneering solution for region specific AI applications. We envision this release to set a precedent for future models designed to address localised linguistic and cultural contexts in a global framework.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09818v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yingxu He, Zhuohan Liu, Shuo Sun, Bin Wang, Wenyu Zhang, Xunlong Zou, Nancy F. Chen, Ai Ti Aw</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low-Rank Adaptation with Task-Relevant Feature Enhancement for Fine-tuning Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09827</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09827v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Fine-tuning pre-trained large language models in a parameter-efficient manner is widely studied for its effectiveness and efficiency. LoRA is one of the most widely used methods, which assumes that the optimization process is essentially low dimensional. Although LoRA has demonstrated commendable performance, there remains a significant performance gap between LoRA and full fine-tuning when learning new tasks. In this work, we propose Low-Rank Adaptation with Task-Relevant Feature Enhancement(LoRATRF) for enhancing task-relevant features from the perspective of editing neural network representations. To prioritize task-relevant features, a task-aware filter that selectively extracts valuable knowledge from hidden representations for the target or current task is designed. As the experiments on a vareity of datasets including NLU, commonsense reasoning and mathematical reasoning tasks demonstrates, our method reduces 33.71% parameters and achieves better performance on a variety of datasets in comparison with SOTA low-rank methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09827v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Changqun Li, Chaofan Ding, Kexin Luan, Xinhan Di</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human-Like Embodied AI Interviewer: Employing Android ERICA in Real International Conference</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09867</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09867v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper introduces the human-like embodied AI interviewer which integrates android robots equipped with advanced conversational capabilities, including attentive listening, conversational repairs, and user fluency adaptation. Moreover, it can analyze and present results post-interview. We conducted a real-world case study at SIGDIAL 2024 with 42 participants, of whom 69% reported positive experiences. This study demonstrated the system's effectiveness in conducting interviews just like a human and marked the first employment of such a system at an international conference. The demonstration video is available at https://youtu.be/jCuw9g99KuE.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09867v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zi Haur Pang, Yahui Fu, Divesh Lala, Mikey Elmers, Koji Inoue, Tatsuya Kawahara</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Byte Latent Transformer: Patches Scale Better Than Tokens</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09871</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09871v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We introduce the Byte Latent Transformer (BLT), a new byte-level LLM architecture that, for the first time, matches tokenization-based LLM performance at scale with significant improvements in inference efficiency and robustness. BLT encodes bytes into dynamically sized patches, which serve as the primary units of computation. Patches are segmented based on the entropy of the next byte, allocating more compute and model capacity where increased data complexity demands it. We present the first FLOP controlled scaling study of byte-level models up to 8B parameters and 4T training bytes. Our results demonstrate the feasibility of scaling models trained on raw bytes without a fixed vocabulary. Both training and inference efficiency improve due to dynamically selecting long patches when data is predictable, along with qualitative improvements on reasoning and long tail generalization. Overall, for fixed inference costs, BLT shows significantly better scaling than tokenization-based models, by simultaneously growing both patch and model size.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09871v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Artidoro Pagnoni, Ram Pasunuru, Pedro Rodriguez, John Nguyen, Benjamin Muller, Margaret Li, Chunting Zhou, Lili Yu, Jason Weston, Luke Zettlemoyer, Gargi Ghosh, Mike Lewis, Ari Holtzman, Srinivasan Iyer</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Limit of Language Models as Planning Formalizers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09879</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09879v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models have been shown to fail to create executable and verifiable plans in grounded environments. An emerging line of work shows success in using LLM as a formalizer to generate a formal representation (e.g., PDDL) of the planning domain, which can be deterministically solved to find a plan. We systematically evaluate this methodology while bridging some major gaps. While previous work only generates a partial PDDL representation given templated and thus unrealistic environment descriptions, we generate the complete representation given descriptions of various naturalness levels. Among an array of observations critical to improve LLMs' formal planning ability, we note that large enough models can effectively formalize descriptions as PDDL, outperforming those directly generating plans, while being robust to lexical perturbation. As the descriptions become more natural-sounding, we observe a decrease in performance and provide detailed error analysis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09879v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Cassie Huang, Li Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking Table Comprehension In The Wild</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09884</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09884v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs), while being increasingly dominant on a myriad of knowledge-intensive activities, have only had limited success understanding lengthy table-text mixtures, such as academic papers and financial reports. Recent advances of long-context LLMs have opened up new possibilities for this field. Nonetheless, we identify two roadblocks: (1) Prior benchmarks of table question answering (TableQA) have focused on isolated tables without context, making it hard to evaluate models in real-world scenarios. (2) Prior benchmarks have focused on some narrow skill sets of table comprehension such as table recognition, data manipulation/calculation, table summarization etc., while a skilled human employs those skills collectively. In this work, we introduce TableQuest, a new benchmark designed to evaluate the holistic table comprehension capabilities of LLMs in the natural table-rich context of financial reports. We employ a rigorous data processing and filtering procedure to ensure that the question-answer pairs are logical, reasonable, and diverse. We experiment with 7 state-of-the-art models, and find that despite reasonable accuracy in locating facts, they often falter when required to execute more sophisticated reasoning or multi-step calculations. We conclude with a qualitative study of the failure modes and discuss the challenges of constructing a challenging benchmark. We make the evaluation data, judging procedure and results of this study publicly available to facilitate research in this field.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09884v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yikang Pan, Yi Zhu, Rand Xie, Yizhi Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the Reasoning Capabilities of Small Language Models via Solution Guidance Fine-Tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09906</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09906v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated remarkable performance across a wide range of tasks. Advances in prompt engineering and fine-tuning techniques have further enhanced their ability to address complex reasoning challenges. However, these advanced capabilities are often exclusive to models exceeding 100 billion parameters. Although Chain-of-Thought (CoT) fine-tuning methods have been explored for smaller models (under 10 billion parameters), they typically depend on extensive CoT training data, which can introduce inconsistencies and limit effectiveness in low-data settings. To overcome these limitations, this paper introduce a new reasoning strategy Solution Guidance (SG) and a plug-and-play training paradigm Solution-Guidance Fine-Tuning (SGFT) for enhancing the reasoning capabilities of small language models. SG focuses on problem understanding and decomposition at the semantic and logical levels, rather than specific computations, which can effectively improve the SLMs' generalization and reasoning abilities. With only a small amount of SG training data, SGFT can fine-tune a SLM to produce accurate problem-solving guidances, which can then be flexibly fed to any SLM as prompts, enabling it to generate correct answers directly. Experimental results demonstrate that our method significantly improves the performance of SLMs on various reasoning tasks, enhancing both their practicality and efficiency within resource-constrained environments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09906v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jing Bi, Yuting Wu, Weiwei Xing, Zhenjie Wei</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low-Resource Fast Text Classification Based on Intra-Class and Inter-Class Distance Calculation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09922</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09922v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In recent years, text classification methods based on neural networks and pre-trained models have gained increasing attention and demonstrated excellent performance. However, these methods still have some limitations in practical applications: (1) They typically focus only on the matching similarity between sentences. However, there exists implicit high-value information both within sentences of the same class and across different classes, which is very crucial for classification tasks. (2) Existing methods such as pre-trained language models and graph-based approaches often consume substantial memory for training and text-graph construction. (3) Although some low-resource methods can achieve good performance, they often suffer from excessively long processing times. To address these challenges, we propose a low-resource and fast text classification model called LFTC. Our approach begins by constructing a compressor list for each class to fully mine the regularity information within intra-class data. We then remove redundant information irrelevant to the target classification to reduce processing time. Finally, we compute the similarity distance between text pairs for classification. We evaluate LFTC on 9 publicly available benchmark datasets, and the results demonstrate significant improvements in performance and processing time, especially under limited computational and data resources, highlighting its superior advantages.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09922v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yanxu Mao, Peipei Liu, Tiehan Cui, Congying Liu, Datao You</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Nursing and Elderly Care with Large Language Models: An AI-Driven Framework</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09946</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09946v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper explores the application of large language models (LLMs) in nursing and elderly care, focusing on AI-driven patient monitoring and interaction. We introduce a novel Chinese nursing dataset and implement incremental pre-training (IPT) and supervised fine-tuning (SFT) techniques to enhance LLM performance in specialized tasks. Using LangChain, we develop a dynamic nursing assistant capable of real-time care and personalized interventions. Experimental results demonstrate significant improvements, paving the way for AI-driven solutions to meet the growing demands of healthcare in aging populations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09946v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qiao Sun, Jiexin Xie, Nanyang Ye, Qinying Gu, Shijie Guo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Romanized to Native Malayalam Script Transliteration Using an Encoder-Decoder Framework</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09957</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09957v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this work, we present the development of a reverse transliteration model to convert romanized Malayalam to native script using an encoder-decoder framework built with attention-based bidirectional Long Short Term Memory (Bi-LSTM) architecture. To train the model, we have used curated and combined collection of 4.3 million transliteration pairs derived from publicly available Indic language translitertion datasets, Dakshina and Aksharantar. We evaluated the model on two different test dataset provided by IndoNLP-2025-Shared-Task that contain, (1) General typing patterns and (2) Adhoc typing patterns, respectively. On the Test Set-1, we obtained a character error rate (CER) of 7.4%. However upon Test Set-2, with adhoc typing patterns, where most vowel indicators are missing, our model gave a CER of 22.7%.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09957v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bajiyo Baiju, Kavya Manohar, Leena G Pillai, Elizabeth Sherly</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Small Language Model as Data Prospector for Large Language Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09990</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09990v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The quality of instruction data directly affects the performance of fine-tuned Large Language Models (LLMs). Previously, \cite{li2023one} proposed \texttt{NUGGETS}, which identifies and selects high-quality quality data from a large dataset by identifying those individual instruction examples that can significantly improve the performance of different tasks after being learnt as one-shot instances. In this work, we propose \texttt{SuperNUGGETS}, an improved variant of \texttt{NUGGETS} optimised for efficiency and performance. Our \texttt{SuperNUGGETS} uses a small language model (SLM) instead of a large language model (LLM) to filter the data for outstanding one-shot instances and refines the predefined set of tests. The experimental results show that the performance of \texttt{SuperNUGGETS} only decreases by 1-2% compared to \texttt{NUGGETS}, but the efficiency can be increased by a factor of 58. Compared to the original \texttt{NUGGETS}, our \texttt{SuperNUGGETS} has a higher utility value due to the significantly lower resource consumption.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09990v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shiwen Ni, Haihong Wu, Di Yang, Qiang Qu, Hamid Alinejad-Rokny, Min Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comparative Study of LLMs, NMT Models, and Their Combination in Persian-English Idiom Translation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09993</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09993v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have shown superior capabilities in translating figurative language compared to neural machine translation (NMT) systems. However, the impact of different prompting methods and LLM-NMT combinations on idiom translation has yet to be thoroughly investigated. This paper introduces two parallel datasets of sentences containing idiomatic expressions for Persian$\rightarrow$English and English$\rightarrow$Persian translations, with Persian idioms sampled from our PersianIdioms resource, a collection of 2,200 idioms and their meanings. Using these datasets, we evaluate various open- and closed-source LLMs, NMT models, and their combinations. Translation quality is assessed through idiom translation accuracy and fluency. We also find that automatic evaluation methods like LLM-as-a-judge, BLEU and BERTScore are effective for comparing different aspects of model performance. Our experiments reveal that Claude-3.5-Sonnet delivers outstanding results in both translation directions. For English$\rightarrow$Persian, combining weaker LLMs with Google Translate improves results, while Persian$\rightarrow$English translations benefit from single prompts for simpler models and complex prompts for advanced ones.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09993v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sara Rezaeimanesh, Faezeh Hosseini, Yadollah Yaghoobzadeh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The role of inhibitory control in garden-path sentence processing: A Chinese-English bilingual perspective</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10006</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10006v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In reading garden-path sentences, people must resolve competing interpretations, though initial misinterpretations can linger despite reanalysis. This study examines the role of inhibitory control (IC) in managing these misinterpretations among Chinese-English bilinguals. Using self-paced reading tasks, we investigated how IC influences recovery from garden-path sentences in Chinese (L1) and its interaction with language proficiency during English (L2) processing. Results indicate that IC does not affect garden-path recovery in Chinese, suggesting reliance on semantic context may reduce the need for IC. In contrast, findings for English L2 learners reveal a complex relationship between language proficiency and IC: Participants with low L2 proficiency but high IC showed lingering misinterpretations, while those with high proficiency exhibited none. These results support and extend the Model of Cognitive Control (Ness et al., 2023). Moreover, our comparison of three Stroop task versions identifies L1 colour-word Stroop task as the preferred measure of IC in bilingual research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10006v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaohui Rao, Haoze Li, Xiaofang Lin, Lijuan Liang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automated Collection of Evaluation Dataset for Semantic Search in Low-Resource Domain Language</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10008</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10008v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Domain-specific languages that use a lot of specific terminology often fall into the category of low-resource languages. Collecting test datasets in a narrow domain is time-consuming and requires skilled human resources with domain knowledge and training for the annotation task. This study addresses the challenge of automated collecting test datasets to evaluate semantic search in low-resource domain-specific German language of the process industry. Our approach proposes an end-to-end annotation pipeline for automated query generation to the score reassessment of query-document pairs. To overcome the lack of text encoders trained in the German chemistry domain, we explore a principle of an ensemble of "weak" text encoders trained on common knowledge datasets. We combine individual relevance scores from diverse models to retrieve document candidates and relevance scores generated by an LLM, aiming to achieve consensus on query-document alignment. Evaluation results demonstrate that the ensemble method significantly improves alignment with human-assigned relevance scores, outperforming individual models in both inter-coder agreement and accuracy metrics. These findings suggest that ensemble learning can effectively adapt semantic search systems for specialized, low-resource languages, offering a practical solution to resource limitations in domain-specific contexts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10008v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Anastasia Zhukova, Christian E. Matt, Bela Gipp</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unsupervised Named Entity Disambiguation for Low Resource Domains</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10054</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10054v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In the ever-evolving landscape of natural language processing and information retrieval, the need for robust and domain-specific entity linking algorithms has become increasingly apparent. It is crucial in a considerable number of fields such as humanities, technical writing and biomedical sciences to enrich texts with semantics and discover more knowledge. The use of Named Entity Disambiguation (NED) in such domains requires handling noisy texts, low resource settings and domain-specific KBs. Existing approaches are mostly inappropriate for such scenarios, as they either depend on training data or are not flexible enough to work with domain-specific KBs. Thus in this work, we present an unsupervised approach leveraging the concept of Group Steiner Trees (GST), which can identify the most relevant candidates for entity disambiguation using the contextual similarities across candidate entities for all the mentions present in a document. We outperform the state-of-the-art unsupervised methods by more than 40\% (in avg.) in terms of Precision@1 across various domain-specific datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10054v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Debarghya Datta, Soumajit Pramanik</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GAOKAO-Eval: Does high scores truly reflect strong capabilities in LLMs?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10056</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10056v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) are commonly evaluated using human-crafted benchmarks, under the premise that higher scores implicitly reflect stronger human-like performance. However, there is growing concern that LLMs may ``game" these benchmarks due to data leakage, achieving high scores while struggling with tasks simple for humans. To substantively address the problem, we create GAOKAO-Eval, a comprehensive benchmark based on China's National College Entrance Examination (Gaokao), and conduct ``closed-book" evaluations for representative models released prior to Gaokao. Contrary to prevailing consensus, even after addressing data leakage and comprehensiveness, GAOKAO-Eval reveals that high scores still fail to truly reflect human-aligned capabilities. To better understand this mismatch, We introduce the Rasch model from cognitive psychology to analyze LLM scoring patterns and identify two key discrepancies: 1) anomalous consistent performance across various question difficulties, and 2) high variance in performance on questions of similar difficulty. In addition, We identified inconsistent grading of LLM-generated answers among teachers and recurring mistake patterns. we find that the phenomenons are well-grounded in the motivations behind OpenAI o1, and o1's reasoning-as-difficulties can mitigate the mismatch. These results show that GAOKAO-Eval can reveal limitations in LLM capabilities not captured by current benchmarks and highlight the need for more LLM-aligned difficulty analysis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10056v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhikai Lei, Tianyi Liang, Hanglei Hu, Jin Zhang, Yunhua Zhou, Yunfan Shao, Linyang Li, Chenchui Li, Changbo Wang, Hang Yan, Qipeng Guo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost in the Middle, and In-Between: Enhancing Language Models' Ability to Reason Over Long Contexts in Multi-Hop QA</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10079</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10079v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Previous work finds that recent long-context language models fail to make equal use of information in the middle of their inputs, preferring pieces of information located at the tail ends which creates an undue bias in situations where we would like models to be equally capable of using different parts of the input. Thus far, the problem has mainly only been considered in settings with single pieces of critical information, leading us to question what happens when multiple necessary pieces of information are spread out over the inputs. Here, we demonstrate the effects of the "lost in the middle" problem in the multi-hop question answering setting -- in which multiple reasoning "hops" over disconnected documents are required -- and show that performance degrades not only with respect to the distance of information from the edges of the context, but also between pieces of information. Additionally, we experiment with means of alleviating the problem by reducing superfluous document contents through knowledge graph triple extraction and summarization, and prompting models to reason more thoroughly using chain-of-thought prompting.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10079v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>George Arthur Baker, Ankush Raut, Sagi Shaier, Lawrence E Hunter, Katharina von der Wense</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HiTZ at VarDial 2025 NorSID: Overcoming Data Scarcity with Language Transfer and Automatic Data Annotation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10095</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10095v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this paper we present our submission for the NorSID Shared Task as part of the 2025 VarDial Workshop (Scherrer et al., 2025), consisting of three tasks: Intent Detection, Slot Filling and Dialect Identification, evaluated using data in different dialects of the Norwegian language. For Intent Detection and Slot Filling, we have fine-tuned a multitask model in a cross-lingual setting, to leverage the xSID dataset available in 17 languages. In the case of Dialect Identification, our final submission consists of a model fine-tuned on the provided development set, which has obtained the highest scores within our experiments. Our final results on the test set show that our models do not drop in performance compared to the development set, likely due to the domain-specificity of the dataset and the similar distribution of both subsets. Finally, we also report an in-depth analysis of the provided datasets and their artifacts, as well as other sets of experiments that have been carried out but did not yield the best results. Additionally, we present an analysis on the reasons why some methods have been more successful than others; mainly the impact of the combination of languages and domain-specificity of the training data on the results.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10095v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jaione Bengoetxea, Mikel Zubillaga, Ekhi Azurmendi, Maite Heredia, Julen Etxaniz, Markel Ferro, Jeremy Barnes</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMuSeD: An Attentive Deep Neural Network for Multimodal Sarcasm Detection Incorporating Bi-modal Data Augmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10103</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10103v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Detecting sarcasm effectively requires a nuanced understanding of context, including vocal tones and facial expressions. The progression towards multimodal computational methods in sarcasm detection, however, faces challenges due to the scarcity of data. To address this, we present AMuSeD (Attentive deep neural network for MUltimodal Sarcasm dEtection incorporating bi-modal Data augmentation). This approach utilizes the Multimodal Sarcasm Detection Dataset (MUStARD) and introduces a two-phase bimodal data augmentation strategy. The first phase involves generating varied text samples through Back Translation from several secondary languages. The second phase involves the refinement of a FastSpeech 2-based speech synthesis system, tailored specifically for sarcasm to retain sarcastic intonations. Alongside a cloud-based Text-to-Speech (TTS) service, this Fine-tuned FastSpeech 2 system produces corresponding audio for the text augmentations. We also investigate various attention mechanisms for effectively merging text and audio data, finding self-attention to be the most efficient for bimodal integration. Our experiments reveal that this combined augmentation and attention approach achieves a significant F1-score of 81.0% in text-audio modalities, surpassing even models that use three modalities from the MUStARD dataset.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10103v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiyuan Gao, Shubhi Bansal, Kushaan Gowda, Zhu Li, Shekhar Nayak, Nagendra Kumar, Matt Coler</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RETQA: A Large-Scale Open-Domain Tabular Question Answering Dataset for Real Estate Sector</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10104</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10104v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The real estate market relies heavily on structured data, such as property details, market trends, and price fluctuations. However, the lack of specialized Tabular Question Answering datasets in this domain limits the development of automated question-answering systems. To fill this gap, we introduce RETQA, the first large-scale open-domain Chinese Tabular Question Answering dataset for Real Estate. RETQA comprises 4,932 tables and 20,762 question-answer pairs across 16 sub-fields within three major domains: property information, real estate company finance information and land auction information. Compared with existing tabular question answering datasets, RETQA poses greater challenges due to three key factors: long-table structures, open-domain retrieval, and multi-domain queries. To tackle these challenges, we propose the SLUTQA framework, which integrates large language models with spoken language understanding tasks to enhance retrieval and answering accuracy. Extensive experiments demonstrate that SLUTQA significantly improves the performance of large language models on RETQA by in-context learning. RETQA and SLUTQA provide essential resources for advancing tabular question answering research in the real estate domain, addressing critical challenges in open-domain and long-table question-answering. The dataset and code are publicly available at \url{https://github.com/jensen-w/RETQA}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10104v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhensheng Wang, Wenmian Yang, Kun Zhou, Yiquan Zhang, Weijia Jia</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MALAMUTE: A Multilingual, Highly-granular, Template-free, Education-based Probing Dataset</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10105</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10105v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Language models (LMs) have excelled in various broad domains. However, to ensure their safe and effective integration into real-world educational settings, they must demonstrate proficiency in specific, granular areas of knowledge. Existing cloze-style benchmarks, commonly used to evaluate LMs' knowledge, have three major limitations. They: 1) do not cover the educational domain; 2) typically focus on low-complexity, generic knowledge or broad domains, which do not adequately assess the models' knowledge in specific subjects; and 3) often rely on templates that can bias model predictions. Here, we introduce MALAMUTE, a multilingual, template-free, and highly granular probing dataset comprising expert-written, peer-reviewed probes from 71 university-level textbooks across three languages (English, Spanish, and Polish). MALAMUTE is the first education-based cloze-style dataset. It covers eight domains, each with up to 14 subdomains, further broken down into concepts and concept-based prompts, totaling 33,361 university curriculum concepts and 116,887 prompts. MALAMUTE's fine granularity, educational focus, and inclusion of both sentence-level and paragraph-level prompts make it an ideal tool for evaluating LMs' course-related knowledge. Our evaluation of masked and causal LMs on MALAMUTE shows that despite overall proficiency, they have significant gaps in knowledge when examined closely on specific subjects, hindering their safe use in classrooms and underscoring the need for further development.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10105v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sagi Shaier, George Arthur Baker, Chiranthan Sridhar, Lawrence E Hunter, Katharina von der Wense</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Label-template based Few-Shot Text Classification with Contrastive Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10110</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10110v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: As an algorithmic framework for learning to learn, meta-learning provides a promising solution for few-shot text classification. However, most existing research fail to give enough attention to class labels. Traditional basic framework building meta-learner based on prototype networks heavily relies on inter-class variance, and it is easily influenced by noise. To address these limitations, we proposes a simple and effective few-shot text classification framework. In particular, the corresponding label templates are embed into input sentences to fully utilize the potential value of class labels, guiding the pre-trained model to generate more discriminative text representations through the semantic information conveyed by labels. With the continuous influence of label semantics, supervised contrastive learning is utilized to model the interaction information between support samples and query samples. Furthermore, the averaging mechanism is replaced with an attention mechanism to highlight vital semantic information. To verify the proposed scheme, four typical datasets are employed to assess the performance of different methods. Experimental results demonstrate that our method achieves substantial performance enhancements and outperforms existing state-of-the-art models on few-shot text classification tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10110v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Guanghua Hou, Shuhui Cao, Deqiang Ouyang, Ning Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Familiarity: Better Evaluation of Zero-Shot Named Entity Recognition by Quantifying Label Shifts in Synthetic Training Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10121</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10121v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Zero-shot named entity recognition (NER) is the task of detecting named entities of specific types (such as 'Person' or 'Medicine') without any training examples. Current research increasingly relies on large synthetic datasets, automatically generated to cover tens of thousands of distinct entity types, to train zero-shot NER models. However, in this paper, we find that these synthetic datasets often contain entity types that are semantically highly similar to (or even the same as) those in standard evaluation benchmarks. Because of this overlap, we argue that reported F1 scores for zero-shot NER overestimate the true capabilities of these approaches. Further, we argue that current evaluation setups provide an incomplete picture of zero-shot abilities since they do not quantify the label shift (i.e., the similarity of labels) between training and evaluation datasets. To address these issues, we propose Familiarity, a novel metric that captures both the semantic similarity between entity types in training and evaluation, as well as their frequency in the training data, to provide an estimate of label shift. It allows researchers to contextualize reported zero-shot NER scores when using custom synthetic training datasets. Further, it enables researchers to generate evaluation setups of various transfer difficulties for fine-grained analysis of zero-shot NER.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10121v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jonas Golde, Patrick Haller, Max Ploner, Fabio Barth, Nicolaas Jedema, Alan Akbik</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASLoRA: Adaptive Sharing Low-Rank Adaptation Across Layers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10135</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10135v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: As large language models (LLMs) grow in size, traditional full fine-tuning becomes increasingly impractical due to its high computational and storage costs. Although popular parameter-efficient fine-tuning methods, such as LoRA, have significantly reduced the number of tunable parameters, there is still room for further optimization. In this work, we propose ASLoRA, a cross-layer parameter-sharing strategy combining global sharing with partial adaptive sharing. Specifically, we share the low-rank matrix A across all layers and adaptively merge matrix B during training. This sharing mechanism not only mitigates overfitting effectively but also captures inter-layer dependencies, significantly enhancing the model's representational capability. We conduct extensive experiments on various NLP tasks, showing that ASLoRA outperforms LoRA while using less than 25% of the parameters, highlighting its flexibility and superior parameter efficiency. Furthermore, in-depth analyses of the adaptive sharing strategy confirm its significant advantages in enhancing both model flexibility and task adaptability.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10135v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junyan Hu, Xue Xiao, Mengqi Zhang, Xiao Chen, Zhaochun Ren, Zhumin Chen, Pengjie Ren</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can LLMs Convert Graphs to Text-Attributed Graphs?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10136</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10136v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Graphs are ubiquitous data structures found in numerous real-world applications, such as drug discovery, recommender systems, and social network analysis. Graph neural networks (GNNs) have become a popular tool to learn node embeddings through message passing on these structures. However, a significant challenge arises when applying GNNs to multiple graphs with different feature spaces, as existing GNN architectures are not designed for cross-graph feature alignment. To address this, recent approaches introduce text-attributed graphs, where each node is associated with a textual description, enabling the use of a shared textual encoder to project nodes from different graphs into a unified feature space. While promising, this method relies heavily on the availability of text-attributed data, which can be difficult to obtain in practice. To bridge this gap, we propose a novel method named Topology-Aware Node description Synthesis (TANS), which leverages large language models (LLMs) to automatically convert existing graphs into text-attributed graphs. The key idea is to integrate topological information with each node's properties, enhancing the LLMs' ability to explain how graph topology influences node semantics. We evaluate our TANS on text-rich, text-limited, and text-free graphs, demonstrating that it enables a single GNN to operate across diverse graphs. Notably, on text-free graphs, our method significantly outperforms existing approaches that manually design node features, showcasing the potential of LLMs for preprocessing graph-structured data, even in the absence of textual information. The code and data are available at https://github.com/Zehong-Wang/TANS.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10136v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zehong Wang, Sidney Liu, Zheyuan Zhang, Tianyi Ma, Chuxu Zhang, Yanfang Ye</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ROUTE: Robust Multitask Tuning and Collaboration for Text-to-SQL</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10138</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10138v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Despite the significant advancements in Text-to-SQL (Text2SQL) facilitated by large language models (LLMs), the latest state-of-the-art techniques are still trapped in the in-context learning of closed-source LLMs (e.g., GPT-4), which limits their applicability in open scenarios. To address this challenge, we propose a novel RObust mUltitask Tuning and collaboration mEthod (ROUTE) to improve the comprehensive capabilities of open-source LLMs for Text2SQL, thereby providing a more practical solution. Our approach begins with multi-task supervised fine-tuning (SFT) using various synthetic training data related to SQL generation. Unlike existing SFT-based Text2SQL methods, we introduced several additional SFT tasks, including schema linking, noise correction, and continuation writing. Engaging in a variety of SQL generation tasks enhances the model's understanding of SQL syntax and improves its ability to generate high-quality SQL queries. Additionally, inspired by the collaborative modes of LLM agents, we introduce a Multitask Collaboration Prompting (MCP) strategy. This strategy leverages collaboration across several SQL-related tasks to reduce hallucinations during SQL generation, thereby maximizing the potential of enhancing Text2SQL performance through explicit multitask capabilities. Extensive experiments and in-depth analyses have been performed on eight open-source LLMs and five widely-used benchmarks. The results demonstrate that our proposal outperforms the latest Text2SQL methods and yields leading performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10138v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yang Qin, Chao Chen, Zhihang Fu, Ze Chen, Dezhong Peng, Peng Hu, Jieping Ye</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TACOMORE: Leveraging the Potential of LLMs in Corpus-based Discourse Analysis with Prompt Engineering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10139</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10139v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The capacity of LLMs to carry out automated qualitative analysis has been questioned by corpus linguists, and it has been argued that corpus-based discourse analysis incorporating LLMs is hindered by issues of unsatisfying performance, hallucination, and irreproducibility. Our proposed method, TACOMORE, aims to address these concerns by serving as an effective prompting framework in this domain. The framework consists of four principles, i.e., Task, Context, Model and Reproducibility, and specifies five fundamental elements of a good prompt, i.e., Role Description, Task Definition, Task Procedures, Contextual Information and Output Format. We conduct experiments on three LLMs, i.e., GPT-4o, Gemini-1.5-Pro and Gemini-1.5.Flash, and find that TACOMORE helps improve LLM performance in three representative discourse analysis tasks, i.e., the analysis of keywords, collocates and concordances, based on an open corpus of COVID-19 research articles. Our findings show the efficacy of the proposed prompting framework TACOMORE in corpus-based discourse analysis in terms of Accuracy, Ethicality, Reasoning, and Reproducibility, and provide novel insights into the application and evaluation of LLMs in automated qualitative studies.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10139v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bingru Li, Han Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retrieval-Augmented Semantic Parsing: Using Large Language Models to Improve Generalization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10207</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10207v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Open-domain semantic parsing remains a challenging task, as models often rely on heuristics and struggle to handle unseen concepts. In this paper, we investigate the potential of large language models (LLMs) for this task and introduce Retrieval-Augmented Semantic Parsing (RASP), a simple yet effective approach that integrates external lexical knowledge into the parsing process. Our experiments not only show that LLMs outperform previous encoder-decoder baselines for semantic parsing, but that RASP further enhances their ability to predict unseen concepts, nearly doubling the performance of previous models on out-of-distribution concepts. These findings highlight the promise of leveraging large language models and retrieval mechanisms for robust and open-domain semantic parsing.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10207v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiao Zhang, Qianru Meng, Johan Bos</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How good is my story? Towards quantitative metrics for evaluating LLM-generated XAI narratives</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10220</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10220v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: A rapidly developing application of LLMs in XAI is to convert quantitative explanations such as SHAP into user-friendly narratives to explain the decisions made by smaller prediction models. Evaluating the narratives without relying on human preference studies or surveys is becoming increasingly important in this field. In this work we propose a framework and explore several automated metrics to evaluate LLM-generated narratives for explanations of tabular classification tasks. We apply our approach to compare several state-of-the-art LLMs across different datasets and prompt types. As a demonstration of their utility, these metrics allow us to identify new challenges related to LLM hallucinations for XAI narratives.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10220v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Timour Ichmoukhamedov, James Hinns, David Martens</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Continual Pre-training of LLMs for Low-resource Languages</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10244</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10244v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Open-source Large Language models (OsLLMs) propel the democratization of natural language research by giving the flexibility to augment or update model parameters for performance improvement. Nevertheless, like proprietary LLMs, Os-LLMs offer poorer performance on low-resource languages (LRLs) than high-resource languages (HRLs), owing to smaller amounts of training data and underrepresented vocabulary. On the other hand, continual pre-training (CPT) with large amounts of language-specific data is a costly proposition in terms of data acquisition and computational resources. Our goal is to drastically reduce CPT cost. To that end, we first develop a new algorithm to select a subset of texts from a larger corpus. We show the effectiveness of our technique using very little CPT data. In search of further improvement, we design a new algorithm to select tokens to include in the LLM vocabulary. We experiment with the recent Llama-3 model and nine Indian languages with diverse scripts and extent of resource availability. For evaluation, we use IndicGenBench, a generation task benchmark dataset for Indic languages. We experiment with various CPT corpora and augmented vocabulary size and offer insights across language families.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10244v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Arijit Nag, Soumen Chakrabarti, Animesh Mukherjee, Niloy Ganguly</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Targeted Angular Reversal of Weights (TARS) for Knowledge Removal in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10257</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10257v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The sheer scale of data required to train modern large language models (LLMs) poses significant risks, as models are likely to gain knowledge of sensitive topics such as bio-security, as well the ability to replicate copyrighted works. Methods designed to remove such knowledge must do so from all prompt directions, in a multi-lingual capacity and without degrading general model performance. To this end, we introduce the targeted angular reversal (TARS) method of knowledge removal from LLMs. The TARS method firstly leverages the LLM in combination with a detailed prompt to aggregate information about a selected concept in the internal representation space of the LLM. It then refines this approximate concept vector to trigger the concept token with high probability, by perturbing the approximate concept vector with noise and transforming it into token scores with the language model head. The feedforward weight vectors in the LLM which operate directly on the internal representation space, and have the highest cosine similarity with this targeting vector, are then replaced by a reversed targeting vector, thus limiting the ability of the concept to propagate through the model. The modularity of the TARS method allows for a sequential removal of concepts from Llama 3.1 8B, such as the famous literary detective Sherlock Holmes, and the planet Saturn. It is demonstrated that the probability of triggering target concepts can be reduced to 0.00 with as few as 1 TARS edit, whilst simultaneously removing the knowledge bi-directionally. Moreover, knowledge is shown to be removed across all languages despite only being targeted in English. Importantly, TARS has minimal impact on the general model capabilities, as after removing 5 diverse concepts in a modular fashion, there is minimal KL divergence in the next token probabilities of the LLM on large corpora of Wikipedia text (median of 0.002).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10257v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Harry J. Davies, Giorgos Iacovides, Danilo P. Mandic</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reasoner Outperforms: Generative Stance Detection with Rationalization for Social Media</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10266</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10266v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Stance detection is crucial for fostering a human-centric Web by analyzing user-generated content to identify biases and harmful narratives that undermine trust. With the development of Large Language Models (LLMs), existing approaches treat stance detection as a classification problem, providing robust methodologies for modeling complex group interactions and advancing capabilities in natural language tasks. However, these methods often lack interpretability, limiting their ability to offer transparent and understandable justifications for predictions. This study adopts a generative approach, where stance predictions include explicit, interpretable rationales, and integrates them into smaller language models through single-task and multitask learning. We find that incorporating reasoning into stance detection enables the smaller model (FlanT5) to outperform GPT-3.5's zero-shot performance, achieving an improvement of up to 9.57%. Moreover, our results show that reasoning capabilities enhance multitask learning performance but may reduce effectiveness in single-task settings. Crucially, we demonstrate that faithful rationales improve rationale distillation into SLMs, advancing efforts to build interpretable, trustworthy systems for addressing discrimination, fostering trust, and promoting equitable engagement on social media.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10266v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiaqing Yuan, Ruijie Xi, Munindar P. Singh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking Linguistic Diversity of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10271</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10271v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The development and evaluation of Large Language Models (LLMs) has primarily focused on their task-solving capabilities, with recent models even surpassing human performance in some areas. However, this focus often neglects whether machine-generated language matches the human level of diversity, in terms of vocabulary choice, syntactic construction, and expression of meaning, raising questions about whether the fundamentals of language generation have been fully addressed. This paper emphasizes the importance of examining the preservation of human linguistic richness by language models, given the concerning surge in online content produced or aided by LLMs. We propose a comprehensive framework for evaluating LLMs from various linguistic diversity perspectives including lexical, syntactic, and semantic dimensions. Using this framework, we benchmark several state-of-the-art LLMs across all diversity dimensions, and conduct an in-depth case study for syntactic diversity. Finally, we analyze how different development and deployment choices impact the linguistic diversity of LLM outputs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10271v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yanzhu Guo, Guokan Shang, Chlo\'e Clavel</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One world, one opinion? The superstar effect in LLM responses</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10281</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10281v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: As large language models (LLMs) are shaping the way information is shared and accessed online, their opinions have the potential to influence a wide audience. This study examines who the LLMs view as the most prominent figures across various fields, using prompts in ten different languages to explore the influence of linguistic diversity. Our findings reveal low diversity in responses, with a small number of figures dominating recognition across languages (also known as the "superstar effect"). These results highlight the risk of narrowing global knowledge representation when LLMs retrieve subjective information.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10281v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sofie Goethals, Lauren Rhue</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Still "Talking About Large Language Models": Some Clarifications</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10291</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10291v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: My paper "Talking About Large Language Models" has more than once been interpreted as advocating a reductionist stance towards large language models. But the paper was not intended that way, and I do not endorse such positions. This short note situates the paper in the context of a larger philosophical project that is concerned with the (mis)use of words rather than metaphysics, in the spirit of Wittgenstein's later writing.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10291v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Murray Shanahan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SCBench: A KV Cache-Centric Analysis of Long-Context Methods</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10319</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10319v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Long-context LLMs have enabled numerous downstream applications but also introduced significant challenges related to computational and memory efficiency. To address these challenges, optimizations for long-context inference have been developed, centered around the KV cache. However, existing benchmarks often evaluate in single-request, neglecting the full lifecycle of the KV cache in real-world use. This oversight is particularly critical, as KV cache reuse has become widely adopted in LLMs inference frameworks, such as vLLM and SGLang, as well as by LLM providers, including OpenAI, Microsoft, Google, and Anthropic. To address this gap, we introduce SCBench(SharedContextBench), a comprehensive benchmark for evaluating long-context methods from a KV cachecentric perspective: 1) KV cache generation, 2) KV cache compression, 3) KV cache retrieval, 4) KV cache loading. Specifically, SCBench uses test examples with shared context, ranging 12 tasks with two shared context modes, covering four categories of long-context capabilities: string retrieval, semantic retrieval, global information, and multi-task. With it, we provide an extensive KV cache-centric analysis of eight categories long-context solutions, including Gated Linear RNNs, Mamba-Attention hybrids, and efficient methods such as sparse attention, KV cache dropping, quantization, retrieval, loading, and prompt compression. The evaluation is conducted on 8 long-context LLMs. Our findings show that sub-O(n) memory methods suffer in multi-turn scenarios, while sparse encoding with O(n) memory and sub-O(n^2) pre-filling computation perform robustly. Dynamic sparsity yields more expressive KV caches than static patterns, and layer-level sparsity in hybrid architectures reduces memory usage with strong performance. Additionally, we identify attention distribution shift issues in long-generation scenarios. https://aka.ms/SCBench.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10319v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yucheng Li, Huiqiang Jiang, Qianhui Wu, Xufang Luo, Surin Ahn, Chengruidong Zhang, Amir H. Abdi, Dongsheng Li, Jianfeng Gao, Yuqing Yang, Lili Qiu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Grounded Typology of Word Classes</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10369</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10369v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We propose a grounded approach to meaning in language typology. We treat data from perceptual modalities, such as images, as a language-agnostic representation of meaning. Hence, we can quantify the function--form relationship between images and captions across languages. Inspired by information theory, we define "groundedness", an empirical measure of contextual semantic contentfulness (formulated as a difference in surprisal) which can be computed with multilingual multimodal language models. As a proof of concept, we apply this measure to the typology of word classes. Our measure captures the contentfulness asymmetry between functional (grammatical) and lexical (content) classes across languages, but contradicts the view that functional classes do not convey content. Moreover, we find universal trends in the hierarchy of groundedness (e.g., nouns &gt; adjectives &gt; verbs), and show that our measure partly correlates with psycholinguistic concreteness norms in English. We release a dataset of groundedness scores for 30 languages. Our results suggest that the grounded typology approach can provide quantitative evidence about semantic function in language.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10369v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Coleman Haley, Sharon Goldwater, Edoardo Ponti</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transformative Influence of LLM and AI Tools in Student Social Media Engagement: Analyzing Personalization, Communication Efficiency, and Collaborative Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.15012</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.15012v2 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The advent of Large Language Models (LLMs) and Artificial Intelligence (AI) tools has revolutionized various facets of our lives, particularly in the realm of social media. For students, these advancements have unlocked unprecedented opportunities for learning, collaboration, and personal growth. AI-driven applications are transforming how students interact with social media, offering personalized content and recommendations, and enabling smarter, more efficient communication. Recent studies utilizing data from UniversityCube underscore the profound impact of AI tools on students' academic and social experiences. These studies reveal that students engaging with AI-enhanced social media platforms report higher academic performance, enhanced critical thinking skills, and increased engagement in collaborative projects.
  Moreover, AI tools assist in filtering out distracting content, allowing students to concentrate more on educational materials and pertinent discussions. The integration of LLMs in social media has further facilitated improved peer-to-peer communication and mentorship opportunities. AI algorithms effectively match students based on shared academic interests and career goals, fostering a supportive and intellectually stimulating online community, thereby contributing to increased student satisfaction and retention rates.
  In this article, we delve into the data provided by UniversityCube to explore how LLMs and AI tools are specifically transforming social media for students. Through case studies and statistical analyses, we offer a comprehensive understanding of the educational and social benefits these technologies offer. Our exploration highlights the potential of AI-driven tools to create a more enriched, efficient, and supportive educational environment for students in the digital age.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.15012v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Masoud Bashiri, Kamran Kowsari</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chatbots im Schulunterricht: Wir testen das Fobizz-Tool zur automatischen Bewertung von Hausaufgaben</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.06651</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.06651v3 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: [Study in German language.] This study examines the AI-powered grading tool "AI Grading Assistant" by the German company Fobizz, designed to support teachers in evaluating and providing feedback on student assignments. Against the societal backdrop of an overburdened education system and rising expectations for artificial intelligence as a solution to these challenges, the investigation evaluates the tool's functional suitability through two test series. The results reveal significant shortcomings: The tool's numerical grades and qualitative feedback are often random and do not improve even when its suggestions are incorporated. The highest ratings are achievable only with texts generated by ChatGPT. False claims and nonsensical submissions frequently go undetected, while the implementation of some grading criteria is unreliable and opaque. Since these deficiencies stem from the inherent limitations of large language models (LLMs), fundamental improvements to this or similar tools are not immediately foreseeable. The study critiques the broader trend of adopting AI as a quick fix for systemic problems in education, concluding that Fobizz's marketing of the tool as an objective and time-saving solution is misleading and irresponsible. Finally, the study calls for systematic evaluation and subject-specific pedagogical scrutiny of the use of AI tools in educational contexts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.06651v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.ET</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rainer Muehlhoff, Marte Henningsen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation Agent: Efficient and Promptable Evaluation Framework for Visual Generative Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09645</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09645v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recent advancements in visual generative models have enabled high-quality image and video generation, opening diverse applications. However, evaluating these models often demands sampling hundreds or thousands of images or videos, making the process computationally expensive, especially for diffusion-based models with inherently slow sampling. Moreover, existing evaluation methods rely on rigid pipelines that overlook specific user needs and provide numerical results without clear explanations. In contrast, humans can quickly form impressions of a model's capabilities by observing only a few samples. To mimic this, we propose the Evaluation Agent framework, which employs human-like strategies for efficient, dynamic, multi-round evaluations using only a few samples per round, while offering detailed, user-tailored analyses. It offers four key advantages: 1) efficiency, 2) promptable evaluation tailored to diverse user needs, 3) explainability beyond single numerical scores, and 4) scalability across various models and tools. Experiments show that Evaluation Agent reduces evaluation time to 10% of traditional methods while delivering comparable results. The Evaluation Agent framework is fully open-sourced to advance research in visual generative models and their efficient evaluation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09645v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fan Zhang, Shulin Tian, Ziqi Huang, Yu Qiao, Ziwei Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Systematic Analysis of LLM Contributions to Planning: Solver, Verifier, Heuristic</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09666</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09666v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In this work, we provide a systematic analysis of how large language models (LLMs) contribute to solving planning problems. In particular, we examine how LLMs perform when they are used as problem solver, solution verifier, and heuristic guidance to improve intermediate solutions. Our analysis reveals that although it is difficult for LLMs to generate correct plans out-of-the-box, LLMs are much better at providing feedback signals to intermediate/incomplete solutions in the form of comparative heuristic functions. This evaluation framework provides insights into how future work may design better LLM-based tree-search algorithms to solve diverse planning and reasoning problems. We also propose a novel benchmark to evaluate LLM's ability to learn user preferences on the fly, which has wide applications in practical settings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09666v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haoming Li, Zhaoliang Chen, Songyuan Liu, Yiming Lu, Fei Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Formal Languages and TQFTs with Defects</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09688</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09688v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: A construction that assigns a Boolean 1D TQFT with defects to a finite state automaton was recently developed by Gustafson, Im, Kaldawy, Khovanov, and Lihn. We show that the construction is functorial with respect to the category of finite state automata with transducers as morphisms. Certain classes of subregular languages correspond to additional cohomological structures on the associated TQFTs. We also show that the construction generalizes to context-free grammars through a categorical version of the Chomsky-Sch\"utzenberger representation theorem, due to Melli\`es and Zeilberger. The corresponding TQFTs are then described as morphisms of colored operads on an operad of cobordisms with defects.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09688v1</guid>
      <category>math-ph</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>math.MP</category>
      <category>math.QA</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Luisa Boateng, Matilde Marcolli</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human vs. AI: A Novel Benchmark and a Comparative Study on the Detection of Generated Images and the Impact of Prompts</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09715</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09715v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: With the advent of publicly available AI-based text-to-image systems, the process of creating photorealistic but fully synthetic images has been largely democratized. This can pose a threat to the public through a simplified spread of disinformation. Machine detectors and human media expertise can help to differentiate between AI-generated (fake) and real images and counteract this danger. Although AI generation models are highly prompt-dependent, the impact of the prompt on the fake detection performance has rarely been investigated yet. This work therefore examines the influence of the prompt's level of detail on the detectability of fake images, both with an AI detector and in a user study. For this purpose, we create a novel dataset, COCOXGEN, which consists of real photos from the COCO dataset as well as images generated with SDXL and Fooocus using prompts of two standardized lengths. Our user study with 200 participants shows that images generated with longer, more detailed prompts are detected significantly more easily than those generated with short prompts. Similarly, an AI-based detection model achieves better performance on images generated with longer prompts. However, humans and AI models seem to pay attention to different details, as we show in a heat map analysis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09715v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Philipp Moe{\ss}ner, Heike Adel</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Multimodal Large Language Models Complex Reason via Similarity Computation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09817</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09817v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Multimodal large language models have experienced rapid growth, and numerous different models have emerged. The interpretability of LVLMs remains an under-explored area. Especially when faced with more complex tasks such as chain-of-thought reasoning, its internal mechanisms still resemble a black box that is difficult to decipher. By studying the interaction and information flow between images and text, we noticed that in models such as LLaVA1.5, image tokens that are semantically related to text are more likely to have information flow convergence in the LLM decoding layer, and these image tokens receive higher attention scores. However, those image tokens that are less relevant to the text do not have information flow convergence, and they only get very small attention scores. To efficiently utilize the image information, we propose a new image token reduction method, Simignore, which aims to improve the complex reasoning ability of LVLMs by computing the similarity between image and text embeddings and ignoring image tokens that are irrelevant and unimportant to the text. Through extensive experiments, we demonstrate the effectiveness of our method for complex reasoning tasks. The paper's source code can be accessed from \url{https://github.com/FanshuoZeng/Simignore}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09817v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaofeng Zhang, Fanshuo Zeng, Yihao Quan, Zheng Hui, Jiawei Yao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Financial Sentiment Analysis: Leveraging Actual and Synthetic Data for Supervised Fine-tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09859</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09859v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The Efficient Market Hypothesis (EMH) highlights the essence of financial news in stock price movement. Financial news comes in the form of corporate announcements, news titles, and other forms of digital text. The generation of insights from financial news can be done with sentiment analysis. General-purpose language models are too general for sentiment analysis in finance. Curated labeled data for fine-tuning general-purpose language models are scare, and existing fine-tuned models for sentiment analysis in finance do not capture the maximum context width. We hypothesize that using actual and synthetic data can improve performance. We introduce BertNSP-finance to concatenate shorter financial sentences into longer financial sentences, and finbert-lc to determine sentiment from digital text. The results show improved performance on the accuracy and the f1 score for the financial phrasebank data with $50\%$ and $100\%$ agreement levels.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09859v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Abraham Atsiwo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Fairness of Computer Vision and Natural Language Processing Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09900</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09900v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Machine learning (ML) algorithms play a crucial role in decision making across diverse fields such as healthcare, finance, education, and law enforcement. Despite their widespread adoption, these systems raise ethical and social concerns due to potential biases and fairness issues. This study focuses on evaluating and improving the fairness of Computer Vision and Natural Language Processing (NLP) models applied to unstructured datasets, emphasizing how biased predictions can reinforce existing systemic inequalities. A publicly available dataset from Kaggle was utilized to simulate a practical scenario for examining fairness in ML workflows. To address and mitigate biases, the study employed two leading fairness libraries: Fairlearn by Microsoft, and AIF360 by IBM. These tools offer comprehensive frameworks for fairness analysis, including metrics evaluation, result visualization, and bias mitigation techniques. The research aims to measure bias levels in ML models, compare the effectiveness of these fairness libraries, and provide actionable recommendations for practitioners. The results demonstrate that each library possesses distinct strengths and limitations in evaluating and mitigating fairness. By systematically analyzing these tools, the study contributes valuable insights to the growing field of ML fairness, offering practical guidance for integrating fairness solutions into real world applications. This research underscores the importance of building more equitable and responsible machine learning systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09900v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ahmed Rashed, Abdelkrim Kallich, Mohamed Eltayeb</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simulating Hard Attention Using Soft Attention</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09925</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09925v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We study conditions under which transformers using soft attention can simulate hard attention, that is, effectively focus all attention on a subset of positions. First, we examine several variants of linear temporal logic, whose formulas have been previously been shown to be computable using hard attention transformers. We demonstrate how soft attention transformers can compute formulas of these logics using unbounded positional embeddings or temperature scaling. Second, we demonstrate how temperature scaling allows softmax transformers to simulate a large subclass of average-hard attention transformers, those that have what we call the uniform-tieless property.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09925v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.FL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Andy Yang, Lena Strobl, David Chiang, Dana Angluin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VLR-Bench: Multilingual Benchmark Dataset for Vision-Language Retrieval Augmented Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10151</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10151v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We propose the VLR-Bench, a visual question answering (VQA) benchmark for evaluating vision language models (VLMs) based on retrieval augmented generation (RAG). Unlike existing evaluation datasets for external knowledge-based VQA, the proposed VLR-Bench includes five input passages. This allows testing of the ability to determine which passage is useful for answering a given query, a capability lacking in previous research. In this context, we constructed a dataset of 32,000 automatically generated instruction-following examples, which we denote as VLR-IF. This dataset is specifically designed to enhance the RAG capabilities of VLMs by enabling them to learn how to generate appropriate answers based on input passages. We evaluated the validity of the proposed benchmark and training data and verified its performance using the state-of-the-art Llama3-based VLM, the Llava-Llama-3 model. The proposed VLR-Bench and VLR-IF datasets are publicly available online.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10151v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hyeonseok Lim, Dongjae Shin, Seohyun Song, Inho Won, Minjun Kim, Junghun Yuk, Haneol Jang, KyungTae Lim</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DeepSeek-VL2: Mixture-of-Experts Vision-Language Models for Advanced Multimodal Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10302</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10302v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We present DeepSeek-VL2, an advanced series of large Mixture-of-Experts (MoE) Vision-Language Models that significantly improves upon its predecessor, DeepSeek-VL, through two key major upgrades. For the vision component, we incorporate a dynamic tiling vision encoding strategy designed for processing high-resolution images with different aspect ratios. For the language component, we leverage DeepSeekMoE models with the Multi-head Latent Attention mechanism, which compresses Key-Value cache into latent vectors, to enable efficient inference and high throughput. Trained on an improved vision-language dataset, DeepSeek-VL2 demonstrates superior capabilities across various tasks, including but not limited to visual question answering, optical character recognition, document/table/chart understanding, and visual grounding. Our model series is composed of three variants: DeepSeek-VL2-Tiny, DeepSeek-VL2-Small and DeepSeek-VL2, with 1.0B, 2.8B and 4.5B activated parameters respectively. DeepSeek-VL2 achieves competitive or state-of-the-art performance with similar or fewer activated parameters compared to existing open-source dense and MoE-based models. Codes and pre-trained models are publicly accessible at https://github.com/deepseek-ai/DeepSeek-VL2.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10302v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhiyu Wu, Xiaokang Chen, Zizheng Pan, Xingchao Liu, Wen Liu, Damai Dai, Huazuo Gao, Yiyang Ma, Chengyue Wu, Bingxuan Wang, Zhenda Xie, Yu Wu, Kai Hu, Jiawei Wang, Yaofeng Sun, Yukun Li, Yishi Piao, Kang Guan, Aixin Liu, Xin Xie, Yuxiang You, Kai Dong, Xingkai Yu, Haowei Zhang, Liang Zhao, Yisong Wang, Chong Ruan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interlocking-free Selective Rationalization Through Genetic-based Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10312</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10312v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: A popular end-to-end architecture for selective rationalization is the select-then-predict pipeline, comprising a generator to extract highlights fed to a predictor. Such a cooperative system suffers from suboptimal equilibrium minima due to the dominance of one of the two modules, a phenomenon known as interlocking. While several contributions aimed at addressing interlocking, they only mitigate its effect, often by introducing feature-based heuristics, sampling, and ad-hoc regularizations. We present GenSPP, the first interlocking-free architecture for selective rationalization that does not require any learning overhead, as the above-mentioned. GenSPP avoids interlocking by performing disjoint training of the generator and predictor via genetic global search. Experiments on a synthetic and a real-world benchmark show that our model outperforms several state-of-the-art competitors.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10312v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.NE</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Federico Ruggeri, Gaetano Signorelli</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AdvPrefix: An Objective for Nuanced LLM Jailbreaks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10321</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10321v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Many jailbreak attacks on large language models (LLMs) rely on a common objective: making the model respond with the prefix "Sure, here is (harmful request)". While straightforward, this objective has two limitations: limited control over model behaviors, often resulting in incomplete or unrealistic responses, and a rigid format that hinders optimization. To address these limitations, we introduce AdvPrefix, a new prefix-forcing objective that enables more nuanced control over model behavior while being easy to optimize. Our objective leverages model-dependent prefixes, automatically selected based on two criteria: high prefilling attack success rates and low negative log-likelihood. It can further simplify optimization by using multiple prefixes for a single user request. AdvPrefix can integrate seamlessly into existing jailbreak attacks to improve their performance for free. For example, simply replacing GCG attack's target prefixes with ours on Llama-3 improves nuanced attack success rates from 14% to 80%, suggesting that current alignment struggles to generalize to unseen prefixes. Our work demonstrates the importance of jailbreak objectives in achieving nuanced jailbreaks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10321v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sicheng Zhu, Brandon Amos, Yuandong Tian, Chuan Guo, Ivan Evtimov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CCT-Code: Cross-Consistency Training for Multilingual Clone Detection and Code Search</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2305.11626</link>
      <description>arXiv:2305.11626v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We consider the well-known and important tasks of clone detection and information retrieval for source code. The most standard setup is to search clones inside the same language code snippets. But it is also useful to find code snippets with identical behaviour in different programming languages. Nevertheless multi- and cross-lingual clone detection has been little studied in literature. We present a novel training procedure, cross-consistency training (CCT) leveraging cross-lingual similarity, that we apply to train language models on source code in various programming languages. We show that this training is effective both for encoder- and decoder-based models. The trained encoder-based CCT-LM model achieves a new state of the art on POJ-104 (monolingual C++ clone detection benchmark) with 96.73\% MAP and AdvTest (monolingual Python code search benchmark) with 47.18\% MRR. The decoder-based CCT-LM model shows comparable performance in these tasks. In addition, we formulate the multi- and cross-lingual clone detection problem and present XCD, a new benchmark dataset produced from CodeForces submissions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2305.11626v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Anton Tikhonov, Nikita Sorokin, Dmitry Abulkhanov, Irina Piontkovskaya, Sergey Nikolenko, Valentin Malykh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Efficient Methods in Medical Question Answering using Knowledge Graph Embeddings</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.07977</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.07977v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In Natural Language Processing (NLP), Machine Reading Comprehension (MRC) is the task of answering a question based on a given context. To handle questions in the medical domain, modern language models such as BioBERT, SciBERT and even ChatGPT are trained on vast amounts of in-domain medical corpora. However, in-domain pre-training is expensive in terms of time and resources. In this paper, we propose a resource-efficient approach for injecting domain knowledge into a model without relying on such domain-specific pre-training.
  Knowledge graphs are powerful resources for accessing medical information. Building on existing work, we introduce a method using Multi-Layer Perceptrons (MLPs) for aligning and integrating embeddings extracted from medical knowledge graphs with the embedding spaces of pre-trained language models (LMs). The aligned embeddings are fused with open-domain LMs BERT and RoBERTa that are fine-tuned for two MRC tasks, span detection (COVID-QA) and multiple-choice questions (PubMedQA). We compare our method to prior techniques that rely on a vocabulary overlap for embedding alignment and show how our method circumvents this requirement to deliver better performance. On both datasets, our method allows BERT/RoBERTa to either perform on par (occasionally exceeding) with stronger domain-specific models or show improvements in general over prior techniques. With the proposed approach, we signal an alternative method to in-domain pre-training to achieve domain proficiency. Our code is available here.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.07977v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Saptarshi Sengupta, Connor Heaton, Suhan Cui, Soumalya Sarkar, Prasenjit Mitra</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Salute the Classic: Revisiting Challenges of Machine Translation in the Age of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.08350</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.08350v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The evolution of Neural Machine Translation (NMT) has been significantly influenced by six core challenges (Koehn and Knowles, 2017), which have acted as benchmarks for progress in this field. This study revisits these challenges, offering insights into their ongoing relevance in the context of advanced Large Language Models (LLMs): domain mismatch, amount of parallel data, rare word prediction, translation of long sentences, attention model as word alignment, and sub-optimal beam search. Our empirical findings indicate that LLMs effectively lessen the reliance on parallel data for major languages in the pretraining phase. Additionally, the LLM-based translation system significantly enhances the translation of long sentences that contain approximately 80 words and shows the capability to translate documents of up to 512 words. However, despite these significant improvements, the challenges of domain mismatch and prediction of rare words persist. While the challenges of word alignment and beam search, specifically associated with NMT, may not apply to LLMs, we identify three new challenges for LLMs in translation tasks: inference efficiency, translation of low-resource languages in the pretraining phase, and human-aligned evaluation. The datasets and models are released at https://github.com/pangjh3/LLM4MT.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.08350v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jianhui Pang, Fanghua Ye, Longyue Wang, Dian Yu, Derek F. Wong, Shuming Shi, Zhaopeng Tu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ReFT: Reasoning with Reinforced Fine-Tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.08967</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.08967v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: One way to enhance the reasoning capability of Large Language Models (LLMs) is to conduct Supervised Fine-Tuning (SFT) using Chain-of-Thought (CoT) annotations. This approach does not show sufficiently strong generalization ability, however, because the training only relies on the given CoT data. In math problem-solving, for example, there is usually only one annotated reasoning path for each question in the training data. Intuitively, it would be better for the algorithm to learn from multiple annotated reasoning paths given a question. To address this issue, we propose a simple yet effective approach called Reinforced Fine-Tuning (ReFT) to enhance the generalizability of learning LLMs for reasoning, with math problem-solving as an example. ReFT first warmups the model with SFT, and then employs on-line reinforcement learning, specifically the PPO algorithm in this paper, to further fine-tune the model, where an abundance of reasoning paths are automatically sampled given the question and the rewards are naturally derived from the ground-truth answers. Extensive experiments on GSM8K, MathQA, and SVAMP datasets show that ReFT significantly outperforms SFT, and the performance can be potentially further boosted by combining inference-time strategies such as majority voting and re-ranking. Note that ReFT obtains the improvement by learning from the same training questions as SFT, without relying on extra or augmented training questions. This indicates a superior generalization ability for ReFT.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.08967v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Trung Quoc Luong, Xinbo Zhang, Zhanming Jie, Peng Sun, Xiaoran Jin, Hang Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TreeEval: Benchmark-Free Evaluation of Large Language Models through Tree Planning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.13125</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.13125v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recently, numerous new benchmarks have been established to evaluate the performance of large language models (LLMs) via either computing a holistic score or employing another LLM as a judge. However, these approaches suffer from data leakage due to the open access of the benchmark and inflexible evaluation process. To address this issue, we introduce $\textbf{TreeEval}$, a benchmark-free evaluation method for LLMs that let a high-performance LLM host an irreproducible evaluation session and essentially avoids the data leakage. Moreover, this LLM performs as an examiner to raise up a series of questions under a topic with a tree planing strategy, which considers the current evaluation status to decide the next question generation and ensures the completeness and efficiency of the evaluation process. We evaluate $6$ models of different parameter sizes, including $7$B, $13$B, and $33$B, and ultimately achieved the highest correlation coefficient with AlpacaEval2.0 using only around $45$ questions. We also conduct more analysis to show the robustness and reliability of TreeEval. Our code can be accessed via the provided https://github.com/Ashura5/TreeEval.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.13125v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiang Li, Yunshi Lan, Chao Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Embedding-Informed Adaptive Retrieval-Augmented Generation of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03514</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03514v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Retrieval-augmented large language models (LLMs) have been remarkably competent in various NLP tasks. However, it was observed by previous works that retrieval is not always helpful, especially when the LLM is already knowledgeable on the query to answer. Motivated by this, Adaptive Retrieval-Augmented Generation (ARAG) studies retrieving only when the knowledge asked by the query is absent in the LLM. Previous works of ARAG either require accessing the pre-training corpus or prompting with additional model inferences. Aiming to avoid such drawbacks, we propose to determine whether the model is knowledgeable on a query via inspecting the (contextualized) pre-trained token embeddings of LLMs. We hypothesize that such embeddings capture rich information on the model's intrinsic knowledge base, which enables an efficient way of judging the necessity to retrieve from an external corpus. Extensive experiments demonstrate our ARAG approach's superior performance across various benchmarks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03514v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chengkai Huang, Yu Xia, Rui Wang, Kaige Xie, Tong Yu, Julian McAuley, Lina Yao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Training LLMs over Neurally Compressed Text</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03626</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03626v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this paper, we explore the idea of training large language models (LLMs) over highly compressed text. While standard subword tokenizers compress text by a small factor, neural text compressors can achieve much higher rates of compression. If it were possible to train LLMs directly over neurally compressed text, this would confer advantages in training and serving efficiency, as well as easier handling of long text spans. The main obstacle to this goal is that strong compression tends to produce opaque outputs that are not well-suited for learning. In particular, we find that text na\"ively compressed via Arithmetic Coding is not readily learnable by LLMs. To overcome this, we propose Equal-Info Windows, a novel compression technique whereby text is segmented into blocks that each compress to the same bit length. Using this method, we demonstrate effective learning over neurally compressed text that improves with scale, and outperforms byte-level baselines by a wide margin on perplexity and inference speed benchmarks. While our method delivers worse perplexity than subword tokenizers for models trained with the same parameter count, it has the benefit of shorter sequence lengths. Shorter sequence lengths require fewer autoregressive generation steps, and reduce latency. Finally, we provide extensive analysis of the properties that contribute to learnability, and offer concrete suggestions for how to further improve the performance of high-compression tokenizers.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03626v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Brian Lester, Jaehoon Lee, Alex Alemi, Jeffrey Pennington, Adam Roberts, Jascha Sohl-Dickstein, Noah Constant</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ViTHSD: Exploiting Hatred by Targets for Hate Speech Detection on Vietnamese Social Media Texts</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.19252</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.19252v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The growth of social networks makes toxic content spread rapidly. Hate speech detection is a task to help decrease the number of harmful comments. With the diversity in the hate speech created by users, it is necessary to interpret the hate speech besides detecting it. Hence, we propose a methodology to construct a system for targeted hate speech detection from online streaming texts from social media. We first introduce the ViTHSD - a targeted hate speech detection dataset for Vietnamese Social Media Texts. The dataset contains 10K comments, each comment is labeled to specific targets with three levels: clean, offensive, and hate. There are 5 targets in the dataset, and each target is labeled with the corresponding level manually by humans with strict annotation guidelines. The inter-annotator agreement obtained from the dataset is 0.45 by Cohen's Kappa index, which is indicated as a moderate level. Then, we construct a baseline for this task by combining the Bi-GRU-LSTM-CNN with the pre-trained language model to leverage the power of text representation of BERTology. Finally, we suggest a methodology to integrate the baseline model for targeted hate speech detection into the online streaming system for practical application in preventing hateful and offensive content on social media.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.19252v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Cuong Nhat Vo, Khanh Bao Huynh, Son T. Luu, Trong-Hop Do</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role-playing Prompt Framework: Generation and Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.00627</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.00627v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) exhibit impressive proficiency in natural language generation, understanding user instructions, and emulating human-like language use, which has led to significant interest in their application to role-playing scenarios. However, the manual collection of role-specific script data and the evaluation of model performance are resource-intensive processes. This paper introduces a prompt-based framework designed to leverage GPT's capabilities for the generation of role-playing dialogue datasets and the evaluation of role-playing performance. To validate the effectiveness of the GPT-based generation and evaluation, we further incorporate the recall-oriented Rouge-L metric, providing an additional quantitative measure of performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.00627v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xun Liu, Zhengwei Ni</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learn and Unlearn in Multilingual LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.13748</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.13748v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper investigates the propagation of harmful information in multilingual large language models (LLMs) and evaluates the efficacy of various unlearning methods. We demonstrate that fake information, regardless of the language it is in, once introduced into these models through training data, can spread across different languages, compromising the integrity and reliability of the generated content. Our findings reveal that standard unlearning techniques, which typically focus on English data, are insufficient in mitigating the spread of harmful content in multilingual contexts and could inadvertently reinforce harmful content across languages. We show that only by addressing harmful responses in both English and the original language of the harmful data can we effectively eliminate generations for all languages. This underscores the critical need for comprehensive unlearning strategies that consider the multilingual nature of modern LLMs to enhance their safety and reliability across diverse linguistic landscapes.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.13748v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Taiming Lu, Philipp Koehn</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TrustUQA: A Trustful Framework for Unified Structured Data Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.18916</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.18916v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Natural language question answering (QA) over structured data sources such as tables and knowledge graphs have been widely investigated, especially with Large Language Models (LLMs) in recent years. The main solutions include question to formal query parsing and retrieval-based answer generation. However, current methods of the former often suffer from weak generalization, failing to dealing with multi-types of sources, while the later is limited in trustfulness. In this paper, we propose TrustUQA, a trustful QA framework that can simultaneously support multiple types of structured data in a unified way. To this end, it adopts an LLM-friendly and unified knowledge representation method called Condition Graph(CG), and uses an LLM and demonstration-based two-level method for CG querying. For enhancement, it is also equipped with dynamic demonstration retrieval. We have evaluated TrustUQA with 5 benchmarks covering 3 types of structured data. It outperforms 2 existing unified structured data QA methods. In comparison with the baselines that are specific to one data type, it achieves state-of-the-art on 2 of the datasets. Further more, we have demonstrated the potential of our method for more general QA tasks, QA over mixed structured data and QA across structured data. The code is available at https://github.com/zjukg/TrustUQA.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.18916v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wen Zhang, Long Jin, Yushan Zhu, Jiaoyan Chen, Zhiwei Huang, Junjie Wang, Yin Hua, Lei Liang, Huajun Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Too Late to Train, Too Early To Use? A Study on Necessity and Viability of Low-Resource Bengali LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.00416</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.00416v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Each new generation of English-oriented Large Language Models (LLMs) exhibits enhanced cross-lingual transfer capabilities and significantly outperforms older LLMs on low-resource languages. This prompts the question: Is there a need for LLMs dedicated to a particular low-resource language? We aim to explore this question for Bengali, a low-to-moderate resource Indo-Aryan language native to the Bengal region of South Asia.
  We compare the performance of open-weight and closed-source LLMs such as LLaMA-3 and GPT-4 against fine-tuned encoder-decoder models across a diverse set of Bengali downstream tasks, including translation, summarization, paraphrasing, question-answering, and natural language inference. Our findings reveal that while LLMs generally excel in reasoning tasks, their performance in tasks requiring Bengali script generation is inconsistent. Key challenges include inefficient tokenization of Bengali script by existing LLMs, leading to increased computational costs and potential performance degradation. Additionally, we highlight biases in machine-translated datasets commonly used for Bengali NLP tasks. We conclude that there is a significant need for a Bengali-oriented LLM, but the field currently lacks the high-quality pretraining and instruction-tuning datasets necessary to develop a highly effective model.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.00416v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tamzeed Mahfuz, Satak Kumar Dey, Ruwad Naswan, Hasnaen Adil, Khondker Salman Sayeed, Haz Sameen Shahgir</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social Bias in Large Language Models For Bangla: An Empirical Study on Gender and Religious Bias</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.03536</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.03536v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The rapid growth of Large Language Models (LLMs) has put forward the study of biases as a crucial field. It is important to assess the influence of different types of biases embedded in LLMs to ensure fair use in sensitive fields. Although there have been extensive works on bias assessment in English, such efforts are rare and scarce for a major language like Bangla. In this work, we examine two types of social biases in LLM generated outputs for Bangla language. Our main contributions in this work are: (1) bias studies on two different social biases for Bangla, (2) a curated dataset for bias measurement benchmarking and (3) testing two different probing techniques for bias detection in the context of Bangla. This is the first work of such kind involving bias assessment of LLMs for Bangla to the best of our knowledge. All our code and resources are publicly available for the progress of bias related research in Bangla NLP.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.03536v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jayanta Sadhu, Maneesha Rani Saha, Rifat Shahriyar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Fog Computing for Enhanced LLM Execution in Medical Applications</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.04680</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.04680v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The ability of large language models (LLMs) to transform, interpret, and comprehend vast quantities of heterogeneous data presents a significant opportunity to enhance data-driven care delivery. However, the sensitive nature of protected health information (PHI) raises valid concerns about data privacy and trust in remote LLM platforms. In addition, the cost associated with cloud-based artificial intelligence (AI) services continues to impede widespread adoption. To address these challenges, we propose a shift in the LLM execution environment from opaque, centralized cloud providers to a decentralized and dynamic fog computing architecture. By executing open-weight LLMs in more trusted environments, such as the user's edge device or a fog layer within a local network, we aim to mitigate the privacy, trust, and financial challenges associated with cloud-based LLMs. We further present SpeziLLM, an open-source framework designed to facilitate rapid and seamless leveraging of different LLM execution layers and lowering barriers to LLM integration in digital health applications. We demonstrate SpeziLLM's broad applicability across six digital health applications, showcasing its versatility in various healthcare settings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.04680v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Philipp Zagar, Vishnu Ravi, Lauren Aalami, Stephan Krusche, Oliver Aalami, Paul Schmiedmayer</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recording for Eyes, Not Echoing to Ears: Contextualized Spoken-to-Written Conversion of ASR Transcripts</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09688</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.09688v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Automatic Speech Recognition (ASR) transcripts exhibit recognition errors and various spoken language phenomena such as disfluencies, ungrammatical sentences, and incomplete sentences, hence suffering from poor readability. To improve readability, we propose a Contextualized Spoken-to-Written conversion (CoS2W) task to address ASR and grammar errors and also transfer the informal text into the formal style with content preserved, utilizing contexts and auxiliary information. This task naturally matches the in-context learning capabilities of Large Language Models (LLMs). To facilitate comprehensive comparisons of various LLMs, we construct a document-level Spoken-to-Written conversion of ASR Transcripts Benchmark (SWAB) dataset. Using SWAB, we study the impact of different granularity levels on the CoS2W performance, and propose methods to exploit contexts and auxiliary information to enhance the outputs. Experimental results reveal that LLMs have the potential to excel in the CoS2W task, particularly in grammaticality and formality, our methods achieve effective understanding of contexts and auxiliary information by LLMs. We further investigate the effectiveness of using LLMs as evaluators and find that LLM evaluators show strong correlations with human evaluations on rankings of faithfulness and formality, which validates the reliability of LLM evaluators for the CoS2W task.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.09688v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiaqing Liu, Chong Deng, Qinglin Zhang, Shilin Zhou, Qian Chen, Hai Yu, Wen Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Factuality in Large Language Models via Decoding-Time Hallucinatory and Truthful Comparators</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12325</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12325v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Despite their remarkable capabilities, Large Language Models (LLMs) are prone to generate responses that contradict verifiable facts, i.e., unfaithful hallucination content. Existing efforts generally focus on optimizing model parameters or editing semantic representations, which compromise the internal factual knowledge of target LLMs. In addition, hallucinations typically exhibit multifaceted patterns in downstream tasks, limiting the model's holistic performance across tasks. In this paper, we propose a Comparator-driven Decoding-Time (CDT) framework to alleviate the response hallucination. Firstly, we construct hallucinatory and truthful comparators with multi-task fine-tuning samples. In this case, we present an instruction prototype-guided mixture of experts strategy to enhance the ability of the corresponding comparators to capture different hallucination or truthfulness patterns in distinct task instructions. CDT constrains next-token predictions to factuality-robust distributions by contrasting the logit differences between the target LLMs and these comparators. Systematic experiments on multiple downstream tasks show that our framework can significantly improve the model performance and response factuality.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12325v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dingkang Yang, Dongling Xiao, Jinjie Wei, Mingcheng Li, Zhaoyu Chen, Ke Li, Lihua Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strategic Insights in Human and Large Language Model Tactics at Word Guessing Games</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.11112</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.11112v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: At the beginning of 2022, a simplistic word-guessing game took the world by storm and was further adapted to many languages beyond the original English version. In this paper, we examine the strategies of daily word-guessing game players that have evolved during a period of over two years. A survey gathered from 25% of frequent players reveals their strategies and motivations for continuing the daily journey. We also explore the capability of several popular open-access large language model systems and open-source models at comprehending and playing the game in two different languages. Results highlight the struggles of certain models to maintain correct guess length and generate repetitions, as well as hallucinations of non-existent words and inflections.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.11112v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Published in the 4th Wordplay: When Language Meets Games Workshop @ ACL 2024</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Mat\=iss Rikters, Sanita Reinsone</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linguistic Minimal Pairs Elicit Linguistic Similarity in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.12435</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.12435v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We introduce a novel analysis that leverages linguistic minimal pairs to probe the internal linguistic representations of Large Language Models (LLMs). By measuring the similarity between LLM activation differences across minimal pairs, we quantify the and gain insight into the linguistic knowledge captured by LLMs. Our large-scale experiments, spanning 100+ LLMs and 150k minimal pairs in three languages, reveal properties of linguistic similarity from four key aspects: consistency across LLMs, relation to theoretical categorizations, dependency to semantic context, and cross-lingual alignment of relevant phenomena. Our findings suggest that 1) linguistic similarity is significantly influenced by training data exposure, leading to higher cross-LLM agreement in higher-resource languages. 2) Linguistic similarity strongly aligns with fine-grained theoretical linguistic categories but weakly with broader ones. 3) Linguistic similarity shows a weak correlation with semantic similarity, showing its context-dependent nature. 4) LLMs exhibit limited cross-lingual alignment in their understanding of relevant linguistic phenomena. This work demonstrates the potential of minimal pairs as a window into the neural representations of language in LLMs, shedding light on the relationship between LLMs and linguistic theory. Codes and data are available at https://github.com/ChenDelong1999/Linguistic-Similarity</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.12435v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xinyu Zhou, Delong Chen, Samuel Cahyawijaya, Xufeng Duan, Zhenguang G. Cai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fine Tuning Large Language Models for Medicine: The Role and Importance of Direct Preference Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.12741</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.12741v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Model (LLM) fine tuning is underutilized in the field of medicine. Two of the most common methods of fine tuning are Supervised Fine Tuning (SFT) and Direct Preference Optimization (DPO), but there is little guidance informing users when to use either technique. In this investigation, we compare the performance of SFT and DPO for five common natural language tasks in medicine: Classification with text data, Classification with numeric data, Clinical Reasoning, Summarization, and Clinical Triage. We find that SFT alone is sufficient for Classification with text data, whereas DPO improves performance for the more complex tasks of Clinical Reasoning, Summarization and Clinical Triage. Our results establish the role and importance of DPO fine tuning within medicine, and consequently call attention to current software gaps that prevent widespread deployment of this technique.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.12741v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Thomas Savage, Stephen Ma, Abdessalem Boukil, Vishwesh Patel, Ekanath Rangan, Ivan Lopez, Jonathan H Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Character-Centric Creative Story Generation via Imagination</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.16667</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.16667v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Creative story generation has long been a goal of NLP research. While existing methodologies have aimed to generate long and coherent stories, they fall significantly short of human capabilities in terms of diversity and character depth. To address this, we introduce a novel story generation framework called CCI (Character-centric Creative story generation via Imagination). CCI features two modules for creative story generation: IG (Image-Guided Imagination) and MW (Multi-Writer model). In the IG module, we utilize a text-to-image model to create visual representations of key story elements, such as characters, backgrounds, and main plots, in a more novel and concrete manner than text-only approaches. The MW module uses these story elements to generate multiple persona-description candidates and selects the best one to insert into the story, thereby enhancing the richness and depth of the narrative. We compared the stories generated by CCI and baseline models through statistical analysis, as well as human and LLM evaluations. The results showed that the IG and MW modules significantly improve various aspects of the stories' creativity. Furthermore, our framework enables interactive multi-modal story generation with users, opening up new possibilities for human-LLM integration in cultural development. Project page : https://www.2024cci.p-e.kr/</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.16667v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kyeongman Park, Minbeom Kim, Kyomin Jung</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of Code LLMs on Geospatial Code Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.04617</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.04617v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Software development support tools have been studied for a long time, with recent approaches using Large Language Models (LLMs) for code generation. These models can generate Python code for data science and machine learning applications. LLMs are helpful for software engineers because they increase productivity in daily work. An LLM can also serve as a "mentor" for inexperienced software developers, and be a viable learning support. High-quality code generation with LLMs can also be beneficial in geospatial data science. However, this domain poses different challenges, and code generation LLMs are typically not evaluated on geospatial tasks. Here, we show how we constructed an evaluation benchmark for code generation models, based on a selection of geospatial tasks. We categorised geospatial tasks based on their complexity and required tools. Then, we created a dataset with tasks that test model capabilities in spatial reasoning, spatial data processing, and geospatial tools usage. The dataset consists of specific coding problems that were manually created for high quality. For every problem, we proposed a set of test scenarios that make it possible to automatically check the generated code for correctness. In addition, we tested a selection of existing code generation LLMs for code generation in the geospatial domain. We share our dataset and reproducible evaluation code on a public GitHub repository, arguing that this can serve as an evaluation benchmark for new LLMs in the future. Our dataset will hopefully contribute to the development new models capable of solving geospatial coding tasks with high accuracy. These models will enable the creation of coding assistants tailored for geospatial applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.04617v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3687123.3698286</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Piotr Gramacki, Bruno Martins, Piotr Szyma\'nski</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Better: Avoiding Pitfalls in Developing Language Resources when Data is Scarce</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.12691</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.12691v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Language is a symbolic capital that affects people's lives in many ways (Bourdieu, 1977, 1991). It is a powerful tool that accounts for identities, cultures, traditions, and societies in general. Hence, data in a given language should be viewed as more than a collection of tokens. Good data collection and labeling practices are key to building more human-centered and socially aware technologies. While there has been a rising interest in mid- to low-resource languages within the NLP community, work in this space has to overcome unique challenges such as data scarcity and access to suitable annotators. In this paper, we collect feedback from those directly involved in and impacted by NLP artefacts for mid- to low-resource languages. We conduct a quantitative and qualitative analysis of the responses and highlight the main issues related to (1) data quality such as linguistic and cultural data suitability; and (2) the ethics of common annotation practices such as the misuse of online community services. Based on these findings, we make several recommendations for the creation of high-quality language artefacts that reflect the cultural milieu of its speakers, while simultaneously respecting the dignity and labor of data workers.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.12691v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nedjma Ousidhoum, Meriem Beloucif, Saif M. Mohammad</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GATEAU: Selecting Influential Sample for Long Context Alignment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.15633</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.15633v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Aligning large language models to handle instructions with extremely long contexts has yet to be fully investigated. Previous studies attempt to scale up the available data volume by synthesizing long instruction-following samples, as constructing such a dataset tends to be challenging for annotators. However, a lack of a well-defined strategy for ensuring data quality may introduce low-quality samples and restrict the model performance. Thus, we propose GATEAU, a novel framework to address the unique challenge of long context alignment by identifying the influential samples enriched with long-range dependency relations. Specifically, GATEAU measures the long-range dependencies from two essential aspects: the difficulty of generating target responses due to the long-range dependencies, and the difficulty of understanding long inputs due to such dependencies. Comprehensive experiments indicate that GATEAU effectively identifies influential samples and the model trained on these selected samples exhibits better instruction-following and long-context understanding capabilities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.15633v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shuzheng Si, Haozhe Zhao, Gang Chen, Yunshui Li, Kangyang Luo, Chuancheng Lv, Kaikai An, Fanchao Qi, Baobao Chang, Maosong Sun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frequency matters: Modeling irregular morphological patterns in Spanish with Transformers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.21013</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.21013v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The present paper evaluates the learning behaviour of a transformer-based neural network with regard to an irregular inflectional paradigm. We apply the paradigm cell filling problem to irregular patterns. We approach this problem using the morphological reinflection task and model it as a character sequence-to-sequence learning problem. The test case under investigation are irregular verbs in Spanish. Besides many regular verbs in Spanish L-shaped verbs the first person singular indicative stem irregularly matches the subjunctive paradigm, while other indicative forms remain unaltered. We examine the role of frequency during learning and compare models under differing input frequency conditions. We train the model on a corpus of Spanish with a realistic distribution of regular and irregular verbs to compare it with models trained on input with augmented distributions of (ir)regular words. We explore how the neural models learn this L-shaped pattern using post-hoc analyses. Our experiments show that, across frequency conditions, the models are surprisingly capable of learning the irregular pattern. Furthermore, our post-hoc analyses reveal the possible sources of errors. All code and data are available at \url{https://anonymous.4open.science/r/modeling_spanish_acl-7567/} under MIT license.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.21013v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Akhilesh Kakolu Ramarao, Kevin Tang, Dinah Baer-Henney</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clustering Algorithms and RAG Enhancing Semi-Supervised Text Classification with Large LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.06175</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.06175v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper introduces a novel semi-supervised learning framework specifically designed for text classification tasks, effectively addressing the challenge of vast datasets with limited labeled examples. By integrating multi-level similarity based data augmentation techniques from Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) to Large Language Model (LLM) rewriting and traditional word substitution-we constructed an intelligent augmentation pipeline. This framework innovatively employs the selection of representative landmarks through clustering, which serve as intermediaries in the retrieval and rewriting processes, ensuring that the augmented data maintains a distribution similar to the original dataset. Empirical results show that even in complex text document classification scenarios with over 100 categories, our method achieves state-of-the-art accuracies of 95.41% and 82.43% on the Reuters and Web of Science datasets, respectively. These findings highlight the effectiveness and broad applicability of our semi-supervised learning approach for text classification tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.06175v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shan Zhong, Jiahao Zeng, Yongxin Yu, Bohong Lin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Piecing It All Together: Verifying Multi-Hop Multimodal Claims</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09547</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09547v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Existing claim verification datasets often do not require systems to perform complex reasoning or effectively interpret multimodal evidence. To address this, we introduce a new task: multi-hop multimodal claim verification. This task challenges models to reason over multiple pieces of evidence from diverse sources, including text, images, and tables, and determine whether the combined multimodal evidence supports or refutes a given claim. To study this task, we construct MMCV, a large-scale dataset comprising 15k multi-hop claims paired with multimodal evidence, generated and refined using large language models, with additional input from human feedback. We show that MMCV is challenging even for the latest state-of-the-art multimodal large language models, especially as the number of reasoning hops increases. Additionally, we establish a human performance benchmark on a subset of MMCV. We hope this dataset and its evaluation task will encourage future research in multimodal multi-hop claim verification.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09547v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haoran Wang, Aman Rangapur, Xiongxiao Xu, Yueqing Liang, Haroon Gharwi, Carl Yang, Kai Shu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Cross-Lingual Audio Abuse Detection in Low-Resource Settings with Few-Shot Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.01408</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.01408v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Online abusive content detection, particularly in low-resource settings and within the audio modality, remains underexplored. We investigate the potential of pre-trained audio representations for detecting abusive language in low-resource languages, in this case, in Indian languages using Few Shot Learning (FSL). Leveraging powerful representations from models such as Wav2Vec and Whisper, we explore cross-lingual abuse detection using the ADIMA dataset with FSL. Our approach integrates these representations within the Model-Agnostic Meta-Learning (MAML) framework to classify abusive language in 10 languages. We experiment with various shot sizes (50-200) evaluating the impact of limited data on performance. Additionally, a feature visualization study was conducted to better understand model behaviour. This study highlights the generalization ability of pre-trained models in low-resource scenarios and offers valuable insights into detecting abusive language in multilingual contexts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.01408v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aditya Narayan Sankaran, Reza Farahbakhsh, Noel Crespi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Searching for Structure: Investigating Emergent Communication with Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.07646</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.07646v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Human languages have evolved to be structured through repeated language learning and use. These processes introduce biases that operate during language acquisition and shape linguistic systems toward communicative efficiency. In this paper, we investigate whether the same happens if artificial languages are optimised for implicit biases of Large Language Models (LLMs). To this end, we simulate a classical referential game in which LLMs learn and use artificial languages. Our results show that initially unstructured holistic languages are indeed shaped to have some structural properties that allow two LLM agents to communicate successfully. Similar to observations in human experiments, generational transmission increases the learnability of languages, but can at the same time result in non-humanlike degenerate vocabularies. Taken together, this work extends experimental findings, shows that LLMs can be used as tools in simulations of language evolution, and opens possibilities for future human-machine experiments in this field.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.07646v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tom Kouwenhoven, Max Peeperkorn, Tessa Verhoef</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improvement in Sign Language Translation Using Text CTC Alignment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09014</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09014v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Current sign language translation (SLT) approaches often rely on gloss-based supervision with Connectionist Temporal Classification (CTC), limiting their ability to handle non-monotonic alignments between sign language video and spoken text. In this work, we propose a novel method combining joint CTC/Attention and transfer learning. The joint CTC/Attention introduces hierarchical encoding and integrates CTC with the attention mechanism during decoding, effectively managing both monotonic and non-monotonic alignments. Meanwhile, transfer learning helps bridge the modality gap between vision and language in SLT. Experimental results on two widely adopted benchmarks, RWTH-PHOENIX-Weather 2014 T and CSL-Daily, show that our method achieves results comparable to state-of-the-art and outperforms the pure-attention baseline. Additionally, this work opens a new door for future research into gloss-free SLT using text-based CTC alignment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09014v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sihan Tan, Taro Miyazaki, Nabeela Khan, Kazuhiro Nakadai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Train to Generate, then Generate to Train: UnitedSynT5 for Few-Shot NLI</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09263</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09263v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Natural Language Inference (NLI) tasks require identifying the relationship between sentence pairs, typically classified as entailment, contradiction, or neutrality. While the current state-of-the-art (SOTA) model, Entailment Few-Shot Learning (EFL), achieves a 93.1% accuracy on the Stanford Natural Language Inference (SNLI) dataset, further advancements are constrained by the dataset's limitations. To address this, we propose a novel approach leveraging synthetic data augmentation to enhance dataset diversity and complexity. We present UnitedSynT5, an advanced extension of EFL that leverages a T5-based generator to synthesize additional premise-hypothesis pairs, which are rigorously cleaned and integrated into the training data. These augmented examples are processed within the EFL framework, embedding labels directly into hypotheses for consistency. We train a GTR-T5-XL model on this expanded dataset, achieving a new benchmark of 94.7% accuracy on the SNLI dataset, 94.0% accuracy on the E-SNLI dataset, and 92.6% accuracy on the MultiNLI dataset, surpassing the previous SOTA models. This research demonstrates the potential of synthetic data augmentation in improving NLI models, offering a path forward for further advancements in natural language understanding tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09263v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sourav Banerjee, Anush Mahajan, Ayushi Agarwal, Eishkaran Singh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking LLMs for Mimicking Child-Caregiver Language in Interaction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09318</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09318v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: LLMs can generate human-like dialogues, yet their ability to simulate early child-adult interactions remains largely unexplored. In this paper, we examined how effectively LLMs can capture the distinctive features of child-caregiver language in interaction, using both static and interactive benchmarking methods. We found that state-of-the-art LLMs like Llama 3 and GPT-4o can approximate child-caregiver dialogues at the word and utterance level, but they struggle to reproduce the child and caregiver's discursive patterns, exaggerate alignment, and fail to reach the level of diversity shown by humans. The broader goal of this work is to initiate the development of a comprehensive benchmark for LLMs in child-oriented applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09318v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jing Liu, Abdellah Fourtassi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neural Text Normalization for Luxembourgish using Real-Life Variation Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09383</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09383v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Orthographic variation is very common in Luxembourgish texts due to the absence of a fully-fledged standard variety. Additionally, developing NLP tools for Luxembourgish is a difficult task given the lack of annotated and parallel data, which is exacerbated by ongoing standardization. In this paper, we propose the first sequence-to-sequence normalization models using the ByT5 and mT5 architectures with training data obtained from word-level real-life variation data. We perform a fine-grained, linguistically-motivated evaluation to test byte-based, word-based and pipeline-based models for their strengths and weaknesses in text normalization. We show that our sequence model using real-life variation data is an effective approach for tailor-made normalization in Luxembourgish.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09383v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Anne-Marie Lutgen, Alistair Plum, Christoph Purschke, Barbara Plank</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pretraining Vision-Language Model for Difference Visual Question Answering in Longitudinal Chest X-rays</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.08966</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.08966v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Difference visual question answering (diff-VQA) is a challenging task that requires answering complex questions based on differences between a pair of images. This task is particularly important in reading chest X-ray images because radiologists often compare multiple images of the same patient taken at different times to track disease progression and changes in its severity in their clinical practice. However, previous works focused on designing specific network architectures for the diff-VQA task, missing opportunities to enhance the model's performance using a pretrained vision-language model (VLM). Here, we introduce a novel VLM called PLURAL, which is pretrained on natural and longitudinal chest X-ray data for the diff-VQA task. The model is developed using a step-by-step approach, starting with being pretrained on natural images and texts, followed by being trained using longitudinal chest X-ray data. The longitudinal data consist of pairs of X-ray images, along with question-answer sets and radiologist's reports that describe the changes in lung abnormalities and diseases over time. Our experimental results show that the PLURAL model outperforms state-of-the-art methods not only in diff-VQA for longitudinal X-rays but also in conventional VQA for a single X-ray image. Through extensive experiments, we demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed VLM architecture and pretraining method in improving the model's performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.08966v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yeongjae Cho, Taehee Kim, Heejun Shin, Sungzoon Cho, Dongmyung Shin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citation Amnesia: On The Recency Bias of NLP and Other Academic Fields</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12046</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.12046v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: This study examines the tendency to cite older work across 20 fields of study over 43 years (1980--2023). We put NLP's propensity to cite older work in the context of these 20 other fields to analyze whether NLP shows similar temporal citation patterns to these other fields over time or whether differences can be observed. Our analysis, based on a dataset of approximately 240 million papers, reveals a broader scientific trend: many fields have markedly declined in citing older works (e.g., psychology, computer science). We term this decline a 'citation age recession', analogous to how economists define periods of reduced economic activity. The trend is strongest in NLP and ML research (-12.8% and -5.5% in citation age from previous peaks). Our results suggest that citing more recent works is not directly driven by the growth in publication rates (-3.4% across fields; -5.2% in humanities; -5.5% in formal sciences) -- even when controlling for an increase in the volume of papers. Our findings raise questions about the scientific community's engagement with past literature, particularly for NLP, and the potential consequences of neglecting older but relevant research. The data and a demo showcasing our results are publicly available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.12046v2</guid>
      <category>cs.DL</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>COLING 2025</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Jan Philip Wahle, Terry Ruas, Mohamed Abdalla, Bela Gipp, Saif M. Mohammad</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging Sequence-Structure Alignment in RNA Foundation Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.11242</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.11242v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The alignment between RNA sequences and structures in foundation models (FMs) has yet to be thoroughly investigated. Existing FMs have struggled to establish sequence-structure alignment, hindering the free flow of genomic information between RNA sequences and structures. In this study, we introduce OmniGenome, an RNA FM trained to align RNA sequences with respect to secondary structures based on structure-contextualised modelling. The alignment enables free and bidirectional mappings between sequences and structures by utilising the flexible RNA modelling paradigm that supports versatile input and output modalities, i.e., sequence and/or structure as input/output. We implement RNA design and zero-shot secondary structure prediction as case studies to evaluate the Seq2Str and Str2Seq mapping capacity of OmniGenome. Results on the EternaV2 benchmark show that OmniGenome solved 74% of puzzles, whereas existing FMs only solved up to 3% of the puzzles due to the oversight of sequence-structure alignment. We leverage four comprehensive in-silico genome modelling benchmarks to evaluate performance across a diverse set of genome downstream tasks, where the results show that OmniGenome achieves state-of-the-art performance on RNA and DNA benchmarks, even without any training on DNA genomes.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.11242v3</guid>
      <category>q-bio.GN</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Heng Yang, Renzhi Chen, Ke Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Temporal Understanding in Audio Question Answering for Large Audio Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.06223</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.06223v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The Audio Question Answering (AQA) task includes audio event classification, audio captioning, and open-ended reasoning. Recently, AQA has garnered attention due to the advent of Large Audio Language Models (LALMs). Current literature focuses on constructing LALMs by integrating audio encoders with text-only Large Language Models (LLMs) through a projection module. While LALMs excel in general audio understanding, they are limited in temporal reasoning, which may hinder their commercial applications and on-device deployment. This paper addresses these challenges and limitations in audio temporal reasoning. First, we introduce a data augmentation technique for generating reliable audio temporal questions and answers using an LLM. Second, we perform a further fine-tuning of an existing baseline using curriculum learning strategy to specialize in temporal reasoning without compromising performance on fine-tuned tasks. We demonstrate the performance of our model using state-of-the-art LALMs on public audio benchmark datasets. Third, we implement our AQA model on-device locally and investigate its CPU inference for edge applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.06223v3</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Arvind Krishna Sridhar, Yinyi Guo, Erik Visser</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Test Case-Informed Knowledge Tracing for Open-ended Coding Tasks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.10829</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.10829v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Open-ended coding tasks, which ask students to construct programs according to certain specifications, are common in computer science education. Student modeling can be challenging since their open-ended nature means that student code can be diverse. Traditional knowledge tracing (KT) models that only analyze response correctness may not fully capture nuances in student knowledge from student code. In this paper, we introduce Test case-Informed Knowledge Tracing for Open-ended Coding (TIKTOC), a framework to simultaneously analyze and predict both open-ended student code and whether the code passes each test case. We augment the existing CodeWorkout dataset with the test cases used for a subset of the open-ended coding questions, and propose a multi-task learning KT method to simultaneously analyze and predict 1) whether a student's code submission passes each test case and 2) the student's open-ended code, using a large language model as the backbone. We quantitatively show that these methods outperform existing KT methods for coding that only use the overall score a code submission receives. We also qualitatively demonstrate how test case information, combined with open-ended code, helps us gain fine-grained insights into student knowledge.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.10829v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhangqi Duan, Nigel Fernandez, Alexander Hicks, Andrew Lan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DroidSpeak: KV Cache Sharing for Efficient Multi-LLM Serving</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.02820</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.02820v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) are increasingly employed in complex workflows, where different LLMs and fine-tuned variants collaboratively address complex tasks. However, these systems face significant inefficiencies due to redundant context processing of the shared context. We propose DroidSpeak, a framework that optimizes context sharing between fine-tuned LLMs derived from the same foundational model. DroidSpeak identifies critical layers in the KV cache and selectively recomputes them, enabling effective reuse of intermediate data while maintaining high accuracy.
  Our approach balances computational efficiency and task fidelity, significantly reducing inference latency and throughput bottlenecks. Experiments on diverse datasets and model pairs demonstrate that DroidSpeak achieves up to 3x higher throughputs and 2.6x faster prefill times with negligible accuracy loss compared to full recomputation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.02820v2</guid>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuhan Liu, Yuyang Huang, Jiayi Yao, Zhuohan Gu, Kuntai Du, Hanchen Li, Yihua Cheng, Junchen Jiang, Shan Lu, Madan Musuvathi, Esha Choukse</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NLP Cluster Analysis of Common Core State Standards and NAEP Item Specifications</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.04482</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.04482v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Camilli (2024) proposed a methodology using natural language processing (NLP) to map the relationship of a set of content standards to item specifications. This study provided evidence that NLP can be used to improve the mapping process. As part of this investigation, the nominal classifications of standards and items specifications were used to examine construct equivalence. In the current paper, we determine the strength of empirical support for the semantic distinctiveness of these classifications, which are known as "domains" for Common Core standards, and "strands" for National Assessment of Educational Progress (NAEP) item specifications. This is accomplished by separate k-means clustering for standards and specifications of their corresponding embedding vectors. We then briefly illustrate an application of these findings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.04482v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gregory Camilli, Larry Suter</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AutoDCWorkflow: LLM-based Data Cleaning Workflow Auto-Generation and Benchmark</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.06724</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.06724v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We investigate the reasoning capabilities of large language models (LLMs) for automatically generating data-cleaning workflows. To evaluate LLMs' ability to complete data-cleaning tasks, we implemented a pipeline for LLM-based Auto Data Cleaning Workflow (AutoDCWorkflow), prompting LLMs on data cleaning operations to repair three types of data quality issues: duplicates, missing values, and inconsistent data formats. Given a dirty table and a purpose (expressed as a query), this pipeline generates a minimal, clean table sufficient to address the purpose and the data cleaning workflow used to produce the table. The planning process involves three main LLM-driven components: (1) Select Target Columns: Identifies a set of target columns related to the purpose. (2) Inspect Column Quality: Assesses the data quality for each target column and generates a Data Quality Report as operation objectives. (3) Generate Operation &amp; Arguments: Predicts the next operation and arguments based on the data quality report results. Additionally, we propose a data cleaning benchmark to evaluate the capability of LLM agents to automatically generate workflows that address data cleaning purposes of varying difficulty levels. The benchmark comprises the annotated datasets as a collection of purpose, raw table, clean table, data cleaning workflow, and answer set. In our experiments, we evaluated three LLMs that auto-generate purpose-driven data cleaning workflows. The results indicate that LLMs perform well in planning and generating data-cleaning workflows without the need for fine-tuning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.06724v2</guid>
      <category>cs.DB</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lan Li, Liri Fang, Vetle I. Torvik</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Political Actor Agent: Simulating Legislative System for Roll Call Votes Prediction with Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.07144</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.07144v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Predicting roll call votes through modeling political actors has emerged as a focus in quantitative political science and computer science. Widely used embedding-based methods generate vectors for legislators from diverse data sets to predict legislative behaviors. However, these methods often contend with challenges such as the need for manually predefined features, reliance on extensive training data, and a lack of interpretability. Achieving more interpretable predictions under flexible conditions remains an unresolved issue. This paper introduces the Political Actor Agent (PAA), a novel agent-based framework that utilizes Large Language Models to overcome these limitations. By employing role-playing architectures and simulating legislative system, PAA provides a scalable and interpretable paradigm for predicting roll-call votes. Our approach not only enhances the accuracy of predictions but also offers multi-view, human-understandable decision reasoning, providing new insights into political actor behaviors. We conducted comprehensive experiments using voting records from the 117-118th U.S. House of Representatives, validating the superior performance and interpretability of PAA. This study not only demonstrates PAA's effectiveness but also its potential in political science research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.07144v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hao Li, Ruoyuan Gong, Hao Jiang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bootstrapping Heterogeneous Graph Representation Learning via Large Language Models: A Generalized Approach</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.08038</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.08038v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Graph representation learning methods are highly effective in handling complex non-Euclidean data by capturing intricate relationships and features within graph structures. However, traditional methods face challenges when dealing with heterogeneous graphs that contain various types of nodes and edges due to the diverse sources and complex nature of the data. Existing Heterogeneous Graph Neural Networks (HGNNs) have shown promising results but require prior knowledge of node and edge types and unified node feature formats, which limits their applicability. Recent advancements in graph representation learning using Large Language Models (LLMs) offer new solutions by integrating LLMs' data processing capabilities, enabling the alignment of various graph representations. Nevertheless, these methods often overlook heterogeneous graph data and require extensive preprocessing. To address these limitations, we propose a novel method that leverages the strengths of both LLM and GNN, allowing for the processing of graph data with any format and type of nodes and edges without the need for type information or special preprocessing. Our method employs LLM to automatically summarize and classify different data formats and types, aligns node features, and uses a specialized GNN for targeted learning, thus obtaining effective graph representations for downstream tasks. Theoretical analysis and experimental validation have demonstrated the effectiveness of our method.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.08038v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hang Gao, Chenhao Zhang, Fengge Wu, Junsuo Zhao, Changwen Zheng, Huaping Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Olympus: A Universal Task Router for Computer Vision Tasks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09612</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09612v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We introduce Olympus, a new approach that transforms Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) into a unified framework capable of handling a wide array of computer vision tasks. Utilizing a controller MLLM, Olympus delegates over 20 specialized tasks across images, videos, and 3D objects to dedicated modules. This instruction-based routing enables complex workflows through chained actions without the need for training heavy generative models. Olympus easily integrates with existing MLLMs, expanding their capabilities with comparable performance. Experimental results demonstrate that Olympus achieves an average routing accuracy of 94.75% across 20 tasks and precision of 91.82% in chained action scenarios, showcasing its effectiveness as a universal task router that can solve a diverse range of computer vision tasks. Project page: http://yuanze-lin.me/Olympus_page/</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09612v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuanze Lin, Yunsheng Li, Dongdong Chen, Weijian Xu, Ronald Clark, Philip H. S. Torr</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
