<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL</link>
    <description>cs.CL updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 04:00:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Saturday</day>
      <day>Sunday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>NL2FOL: Translating Natural Language to First-Order Logic for Logical Fallacy Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02318</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02318v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Logical fallacies are common errors in reasoning that undermine the logic of an argument. Automatically detecting logical fallacies has important applications in tracking misinformation and validating claims. In this paper, we design a process to reliably detect logical fallacies by translating natural language to First-order Logic (FOL) step-by-step using Large Language Models (LLMs). We then utilize Satisfiability Modulo Theory (SMT) solvers to reason about the validity of the formula and classify inputs as either a fallacy or valid statement. Our model also provides a novel means of utilizing LLMs to interpret the output of the SMT solver, offering insights into the counter-examples that illustrate why a given sentence is considered a logical fallacy. Our approach is robust, interpretable and does not require training data or fine-tuning. We evaluate our model on a mixed dataset of fallacies and valid sentences. The results demonstrate improved performance compared to end-to-end LLMs, with our classifier achieving an F1-score of 71\% on the Logic dataset. The approach is able to generalize effectively, achieving an F1-score of 73% on the challenge set, LogicClimate, outperforming state-of-the-art models by 21% despite its much smaller size.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02318v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.LO</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Abhinav Lalwani, Lovish Chopra, Christopher Hahn, Caroline Trippel, Zhijing Jin, Mrinmaya Sachan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Early Transformers: A study on Efficient Training of Transformer Models through Early-Bird Lottery Tickets</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02353</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02353v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The training of Transformer models has revolutionized natural language processing and computer vision, but it remains a resource-intensive and time-consuming process. This paper investigates the applicability of the early-bird ticket hypothesis to optimize the training efficiency of Transformer models. We propose a methodology that combines iterative pruning, masked distance calculation, and selective retraining to identify early-bird tickets in various Transformer architectures, including ViT, Swin-T, GPT-2, and RoBERTa. Our experimental results demonstrate that early-bird tickets can be consistently found within the first few epochs of training or fine-tuning, enabling significant resource optimization without compromising performance. The pruned models obtained from early-bird tickets achieve comparable or even superior accuracy to their unpruned counterparts while substantially reducing memory usage. Furthermore, our comparative analysis highlights the generalizability of the early-bird ticket phenomenon across different Transformer models and tasks. This research contributes to the development of efficient training strategies for Transformer models, making them more accessible and resource-friendly. By leveraging early-bird tickets, practitioners can accelerate the progress of natural language processing and computer vision applications while reducing the computational burden associated with training Transformer models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02353v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shravan Cheekati</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Call for Socially Aware Language Technologies</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02411</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02411v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Language technologies have made enormous progress, especially with the introduction of large language models (LLMs). On traditional tasks such as machine translation and sentiment analysis, these models perform at near-human level. These advances can, however, exacerbate a variety of issues that models have traditionally struggled with, such as bias, evaluation, and risks. In this position paper, we argue that many of these issues share a common core: a lack of awareness of the factors, context, and implications of the social environment in which NLP operates, which we call social awareness. While NLP is getting better at solving the formal linguistic aspects, limited progress has been made in adding the social awareness required for language applications to work in all situations for all users. Integrating social awareness into NLP models will make applications more natural, helpful, and safe, and will open up new possibilities. Thus we argue that substantial challenges remain for NLP to develop social awareness and that we are just at the beginning of a new era for the field.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02411v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Diyi Yang, Dirk Hovy, David Jurgens, Barbara Plank</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What does the Knowledge Neuron Thesis Have to do with Knowledge?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02421</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02421v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We reassess the Knowledge Neuron (KN) Thesis: an interpretation of the mechanism underlying the ability of large language models to recall facts from a training corpus. This nascent thesis proposes that facts are recalled from the training corpus through the MLP weights in a manner resembling key-value memory, implying in effect that "knowledge" is stored in the network. Furthermore, by modifying the MLP modules, one can control the language model's generation of factual information. The plausibility of the KN thesis has been demonstrated by the success of KN-inspired model editing methods (Dai et al., 2022; Meng et al., 2022).
  We find that this thesis is, at best, an oversimplification. Not only have we found that we can edit the expression of certain linguistic phenomena using the same model editing methods but, through a more comprehensive evaluation, we have found that the KN thesis does not adequately explain the process of factual expression. While it is possible to argue that the MLP weights store complex patterns that are interpretable both syntactically and semantically, these patterns do not constitute "knowledge." To gain a more comprehensive understanding of the knowledge representation process, we must look beyond the MLP weights and explore recent models' complex layer structures and attention mechanisms.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02421v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jingcheng Niu, Andrew Liu, Zining Zhu, Gerald Penn</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Sentiment Meant to Mean to Language Models?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02454</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02454v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Sentiment analysis is one of the most widely used techniques in text analysis. Recent advancements with Large Language Models have made it more accurate and accessible than ever, allowing researchers to classify text with only a plain English prompt. However, "sentiment" entails a wide variety of concepts depending on the domain and tools used. It has been used to mean emotion, opinions, market movements, or simply a general ``good-bad'' dimension. This raises a question: What exactly are language models doing when prompted to label documents by sentiment? This paper first overviews how sentiment is defined across different contexts, highlighting that it is a confounded measurement construct in that it entails multiple variables, such as emotional valence and opinion, without disentangling them. I then test three language models across two data sets with prompts requesting sentiment, valence, and stance classification. I find that sentiment labels most strongly correlate with valence labels. I further find that classification improves when researchers more precisely specify their dimension of interest rather than using the less well-defined concept of sentiment. I conclude by encouraging researchers to move beyond "sentiment" when feasible and use a more precise measurement construct.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02454v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Michael Burnham</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Scaling: Bayesian Ideal Point Estimates with Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02472</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02472v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper introduces "Semantic Scaling," a novel method for ideal point estimation from text. I leverage large language models to classify documents based on their expressed stances and extract survey-like data. I then use item response theory to scale subjects from these data. Semantic Scaling significantly improves on existing text-based scaling methods, and allows researchers to explicitly define the ideological dimensions they measure. This represents the first scaling approach that allows such flexibility outside of survey instruments and opens new avenues of inquiry for populations difficult to survey. Additionally, it works with documents of varying length, and produces valid estimates of both mass and elite ideology. I demonstrate that the method can differentiate between policy preferences and in-group/out-group affect. Among the public, Semantic Scaling out-preforms Tweetscores according to human judgement; in Congress, it recaptures the first dimension DW-NOMINATE while allowing for greater flexibility in resolving construct validity challenges.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02472v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Michael Burnham</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Helpfulness and Harmlessness: Eliciting Diverse Behaviors from Large Language Models with Persona In-Context Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02501</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02501v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) are trained on massive text corpora, which are encoded with diverse personality traits. This triggers an interesting goal of eliciting a desired personality trait from the LLM, and probing its behavioral preferences. Accordingly, we formalize the persona elicitation task, aiming to customize LLM behaviors to align with a target persona. We present Persona In-Context Learning (PICLe), a novel persona elicitation framework grounded in Bayesian inference. At the core, PICLe introduces a new ICL example selection criterion based on likelihood ratio, which is designed to optimally guide the model in eliciting a specific target persona. We demonstrate the effectiveness of PICLe through extensive comparisons against baseline methods across three contemporary LLMs. Code is available at https://github.com/deeplearning-wisc/picle.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02501v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hyeong Kyu Choi, Yixuan Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mothman at SemEval-2024 Task 9: An Iterative System for Chain-of-Thought Prompt Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02517</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02517v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Extensive research exists on the performance of large language models on logic-based tasks, whereas relatively little has been done on their ability to generate creative solutions on lateral thinking tasks. The BrainTeaser shared task tests lateral thinking and uses adversarial datasets to prevent memorization, resulting in poor performance for out-of-the-box models. We propose a system for iterative, chain-of-thought prompt engineering which optimizes prompts using human evaluation. Using this shared task, we demonstrate our system's ability to significantly improve model performance by optimizing prompts and evaluate the input dataset.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02517v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alvin Po-Chun Chen, Ray Groshan, Sean von Bayern</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Literature Review and Framework for Human Evaluation of Generative Large Language Models in Healthcare</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02559</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02559v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: As generative artificial intelligence (AI), particularly Large Language Models (LLMs), continues to permeate healthcare, it remains crucial to supplement traditional automated evaluations with human expert evaluation. Understanding and evaluating the generated texts is vital for ensuring safety, reliability, and effectiveness. However, the cumbersome, time-consuming, and non-standardized nature of human evaluation presents significant obstacles to the widespread adoption of LLMs in practice. This study reviews existing literature on human evaluation methodologies for LLMs within healthcare. We highlight a notable need for a standardized and consistent human evaluation approach. Our extensive literature search, adhering to the Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses (PRISMA) guidelines, spans publications from January 2018 to February 2024. This review provides a comprehensive overview of the human evaluation approaches used in diverse healthcare applications.This analysis examines the human evaluation of LLMs across various medical specialties, addressing factors such as evaluation dimensions, sample types, and sizes, the selection and recruitment of evaluators, frameworks and metrics, the evaluation process, and statistical analysis of the results. Drawing from diverse evaluation strategies highlighted in these studies, we propose a comprehensive and practical framework for human evaluation of generative LLMs, named QUEST: Quality of Information, Understanding and Reasoning, Expression Style and Persona, Safety and Harm, and Trust and Confidence. This framework aims to improve the reliability, generalizability, and applicability of human evaluation of generative LLMs in different healthcare applications by defining clear evaluation dimensions and offering detailed guidelines.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02559v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Thomas Yu Chow Tam, Sonish Sivarajkumar, Sumit Kapoor, Alisa V Stolyar, Katelyn Polanska, Karleigh R McCarthy, Hunter Osterhoudt, Xizhi Wu, Shyam Visweswaran, Sunyang Fu, Piyush Mathur, Giovanni E. Cacciamani, Cong Sun, Yifan Peng, Yanshan Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Combination of BERT and Transformer for Vietnamese Spelling Correction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02573</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02573v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recently, many studies have shown the efficiency of using Bidirectional Encoder Representations from Transformers (BERT) in various Natural Language Processing (NLP) tasks. Specifically, English spelling correction task that uses Encoder-Decoder architecture and takes advantage of BERT has achieved state-of-the-art result. However, to our knowledge, there is no implementation in Vietnamese yet. Therefore, in this study, a combination of Transformer architecture (state-of-the-art for Encoder-Decoder model) and BERT was proposed to deal with Vietnamese spelling correction. The experiment results have shown that our model outperforms other approaches as well as the Google Docs Spell Checking tool, achieves an 86.24 BLEU score on this task.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02573v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1007/978-3-031-21743-2_43</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>ACIIDS 2022, LNCS, vol 13757, Springer, Cham</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Hieu Ngo Trung, Duong Tran Ham, Tin Huynh, Kiem Hoang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mixat: A Data Set of Bilingual Emirati-English Speech</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02578</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02578v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper introduces Mixat: a dataset of Emirati speech code-mixed with English. Mixat was developed to address the shortcomings of current speech recognition resources when applied to Emirati speech, and in particular, to bilignual Emirati speakers who often mix and switch between their local dialect and English. The data set consists of 15 hours of speech derived from two public podcasts featuring native Emirati speakers, one of which is in the form of conversations between the host and a guest. Therefore, the collection contains examples of Emirati-English code-switching in both formal and natural conversational contexts. In this paper, we describe the process of data collection and annotation, and describe some of the features and statistics of the resulting data set. In addition, we evaluate the performance of pre-trained Arabic and multi-lingual ASR systems on our dataset, demonstrating the shortcomings of existing models on this low-resource dialectal Arabic, and the additional challenge of recognizing code-switching in ASR. The dataset will be made publicly available for research use.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02578v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Maryam Al Ali, Hanan Aldarmaki</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Astro-NER -- Astronomy Named Entity Recognition: Is GPT a Good Domain Expert Annotator?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02602</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02602v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this study, we address one of the challenges of developing NER models for scholarly domains, namely the scarcity of suitable labeled data. We experiment with an approach using predictions from a fine-tuned LLM model to aid non-domain experts in annotating scientific entities within astronomy literature, with the goal of uncovering whether such a collaborative process can approximate domain expertise. Our results reveal moderate agreement between a domain expert and the LLM-assisted non-experts, as well as fair agreement between the domain expert and the LLM model's predictions. In an additional experiment, we compare the performance of finetuned and default LLMs on this task. We have also introduced a specialized scientific entity annotation scheme for astronomy, validated by a domain expert. Our approach adopts a scholarly research contribution-centric perspective, focusing exclusively on scientific entities relevant to the research theme. The resultant dataset, containing 5,000 annotated astronomy article titles, is made publicly available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02602v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.IT</category>
      <category>math.IT</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Julia Evans, Sameer Sadruddin, Jennifer D'Souza</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identifying Narrative Patterns and Outliers in Holocaust Testimonies Using Topic Modeling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02650</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02650v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The vast collection of Holocaust survivor testimonies presents invaluable historical insights but poses challenges for manual analysis. This paper leverages advanced Natural Language Processing (NLP) techniques to explore the USC Shoah Foundation Holocaust testimony corpus. By treating testimonies as structured question-and-answer sections, we apply topic modeling to identify key themes. We experiment with BERTopic, which leverages recent advances in language modeling technology. We align testimony sections into fixed parts, revealing the evolution of topics across the corpus of testimonies. This highlights both a common narrative schema and divergences between subgroups based on age and gender. We introduce a novel method to identify testimonies within groups that exhibit atypical topic distributions resembling those of other groups. This study offers unique insights into the complex narratives of Holocaust survivors, demonstrating the power of NLP to illuminate historical discourse and identify potential deviations in survivor experiences.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02650v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Maxim Ifergan, Renana Keydar, Omri Abend, Amit Pinchevski</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>R4: Reinforced Retriever-Reorder-Responder for Retrieval-Augmented Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02659</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02659v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Retrieval-augmented large language models (LLMs) leverage relevant content retrieved by information retrieval systems to generate correct responses, aiming to alleviate the hallucination problem. However, existing retriever-responder methods typically append relevant documents to the prompt of LLMs to perform text generation tasks without considering the interaction of fine-grained structural semantics between the retrieved documents and the LLMs. This issue is particularly important for accurate response generation as LLMs tend to ``lose in the middle'' when dealing with input prompts augmented with lengthy documents. In this work, we propose a new pipeline named ``Reinforced Retriever-Reorder-Responder'' (R$^4$) to learn document orderings for retrieval-augmented LLMs, thereby further enhancing their generation abilities while the large numbers of parameters of LLMs remain frozen. The reordering learning process is divided into two steps according to the quality of the generated responses: document order adjustment and document representation enhancement. Specifically, document order adjustment aims to organize retrieved document orderings into beginning, middle, and end positions based on graph attention learning, which maximizes the reinforced reward of response quality. Document representation enhancement further refines the representations of retrieved documents for responses of poor quality via document-level gradient adversarial learning. Extensive experiments demonstrate that our proposed pipeline achieves better factual question-answering performance on knowledge-intensive tasks compared to strong baselines across various public datasets. The source codes and trained models will be released upon paper acceptance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02659v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Taolin Zhang, Dongyang Li, Qizhou Chen, Chengyu Wang, Longtao Huang, Hui Xue, Xiaofeng He, Jun Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Information Redundancy in Non-Autoregressive Translation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02673</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02673v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Token repetition is a typical form of multi-modal problem in fully non-autoregressive translation (NAT). In this work, we revisit the multi-modal problem in recently proposed NAT models. Our study reveals that these advanced models have introduced other types of information redundancy errors, which cannot be measured by the conventional metric - the continuous repetition ratio. By manually annotating the NAT outputs, we identify two types of information redundancy errors that correspond well to lexical and reordering multi-modality problems. Since human annotation is time-consuming and labor-intensive, we propose automatic metrics to evaluate the two types of redundant errors. Our metrics allow future studies to evaluate new methods and gain a more comprehensive understanding of their effectiveness.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02673v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhihao Wang, Longyue Wang, Jinsong Su, Junfeng Yao, Zhaopeng Tu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the Ability of Computationally Extracted Narrative Maps to Encode Media Framing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02677</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02677v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Narratives serve as fundamental frameworks in our understanding of the world and play a crucial role in collaborative sensemaking, providing a versatile foundation for sensemaking. Framing is a subtle yet potent mechanism that influences public perception through specific word choices, shaping interpretations of reported news events. Despite the recognized importance of narratives and framing, a significant gap exists in the literature with regard to the explicit consideration of framing within the context of computational extraction and representation. This article explores the capabilities of a specific narrative extraction and representation approach -- narrative maps -- to capture framing information from news data. The research addresses two key questions: (1) Does the narrative extraction method capture the framing distribution of the data set? (2) Does it produce a representation with consistent framing? Our results indicate that while the algorithm captures framing distributions, achieving consistent framing across various starting and ending events poses challenges. Our results highlight the potential of narrative maps to provide users with insights into the intricate framing dynamics within news narratives. However, we note that directly leveraging framing information in the computational narrative extraction process remains an open challenge.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02677v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sebasti\'an Concha Mac\'ias, Brian Keith Norambuena</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing News Summarization with ELearnFit through Efficient In-Context Learning and Efficient Fine-Tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02710</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02710v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: With the deluge of information delivered by the daily news cycle, there is a growing need to effectively and efficiently summarize news feeds for quick consumption. We leverage large language models (LLMs), with their advanced learning and generative abilities as compared to conventional language models, to generate concise and coherent summaries for news articles from the XSum dataset. Our paper focuses on two key aspects of LLMs: Efficient in-context Learning (ELearn) and Parameter Efficient Fine-tuning (EFit). Under ELearn, we find that increasing the number of shots in prompts and utilizing simple templates generally improve the quality of summaries. We also find that utilizing relevant examples in few-shot learning for ELearn does not improve model performance. In addition, we studied EFit using different methods and demonstrate that fine-tuning the first layer of LLMs produces better outcomes as compared to fine-tuning other layers or utilizing LoRA. We also find that leveraging more relevant training samples using selective layers does not result in better performance. By combining ELearn and EFit, we create a new model (ELearnFit) that leverages the benefits of both few-shot learning and fine-tuning and produces superior performance to either model alone. We also use ELearnFit to highlight the trade-offs between prompting and fine-tuning, especially for situations where only a limited number of annotated samples are available. Ultimately, our research provides practical techniques to optimize news summarization during the prompting and fine-tuning stages and enhances the synthesis of news articles.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02710v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Che Guan, Andrew Chin, Puya Vahabi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoE-SQL: In-Context Learning for Multi-Turn Text-to-SQL with Chain-of-Editions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02712</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02712v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recently, Large Language Models (LLMs) have been demonstrated to possess impressive capabilities in a variety of domains and tasks. We investigate the issue of prompt design in the multi-turn text-to-SQL task and attempt to enhance the LLMs' reasoning capacity when generating SQL queries. In the conversational context, the current SQL query can be modified from the preceding SQL query with only a few operations due to the context dependency. We introduce our method called CoE-SQL which can prompt LLMs to generate the SQL query based on the previously generated SQL query with an edition chain. We also conduct extensive ablation studies to determine the optimal configuration of our approach. Our approach outperforms different in-context learning baselines stably and achieves state-of-the-art performances on two benchmarks SParC and CoSQL using LLMs, which is also competitive to the SOTA fine-tuned models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02712v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hanchong Zhang, Ruisheng Cao, Hongshen Xu, Lu Chen, Kai Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recall Them All: Retrieval-Augmented Language Models for Long Object List Extraction from Long Documents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02732</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02732v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Methods for relation extraction from text mostly focus on high precision, at the cost of limited recall. High recall is crucial, though, to populate long lists of object entities that stand in a specific relation with a given subject. Cues for relevant objects can be spread across many passages in long texts. This poses the challenge of extracting long lists from long texts. We present the L3X method which tackles the problem in two stages: (1) recall-oriented generation using a large language model (LLM) with judicious techniques for retrieval augmentation, and (2) precision-oriented scrutinization to validate or prune candidates. Our L3X method outperforms LLM-only generations by a substantial margin.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02732v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sneha Singhania, Simon Razniewski, Gerhard Weikum</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Relations Prediction for Knowledge Graph Completion using Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02738</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02738v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Knowledge Graphs have been widely used to represent facts in a structured format. Due to their large scale applications, knowledge graphs suffer from being incomplete. The relation prediction task obtains knowledge graph completion by assigning one or more possible relations to each pair of nodes. In this work, we make use of the knowledge graph node names to fine-tune a large language model for the relation prediction task. By utilizing the node names only we enable our model to operate sufficiently in the inductive settings. Our experiments show that we accomplish new scores on a widely used knowledge graph benchmark.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02738v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sakher Khalil Alqaaidi, Krzysztof Kochut</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Performance: Quantifying and Mitigating Label Bias in LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02743</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02743v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have shown remarkable adaptability to diverse tasks, by leveraging context prompts containing instructions, or minimal input-output examples. However, recent work revealed they also exhibit label bias -- an undesirable preference toward predicting certain answers over others. Still, detecting and measuring this bias reliably and at scale has remained relatively unexplored. In this study, we evaluate different approaches to quantifying label bias in a model's predictions, conducting a comprehensive investigation across 279 classification tasks and ten LLMs. Our investigation reveals substantial label bias in models both before and after debiasing attempts, as well as highlights the importance of outcomes-based evaluation metrics, which were not previously used in this regard. We further propose a novel label bias calibration method tailored for few-shot prompting, which outperforms recent calibration approaches for both improving performance and mitigating label bias. Our results emphasize that label bias in the predictions of LLMs remains a barrier to their reliability.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02743v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuval Reif, Roy Schwartz</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Contextual Understanding in Large Language Models through Contrastive Decoding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02750</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02750v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) tend to inadequately integrate input context during text generation, relying excessively on encoded prior knowledge in model parameters, potentially resulting in generated text with factual inconsistencies or contextually unfaithful content. LLMs utilize two primary knowledge sources: 1) prior (parametric) knowledge from pretraining, and 2) contextual (non-parametric) knowledge from input prompts. The study addresses the open question of how LLMs effectively balance these knowledge sources during the generation process, specifically in the context of open-domain question answering. To address this issue, we introduce a novel approach integrating contrastive decoding with adversarial irrelevant passages as negative samples to enhance robust context grounding during generation. Notably, our method operates at inference time without requiring further training. We conduct comprehensive experiments to demonstrate its applicability and effectiveness, providing empirical evidence showcasing its superiority over existing methodologies. Our code is publicly available at: https://github.com/amazon-science/ContextualUnderstanding-ContrastiveDecoding.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02750v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zheng Zhao, Emilio Monti, Jens Lehmann, Haytham Assem</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing Adversarial Robustness of Large Language Models: An Empirical Study</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02764</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02764v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have revolutionized natural language processing, but their robustness against adversarial attacks remains a critical concern. We presents a novel white-box style attack approach that exposes vulnerabilities in leading open-source LLMs, including Llama, OPT, and T5. We assess the impact of model size, structure, and fine-tuning strategies on their resistance to adversarial perturbations. Our comprehensive evaluation across five diverse text classification tasks establishes a new benchmark for LLM robustness. The findings of this study have far-reaching implications for the reliable deployment of LLMs in real-world applications and contribute to the advancement of trustworthy AI systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02764v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zeyu Yang, Zhao Meng, Xiaochen Zheng, Roger Wattenhofer</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Detecting Edited Knowledge in Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02765</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02765v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Knowledge editing techniques (KEs) can update language models' obsolete or inaccurate knowledge learned from pre-training. However, KE also faces potential malicious applications, e.g. inserting misinformation and toxic content. Moreover, in the context of responsible AI, it is instructive for end-users to know whether a generated output is driven by edited knowledge or first-hand knowledge from pre-training. To this end, we study detecting edited knowledge in language models by introducing a novel task: given an edited model and a specific piece of knowledge the model generates, our objective is to classify the knowledge as either "non-edited" (based on the pre-training), or ``edited'' (based on subsequent editing). We initiate the task with two state-of-the-art KEs, two language models, and two datasets. We further propose a simple classifier, RepReg, a logistic regression model that takes hidden state representations as input features. Our results reveal that RepReg establishes a strong baseline, achieving a peak accuracy of 99.81%, and 97.79% in out-of-domain settings. Second, RepReg achieves near-optimal performance with a limited training set (200 training samples), and it maintains its performance even in out-of-domain settings. Last, we find it more challenging to separate edited and non-edited knowledge when they contain the same subject or object.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02765v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Paul Youssef, Zhixue Zhao, J\"org Schl\"otterer, Christin Seifert</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NegativePrompt: Leveraging Psychology for Large Language Models Enhancement via Negative Emotional Stimuli</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02814</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02814v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have become integral to a wide spectrum of applications, ranging from traditional computing tasks to advanced artificial intelligence (AI) applications. This widespread adoption has spurred extensive research into LLMs across various disciplines, including the social sciences. Notably, studies have revealed that LLMs possess emotional intelligence, which can be further developed through positive emotional stimuli. This discovery raises an intriguing question: can negative emotions similarly influence LLMs, potentially enhancing their performance? In response to this question, we introduce NegativePrompt, a novel approach underpinned by psychological principles, involving ten specifically designed negative emotional stimuli. We embark on rigorous experimental evaluations of five LLMs including Flan-T5-Large, Vicuna, Llama 2, ChatGPT, and GPT-4, across a set of 45 tasks. The results are revealing: NegativePrompt markedly enhances the performance of LLMs, evidenced by relative improvements of 12.89% in Instruction Induction tasks and 46.25% in BIG-Bench tasks. Moreover, we conduct attention visualization experiments to decipher the underlying mechanisms of NegativePrompt's influence. Our research contributes significantly to the understanding of LLMs and emotion interaction, demonstrating the practical efficacy of NegativePrompt as an emotion-driven method and offering novel insights for the enhancement of LLMs in real-world applications. The code is available at https://github.com/wangxu0820/NegativePrompt.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02814v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xu Wang, Cheng Li, Yi Chang, Jindong Wang, Yuan Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stochastic RAG: End-to-End Retrieval-Augmented Generation through Expected Utility Maximization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02816</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02816v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper introduces Stochastic RAG--a novel approach for end-to-end optimization of retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) models that relaxes the simplifying assumptions of marginalization and document independence, made in most prior work. Stochastic RAG casts the retrieval process in RAG as a stochastic sampling without replacement process. Through this formulation, we employ straight-through Gumbel-top-k that provides a differentiable approximation for sampling without replacement and enables effective end-to-end optimization for RAG. We conduct extensive experiments on seven diverse datasets on a wide range of tasks, from open-domain question answering to fact verification to slot-filling for relation extraction and to dialogue systems. By applying this optimization method to a recent and effective RAG model, we advance state-of-the-art results on six out of seven datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02816v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hamed Zamani, Michael Bendersky</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HuixiangDou-CR: Coreference Resolution in Group Chats</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02817</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02817v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: How to eliminate pronominal reference in group chats? In this work, we have preprocessed 58k authentic chat data and manually annotated 2.3k questions. The reliability of this annotation was confirmed by the scaling law. After this, we conducted fine-tuning on Qwen models, ranging from 0.5B to 32B parameters. The optimal version improved 29.07 in F1 score. This confirms the viability of fine-tuning Large Language Model (LLM) for downstream Natural Language Processing (NLP) tasks. Our contributions are: 1) Created Supervised Fine-Tuning (SFT) training data in alpaca format, along with a set of Low-Rank Adaptation (LoRA) weights, and 2) Developed a method for acquiring high-quality data leveraging scaling law principle. The script, raw data with alpaca format and experiments track are open-sourced on Github https://github.com/InternLM/HuixiangDou/tree/main/web/tools, HuggingFace https://huggingface.co/tpoisonooo and WandB https://wandb.ai/tpoisonooo/huixiangdou-cr/table?nw=nwusertpoisonooo . The privacy of the data involved has been authorized by users.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02817v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Huanjun Kong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting a Pain in the Neck: Semantic Phrase Processing Benchmark for Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02861</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02861v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We introduce LexBench, a comprehensive evaluation suite enabled to test language models (LMs) on ten semantic phrase processing tasks. Unlike prior studies, it is the first work to propose a framework from the comparative perspective to model the general semantic phrase (i.e., lexical collocation) and three fine-grained semantic phrases, including idiomatic expression, noun compound, and verbal construction. Thanks to \ourbenchmark, we assess the performance of 15 LMs across model architectures and parameter scales in classification, extraction, and interpretation tasks. Through the experiments, we first validate the scaling law and find that, as expected, large models excel better than the smaller ones in most tasks. Second, we investigate further through the scaling semantic relation categorization and find that few-shot LMs still lag behind vanilla fine-tuned models in the task. Third, through human evaluation, we find that the performance of strong models is comparable to the human level regarding semantic phrase processing. Our benchmarking findings can serve future research aiming to improve the generic capability of LMs on semantic phrase comprehension. Our source code and data are available at https://github.com/jacklanda/LexBench</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02861v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yang Liu, Melissa Xiaohui Qin, Hongming Li, Chao Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment Analysis Across Languages: Evaluation Before and After Machine Translation to English</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02887</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02887v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: People communicate in more than 7,000 languages around the world, with around 780 languages spoken in India alone. Despite this linguistic diversity, research on Sentiment Analysis has predominantly focused on English text data, resulting in a disproportionate availability of sentiment resources for English. This paper examines the performance of transformer models in Sentiment Analysis tasks across multilingual datasets and text that has undergone machine translation. By comparing the effectiveness of these models in different linguistic contexts, we gain insights into their performance variations and potential implications for sentiment analysis across diverse languages. We also discuss the shortcomings and potential for future work towards the end.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02887v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aekansh Kathunia, Mohammad Kaif, Nalin Arora, N Narotam</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Two-Stage Prediction-Aware Contrastive Learning Framework for Multi-Intent NLU</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02925</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02925v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Multi-intent natural language understanding (NLU) presents a formidable challenge due to the model confusion arising from multiple intents within a single utterance. While previous works train the model contrastively to increase the margin between different multi-intent labels, they are less suited to the nuances of multi-intent NLU. They ignore the rich information between the shared intents, which is beneficial to constructing a better embedding space, especially in low-data scenarios. We introduce a two-stage Prediction-Aware Contrastive Learning (PACL) framework for multi-intent NLU to harness this valuable knowledge. Our approach capitalizes on shared intent information by integrating word-level pre-training and prediction-aware contrastive fine-tuning. We construct a pre-training dataset using a word-level data augmentation strategy. Subsequently, our framework dynamically assigns roles to instances during contrastive fine-tuning while introducing a prediction-aware contrastive loss to maximize the impact of contrastive learning. We present experimental results and empirical analysis conducted on three widely used datasets, demonstrating that our method surpasses the performance of three prominent baselines on both low-data and full-data scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02925v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Guanhua Chen, Yutong Yao, Derek F. Wong, Lidia S. Chao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Relay Decoding: Concatenating Large Language Models for Machine Translation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02933</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02933v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Leveraging large language models for machine translation has demonstrated promising results. However, it does require the large language models to possess the capability of handling both the source and target languages in machine translation. When it is challenging to find large models that support the desired languages, resorting to continuous learning methods becomes a costly endeavor. To mitigate these expenses, we propose an innovative approach called RD (Relay Decoding), which entails concatenating two distinct large models that individually support the source and target languages. By incorporating a simple mapping layer to facilitate the connection between these two models and utilizing a limited amount of parallel data for training, we successfully achieve superior results in the machine translation task. Experimental results conducted on the Multi30k and WikiMatrix datasets validate the effectiveness of our proposed method.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02933v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chengpeng Fu, Xiaocheng Feng, Yichong Huang, Wenshuai Huo, Baohang Li, Hui Wang, Bin Qin, Ting Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enabling Patient-side Disease Prediction via the Integration of Patient Narratives</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02935</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02935v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Disease prediction holds considerable significance in modern healthcare, because of its crucial role in facilitating early intervention and implementing effective prevention measures. However, most recent disease prediction approaches heavily rely on laboratory test outcomes (e.g., blood tests and medical imaging from X-rays). Gaining access to such data for precise disease prediction is often a complex task from the standpoint of a patient and is always only available post-patient consultation. To make disease prediction available from patient-side, we propose Personalized Medical Disease Prediction (PoMP), which predicts diseases using patient health narratives including textual descriptions and demographic information. By applying PoMP, patients can gain a clearer comprehension of their conditions, empowering them to directly seek appropriate medical specialists and thereby reducing the time spent navigating healthcare communication to locate suitable doctors. We conducted extensive experiments using real-world data from Haodf to showcase the effectiveness of PoMP.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02935v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhixiang Su, Yinan Zhang, Jiazheng Jing, Jie Xiao, Zhiqi Shen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Dominance of Large Language Models Over Transformer Models for Bangla Natural Language Inference: A Comprehensive Study</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02937</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02937v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Natural Language Inference (NLI) is a cornerstone of Natural Language Processing (NLP), providing insights into the entailment relationships between text pairings. It is a critical component of Natural Language Understanding (NLU), demonstrating the ability to extract information from spoken or written interactions. NLI is mainly concerned with determining the entailment relationship between two statements, known as the premise and hypothesis. When the premise logically implies the hypothesis, the pair is labeled ``entailment''. If the hypothesis contradicts the premise, the pair receives the ``contradiction'' label. When there is insufficient evidence to establish a connection, the pair is described as ``neutral''. Despite the success of Large Language Models (LLMs) in various tasks, their effectiveness in NLI remains constrained by issues like low-resource domain accuracy, model overconfidence, and difficulty in capturing human judgment disagreements. This study addresses the underexplored area of evaluating LLMs in low-resourced languages such as Bengali. Through a comprehensive evaluation, we assess the performance of prominent LLMs and state-of-the-art (SOTA) models in Bengali NLP tasks, focusing on natural language inference. Utilizing the XNLI dataset, we conduct zero-shot and few-shot evaluations, comparing LLMs like GPT-3.5 Turbo and Gemini 1.5 Pro with models such as BanglaBERT, Bangla BERT Base, DistilBERT, mBERT, and sahajBERT. Our findings reveal that while LLMs can achieve comparable or superior performance to fine-tuned SOTA models in few-shot scenarios, further research is necessary to enhance our understanding of LLMs in languages with modest resources like Bengali. This study underscores the importance of continued efforts in exploring LLM capabilities across diverse linguistic contexts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02937v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fatema Tuj Johora Faria, Mukaffi Bin Moin, Asif Iftekher Fahim, Pronay Debnath, Faisal Muhammad Shah</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>E-TSL: A Continuous Educational Turkish Sign Language Dataset with Baseline Methods</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02984</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02984v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This study introduces the continuous Educational Turkish Sign Language (E-TSL) dataset, collected from online Turkish language lessons for 5th, 6th, and 8th grades. The dataset comprises 1,410 videos totaling nearly 24 hours and includes performances from 11 signers. Turkish, an agglutinative language, poses unique challenges for sign language translation, particularly with a vocabulary where 64% are singleton words and 85% are rare words, appearing less than five times. We developed two baseline models to address these challenges: the Pose to Text Transformer (P2T-T) and the Graph Neural Network based Transformer (GNN-T) models. The GNN-T model achieved 19.13% BLEU-1 score and 3.28% BLEU-4 score, presenting a significant challenge compared to existing benchmarks. The P2T-T model, while demonstrating slightly lower performance in BLEU scores, achieved a higher ROUGE-L score of 22.09%. Additionally, we benchmarked our model using the well-known PHOENIX-Weather 2014T dataset to validate our approach.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02984v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>\c{S}\"ukr\"u \"Ozt\"urk, Hacer Yalim Keles</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Large Language Models Make the Grade? An Empirical Study Evaluating LLMs Ability to Mark Short Answer Questions in K-12 Education</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02985</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02985v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper presents reports on a series of experiments with a novel dataset evaluating how well Large Language Models (LLMs) can mark (i.e. grade) open text responses to short answer questions, Specifically, we explore how well different combinations of GPT version and prompt engineering strategies performed at marking real student answers to short answer across different domain areas (Science and History) and grade-levels (spanning ages 5-16) using a new, never-used-before dataset from Carousel, a quizzing platform. We found that GPT-4, with basic few-shot prompting performed well (Kappa, 0.70) and, importantly, very close to human-level performance (0.75). This research builds on prior findings that GPT-4 could reliably score short answer reading comprehension questions at a performance-level very close to that of expert human raters. The proximity to human-level performance, across a variety of subjects and grade levels suggests that LLMs could be a valuable tool for supporting low-stakes formative assessment tasks in K-12 education and has important implications for real-world education delivery.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02985v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Owen Henkel, Adam Boxer, Libby Hills, Bill Roberts</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MedAdapter: Efficient Test-Time Adaptation of Large Language Models towards Medical Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03000</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.03000v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Despite their improved capabilities in generation and reasoning, adapting large language models (LLMs) to the biomedical domain remains challenging due to their immense size and corporate privacy. In this work, we propose MedAdapter, a unified post-hoc adapter for test-time adaptation of LLMs towards biomedical applications. Instead of fine-tuning the entire LLM, MedAdapter effectively adapts the original model by fine-tuning only a small BERT-sized adapter to rank candidate solutions generated by LLMs. Experiments demonstrate that MedAdapter effectively adapts both white-box and black-box LLMs in biomedical reasoning, achieving average performance improvements of 25.48% and 11.31%, respectively, without requiring extensive computational resources or sharing data with third parties. MedAdapter also yields superior performance when combined with train-time adaptation, highlighting a flexible and complementary solution to existing adaptation methods. Faced with the challenges of balancing model performance, computational resources, and data privacy, MedAdapter provides an efficient, privacy-preserving, cost-effective, and transparent solution for adapting LLMs to the biomedical domain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.03000v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenqi Shi, Ran Xu, Yuchen Zhuang, Yue Yu, Hang Wu, Carl Yang, May D. Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring prompts to elicit memorization in masked language model-based named entity recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03004</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.03004v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Training data memorization in language models impacts model capability (generalization) and safety (privacy risk). This paper focuses on analyzing prompts' impact on detecting the memorization of 6 masked language model-based named entity recognition models. Specifically, we employ a diverse set of 400 automatically generated prompts, and a pairwise dataset where each pair consists of one person's name from the training set and another name out of the set. A prompt completed with a person's name serves as input for getting the model's confidence in predicting this name. Finally, the prompt performance of detecting model memorization is quantified by the percentage of name pairs for which the model has higher confidence for the name from the training set. We show that the performance of different prompts varies by as much as 16 percentage points on the same model, and prompt engineering further increases the gap. Moreover, our experiments demonstrate that prompt performance is model-dependent but does generalize across different name sets. A comprehensive analysis indicates how prompt performance is influenced by prompt properties, contained tokens, and the model's self-attention weights on the prompt.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.03004v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuxi Xia, Anastasiia Sedova, Pedro Henrique Luz de Araujo, Vasiliki Kougia, Lisa Nu{\ss}baumer, Benjamin Roth</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Emotional Trends from X platform using SenticNet: A Comparative Analysis with Cryptocurrency Price</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03084</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.03084v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This study delves into the relationship between emotional trends from X platform data and the market dynamics of well-known cryptocurrencies Cardano, Binance, Fantom, Matic, and Ripple over the period from October 2022 to March 2023. Leveraging SenticNet, we identified emotions like Fear and Anxiety, Rage and Anger, Grief and Sadness, Delight and Pleasantness, Enthusiasm and Eagerness, and Delight and Joy. Following data extraction, we segmented each month into bi-weekly intervals, replicating this process for price data obtained from Finance-Yahoo. Consequently, a comparative analysis was conducted, establishing connections between emotional trends observed across bi-weekly intervals and cryptocurrency prices, uncovering significant correlations between emotional sentiments and coin valuations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.03084v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Moein Shahiki Tash, Zahra Ahani, Olga Kolesnikova, Grigori Sidorov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compressing Long Context for Enhancing RAG with AMR-based Concept Distillation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03085</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.03085v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have made significant strides in information acquisition. However, their overreliance on potentially flawed parametric knowledge leads to hallucinations and inaccuracies, particularly when handling long-tail, domain-specific queries. Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) addresses this limitation by incorporating external, non-parametric knowledge. Nevertheless, the retrieved long-context documents often contain noisy, irrelevant information alongside vital knowledge, negatively diluting LLMs' attention. Inspired by the supportive role of essential concepts in individuals' reading comprehension, we propose a novel concept-based RAG framework with the Abstract Meaning Representation (AMR)-based concept distillation algorithm. The proposed algorithm compresses the cluttered raw retrieved documents into a compact set of crucial concepts distilled from the informative nodes of AMR by referring to reliable linguistic features. The concepts explicitly constrain LLMs to focus solely on vital information in the inference process. We conduct extensive experiments on open-domain question-answering datasets to empirically evaluate the proposed method's effectiveness. The results indicate that the concept-based RAG framework outperforms other baseline methods, particularly as the number of supporting documents increases, while also exhibiting robustness across various backbone LLMs. This emphasizes the distilled concepts are informative for augmenting the RAG process by filtering out interference information. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first work introducing AMR to enhance the RAG, presenting a potential solution to augment inference performance with semantic-based context compression.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.03085v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kaize Shi, Xueyao Sun, Qing Li, Guandong Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FairMonitor: A Dual-framework for Detecting Stereotypes and Biases in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03098</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.03098v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Detecting stereotypes and biases in Large Language Models (LLMs) is crucial for enhancing fairness and reducing adverse impacts on individuals or groups when these models are applied. Traditional methods, which rely on embedding spaces or are based on probability metrics, fall short in revealing the nuanced and implicit biases present in various contexts. To address this challenge, we propose the FairMonitor framework and adopt a static-dynamic detection method for a comprehensive evaluation of stereotypes and biases in LLMs. The static component consists of a direct inquiry test, an implicit association test, and an unknown situation test, including 10,262 open-ended questions with 9 sensitive factors and 26 educational scenarios. And it is effective for evaluating both explicit and implicit biases. Moreover, we utilize the multi-agent system to construst the dynamic scenarios for detecting subtle biases in more complex and realistic setting. This component detects the biases based on the interaction behaviors of LLMs across 600 varied educational scenarios. The experimental results show that the cooperation of static and dynamic methods can detect more stereotypes and biased in LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.03098v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yanhong Bai, Jiabao Zhao, Jinxin Shi, Zhentao Xie, Xingjiao Wu, Liang He</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Active Inference Agent for Simulating Human Translation Processes in a Hierarchical Architecture: Integrating the Task Segment Framework and the HOF taxonomy</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03111</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.03111v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this paper, we propose modelling human translation production as a hierarchy of three embedded translation processes. The proposed architecture replicates the temporal dynamics of keystroke production across sensorimotor, cognitive, and phenomenal layers. Utilizing data from the CRITT TPR-DB, the Task Segment Framework, and the HOF taxonomy, we demonstrate the temporal breakdown of the typing flow on distinct timelines within these three layers.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.03111v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Michael Carl</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lory: Fully Differentiable Mixture-of-Experts for Autoregressive Language Model Pre-training</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03133</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.03133v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Mixture-of-experts (MoE) models facilitate efficient scaling; however, training the router network introduces the challenge of optimizing a non-differentiable, discrete objective. Recently, a fully-differentiable MoE architecture, SMEAR, was proposed (Muqeeth et al., 2023), which softly merges experts in the parameter space; nevertheless, its effectiveness was only demonstrated in downstream fine-tuning on classification tasks. In this paper, we present Lory, the first approach that scales such architectures to autoregressive language model pre-training. Lory introduces two key techniques: (1) a causal segment routing strategy that achieves high efficiency for expert merging operations while preserving the autoregressive nature of language models; (2) a similarity-based data batching method that encourages expert specialization by grouping similar documents in training instances. We pre-train a series of Lory models on 150B tokens from scratch, with up to 32 experts and 30B (1.5B active) parameters. Experimental results show significant performance gains over parameter-matched dense models on both perplexity (+13.9%) and a variety of downstream tasks (+1.5%-11.1%). Despite segment-level routing, Lory models achieve competitive performance compared to state-of-the-art MoE models with token-level routing. We further demonstrate that the trained experts in Lory capture domain-level specialization without supervision. Our work highlights the potential of fully-differentiable MoE architectures for language model pre-training and advocates future research in this area.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.03133v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zexuan Zhong, Mengzhou Xia, Danqi Chen, Mike Lewis</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CRAFT: Extracting and Tuning Cultural Instructions from the Wild</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03138</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.03138v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have rapidly evolved as the foundation of various natural language processing (NLP) applications. Despite their wide use cases, their understanding of culturally-related concepts and reasoning remains limited. Meantime, there is a significant need to enhance these models' cultural reasoning capabilities, especially concerning underrepresented regions. This paper introduces a novel pipeline for extracting high-quality, culturally-related instruction tuning datasets from vast unstructured corpora. We utilize a self-instruction generation pipeline to identify cultural concepts and trigger instruction. By integrating with a general-purpose instruction tuning dataset, our model demonstrates enhanced capabilities in recognizing and understanding regional cultural nuances, thereby enhancing its reasoning capabilities. We conduct experiments across three regions: Singapore, the Philippines, and the United States, achieving performance improvement of up to 6%. Our research opens new avenues for extracting cultural instruction tuning sets directly from unstructured data, setting a precedent for future innovations in the field.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.03138v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bin Wang, Geyu Lin, Zhengyuan Liu, Chengwei Wei, Nancy F. Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Potential of the Large Language Models (LLMs) in Identifying Misleading News Headlines</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03153</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.03153v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In the digital age, the prevalence of misleading news headlines poses a significant challenge to information integrity, necessitating robust detection mechanisms. This study explores the efficacy of Large Language Models (LLMs) in identifying misleading versus non-misleading news headlines. Utilizing a dataset of 60 articles, sourced from both reputable and questionable outlets across health, science &amp; tech, and business domains, we employ three LLMs- ChatGPT-3.5, ChatGPT-4, and Gemini-for classification. Our analysis reveals significant variance in model performance, with ChatGPT-4 demonstrating superior accuracy, especially in cases with unanimous annotator agreement on misleading headlines. The study emphasizes the importance of human-centered evaluation in developing LLMs that can navigate the complexities of misinformation detection, aligning technical proficiency with nuanced human judgment. Our findings contribute to the discourse on AI ethics, emphasizing the need for models that are not only technically advanced but also ethically aligned and sensitive to the subtleties of human interpretation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.03153v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Md Main Uddin Rony, Md Mahfuzul Haque, Mohammad Ali, Ahmed Shatil Alam, Naeemul Hassan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle-Checker Scheme for Evaluating a Generative Large Language Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03170</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.03170v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This work presents a novel approach called oracle-checker scheme for evaluating the answer given by a generative large language model (LLM). Two types of checkers are presented. The first type of checker follows the idea of property testing. The second type of checker follows the idea of program checking. Their applications are demonstrated in two separate contexts, entity extraction and paraphrase decision, respectively.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.03170v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yueling Jenny Zeng, Li-C. Wang, Thomas Ibbetson</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anchored Answers: Unravelling Positional Bias in GPT-2's Multiple-Choice Questions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03205</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.03205v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs), such as the GPT-4 and LLaMA families, have demonstrated considerable success across diverse tasks, including multiple-choice questions (MCQs). However, these models exhibit a positional bias, particularly an even worse anchored bias in the GPT-2 family, where they consistently favour the first choice 'A' in MCQs during inference. This anchored bias challenges the integrity of GPT-2's decision-making process, as it skews performance based on the position rather than the content of the choices in MCQs. In this study, we utilise the mechanistic interpretability approach to identify the internal modules within GPT-2 models responsible for this bias. We focus on the Multi-Layer Perceptron (MLP) layers and attention heads, using the "logit lens" method to trace and modify the specific value vectors that contribute to the bias. By updating these vectors within MLP and recalibrating attention patterns to neutralise the preference for the first choice 'A', we effectively mitigate the anchored bias. Our interventions not only correct the bias but also improve the overall MCQ prediction accuracy for the GPT-2 family across various datasets. This work represents the first comprehensive mechanistic analysis of anchored bias in MCQs within the GPT-2 models, introducing targeted, minimal-intervention strategies that significantly enhance GPT2 model robustness and accuracy in MCQs. Our code is available at https://github.com/ruizheliUOA/Anchored_Bias_GPT2.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.03205v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ruizhe Li, Yanjun Gao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vietnamese AI Generated Text Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03206</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.03206v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In recent years, Large Language Models (LLMs) have become integrated into our daily lives, serving as invaluable assistants in completing tasks. Widely embraced by users, the abuse of LLMs is inevitable, particularly in using them to generate text content for various purposes, leading to difficulties in distinguishing between text generated by LLMs and that written by humans. In this study, we present a dataset named ViDetect, comprising 6.800 samples of Vietnamese essay, with 3.400 samples authored by humans and the remainder generated by LLMs, serving the purpose of detecting text generated by AI. We conducted evaluations using state-of-the-art methods, including ViT5, BartPho, PhoBERT, mDeberta V3, and mBERT. These results contribute not only to the growing body of research on detecting text generated by AI but also demonstrate the adaptability and effectiveness of different methods in the Vietnamese language context. This research lays the foundation for future advancements in AI-generated text detection and provides valuable insights for researchers in the field of natural language processing.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.03206v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Quang-Dan Tran, Van-Quan Nguyen, Quang-Huy Pham, K. B. Thang Nguyen, Trong-Hop Do</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Philosophical Introduction to Language Models - Part II: The Way Forward</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03207</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.03207v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this paper, the second of two companion pieces, we explore novel philosophical questions raised by recent progress in large language models (LLMs) that go beyond the classical debates covered in the first part. We focus particularly on issues related to interpretability, examining evidence from causal intervention methods about the nature of LLMs' internal representations and computations. We also discuss the implications of multimodal and modular extensions of LLMs, recent debates about whether such systems may meet minimal criteria for consciousness, and concerns about secrecy and reproducibility in LLM research. Finally, we discuss whether LLM-like systems may be relevant to modeling aspects of human cognition, if their architectural characteristics and learning scenario are adequately constrained.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.03207v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rapha\"el Milli\`ere, Cameron Buckner</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lifelong Knowledge Editing for LLMs with Retrieval-Augmented Continuous Prompt Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03279</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.03279v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Model editing aims to correct outdated or erroneous knowledge in large language models (LLMs) without the need for costly retraining. Lifelong model editing is the most challenging task that caters to the continuous editing requirements of LLMs. Prior works primarily focus on single or batch editing; nevertheless, these methods fall short in lifelong editing scenarios due to catastrophic knowledge forgetting and the degradation of model performance. Although retrieval-based methods alleviate these issues, they are impeded by slow and cumbersome processes of integrating the retrieved knowledge into the model. In this work, we introduce RECIPE, a RetriEval-augmented ContInuous Prompt lEarning method, to boost editing efficacy and inference efficiency in lifelong learning. RECIPE first converts knowledge statements into short and informative continuous prompts, prefixed to the LLM's input query embedding, to efficiently refine the response grounded on the knowledge. It further integrates the Knowledge Sentinel (KS) that acts as an intermediary to calculate a dynamic threshold, determining whether the retrieval repository contains relevant knowledge. Our retriever and prompt encoder are jointly trained to achieve editing properties, i.e., reliability, generality, and locality. In our experiments, RECIPE is assessed extensively across multiple LLMs and editing datasets, where it achieves superior editing performance. RECIPE also demonstrates its capability to maintain the overall performance of LLMs alongside showcasing fast editing and inference speed.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.03279v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qizhou Chen, Taolin Zhang, Dongyang Li, Longtao Huang, Hui Xue, Chengyu Wang, Xiaofeng He</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MedDoc-Bot: A Chat Tool for Comparative Analysis of Large Language Models in the Context of the Pediatric Hypertension Guideline</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03359</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.03359v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This research focuses on evaluating the non-commercial open-source large language models (LLMs) Meditron, MedAlpaca, Mistral, and Llama-2 for their efficacy in interpreting medical guidelines saved in PDF format. As a specific test scenario, we applied these models to the guidelines for hypertension in children and adolescents provided by the European Society of Cardiology (ESC). Leveraging Streamlit, a Python library, we developed a user-friendly medical document chatbot tool (MedDoc-Bot). This tool enables authorized users to upload PDF files and pose questions, generating interpretive responses from four locally stored LLMs. A pediatric expert provides a benchmark for evaluation by formulating questions and responses extracted from the ESC guidelines. The expert rates the model-generated responses based on their fidelity and relevance. Additionally, we evaluated the METEOR and chrF metric scores to assess the similarity of model responses to reference answers. Our study found that Llama-2 and Mistral performed well in metrics evaluation. However, Llama-2 was slower when dealing with text and tabular data. In our human evaluation, we observed that responses created by Mistral, Meditron, and Llama-2 exhibited reasonable fidelity and relevance. This study provides valuable insights into the strengths and limitations of LLMs for future developments in medical document interpretation. Open-Source Code: https://github.com/yaseen28/MedDoc-Bot</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.03359v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mohamed Yaseen Jabarulla, Steffen Oeltze-Jafra, Philipp Beerbaum, Theodor Uden</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explainable Fake News Detection With Large Language Model via Defense Among Competing Wisdom</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03371</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.03371v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Most fake news detection methods learn latent feature representations based on neural networks, which makes them black boxes to classify a piece of news without giving any justification. Existing explainable systems generate veracity justifications from investigative journalism, which suffer from debunking delayed and low efficiency. Recent studies simply assume that the justification is equivalent to the majority opinions expressed in the wisdom of crowds. However, the opinions typically contain some inaccurate or biased information since the wisdom of crowds is uncensored. To detect fake news from a sea of diverse, crowded and even competing narratives, in this paper, we propose a novel defense-based explainable fake news detection framework. Specifically, we first propose an evidence extraction module to split the wisdom of crowds into two competing parties and respectively detect salient evidences. To gain concise insights from evidences, we then design a prompt-based module that utilizes a large language model to generate justifications by inferring reasons towards two possible veracities. Finally, we propose a defense-based inference module to determine veracity via modeling the defense among these justifications. Extensive experiments conducted on two real-world benchmarks demonstrate that our proposed method outperforms state-of-the-art baselines in terms of fake news detection and provides high-quality justifications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.03371v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bo Wang, Jing Ma, Hongzhan Lin, Zhiwei Yang, Ruichao Yang, Yuan Tian, Yi Chang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The high dimensional psychological profile and cultural bias of ChatGPT</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03387</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.03387v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Given the rapid advancement of large-scale language models, artificial intelligence (AI) models, like ChatGPT, are playing an increasingly prominent role in human society. However, to ensure that artificial intelligence models benefit human society, we must first fully understand the similarities and differences between the human-like characteristics exhibited by artificial intelligence models and real humans, as well as the cultural stereotypes and biases that artificial intelligence models may exhibit in the process of interacting with humans. This study first measured ChatGPT in 84 dimensions of psychological characteristics, revealing differences between ChatGPT and human norms in most dimensions as well as in high-dimensional psychological representations. Additionally, through the measurement of ChatGPT in 13 dimensions of cultural values, it was revealed that ChatGPT's cultural value patterns are dissimilar to those of various countries/regions worldwide. Finally, an analysis of ChatGPT's performance in eight decision-making tasks involving interactions with humans from different countries/regions revealed that ChatGPT exhibits clear cultural stereotypes in most decision-making tasks and shows significant cultural bias in third-party punishment and ultimatum games. The findings indicate that, compared to humans, ChatGPT exhibits a distinct psychological profile and cultural value orientation, and it also shows cultural biases and stereotypes in interpersonal decision-making. Future research endeavors should emphasize enhanced technical oversight and augmented transparency in the database and algorithmic training procedures to foster more efficient cross-cultural communication and mitigate social disparities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.03387v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hang Yuan (Sun Yat-Sen University), Zhongyue Che (Sun Yat-Sen University), Shao Li (Sun Yat-Sen University), Yue Zhang (Renmin University of China), Xiaomeng Hu (Renmin University of China), Siyang Luo (Sun Yat-Sen University)</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaussian Stochastic Weight Averaging for Bayesian Low-Rank Adaptation of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03425</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.03425v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Fine-tuned Large Language Models (LLMs) often suffer from overconfidence and poor calibration, particularly when fine-tuned on small datasets. To address these challenges, we propose a simple combination of Low-Rank Adaptation (LoRA) with Gaussian Stochastic Weight Averaging (SWAG), facilitating approximate Bayesian inference in LLMs. Through extensive testing across several Natural Language Processing (NLP) benchmarks, we demonstrate that our straightforward and computationally efficient approach improves model generalization and calibration. We further show that our method exhibits greater robustness against distribution shift, as reflected in its performance on out-of-distribution tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.03425v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Emre Onal, Klemens Fl\"oge, Emma Caldwell, Arsen Sheverdin, Vincent Fortuin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MAmmoTH2: Scaling Instructions from the Web</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03548</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.03548v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Instruction tuning improves the reasoning abilities of large language models (LLMs), with data quality and scalability being the crucial factors. Most instruction tuning data come from human crowd-sourcing or GPT-4 distillation. We propose a paradigm to efficiently harvest 10 million naturally existing instruction data from the pre-training web corpus to enhance LLM reasoning. Our approach involves (1) recalling relevant documents, (2) extracting instruction-response pairs, and (3) refining the extracted pairs using open-source LLMs. Fine-tuning base LLMs on this dataset, we build MAmmoTH2 models, which significantly boost performance on reasoning benchmarks. Notably, MAmmoTH2-7B's (Mistral) performance increases from 11% to 34% on MATH and from 36% to 67% on GSM8K without training on any in-domain data. Further training MAmmoTH2 on public instruction tuning datasets yields MAmmoTH2-Plus, achieving state-of-the-art performance on several reasoning and chatbot benchmarks. Our work demonstrates how to harvest large-scale, high-quality instruction data without costly human annotation or GPT-4 distillation, providing a new paradigm for building better instruction tuning data.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.03548v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiang Yue, Tuney Zheng, Ge Zhang, Wenhu Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AlphaMath Almost Zero: process Supervision without process</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03553</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.03553v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent advancements in large language models (LLMs) have substantially enhanced their mathematical reasoning abilities. However, these models still struggle with complex problems that require multiple reasoning steps, frequently leading to logical or numerical errors. While numerical mistakes can largely be addressed by integrating a code interpreter, identifying logical errors within intermediate steps is more challenging. Moreover, manually annotating these steps for training is not only expensive but also demands specialized expertise. In this study, we introduce an innovative approach that eliminates the need for manual annotation by leveraging the Monte Carlo Tree Search (MCTS) framework to generate both the process supervision and evaluation signals automatically. Essentially, when a LLM is well pre-trained, only the mathematical questions and their final answers are required to generate our training data, without requiring the solutions. We proceed to train a step-level value model designed to improve the LLM's inference process in mathematical domains. Our experiments indicate that using automatically generated solutions by LLMs enhanced with MCTS significantly improves the model's proficiency in dealing with intricate mathematical reasoning tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.03553v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Guoxin Chen, Minpeng Liao, Chengxi Li, Kai Fan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enabling High-Sparsity Foundational Llama Models with Efficient Pretraining and Deployment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03594</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.03594v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have revolutionized Natural Language Processing (NLP), but their size creates computational bottlenecks. We introduce a novel approach to create accurate, sparse foundational versions of performant LLMs that achieve full accuracy recovery for fine-tuning tasks at up to 70% sparsity. We achieve this for the LLaMA-2 7B model by combining the SparseGPT one-shot pruning method and sparse pretraining of those models on a subset of the SlimPajama dataset mixed with a Python subset of The Stack dataset. We exhibit training acceleration due to sparsity on Cerebras CS-3 chips that closely matches theoretical scaling. In addition, we establish inference acceleration of up to 3x on CPUs by utilizing Neural Magic's DeepSparse engine and 1.7x on GPUs through Neural Magic's nm-vllm engine. The above gains are realized via sparsity alone, thus enabling further gains through additional use of quantization. Specifically, we show a total speedup on CPUs for sparse-quantized LLaMA models of up to 8.6x. We demonstrate these results across diverse, challenging tasks, including chat, instruction following, code generation, arithmetic reasoning, and summarization to prove their generality. This work paves the way for rapidly creating smaller and faster LLMs without sacrificing accuracy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.03594v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Abhinav Agarwalla, Abhay Gupta, Alexandre Marques, Shubhra Pandit, Michael Goin, Eldar Kurtic, Kevin Leong, Tuan Nguyen, Mahmoud Salem, Dan Alistarh, Sean Lie, Mark Kurtz</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GREEN: Generative Radiology Report Evaluation and Error Notation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03595</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.03595v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Evaluating radiology reports is a challenging problem as factual correctness is extremely important due to the need for accurate medical communication about medical images. Existing automatic evaluation metrics either suffer from failing to consider factual correctness (e.g., BLEU and ROUGE) or are limited in their interpretability (e.g., F1CheXpert and F1RadGraph). In this paper, we introduce GREEN (Generative Radiology Report Evaluation and Error Notation), a radiology report generation metric that leverages the natural language understanding of language models to identify and explain clinically significant errors in candidate reports, both quantitatively and qualitatively. Compared to current metrics, GREEN offers: 1) a score aligned with expert preferences, 2) human interpretable explanations of clinically significant errors, enabling feedback loops with end-users, and 3) a lightweight open-source method that reaches the performance of commercial counterparts. We validate our GREEN metric by comparing it to GPT-4, as well as to error counts of 6 experts and preferences of 2 experts. Our method demonstrates not only higher correlation with expert error counts, but simultaneously higher alignment with expert preferences when compared to previous approaches."</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.03595v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sophie Ostmeier, Justin Xu, Zhihong Chen, Maya Varma, Louis Blankemeier, Christian Bluethgen, Arne Edward Michalson, Michael Moseley, Curtis Langlotz, Akshay S Chaudhari, Jean-Benoit Delbrouck</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards A Human-in-the-Loop LLM Approach to Collaborative Discourse Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03677</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.03677v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: LLMs have demonstrated proficiency in contextualizing their outputs using human input, often matching or beating human-level performance on a variety of tasks. However, LLMs have not yet been used to characterize synergistic learning in students' collaborative discourse. In this exploratory work, we take a first step towards adopting a human-in-the-loop prompt engineering approach with GPT-4-Turbo to summarize and categorize students' synergistic learning during collaborative discourse. Our preliminary findings suggest GPT-4-Turbo may be able to characterize students' synergistic learning in a manner comparable to humans and that our approach warrants further investigation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.03677v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Clayton Cohn, Caitlin Snyder, Justin Montenegro, Gautam Biswas</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Language Models Reveal Information Operation Goals, Tactics, and Narrative Frames</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03688</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.03688v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Adversarial information operations can destabilize societies by undermining fair elections, manipulating public opinions on policies, and promoting scams. Despite their widespread occurrence and potential impacts, our understanding of influence campaigns is limited by manual analysis of messages and subjective interpretation of their observable behavior. In this paper, we explore whether these limitations can be mitigated with large language models (LLMs), using GPT-3.5 as a case-study for coordinated campaign annotation. We first use GPT-3.5 to scrutinize 126 identified information operations spanning over a decade. We utilize a number of metrics to quantify the close (if imperfect) agreement between LLM and ground truth descriptions. We next extract coordinated campaigns from two large multilingual datasets from X (formerly Twitter) that respectively discuss the 2022 French election and 2023 Balikaran Philippine-U.S. military exercise in 2023. For each coordinated campaign, we use GPT-3.5 to analyze posts related to a specific concern and extract goals, tactics, and narrative frames, both before and after critical events (such as the date of an election). While the GPT-3.5 sometimes disagrees with subjective interpretation, its ability to summarize and interpret demonstrates LLMs' potential to extract higher-order indicators from text to provide a more complete picture of the information campaigns compared to previous methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.03688v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Keith Burghardt, Kai Chen, Kristina Lerman</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inserting Faces inside Captions: Image Captioning with Attention Guided Merging</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02305</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02305v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Image captioning models are widely used to describe recent and archived pictures with the objective of improving their accessibility and retrieval. Yet, these approaches tend to be inefficient and biased at retrieving people's names. In this work we introduce AstroCaptions, a dataset for the image captioning task. This dataset specifically contains thousands of public fig-ures that are complex to identify for a traditional model. We also propose a novel post-processing method to insert identified people's names inside the caption using explainable AI tools and the grounding capabilities of vi-sion-language models. The results obtained with this method show signifi-cant improvements of captions quality and a potential of reducing halluci-nations. Up to 93.2% of the persons detected can be inserted in the image captions leading to improvements in the BLEU, ROUGE, CIDEr and METEOR scores of each captioning model.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02305v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yannis Tevissen (ARMEDIA-SAMOVAR, ML), Khalil Guetari, Marine Tassel, Erwan Kerleroux, Fr\'ed\'eric Petitpont</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A geometric framework for interstellar discourse on fundamental physical structures</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02314</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02314v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This paper considers the possibility that abstract thinking and advanced synthesis skills might encourage extraterrestrial civilizations to accept communication with mankind on Earth. For this purpose, a notation not relying upon the use of alphabet and numbers is proposed, in order to denote just some basic geometric structures of current physical theories: vector fields, one-form fields, and tensor fields of arbitrary order. An advanced civilization might appreciate the way here proposed to achieve a concise description of electromagnetism and general relativity, and hence it might accept the challenge of responding to our signals. The abstract symbols introduced in this paper to describe the basic structures of physical theories are encoded into black and white bitmap images that can be easily converted into short bit sequences and modulated on a carrier wave for radio transmission.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02314v1</guid>
      <category>cs.IT</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>math.IT</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Giampiero Esposito, Valeria Fionda</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating LLMs for Hardware Design and Test</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02326</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02326v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated capabilities for producing code in Hardware Description Languages (HDLs). However, most of the focus remains on their abilities to write functional code, not test code. The hardware design process consists of both design and test, and so eschewing validation and verification leaves considerable potential benefit unexplored, given that a design and test framework may allow for progress towards full automation of the digital design pipeline. In this work, we perform one of the first studies exploring how a LLM can both design and test hardware modules from provided specifications. Using a suite of 8 representative benchmarks, we examined the capabilities and limitations of the state-of-the-art conversational LLMs when producing Verilog for functional and verification purposes. We taped out the benchmarks on a Skywater 130nm shuttle and received the functional chip.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02326v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.PL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jason Blocklove, Siddharth Garg, Ramesh Karri, Hammond Pearce</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital ASIC Design with Ongoing LLMs: Strategies and Prospects</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02329</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02329v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The escalating complexity of modern digital systems has imposed significant challenges on integrated circuit (IC) design, necessitating tools that can simplify the IC design flow. The advent of Large Language Models (LLMs) has been seen as a promising development, with the potential to automate the generation of Hardware Description Language (HDL) code, thereby streamlining digital IC design. However, the practical application of LLMs in this area faces substantial hurdles. Notably, current LLMs often generate HDL code with small but critical syntax errors and struggle to accurately convey the high-level semantics of circuit designs. These issues significantly undermine the utility of LLMs for IC design, leading to misinterpretations and inefficiencies.
  In response to these challenges, this paper presents targeted strategies to harness the capabilities of LLMs for digital ASIC design. We outline approaches that improve the reliability and accuracy of HDL code generation by LLMs. As a practical demonstration of these strategies, we detail the development of a simple three-phase Pulse Width Modulation (PWM) generator. This project, part of the "Efabless AI-Generated Open-Source Chip Design Challenge," successfully passed the Design Rule Check (DRC) and was fabricated, showcasing the potential of LLMs to enhance digital ASIC design. This work underscores the feasibility and benefits of integrating LLMs into the IC design process, offering a novel approach to overcoming the complexities of modern digital systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02329v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Maoyang Xiang, Emil Goh, T. Hui Teo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speech Technology Services for Oral History Research</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02333</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02333v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Oral history is about oral sources of witnesses and commentors on historical events. Speech technology is an important instrument to process such recordings in order to obtain transcription and further enhancements to structure the oral account In this contribution we address the transcription portal and the webservices associated with speech processing at BAS, speech solutions developed at LINDAT, how to do it yourself with Whisper, remaining challenges, and future developments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02333v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Christoph Draxler, Henk van den Heuvel, Arjan van Hessen, Pavel Ircing, Jan Lehe\v{c}ka</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COPAL: Continual Pruning in Large Language Generative Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02347</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02347v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Adapting pre-trained large language models to different domains in natural language processing requires two key considerations: high computational demands and model's inability to continual adaptation. To simultaneously address both issues, this paper presents COPAL (COntinual Pruning in Adaptive Language settings), an algorithm developed for pruning large language generative models under a continual model adaptation setting. While avoiding resource-heavy finetuning or retraining, our pruning process is guided by the proposed sensitivity analysis. The sensitivity effectively measures model's ability to withstand perturbations introduced by the new dataset and finds model's weights that are relevant for all encountered datasets. As a result, COPAL allows seamless model adaptation to new domains while enhancing the resource efficiency. Our empirical evaluation on a various size of LLMs show that COPAL outperforms baseline models, demonstrating its efficacy in efficiency and adaptability.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02347v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Srikanth Malla, Joon Hee Choi, Chiho Choi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM as Dataset Analyst: Subpopulation Structure Discovery with Large Language Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02363</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02363v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The distribution of subpopulations is an important property hidden within a dataset. Uncovering and analyzing the subpopulation distribution within datasets provides a comprehensive understanding of the datasets, standing as a powerful tool beneficial to various downstream tasks, including Dataset Subpopulation Organization, Subpopulation Shift, and Slice Discovery. Despite its importance, there has been no work that systematically explores the subpopulation distribution of datasets to our knowledge. To address the limitation and solve all the mentioned tasks in a unified way, we introduce a novel concept of subpopulation structures to represent, analyze, and utilize subpopulation distributions within datasets. To characterize the structures in an interpretable manner, we propose the Subpopulation Structure Discovery with Large Language Models (SSD-LLM) framework, which employs world knowledge and instruction-following capabilities of Large Language Models (LLMs) to linguistically analyze informative image captions and summarize the structures. Furthermore, we propose complete workflows to address downstream tasks, named Task-specific Tuning, showcasing the application of the discovered structure to a spectrum of subpopulation-related tasks, including dataset subpopulation organization, subpopulation shift, and slice discovery. Furthermore, we propose complete workflows to address downstream tasks, named Task-specific Tuning, showcasing the application of the discovered structure to a spectrum of subpopulation-related tasks, including dataset subpopulation organization, subpopulation shift, and slice discovery.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02363v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yulin Luo, Ruichuan An, Bocheng Zou, Yiming Tang, Jiaming Liu, Shanghang Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CALRec: Contrastive Alignment of Generative LLMs For Sequential Recommendation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02429</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02429v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Traditional recommender systems such as matrix factorization methods rely on learning a shared dense embedding space to represent both items and user preferences. Sequence models such as RNN, GRUs, and, recently, Transformers have also excelled in the task of sequential recommendation. This task requires understanding the sequential structure present in users' historical interactions to predict the next item they may like. Building upon the success of Large Language Models (LLMs) in a variety of tasks, researchers have recently explored using LLMs that are pretrained on vast corpora of text for sequential recommendation. To use LLMs in sequential recommendations, both the history of user interactions and the model's prediction of the next item are expressed in text form. We propose CALRec, a two-stage LLM finetuning framework that finetunes a pretrained LLM in a two-tower fashion using a mixture of two contrastive losses and a language modeling loss: the LLM is first finetuned on a data mixture from multiple domains followed by another round of target domain finetuning. Our model significantly outperforms many state-of-the-art baselines (+37% in Recall@1 and +24% in NDCG@10) and systematic ablation studies reveal that (i) both stages of finetuning are crucial, and, when combined, we achieve improved performance, and (ii) contrastive alignment is effective among the target domains explored in our experiments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02429v1</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yaoyiran Li, Xiang Zhai, Moustafa Alzantot, Keyi Yu, Ivan Vuli\'c, Anna Korhonen, Mohamed Hammad</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Random Masking Finds Winning Tickets for Parameter Efficient Fine-tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02596</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02596v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Fine-tuning large language models (LLM) can be costly. Parameter-efficient fine-tuning (PEFT) addresses the problems by training a fraction of the parameters, whose success reveals the expressiveness and flexibility of pretrained models. This paper studies the limit of PEFT, by further simplifying its design and reducing the number of trainable parameters beyond standard setups. To this end, we use Random Masking to fine-tune the pretrained model. Despite its simplicity, we show that Random Masking is surprisingly effective: with a larger-than-expected learning rate, Random Masking can match the performance of standard PEFT algorithms such as LoRA on various tasks, using fewer trainable parameters. We provide both empirical and theoretical explorations into the success of Random Masking. We show that masking induces a flatter loss landscape and more distant solutions, which allows for and necessitates large learning rates.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02596v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jing Xu, Jingzhao Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TREC iKAT 2023: A Test Collection for Evaluating Conversational and Interactive Knowledge Assistants</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02637</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02637v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Conversational information seeking has evolved rapidly in the last few years with the development of Large Language Models (LLMs), providing the basis for interpreting and responding in a naturalistic manner to user requests. The extended TREC Interactive Knowledge Assistance Track (iKAT) collection aims to enable researchers to test and evaluate their Conversational Search Agents (CSA). The collection contains a set of 36 personalized dialogues over 20 different topics each coupled with a Personal Text Knowledge Base (PTKB) that defines the bespoke user personas. A total of 344 turns with approximately 26,000 passages are provided as assessments on relevance, as well as additional assessments on generated responses over four key dimensions: relevance, completeness, groundedness, and naturalness. The collection challenges CSA to efficiently navigate diverse personal contexts, elicit pertinent persona information, and employ context for relevant conversations. The integration of a PTKB and the emphasis on decisional search tasks contribute to the uniqueness of this test collection, making it an essential benchmark for advancing research in conversational and interactive knowledge assistants.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02637v1</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3626772.3657860</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Mohammad Aliannejadi, Zahra Abbasiantaeb, Shubham Chatterjee, Jeffery Dalton, Leif Azzopardi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Relevance: Evaluate and Improve Retrievers on Perspective Awareness</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02714</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02714v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The task of Information Retrieval (IR) requires a system to identify relevant documents based on users' information needs. In real-world scenarios, retrievers are expected to not only rely on the semantic relevance between the documents and the queries but also recognize the nuanced intents or perspectives behind a user query. For example, when asked to verify a claim, a retrieval system is expected to identify evidence from both supporting vs. contradicting perspectives, for the downstream system to make a fair judgment call. In this work, we study whether retrievers can recognize and respond to different perspectives of the queries -- beyond finding relevant documents for a claim, can retrievers distinguish supporting vs. opposing documents? We reform and extend six existing tasks to create a benchmark for retrieval, where we have diverse perspectives described in free-form text, besides root, neutral queries. We show that current retrievers covered in our experiments have limited awareness of subtly different perspectives in queries and can also be biased toward certain perspectives. Motivated by the observation, we further explore the potential to leverage geometric features of retriever representation space to improve the perspective awareness of retrievers in a zero-shot manner. We demonstrate the efficiency and effectiveness of our projection-based methods on the same set of tasks. Further analysis also shows how perspective awareness improves performance on various downstream tasks, with 4.2% higher accuracy on AmbigQA and 29.9% more correlation with designated viewpoints on essay writing, compared to non-perspective-aware baselines.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02714v1</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xinran Zhao, Tong Chen, Sihao Chen, Hongming Zhang, Tongshuang Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Get more for less: Principled Data Selection for Warming Up Fine-Tuning in LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02774</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02774v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This work focuses on leveraging and selecting from vast, unlabeled, open data to pre-fine-tune a pre-trained language model. The goal is to minimize the need for costly domain-specific data for subsequent fine-tuning while achieving desired performance levels. While many data selection algorithms have been designed for small-scale applications, rendering them unsuitable for our context, some emerging methods do cater to language data scales. However, they often prioritize data that aligns with the target distribution. While this strategy may be effective when training a model from scratch, it can yield limited results when the model has already been pre-trained on a different distribution. Differing from prior work, our key idea is to select data that nudges the pre-training distribution closer to the target distribution. We show the optimality of this approach for fine-tuning tasks under certain conditions. We demonstrate the efficacy of our methodology across a diverse array of tasks (NLU, NLG, zero-shot) with models up to 2.7B, showing that it consistently surpasses other selection methods. Moreover, our proposed method is significantly faster than existing techniques, scaling to millions of samples within a single GPU hour. Our code is open-sourced (Code repository: https://anonymous.4open.science/r/DV4LLM-D761/ ). While fine-tuning offers significant potential for enhancing performance across diverse tasks, its associated costs often limit its widespread adoption; with this work, we hope to lay the groundwork for cost-effective fine-tuning, making its benefits more accessible.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02774v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Feiyang Kang, Hoang Anh Just, Yifan Sun, Himanshu Jahagirdar, Yuanzhi Zhang, Rongxing Du, Anit Kumar Sahu, Ruoxi Jia</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ImageInWords: Unlocking Hyper-Detailed Image Descriptions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02793</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02793v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Despite the longstanding adage "an image is worth a thousand words," creating accurate and hyper-detailed image descriptions for training Vision-Language models remains challenging. Current datasets typically have web-scraped descriptions that are short, low-granularity, and often contain details unrelated to the visual content. As a result, models trained on such data generate descriptions replete with missing information, visual inconsistencies, and hallucinations. To address these issues, we introduce ImageInWords (IIW), a carefully designed human-in-the-loop annotation framework for curating hyper-detailed image descriptions and a new dataset resulting from this process. We validate the framework through evaluations focused on the quality of the dataset and its utility for fine-tuning with considerations for readability, comprehensiveness, specificity, hallucinations, and human-likeness. Our dataset significantly improves across these dimensions compared to recently released datasets (+66%) and GPT-4V outputs (+48%). Furthermore, models fine-tuned with IIW data excel by +31% against prior work along the same human evaluation dimensions. Given our fine-tuned models, we also evaluate text-to-image generation and vision-language reasoning. Our model's descriptions can generate images closest to the original, as judged by both automated and human metrics. We also find our model produces more compositionally rich descriptions, outperforming the best baseline by up to 6% on ARO, SVO-Probes, and Winoground datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02793v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Roopal Garg, Andrea Burns, Burcu Karagol Ayan, Yonatan Bitton, Ceslee Montgomery, Yasumasa Onoe, Andrew Bunner, Ranjay Krishna, Jason Baldridge, Radu Soricut</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Language Evolution for Evading Social Media Regulation via LLM-based Multi-agent Simulation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02858</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02858v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Social media platforms such as Twitter, Reddit, and Sina Weibo play a crucial role in global communication but often encounter strict regulations in geopolitically sensitive regions. This situation has prompted users to ingeniously modify their way of communicating, frequently resorting to coded language in these regulated social media environments. This shift in communication is not merely a strategy to counteract regulation, but a vivid manifestation of language evolution, demonstrating how language naturally evolves under societal and technological pressures. Studying the evolution of language in regulated social media contexts is of significant importance for ensuring freedom of speech, optimizing content moderation, and advancing linguistic research. This paper proposes a multi-agent simulation framework using Large Language Models (LLMs) to explore the evolution of user language in regulated social media environments. The framework employs LLM-driven agents: supervisory agent who enforce dialogue supervision and participant agents who evolve their language strategies while engaging in conversation, simulating the evolution of communication styles under strict regulations aimed at evading social media regulation. The study evaluates the framework's effectiveness through a range of scenarios from abstract scenarios to real-world situations. Key findings indicate that LLMs are capable of simulating nuanced language dynamics and interactions in constrained settings, showing improvement in both evading supervision and information accuracy as evolution progresses. Furthermore, it was found that LLM agents adopt different strategies for different scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02858v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jinyu Cai, Jialong Li, Mingyue Zhang, Munan Li, Chen-Shu Wang, Kenji Tei</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overconfidence is Key: Verbalized Uncertainty Evaluation in Large Language and Vision-Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02917</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02917v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Language and Vision-Language Models (LLMs/VLMs) have revolutionized the field of AI by their ability to generate human-like text and understand images, but ensuring their reliability is crucial. This paper aims to evaluate the ability of LLMs (GPT4, GPT-3.5, LLaMA2, and PaLM 2) and VLMs (GPT4V and Gemini Pro Vision) to estimate their verbalized uncertainty via prompting. We propose the new Japanese Uncertain Scenes (JUS) dataset, aimed at testing VLM capabilities via difficult queries and object counting, and the Net Calibration Error (NCE) to measure direction of miscalibration. Results show that both LLMs and VLMs have a high calibration error and are overconfident most of the time, indicating a poor capability for uncertainty estimation. Additionally we develop prompts for regression tasks, and we show that VLMs have poor calibration when producing mean/standard deviation and 95% confidence intervals.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02917v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tobias Groot, Matias Valdenegro-Toro</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parameter-Efficient Fine-Tuning with Discrete Fourier Transform</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03003</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.03003v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Low-rank adaptation~(LoRA) has recently gained much interest in fine-tuning foundation models. It effectively reduces the number of trainable parameters by incorporating low-rank matrices $A$ and $B$ to represent the weight change, i.e., $\Delta W=BA$. Despite LoRA's progress, it faces storage challenges when handling extensive customization adaptations or larger base models. In this work, we aim to further compress trainable parameters by enjoying the powerful expressiveness of the Fourier transform. Specifically, we introduce FourierFT, which treats $\Delta W$ as a matrix in the spatial domain and learns only a small fraction of its spectral coefficients. With the trained spectral coefficients, we implement the inverse discrete Fourier transform to recover $\Delta W$. Empirically, our FourierFT method shows comparable or better performance with fewer parameters than LoRA on various tasks, including natural language understanding, natural language generation, instruction tuning, and image classification. For example, when performing instruction tuning on the LLaMA2-7B model, FourierFT surpasses LoRA with only 0.064M trainable parameters, compared to LoRA's 33.5M. Our code is released at \url{https://github.com/Chaos96/fourierft}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.03003v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ziqi Gao, Qichao Wang, Aochuan Chen, Zijing Liu, Bingzhe Wu, Liang Chen, Jia Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the performativity of SDG classifications in large bibliometric databases</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03007</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.03007v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large bibliometric databases, such as Web of Science, Scopus, and OpenAlex, facilitate bibliometric analyses, but are performative, affecting the visibility of scientific outputs and the impact measurement of participating entities. Recently, these databases have taken up the UN's Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) in their respective classifications, which have been criticised for their diverging nature. This work proposes using the feature of large language models (LLMs) to learn about the "data bias" injected by diverse SDG classifications into bibliometric data by exploring five SDGs. We build a LLM that is fine-tuned in parallel by the diverse SDG classifications inscribed into the databases' SDG classifications. Our results show high sensitivity in model architecture, classified publications, fine-tuning process, and natural language generation. The wide arbitrariness at different levels raises concerns about using LLM in research practice.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.03007v1</guid>
      <category>cs.DL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Matteo Ottaviani, Stephan Stahlschmidt</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Each (Textual Sequence) Its Own: Improving Memorized-Data Unlearning in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03097</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.03097v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: LLMs have been found to memorize training textual sequences and regurgitate verbatim said sequences during text generation time. This fact is known to be the cause of privacy and related (e.g., copyright) problems. Unlearning in LLMs then takes the form of devising new algorithms that will properly deal with these side-effects of memorized data, while not hurting the model's utility. We offer a fresh perspective towards this goal, namely, that each textual sequence to be forgotten should be treated differently when being unlearned based on its degree of memorization within the LLM. We contribute a new metric for measuring unlearning quality, an adversarial attack showing that SOTA algorithms lacking this perspective fail for privacy, and two new unlearning methods based on Gradient Ascent and Task Arithmetic, respectively. A comprehensive performance evaluation across an extensive suite of NLP tasks then mapped the solution space, identifying the best solutions under different scales in model capacities and forget set sizes and quantified the gains of the new approaches.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.03097v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>George-Octavian Barbulescu, Peter Triantafillou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying the Capabilities of LLMs across Scale and Precision</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03146</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.03146v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Scale is often attributed as one of the factors that cause an increase in the performance of LLMs, resulting in models with billion and trillion parameters. One of the limitations of such large models is the high computational requirements that limit their usage, deployment, and debugging in resource-constrained scenarios. Two commonly used alternatives to bypass these limitations are to use the smaller versions of LLMs (e.g. Llama 7B instead of Llama 70B) and lower the memory requirements by using quantization. While these approaches effectively address the limitation of resources, their impact on model performance needs thorough examination. In this study, we perform a comprehensive evaluation to investigate the effect of model scale and quantization on the performance. We experiment with two major families of open-source instruct models ranging from 7 billion to 70 billion parameters. Our extensive zero-shot experiments across various tasks including natural language understanding, reasoning, misinformation detection, and hallucination reveal that larger models generally outperform their smaller counterparts, suggesting that scale remains an important factor in enhancing performance. We found that larger models show exceptional resilience to precision reduction and can maintain high accuracy even at 4-bit quantization for numerous tasks and they serve as a better solution than using smaller models at high precision under similar memory requirements.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.03146v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sher Badshah, Hassan Sajjad</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing Multimodal Medical Capabilities of Gemini</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03162</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.03162v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Many clinical tasks require an understanding of specialized data, such as medical images and genomics, which is not typically found in general-purpose large multimodal models. Building upon Gemini's multimodal models, we develop several models within the new Med-Gemini family that inherit core capabilities of Gemini and are optimized for medical use via fine-tuning with 2D and 3D radiology, histopathology, ophthalmology, dermatology and genomic data. Med-Gemini-2D sets a new standard for AI-based chest X-ray (CXR) report generation based on expert evaluation, exceeding previous best results across two separate datasets by an absolute margin of 1% and 12%, where 57% and 96% of AI reports on normal cases, and 43% and 65% on abnormal cases, are evaluated as "equivalent or better" than the original radiologists' reports. We demonstrate the first ever large multimodal model-based report generation for 3D computed tomography (CT) volumes using Med-Gemini-3D, with 53% of AI reports considered clinically acceptable, although additional research is needed to meet expert radiologist reporting quality. Beyond report generation, Med-Gemini-2D surpasses the previous best performance in CXR visual question answering (VQA) and performs well in CXR classification and radiology VQA, exceeding SoTA or baselines on 17 of 20 tasks. In histopathology, ophthalmology, and dermatology image classification, Med-Gemini-2D surpasses baselines across 18 out of 20 tasks and approaches task-specific model performance. Beyond imaging, Med-Gemini-Polygenic outperforms the standard linear polygenic risk score-based approach for disease risk prediction and generalizes to genetically correlated diseases for which it has never been trained. Although further development and evaluation are necessary in the safety-critical medical domain, our results highlight the potential of Med-Gemini across a wide range of medical tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.03162v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lin Yang, Shawn Xu, Andrew Sellergren, Timo Kohlberger, Yuchen Zhou, Ira Ktena, Atilla Kiraly, Faruk Ahmed, Farhad Hormozdiari, Tiam Jaroensri, Eric Wang, Ellery Wulczyn, Fayaz Jamil, Theo Guidroz, Chuck Lau, Siyuan Qiao, Yun Liu, Akshay Goel, Kendall Park, Arnav Agharwal, Nick George, Yang Wang, Ryutaro Tanno, David G. T. Barrett, Wei-Hung Weng, S. Sara Mahdavi, Khaled Saab, Tao Tu, Sreenivasa Raju Kalidindi, Mozziyar Etemadi, Jorge Cuadros, Gregory Sorensen, Yossi Matias, Katherine Chou, Greg Corrado, Joelle Barral, Shravya Shetty, David Fleet, S. M. Ali Eslami, Daniel Tse, Shruthi Prabhakara, Cory McLean, Dave Steiner, Rory Pilgrim, Christopher Kelly, Shekoofeh Azizi, Daniel Golden</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Language Models (LLMs) as Agents for Augmented Democracy</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03452</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.03452v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We explore the capabilities of an augmented democracy system built on off-the-shelf LLMs fine-tuned on data summarizing individual preferences across 67 policy proposals collected during the 2022 Brazilian presidential elections. We use a train-test cross-validation setup to estimate the accuracy with which the LLMs predict both: a subject's individual political choices and the aggregate preferences of the full sample of participants. At the individual level, the accuracy of the out of sample predictions lie in the range 69%-76% and are significantly better at predicting the preferences of liberal and college educated participants. At the population level, we aggregate preferences using an adaptation of the Borda score and compare the ranking of policy proposals obtained from a probabilistic sample of participants and from data augmented using LLMs. We find that the augmented data predicts the preferences of the full population of participants better than probabilistic samples alone when these represent less than 30% to 40% of the total population. These results indicate that LLMs are potentially useful for the construction of systems of augmented democracy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.03452v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jairo Gudi\~no-Rosero, Umberto Grandi, C\'esar A. Hidalgo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Language-Image Models with 3D Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03685</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.03685v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Multi-modal large language models (MLLMs) have shown incredible capabilities in a variety of 2D vision and language tasks. We extend MLLMs' perceptual capabilities to ground and reason about images in 3-dimensional space. To that end, we first develop a large-scale pre-training dataset for 2D and 3D called LV3D by combining multiple existing 2D and 3D recognition datasets under a common task formulation: as multi-turn question-answering. Next, we introduce a new MLLM named Cube-LLM and pre-train it on LV3D. We show that pure data scaling makes a strong 3D perception capability without 3D specific architectural design or training objective. Cube-LLM exhibits intriguing properties similar to LLMs: (1) Cube-LLM can apply chain-of-thought prompting to improve 3D understanding from 2D context information. (2) Cube-LLM can follow complex and diverse instructions and adapt to versatile input and output formats. (3) Cube-LLM can be visually prompted such as 2D box or a set of candidate 3D boxes from specialists. Our experiments on outdoor benchmarks demonstrate that Cube-LLM significantly outperforms existing baselines by 21.3 points of AP-BEV on the Talk2Car dataset for 3D grounded reasoning and 17.7 points on the DriveLM dataset for complex reasoning about driving scenarios, respectively. Cube-LLM also shows competitive results in general MLLM benchmarks such as refCOCO for 2D grounding with (87.0) average score, as well as visual question answering benchmarks such as VQAv2, GQA, SQA, POPE, etc. for complex reasoning. Our project is available at https://janghyuncho.github.io/Cube-LLM.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.03685v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jang Hyun Cho, Boris Ivanovic, Yulong Cao, Edward Schmerling, Yue Wang, Xinshuo Weng, Boyi Li, Yurong You, Philipp Kr\"ahenb\"uhl, Yan Wang, Marco Pavone</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pose Priors from Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03689</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.03689v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We present a zero-shot pose optimization method that enforces accurate physical contact constraints when estimating the 3D pose of humans. Our central insight is that since language is often used to describe physical interaction, large pretrained text-based models can act as priors on pose estimation.
  We can thus leverage this insight to improve pose estimation by converting natural language descriptors, generated by a large multimodal model (LMM), into tractable losses to constrain the 3D pose optimization. Despite its simplicity, our method produces surprisingly compelling pose reconstructions of people in close contact, correctly capturing the semantics of the social and physical interactions. We demonstrate that our method rivals more complex state-of-the-art approaches that require expensive human annotation of contact points and training specialized models. Moreover, unlike previous approaches, our method provides a unified framework for resolving self-contact and person-to-person contact.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.03689v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sanjay Subramanian, Evonne Ng, Lea M\"uller, Dan Klein, Shiry Ginosar, Trevor Darrell</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Unified Review of Deep Learning for Automated Medical Coding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2201.02797</link>
      <description>arXiv:2201.02797v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Automated medical coding, an essential task for healthcare operation and delivery, makes unstructured data manageable by predicting medical codes from clinical documents. Recent advances in deep learning and natural language processing have been widely applied to this task. However, deep learning-based medical coding lacks a unified view of the design of neural network architectures. This review proposes a unified framework to provide a general understanding of the building blocks of medical coding models and summarizes recent advanced models under the proposed framework. Our unified framework decomposes medical coding into four main components, i.e., encoder modules for text feature extraction, mechanisms for building deep encoder architectures, decoder modules for transforming hidden representations into medical codes, and the usage of auxiliary information. Finally, we introduce the benchmarks and real-world usage and discuss key research challenges and future directions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2201.02797v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shaoxiong Ji, Wei Sun, Xiaobo Li, Hang Dong, Ara Taalas, Yijia Zhang, Honghan Wu, Esa Pitk\"anen, Pekka Marttinen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AraSpot: Arabic Spoken Command Spotting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2303.16621</link>
      <description>arXiv:2303.16621v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Spoken keyword spotting (KWS) is the task of identifying a keyword in an audio stream and is widely used in smart devices at the edge in order to activate voice assistants and perform hands-free tasks. The task is daunting as there is a need, on the one hand, to achieve high accuracy while at the same time ensuring that such systems continue to run efficiently on low power and possibly limited computational capabilities devices. This work presents AraSpot for Arabic keyword spotting trained on 40 Arabic keywords, using different online data augmentation, and introducing ConformerGRU model architecture. Finally, we further improve the performance of the model by training a text-to-speech model for synthetic data generation. AraSpot achieved a State-of-the-Art SOTA 99.59% result outperforming previous approaches.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2303.16621v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mahmoud Salhab, Haidar Harmanani</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stance Detection: A Practical Guide to Classifying Political Beliefs in Text</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2305.01723</link>
      <description>arXiv:2305.01723v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Stance detection is identifying expressed beliefs in a document. While researchers widely use sentiment analysis for this, recent research demonstrates that sentiment and stance are distinct. This paper advances text analysis methods by precisely defining stance detection and presenting three distinct approaches: supervised classification, natural language inference, and in-context learning with generative language models. I discuss how document context and trade-offs between resources and workload should inform your methods. For all three approaches I provide guidance on application and validation techniques, as well as coding tutorials for implementation. Finally, I demonstrate how newer classification approaches can replicate supervised classifiers.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2305.01723v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Michael Burnham</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Make Prompt-based Black-Box Tuning Colorful: Boosting Model Generalization from Three Orthogonal Perspectives</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2305.08088</link>
      <description>arXiv:2305.08088v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have shown increasing power on various natural language processing (NLP) tasks. However, tuning these models for downstream tasks usually needs exorbitant costs or is unavailable due to commercial considerations. Recently, black-box tuning has been proposed to address this problem by optimizing task-specific prompts without accessing the gradients and hidden representations. However, most existing works have yet fully exploited the potential of gradient-free optimization under the scenario of few-shot learning. In this paper, we describe BBT-RGB, a suite of straightforward and complementary techniques for enhancing the efficiency and performance of black-box optimization. Specifically, our method includes three plug-and-play components: (1) Two-stage derivative-free optimization strategy that facilitates fast convergence and mitigates overfitting; (2) Automatic verbalizer construction with its novel usage under few-shot settings; (3) Better prompt initialization policy based on instruction search and auto-selected demonstration. Extensive experiments across various tasks on natural language understanding and inference demonstrate the effectiveness of our method. Our codes are publicly available at https://github.com/QiushiSun/BBT-RGB.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2305.08088v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qiushi Sun, Chengcheng Han, Nuo Chen, Renyu Zhu, Jingyang Gong, Xiang Li, Ming Gao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Persian Typographical Error Type Detection Using Deep Neural Networks on Algorithmically-Generated Misspellings</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2305.11731</link>
      <description>arXiv:2305.11731v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Spelling correction is a remarkable challenge in the field of natural language processing. The objective of spelling correction tasks is to recognize and rectify spelling errors automatically. The development of applications that can effectually diagnose and correct Persian spelling and grammatical errors has become more important in order to improve the quality of Persian text. The Typographical Error Type Detection in Persian is a relatively understudied area. Therefore, this paper presents a compelling approach for detecting typographical errors in Persian texts. Our work includes the presentation of a publicly available dataset called FarsTypo, which comprises 3.4 million words arranged in chronological order and tagged with their corresponding part-of-speech. These words cover a wide range of topics and linguistic styles. We develop an algorithm designed to apply Persian-specific errors to a scalable portion of these words, resulting in a parallel dataset of correct and incorrect words. By leveraging FarsTypo, we establish a strong foundation and conduct a thorough comparison of various methodologies employing different architectures. Additionally, we introduce a groundbreaking Deep Sequential Neural Network that utilizes both word and character embeddings, along with bidirectional LSTM layers, for token classification aimed at detecting typographical errors across 51 distinct classes. Our approach is contrasted with highly advanced industrial systems that, unlike this study, have been developed using a diverse range of resources. The outcomes of our final method proved to be highly competitive, achieving an accuracy of 97.62%, precision of 98.83%, recall of 98.61%, and surpassing others in terms of speed.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2305.11731v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mohammad Dehghani, Heshaam Faili</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Solve Few-Shot Abusive Content Detection Using the Data We Actually Have</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2305.14081</link>
      <description>arXiv:2305.14081v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Due to the broad range of social media platforms, the requirements of abusive language detection systems are varied and ever-changing. Already a large set of annotated corpora with different properties and label sets were created, such as hate or misogyny detection, but the form and targets of abusive speech are constantly evolving. Since, the annotation of new corpora is expensive, in this work we leverage datasets we already have, covering a wide range of tasks related to abusive language detection. Our goal is to build models cheaply for a new target label set and/or language, using only a few training examples of the target domain. We propose a two-step approach: first we train our model in a multitask fashion. We then carry out few-shot adaptation to the target requirements. Our experiments show that using already existing datasets and only a few-shots of the target task the performance of models improve both monolingually and across languages. Our analysis also shows that our models acquire a general understanding of abusive language, since they improve the prediction of labels which are present only in the target dataset and can benefit from knowledge about labels which are not directly used for the target task.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2305.14081v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Viktor Hangya, Alexander Fraser</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate What You Can't Evaluate: Unassessable Quality for Generated Response</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2305.14658</link>
      <description>arXiv:2305.14658v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: LLMs (large language models) such as ChatGPT have shown remarkable language understanding and generation capabilities. Although reference-free evaluators based on LLMs show better human alignment than traditional reference-based evaluators, there are many challenges in using reference-free evaluators based on LLMs. Reference-free evaluators are more suitable for open-ended examples with different semantics responses. But not all examples are open-ended. For closed-ended examples with unique correct semantic response, reference-free evaluators will still consider it high quality when giving a response that is inconsistent with the facts and the semantic of reference. In order to comprehensively evaluate the reliability of evaluators based on LLMs, we construct two adversarial meta-evaluation dialogue generation datasets KdConv-ADV and DSTC7-ADV based on KdConv and DSTC7-AVSD, respectively. Compared to previous meta-evaluation benchmarks, KdConv-ADV and DSTC7-ADV are much more challenging since they requires evaluators to be able to reasonably evaluate closed-ended examples with the help of external knowledge or even its own knowledge. Empirical results show that the ability of LLMs to identify unreasonable responses is insufficient. There are risks in using eference-free evaluators based on LLMs to evaluate the quality of dialogue responses.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2305.14658v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yongkang Liu, Shi Feng, Daling Wang, Yifei Zhang, Hinrich Sch\"utze</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision-Oriented Dialogue for Human-AI Collaboration</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2305.20076</link>
      <description>arXiv:2305.20076v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We describe a class of tasks called decision-oriented dialogues, in which AI assistants such as large language models (LMs) must collaborate with one or more humans via natural language to help them make complex decisions. We formalize three domains in which users face everyday decisions: (1) choosing an assignment of reviewers to conference papers, (2) planning a multi-step itinerary in a city, and (3) negotiating travel plans for a group of friends. In each of these settings, AI assistants and users have disparate abilities that they must combine to arrive at the best decision: assistants can access and process large amounts of information, while users have preferences and constraints external to the system. For each task, we build a dialogue environment where agents receive a reward based on the quality of the final decision they reach. We evaluate LMs in self-play and in collaboration with humans and find that they fall short compared to human assistants, achieving much lower rewards despite engaging in longer dialogues. We highlight a number of challenges models face in decision-oriented dialogues, ranging from goal-directed behavior to reasoning and optimization, and release our environments as a testbed for future work.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2305.20076v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jessy Lin, Nicholas Tomlin, Jacob Andreas, Jason Eisner</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing African-Accented Speech Recognition: Epistemic Uncertainty-Driven Data Selection for Generalizable ASR Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2306.02105</link>
      <description>arXiv:2306.02105v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Accents are crucial in human communication as they help us understand others and allow us to communicate intelligibly in a way others understand us. While there has been significant progress in ASR, African-accented ASR has been understudied due to a lack of training datasets which are often expensive to create and demand colossal human labor. Our study aims to address this problem by automating the annotation process and reducing annotation-related expenses through informative uncertainty-based data selection. We propose a new multi-rounds adaptation process that uses epistemic uncertainty and evaluate it across several domains, datasets, and high-performing ASR models. Our results show that our approach leads to a 69.44\% WER improvement while requiring on average 45\% less data than established baselines. Our approach also improves out-of-distribution generalization for very low-resource accents, demonstrating its viability for building generalizable ASR models in the context of accented African ASR. Moreover, the results of our active learning experiments, simulating real-world settings, where there are no \textit{gold} transcriptions available, also demonstrate the ability of our approach to favor good quality real-life transcriptions. This indicates that our proposed approach addresses the immediate issue of African-accented ASR and has broader implications for improving ASR systems for other underrepresented and low-resource languages and accents. We open-source the code https://github.com/bonaventuredossou/active_learning_african_asr</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2306.02105v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bonaventure F. P. Dossou, Atnafu Lambebo Tonja, Chris Chinenye Emezue, Tobi Olatunji, Naome A Etori, Salomey Osei, Tosin Adewumi, Sahib Singh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data-Copilot: Bridging Billions of Data and Humans with Autonomous Workflow</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2306.07209</link>
      <description>arXiv:2306.07209v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Various industries such as finance, meteorology, and energy produce vast amounts of heterogeneous data every day. There is a natural demand for humans to manage, process, and display data efficiently. However, it necessitates labor-intensive efforts and a high level of expertise for these data-related tasks. Considering large language models (LLMs) showcase promising capabilities in semantic understanding and reasoning, we advocate that the deployment of LLMs could autonomously manage and process massive amounts of data while interacting and displaying in a human-friendly manner. Based on this, we propose Data-Copilot, an LLM-based system that connects numerous data sources on one end and caters to diverse human demands on the other end. Acting as an experienced expert, Data-Copilot autonomously transforms raw data into multi-form output that best matches the user's intent. Specifically, it first designs multiple universal interfaces to satisfy diverse data-related requests, like querying, analysis, prediction, and visualization. In real-time response, it automatically deploys a concise workflow by invoking corresponding interfaces. The whole process is fully controlled by Data-Copilot, without human assistance. We release Data-Copilot-1.0 using massive Chinese financial data, e.g., stocks, funds, and news. Experiments indicate it achieves reliable performance with lower token consumption, showing promising application prospects.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2306.07209v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CE</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenqi Zhang, Yongliang Shen, Weiming Lu, Yueting Zhuang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Simple and Effective Pruning Approach for Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2306.11695</link>
      <description>arXiv:2306.11695v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: As their size increases, Large Languages Models (LLMs) are natural candidates for network pruning methods: approaches that drop a subset of network weights while striving to preserve performance. Existing methods, however, require either retraining, which is rarely affordable for billion-scale LLMs, or solving a weight reconstruction problem reliant on second-order information, which may also be computationally expensive. In this paper, we introduce a novel, straightforward yet effective pruning method, termed Wanda (Pruning by Weights and activations), designed to induce sparsity in pretrained LLMs. Motivated by the recent observation of emergent large magnitude features in LLMs, our approach prunes weights with the smallest magnitudes multiplied by the corresponding input activations, on a per-output basis. Notably, Wanda requires no retraining or weight update, and the pruned LLM can be used as is. We conduct a thorough evaluation of our method Wanda on LLaMA and LLaMA-2 across various language benchmarks. Wanda significantly outperforms the established baseline of magnitude pruning and performs competitively against recent method involving intensive weight update. Code is available at https://github.com/locuslab/wanda.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2306.11695v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mingjie Sun, Zhuang Liu, Anna Bair, J. Zico Kolter</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open-Domain Text Evaluation via Contrastive Distribution Modeling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2306.11879</link>
      <description>arXiv:2306.11879v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advancements in open-domain text generation, driven by the power of large pre-trained language models (LLMs), have demonstrated remarkable performance. However, assessing these models' generation quality remains a challenge. In this paper, we introduce a novel method for evaluating open-domain text generation called Contrastive Distribution Methods (CDM). Leveraging the connection between increasing model parameters and enhanced LLM performance, CDM creates a mapping from the _contrast_ of two probabilistic distributions -- one known to be superior to the other -- to quality measures. We investigate CDM for open-domain text generation evaluation under two paradigms: 1) _Generative_ CDM, which harnesses the contrast of two language models' distributions to generate synthetic examples for training discriminator-based metrics; 2) _Discriminative_ CDM, which directly uses distribution disparities between two language models for evaluation. Our experiments on coherence evaluation for multi-turn dialogue and commonsense evaluation for controllable generation demonstrate CDM's superior correlate with human judgment than existing automatic evaluation metrics, highlighting the strong performance and generalizability of our approach.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2306.11879v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sidi Lu, Hongyi Liu, Asli Celikyilmaz, Tianlu Wang, Nanyun Peng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LMFlow: An Extensible Toolkit for Finetuning and Inference of Large Foundation Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2306.12420</link>
      <description>arXiv:2306.12420v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Foundation models have demonstrated a great ability to achieve general human-level intelligence far beyond traditional approaches. As the technique keeps attracting attention from the AI community, an increasing number of foundation models are becoming publicly accessible. However, a significant shortcoming of most of these models lies in their performance in specialized-domain and task-specific applications, necessitating domain- and task-aware fine-tuning to develop effective scientific language models. As the number of available foundation models and specialized tasks keeps growing, the job of training scientific language models becomes highly nontrivial. In this paper, we initiate steps to tackle this issue. We introduce an extensible and lightweight toolkit, LMFlow, which aims to simplify the domain- and task-aware finetuning of general foundation models. LMFlow offers a complete finetuning workflow for a foundation model to support specialized training with limited computing resources. Furthermore, it supports continuous pretraining, instruction tuning, parameter-efficient finetuning, alignment tuning, inference acceleration, long context generalization, model customization, and even multimodal finetuning, along with carefully designed and extensible APIs. This toolkit has been thoroughly tested and is available at https://github.com/OptimalScale/LMFlow.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2306.12420v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shizhe Diao, Rui Pan, Hanze Dong, Ka Shun Shum, Jipeng Zhang, Wei Xiong, Tong Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Potential of Sentiment: Can Large Language Models Predict Chinese Stock Price Movements?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2306.14222</link>
      <description>arXiv:2306.14222v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The rapid advancement of Large Language Models (LLMs) has spurred discussions about their potential to enhance quantitative trading strategies. LLMs excel in analyzing sentiments about listed companies from financial news, providing critical insights for trading decisions. However, the performance of LLMs in this task varies substantially due to their inherent characteristics. This paper introduces a standardized experimental procedure for comprehensive evaluations. We detail the methodology using three distinct LLMs, each embodying a unique approach to performance enhancement, applied specifically to the task of sentiment factor extraction from large volumes of Chinese news summaries. Subsequently, we develop quantitative trading strategies using these sentiment factors and conduct back-tests in realistic scenarios. Our results will offer perspectives about the performances of Large Language Models applied to extracting sentiments from Chinese news texts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2306.14222v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>q-fin.ST</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haohan Zhang, Fengrui Hua, Chengjin Xu, Hao Kong, Ruiting Zuo, Jian Guo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are aligned neural networks adversarially aligned?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2306.15447</link>
      <description>arXiv:2306.15447v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models are now tuned to align with the goals of their creators, namely to be "helpful and harmless." These models should respond helpfully to user questions, but refuse to answer requests that could cause harm. However, adversarial users can construct inputs which circumvent attempts at alignment. In this work, we study adversarial alignment, and ask to what extent these models remain aligned when interacting with an adversarial user who constructs worst-case inputs (adversarial examples). These inputs are designed to cause the model to emit harmful content that would otherwise be prohibited. We show that existing NLP-based optimization attacks are insufficiently powerful to reliably attack aligned text models: even when current NLP-based attacks fail, we can find adversarial inputs with brute force. As a result, the failure of current attacks should not be seen as proof that aligned text models remain aligned under adversarial inputs.
  However the recent trend in large-scale ML models is multimodal models that allow users to provide images that influence the text that is generated. We show these models can be easily attacked, i.e., induced to perform arbitrary un-aligned behavior through adversarial perturbation of the input image. We conjecture that improved NLP attacks may demonstrate this same level of adversarial control over text-only models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2306.15447v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nicholas Carlini, Milad Nasr, Christopher A. Choquette-Choo, Matthew Jagielski, Irena Gao, Anas Awadalla, Pang Wei Koh, Daphne Ippolito, Katherine Lee, Florian Tramer, Ludwig Schmidt</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How far is Language Model from 100% Few-shot Named Entity Recognition in Medical Domain</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2307.00186</link>
      <description>arXiv:2307.00186v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advancements in language models (LMs) have led to the emergence of powerful models such as Small LMs (e.g., T5) and Large LMs (e.g., GPT-4). These models have demonstrated exceptional capabilities across a wide range of tasks, such as name entity recognition (NER) in the general domain. (We define SLMs as pre-trained models with fewer parameters compared to models like GPT-3/3.5/4, such as T5, BERT, and others.) Nevertheless, their efficacy in the medical section remains uncertain and the performance of medical NER always needs high accuracy because of the particularity of the field. This paper aims to provide a thorough investigation to compare the performance of LMs in medical few-shot NER and answer How far is LMs from 100\% Few-shot NER in Medical Domain, and moreover to explore an effective entity recognizer to help improve the NER performance. Based on our extensive experiments conducted on 16 NER models spanning from 2018 to 2023, our findings clearly indicate that LLMs outperform SLMs in few-shot medical NER tasks, given the presence of suitable examples and appropriate logical frameworks. Despite the overall superiority of LLMs in few-shot medical NER tasks, it is important to note that they still encounter some challenges, such as misidentification, wrong template prediction, etc. Building on previous findings, we introduce a simple and effective method called \textsc{RT} (Retrieving and Thinking), which serves as retrievers, finding relevant examples, and as thinkers, employing a step-by-step reasoning process. Experimental results show that our proposed \textsc{RT} framework significantly outperforms the strong open baselines on the two open medical benchmark datasets</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2307.00186v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mingchen Li, Rui Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bengali Fake Reviews: A Benchmark Dataset and Detection System</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2308.01987</link>
      <description>arXiv:2308.01987v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The proliferation of fake reviews on various online platforms has created a major concern for both consumers and businesses. Such reviews can deceive customers and cause damage to the reputation of products or services, making it crucial to identify them. Although the detection of fake reviews has been extensively studied in English language, detecting fake reviews in non-English languages such as Bengali is still a relatively unexplored research area. This paper introduces the Bengali Fake Review Detection (BFRD) dataset, the first publicly available dataset for identifying fake reviews in Bengali. The dataset consists of 7710 non-fake and 1339 fake food-related reviews collected from social media posts. To convert non-Bengali words in a review, a unique pipeline has been proposed that translates English words to their corresponding Bengali meaning and also back transliterates Romanized Bengali to Bengali. We have conducted rigorous experimentation using multiple deep learning and pre-trained transformer language models to develop a reliable detection system. Finally, we propose a weighted ensemble model that combines four pre-trained transformers: BanglaBERT, BanglaBERT Base, BanglaBERT Large, and BanglaBERT Generator . According to the experiment results, the proposed ensemble model obtained a weighted F1-score of 0.9843 on 13390 reviews, including 1339 actual fake reviews and 5356 augmented fake reviews generated with the nlpaug library. The remaining 6695 reviews were randomly selected from the 7710 non-fake instances. The model achieved a 0.9558 weighted F1-score when the fake reviews were augmented using the bnaug library.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2308.01987v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>G. M. Shahariar, Md. Tanvir Rouf Shawon, Faisal Muhammad Shah, Mohammad Shafiul Alam, Md. Shahriar Mahbub</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retroformer: Retrospective Large Language Agents with Policy Gradient Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2308.02151</link>
      <description>arXiv:2308.02151v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent months have seen the emergence of a powerful new trend in which large language models (LLMs) are augmented to become autonomous language agents capable of performing objective oriented multi-step tasks on their own, rather than merely responding to queries from human users. Most existing language agents, however, are not optimized using environment-specific rewards. Although some agents enable iterative refinement through verbal feedback, they do not reason and plan in ways that are compatible with gradient-based learning from rewards. This paper introduces a principled framework for reinforcing large language agents by learning a retrospective model, which automatically tunes the language agent prompts from environment feedback through policy gradient. Specifically, our proposed agent architecture learns from rewards across multiple environments and tasks, for fine-tuning a pre-trained language model which refines the language agent prompt by summarizing the root cause of prior failed attempts and proposing action plans. Experimental results on various tasks demonstrate that the language agents improve over time and that our approach considerably outperforms baselines that do not properly leverage gradients from the environment. This demonstrates that using policy gradient optimization to improve language agents, for which we believe our work is one of the first, seems promising and can be applied to optimize other models in the agent architecture to enhance agent performances over time.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2308.02151v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weiran Yao, Shelby Heinecke, Juan Carlos Niebles, Zhiwei Liu, Yihao Feng, Le Xue, Rithesh Murthy, Zeyuan Chen, Jianguo Zhang, Devansh Arpit, Ran Xu, Phil Mui, Huan Wang, Caiming Xiong, Silvio Savarese</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RA-DIT: Retrieval-Augmented Dual Instruction Tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.01352</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.01352v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Retrieval-augmented language models (RALMs) improve performance by accessing long-tail and up-to-date knowledge from external data stores, but are challenging to build. Existing approaches require either expensive retrieval-specific modifications to LM pre-training or use post-hoc integration of the data store that leads to suboptimal performance. We introduce Retrieval-Augmented Dual Instruction Tuning (RA-DIT), a lightweight fine-tuning methodology that provides a third option by retrofitting any LLM with retrieval capabilities. Our approach operates in two distinct fine-tuning steps: (1) one updates a pre-trained LM to better use retrieved information, while (2) the other updates the retriever to return more relevant results, as preferred by the LM. By fine-tuning over tasks that require both knowledge utilization and contextual awareness, we demonstrate that each stage yields significant performance improvements, and using both leads to additional gains. Our best model, RA-DIT 65B, achieves state-of-the-art performance across a range of knowledge-intensive zero- and few-shot learning benchmarks, significantly outperforming existing in-context RALM approaches by up to +8.9% in 0-shot setting and +1.4% in 5-shot setting on average.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.01352v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xi Victoria Lin, Xilun Chen, Mingda Chen, Weijia Shi, Maria Lomeli, Rich James, Pedro Rodriguez, Jacob Kahn, Gergely Szilvasy, Mike Lewis, Luke Zettlemoyer, Scott Yih</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making Retrieval-Augmented Language Models Robust to Irrelevant Context</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.01558</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.01558v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Retrieval-augmented language models (RALMs) hold promise to produce language understanding systems that are are factual, efficient, and up-to-date. An important desideratum of RALMs, is that retrieved information helps model performance when it is relevant, and does not harm performance when it is not. This is particularly important in multi-hop reasoning scenarios, where misuse of irrelevant evidence can lead to cascading errors. However, recent work has shown that retrieval augmentation can sometimes have a negative effect on performance. In this work, we present a thorough analysis on five open-domain question answering benchmarks, characterizing cases when retrieval reduces accuracy. We then propose two methods to mitigate this issue. First, a simple baseline that filters out retrieved passages that do not entail question-answer pairs according to a natural language inference (NLI) model. This is effective in preventing performance reduction, but at a cost of also discarding relevant passages. Thus, we propose a method for automatically generating data to fine-tune the language model to properly leverage retrieved passages, using a mix of relevant and irrelevant contexts at training time. We empirically show that even 1,000 examples suffice to train the model to be robust to irrelevant contexts while maintaining high performance on examples with relevant ones.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.01558v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ori Yoran, Tomer Wolfson, Ori Ram, Jonathan Berant</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Circuit Component Reuse Across Tasks in Transformer Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.08744</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.08744v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent work in mechanistic interpretability has shown that behaviors in language models can be successfully reverse-engineered through circuit analysis. A common criticism, however, is that each circuit is task-specific, and thus such analysis cannot contribute to understanding the models at a higher level. In this work, we present evidence that insights (both low-level findings about specific heads and higher-level findings about general algorithms) can indeed generalize across tasks. Specifically, we study the circuit discovered in Wang et al. (2022) for the Indirect Object Identification (IOI) task and 1.) show that it reproduces on a larger GPT2 model, and 2.) that it is mostly reused to solve a seemingly different task: Colored Objects (Ippolito &amp; Callison-Burch, 2023). We provide evidence that the process underlying both tasks is functionally very similar, and contains about a 78% overlap in in-circuit attention heads. We further present a proof-of-concept intervention experiment, in which we adjust four attention heads in middle layers in order to 'repair' the Colored Objects circuit and make it behave like the IOI circuit. In doing so, we boost accuracy from 49.6% to 93.7% on the Colored Objects task and explain most sources of error. The intervention affects downstream attention heads in specific ways predicted by their interactions in the IOI circuit, indicating that this subcircuit behavior is invariant to the different task inputs. Overall, our results provide evidence that it may yet be possible to explain large language models' behavior in terms of a relatively small number of interpretable task-general algorithmic building blocks and computational components.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.08744v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jack Merullo, Carsten Eickhoff, Ellie Pavlick</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Language Models for In-Context Student Modeling: Synthesizing Student's Behavior in Visual Programming</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.10690</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.10690v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Student modeling is central to many educational technologies as it enables predicting future learning outcomes and designing targeted instructional strategies. However, open-ended learning domains pose challenges for accurately modeling students due to the diverse behaviors and a large space of possible misconceptions. To approach these challenges, we explore the application of large language models (LLMs) for in-context student modeling in open-ended learning domains. More concretely, given a particular student's attempt on a reference task as observation, the objective is to synthesize the student's attempt on a target task. We introduce a novel framework, LLM for Student Synthesis (LLM-SS), that leverages LLMs for synthesizing a student's behavior. Our framework can be combined with different LLMs; moreover, we fine-tune LLMs to boost their student modeling capabilities. We instantiate several methods based on LLM-SS framework and evaluate them using an existing benchmark, StudentSyn, for student attempt synthesis in a visual programming domain. Experimental results show that our methods perform significantly better than the baseline method NeurSS provided in the StudentSyn benchmark. Furthermore, our method using a fine-tuned version of the GPT-3.5 model is significantly better than using the base GPT-3.5 model and gets close to human tutors' performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.10690v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Manh Hung Nguyen, Sebastian Tschiatschek, Adish Singla</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can LLMs Grade Short-Answer Reading Comprehension Questions : An Empirical Study with a Novel Dataset</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.18373</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.18373v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Open-ended questions, which require students to produce multi-word, nontrivial responses, are a popular tool for formative assessment as they provide more specific insights into what students do and don't know. However, grading open-ended questions can be time-consuming leading teachers to resort to simpler question formats or conduct fewer formative assessments. While there has been a longstanding interest in automating of short-answer grading (ASAG), but previous approaches have been technically complex, limiting their use in formative assessment contexts. The newest generation of Large Language Models (LLMs) potentially makes grading short answer questions more feasible. This paper investigates the potential for the newest version of LLMs to be used in ASAG, specifically in the grading of short answer questions for formative assessments, in two ways. First, it introduces a novel dataset of short answer reading comprehension questions, drawn from a set of reading assessments conducted with over 150 students in Ghana. This dataset allows for the evaluation of LLMs in a new context, as they are predominantly designed and trained on data from high-income North American countries. Second, the paper empirically evaluates how well various configurations of generative LLMs grade student short answer responses compared to expert human raters. The findings show that GPT-4, with minimal prompt engineering, performed extremely well on grading the novel dataset (QWK 0.92, F1 0.89), reaching near parity with expert human raters. To our knowledge this work is the first to empirically evaluate the performance of generative LLMs on short answer reading comprehension questions using real student data, with low technical hurdles to attaining this performance. These findings suggest that generative LLMs could be used to grade formative literacy assessment tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.18373v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Owen Henkel, Libby Hills, Bill Roberts, Joshua McGrane</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CreoleVal: Multilingual Multitask Benchmarks for Creoles</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.19567</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.19567v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Creoles represent an under-explored and marginalized group of languages, with few available resources for NLP research.While the genealogical ties between Creoles and a number of highly-resourced languages imply a significant potential for transfer learning, this potential is hampered due to this lack of annotated data. In this work we present CreoleVal, a collection of benchmark datasets spanning 8 different NLP tasks, covering up to 28 Creole languages; it is an aggregate of novel development datasets for reading comprehension, relation classification, and machine translation for Creoles, in addition to a practical gateway to a handful of preexisting benchmarks. For each benchmark, we conduct baseline experiments in a zero-shot setting in order to further ascertain the capabilities and limitations of transfer learning for Creoles. Ultimately, we see CreoleVal as an opportunity to empower research on Creoles in NLP and computational linguistics, and in general, a step towards more equitable language technology around the globe.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.19567v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Heather Lent, Kushal Tatariya, Raj Dabre, Yiyi Chen, Marcell Fekete, Esther Ploeger, Li Zhou, Ruth-Ann Armstrong, Abee Eijansantos, Catriona Malau, Hans Erik Heje, Ernests Lavrinovics, Diptesh Kanojia, Paul Belony, Marcel Bollmann, Lo\"ic Grobol, Miryam de Lhoneux, Daniel Hershcovich, Michel DeGraff, Anders S{\o}gaard, Johannes Bjerva</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On-the-Fly Fusion of Large Language Models and Machine Translation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.08306</link>
      <description>arXiv:2311.08306v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We propose the on-the-fly ensembling of a machine translation model with an LLM, prompted on the same task and input. We perform experiments on 4 language pairs (both directions) with varying data amounts. We find that a slightly weaker-at-translation LLM can improve translations of a NMT model, and ensembling with an LLM can produce better translations than ensembling two stronger MT models. We combine our method with various techniques from LLM prompting, such as in context learning and translation context.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2311.08306v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hieu Hoang, Huda Khayrallah, Marcin Junczys-Dowmunt</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>R-Tuning: Instructing Large Language Models to Say `I Don't Know'</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.09677</link>
      <description>arXiv:2311.09677v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have revolutionized numerous domains with their impressive performance but still face their challenges. A predominant issue is the propensity for these models to generate non-existent facts, a concern termed hallucination. Our research is motivated by the observation that previous instruction tuning methods force the model to complete a sentence no matter whether the model knows the knowledge or not. When the question is out of the parametric knowledge, it will try to make up something and fail to indicate when it lacks knowledge. In this paper, we present a new approach called Refusal-Aware Instruction Tuning (R-Tuning). This approach is formalized by first identifying the disparity in knowledge encompassed by pre-trained parameters compared to that of instruction tuning data. Then, we construct the refusal-aware data based on the knowledge intersection, to tune LLMs to refrain from responding to questions beyond its parametric knowledge. Experimental results demonstrate R-Tuning effectively improves a model's ability to answer known questions and refrain from answering unknown questions. Furthermore, when tested on out-of-domain datasets, the refusal ability was found to be a meta-skill that could be generalized to other tasks. Further analysis surprisingly finds that learning the uncertainty results in better calibration and an improved ability to estimate the uncertainty than uncertainty-based testing. Our code is available at https://github.com/shizhediao/R-Tuning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2311.09677v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hanning Zhang, Shizhe Diao, Yong Lin, Yi R. Fung, Qing Lian, Xingyao Wang, Yangyi Chen, Heng Ji, Tong Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Language Model Moderators Improve the Health of Online Discourse?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.10781</link>
      <description>arXiv:2311.10781v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Conversational moderation of online communities is crucial to maintaining civility for a constructive environment, but it is challenging to scale and harmful to moderators. The inclusion of sophisticated natural language generation modules as a force multiplier to aid human moderators is a tantalizing prospect, but adequate evaluation approaches have so far been elusive. In this paper, we establish a systematic definition of conversational moderation effectiveness grounded on moderation literature and establish design criteria for conducting realistic yet safe evaluation. We then propose a comprehensive evaluation framework to assess models' moderation capabilities independently of human intervention. With our framework, we conduct the first known study of language models as conversational moderators, finding that appropriately prompted models that incorporate insights from social science can provide specific and fair feedback on toxic behavior but struggle to influence users to increase their levels of respect and cooperation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2311.10781v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hyundong Cho, Shuai Liu, Taiwei Shi, Darpan Jain, Basem Rizk, Yuyang Huang, Zixun Lu, Nuan Wen, Jonathan Gratch, Emilio Ferrara, Jonathan May</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A ripple in time: a discontinuity in American history</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.01185</link>
      <description>arXiv:2312.01185v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this note we use the State of the Union Address (SOTU) dataset from Kaggle to make some surprising (and some not so surprising) observations pertaining to the general timeline of American history, and the character and nature of the addresses themselves. Our main approach is using vector embeddings, such as BERT (DistilBERT) and GPT-2.
  While it is widely believed that BERT (and its variations) is most suitable for NLP classification tasks, we find out that GPT-2 in conjunction with nonlinear dimension reduction methods such as UMAP provide better separation and stronger clustering. This makes GPT-2 + UMAP an interesting alternative. In our case, no model fine-tuning is required, and the pre-trained out-of-the-box GPT-2 model is enough.
  We also used a fine-tuned DistilBERT model for classification detecting which President delivered which address, with very good results (accuracy 93% - 95% depending on the run). An analogous task was performed to determine the year of writing, and we were able to pin it down to about 4 years (which is a single presidential term).
  It is worth noting that SOTU addresses provide relatively small writing samples (with about 8'000 words on average, and varying widely from under 2'000 words to more than 20'000), and that the number of authors is relatively large (we used SOTU addresses of 42 US presidents). This shows that the techniques employed turn out to be rather efficient, while all the computations described in this note can be performed using a single GPU instance of Google Colab.
  The accompanying code is available on GitHub.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2312.01185v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alexander Kolpakov, Igor Rivin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State of What Art? A Call for Multi-Prompt LLM Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.00595</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.00595v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advances in large language models (LLMs) have led to the development of various evaluation benchmarks. These benchmarks typically rely on a single instruction template for evaluating all LLMs on a specific task. In this paper, we comprehensively analyze the brittleness of results obtained via single-prompt evaluations across 6.5M instances, involving 20 different LLMs and 39 tasks from 3 benchmarks. To improve robustness of the analysis, we propose to evaluate LLMs with a set of diverse prompts instead. We discuss tailored evaluation metrics for specific use cases (e.g., LLM developers vs. developers interested in a specific downstream task), ensuring a more reliable and meaningful assessment of LLM capabilities. We then implement these criteria and conduct evaluations of multiple models, providing insights into the true strengths and limitations of current LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.00595v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Moran Mizrahi, Guy Kaplan, Dan Malkin, Rotem Dror, Dafna Shahaf, Gabriel Stanovsky</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linear Alignment: A Closed-form Solution for Aligning Human Preferences without Tuning and Feedback</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.11458</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.11458v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The success of AI assistants based on Language Models (LLMs) hinges on Reinforcement Learning from Human Feedback (RLHF) to comprehend and align with user intentions. However, traditional alignment algorithms, such as PPO, are hampered by complex annotation and training requirements. This reliance limits the applicability of RLHF and hinders the development of professional assistants tailored to diverse human preferences. In this work, we introduce \textit{Linear Alignment}, a novel algorithm that aligns language models with human preferences in one single inference step, eliminating the reliance on data annotation and model training. Linear alignment incorporates a new parameterization for policy optimization under divergence constraints, which enables the extraction of optimal policy in a closed-form manner and facilitates the direct estimation of the aligned response. Extensive experiments on both general and personalized preference datasets demonstrate that linear alignment significantly enhances the performance and efficiency of LLM alignment across diverse scenarios. Our code and dataset is published on \url{https://github.com/Wizardcoast/Linear_Alignment.git}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.11458v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Songyang Gao, Qiming Ge, Wei Shen, Shihan Dou, Junjie Ye, Xiao Wang, Rui Zheng, Yicheng Zou, Zhi Chen, Hang Yan, Qi Zhang, Dahua Lin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Values That Are Explicitly Present in Fairy Tales: Comparing Samples from German, Italian and Portuguese Traditions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.08318</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.08318v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Looking at how social values are represented in fairy tales can give insights about the variations in communication of values across cultures. We study how values are communicated in fairy tales from Portugal, Italy and Germany using a technique called word embedding with a compass to quantify vocabulary differences and commonalities. We study how these three national traditions differ in their explicit references to values. To do this, we specify a list of value-charged tokens, consider their word stems and analyse the distance between these in a bespoke pre-trained Word2Vec model. We triangulate and critically discuss the validity of the resulting hypotheses emerging from this quantitative model. Our claim is that this is a reusable and reproducible method for the study of the values explicitly referenced in historical corpora. Finally, our preliminary findings hint at a shared cultural understanding and the expression of values such as Benevolence, Conformity, and Universalism across the studied cultures, suggesting the potential existence of a pan-European cultural memory.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.08318v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alba Morollon Diaz-Faes, Carla Sofia Ribeiro Murteira, Martin Ruskov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicting postoperative risks using large language models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.17493</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.17493v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Predicting postoperative risk can inform effective care management &amp; planning. We explored large language models (LLMs) in predicting postoperative risk through clinical texts using various tuning strategies. Records spanning 84,875 patients from Barnes Jewish Hospital (BJH) between 2018 &amp; 2021, with a mean duration of follow-up based on the length of postoperative ICU stay less than 7 days, were utilized. Methods were replicated on the MIMIC-III dataset. Outcomes included 30-day mortality, pulmonary embolism (PE) &amp; pneumonia. Three domain adaptation &amp; finetuning strategies were implemented for three LLMs (BioGPT, ClinicalBERT &amp; BioClinicalBERT): self-supervised objectives; incorporating labels with semi-supervised fine-tuning; &amp; foundational modelling through multi-task learning. Model performance was compared using the AUROC &amp; AUPRC for classification tasks &amp; MSE &amp; R2 for regression tasks. Cohort had a mean age of 56.9 (sd: 16.8) years; 50.3% male; 74% White. Pre-trained LLMs outperformed traditional word embeddings, with absolute maximal gains of 38.3% for AUROC &amp; 14% for AUPRC. Adapting models through self-supervised finetuning further improved performance by 3.2% for AUROC &amp; 1.5% for AUPRC Incorporating labels into the finetuning procedure further boosted performances, with semi-supervised finetuning improving by 1.8% for AUROC &amp; 2% for AUPRC &amp; foundational modelling improving by 3.6% for AUROC &amp; 2.6% for AUPRC compared to self-supervised finetuning. Pre-trained clinical LLMs offer opportunities for postoperative risk predictions with unseen data, &amp; further improvements from finetuning suggests benefits in adapting pre-trained models to note-specific perioperative use cases. Incorporating labels can further boost performance. The superior performance of foundational models suggests the potential of task-agnostic learning towards the generalizable LLMs in perioperative care.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.17493v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bing Xue, Charles Alba, Joanna Abraham, Thomas Kannampallil, Chenyang Lu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neural Automated Writing Evaluation with Corrective Feedback</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.17613</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.17613v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The utilization of technology in second language learning and teaching has become ubiquitous. For the assessment of writing specifically, automated writing evaluation (AWE) and grammatical error correction (GEC) have become immensely popular and effective methods for enhancing writing proficiency and delivering instant and individualized feedback to learners. By leveraging the power of natural language processing (NLP) and machine learning algorithms, AWE and GEC systems have been developed separately to provide language learners with automated corrective feedback and more accurate and unbiased scoring that would otherwise be subject to examiners. In this paper, we propose an integrated system for automated writing evaluation with corrective feedback as a means of bridging the gap between AWE and GEC results for second language learners. This system enables language learners to simulate the essay writing tests: a student writes and submits an essay, and the system returns the assessment of the writing along with suggested grammatical error corrections. Given that automated scoring and grammatical correction are more efficient and cost-effective than human grading, this integrated system would also alleviate the burden of manually correcting innumerable essays.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.17613v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Izia Xiaoxiao Wang, Xihan Wu, Edith Coates, Min Zeng, Jiexin Kuang, Siliang Liu, Mengyang Qiu, Jungyeul Park</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to think step-by-step: A mechanistic understanding of chain-of-thought reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18312</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.18312v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Despite superior reasoning prowess demonstrated by Large Language Models (LLMs) with Chain-of-Thought (CoT) prompting, a lack of understanding prevails around the internal mechanisms of the models that facilitate CoT generation. This work investigates the neural sub-structures within LLMs that manifest CoT reasoning from a mechanistic point of view. From an analysis of Llama-2 7B applied to multistep reasoning over fictional ontologies, we demonstrate that LLMs deploy multiple parallel pathways of answer generation for step-by-step reasoning. These parallel pathways provide sequential answers from the input question context as well as the generated CoT. We observe a functional rift in the middle layers of the LLM. Token representations in the initial half remain strongly biased towards the pretraining prior, with the in-context prior taking over in the later half. This internal phase shift manifests in different functional components: attention heads that write the answer token appear in the later half, attention heads that move information along ontological relationships appear in the initial half, and so on. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first attempt towards mechanistic investigation of CoT reasoning in LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.18312v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Subhabrata Dutta, Joykirat Singh, Soumen Chakrabarti, Tanmoy Chakraborty</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distilling Text Style Transfer With Self-Explanation From LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.01106</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.01106v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Text Style Transfer (TST) seeks to alter the style of text while retaining its core content. Given the constraints of limited parallel datasets for TST, we propose CoTeX, a framework that leverages large language models (LLMs) alongside chain-of-thought (CoT) prompting to facilitate TST. CoTeX distills the complex rewriting and reasoning capabilities of LLMs into more streamlined models capable of working with both non-parallel and parallel data. Through experimentation across four TST datasets, CoTeX is shown to surpass traditional supervised fine-tuning and knowledge distillation methods, particularly in low-resource settings. We conduct a comprehensive evaluation, comparing CoTeX against current unsupervised, supervised, in-context learning (ICL) techniques, and instruction-tuned LLMs. Furthermore, CoTeX distinguishes itself by offering transparent explanations for its style transfer process.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.01106v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chiyu Zhang (Music), Honglong Cai (Music),  Yuezhang (Music),  Li, Yuexin Wu, Le Hou, Muhammad Abdul-Mageed</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantity Matters: Towards Assessing and Mitigating Number Hallucination in Large Vision-Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.01373</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.01373v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large-scale vision-language models have demonstrated impressive skill in handling tasks that involve both areas. Nevertheless, these models frequently experience significant issues with generating inaccurate information, which is hallucination. In this study, we concentrate on a specific type of hallucination-number hallucination, referring to models incorrectly identifying the number of certain objects in pictures. We perform quantitative evaluations regarding number hallucination, showing it to be critical in major open-source large vision-language models. Furthermore, we utilizes two related tasks to conduct an in-depth analysis of number hallucination, revealing the severe inner and outer inconsistency among all tasks. Based on this examination, we devise a training approach aimed at improving consistency to reduce number hallucinations, which leads to an 8% enhancement in performance over direct finetuning methods. Our code and dataset will be released to the community.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.01373v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Huixuan Zhang, Junzhe Zhang, Xiaojun Wan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HaluEval-Wild: Evaluating Hallucinations of Language Models in the Wild</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.04307</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.04307v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Hallucinations pose a significant challenge to the reliability of large language models (LLMs) in critical domains. Recent benchmarks designed to assess LLM hallucinations within conventional NLP tasks, such as knowledge-intensive question answering (QA) and summarization, are insufficient for capturing the complexities of user-LLM interactions in dynamic, real-world settings. To address this gap, we introduce HaluEval-Wild, the first benchmark specifically designed to evaluate LLM hallucinations in the wild. We meticulously collect challenging (adversarially filtered by Alpaca) user queries from existing real-world user-LLM interaction datasets, including ShareGPT, to evaluate the hallucination rates of various LLMs. Upon analyzing the collected queries, we categorize them into five distinct types, which enables a fine-grained analysis of the types of hallucinations LLMs exhibit, and synthesize the reference answers with the powerful GPT-4 model and retrieval-augmented generation (RAG). Our benchmark offers a novel approach towards enhancing our comprehension and improvement of LLM reliability in scenarios reflective of real-world interactions. Our benchmark is available at https://github.com/Dianezzy/HaluEval-Wild.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.04307v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhiying Zhu, Yiming Yang, Zhiqing Sun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards a clinically accessible radiology foundation model: open-access and lightweight, with automated evaluation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.08002</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.08002v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The scaling laws and extraordinary performance of large foundation models motivate the development and utilization of such models in biomedicine. However, despite early promising results on some biomedical benchmarks, there are still major challenges that need to be addressed before these models can be used in real-world clinics. Frontier general-domain models such as GPT-4V still have significant performance gaps in multimodal biomedical applications. More importantly, less-acknowledged pragmatic issues, including accessibility, model cost, and tedious manual evaluation make it hard for clinicians to use state-of-the-art large models directly on private patient data. Here, we explore training open-source small multimodal models (SMMs) to bridge competency gaps for unmet clinical needs in radiology. To maximize data efficiency, we adopt a modular approach by incorporating state-of-the-art pre-trained models for image and text modalities, and focusing on training a lightweight adapter to ground each modality to the text embedding space, as exemplified by LLaVA-Med. For training, we assemble a large dataset of over 697 thousand radiology image-text pairs. For evaluation, we propose CheXprompt, a GPT-4-based metric for factuality evaluation, and demonstrate its parity with expert evaluation. For best practice, we conduct a systematic ablation study on various choices in data engineering and multimodal training. The resulting LlaVA-Rad (7B) model attains state-of-the-art results on standard radiology tasks such as report generation and cross-modal retrieval, even outperforming much larger models such as GPT-4V and Med-PaLM M (84B). The inference of LlaVA-Rad is fast and can be performed on a single V100 GPU in private settings, offering a promising state-of-the-art tool for real-world clinical applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.08002v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Juan Manuel Zambrano Chaves, Shih-Cheng Huang, Yanbo Xu, Hanwen Xu, Naoto Usuyama, Sheng Zhang, Fei Wang, Yujia Xie, Mahmoud Khademi, Ziyi Yang, Hany Awadalla, Julia Gong, Houdong Hu, Jianwei Yang, Chunyuan Li, Jianfeng Gao, Yu Gu, Cliff Wong, Mu Wei, Tristan Naumann, Muhao Chen, Matthew P. Lungren, Serena Yeung-Levy, Curtis P. Langlotz, Sheng Wang, Hoifung Poon</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TeaMs-RL: Teaching LLMs to Teach Themselves Better Instructions via Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.08694</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.08694v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The development of Large Language Models (LLMs) often confronts challenges stemming from the heavy reliance on human annotators in the reinforcement learning with human feedback (RLHF) framework, or the frequent and costly external queries tied to the self-instruct paradigm. In this work, we pivot to Reinforcement Learning (RL) -- but with a twist. Diverging from the typical RLHF, which refines LLMs following instruction data training, we use RL to directly generate the foundational instruction dataset that alone suffices for fine-tuning. Our method, TeaMs-RL, uses a suite of textual operations and rules, prioritizing the diversification of training datasets. It facilitates the generation of high-quality data without excessive reliance on external advanced models, paving the way for a single fine-tuning step and negating the need for subsequent RLHF stages. Our findings highlight key advantages of our approach: reduced need for human involvement and fewer model queries (only $5.73\%$ of WizardLM's total), along with enhanced capabilities of LLMs in crafting and comprehending complex instructions compared to strong baselines, and substantially improved model privacy protection.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.08694v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shangding Gu, Alois Knoll, Ming Jin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FakeWatch: A Framework for Detecting Fake News to Ensure Credible Elections</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.09858</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.09858v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In today's technologically driven world, the rapid spread of fake news, particularly during critical events like elections, poses a growing threat to the integrity of information. To tackle this challenge head-on, we introduce FakeWatch, a comprehensive framework carefully designed to detect fake news. Leveraging a newly curated dataset of North American election-related news articles, we construct robust classification models. Our framework integrates a model hub comprising of both traditional machine learning (ML) techniques, and state-of-the-art Language Models (LMs) to discern fake news effectively. Our objective is to provide the research community with adaptable and precise classification models adept at identifying fake news for the elections agenda. Quantitative evaluations of fake news classifiers on our dataset reveal that, while state-of-the-art LMs exhibit a slight edge over traditional ML models, classical models remain competitive due to their balance of accuracy and computational efficiency. Additionally, qualitative analyses shed light on patterns within fake news articles. We provide our labeled data at https://huggingface.co/datasets/newsmediabias/fake_news_elections_labelled_data and model https://huggingface.co/newsmediabias/FakeWatch for reproducibility and further research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.09858v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shaina Raza, Tahniat Khan, Veronica Chatrath, Drai Paulen-Patterson, Mizanur Rahman, Oluwanifemi Bamgbose</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MetaAligner: Towards Generalizable Multi-Objective Alignment of Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.17141</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.17141v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advancements in large language models (LLMs) aim to tackle heterogeneous human expectations and values via multi-objective preference alignment. However, existing methods are parameter-adherent to the policy model, leading to two key limitations: (1) the high-cost repetition of their alignment algorithms for each new target model; (2) they cannot expand to unseen objectives due to their static alignment objectives. In this work, we propose Meta-Objective Aligner (MetaAligner), a model that performs conditional weak-to-strong correction for weak responses to approach strong responses. MetaAligner is the first policy-agnostic and generalizable method for multi-objective preference alignment, which enables plug-and-play alignment by decoupling parameter updates from the policy models and facilitates zero-shot preference alignment for unseen objectives via in-context learning. Experimental results show that MetaAligner achieves significant and balanced improvements in multi-objective alignments on 10 state-of-the-art policy models, and outperforms previous alignment methods with down to 15.71x less GPU training hours. The model also effectively aligns unseen objectives, marking the first step towards generalizable multi-objective preference alignment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.17141v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kailai Yang, Zhiwei Liu, Qianqian Xie, Jimin Huang, Tianlin Zhang, Sophia Ananiadou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can LLMs Correct Physicians, Yet? Investigating Effective Interaction Methods in the Medical Domain</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.20288</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.20288v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We explore the potential of Large Language Models (LLMs) to assist and potentially correct physicians in medical decision-making tasks. We evaluate several LLMs, including Meditron, Llama2, and Mistral, to analyze the ability of these models to interact effectively with physicians across different scenarios. We consider questions from PubMedQA and several tasks, ranging from binary (yes/no) responses to long answer generation, where the answer of the model is produced after an interaction with a physician. Our findings suggest that prompt design significantly influences the downstream accuracy of LLMs and that LLMs can provide valuable feedback to physicians, challenging incorrect diagnoses and contributing to more accurate decision-making. For example, when the physician is accurate 38% of the time, Mistral can produce the correct answer, improving accuracy up to 74% depending on the prompt being used, while Llama2 and Meditron models exhibit greater sensitivity to prompt choice. Our analysis also uncovers the challenges of ensuring that LLM-generated suggestions are pertinent and useful, emphasizing the need for further research in this area.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.20288v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Burcu Sayin, Pasquale Minervini, Jacopo Staiano, Andrea Passerini</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Concept -- An Evaluation Protocol on Conversational Recommender Systems with System-centric and User-centric Factors</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03304</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03304v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The conversational recommendation system (CRS) has been criticized regarding its user experience in real-world scenarios, despite recent significant progress achieved in academia. Existing evaluation protocols for CRS may prioritize system-centric factors such as effectiveness and fluency in conversation while neglecting user-centric aspects. Thus, we propose a new and inclusive evaluation protocol, Concept, which integrates both system- and user-centric factors. We conceptualise three key characteristics in representing such factors and further divide them into six primary abilities. To implement Concept, we adopt a LLM-based user simulator and evaluator with scoring rubrics that are tailored for each primary ability. Our protocol, Concept, serves a dual purpose. First, it provides an overview of the pros and cons in current CRS models. Second, it pinpoints the problem of low usability in the "omnipotent" ChatGPT and offers a comprehensive reference guide for evaluating CRS, thereby setting the foundation for CRS improvement.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03304v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chen Huang, Peixin Qin, Yang Deng, Wenqiang Lei, Jiancheng Lv, Tat-Seng Chua</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Explore to Avoid the Pit: Improving the Reasoning Capabilities of Language Models with Fine-grained Rewards</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.10346</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.10346v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Training on large amounts of rationales (i.e., CoT Fine-tuning) is effective at improving the reasoning capabilities of large language models (LLMs). However, acquiring human-authored rationales or augmenting rationales from proprietary models is costly and not scalable. In this paper, we study the problem of whether LLMs could self-improve their reasoning capabilities. To this end, we propose Self-Explore, where the LLM is tasked to explore the first wrong step (i.e., the first pit) within the rationale and use such signals as fine-grained rewards for further improvement. On the GSM8K and MATH test set, Self-Explore achieves 11.57% and 2.89% improvement on average across three LLMs compared to supervised fine-tuning (SFT). Our code is available at https://github.com/hbin0701/Self-Explore.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.10346v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hyeonbin Hwang, Doyoung Kim, Seungone Kim, Seonghyeon Ye, Minjoon Seo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehensive Survey on Evaluating Large Language Model Applications in the Medical Industry</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15777</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15777v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Since the inception of the Transformer architecture in 2017, Large Language Models (LLMs) such as GPT and BERT have evolved significantly, impacting various industries with their advanced capabilities in language understanding and generation. These models have shown potential to transform the medical field, highlighting the necessity for specialized evaluation frameworks to ensure their effective and ethical deployment. This comprehensive survey delineates the extensive application and requisite evaluation of LLMs within healthcare, emphasizing the critical need for empirical validation to fully exploit their capabilities in enhancing healthcare outcomes.
  Our survey is structured to provide an in-depth analysis of LLM applications across clinical settings, medical text data processing, research, education, and public health awareness. We begin by exploring the roles of LLMs in different medical applications, detailing how they are evaluated based on their performance in tasks such as clinical application, medical text data processing, information retrieval, data analysis, medical scientific writing, educational content generation etc. The subsequent sections delve into the methodologies employed in these evaluations, discussing the benchmarks and metrics used to assess the models' effectiveness, accuracy, and ethical alignment.
  Through this survey, we aim to equip healthcare professionals, researchers, and policymakers with a comprehensive understanding of the potential strengths and limitations of LLMs in medical applications. By providing detailed insights into the evaluation processes and the challenges faced in integrating LLMs into healthcare, this survey seeks to guide the responsible development and deployment of these powerful models, ensuring they are harnessed to their full potential while maintaining stringent ethical standards.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15777v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yining Huang, Keke Tang, Meilian Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PatentGPT: A Large Language Model for Intellectual Property</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.18255</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.18255v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In recent years, large language models have attracted significant attention due to their exceptional performance across a multitude of natural language process tasks, and have been widely applied in various fields. However, the application of large language models in the Intellectual Property (IP) space is challenging due to the strong need for specialized knowledge, privacy protection, processing of extremely long text in this field. In this technical report, we present for the first time a low-cost, standardized procedure for training IP-oriented LLMs, meeting the unique requirements of the IP domain. Using this standard process, we have trained the PatentGPT series models based on open-source pretrained models. By evaluating them on the open-source IP-oriented benchmark MOZIP, our domain-specific LLMs outperforms GPT-4, indicating the effectiveness of the proposed training procedure and the expertise of the PatentGPT models in the IP demain. What is impressive is that our model significantly outperformed GPT-4 on the 2019 China Patent Agent Qualification Examination by achieving a score of 65, reaching the level of human experts. Additionally, the PatentGPT model, which utilizes the SMoE architecture, achieves performance comparable to that of GPT-4 in the IP domain and demonstrates a better cost-performance ratio on long-text tasks, potentially serving as an alternative to GPT-4 within the IP domain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.18255v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zilong Bai, Ruiji Zhang, Linqing Chen, Qijun Cai, Yuan Zhong, Cong Wang, Yan Fang, Jie Fang, Jing Sun, Weikuan Wang, Lizhi Zhou, Haoran Hua, Tian Qiu, Chaochao Wang, Cheng Sun, Jianping Lu, Yixin Wang, Yubin Xia, Meng Hu, Haowen Liu, Peng Xu, Licong Xu, Fu Bian, Xiaolong Gu, Lisha Zhang, Weilei Wang, Changyang Tu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automated Generation of High-Quality Medical Simulation Scenarios Through Integration of Semi-Structured Data and Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.19713</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.19713v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This study introduces a transformative framework for medical education by integrating semi-structured data with Large Language Models (LLMs), primarily OpenAIs ChatGPT3.5, to automate the creation of medical simulation scenarios. Traditionally, developing these scenarios was a time-intensive process with limited flexibility to meet diverse educational needs. The proposed approach utilizes AI to efficiently generate detailed, clinically relevant scenarios that are tailored to specific educational objectives. This innovation has significantly reduced the time and resources required for scenario development, allowing for a broader variety of simulations. Preliminary feedback from educators and learners has shown enhanced engagement and improved knowledge acquisition, confirming the effectiveness of this AI-enhanced methodology in simulation-based learning. The integration of structured data with LLMs not only streamlines the creation process but also offers a scalable, dynamic solution that could revolutionize medical training, highlighting the critical role of AI in advancing educational outcomes and patient care standards.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.19713v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Scott Sumpter</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"Ask Me Anything": How Comcast Uses LLMs to Assist Agents in Real Time</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.00801</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.00801v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Customer service is how companies interface with their customers. It can contribute heavily towards the overall customer satisfaction. However, high-quality service can become expensive, creating an incentive to make it as cost efficient as possible and prompting most companies to utilize AI-powered assistants, or "chat bots". On the other hand, human-to-human interaction is still desired by customers, especially when it comes to complex scenarios such as disputes and sensitive topics like bill payment.
  This raises the bar for customer service agents. They need to accurately understand the customer's question or concern, identify a solution that is acceptable yet feasible (and within the company's policy), all while handling multiple conversations at once.
  In this work, we introduce "Ask Me Anything" (AMA) as an add-on feature to an agent-facing customer service interface. AMA allows agents to ask questions to a large language model (LLM) on demand, as they are handling customer conversations -- the LLM provides accurate responses in real-time, reducing the amount of context switching the agent needs. In our internal experiments, we find that agents using AMA versus a traditional search experience spend approximately 10% fewer seconds per conversation containing a search, translating to millions of dollars of savings annually. Agents that used the AMA feature provided positive feedback nearly 80% of the time, demonstrating its usefulness as an AI-assisted feature for customer care.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.00801v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3626772.3661345</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Scott Rome, Tianwen Chen, Raphael Tang, Luwei Zhou, Ferhan Ture</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A quantitative and typological study of Early Slavic participle clauses and their competition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.01972</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.01972v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This thesis is a corpus-based, quantitative, and typological analysis of the functions of Early Slavic participle constructions and their finite competitors ($jegda$-'when'-clauses). The first part leverages detailed linguistic annotation on Early Slavic corpora at the morphosyntactic, dependency, information-structural, and lexical levels to obtain indirect evidence for different potential functions of participle clauses and their main finite competitor and understand the roles of compositionality and default discourse reasoning as explanations for the distribution of participle constructions and $jegda$-clauses in the corpus. The second part uses massively parallel data to analyze typological variation in how languages express the semantic space of English $when$, whose scope encompasses that of Early Slavic participle constructions and $jegda$-clauses. Probabilistic semantic maps are generated and statistical methods (including Kriging, Gaussian Mixture Modelling, precision and recall analysis) are used to induce cross-linguistically salient dimensions from the parallel corpus and to study conceptual variation within the semantic space of the hypothetical concept WHEN.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.01972v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.5287/ora-8gv0b4qyo</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Nilo Pedrazzini</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Brain Signals Reveal Inner Alignment with Human Languages?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2208.06348</link>
      <description>arXiv:2208.06348v5 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Brain Signals, such as Electroencephalography (EEG), and human languages have been widely explored independently for many downstream tasks, however, the connection between them has not been well explored. In this study, we explore the relationship and dependency between EEG and language. To study at the representation level, we introduced \textbf{MTAM}, a \textbf{M}ultimodal \textbf{T}ransformer \textbf{A}lignment \textbf{M}odel, to observe coordinated representations between the two modalities. We used various relationship alignment-seeking techniques, such as Canonical Correlation Analysis and Wasserstein Distance, as loss functions to transfigure features. On downstream applications, sentiment analysis and relation detection, we achieved new state-of-the-art results on two datasets, ZuCo and K-EmoCon. Our method achieved an F1-score improvement of 1.7% on K-EmoCon and 9.3% on Zuco datasets for sentiment analysis, and 7.4% on ZuCo for relation detection. In addition, we provide interpretations of the performance improvement: (1) feature distribution shows the effectiveness of the alignment module for discovering and encoding the relationship between EEG and language; (2) alignment weights show the influence of different language semantics as well as EEG frequency features; (3) brain topographical maps provide an intuitive demonstration of the connectivity in the brain regions. Our code is available at \url{https://github.com/Jason-Qiu/EEG_Language_Alignment}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2208.06348v5</guid>
      <category>q-bio.NC</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>William Han, Jielin Qiu, Jiacheng Zhu, Mengdi Xu, Douglas Weber, Bo Li, Ding Zhao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing And Editing Inner Mechanisms Of Backdoored Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2302.12461</link>
      <description>arXiv:2302.12461v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Poisoning of data sets is a potential security threat to large language models that can lead to backdoored models. A description of the internal mechanisms of backdoored language models and how they process trigger inputs, e.g., when switching to toxic language, has yet to be found. In this work, we study the internal representations of transformer-based backdoored language models and determine early-layer MLP modules as most important for the backdoor mechanism in combination with the initial embedding projection. We use this knowledge to remove, insert, and modify backdoor mechanisms with engineered replacements that reduce the MLP module outputs to essentials for the backdoor mechanism. To this end, we introduce PCP ablation, where we replace transformer modules with low-rank matrices based on the principal components of their activations. We demonstrate our results on backdoored toy, backdoored large, and non-backdoored open-source models. We show that we can improve the backdoor robustness of large language models by locally constraining individual modules during fine-tuning on potentially poisonous data sets.
  Trigger warning: Offensive language.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2302.12461v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3630106.3659042</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>The 2024 ACM Conference on Fairness, Accountability, and Transparency (FAccT 24), June 3-6, 2024, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Max Lamparth, Anka Reuel</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fairness of ChatGPT</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2305.18569</link>
      <description>arXiv:2305.18569v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Understanding and addressing unfairness in LLMs are crucial for responsible AI deployment. However, there is a limited number of quantitative analyses and in-depth studies regarding fairness evaluations in LLMs, especially when applying LLMs to high-stakes fields. This work aims to fill this gap by providing a systematic evaluation of the effectiveness and fairness of LLMs using ChatGPT as a study case. We focus on assessing ChatGPT's performance in high-takes fields including education, criminology, finance and healthcare. To conduct a thorough evaluation, we consider both group fairness and individual fairness metrics. We also observe the disparities in ChatGPT's outputs under a set of biased or unbiased prompts. This work contributes to a deeper understanding of LLMs' fairness performance, facilitates bias mitigation and fosters the development of responsible AI systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2305.18569v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yunqi Li, Lanjing Zhang, Yongfeng Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PLMM: Personal Large Language Models on Mobile Devices</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2309.14726</link>
      <description>arXiv:2309.14726v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Inspired by Federated Learning, in this paper, we propose personal large models that are distilled from traditional large language models but more adaptive to local users' personal information such as education background and hobbies. We classify the large language models into three levels: the personal level, expert level and traditional level. The personal level models are adaptive to users' personal information. They encrypt the users' input and protect their privacy. The expert level models focus on merging specific knowledge such as finance, IT and art. The traditional models focus on the universal knowledge discovery and upgrading the expert models. In such classifications, the personal models directly interact with the user. For the whole system, the personal models have users' (encrypted) personal information. Moreover, such models must be small enough to be performed on personal computers or mobile devices. Finally, they also have to response in real-time for better user experience and produce high quality results. The proposed personal large models can be applied in a wide range of applications such as language and vision tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2309.14726v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CE</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuanhao Gong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM-grounded Video Diffusion Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2309.17444</link>
      <description>arXiv:2309.17444v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Text-conditioned diffusion models have emerged as a promising tool for neural video generation. However, current models still struggle with intricate spatiotemporal prompts and often generate restricted or incorrect motion. To address these limitations, we introduce LLM-grounded Video Diffusion (LVD). Instead of directly generating videos from the text inputs, LVD first leverages a large language model (LLM) to generate dynamic scene layouts based on the text inputs and subsequently uses the generated layouts to guide a diffusion model for video generation. We show that LLMs are able to understand complex spatiotemporal dynamics from text alone and generate layouts that align closely with both the prompts and the object motion patterns typically observed in the real world. We then propose to guide video diffusion models with these layouts by adjusting the attention maps. Our approach is training-free and can be integrated into any video diffusion model that admits classifier guidance. Our results demonstrate that LVD significantly outperforms its base video diffusion model and several strong baseline methods in faithfully generating videos with the desired attributes and motion patterns.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2309.17444v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Long Lian, Baifeng Shi, Adam Yala, Trevor Darrell, Boyi Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jailbreak and Guard Aligned Language Models with Only Few In-Context Demonstrations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.06387</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.06387v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have shown remarkable success in various tasks, but concerns about their safety and the potential for generating harmful content have emerged. In this paper, we delve into the potential of In-Context Learning (ICL) to modulate the alignment of LLMs. Specifically, we propose the In-Context Attack (ICA), which employs strategically crafted harmful demonstrations to subvert LLMs, and the In-Context Defense (ICD), which bolsters model resilience through examples that demonstrate refusal to produce harmful responses. Through extensive experiments, we demonstrate the efficacy of ICA and ICD in respectively elevating and mitigating the success rates of jailbreaking prompts. Moreover, we offer theoretical insights into the mechanism by which a limited set of in-context demonstrations can pivotally influence the safety alignment of LLMs. Our findings illuminate the profound influence of ICL on LLM behavior, opening new avenues for improving the safety and alignment of LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.06387v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zeming Wei, Yifei Wang, Yisen Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frozen Transformers in Language Models Are Effective Visual Encoder Layers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.12973</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.12973v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: This paper reveals that large language models (LLMs), despite being trained solely on textual data, are surprisingly strong encoders for purely visual tasks in the absence of language. Even more intriguingly, this can be achieved by a simple yet previously overlooked strategy -- employing a frozen transformer block from pre-trained LLMs as a constituent encoder layer to directly process visual tokens. Our work pushes the boundaries of leveraging LLMs for computer vision tasks, significantly departing from conventional practices that typically necessitate a multi-modal vision-language setup with associated language prompts, inputs, or outputs. We demonstrate that our approach consistently enhances performance across a diverse range of tasks, encompassing pure 2D and 3D visual recognition tasks (e.g., image and point cloud classification), temporal modeling tasks (e.g., action recognition), non-semantic tasks (e.g., motion forecasting), and multi-modal tasks (e.g., 2D/3D visual question answering and image-text retrieval). Such improvements are a general phenomenon, applicable to various types of LLMs (e.g., LLaMA and OPT) and different LLM transformer blocks. We additionally propose the information filtering hypothesis to explain the effectiveness of pre-trained LLMs in visual encoding -- the pre-trained LLM transformer blocks discern informative visual tokens and further amplify their effect. This hypothesis is empirically supported by the observation that the feature activation, after training with LLM transformer blocks, exhibits a stronger focus on relevant regions. We hope that our work inspires new perspectives on utilizing LLMs and deepening our understanding of their underlying mechanisms. Code is available at https://github.com/ziqipang/LM4VisualEncoding.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.12973v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ziqi Pang, Ziyang Xie, Yunze Man, Yu-Xiong Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How do Language Models Bind Entities in Context?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.17191</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.17191v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: To correctly use in-context information, language models (LMs) must bind entities to their attributes. For example, given a context describing a "green square" and a "blue circle", LMs must bind the shapes to their respective colors. We analyze LM representations and identify the binding ID mechanism: a general mechanism for solving the binding problem, which we observe in every sufficiently large model from the Pythia and LLaMA families. Using causal interventions, we show that LMs' internal activations represent binding information by attaching binding ID vectors to corresponding entities and attributes. We further show that binding ID vectors form a continuous subspace, in which distances between binding ID vectors reflect their discernability. Overall, our results uncover interpretable strategies in LMs for representing symbolic knowledge in-context, providing a step towards understanding general in-context reasoning in large-scale LMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.17191v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiahai Feng, Jacob Steinhardt</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>QualEval: Qualitative Evaluation for Model Improvement</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.02807</link>
      <description>arXiv:2311.02807v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Quantitative evaluation metrics have traditionally been pivotal in gauging the advancements of artificial intelligence systems, including large language models (LLMs). However, these metrics have inherent limitations. Given the intricate nature of real-world tasks, a single scalar to quantify and compare is insufficient to capture the fine-grained nuances of model behavior. Metrics serve only as a way to compare and benchmark models, and do not yield actionable diagnostics, thus making the model improvement process challenging. Model developers find themselves amid extensive manual efforts involving sifting through vast datasets and attempting hit-or-miss adjustments to training data or setups. In this work, we address the shortcomings of quantitative metrics by proposing QualEval, which augments quantitative scalar metrics with automated qualitative evaluation as a vehicle for model improvement. QualEval uses a powerful LLM reasoner and our novel flexible linear programming solver to generate human-readable insights that when applied, accelerate model improvement. The insights are backed by a comprehensive dashboard with fine-grained visualizations and human-interpretable analyses. We corroborate the faithfulness of QualEval by demonstrating that leveraging its insights, for example, improves the absolute performance of the Llama 2 model by up to 15% points relative on a challenging dialogue task (DialogSum) when compared to baselines. QualEval successfully increases the pace of model development, thus in essence serving as a data-scientist-in-a-box. Given the focus on critiquing and improving current evaluation metrics, our method serves as a refreshingly new technique for both model evaluation and improvement.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2311.02807v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Vishvak Murahari, Ameet Deshpande, Peter Clark, Tanmay Rajpurohit, Ashish Sabharwal, Karthik Narasimhan, Ashwin Kalyan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GPT-4V(ision) for Robotics: Multimodal Task Planning from Human Demonstration</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.12015</link>
      <description>arXiv:2311.12015v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We introduce a pipeline that enhances a general-purpose Vision Language Model, GPT-4V(ision), to facilitate one-shot visual teaching for robotic manipulation. This system analyzes videos of humans performing tasks and outputs executable robot programs that incorporate insights into affordances. The process begins with GPT-4V analyzing the videos to obtain textual explanations of environmental and action details. A GPT-4-based task planner then encodes these details into a symbolic task plan. Subsequently, vision systems spatially and temporally ground the task plan in the videos. Object are identified using an open-vocabulary object detector, and hand-object interactions are analyzed to pinpoint moments of grasping and releasing. This spatiotemporal grounding allows for the gathering of affordance information (e.g., grasp types, waypoints, and body postures) critical for robot execution. Experiments across various scenarios demonstrate the method's efficacy in achieving real robots' operations from human demonstrations in a one-shot manner. Meanwhile, quantitative tests have revealed instances of hallucination in GPT-4V, highlighting the importance of incorporating human supervision within the pipeline. The prompts of GPT-4V/GPT-4 are available at this project page:</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2311.12015v2</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Naoki Wake, Atsushi Kanehira, Kazuhiro Sasabuchi, Jun Takamatsu, Katsushi Ikeuchi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DoraemonGPT: Toward Understanding Dynamic Scenes with Large Language Models (Exemplified as A Video Agent)</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.08392</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.08392v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Recent LLM-driven visual agents mainly focus on solving image-based tasks, which limits their ability to understand dynamic scenes, making it far from real-life applications like guiding students in laboratory experiments and identifying their mistakes. Hence, this paper explores DoraemonGPT, a comprehensive and conceptually elegant system driven by LLMs to understand dynamic scenes. Considering the video modality better reflects the ever-changing nature of real-world scenarios, we exemplify DoraemonGPT as a video agent. Given a video with a question/task, DoraemonGPT begins by converting the input video into a symbolic memory that stores task-related attributes. This structured representation allows for spatial-temporal querying and reasoning by well-designed sub-task tools, resulting in concise intermediate results. Recognizing that LLMs have limited internal knowledge when it comes to specialized domains (e.g., analyzing the scientific principles underlying experiments), we incorporate plug-and-play tools to assess external knowledge and address tasks across different domains. Moreover, a novel LLM-driven planner based on Monte Carlo Tree Search is introduced to explore the large planning space for scheduling various tools. The planner iteratively finds feasible solutions by backpropagating the result's reward, and multiple solutions can be summarized into an improved final answer. We extensively evaluate DoraemonGPT's effectiveness on three benchmarks and several in-the-wild scenarios. The code will be released at https://github.com/z-x-yang/DoraemonGPT.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.08392v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zongxin Yang, Guikun Chen, Xiaodi Li, Wenguan Wang, Yi Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Survey on Hallucination in Large Vision-Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.00253</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.00253v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Recent development of Large Vision-Language Models (LVLMs) has attracted growing attention within the AI landscape for its practical implementation potential. However, ``hallucination'', or more specifically, the misalignment between factual visual content and corresponding textual generation, poses a significant challenge of utilizing LVLMs. In this comprehensive survey, we dissect LVLM-related hallucinations in an attempt to establish an overview and facilitate future mitigation. Our scrutiny starts with a clarification of the concept of hallucinations in LVLMs, presenting a variety of hallucination symptoms and highlighting the unique challenges inherent in LVLM hallucinations. Subsequently, we outline the benchmarks and methodologies tailored specifically for evaluating hallucinations unique to LVLMs. Additionally, we delve into an investigation of the root causes of these hallucinations, encompassing insights from the training data and model components. We also critically review existing methods for mitigating hallucinations. The open questions and future directions pertaining to hallucinations within LVLMs are discussed to conclude this survey.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.00253v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hanchao Liu, Wenyuan Xue, Yifei Chen, Dapeng Chen, Xiutian Zhao, Ke Wang, Liping Hou, Rongjun Li, Wei Peng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Increasing Trust in Language Models through the Reuse of Verified Circuits</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.02619</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.02619v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Language Models (LMs) are increasingly used for a wide range of prediction tasks, but their training can often neglect rare edge cases, reducing their reliability. Here, we define a stringent standard of trustworthiness whereby the task algorithm and circuit implementation must be verified, accounting for edge cases, with no known failure modes. We show that a transformer model can be trained to meet this standard if built using mathematically and logically specified frameworks. In this paper, we fully verify a model for n-digit integer addition. To exhibit the reusability of verified modules, we insert the trained integer addition model into an untrained model and train the combined model to perform both addition and subtraction. We find extensive reuse of the addition circuits for both tasks, easing verification of the more complex subtractor model. We discuss how inserting verified task modules into LMs can leverage model reuse to improve verifiability and trustworthiness of language models built using them. The reuse of verified circuits reduces the effort to verify more complex composite models which we believe to be a significant step towards safety of language models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.02619v4</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Philip Quirke, Clement Neo, Fazl Barez</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open-ended VQA benchmarking of Vision-Language models by exploiting Classification datasets and their semantic hierarchy</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.07270</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.07270v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The evaluation of text-generative vision-language models is a challenging yet crucial endeavor. By addressing the limitations of existing Visual Question Answering (VQA) benchmarks and proposing innovative evaluation methodologies, our research seeks to advance our understanding of these models' capabilities. We propose a novel VQA benchmark based on well-known visual classification datasets which allows a granular evaluation of text-generative vision-language models and their comparison with discriminative vision-language models. To improve the assessment of coarse answers on fine-grained classification tasks, we suggest using the semantic hierarchy of the label space to ask automatically generated follow-up questions about the ground-truth category. Finally, we compare traditional NLP and LLM-based metrics for the problem of evaluating model predictions given ground-truth answers. We perform a human evaluation study upon which we base our decision on the final metric. We apply our benchmark to a suite of vision-language models and show a detailed comparison of their abilities on object, action, and attribute classification. Our contributions aim to lay the foundation for more precise and meaningful assessments, facilitating targeted progress in the exciting field of vision-language modeling.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.07270v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Simon Ging, Mar\'ia A. Bravo, Thomas Brox</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emoji Driven Crypto Assets Market Reactions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.10481</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.10481v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In the burgeoning realm of cryptocurrency, social media platforms like Twitter have become pivotal in influencing market trends and investor sentiments. In our study, we leverage GPT-4 and a fine-tuned transformer-based BERT model for a multimodal sentiment analysis, focusing on the impact of emoji sentiment on cryptocurrency markets. By translating emojis into quantifiable sentiment data, we correlate these insights with key market indicators like BTC Price and the VCRIX index. Our architecture's analysis of emoji sentiment demonstrated a distinct advantage over FinBERT's pure text sentiment analysis in such predicting power. This approach may be fed into the development of trading strategies aimed at utilizing social media elements to identify and forecast market trends. Crucially, our findings suggest that strategies based on emoji sentiment can facilitate the avoidance of significant market downturns and contribute to the stabilization of returns. This research underscores the practical benefits of integrating advanced AI-driven analyses into financial strategies, offering a nuanced perspective on the interplay between digital communication and market dynamics in an academic context.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.10481v2</guid>
      <category>q-fin.CP</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>q-fin.ST</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaorui Zuo, Yao-Tsung Chen, Wolfgang Karl H\"ardle</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wisdom of the Silicon Crowd: LLM Ensemble Prediction Capabilities Rival Human Crowd Accuracy</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.19379</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.19379v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Human forecasting accuracy in practice relies on the 'wisdom of the crowd' effect, in which predictions about future events are significantly improved by aggregating across a crowd of individual forecasters. Past work on the forecasting ability of large language models (LLMs) suggests that frontier LLMs, as individual forecasters, underperform compared to the gold standard of a human crowd forecasting tournament aggregate. In Study 1, we expand this research by using an LLM ensemble approach consisting of a crowd of twelve LLMs. We compare the aggregated LLM predictions on 31 binary questions to that of a crowd of 925 human forecasters from a three-month forecasting tournament. Our preregistered main analysis shows that the LLM crowd outperforms a simple no-information benchmark and is not statistically different from the human crowd. In exploratory analyses, we find that these two approaches are equivalent with respect to medium-effect-size equivalence bounds. We also observe an acquiescence effect, with mean model predictions being significantly above 50%, despite an almost even split of positive and negative resolutions. Moreover, in Study 2, we test whether LLM predictions (of GPT-4 and Claude 2) can be improved by drawing on human cognitive output. We find that both models' forecasting accuracy benefits from exposure to the median human prediction as information, improving accuracy by between 17% and 28%: though this leads to less accurate predictions than simply averaging human and machine forecasts. Our results suggest that LLMs can achieve forecasting accuracy rivaling that of human crowd forecasting tournaments: via the simple, practically applicable method of forecast aggregation. This replicates the 'wisdom of the crowd' effect for LLMs, and opens up their use for a variety of applications throughout society.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.19379v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Philipp Schoenegger, Indre Tuminauskaite, Peter S. Park, Philip E. Tetlock</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EAMA : Entity-Aware Multimodal Alignment Based Approach for News Image Captioning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.19404</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.19404v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: News image captioning requires model to generate an informative caption rich in entities, with the news image and the associated news article. Though Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) have demonstrated remarkable capabilities in addressing various vision-language tasks, our research finds that current MLLMs still bear limitations in handling entity information on news image captioning task. Besides, while MLLMs have the ability to process long inputs, generating high-quality news image captions still requires a trade-off between sufficiency and conciseness of textual input information. To explore the potential of MLLMs and address problems we discovered, we propose : an Entity-Aware Multimodal Alignment based approach for news image captioning. Our approach first aligns the MLLM through Balance Training Strategy with two extra alignment tasks: Entity-Aware Sentence Selection task and Entity Selection task, together with News Image Captioning task, to enhance its capability in handling multimodal entity information. The aligned MLLM will utilizes the additional entity-related information it explicitly extracts to supplement its textual input while generating news image captions. Our approach achieves better results than all previous models in CIDEr score on GoodNews dataset (72.33 -&gt; 88.39) and NYTimes800k dataset (70.83 -&gt; 85.61).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.19404v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junzhe Zhang, Huixuan Zhang, Xunjian Yin, Xiaojun Wan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Compressibility of Quantized Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.01384</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.01384v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Deploying Large Language Models (LLMs) on edge or mobile devices offers significant benefits, such as enhanced data privacy and real-time processing capabilities. However, it also faces critical challenges due to the substantial memory requirement of LLMs. Quantization is an effective way of reducing the model size while maintaining good performance. However, even after quantization, LLMs may still be too big to fit entirely into the limited memory of edge or mobile devices and have to be partially loaded from the storage to complete the inference. In this case, the I/O latency of model loading becomes the bottleneck of the LLM inference latency. In this work, we take a preliminary step of studying applying data compression techniques to reduce data movement and thus speed up the inference of quantized LLM on memory-constrained devices. In particular, we discussed the compressibility of quantized LLMs, the trade-off between the compressibility and performance of quantized LLMs, and opportunities to optimize both of them jointly.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.01384v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yu Mao, Weilan Wang, Hongchao Du, Nan Guan, Chun Jason Xue</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating and Optimizing Educational Content with Large Language Model Judgments</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.02795</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.02795v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Creating effective educational materials generally requires expensive and time-consuming studies of student learning outcomes. To overcome this barrier, one idea is to build computational models of student learning and use them to optimize instructional materials. However, it is difficult to model the cognitive processes of learning dynamics. We propose an alternative approach that uses Language Models (LMs) as educational experts to assess the impact of various instructions on learning outcomes. Specifically, we use GPT-3.5 to evaluate the overall effect of instructional materials on different student groups and find that it can replicate well-established educational findings such as the Expertise Reversal Effect and the Variability Effect. This demonstrates the potential of LMs as reliable evaluators of educational content. Building on this insight, we introduce an instruction optimization approach in which one LM generates instructional materials using the judgments of another LM as a reward function. We apply this approach to create math word problem worksheets aimed at maximizing student learning gains. Human teachers' evaluations of these LM-generated worksheets show a significant alignment between the LM judgments and human teacher preferences. We conclude by discussing potential divergences between human and LM opinions and the resulting pitfalls of automating instructional design.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.02795v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Joy He-Yueya, Noah D. Goodman, Emma Brunskill</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FollowIR: Evaluating and Teaching Information Retrieval Models to Follow Instructions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.15246</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.15246v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Modern Language Models (LMs) are capable of following long and complex instructions that enable a large and diverse set of user requests. While Information Retrieval (IR) models use these LMs as the backbone of their architectures, virtually none of them allow users to provide detailed instructions alongside queries, thus limiting their ability to satisfy complex information needs. In this work, we study the use of instructions in IR systems. First, we introduce our dataset FollowIR, which contains a rigorous instruction evaluation benchmark as well as a training set for helping IR models learn to better follow real-world instructions. FollowIR repurposes detailed instructions -- also known as narratives -- developed for professional assessors to evaluate retrieval systems. In particular, we build our benchmark from three collections curated for shared tasks at the Text REtrieval Conference (TREC). These collections contains hundreds to thousands of labeled documents per query, making them suitable for our exploration. Through this process, we can measure how well IR models follow instructions, through a new pairwise evaluation framework. Our results indicate that existing retrieval models fail to correctly use instructions, using them for basic keywords and struggling to understand long-form information. However, we show that it is possible for IR models to learn to follow complex instructions: our new FollowIR-7B model has significant improvements after fine-tuning on our training set.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.15246v2</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Orion Weller, Benjamin Chang, Sean MacAvaney, Kyle Lo, Arman Cohan, Benjamin Van Durme, Dawn Lawrie, Luca Soldaini</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AC4: Algebraic Computation Checker for Circuit Constraints in ZKPs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.15676</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.15676v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: ZKP systems have surged attention and held a fundamental role in contemporary cryptography. Zk-SNARK protocols dominate the ZKP usage, often implemented through arithmetic circuit programming paradigm. However, underconstrained or overconstrained circuits may lead to bugs. Underconstrained circuits refer to circuits that lack the necessary constraints, resulting in unexpected solutions in the circuit and causing the verifier to accept a bogus witness. Overconstrained circuits refer to circuits that are constrained excessively, resulting in the circuit lacking necessary solutions and causing the verifier to accept no witness, rendering the circuit meaningless. This paper introduces a novel approach for pinpointing two distinct types of bugs in ZKP circuits. The method involves encoding the arithmetic circuit constraints to polynomial equation systems and solving polynomial equation systems over a finite field by algebraic computation. The classification of verification results is refined, greatly enhancing the expressive power of the system. We proposed a tool, AC4, to represent the implementation of this method. Experiments demonstrate that AC4 represents a substantial 29% increase in the checked ratio compared to prior work. Within a solvable range, the checking time of AC4 has also exhibited noticeable improvement, demonstrating a magnitude increase compared to previous efforts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.15676v2</guid>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hao Chen, Minyu Chen, Ruibang Liu, Guoqiang Li, Sinka Gao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploiting Semantic Reconstruction to Mitigate Hallucinations in Vision-Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.16167</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.16167v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Hallucinations in vision-language models pose a significant challenge to their reliability, particularly in the generation of long captions. Current methods fall short of accurately identifying and mitigating these hallucinations. To address this issue, we introduce ESREAL, a novel unsupervised learning framework designed to suppress the generation of hallucinations through accurate localization and penalization of hallucinated tokens. Initially, ESREAL creates a reconstructed image based on the generated caption and aligns its corresponding regions with those of the original image. This semantic reconstruction aids in identifying both the presence and type of token-level hallucinations within the generated caption. Subsequently, ESREAL computes token-level hallucination scores by assessing the semantic similarity of aligned regions based on the type of hallucination. Finally, ESREAL employs a proximal policy optimization algorithm, where it selectively penalizes hallucinated tokens according to their token-level hallucination scores. Our framework notably reduces hallucinations in LLaVA, InstructBLIP, and mPLUG-Owl2 by 32.81%, 27.08%, and 7.46% on the CHAIR metric. This improvement is achieved solely through signals derived from the image itself, without the need for any image-text pairs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.16167v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Minchan Kim, Minyeong Kim, Junik Bae, Suhwan Choi, Sungkyung Kim, Buru Chang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BLINK: Multimodal Large Language Models Can See but Not Perceive</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.12390</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.12390v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We introduce Blink, a new benchmark for multimodal language models (LLMs) that focuses on core visual perception abilities not found in other evaluations. Most of the Blink tasks can be solved by humans "within a blink" (e.g., relative depth estimation, visual correspondence, forensics detection, and multi-view reasoning). However, we find these perception-demanding tasks cast significant challenges for current multimodal LLMs because they resist mediation through natural language. Blink reformats 14 classic computer vision tasks into 3,807 multiple-choice questions, paired with single or multiple images and visual prompting. While humans get 95.70% accuracy on average, Blink is surprisingly challenging for existing multimodal LLMs: even the best-performing GPT-4V and Gemini achieve accuracies of 51.26% and 45.72%, only 13.17% and 7.63% higher than random guessing, indicating that such perception abilities have not "emerged" yet in recent multimodal LLMs. Our analysis also highlights that specialist CV models could solve these problems much better, suggesting potential pathways for future improvements. We believe Blink will stimulate the community to help multimodal LLMs catch up with human-level visual perception.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.12390v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xingyu Fu, Yushi Hu, Bangzheng Li, Yu Feng, Haoyu Wang, Xudong Lin, Dan Roth, Noah A. Smith, Wei-Chiu Ma, Ranjay Krishna</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retrieval-Augmented Generation with Knowledge Graphs for Customer Service Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.17723</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.17723v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In customer service technical support, swiftly and accurately retrieving relevant past issues is critical for efficiently resolving customer inquiries. The conventional retrieval methods in retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) for large language models (LLMs) treat a large corpus of past issue tracking tickets as plain text, ignoring the crucial intra-issue structure and inter-issue relations, which limits performance. We introduce a novel customer service question-answering method that amalgamates RAG with a knowledge graph (KG). Our method constructs a KG from historical issues for use in retrieval, retaining the intra-issue structure and inter-issue relations. During the question-answering phase, our method parses consumer queries and retrieves related sub-graphs from the KG to generate answers. This integration of a KG not only improves retrieval accuracy by preserving customer service structure information but also enhances answering quality by mitigating the effects of text segmentation. Empirical assessments on our benchmark datasets, utilizing key retrieval (MRR, Recall@K, NDCG@K) and text generation (BLEU, ROUGE, METEOR) metrics, reveal that our method outperforms the baseline by 77.6% in MRR and by 0.32 in BLEU. Our method has been deployed within LinkedIn's customer service team for approximately six months and has reduced the median per-issue resolution time by 28.6%.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.17723v2</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3626772.3661370</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Zhentao Xu, Mark Jerome Cruz, Matthew Guevara, Tie Wang, Manasi Deshpande, Xiaofeng Wang, Zheng Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Incremental Learning in Large Language Models: A Critical Review</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.18311</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.18311v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Incremental learning is the ability of systems to acquire knowledge over time, enabling their adaptation and generalization to novel tasks. It is a critical ability for intelligent, real-world systems, especially when data changes frequently or is limited. This review provides a comprehensive analysis of incremental learning in Large Language Models. It synthesizes the state-of-the-art incremental learning paradigms, including continual learning, meta-learning, parameter-efficient learning, and mixture-of-experts learning. We demonstrate their utility for incremental learning by describing specific achievements from these related topics and their critical factors. An important finding is that many of these approaches do not update the core model, and none of them update incrementally in real-time. The paper highlights current problems and challenges for future research in the field. By consolidating the latest relevant research developments, this review offers a comprehensive understanding of incremental learning and its implications for designing and developing LLM-based learning systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.18311v4</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mladjan Jovanovic, Peter Voss</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling Caption Diversity in Contrastive Vision-Language Pretraining</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.00740</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.00740v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: There are a thousand ways to caption an image. Contrastive Language Pretraining (CLIP) on the other hand, works by mapping an image and its caption to a single vector -- limiting how well CLIP-like models can represent the diverse ways to describe an image. In this work, we introduce Llip, Latent Language Image Pretraining, which models the diversity of captions that could match an image. Llip's vision encoder outputs a set of visual features that are mixed into a final representation by conditioning on information derived from the text. We show that Llip outperforms non-contextualized baselines like CLIP and SigLIP on a variety of tasks even with large-scale encoders. Llip improves zero-shot classification by an average of 2.9% zero-shot classification benchmarks with a ViT-G/14 encoder. Specifically, Llip attains a zero-shot top-1 accuracy of 83.5% on ImageNet outperforming a similarly sized CLIP by 1.4%. We also demonstrate improvement on zero-shot retrieval on MS-COCO by 6.0%. We provide a comprehensive analysis of the components introduced by the method and demonstrate that Llip leads to richer visual representations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.00740v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Samuel Lavoie, Polina Kirichenko, Mark Ibrahim, Mahmoud Assran, Andrew Gordon Wildon, Aaron Courville, Nicolas Ballas</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Potential of LLM-Based ASR on Chinese Open-Source Datasets</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02132</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02132v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated unparalleled effectiveness in various NLP tasks, and integrating LLMs with automatic speech recognition (ASR) is becoming a mainstream paradigm. Building upon this momentum, our research delves into an in-depth examination of this paradigm on a large open-source Chinese dataset. Specifically, our research aims to evaluate the impact of various configurations of speech encoders, LLMs, and projector modules in the context of the speech foundation encoder-LLM ASR paradigm. Furthermore, we introduce a three-stage training approach, expressly developed to enhance the model's ability to align auditory and textual information. The implementation of this approach, alongside the strategic integration of ASR components, enabled us to achieve the SOTA performance on the AISHELL-1, Test_Net, and Test_Meeting test sets. Our analysis presents an empirical foundation for future research in LLM-based ASR systems and offers insights into optimizing performance using Chinese datasets. We will publicly release all scripts used for data preparation, training, inference, and scoring, as well as pre-trained models and training logs to promote reproducible research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02132v2</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xuelong Geng, Tianyi Xu, Kun Wei, Bingshen Mu, Hongfei Xue, He Wang, Yangze Li, Pengcheng Guo, Yuhang Dai, Longhao Li, Mingchen Shao, Lei Xie</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
