<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CV updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CV</link>
    <description>cs.CV updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CV" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 05:00:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Saturday</day>
      <day>Sunday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Archives: Using Large Language Models to Transcribe Handwritten Historical Documents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03340</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03340v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This study demonstrates that Large Language Models (LLMs) can transcribe historical handwritten documents with significantly higher accuracy than specialized Handwritten Text Recognition (HTR) software, while being faster and more cost-effective. We introduce an open-source software tool called Transcription Pearl that leverages these capabilities to automatically transcribe and correct batches of handwritten documents using commercially available multimodal LLMs from OpenAI, Anthropic, and Google. In tests on a diverse corpus of 18th/19th century English language handwritten documents, LLMs achieved Character Error Rates (CER) of 5.7 to 7% and Word Error Rates (WER) of 8.9 to 15.9%, improvements of 14% and 32% respectively over specialized state-of-the-art HTR software like Transkribus. Most significantly, when LLMs were then used to correct those transcriptions as well as texts generated by conventional HTR software, they achieved near-human levels of accuracy, that is CERs as low as 1.8% and WERs of 3.5%. The LLMs also completed these tasks 50 times faster and at approximately 1/50th the cost of proprietary HTR programs. These results demonstrate that when LLMs are incorporated into software tools like Transcription Pearl, they provide an accessible, fast, and highly accurate method for mass transcription of historical handwritten documents, significantly streamlining the digitization process.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03340v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.DL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mark Humphries, Lianne C. Leddy, Quinn Downton, Meredith Legace, John McConnell, Isabella Murray, Elizabeth Spence</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Calibrated Tuning of Vision-Language Models for Out-of-Distribution Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03359</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03359v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Out-of-distribution (OOD) detection is crucial for deploying reliable machine learning models in open-world applications. Recent advances in CLIP-based OOD detection have shown promising results via regularizing prompt tuning with OOD features extracted from ID data. However, the irrelevant context mined from ID data can be spurious due to the inaccurate foreground-background decomposition, thus limiting the OOD detection performance. In this work, we propose a novel framework, namely, Self-Calibrated Tuning (SCT), to mitigate this problem for effective OOD detection with only the given few-shot ID data. Specifically, SCT introduces modulating factors respectively on the two components of the original learning objective. It adaptively directs the optimization process between the two tasks during training on data with different prediction uncertainty to calibrate the influence of OOD regularization, which is compatible with many prompt tuning based OOD detection methods. Extensive experiments and analyses have been conducted to characterize and demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed SCT. The code is publicly available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03359v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Geng Yu, Jianing Zhu, Jiangchao Yao, Bo Han</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Maritime Situational Awareness through End-to-End Onboard Raw Data Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03403</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03403v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Satellite-based onboard data processing is crucial for time-sensitive applications requiring timely and efficient rapid response. Advances in edge artificial intelligence are shifting computational power from ground-based centers to on-orbit platforms, transforming the "sensing-communication-decision-feedback" cycle and reducing latency from acquisition to delivery. The current research presents a framework addressing the strict bandwidth, energy, and latency constraints of small satellites, focusing on maritime monitoring. The study contributes three main innovations. Firstly, it investigates the application of deep learning techniques for direct ship detection and classification from raw satellite imagery. By simplifying the onboard processing chain, our approach facilitates direct analyses without requiring computationally intensive steps such as calibration and ortho-rectification. Secondly, to address the scarcity of raw satellite data, we introduce two novel datasets, VDS2Raw and VDV2Raw, which are derived from raw data from Sentinel-2 and Vegetation and Environment Monitoring New Micro Satellite (VENuS) missions, respectively, and enriched with Automatic Identification System (AIS) records. Thirdly, we characterize the tasks' optimal single and multiple spectral band combinations through statistical and feature-based analyses validated on both datasets. In sum, we demonstrate the feasibility of the proposed method through a proof-of-concept on CubeSat-like hardware, confirming the models' potential for operational satellite-based maritime monitoring.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03403v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Roberto Del Prete, Manuel Salvoldi, Domenico Barretta, Nicolas Long\'ep\'e, Gabriele Meoni, Arnon Karnieli, Maria Daniela Graziano, Alfredo Renga</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fine-Grained Spatial and Verbal Losses for 3D Visual Grounding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03405</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03405v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: 3D visual grounding consists of identifying the instance in a 3D scene which is referred by an accompanying language description. While several architectures have been proposed within the commonly employed grounding-by-selection framework, the utilized losses are comparatively under-explored. In particular, most methods rely on a basic supervised cross-entropy loss on the predicted distribution over candidate instances, which fails to model both spatial relations between instances and the internal fine-grained word-level structure of the verbal referral. Sparse attempts to additionally supervise verbal embeddings globally by learning the class of the referred instance from the description or employing verbo-visual contrast to better separate instance embeddings do not fundamentally lift the aforementioned limitations. Responding to these shortcomings, we introduce two novel losses for 3D visual grounding: a visual-level offset loss on regressed vector offsets from each instance to the ground-truth referred instance and a language-related span loss on predictions for the word-level span of the referred instance in the description. In addition, we equip the verbo-visual fusion module of our new 3D visual grounding architecture AsphaltNet with a top-down bidirectional attentive fusion block, which enables the supervisory signals from our two losses to propagate to the respective converse branches of the network and thus aid the latter to learn context-aware instance embeddings and grounding-aware verbal embeddings. AsphaltNet proposes novel auxiliary losses to aid 3D visual grounding with competitive results compared to the state-of-the-art on the ReferIt3D benchmark.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03405v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sombit Dey, Ozan Unal, Christos Sakaridis, Luc Van Gool</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self Supervised Networks for Learning Latent Space Representations of Human Body Scans and Motions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03475</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03475v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper introduces self-supervised neural network models to tackle several fundamental problems in the field of 3D human body analysis and processing. First, we propose VariShaPE (Varifold Shape Parameter Estimator), a novel architecture for the retrieval of latent space representations of body shapes and poses. This network offers a fast and robust method to estimate the embedding of arbitrary unregistered meshes into the latent space. Second, we complement the estimation of latent codes with MoGeN (Motion Geometry Network) a framework that learns the geometry on the latent space itself. This is achieved by lifting the body pose parameter space into a higher dimensional Euclidean space in which body motion mini-sequences from a training set of 4D data can be approximated by simple linear interpolation. Using the SMPL latent space representation we illustrate how the combination of these network models, once trained, can be used to perform a variety of tasks with very limited computational cost. This includes operations such as motion interpolation, extrapolation and transfer as well as random shape and pose generation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03475v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Emmanuel Hartman, Nicolas Charon, Martin Bauer</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rainfall regression from C-band Synthetic Aperture Radar using Multi-Task Generative Adversarial Networks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03480</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03480v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper introduces a data-driven approach to estimate precipitation rates from Synthetic Aperture Radar (SAR) at a spatial resolution of 200 meters per pixel. It addresses previous challenges related to the collocation of SAR and weather radar data, specifically the misalignment in collocations and the scarcity of rainfall examples under strong wind. To tackle these challenges, the paper proposes a multi-objective formulation, introducing patch-level components and an adversarial component. It exploits the full NEXRAD archive to look for potential co-locations with Sentinel-1 data. With additional enhancements to the training procedure and the incorporation of additional inputs, the resulting model demonstrates improved accuracy in rainfall estimates and the ability to extend its performance to scenarios up to 15 m/s.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03480v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aur\'elien Colin, Romain Husson</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Application-Agnostic Automatic Target Recognition System Using Vision Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03491</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03491v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present a novel Automatic Target Recognition (ATR) system using open-vocabulary object detection and classification models. A primary advantage of this approach is that target classes can be defined just before runtime by a non-technical end user, using either a few natural language text descriptions of the target, or a few image exemplars, or both. Nuances in the desired targets can be expressed in natural language, which is useful for unique targets with little or no training data. We also implemented a novel combination of several techniques to improve performance, such as leveraging the additional information in the sequence of overlapping frames to perform tubelet identification (i.e., sequential bounding box matching), bounding box re-scoring, and tubelet linking. Additionally, we developed a technique to visualize the aggregate output of many overlapping frames as a mosaic of the area scanned during the aerial surveillance or reconnaissance, and a kernel density estimate (or heatmap) of the detected targets. We initially applied this ATR system to the use case of detecting and clearing unexploded ordinance on airfield runways and we are currently extending our research to other real-world applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03491v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Anthony Palladino, Dana Gajewski, Abigail Aronica, Patryk Deptula, Alexander Hamme, Seiyoung C. Lee, Jeff Muri, Todd Nelling, Michael A. Riley, Brian Wong, Margaret Duff</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SynthSet: Generative Diffusion Model for Semantic Segmentation in Precision Agriculture</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03505</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03505v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper introduces a methodology for generating synthetic annotated data to address data scarcity in semantic segmentation tasks within the precision agriculture domain. Utilizing Denoising Diffusion Probabilistic Models (DDPMs) and Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs), we propose a dual diffusion model architecture for synthesizing realistic annotated agricultural data, without any human intervention. We employ super-resolution to enhance the phenotypic characteristics of the synthesized images and their coherence with the corresponding generated masks. We showcase the utility of the proposed method for wheat head segmentation. The high quality of synthesized data underscores the effectiveness of the proposed methodology in generating image-mask pairs. Furthermore, models trained on our generated data exhibit promising performance when tested on an external, diverse dataset of real wheat fields. The results show the efficacy of the proposed methodology for addressing data scarcity for semantic segmentation tasks. Moreover, the proposed approach can be readily adapted for various segmentation tasks in precision agriculture and beyond.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03505v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Andrew Heschl, Mauricio Murillo, Keyhan Najafian, Farhad Maleki</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Complete Shapes: A quantitative Evaluation of 3D Shape Matching Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03511</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03511v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Finding correspondences between 3D shapes is an important and long-standing problem in computer vision, graphics and beyond. While approaches based on machine learning dominate modern 3D shape matching, almost all existing (learning-based) methods require that at least one of the involved shapes is complete. In contrast, the most challenging and arguably most practically relevant setting of matching partially observed shapes, is currently underexplored. One important factor is that existing datasets contain only a small number of shapes (typically below 100), which are unable to serve data-hungry machine learning approaches, particularly in the unsupervised regime. In addition, the type of partiality present in existing datasets is often artificial and far from realistic. To address these limitations and to encourage research on these relevant settings, we provide a generic and flexible framework for the procedural generation of challenging partial shape matching scenarios. Our framework allows for a virtually infinite generation of partial shape matching instances from a finite set of shapes with complete geometry. Further, we manually create cross-dataset correspondences between seven existing (complete geometry) shape matching datasets, leading to a total of 2543 shapes. Based on this, we propose several challenging partial benchmark settings, for which we evaluate respective state-of-the-art methods as baselines.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03511v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Viktoria Ehm, Nafie El Amrani, Yizheng Xie, Lennart Bastian, Maolin Gao, Weikang Wang, Lu Sang, Dongliang Cao, Zorah L\"ahner, Daniel Cremers, Florian Bernard</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personalized Video Summarization by Multimodal Video Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03531</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03531v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Video summarization techniques have been proven to improve the overall user experience when it comes to accessing and comprehending video content. If the user's preference is known, video summarization can identify significant information or relevant content from an input video, aiding them in obtaining the necessary information or determining their interest in watching the original video. Adapting video summarization to various types of video and user preferences requires significant training data and expensive human labeling. To facilitate such research, we proposed a new benchmark for video summarization that captures various user preferences. Also, we present a pipeline called Video Summarization with Language (VSL) for user-preferred video summarization that is based on pre-trained visual language models (VLMs) to avoid the need to train a video summarization system on a large training dataset. The pipeline takes both video and closed captioning as input and performs semantic analysis at the scene level by converting video frames into text. Subsequently, the user's genre preference was used as the basis for selecting the pertinent textual scenes. The experimental results demonstrate that our proposed pipeline outperforms current state-of-the-art unsupervised video summarization models. We show that our method is more adaptable across different datasets compared to supervised query-based video summarization models. In the end, the runtime analysis demonstrates that our pipeline is more suitable for practical use when scaling up the number of user preferences and videos.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03531v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3627673.3680011</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>33rd ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM 2024)</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Brian Chen, Xiangyuan Zhao, Yingnan Zhu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking Vision Language Model Unlearning via Fictitious Facial Identity Dataset</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03554</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03554v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Machine unlearning has emerged as an effective strategy for forgetting specific information in the training data. However, with the increasing integration of visual data, privacy concerns in Vision Language Models (VLMs) remain underexplored. To address this, we introduce Facial Identity Unlearning Benchmark (FIUBench), a novel VLM unlearning benchmark designed to robustly evaluate the effectiveness of unlearning algorithms under the Right to be Forgotten setting. Specifically, we formulate the VLM unlearning task via constructing the Fictitious Facial Identity VQA dataset and apply a two-stage evaluation pipeline that is designed to precisely control the sources of information and their exposure levels. In terms of evaluation, since VLM supports various forms of ways to ask questions with the same semantic meaning, we also provide robust evaluation metrics including membership inference attacks and carefully designed adversarial privacy attacks to evaluate the performance of algorithms. Through the evaluation of four baseline VLM unlearning algorithms within FIUBench, we find that all methods remain limited in their unlearning performance, with significant trade-offs between model utility and forget quality. Furthermore, our findings also highlight the importance of privacy attacks for robust evaluations. We hope FIUBench will drive progress in developing more effective VLM unlearning algorithms.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03554v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yingzi Ma, Jiongxiao Wang, Fei Wang, Siyuan Ma, Jiazhao Li, Xiujun Li, Furong Huang, Lichao Sun, Bo Li, Yejin Choi, Muhao Chen, Chaowei Xiao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Object and Contact Point Tracking in Demonstrations Using 3D Gaussian Splatting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03555</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03555v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper introduces a method to enhance Interactive Imitation Learning (IIL) by extracting touch interaction points and tracking object movement from video demonstrations. The approach extends current IIL systems by providing robots with detailed knowledge of both where and how to interact with objects, particularly complex articulated ones like doors and drawers. By leveraging cutting-edge techniques such as 3D Gaussian Splatting and FoundationPose for tracking, this method allows robots to better understand and manipulate objects in dynamic environments. The research lays the foundation for more effective task learning and execution in autonomous robotic systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03555v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Michael B\"uttner, Jonathan Francis, Helge Rhodin, Andrew Melnik</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Estimating Ego-Body Pose from Doubly Sparse Egocentric Video Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03561</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03561v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We study the problem of estimating the body movements of a camera wearer from egocentric videos. Current methods for ego-body pose estimation rely on temporally dense sensor data, such as IMU measurements from spatially sparse body parts like the head and hands. However, we propose that even temporally sparse observations, such as hand poses captured intermittently from egocentric videos during natural or periodic hand movements, can effectively constrain overall body motion. Naively applying diffusion models to generate full-body pose from head pose and sparse hand pose leads to suboptimal results. To overcome this, we develop a two-stage approach that decomposes the problem into temporal completion and spatial completion. First, our method employs masked autoencoders to impute hand trajectories by leveraging the spatiotemporal correlations between the head pose sequence and intermittent hand poses, providing uncertainty estimates. Subsequently, we employ conditional diffusion models to generate plausible full-body motions based on these temporally dense trajectories of the head and hands, guided by the uncertainty estimates from the imputation. The effectiveness of our method was rigorously tested and validated through comprehensive experiments conducted on various HMD setup with AMASS and Ego-Exo4D datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03561v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Seunggeun Chi, Pin-Hao Huang, Enna Sachdeva, Hengbo Ma, Karthik Ramani, Kwonjoon Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Attention for Robust RGB-T Pedestrian Detection in Real-World Conditions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03576</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03576v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Multispectral pedestrian detection has gained significant attention in recent years, particularly in autonomous driving applications. To address the challenges posed by adversarial illumination conditions, the combination of thermal and visible images has demonstrated its advantages. However, existing fusion methods rely on the critical assumption that the RGB-Thermal (RGB-T) image pairs are fully overlapping. These assumptions often do not hold in real-world applications, where only partial overlap between images can occur due to sensors configuration. Moreover, sensor failure can cause loss of information in one modality. In this paper, we propose a novel module called the Hybrid Attention (HA) mechanism as our main contribution to mitigate performance degradation caused by partial overlap and sensor failure, i.e. when at least part of the scene is acquired by only one sensor. We propose an improved RGB-T fusion algorithm, robust against partial overlap and sensor failure encountered during inference in real-world applications. We also leverage a mobile-friendly backbone to cope with resource constraints in embedded systems. We conducted experiments by simulating various partial overlap and sensor failure scenarios to evaluate the performance of our proposed method. The results demonstrate that our approach outperforms state-of-the-art methods, showcasing its superiority in handling real-world challenges.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03576v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Arunkumar Rathinam, Leo Pauly, Abd El Rahman Shabayek, Wassim Rharbaoui, Anis Kacem, Vincent Gaudilli\`ere, Djamila Aouada</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>StreamingBench: Assessing the Gap for MLLMs to Achieve Streaming Video Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03628</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03628v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The rapid development of Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) has expanded their capabilities from image comprehension to video understanding. However, most of these MLLMs focus primarily on offline video comprehension, necessitating extensive processing of all video frames before any queries can be made. This presents a significant gap compared to the human ability to watch, listen, think, and respond to streaming inputs in real time, highlighting the limitations of current MLLMs. In this paper, we introduce StreamingBench, the first comprehensive benchmark designed to evaluate the streaming video understanding capabilities of MLLMs. StreamingBench assesses three core aspects of streaming video understanding: (1) real-time visual understanding, (2) omni-source understanding, and (3) contextual understanding. The benchmark consists of 18 tasks, featuring 900 videos and 4,500 human-curated QA pairs. Each video features five questions presented at different time points to simulate a continuous streaming scenario. We conduct experiments on StreamingBench with 13 open-source and proprietary MLLMs and find that even the most advanced proprietary MLLMs like Gemini 1.5 Pro and GPT-4o perform significantly below human-level streaming video understanding capabilities. We hope our work can facilitate further advancements for MLLMs, empowering them to approach human-level video comprehension and interaction in more realistic scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03628v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junming Lin, Zheng Fang, Chi Chen, Zihao Wan, Fuwen Luo, Peng Li, Yang Liu, Maosong Sun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure Consistent Gaussian Splatting with Matching Prior for Few-shot Novel View Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03637</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03637v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Despite the substantial progress of novel view synthesis, existing methods, either based on the Neural Radiance Fields (NeRF) or more recently 3D Gaussian Splatting (3DGS), suffer significant degradation when the input becomes sparse. Numerous efforts have been introduced to alleviate this problem, but they still struggle to synthesize satisfactory results efficiently, especially in the large scene. In this paper, we propose SCGaussian, a Structure Consistent Gaussian Splatting method using matching priors to learn 3D consistent scene structure. Considering the high interdependence of Gaussian attributes, we optimize the scene structure in two folds: rendering geometry and, more importantly, the position of Gaussian primitives, which is hard to be directly constrained in the vanilla 3DGS due to the non-structure property. To achieve this, we present a hybrid Gaussian representation. Besides the ordinary non-structure Gaussian primitives, our model also consists of ray-based Gaussian primitives that are bound to matching rays and whose optimization of their positions is restricted along the ray. Thus, we can utilize the matching correspondence to directly enforce the position of these Gaussian primitives to converge to the surface points where rays intersect. Extensive experiments on forward-facing, surrounding, and complex large scenes show the effectiveness of our approach with state-of-the-art performance and high efficiency. Code is available at https://github.com/prstrive/SCGaussian.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03637v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rui Peng, Wangze Xu, Luyang Tang, Liwei Liao, Jianbo Jiao, Ronggang Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive Stereo Depth Estimation with Multi-Spectral Images Across All Lighting Conditions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03638</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03638v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Depth estimation under adverse conditions remains a significant challenge. Recently, multi-spectral depth estimation, which integrates both visible light and thermal images, has shown promise in addressing this issue. However, existing algorithms struggle with precise pixel-level feature matching, limiting their ability to fully exploit geometric constraints across different spectra. To address this, we propose a novel framework incorporating stereo depth estimation to enforce accurate geometric constraints. In particular, we treat the visible light and thermal images as a stereo pair and utilize a Cross-modal Feature Matching (CFM) Module to construct a cost volume for pixel-level matching. To mitigate the effects of poor lighting on stereo matching, we introduce Degradation Masking, which leverages robust monocular thermal depth estimation in degraded regions. Our method achieves state-of-the-art (SOTA) performance on the Multi-Spectral Stereo (MS2) dataset, with qualitative evaluations demonstrating high-quality depth maps under varying lighting conditions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03638v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zihan Qin, Jialei Xu, Wenbo Zhao, Junjun Jiang, Xianming Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Touchstone Benchmark: Are We on the Right Way for Evaluating AI Algorithms for Medical Segmentation?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03670</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03670v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: How can we test AI performance? This question seems trivial, but it isn't. Standard benchmarks often have problems such as in-distribution and small-size test sets, oversimplified metrics, unfair comparisons, and short-term outcome pressure. As a consequence, good performance on standard benchmarks does not guarantee success in real-world scenarios. To address these problems, we present Touchstone, a large-scale collaborative segmentation benchmark of 9 types of abdominal organs. This benchmark is based on 5,195 training CT scans from 76 hospitals around the world and 5,903 testing CT scans from 11 additional hospitals. This diverse test set enhances the statistical significance of benchmark results and rigorously evaluates AI algorithms across various out-of-distribution scenarios. We invited 14 inventors of 19 AI algorithms to train their algorithms, while our team, as a third party, independently evaluated these algorithms on three test sets. In addition, we also evaluated pre-existing AI frameworks--which, differing from algorithms, are more flexible and can support different algorithms--including MONAI from NVIDIA, nnU-Net from DKFZ, and numerous other open-source frameworks. We are committed to expanding this benchmark to encourage more innovation of AI algorithms for the medical domain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03670v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Pedro R. A. S. Bassi, Wenxuan Li, Yucheng Tang, Fabian Isensee, Zifu Wang, Jieneng Chen, Yu-Cheng Chou, Yannick Kirchhoff, Maximilian Rokuss, Ziyan Huang, Jin Ye, Junjun He, Tassilo Wald, Constantin Ulrich, Michael Baumgartner, Saikat Roy, Klaus H. Maier-Hein, Paul Jaeger, Yiwen Ye, Yutong Xie, Jianpeng Zhang, Ziyang Chen, Yong Xia, Zhaohu Xing, Lei Zhu, Yousef Sadegheih, Afshin Bozorgpour, Pratibha Kumari, Reza Azad, Dorit Merhof, Pengcheng Shi, Ting Ma, Yuxin Du, Fan Bai, Tiejun Huang, Bo Zhao, Haonan Wang, Xiaomeng Li, Hanxue Gu, Haoyu Dong, Jichen Yang, Maciej A. Mazurowski, Saumya Gupta, Linshan Wu, Jiaxin Zhuang, Hao Chen, Holger Roth, Daguang Xu, Matthew B. Blaschko, Sergio Decherchi, Andrea Cavalli, Alan L. Yuille, Zongwei Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards 3D Semantic Scene Completion for Autonomous Driving: A Meta-Learning Framework Empowered by Deformable Large-Kernel Attention and Mamba Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03672</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03672v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Semantic scene completion (SSC) is essential for achieving comprehensive perception in autonomous driving systems. However, existing SSC methods often overlook the high deployment costs in real-world applications. Traditional architectures, such as 3D Convolutional Neural Networks (3D CNNs) and self-attention mechanisms, face challenges in efficiently capturing long-range dependencies within 3D voxel grids, limiting their effectiveness. To address these issues, we introduce MetaSSC, a novel meta-learning-based framework for SSC that leverages deformable convolution, large-kernel attention, and the Mamba (D-LKA-M) model. Our approach begins with a voxel-based semantic segmentation (SS) pretraining task, aimed at exploring the semantics and geometry of incomplete regions while acquiring transferable meta-knowledge. Using simulated cooperative perception datasets, we supervise the perception training of a single vehicle using aggregated sensor data from multiple nearby connected autonomous vehicles (CAVs), generating richer and more comprehensive labels. This meta-knowledge is then adapted to the target domain through a dual-phase training strategy that does not add extra model parameters, enabling efficient deployment. To further enhance the model's capability in capturing long-sequence relationships within 3D voxel grids, we integrate Mamba blocks with deformable convolution and large-kernel attention into the backbone network. Extensive experiments demonstrate that MetaSSC achieves state-of-the-art performance, significantly outperforming competing models while also reducing deployment costs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03672v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yansong Qu, Zilin Huang, Zihao Sheng, Tiantian Chen, Sikai Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where Do We Stand with Implicit Neural Representations? A Technical and Performance Survey</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03688</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03688v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Implicit Neural Representations (INRs) have emerged as a paradigm in knowledge representation, offering exceptional flexibility and performance across a diverse range of applications. INRs leverage multilayer perceptrons (MLPs) to model data as continuous implicit functions, providing critical advantages such as resolution independence, memory efficiency, and generalisation beyond discretised data structures. Their ability to solve complex inverse problems makes them particularly effective for tasks including audio reconstruction, image representation, 3D object reconstruction, and high-dimensional data synthesis. This survey provides a comprehensive review of state-of-the-art INR methods, introducing a clear taxonomy that categorises them into four key areas: activation functions, position encoding, combined strategies, and network structure optimisation. We rigorously analyse their critical properties, such as full differentiability, smoothness, compactness, and adaptability to varying resolutions while also examining their strengths and limitations in addressing locality biases and capturing fine details. Our experimental comparison offers new insights into the trade-offs between different approaches, showcasing the capabilities and challenges of the latest INR techniques across various tasks. In addition to identifying areas where current methods excel, we highlight key limitations and potential avenues for improvement, such as developing more expressive activation functions, enhancing positional encoding mechanisms, and improving scalability for complex, high-dimensional data. This survey serves as a roadmap for researchers, offering practical guidance for future exploration in the field of INRs. We aim to foster new methodologies by outlining promising research directions for INRs and applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03688v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Amer Essakine, Yanqi Cheng, Chun-Wun Cheng, Lipei Zhang, Zhongying Deng, Lei Zhu, Carola-Bibiane Sch\"onlieb, Angelica I Aviles-Rivero</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMNCutter: Affinity-Attention-Guided Multi-View Normalized Cutter for Unsupervised Surgical Instrument Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03695</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03695v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Surgical instrument segmentation (SIS) is pivotal for robotic-assisted minimally invasive surgery, assisting surgeons by identifying surgical instruments in endoscopic video frames. Recent unsupervised surgical instrument segmentation (USIS) methods primarily rely on pseudo-labels derived from low-level features such as color and optical flow, but these methods show limited effectiveness and generalizability in complex and unseen endoscopic scenarios. In this work, we propose a label-free unsupervised model featuring a novel module named Multi-View Normalized Cutter (m-NCutter). Different from previous USIS works, our model is trained using a graph-cutting loss function that leverages patch affinities for supervision, eliminating the need for pseudo-labels. The framework adaptively determines which affinities from which levels should be prioritized. Therefore, the low- and high-level features and their affinities are effectively integrated to train a label-free unsupervised model, showing superior effectiveness and generalization ability. We conduct comprehensive experiments across multiple SIS datasets to validate our approach's state-of-the-art (SOTA) performance, robustness, and exceptional potential as a pre-trained model. Our code is released at https://github.com/MingyuShengSMY/AMNCutter.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03695v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mingyu Sheng, Jianan Fan, Dongnan Liu, Ron Kikinis, Weidong Cai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OccLoff: Learning Optimized Feature Fusion for 3D Occupancy Prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03696</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03696v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: 3D semantic occupancy prediction is crucial for finely representing the surrounding environment, which is essential for ensuring the safety in autonomous driving. Existing fusion-based occupancy methods typically involve performing a 2D-to-3D view transformation on image features, followed by computationally intensive 3D operations to fuse these with LiDAR features, leading to high computational costs and reduced accuracy. Moreover, current research on occupancy prediction predominantly focuses on designing specific network architectures, often tailored to particular models, with limited attention given to the more fundamental aspect of semantic feature learning. This gap hinders the development of more transferable methods that could enhance the performance of various occupancy models. To address these challenges, we propose OccLoff, a framework that Learns to Optimize Feature Fusion for 3D occupancy prediction. Specifically, we introduce a sparse fusion encoder with entropy masks that directly fuses 3D and 2D features, improving model accuracy while reducing computational overhead. Additionally, we propose a transferable proxy-based loss function and an adaptive hard sample weighting algorithm, which enhance the performance of several state-of-the-art methods. Extensive evaluations on the nuScenes and SemanticKITTI benchmarks demonstrate the superiority of our framework, and ablation studies confirm the effectiveness of each proposed module.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03696v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ji Zhang, Yiran Ding, Zixin Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graph-Based Multi-Modal Sensor Fusion for Autonomous Driving</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03702</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03702v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The growing demand for robust scene understanding in mobile robotics and autonomous driving has highlighted the importance of integrating multiple sensing modalities. By combining data from diverse sensors like cameras and LIDARs, fusion techniques can overcome the limitations of individual sensors, enabling a more complete and accurate perception of the environment. We introduce a novel approach to multi-modal sensor fusion, focusing on developing a graph-based state representation that supports critical decision-making processes in autonomous driving. We present a Sensor-Agnostic Graph-Aware Kalman Filter [3], the first online state estimation technique designed to fuse multi-modal graphs derived from noisy multi-sensor data. The estimated graph-based state representations serve as a foundation for advanced applications like Multi-Object Tracking (MOT), offering a comprehensive framework for enhancing the situational awareness and safety of autonomous systems. We validate the effectiveness of our proposed framework through extensive experiments conducted on both synthetic and real-world driving datasets (nuScenes). Our results showcase an improvement in MOTA and a reduction in estimated position errors (MOTP) and identity switches (IDS) for tracked objects using the SAGA-KF. Furthermore, we highlight the capability of such a framework to develop methods that can leverage heterogeneous information (like semantic objects and geometric structures) from various sensing modalities, enabling a more holistic approach to scene understanding and enhancing the safety and effectiveness of autonomous systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03702v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Depanshu Sani, Saket Anand</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3DGS-CD: 3D Gaussian Splatting-based Change Detection for Physical Object Rearrangement</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03706</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03706v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present 3DGS-CD, the first 3D Gaussian Splatting (3DGS)-based method for detecting physical object rearrangements in 3D scenes. Our approach estimates 3D object-level changes by comparing two sets of unaligned images taken at different times. Leveraging 3DGS's novel view rendering and EfficientSAM's zero-shot segmentation capabilities, we detect 2D object-level changes, which are then associated and fused across views to estimate 3D changes. Our method can detect changes in cluttered environments using sparse post-change images within as little as 18s, using as few as a single new image. It does not rely on depth input, user instructions, object classes, or object models -- An object is recognized simply if it has been re-arranged. Our approach is evaluated on both public and self-collected real-world datasets, achieving up to 14% higher accuracy and three orders of magnitude faster performance compared to the state-of-the-art radiance-field-based change detection method. This significant performance boost enables a broad range of downstream applications, where we highlight three key use cases: object reconstruction, robot workspace reset, and 3DGS model update. Our code and data will be made available at https://github.com/520xyxyzq/3DGS-CD.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03706v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ziqi Lu, Jianbo Ye, John Leonard</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fine-Tuning Vision-Language Model for Automated Engineering Drawing Information Extraction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03707</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03707v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Geometric Dimensioning and Tolerancing (GD&amp;T) plays a critical role in manufacturing by defining acceptable variations in part features to ensure component quality and functionality. However, extracting GD&amp;T information from 2D engineering drawings is a time-consuming and labor-intensive task, often relying on manual efforts or semi-automated tools. To address these challenges, this study proposes an automated and computationally efficient GD&amp;T extraction method by fine-tuning Florence-2, an open-source vision-language model (VLM). The model is trained on a dataset of 400 drawings with ground truth annotations provided by domain experts. For comparison, two state-of-the-art closed-source VLMs, GPT-4o and Claude-3.5-Sonnet, are evaluated on the same dataset. All models are assessed using precision, recall, F1-score, and hallucination metrics. Due to the computational cost and impracticality of fine-tuning large closed-source VLMs for domain-specific tasks, GPT-4o and Claude-3.5-Sonnet are evaluated in a zero-shot setting. In contrast, Florence-2, a smaller model with 0.23 billion parameters, is optimized through full-parameter fine-tuning across three distinct experiments, each utilizing datasets augmented to different levels. The results show that Florence-2 achieves a 29.95% increase in precision, a 37.75% increase in recall, a 52.40% improvement in F1-score, and a 43.15% reduction in hallucination rate compared to the best-performing closed-source model. These findings highlight the effectiveness of fine-tuning smaller, open-source VLMs like Florence-2, offering a practical and efficient solution for automated GD&amp;T extraction to support downstream manufacturing tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03707v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Muhammad Tayyab Khan, Lequn Chen, Ye Han Ng, Wenhe Feng, Nicholas Yew Jin Tan, Seung Ki Moon</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explaining Human Activity Recognition with SHAP: Validating Insights with Perturbation and Quantitative Measures</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03714</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03714v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In Human Activity Recognition (HAR), understanding the intricacy of body movements within high-risk applications is essential. This study uses SHapley Additive exPlanations (SHAP) to explain the decision-making process of Graph Convolution Networks (GCNs) when classifying activities with skeleton data. We employ SHAP to explain two real-world datasets: one for cerebral palsy (CP) classification and the widely used NTU RGB+D 60 action recognition dataset. To test the explanation, we introduce a novel perturbation approach that modifies the model's edge importance matrix, allowing us to evaluate the impact of specific body key points on prediction outcomes. To assess the fidelity of our explanations, we employ informed perturbation, targeting body key points identified as important by SHAP and comparing them against random perturbation as a control condition. This perturbation enables a judgment on whether the body key points are truly influential or non-influential based on the SHAP values. Results on both datasets show that body key points identified as important through SHAP have the largest influence on the accuracy, specificity, and sensitivity metrics. Our findings highlight that SHAP can provide granular insights into the input feature contribution to the prediction outcome of GCNs in HAR tasks. This demonstrates the potential for more interpretable and trustworthy models in high-stakes applications like healthcare or rehabilitation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03714v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Felix Tempel, Espen Alexander F. Ihlen, Lars Adde, Inga Str\"umke</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>These Maps Are Made by Propagation: Adapting Deep Stereo Networks to Road Scenarios with Decisive Disparity Diffusion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03717</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03717v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Stereo matching has emerged as a cost-effective solution for road surface 3D reconstruction, garnering significant attention towards improving both computational efficiency and accuracy. This article introduces decisive disparity diffusion (D3Stereo), marking the first exploration of dense deep feature matching that adapts pre-trained deep convolutional neural networks (DCNNs) to previously unseen road scenarios. A pyramid of cost volumes is initially created using various levels of learned representations. Subsequently, a novel recursive bilateral filtering algorithm is employed to aggregate these costs. A key innovation of D3Stereo lies in its alternating decisive disparity diffusion strategy, wherein intra-scale diffusion is employed to complete sparse disparity images, while inter-scale inheritance provides valuable prior information for higher resolutions. Extensive experiments conducted on our created UDTIRI-Stereo and Stereo-Road datasets underscore the effectiveness of D3Stereo strategy in adapting pre-trained DCNNs and its superior performance compared to all other explicit programming-based algorithms designed specifically for road surface 3D reconstruction. Additional experiments conducted on the Middlebury dataset with backbone DCNNs pre-trained on the ImageNet database further validate the versatility of D3Stereo strategy in tackling general stereo matching problems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03717v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chuang-Wei Liu, Yikang Zhang, Qijun Chen, Ioannis Pitas, Rui Fan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Estimation of Psychosocial Work Environment Exposures Through Video Object Detection. Proof of Concept Using CCTV Footage</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03724</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03724v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper examines the use of computer vision algorithms to estimate aspects of the psychosocial work environment using CCTV footage. We present a proof of concept for a methodology that detects and tracks people in video footage and estimates interactions between customers and employees by estimating their poses and calculating the duration of their encounters. We propose a pipeline that combines existing object detection and tracking algorithms (YOLOv8 and DeepSORT) with pose estimation algorithms (BlazePose) to estimate the number of customers and employees in the footage as well as the duration of their encounters. We use a simple rule-based approach to classify the interactions as positive, neutral or negative based on three different criteria: distance, duration and pose. The proposed methodology is tested on a small dataset of CCTV footage. While the data is quite limited in particular with respect to the quality of the footage, we have chosen this case as it represents a typical setting where the method could be applied. The results show that the object detection and tracking part of the pipeline has a reasonable performance on the dataset with a high degree of recall and reasonable accuracy. At this stage, the pose estimation is still limited to fully detect the type of interactions due to difficulties in tracking employees in the footage. We conclude that the method is a promising alternative to self-reported measures of the psychosocial work environment and could be used in future studies to obtain external observations of the work environment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03724v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Claus D. Hansen, Thuy Hai Le, David Campos</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PX2Tooth: Reconstructing the 3D Point Cloud Teeth from a Single Panoramic X-ray</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03725</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03725v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Reconstructing the 3D anatomical structures of the oral cavity, which originally reside in the cone-beam CT (CBCT), from a single 2D Panoramic X-ray(PX) remains a critical yet challenging task, as it can effectively reduce radiation risks and treatment costs during the diagnostic in digital dentistry. However, current methods are either error-prone or only trained/evaluated on small-scale datasets (less than 50 cases), resulting in compromised trustworthiness. In this paper, we propose PX2Tooth, a novel approach to reconstruct 3D teeth using a single PX image with a two-stage framework. First, we design the PXSegNet to segment the permanent teeth from the PX images, providing clear positional, morphological, and categorical information for each tooth. Subsequently, we design a novel tooth generation network (TGNet) that learns to transform random point clouds into 3D teeth. TGNet integrates the segmented patch information and introduces a Prior Fusion Module (PFM) to enhance the generation quality, especially in the root apex region. Moreover, we construct a dataset comprising 499 pairs of CBCT and Panoramic X-rays. Extensive experiments demonstrate that PX2Tooth can achieve an Intersection over Union (IoU) of 0.793, significantly surpassing previous methods, underscoring the great potential of artificial intelligence in digital dentistry.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03725v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wen Ma, Huikai Wu, Zikai Xiao, Yang Feng, Jian Wu, Zuozhu Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Fourier Filtering Network with Contrastive Learning for UAV-based Unaligned Bi-modal Salient Object Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03728</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03728v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV)-based bi-modal salient object detection (BSOD) aims to segment salient objects in a scene utilizing complementary cues in unaligned RGB and thermal image pairs. However, the high computational expense of existing UAV-based BSOD models limits their applicability to real-world UAV devices. To address this problem, we propose an efficient Fourier filter network with contrastive learning that achieves both real-time and accurate performance. Specifically, we first design a semantic contrastive alignment loss to align the two modalities at the semantic level, which facilitates mutual refinement in a parameter-free way. Second, inspired by the fast Fourier transform that obtains global relevance in linear complexity, we propose synchronized alignment fusion, which aligns and fuses bi-modal features in the channel and spatial dimensions by a hierarchical filtering mechanism. Our proposed model, AlignSal, reduces the number of parameters by 70.0%, decreases the floating point operations by 49.4%, and increases the inference speed by 152.5% compared to the cutting-edge BSOD model (i.e., MROS). Extensive experiments on the UAV RGB-T 2400 and three weakly aligned datasets demonstrate that AlignSal achieves both real-time inference speed and better performance and generalizability compared to sixteen state-of-the-art BSOD models across most evaluation metrics. In addition, our ablation studies further verify AlignSal's potential in boosting the performance of existing aligned BSOD models on UAV-based unaligned data. The code is available at: https://github.com/JoshuaLPF/AlignSal.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03728v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Pengfei Lyu, Pak-Hei Yeung, Xiufei Cheng, Xiaosheng Yu, Chengdong Wu, Jagath C. Rajapakse</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Relation Learning and Aggregate-attention for Multi-person Motion Prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03729</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03729v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Multi-person motion prediction is an emerging and intricate task with broad real-world applications. Unlike single person motion prediction, it considers not just the skeleton structures or human trajectories but also the interactions between others. Previous methods use various networks to achieve impressive predictions but often overlook that the joints relations within an individual (intra-relation) and interactions among groups (inter-relation) are distinct types of representations. These methods often lack explicit representation of inter&amp;intra-relations, and inevitably introduce undesired dependencies. To address this issue, we introduce a new collaborative framework for multi-person motion prediction that explicitly modeling these relations:a GCN-based network for intra-relations and a novel reasoning network for inter-relations.Moreover, we propose a novel plug-and-play aggregation module called the Interaction Aggregation Module (IAM), which employs an aggregate-attention mechanism to seamlessly integrate these relations. Experiments indicate that the module can also be applied to other dual-path models. Extensive experiments on the 3DPW, 3DPW-RC, CMU-Mocap, MuPoTS-3D, as well as synthesized datasets Mix1 &amp; Mix2 (9 to 15 persons), demonstrate that our method achieves state-of-the-art performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03729v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kehua Qu, Rui Ding, Jin Tang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Homotopy Continuation Made Easy: Regression-based Online Simulation of Starting Problem-Solution Pairs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03745</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03745v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: While automatically generated polynomial elimination templates have sparked great progress in the field of 3D computer vision, there remain many problems for which the degree of the constraints or the number of unknowns leads to intractability. In recent years, homotopy continuation has been introduced as a plausible alternative. However, the method currently depends on expensive parallel tracking of all possible solutions in the complex domain, or a classification network for starting problem-solution pairs trained over a limited set of real-world examples. Our innovation consists of employing a regression network trained in simulation to directly predict a solution from input correspondences, followed by an online simulator that invents a consistent problem-solution pair. Subsequently, homotopy continuation is applied to track that single solution back to the original problem. We apply this elegant combination to generalized camera resectioning, and also introduce a new solution to the challenging generalized relative pose and scale problem. As demonstrated, the proposed method successfully compensates the raw error committed by the regressor alone, and leads to state-of-the-art efficiency and success rates while running on CPU resources, only.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03745v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xinyue Zhang, Zijia Dai, Wanting Xu, Laurent Kneip</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harmformer: Harmonic Networks Meet Transformers for Continuous Roto-Translation Equivariance</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03794</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03794v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: CNNs exhibit inherent equivariance to image translation, leading to efficient parameter and data usage, faster learning, and improved robustness. The concept of translation equivariant networks has been successfully extended to rotation transformation using group convolution for discrete rotation groups and harmonic functions for the continuous rotation group encompassing $360^\circ$. We explore the compatibility of the SA mechanism with full rotation equivariance, in contrast to previous studies that focused on discrete rotation. We introduce the Harmformer, a harmonic transformer with a convolutional stem that achieves equivariance for both translation and continuous rotation. Accompanied by an end-to-end equivariance proof, the Harmformer not only outperforms previous equivariant transformers, but also demonstrates inherent stability under any continuous rotation, even without seeing rotated samples during training.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03794v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tom\'a\v{s} Karella, Adam Harmanec, Jan Kotera, Jan Bla\v{z}ek, Filip \v{S}roubek</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VQA$^2$:Visual Question Answering for Video Quality Assessment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03795</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03795v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The advent and proliferation of large multi-modal models (LMMs) have introduced a new paradigm to video-related computer vision fields, including training and inference methods based on visual question answering (VQA). These methods enable models to handle multiple downstream tasks robustly. Video Quality Assessment (VQA), a classic field in low-level visual quality evaluation, originally focused on quantitative video quality scoring. However, driven by advances in LMMs, it is now evolving towards more comprehensive visual quality understanding tasks. Visual question answering has significantly improved low-level visual evaluation within the image domain recently. However, related work is almost nonexistent in the video domain, leaving substantial room for improvement. To address this gap, we introduce the VQA2 Instruction Dataset the first visual question answering instruction dataset entirely focuses on video quality assessment, and based on it, we propose the VQA2 series models The VQA2 Instruction Dataset consists of three stages and covers various video types, containing 157,735 instruction question-answer pairs, including both manually annotated and synthetic data. We conduct extensive experiments on both video quality scoring and video quality understanding tasks. Results demonstrate that the VQA2 series models achieve state-of-the-art (SOTA) performance in quality scoring tasks, and their performance in visual quality question answering surpasses the renowned GPT-4o. Additionally, our final model, the VQA2-Assistant, performs well across both scoring and question-answering tasks, validating its versatility.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03795v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ziheng Jia, Zicheng Zhang, Jiaying Qian, Haoning Wu, Wei Sun, Chunyi Li, Xiaohong Liu, Weisi Lin, Guangtao Zhai, Xiongkuo Min</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GS2Pose: Tow-stage 6D Object Pose Estimation Guided by Gaussian Splatting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03807</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03807v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper proposes a new method for accurate and robust 6D pose estimation of novel objects, named GS2Pose. By introducing 3D Gaussian splatting, GS2Pose can utilize the reconstruction results without requiring a high-quality CAD model, which means it only requires segmented RGBD images as input. Specifically, GS2Pose employs a two-stage structure consisting of coarse estimation followed by refined estimation. In the coarse stage, a lightweight U-Net network with a polarization attention mechanism, called Pose-Net, is designed. By using the 3DGS model for supervised training, Pose-Net can generate NOCS images to compute a coarse pose. In the refinement stage, GS2Pose formulates a pose regression algorithm following the idea of reprojection or Bundle Adjustment (BA), referred to as GS-Refiner. By leveraging Lie algebra to extend 3DGS, GS-Refiner obtains a pose-differentiable rendering pipeline that refines the coarse pose by comparing the input images with the rendered images. GS-Refiner also selectively updates parameters in the 3DGS model to achieve environmental adaptation, thereby enhancing the algorithm's robustness and flexibility to illuminative variation, occlusion, and other challenging disruptive factors. GS2Pose was evaluated through experiments conducted on the LineMod dataset, where it was compared with similar algorithms, yielding highly competitive results. The code for GS2Pose will soon be released on GitHub.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03807v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jilan Mei, Junbo Li, Cai Meng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SA3DIP: Segment Any 3D Instance with Potential 3D Priors</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03819</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03819v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The proliferation of 2D foundation models has sparked research into adapting them for open-world 3D instance segmentation. Recent methods introduce a paradigm that leverages superpoints as geometric primitives and incorporates 2D multi-view masks from Segment Anything model (SAM) as merging guidance, achieving outstanding zero-shot instance segmentation results. However, the limited use of 3D priors restricts the segmentation performance. Previous methods calculate the 3D superpoints solely based on estimated normal from spatial coordinates, resulting in under-segmentation for instances with similar geometry. Besides, the heavy reliance on SAM and hand-crafted algorithms in 2D space suffers from over-segmentation due to SAM's inherent part-level segmentation tendency. To address these issues, we propose SA3DIP, a novel method for Segmenting Any 3D Instances via exploiting potential 3D Priors. Specifically, on one hand, we generate complementary 3D primitives based on both geometric and textural priors, which reduces the initial errors that accumulate in subsequent procedures. On the other hand, we introduce supplemental constraints from the 3D space by using a 3D detector to guide a further merging process. Furthermore, we notice a considerable portion of low-quality ground truth annotations in ScanNetV2 benchmark, which affect the fair evaluations. Thus, we present ScanNetV2-INS with complete ground truth labels and supplement additional instances for 3D class-agnostic instance segmentation. Experimental evaluations on various 2D-3D datasets demonstrate the effectiveness and robustness of our approach. Our code and proposed ScanNetV2-INS dataset are available HERE.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03819v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xi Yang, Xu Gu, Xingyilang Yin, Xinbo Gao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Both Text and Images Leaked! A Systematic Analysis of Multimodal LLM Data Contamination</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03823</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03823v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The rapid progression of multimodal large language models (MLLMs) has demonstrated superior performance on various multimodal benchmarks. However, the issue of data contamination during training creates challenges in performance evaluation and comparison. While numerous methods exist for detecting dataset contamination in large language models (LLMs), they are less effective for MLLMs due to their various modalities and multiple training phases. In this study, we introduce a multimodal data contamination detection framework, MM-Detect, designed for MLLMs. Our experimental results indicate that MM-Detect is sensitive to varying degrees of contamination and can highlight significant performance improvements due to leakage of the training set of multimodal benchmarks. Furthermore, We also explore the possibility of contamination originating from the pre-training phase of LLMs used by MLLMs and the fine-tuning phase of MLLMs, offering new insights into the stages at which contamination may be introduced.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03823v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dingjie Song, Sicheng Lai, Shunian Chen, Lichao Sun, Benyou Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generalize or Detect? Towards Robust Semantic Segmentation Under Multiple Distribution Shifts</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03829</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03829v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In open-world scenarios, where both novel classes and domains may exist, an ideal segmentation model should detect anomaly classes for safety and generalize to new domains. However, existing methods often struggle to distinguish between domain-level and semantic-level distribution shifts, leading to poor out-of-distribution (OOD) detection or domain generalization performance. In this work, we aim to equip the model to generalize effectively to covariate-shift regions while precisely identifying semantic-shift regions. To achieve this, we design a novel generative augmentation method to produce coherent images that incorporate both anomaly (or novel) objects and various covariate shifts at both image and object levels. Furthermore, we introduce a training strategy that recalibrates uncertainty specifically for semantic shifts and enhances the feature extractor to align features associated with domain shifts. We validate the effectiveness of our method across benchmarks featuring both semantic and domain shifts. Our method achieves state-of-the-art performance across all benchmarks for both OOD detection and domain generalization. Code is available at https://github.com/gaozhitong/MultiShiftSeg.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03829v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhitong Gao, Bingnan Li, Mathieu Salzmann, Xuming He</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Enhancement of Haar Cascade Algorithm Applied to Face Recognition for Gate Pass Security</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03831</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03831v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This study is focused on enhancing the Haar Cascade Algorithm to decrease the false positive and false negative rate in face matching and face detection to increase the accuracy rate even under challenging conditions. The face recognition library was implemented with Haar Cascade Algorithm in which the 128-dimensional vectors representing the unique features of a face are encoded. A subprocess was applied where the grayscale image from Haar Cascade was converted to RGB to improve the face encoding. Logical process and face filtering are also used to decrease non-face detection. The Enhanced Haar Cascade Algorithm produced a 98.39% accuracy rate (21.39% increase), 63.59% precision rate, 98.30% recall rate, and 72.23% in F1 Score. In comparison, the Haar Cascade Algorithm achieved a 46.70% to 77.00% accuracy rate, 44.15% precision rate, 98.61% recall rate, and 47.01% in F1 Score. Both algorithms used the Confusion Matrix Test with 301,950 comparisons using the same dataset of 550 images. The 98.39% accuracy rate shows a significant decrease in false positive and false negative rates in facial recognition. Face matching and face detection are more accurate in images with complex backgrounds, lighting variations, and occlusions, or even those with similar attributes.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03831v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Clarence A. Antipona, Romeo R. Magsino, Raymund M. Dioses, Khatalyn E. Mata</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Edge Computing-Based Solution for Real-Time Leaf Disease Classification using Thermal Imaging</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03835</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03835v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Deep learning (DL) technologies can transform agriculture by improving crop health monitoring and management, thus improving food safety. In this paper, we explore the potential of edge computing for real-time classification of leaf diseases using thermal imaging. We present a thermal image dataset for plant disease classification and evaluate deep learning models, including InceptionV3, MobileNetV1, MobileNetV2, and VGG-16, on resource-constrained devices like the Raspberry Pi 4B. Using pruning and quantization-aware training, these models achieve inference times up to 1.48x faster on Edge TPU Max for VGG16, and up to 2.13x faster with precision reduction on Intel NCS2 for MobileNetV1, compared to high-end GPUs like the RTX 3090, while maintaining state-of-the-art accuracy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03835v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1109/LGRS.2024.3456637</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>IEEE Geoscience and Remote Sensing Letters (2024)</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>P\'ublio Elon Correa da Silva, Jurandy Almeida</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FedRISE: Rating Induced Sign Election of Gradients for Byzantine Tolerant Federated Aggregation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03861</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03861v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: One of the most common defense strategies against model poisoning in federated learning is to employ a robust aggregator mechanism that makes the training more resilient. Many of the existing Byzantine robust aggregators provide theoretical guarantees and are empirically effective against certain categories of attacks. However, we observe that certain high-strength attacks can subvert the aggregator and collapse the training. In addition, most aggregators require identifying tolerant settings to converge. Impact of attacks becomes more pronounced when the number of Byzantines is near-majority, and becomes harder to evade if the attacker is omniscient with access to data, honest updates and aggregation methods. Motivated by these observations, we develop a robust aggregator called FedRISE for cross-silo FL that is consistent and less susceptible to poisoning updates by an omniscient attacker. The proposed method explicitly determines the optimal direction of each gradient through a sign-voting strategy that uses variance-reduced sparse gradients. We argue that vote weighting based on the cosine similarity of raw gradients is misleading, and we introduce a sign-based gradient valuation function that ignores the gradient magnitude. We compare our method against 8 robust aggregators under 6 poisoning attacks on 3 datasets and architectures. Our results show that existing robust aggregators collapse for at least some attacks under severe settings, while FedRISE demonstrates better robustness because of a stringent gradient inclusion formulation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03861v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Joseph Geo Benjamin, Mothilal Asokan, Mohammad Yaqub, Karthik Nandakumar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ROBIN: Robust and Invisible Watermarks for Diffusion Models with Adversarial Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03862</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03862v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Watermarking generative content serves as a vital tool for authentication, ownership protection, and mitigation of potential misuse. Existing watermarking methods face the challenge of balancing robustness and concealment. They empirically inject a watermark that is both invisible and robust and passively achieve concealment by limiting the strength of the watermark, thus reducing the robustness. In this paper, we propose to explicitly introduce a watermark hiding process to actively achieve concealment, thus allowing the embedding of stronger watermarks. To be specific, we implant a robust watermark in an intermediate diffusion state and then guide the model to hide the watermark in the final generated image. We employ an adversarial optimization algorithm to produce the optimal hiding prompt guiding signal for each watermark. The prompt embedding is optimized to minimize artifacts in the generated image, while the watermark is optimized to achieve maximum strength. The watermark can be verified by reversing the generation process. Experiments on various diffusion models demonstrate the watermark remains verifiable even under significant image tampering and shows superior invisibility compared to other state-of-the-art robust watermarking methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03862v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Huayang Huang, Yu Wu, Qian Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-supervised Representation Learning for Cell Event Recognition through Time Arrow Prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03924</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03924v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The spatio-temporal nature of live-cell microscopy data poses challenges in the analysis of cell states which is fundamental in bioimaging. Deep-learning based segmentation or tracking methods rely on large amount of high quality annotations to work effectively. In this work, we explore an alternative solution: using feature maps obtained from self-supervised representation learning (SSRL) on time arrow prediction (TAP) for the downstream supervised task of cell event recognition. We demonstrate through extensive experiments and analysis that this approach can achieve better performance with limited annotation compared to models trained from end to end using fully supervised approach. Our analysis also provides insight into applications of the SSRL using TAP in live-cell microscopy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03924v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Cangxiong Chen, Vinay P. Namboodiri, Julia E. Sero</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Act in Collusion: A Persistent Distributed Multi-Target Backdoor in Federated Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03926</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03926v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Federated learning, a novel paradigm designed to protect data privacy, is vulnerable to backdoor attacks due to its distributed nature. Current research often designs attacks based on a single attacker with a single backdoor, overlooking more realistic and complex threats in federated learning. We propose a more practical threat model for federated learning: the distributed multi-target backdoor. In this model, multiple attackers control different clients, embedding various triggers and targeting different classes, collaboratively implanting backdoors into the global model via central aggregation. Empirical validation shows that existing methods struggle to maintain the effectiveness of multiple backdoors in the global model. Our key insight is that similar backdoor triggers cause parameter conflicts and injecting new backdoors disrupts gradient directions, significantly weakening some backdoors performance. To solve this, we propose a Distributed Multi-Target Backdoor Attack (DMBA), ensuring efficiency and persistence of backdoors from different malicious clients. To avoid parameter conflicts, we design a multi-channel dispersed frequency trigger strategy to maximize trigger differences. To mitigate gradient interference, we introduce backdoor replay in local training to neutralize conflicting gradients. Extensive validation shows that 30 rounds after the attack, Attack Success Rates of three different backdoors from various clients remain above 93%. The code will be made publicly available after the review period.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03926v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tao Liu, Wu Yang, Chen Xu, Jiguang Lv, Huanran Wang, Yuhang Zhang, Shuchun Xu, Dapeng Man</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy Score-based Pseudo-Label Filtering and Adaptive Loss for Imbalanced Semi-supervised SAR target recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03959</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03959v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Automatic target recognition (ATR) is an important use case for synthetic aperture radar (SAR) image interpretation. Recent years have seen significant advancements in SAR ATR technology based on semi-supervised learning. However, existing semi-supervised SAR ATR algorithms show low recognition accuracy in the case of class imbalance. This work offers a non-balanced semi-supervised SAR target recognition approach using dynamic energy scores and adaptive loss. First, an energy score-based method is developed to dynamically select unlabeled samples near to the training distribution as pseudo-labels during training, assuring pseudo-label reliability in long-tailed distribution circumstances. Secondly, loss functions suitable for class imbalances are proposed, including adaptive margin perception loss and adaptive hard triplet loss, the former offsets inter-class confusion of classifiers, alleviating the imbalance issue inherent in pseudo-label generation. The latter effectively tackles the model's preference for the majority class by focusing on complex difficult samples during training. Experimental results on extremely imbalanced SAR datasets demonstrate that the proposed method performs well under the dual constraints of scarce labels and data imbalance, effectively overcoming the model bias caused by data imbalance and achieving high-precision target recognition.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03959v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xinzheng Zhang, Yuqing Luo, Guopeng Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Face Reconstruction from Face Embeddings using Adapter to a Face Foundation Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03960</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03960v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Face recognition systems extract embedding vectors from face images and use these embeddings to verify or identify individuals. Face reconstruction attack (also known as template inversion) refers to reconstructing face images from face embeddings and using the reconstructed face image to enter a face recognition system. In this paper, we propose to use a face foundation model to reconstruct face images from the embeddings of a blackbox face recognition model. The foundation model is trained with 42M images to generate face images from the facial embeddings of a fixed face recognition model. We propose to use an adapter to translate target embeddings into the embedding space of the foundation model. The generated images are evaluated on different face recognition models and different datasets, demonstrating the effectiveness of our method to translate embeddings of different face recognition models. We also evaluate the transferability of reconstructed face images when attacking different face recognition models. Our experimental results show that our reconstructed face images outperform previous reconstruction attacks against face recognition models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03960v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hatef Otroshi Shahreza, Anjith George, S\'ebastien Marcel</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HRDecoder: High-Resolution Decoder Network for Fundus Image Lesion Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03976</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03976v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: High resolution is crucial for precise segmentation in fundus images, yet handling high-resolution inputs incurs considerable GPU memory costs, with diminishing performance gains as overhead increases. To address this issue while tackling the challenge of segmenting tiny objects, recent studies have explored local-global fusion methods. These methods preserve fine details using local regions and capture long-range context information from downscaled global images. However, the necessity of multiple forward passes inevitably incurs significant computational overhead, adversely affecting inference speed. In this paper, we propose HRDecoder, a simple High-Resolution Decoder network for fundus lesion segmentation. It integrates a high-resolution representation learning module to capture fine-grained local features and a high-resolution fusion module to fuse multi-scale predictions. Our method effectively improves the overall segmentation accuracy of fundus lesions while consuming reasonable memory and computational overhead, and maintaining satisfying inference speed. Experimental results on the IDRID and DDR datasets demonstrate the effectiveness of our method. Code is available at https://github.com/CVIU-CSU/HRDecoder.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03976v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1007/978-3-031-72114-4_32</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>MICCAI 2024, LNCS 15009, pp. 1-11, 2024</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Ziyuan Ding, Yixiong Liang, Shichao Kan, Qing Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ReEdit: Multimodal Exemplar-Based Image Editing with Diffusion Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03982</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03982v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Modern Text-to-Image (T2I) Diffusion models have revolutionized image editing by enabling the generation of high-quality photorealistic images. While the de facto method for performing edits with T2I models is through text instructions, this approach non-trivial due to the complex many-to-many mapping between natural language and images. In this work, we address exemplar-based image editing -- the task of transferring an edit from an exemplar pair to a content image(s). We propose ReEdit, a modular and efficient end-to-end framework that captures edits in both text and image modalities while ensuring the fidelity of the edited image. We validate the effectiveness of ReEdit through extensive comparisons with state-of-the-art baselines and sensitivity analyses of key design choices. Our results demonstrate that ReEdit consistently outperforms contemporary approaches both qualitatively and quantitatively. Additionally, ReEdit boasts high practical applicability, as it does not require any task-specific optimization and is four times faster than the next best baseline.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03982v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ashutosh Srivastava, Tarun Ram Menta, Abhinav Java, Avadhoot Jadhav, Silky Singh, Surgan Jandial, Balaji Krishnamurthy</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local vs distributed representations: What is the right basis for interpretability?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03993</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03993v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Much of the research on the interpretability of deep neural networks has focused on studying the visual features that maximally activate individual neurons. However, recent work has cast doubts on the usefulness of such local representations for understanding the behavior of deep neural networks because individual neurons tend to respond to multiple unrelated visual patterns, a phenomenon referred to as "superposition". A promising alternative to disentangle these complex patterns is learning sparsely distributed vector representations from entire network layers, as the resulting basis vectors seemingly encode single identifiable visual patterns consistently. Thus, one would expect the resulting code to align better with human perceivable visual patterns, but supporting evidence remains, at best, anecdotal. To fill this gap, we conducted three large-scale psychophysics experiments collected from a pool of 560 participants. Our findings provide (i) strong evidence that features obtained from sparse distributed representations are easier to interpret by human observers and (ii) that this effect is more pronounced in the deepest layers of a neural network. Complementary analyses also reveal that (iii) features derived from sparse distributed representations contribute more to the model's decision. Overall, our results highlight that distributed representations constitute a superior basis for interpretability, underscoring a need for the field to move beyond the interpretation of local neural codes in favor of sparsely distributed ones.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03993v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Julien Colin, Lore Goetschalckx, Thomas Fel, Victor Boutin, Jay Gopal, Thomas Serre, Nuria Oliver</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aligning Characteristic Descriptors with Images for Human-Expert-like Explainability</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.04008</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.04008v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In mission-critical domains such as law enforcement and medical diagnosis, the ability to explain and interpret the outputs of deep learning models is crucial for ensuring user trust and supporting informed decision-making. Despite advancements in explainability, existing methods often fall short in providing explanations that mirror the depth and clarity of those given by human experts. Such expert-level explanations are essential for the dependable application of deep learning models in law enforcement and medical contexts. Additionally, we recognize that most explanations in real-world scenarios are communicated primarily through natural language. Addressing these needs, we propose a novel approach that utilizes characteristic descriptors to explain model decisions by identifying their presence in images, thereby generating expert-like explanations. Our method incorporates a concept bottleneck layer within the model architecture, which calculates the similarity between image and descriptor encodings to deliver inherent and faithful explanations. Through experiments in face recognition and chest X-ray diagnosis, we demonstrate that our approach offers a significant contrast over existing techniques, which are often limited to the use of saliency maps. We believe our approach represents a significant step toward making deep learning systems more accountable, transparent, and trustworthy in the critical domains of face recognition and medical diagnosis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.04008v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bharat Chandra Yalavarthi, Nalini Ratha</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pseudo-labeling with Keyword Refining for Few-Supervised Video Captioning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.04059</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.04059v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Video captioning generate a sentence that describes the video content. Existing methods always require a number of captions (\eg, 10 or 20) per video to train the model, which is quite costly. In this work, we explore the possibility of using only one or very few ground-truth sentences, and introduce a new task named few-supervised video captioning. Specifically, we propose a few-supervised video captioning framework that consists of lexically constrained pseudo-labeling module and keyword-refined captioning module. Unlike the random sampling in natural language processing that may cause invalid modifications (\ie, edit words), the former module guides the model to edit words using some actions (\eg, copy, replace, insert, and delete) by a pretrained token-level classifier, and then fine-tunes candidate sentences by a pretrained language model. Meanwhile, the former employs the repetition penalized sampling to encourage the model to yield concise pseudo-labeled sentences with less repetition, and selects the most relevant sentences upon a pretrained video-text model. Moreover, to keep semantic consistency between pseudo-labeled sentences and video content, we develop the transformer-based keyword refiner with the video-keyword gated fusion strategy to emphasize more on relevant words. Extensive experiments on several benchmarks demonstrate the advantages of the proposed approach in both few-supervised and fully-supervised scenarios. The code implementation is available at https://github.com/mlvccn/PKG_VidCap</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.04059v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ping Li, Tao Wang, Xinkui Zhao, Xianghua Xu, Mingli Song</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>H-POPE: Hierarchical Polling-based Probing Evaluation of Hallucinations in Large Vision-Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.04077</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.04077v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: By leveraging both texts and images, large vision language models (LVLMs) have shown significant progress in various multi-modal tasks. Nevertheless, these models often suffer from hallucinations, e.g., they exhibit inconsistencies between the visual input and the textual output. To address this, we propose H-POPE, a coarse-to-fine-grained benchmark that systematically assesses hallucination in object existence and attributes. Our evaluation shows that models are prone to hallucinations on object existence, and even more so on fine-grained attributes. We further investigate whether these models rely on visual input to formulate the output texts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.04077v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nhi Pham, Michael Schott</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Textual Decomposition Then Sub-motion-space Scattering for Open-Vocabulary Motion Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.04079</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.04079v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Text-to-motion generation is a crucial task in computer vision, which generates the target 3D motion by the given text. The existing annotated datasets are limited in scale, resulting in most existing methods overfitting to the small datasets and unable to generalize to the motions of the open domain. Some methods attempt to solve the open-vocabulary motion generation problem by aligning to the CLIP space or using the Pretrain-then-Finetuning paradigm. However, the current annotated dataset's limited scale only allows them to achieve mapping from sub-text-space to sub-motion-space, instead of mapping between full-text-space and full-motion-space (full mapping), which is the key to attaining open-vocabulary motion generation. To this end, this paper proposes to leverage the atomic motion (simple body part motions over a short time period) as an intermediate representation, and leverage two orderly coupled steps, i.e., Textual Decomposition and Sub-motion-space Scattering, to address the full mapping problem. For Textual Decomposition, we design a fine-grained description conversion algorithm, and combine it with the generalization ability of a large language model to convert any given motion text into atomic texts. Sub-motion-space Scattering learns the compositional process from atomic motions to the target motions, to make the learned sub-motion-space scattered to form the full-motion-space. For a given motion of the open domain, it transforms the extrapolation into interpolation and thereby significantly improves generalization. Our network, $DSO$-Net, combines textual $d$ecomposition and sub-motion-space $s$cattering to solve the $o$pen-vocabulary motion generation. Extensive experiments demonstrate that our DSO-Net achieves significant improvements over the state-of-the-art methods on open-vocabulary motion generation. Code is available at https://vankouf.github.io/DSONet/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.04079v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ke Fan, Jiangning Zhang, Ran Yi, Jingyu Gong, Yabiao Wang, Yating Wang, Xin Tan, Chengjie Wang, Lizhuang Ma</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RaVL: Discovering and Mitigating Spurious Correlations in Fine-Tuned Vision-Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.04097</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.04097v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Fine-tuned vision-language models (VLMs) often capture spurious correlations between image features and textual attributes, resulting in degraded zero-shot performance at test time. Existing approaches for addressing spurious correlations (i) primarily operate at the global image-level rather than intervening directly on fine-grained image features and (ii) are predominantly designed for unimodal settings. In this work, we present RaVL, which takes a fine-grained perspective on VLM robustness by discovering and mitigating spurious correlations using local image features rather than operating at the global image level. Given a fine-tuned VLM, RaVL first discovers spurious correlations by leveraging a region-level clustering approach to identify precise image features contributing to zero-shot classification errors. Then, RaVL mitigates the identified spurious correlation with a novel region-aware loss function that enables the VLM to focus on relevant regions and ignore spurious relationships during fine-tuning. We evaluate RaVL on 654 VLMs with various model architectures, data domains, and learned spurious correlations. Our results show that RaVL accurately discovers (191% improvement over the closest baseline) and mitigates (8.2% improvement on worst-group image classification accuracy) spurious correlations. Qualitative evaluations on general-domain and medical-domain VLMs confirm our findings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.04097v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Maya Varma, Jean-Benoit Delbrouck, Zhihong Chen, Akshay Chaudhari, Curtis Langlotz</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Community Forensics: Using Thousands of Generators to Train Fake Image Detectors</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.04125</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.04125v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: One of the key challenges of detecting AI-generated images is spotting images that have been created by previously unseen generative models. We argue that the limited diversity of the training data is a major obstacle to addressing this problem, and we propose a new dataset that is significantly larger and more diverse than prior work. As part of creating this dataset, we systematically download thousands of text-to-image latent diffusion models and sample images from them. We also collect images from dozens of popular open source and commercial models. The resulting dataset contains 2.7M images that have been sampled from 4803 different models. These images collectively capture a wide range of scene content, generator architectures, and image processing settings. Using this dataset, we study the generalization abilities of fake image detectors. Our experiments suggest that detection performance improves as the number of models in the training set increases, even when these models have similar architectures. We also find that detection performance improves as the diversity of the models increases, and that our trained detectors generalize better than those trained on other datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.04125v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jeongsoo Park, Andrew Owens</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interpretable Embeddings for Segmentation-Free Single-Cell Analysis in Multiplex Imaging</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03341</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03341v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Multiplex Imaging (MI) enables the simultaneous visualization of multiple biological markers in separate imaging channels at subcellular resolution, providing valuable insights into cell-type heterogeneity and spatial organization. However, current computational pipelines rely on cell segmentation algorithms, which require laborious fine-tuning and can introduce downstream errors due to inaccurate single-cell representations. We propose a segmentation-free deep learning approach that leverages grouped convolutions to learn interpretable embedded features from each imaging channel, enabling robust cell-type identification without manual feature selection. Validated on an Imaging Mass Cytometry dataset of 1.8 million cells from neuroblastoma patients, our method enables the accurate identification of known cell types, showcasing its scalability and suitability for high-dimensional MI data.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03341v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Simon Gutwein, Daria Lazic, Thomas Walter, Sabine Taschner-Mandl, Roxane Licandro</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Undermining Image and Text Classification Algorithms Using Adversarial Attacks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03348</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03348v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Machine learning models are prone to adversarial attacks, where inputs can be manipulated in order to cause misclassifications. While previous research has focused on techniques like Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs), there's limited exploration of GANs and Synthetic Minority Oversampling Technique (SMOTE) in text and image classification models to perform adversarial attacks. Our study addresses this gap by training various machine learning models and using GANs and SMOTE to generate additional data points aimed at attacking text classification models. Furthermore, we extend our investigation to face recognition models, training a Convolutional Neural Network(CNN) and subjecting it to adversarial attacks with fast gradient sign perturbations on key features identified by GradCAM, a technique used to highlight key image characteristics CNNs use in classification. Our experiments reveal a significant vulnerability in classification models. Specifically, we observe a 20 % decrease in accuracy for the top-performing text classification models post-attack, along with a 30 % decrease in facial recognition accuracy. This highlights the susceptibility of these models to manipulation of input data. Adversarial attacks not only compromise the security but also undermine the reliability of machine learning systems. By showcasing the impact of adversarial attacks on both text classification and face recognition models, our study underscores the urgent need for develop robust defenses against such vulnerabilities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03348v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Langalibalele Lunga, Suhas Sreehari</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solving Trojan Detection Competitions with Linear Weight Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03445</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03445v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Neural networks can conceal malicious Trojan backdoors that allow a trigger to covertly change the model behavior. Detecting signs of these backdoors, particularly without access to any triggered data, is the subject of ongoing research and open challenges. In one common formulation of the problem, we are given a set of clean and poisoned models and need to predict whether a given test model is clean or poisoned. In this paper, we introduce a detector that works remarkably well across many of the existing datasets and domains. It is obtained by training a binary classifier on a large number of models' weights after performing a few different pre-processing steps including feature selection and standardization, reference model weights subtraction, and model alignment prior to detection. We evaluate this algorithm on a diverse set of Trojan detection benchmarks and domains and examine the cases where the approach is most and least effective.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03445v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Todd Huster, Peter Lin, Razvan Stefanescu, Emmanuel Ekwedike, Ritu Chadha</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BOston Neonatal Brain Injury Data for Hypoxic Ischemic Encephalopathy (BONBID-HIE): II. 2-year Neurocognitive Outcome and NICU Outcome</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03456</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03456v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Hypoxic Ischemic Encephalopathy (HIE) affects approximately 1-5/1000 newborns globally and leads to adverse neurocognitive outcomes in 30% to 50% of cases by two years of age. Despite therapeutic advances with Therapeutic Hypothermia (TH), prognosis remains challenging, highlighting the need for improved biomarkers. This paper introduces the second release of the Boston Neonatal Brain Injury Dataset for Hypoxic-Ischemic Encephalopathy (BONBID-HIE), an open-source, comprehensive MRI and clinical dataset featuring 237 patients, including NICU outcomes and 2-year neurocognitive outcomes from Massachusetts General Hospital and Boston Children's Hospital.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03456v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rina Bao, Yangming Ou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TopoTxR: A topology-guided deep convolutional network for breast parenchyma learning on DCE-MRIs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03464</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03464v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Characterization of breast parenchyma in dynamic contrast-enhanced magnetic resonance imaging (DCE-MRI) is a challenging task owing to the complexity of underlying tissue structures. Existing quantitative approaches, like radiomics and deep learning models, lack explicit quantification of intricate and subtle parenchymal structures, including fibroglandular tissue. To address this, we propose a novel topological approach that explicitly extracts multi-scale topological structures to better approximate breast parenchymal structures, and then incorporates these structures into a deep-learning-based prediction model via an attention mechanism. Our topology-informed deep learning model, \emph{TopoTxR}, leverages topology to provide enhanced insights into tissues critical for disease pathophysiology and treatment response. We empirically validate \emph{TopoTxR} using the VICTRE phantom breast dataset, showing that the topological structures extracted by our model effectively approximate the breast parenchymal structures. We further demonstrate \emph{TopoTxR}'s efficacy in predicting response to neoadjuvant chemotherapy. Our qualitative and quantitative analyses suggest differential topological behavior of breast tissue in treatment-na\"ive imaging, in patients who respond favorably to therapy as achieving pathological complete response (pCR) versus those who do not. In a comparative analysis with several baselines on the publicly available I-SPY 1 dataset (N=161, including 47 patients with pCR and 114 without) and the Rutgers proprietary dataset (N=120, with 69 patients achieving pCR and 51 not), \emph{TopoTxR} demonstrates a notable improvement, achieving a 2.6\% increase in accuracy and a 4.6\% enhancement in AUC compared to the state-of-the-art method.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03464v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1016/j.media.2024.103373</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Volume 99, 2025, 103373</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Fan Wang, Zhilin Zou, Nicole Sakla, Luke Partyka, Nil Rawal, Gagandeep Singh, Wei Zhao, Haibin Ling, Chuan Huang, Prateek Prasanna, Chao Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Weakly Supervised Semantic Segmentation for Fibrosis via Controllable Image Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03551</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03551v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Fibrotic Lung Disease (FLD) is a severe condition marked by lung stiffening and scarring, leading to respiratory decline. High-resolution computed tomography (HRCT) is critical for diagnosing and monitoring FLD; however, fibrosis appears as irregular, diffuse patterns with unclear boundaries, leading to high inter-observer variability and time-intensive manual annotation. To tackle this challenge, we propose DiffSeg, a novel weakly supervised semantic segmentation (WSSS) method that uses image-level annotations to generate pixel-level fibrosis segmentation, reducing the need for fine-grained manual labeling. Additionally, our DiffSeg incorporates a diffusion-based generative model to synthesize HRCT images with different levels of fibrosis from healthy slices, enabling the generation of the fibrosis-injected slices and their paired fibrosis location. Experiments indicate that our method significantly improves the accuracy of pseudo masks generated by existing WSSS methods, greatly reducing the complexity of manual labeling and enhancing the consistency of the generated masks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03551v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhiling Yue, Yingying Fang, Liutao Yang, Nikhil Baid, Simon Walsh, Guang Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The American Sign Language Knowledge Graph: Infusing ASL Models with Linguistic Knowledge</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03568</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03568v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Language models for American Sign Language (ASL) could make language technologies substantially more accessible to those who sign. To train models on tasks such as isolated sign recognition (ISR) and ASL-to-English translation, datasets provide annotated video examples of ASL signs. To facilitate the generalizability and explainability of these models, we introduce the American Sign Language Knowledge Graph (ASLKG), compiled from twelve sources of expert linguistic knowledge. We use the ASLKG to train neuro-symbolic models for 3 ASL understanding tasks, achieving accuracies of 91% on ISR, 14% for predicting the semantic features of unseen signs, and 36% for classifying the topic of Youtube-ASL videos.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03568v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lee Kezar, Nidhi Munikote, Zian Zeng, Zed Sehyr, Naomi Caselli, Jesse Thomason</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Personalized Federated Learning via Comprehensive Knowledge Distillation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03569</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03569v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Federated learning is a distributed machine learning paradigm designed to protect data privacy. However, data heterogeneity across various clients results in catastrophic forgetting, where the model rapidly forgets previous knowledge while acquiring new knowledge. To address this challenge, personalized federated learning has emerged to customize a personalized model for each client. However, the inherent limitation of this mechanism is its excessive focus on personalization, potentially hindering the generalization of those models. In this paper, we present a novel personalized federated learning method that uses global and historical models as teachers and the local model as the student to facilitate comprehensive knowledge distillation. The historical model represents the local model from the last round of client training, containing historical personalized knowledge, while the global model represents the aggregated model from the last round of server aggregation, containing global generalized knowledge. By applying knowledge distillation, we effectively transfer global generalized knowledge and historical personalized knowledge to the local model, thus mitigating catastrophic forgetting and enhancing the general performance of personalized models. Extensive experimental results demonstrate the significant advantages of our method.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03569v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Pengju Wang, Bochao Liu, Weijia Guo, Yong Li, Shiming Ge</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LCP-Fusion: A Neural Implicit SLAM with Enhanced Local Constraints and Computable Prior</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03610</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03610v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recently the dense Simultaneous Localization and Mapping (SLAM) based on neural implicit representation has shown impressive progress in hole filling and high-fidelity mapping. Nevertheless, existing methods either heavily rely on known scene bounds or suffer inconsistent reconstruction due to drift in potential loop-closure regions, or both, which can be attributed to the inflexible representation and lack of local constraints. In this paper, we present LCP-Fusion, a neural implicit SLAM system with enhanced local constraints and computable prior, which takes the sparse voxel octree structure containing feature grids and SDF priors as hybrid scene representation, enabling the scalability and robustness during mapping and tracking. To enhance the local constraints, we propose a novel sliding window selection strategy based on visual overlap to address the loop-closure, and a practical warping loss to constrain relative poses. Moreover, we estimate SDF priors as coarse initialization for implicit features, which brings additional explicit constraints and robustness, especially when a light but efficient adaptive early ending is adopted. Experiments demonstrate that our method achieve better localization accuracy and reconstruction consistency than existing RGB-D implicit SLAM, especially in challenging real scenes (ScanNet) as well as self-captured scenes with unknown scene bounds. The code is available at https://github.com/laliwang/LCP-Fusion.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03610v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiahui Wang, Yinan Deng, Yi Yang, Yufeng Yue</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ADMIRE: a locally adaptive single-image, non-uniformity correction and denoising algorithm: application to uncooled IR camera</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03615</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03615v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We propose a new way to correct for the non-uniformity (NU) and the noise in uncooled infrared-type images. This method works on static images, needs no registration, no camera motion and no model for the non uniformity. The proposed method uses an hybrid scheme including an automatic locally-adaptive contrast adjustment and a state-of-the-art image denoising method. It permits to correct for a fully non-linear NU and the noise efficiently using only one image. We compared it with total variation on real raw and simulated NU infrared images. The strength of this approach lies in its simplicity, low computational cost. It needs no test-pattern or calibration and produces no "ghost-artefact".</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03615v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1117/12.912966</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>SPIE Defense, Security and Sensing conference,Proceedings Volume 8353, Infrared Technology and Applications XXXVIII; 83531O, April 2012</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Yohann Tendero, Jerome Gilles</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cross Feature Fusion of Fundus Image and Generated Lesion Map for Referable Diabetic Retinopathy Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03618</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03618v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Diabetic Retinopathy (DR) is a primary cause of blindness, necessitating early detection and diagnosis. This paper focuses on referable DR classification to enhance the applicability of the proposed method in clinical practice. We develop an advanced cross-learning DR classification method leveraging transfer learning and cross-attention mechanisms. The proposed method employs the Swin U-Net architecture to segment lesion maps from DR fundus images. The Swin U-Net segmentation model, enriched with DR lesion insights, is transferred to generate a lesion map. Both the fundus image and its segmented lesion map are used as complementary inputs for the classification model. A cross-attention mechanism is deployed to improve the model's ability to capture fine-grained details from the input pairs. Our experiments, utilizing two public datasets, FGADR and EyePACS, demonstrate a superior accuracy of 94.6%, surpassing current state-of-the-art methods by 4.4%. To this end, we aim for the proposed method to be seamlessly integrated into clinical workflows, enhancing accuracy and efficiency in identifying referable DR.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03618v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dahyun Mok, Junghyun Bum, Le Duc Tai, Hyunseung Choo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zero-shot Dynamic MRI Reconstruction with Global-to-local Diffusion Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03723</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03723v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Diffusion models have recently demonstrated considerable advancement in the generation and reconstruction of magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) data. These models exhibit great potential in handling unsampled data and reducing noise, highlighting their promise as generative models. However, their application in dynamic MRI remains relatively underexplored. This is primarily due to the substantial amount of fully-sampled data typically required for training, which is difficult to obtain in dynamic MRI due to its spatio-temporal complexity and high acquisition costs. To address this challenge, we propose a dynamic MRI reconstruction method based on a time-interleaved acquisition scheme, termed the Glob-al-to-local Diffusion Model. Specifically, fully encoded full-resolution reference data are constructed by merging under-sampled k-space data from adjacent time frames, generating two distinct bulk training datasets for global and local models. The global-to-local diffusion framework alternately optimizes global information and local image details, enabling zero-shot reconstruction. Extensive experiments demonstrate that the proposed method performs well in terms of noise reduction and detail preservation, achieving reconstruction quality comparable to that of supervised approaches.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03723v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yu Guan, Kunlong Zhang, Qi Qi, Dong Wang, Ziwen Ke, Shaoyu Wang, Dong Liang, Qiegen Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NeurIPS 2023 Competition: Privacy Preserving Federated Learning Document VQA</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03730</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03730v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The Privacy Preserving Federated Learning Document VQA (PFL-DocVQA) competition challenged the community to develop provably private and communication-efficient solutions in a federated setting for a real-life use case: invoice processing. The competition introduced a dataset of real invoice documents, along with associated questions and answers requiring information extraction and reasoning over the document images. Thereby, it brings together researchers and expertise from the document analysis, privacy, and federated learning communities. Participants fine-tuned a pre-trained, state-of-the-art Document Visual Question Answering model provided by the organizers for this new domain, mimicking a typical federated invoice processing setup. The base model is a multi-modal generative language model, and sensitive information could be exposed through either the visual or textual input modality. Participants proposed elegant solutions to reduce communication costs while maintaining a minimum utility threshold in track 1 and to protect all information from each document provider using differential privacy in track 2. The competition served as a new testbed for developing and testing private federated learning methods, simultaneously raising awareness about privacy within the document image analysis and recognition community. Ultimately, the competition analysis provides best practices and recommendations for successfully running privacy-focused federated learning challenges in the future.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03730v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Marlon Tobaben, Mohamed Ali Souibgui, Rub\`en Tito, Khanh Nguyen, Raouf Kerkouche, Kangsoo Jung, Joonas J\"alk\"o, Lei Kang, Andrey Barsky, Vincent Poulain d'Andecy, Aur\'elie Joseph, Aashiq Muhamed, Kevin Kuo, Virginia Smith, Yusuke Yamasaki, Takumi Fukami, Kenta Niwa, Iifan Tyou, Hiro Ishii, Rio Yokota, Ragul N, Rintu Kutum, Josep Llados, Ernest Valveny, Antti Honkela, Mario Fritz, Dimosthenis Karatzas</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deferred Poisoning: Making the Model More Vulnerable via Hessian Singularization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03752</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03752v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recent studies have shown that deep learning models are very vulnerable to poisoning attacks. Many defense methods have been proposed to address this issue. However, traditional poisoning attacks are not as threatening as commonly believed. This is because they often cause differences in how the model performs on the training set compared to the validation set. Such inconsistency can alert defenders that their data has been poisoned, allowing them to take the necessary defensive actions. In this paper, we introduce a more threatening type of poisoning attack called the Deferred Poisoning Attack. This new attack allows the model to function normally during the training and validation phases but makes it very sensitive to evasion attacks or even natural noise. We achieve this by ensuring the poisoned model's loss function has a similar value as a normally trained model at each input sample but with a large local curvature. A similar model loss ensures that there is no obvious inconsistency between the training and validation accuracy, demonstrating high stealthiness. On the other hand, the large curvature implies that a small perturbation may cause a significant increase in model loss, leading to substantial performance degradation, which reflects a worse robustness. We fulfill this purpose by making the model have singular Hessian information at the optimal point via our proposed Singularization Regularization term. We have conducted both theoretical and empirical analyses of the proposed method and validated its effectiveness through experiments on image classification tasks. Furthermore, we have confirmed the hazards of this form of poisoning attack under more general scenarios using natural noise, offering a new perspective for research in the field of security.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03752v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuhao He, Jinyu Tian, Xianwei Zheng, Li Dong, Yuanman Li, Leo Yu Zhang, Jiantao Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sub-DM:Subspace Diffusion Model with Orthogonal Decomposition for MRI Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03758</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03758v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Diffusion model-based approaches recently achieved re-markable success in MRI reconstruction, but integration into clinical routine remains challenging due to its time-consuming convergence. This phenomenon is partic-ularly notable when directly apply conventional diffusion process to k-space data without considering the inherent properties of k-space sampling, limiting k-space learning efficiency and image reconstruction quality. To tackle these challenges, we introduce subspace diffusion model with orthogonal decomposition, a method (referred to as Sub-DM) that restrict the diffusion process via projections onto subspace as the k-space data distribution evolves toward noise. Particularly, the subspace diffusion model circumvents the inference challenges posed by the com-plex and high-dimensional characteristics of k-space data, so the highly compact subspace ensures that diffusion process requires only a few simple iterations to produce accurate prior information. Furthermore, the orthogonal decomposition strategy based on wavelet transform hin-ders the information loss during the migration of the vanilla diffusion process to the subspace. Considering the strate-gy is approximately reversible, such that the entire pro-cess can be reversed. As a result, it allows the diffusion processes in different spaces to refine models through a mutual feedback mechanism, enabling the learning of ac-curate prior even when dealing with complex k-space data. Comprehensive experiments on different datasets clearly demonstrate that the superiority of Sub-DM against state of-the-art methods in terms of reconstruction speed and quality.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03758v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yu Guan, Qinrong Cai, Wei Li, Qiuyun Fan, Dong Liang, Qiegen Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MambaPEFT: Exploring Parameter-Efficient Fine-Tuning for Mamba</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03855</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03855v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: An ecosystem of Transformer-based models has been established by building large models with extensive data. Parameter-efficient fine-tuning (PEFT) is a crucial technology for deploying these models to downstream tasks with minimal cost while achieving effective performance. Recently, Mamba, a State Space Model (SSM)-based model, has attracted attention as a potential alternative to Transformers. While many large-scale Mamba-based models have been proposed, efficiently adapting pre-trained Mamba-based models to downstream tasks remains unexplored. In this paper, we conduct an exploratory analysis of PEFT methods for Mamba. We investigate the effectiveness of existing PEFT methods for Transformers when applied to Mamba. We also modify these methods to better align with the Mamba architecture. Additionally, we propose new Mamba-specific PEFT methods that leverage the distinctive structure of Mamba. Our experiments indicate that PEFT performs more effectively for Mamba than Transformers. Lastly, we demonstrate how to effectively combine multiple PEFT methods and provide a framework that outperforms previous works. To ensure reproducibility, we will release the code after publication.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03855v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Masakazu Yoshimura, Teruaki Hayashi, Yota Maeda</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ET-SEED: Efficient Trajectory-Level SE(3) Equivariant Diffusion Policy</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03990</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03990v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Imitation learning, e.g., diffusion policy, has been proven effective in various robotic manipulation tasks. However, extensive demonstrations are required for policy robustness and generalization. To reduce the demonstration reliance, we leverage spatial symmetry and propose ET-SEED, an efficient trajectory-level SE(3) equivariant diffusion model for generating action sequences in complex robot manipulation tasks. Further, previous equivariant diffusion models require the per-step equivariance in the Markov process, making it difficult to learn policy under such strong constraints. We theoretically extend equivariant Markov kernels and simplify the condition of equivariant diffusion process, thereby significantly improving training efficiency for trajectory-level SE(3) equivariant diffusion policy in an end-to-end manner. We evaluate ET-SEED on representative robotic manipulation tasks, involving rigid body, articulated and deformable object. Experiments demonstrate superior data efficiency and manipulation proficiency of our proposed method, as well as its ability to generalize to unseen configurations with only a few demonstrations. Website: https://et-seed.github.io/</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03990v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chenrui Tie, Yue Chen, Ruihai Wu, Boxuan Dong, Zeyi Li, Chongkai Gao, Hao Dong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synomaly Noise and Multi-Stage Diffusion: A Novel Approach for Unsupervised Anomaly Detection in Ultrasound Imaging</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.04004</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.04004v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Ultrasound (US) imaging is widely used in routine clinical practice due to its advantages of being radiation-free, cost-effective, and portable. However, the low reproducibility and quality of US images, combined with the scarcity of expert-level annotation, make the training of fully supervised segmentation models challenging. To address these issues, we propose a novel unsupervised anomaly detection framework based on a diffusion model that incorporates a synthetic anomaly (Synomaly) noise function and a multi-stage diffusion process. Synomaly noise introduces synthetic anomalies into healthy images during training, allowing the model to effectively learn anomaly removal. The multi-stage diffusion process is introduced to progressively denoise images, preserving fine details while improving the quality of anomaly-free reconstructions. The generated high-fidelity counterfactual healthy images can further enhance the interpretability of the segmentation models, as well as provide a reliable baseline for evaluating the extent of anomalies and supporting clinical decision-making. Notably, the unsupervised anomaly detection model is trained purely on healthy images, eliminating the need for anomalous training samples and pixel-level annotations. We validate the proposed approach on carotid US, brain MRI, and liver CT datasets. The experimental results demonstrate that the proposed framework outperforms existing state-of-the-art unsupervised anomaly detection methods, achieving performance comparable to fully supervised segmentation models in the US dataset. Additionally, ablation studies underline the importance of hyperparameter selection for Synomaly noise and the effectiveness of the multi-stage diffusion process in enhancing model performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.04004v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuan Bi, Lucie Huang, Ricarda Clarenbach, Reza Ghotbi, Angelos Karlas, Nassir Navab, Zhongliang Jiang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-branch Spatio-Temporal Graph Neural Network For Efficient Ice Layer Thickness Prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.04055</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.04055v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Understanding spatio-temporal patterns in polar ice layers is essential for tracking changes in ice sheet balance and assessing ice dynamics. While convolutional neural networks are widely used in learning ice layer patterns from raw echogram images captured by airborne snow radar sensors, noise in the echogram images prevents researchers from getting high-quality results. Instead, we focus on geometric deep learning using graph neural networks, aiming to build a spatio-temporal graph neural network that learns from thickness information of the top ice layers and predicts for deeper layers. In this paper, we developed a novel multi-branch spatio-temporal graph neural network that used the GraphSAGE framework for spatio features learning and a temporal convolution operation to capture temporal changes, enabling different branches of the network to be more specialized and focusing on a single learning task. We found that our proposed multi-branch network can consistently outperform the current fused spatio-temporal graph neural network in both accuracy and efficiency.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.04055v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zesheng Liu, Maryam Rahnemoonfar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fed-EC: Bandwidth-Efficient Clustering-Based Federated Learning For Autonomous Visual Robot Navigation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.04112</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.04112v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Centralized learning requires data to be aggregated at a central server, which poses significant challenges in terms of data privacy and bandwidth consumption. Federated learning presents a compelling alternative, however, vanilla federated learning methods deployed in robotics aim to learn a single global model across robots that works ideally for all. But in practice one model may not be well suited for robots deployed in various environments. This paper proposes Federated-EmbedCluster (Fed-EC), a clustering-based federated learning framework that is deployed with vision based autonomous robot navigation in diverse outdoor environments. The framework addresses the key federated learning challenge of deteriorating model performance of a single global model due to the presence of non-IID data across real-world robots. Extensive real-world experiments validate that Fed-EC reduces the communication size by 23x for each robot while matching the performance of centralized learning for goal-oriented navigation and outperforms local learning. Fed-EC can transfer previously learnt models to new robots that join the cluster.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.04112v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.DC</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shreya Gummadi, Mateus V. Gasparino, Deepak Vasisht, Girish Chowdhary</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CPnP: Consistent Pose Estimator for Perspective-n-Point Problem with Bias Elimination</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2209.05824</link>
      <description>arXiv:2209.05824v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The Perspective-n-Point (PnP) problem has been widely studied in both computer vision and photogrammetry societies. With the development of feature extraction techniques, a large number of feature points might be available in a single shot. It is promising to devise a consistent estimator, i.e., the estimate can converge to the true camera pose as the number of points increases. To this end, we propose a consistent PnP solver, named \emph{CPnP}, with bias elimination. Specifically, linear equations are constructed from the original projection model via measurement model modification and variable elimination, based on which a closed-form least-squares solution is obtained. We then analyze and subtract the asymptotic bias of this solution, resulting in a consistent estimate. Additionally, Gauss-Newton (GN) iterations are executed to refine the consistent solution. Our proposed estimator is efficient in terms of computations -- it has $O(n)$ computational complexity. Experimental tests on both synthetic data and real images show that our proposed estimator is superior to some well-known ones for images with dense visual features, in terms of estimation precision and computing time.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2209.05824v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Guangyang Zeng, Shiyu Chen, Biqiang Mu, Guodong Shi, Junfeng Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EViT: An Eagle Vision Transformer with Bi-Fovea Self-Attention</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.06629</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.06629v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Owing to advancements in deep learning technology, Vision Transformers (ViTs) have demonstrated impressive performance in various computer vision tasks. Nonetheless, ViTs still face some challenges, such as high computational complexity and the absence of desirable inductive biases. To alleviate these issues, {the potential advantages of combining eagle vision with ViTs are explored. We summarize a Bi-Fovea Visual Interaction (BFVI) structure inspired by the unique physiological and visual characteristics of eagle eyes. A novel Bi-Fovea Self-Attention (BFSA) mechanism and Bi-Fovea Feedforward Network (BFFN) are proposed based on this structural design approach, which can be used to mimic the hierarchical and parallel information processing scheme of the biological visual cortex, enabling networks to learn feature representations of targets in a coarse-to-fine manner. Furthermore, a Bionic Eagle Vision (BEV) block is designed as the basic building unit based on the BFSA mechanism and BFFN. By stacking BEV blocks, a unified and efficient family of pyramid backbone networks called Eagle Vision Transformers (EViTs) is developed. Experimental results show that EViTs exhibit highly competitive performance in various computer vision tasks, such as image classification, object detection and semantic segmentation. Compared with other approaches, EViTs have significant advantages, especially in terms of performance and computational efficiency. Code is available at https://github.com/nkusyl/EViT</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.06629v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yulong Shi, Mingwei Sun, Yongshuai Wang, Jiahao Ma, Zengqiang Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Data Perspective on Enhanced Identity Preservation for Diffusion Personalization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.04315</link>
      <description>arXiv:2311.04315v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large text-to-image models have revolutionized the ability to generate imagery using natural language. However, particularly unique or personal visual concepts, such as pets and furniture, will not be captured by the original model. This has led to interest in how to personalize a text-to-image model. Despite significant progress, this task remains a formidable challenge, particularly in preserving the subject's identity. Most researchers attempt to address this issue by modifying model architectures. These methods are capable of keeping the subject structure and color but fail to preserve identity details. Towards this issue, our approach takes a data-centric perspective. We introduce a novel regularization dataset generation strategy on both the text and image level. This strategy enables the model to preserve fine details of the desired subjects, such as text and logos. Our method is architecture-agnostic and can be flexibly applied on various text-to-image models. We show on established benchmarks that our data-centric approach forms the new state of the art in terms of identity preservation and text alignment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2311.04315v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xingzhe He, Zhiwen Cao, Nicholas Kolkin, Lantao Yu, Kun Wan, Helge Rhodin, Ratheesh Kalarot</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LifelongMemory: Leveraging LLMs for Answering Queries in Long-form Egocentric Videos</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.05269</link>
      <description>arXiv:2312.05269v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this paper we introduce LifelongMemory, a new framework for accessing long-form egocentric videographic memory through natural language question answering and retrieval. LifelongMemory generates concise video activity descriptions of the camera wearer and leverages the zero-shot capabilities of pretrained large language models to perform reasoning over long-form video context. Furthermore, LifelongMemory uses a confidence and explanation module to produce confident, high-quality, and interpretable answers. Our approach achieves state-of-the-art performance on the EgoSchema benchmark for question answering and is highly competitive on the natural language query (NLQ) challenge of Ego4D. Code is available at https://github.com/agentic-learning-ai-lab/lifelong-memory.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2312.05269v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ying Wang, Yanlai Yang, Mengye Ren</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cross-Task Affinity Learning for Multitask Dense Scene Predictions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.11124</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.11124v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Multitask learning (MTL) has become prominent for its ability to predict multiple tasks jointly, achieving better per-task performance with fewer parameters than single-task learning. Recently, decoder-focused architectures have significantly improved multitask performance by refining task predictions using features from related tasks. However, most refinement methods struggle to efficiently capture both local and long-range dependencies between task-specific representations and cross-task patterns. In this paper, we introduce the Cross-Task Affinity Learning (CTAL) module, a lightweight framework that enhances task refinement in multitask networks. CTAL effectively captures local and long-range cross-task interactions by optimizing task affinity matrices for parameter-efficient grouped convolutions without concern for information loss. Our results demonstrate state-of-the-art MTL performance for both CNN and transformer backbones, using significantly fewer parameters than single-task learning. Our code is publicly available at https://github.com/Armanfard-Lab/EMA-Net.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.11124v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dimitrios Sinodinos, Narges Armanfard</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LDTrack: Dynamic People Tracking by Service Robots using Diffusion Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.08774</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.08774v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Tracking of dynamic people in cluttered and crowded human-centered environments is a challenging robotics problem due to the presence of intraclass variations including occlusions, pose deformations, and lighting variations. This paper introduces a novel deep learning architecture, using conditional latent diffusion models, the Latent Diffusion Track (LDTrack), for tracking multiple dynamic people under intraclass variations. By uniquely utilizing conditional latent diffusion models to capture temporal person embeddings, our architecture can adapt to appearance changes of people over time. We incorporated a latent feature encoder network which enables the diffusion process to operate within a high-dimensional latent space to allow for the extraction and spatial-temporal refinement of such rich features as person appearance, motion, location, identity, and contextual information. Extensive experiments demonstrate the effectiveness of LDTrack over other state-of-the-art tracking methods in cluttered and crowded human-centered environments under intraclass variations. Namely, the results show our method outperforms existing deep learning robotic people tracking methods in both tracking accuracy and tracking precision with statistical significance. Additionally, a comprehensive multi-object tracking comparison study was performed against the state-of-the-art methods in urban environments, demonstrating the generalizability of LDTrack. An ablation study was performed to validate the design choices of LDTrack.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.08774v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Angus Fung, Beno Benhabib, Goldie Nejat</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VHM: Versatile and Honest Vision Language Model for Remote Sensing Image Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.20213</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.20213v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper develops a Versatile and Honest vision language Model (VHM) for remote sensing image analysis. VHM is built on a large-scale remote sensing image-text dataset with rich-content captions (VersaD), and an honest instruction dataset comprising both factual and deceptive questions (HnstD). Unlike prevailing remote sensing image-text datasets, in which image captions focus on a few prominent objects and their relationships, VersaD captions provide detailed information about image properties, object attributes, and the overall scene. This comprehensive captioning enables VHM to thoroughly understand remote sensing images and perform diverse remote sensing tasks. Moreover, different from existing remote sensing instruction datasets that only include factual questions, HnstD contains additional deceptive questions stemming from the non-existence of objects. This feature prevents VHM from producing affirmative answers to nonsense queries, thereby ensuring its honesty. In our experiments, VHM significantly outperforms various vision language models on common tasks of scene classification, visual question answering, and visual grounding. Additionally, VHM achieves competent performance on several unexplored tasks, such as building vectorizing, multi-label classification and honest question answering. We will release the code, data and model weights at https://github.com/opendatalab/VHM .</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.20213v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chao Pang, Xingxing Weng, Jiang Wu, Jiayu Li, Yi Liu, Jiaxing Sun, Weijia Li, Shuai Wang, Litong Feng, Gui-Song Xia, Conghui He</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OmniGS: Fast Radiance Field Reconstruction using Omnidirectional Gaussian Splatting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.03202</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.03202v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Photorealistic reconstruction relying on 3D Gaussian Splatting has shown promising potential in various domains. However, the current 3D Gaussian Splatting system only supports radiance field reconstruction using undistorted perspective images. In this paper, we present OmniGS, a novel omnidirectional Gaussian splatting system, to take advantage of omnidirectional images for fast radiance field reconstruction. Specifically, we conduct a theoretical analysis of spherical camera model derivatives in 3D Gaussian Splatting. According to the derivatives, we then implement a new GPU-accelerated omnidirectional rasterizer that directly splats 3D Gaussians onto the equirectangular screen space for omnidirectional image rendering. We realize differentiable optimization of the omnidirectional radiance field without the requirement of cube-map rectification or tangent-plane approximation. Extensive experiments conducted in egocentric and roaming scenarios demonstrate that our method achieves state-of-the-art reconstruction quality and high rendering speed using omnidirectional images. The code will be publicly available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.03202v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Longwei Li, Huajian Huang, Sai-Kit Yeung, Hui Cheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Concept-Attention Whitening for Interpretable Skin Lesion Diagnosis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.05997</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.05997v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The black-box nature of deep learning models has raised concerns about their interpretability for successful deployment in real-world clinical applications. To address the concerns, eXplainable Artificial Intelligence (XAI) aims to provide clear and understandable explanations of the decision-making process. In the medical domain, concepts such as attributes of lesions or abnormalities serve as key evidence for deriving diagnostic results. Existing concept-based models mainly depend on concepts that appear independently and require fine-grained concept annotations such as bounding boxes. However, a medical image usually contains multiple concepts, and the fine-grained concept annotations are difficult to acquire. In this paper, we aim to interpret representations in deep neural networks by aligning the axes of the latent space with known concepts of interest. We propose a novel Concept-Attention Whitening (CAW) framework for interpretable skin lesion diagnosis. CAW is comprised of a disease diagnosis branch and a concept alignment branch. In the former branch, we train a convolutional neural network (CNN) with an inserted CAW layer to perform skin lesion diagnosis. The CAW layer decorrelates features and aligns image features to conceptual meanings via an orthogonal matrix. In the latter branch, the orthogonal matrix is calculated under the guidance of the concept attention mask. We particularly introduce a weakly-supervised concept mask generator that only leverages coarse concept labels for filtering local regions that are relevant to certain concepts, improving the optimization of the orthogonal matrix. Extensive experiments on two public skin lesion diagnosis datasets demonstrated that CAW not only enhanced interpretability but also maintained a state-of-the-art diagnostic performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.05997v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junlin Hou, Jilan Xu, Hao Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Applying Guidance in a Limited Interval Improves Sample and Distribution Quality in Diffusion Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.07724</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.07724v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Guidance is a crucial technique for extracting the best performance out of image-generating diffusion models. Traditionally, a constant guidance weight has been applied throughout the sampling chain of an image. We show that guidance is clearly harmful toward the beginning of the chain (high noise levels), largely unnecessary toward the end (low noise levels), and only beneficial in the middle. We thus restrict it to a specific range of noise levels, improving both the inference speed and result quality. This limited guidance interval improves the record FID in ImageNet-512 significantly, from 1.81 to 1.40. We show that it is quantitatively and qualitatively beneficial across different sampler parameters, network architectures, and datasets, including the large-scale setting of Stable Diffusion XL. We thus suggest exposing the guidance interval as a hyperparameter in all diffusion models that use guidance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.07724v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.NE</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tuomas Kynk\"a\"anniemi, Miika Aittala, Tero Karras, Samuli Laine, Timo Aila, Jaakko Lehtinen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-Context Translation: Towards Unifying Image Recognition, Processing, and Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.09633</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.09633v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We propose In-Context Translation (ICT), a general learning framework to unify visual recognition (e.g., semantic segmentation), low-level image processing (e.g., denoising), and conditional image generation (e.g., edge-to-image synthesis). Thanks to unification, ICT significantly reduces the inherent inductive bias that comes with designing models for specific tasks, and it maximizes mutual enhancement across similar tasks. However, the unification across a large number of tasks is non-trivial due to various data formats and training pipelines. To this end, ICT introduces two designs. Firstly, it standardizes input-output data of different tasks into RGB image pairs, e.g., semantic segmentation data pairs an RGB image with its segmentation mask in the same RGB format. This turns different tasks into a general translation task between two RGB images. Secondly, it standardizes the training of different tasks into a general in-context learning, where "in-context" means the input comprises an example input-output pair of the target task and a query image. The learning objective is to generate the "missing" data paired with the query. The implicit translation process is thus between the query and the generated image. In experiments, ICT unifies ten vision tasks and showcases impressive performance on their respective benchmarks. Notably, ICT performs well across three major categories of computer vision tasks, while its two competitors (Painter and PromptDiffusion) are only effective in at most two of these task categories. In addition, compared to its competitors, ICT trained on only 4 RTX 3090 GPUs is shown to be more efficient and less costly in training.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.09633v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Han Xue, Qianru Sun, Li Song, Wenjun Zhang, Zhiwu Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ODGEN: Domain-specific Object Detection Data Generation with Diffusion Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.15199</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.15199v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Modern diffusion-based image generative models have made significant progress and become promising to enrich training data for the object detection task. However, the generation quality and the controllability for complex scenes containing multi-class objects and dense objects with occlusions remain limited. This paper presents ODGEN, a novel method to generate high-quality images conditioned on bounding boxes, thereby facilitating data synthesis for object detection. Given a domain-specific object detection dataset, we first fine-tune a pre-trained diffusion model on both cropped foreground objects and entire images to fit target distributions. Then we propose to control the diffusion model using synthesized visual prompts with spatial constraints and object-wise textual descriptions. ODGEN exhibits robustness in handling complex scenes and specific domains. Further, we design a dataset synthesis pipeline to evaluate ODGEN on 7 domain-specific benchmarks to demonstrate its effectiveness. Adding training data generated by ODGEN improves up to 25.3% mAP@.50:.95 with object detectors like YOLOv5 and YOLOv7, outperforming prior controllable generative methods. In addition, we design an evaluation protocol based on COCO-2014 to validate ODGEN in general domains and observe an advantage up to 5.6% in mAP@.50:.95 against existing methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.15199v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jingyuan Zhu, Shiyu Li, Yuxuan Liu, Ping Huang, Jiulong Shan, Huimin Ma, Jian Yuan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DC-Gaussian: Improving 3D Gaussian Splatting for Reflective Dash Cam Videos</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.17705</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.17705v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We present DC-Gaussian, a new method for generating novel views from in-vehicle dash cam videos. While neural rendering techniques have made significant strides in driving scenarios, existing methods are primarily designed for videos collected by autonomous vehicles. However, these videos are limited in both quantity and diversity compared to dash cam videos, which are more widely used across various types of vehicles and capture a broader range of scenarios. Dash cam videos often suffer from severe obstructions such as reflections and occlusions on the windshields, which significantly impede the application of neural rendering techniques. To address this challenge, we develop DC-Gaussian based on the recent real-time neural rendering technique 3D Gaussian Splatting (3DGS). Our approach includes an adaptive image decomposition module to model reflections and occlusions in a unified manner. Additionally, we introduce illumination-aware obstruction modeling to manage reflections and occlusions under varying lighting conditions. Lastly, we employ a geometry-guided Gaussian enhancement strategy to improve rendering details by incorporating additional geometry priors. Experiments on self-captured and public dash cam videos show that our method not only achieves state-of-the-art performance in novel view synthesis, but also accurately reconstructing captured scenes getting rid of obstructions. See the project page for code, data: https://linhanwang.github.io/dcgaussian/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.17705v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Linhan Wang, Kai Cheng, Shuo Lei, Shengkun Wang, Wei Yin, Chenyang Lei, Xiaoxiao Long, Chang-Tien Lu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Multi-Dimensional Evaluation of Flowchart Comprehension for Multimodal Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10057</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10057v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: With the development of Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) technology, its general capabilities are increasingly powerful. To evaluate the various abilities of MLLMs, numerous evaluation systems have emerged. But now there is still a lack of a comprehensive method to evaluate MLLMs in the tasks related to flowcharts, which are very important in daily life and work. We propose the first comprehensive method, FlowCE, to assess MLLMs across various dimensions for tasks related to flowcharts. It encompasses evaluating MLLMs' abilities in Reasoning, Localization Recognition, Information Extraction, Logical Verification, and Summarization on flowcharts. However, we find that even the GPT4o model achieves only a score of 56.63. Among open-source models, Phi-3-Vision obtained the highest score of 49.97. We hope that FlowCE can contribute to future research on MLLMs for tasks based on flowcharts. \url{https://github.com/360AILABNLP/FlowCE}</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10057v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Enming Zhang, Ruobing Yao, Huanyong Liu, Junhui Yu, Jiale Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identifying and Solving Conditional Image Leakage in Image-to-Video Diffusion Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.15735</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.15735v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Diffusion models have obtained substantial progress in image-to-video generation. However, in this paper, we find that these models tend to generate videos with less motion than expected. We attribute this to the issue called conditional image leakage, where the image-to-video diffusion models (I2V-DMs) tend to over-rely on the conditional image at large time steps. We further address this challenge from both inference and training aspects. First, we propose to start the generation process from an earlier time step to avoid the unreliable large-time steps of I2V-DMs, as well as an initial noise distribution with optimal analytic expressions (Analytic-Init) by minimizing the KL divergence between it and the actual marginal distribution to bridge the training-inference gap. Second, we design a time-dependent noise distribution (TimeNoise) for the conditional image during training, applying higher noise levels at larger time steps to disrupt it and reduce the model's dependency on it. We validate these general strategies on various I2V-DMs on our collected open-domain image benchmark and the UCF101 dataset. Extensive results show that our methods outperform baselines by producing higher motion scores with lower errors while maintaining image alignment and temporal consistency, thereby yielding superior overall performance and enabling more accurate motion control. The project page: \url{https://cond-image-leak.github.io/}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.15735v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Min Zhao, Hongzhou Zhu, Chendong Xiang, Kaiwen Zheng, Chongxuan Li, Jun Zhu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>D2SP: Dynamic Dual-Stage Purification Framework for Dual Noise Mitigation in Vision-based Affective Recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.16473</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.16473v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The contemporary state-of-the-art of Dynamic Facial Expression Recognition (DFER) technology facilitates remarkable progress by deriving emotional mappings of facial expressions from video content, underpinned by training on voluminous datasets. Yet, the DFER datasets encompass a substantial volume of noise data. Noise arises from low-quality captures that defy logical labeling, and instances that suffer from mislabeling due to annotation bias, engendering two principal types of uncertainty: the uncertainty regarding data usability and the uncertainty concerning label reliability. Addressing the two types of uncertainty, we have meticulously crafted a two-stage framework aiming at \textbf{S}eeking \textbf{C}ertain data \textbf{I}n extensive \textbf{U}ncertain data (SCIU). This initiative aims to purge the DFER datasets of these uncertainties, thereby ensuring that only clean, verified data is employed in training processes. To mitigate the issue of low-quality samples, we introduce the Coarse-Grained Pruning (CGP) stage, which assesses sample weights and prunes those deemed unusable due to their low weight. For samples with incorrect annotations, the Fine-Grained Correction (FGC) stage evaluates prediction stability to rectify mislabeled data. Moreover, SCIU is conceived as a universally compatible, plug-and-play framework, tailored to integrate seamlessly with prevailing DFER methodologies. Rigorous experiments across prevalent DFER datasets and against numerous benchmark methods substantiates SCIU's capacity to markedly elevate performance metrics.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.16473v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haoran Wang, Xinji Mai, Zeng Tao, Xuan Tong, Junxiong Lin, Yan Wang, Jiawen Yu, Boyang Wang, Shaoqi Yan, Qing Zhao, Ziheng Zhou, Shuyong Gao, Wenqiang Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Temporal Context Learning for Camera-based Semantic Scene Completion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.02077</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.02077v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Camera-based 3D semantic scene completion (SSC) is pivotal for predicting complicated 3D layouts with limited 2D image observations. The existing mainstream solutions generally leverage temporal information by roughly stacking history frames to supplement the current frame, such straightforward temporal modeling inevitably diminishes valid clues and increases learning difficulty. To address this problem, we present HTCL, a novel Hierarchical Temporal Context Learning paradigm for improving camera-based semantic scene completion. The primary innovation of this work involves decomposing temporal context learning into two hierarchical steps: (a) cross-frame affinity measurement and (b) affinity-based dynamic refinement. Firstly, to separate critical relevant context from redundant information, we introduce the pattern affinity with scale-aware isolation and multiple independent learners for fine-grained contextual correspondence modeling. Subsequently, to dynamically compensate for incomplete observations, we adaptively refine the feature sampling locations based on initially identified locations with high affinity and their neighboring relevant regions. Our method ranks $1^{st}$ on the SemanticKITTI benchmark and even surpasses LiDAR-based methods in terms of mIoU on the OpenOccupancy benchmark. Our code is available on https://github.com/Arlo0o/HTCL.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.02077v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bohan Li, Jiajun Deng, Wenyao Zhang, Zhujin Liang, Dalong Du, Xin Jin, Wenjun Zeng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-supervised 3D Point Cloud Completion via Multi-view Adversarial Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.09786</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.09786v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In real-world scenarios, scanned point clouds are often incomplete due to occlusion issues. The task of self-supervised point cloud completion involves reconstructing missing regions of these incomplete objects without the supervision of complete ground truth. Current self-supervised methods either rely on multiple views of partial observations for supervision or overlook the intrinsic geometric similarity that can be identified and utilized from the given partial point clouds. In this paper, we propose MAL-SPC, a framework that effectively leverages both object-level and category-specific geometric similarities to complete missing structures. Our MAL-SPC does not require any 3D complete supervision and only necessitates a single partial point cloud for each object. Specifically, we first introduce a Pattern Retrieval Network to retrieve similar position and curvature patterns between the partial input and the predicted shape, then leverage these similarities to densify and refine the reconstructed results. Additionally, we render the reconstructed complete shape into multi-view depth maps and design an adversarial learning module to learn the geometry of the target shape from category-specific single-view depth images. To achieve anisotropic rendering, we design a density-aware radius estimation algorithm to improve the quality of the rendered images. Our MAL-SPC yields the best results compared to current state-of-the-art methods.We will make the source code publicly available at \url{https://github.com/ltwu6/malspc</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.09786v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lintai Wu, Xianjing Cheng, Yong Xu, Huanqiang Zeng, Junhui Hou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No Train, all Gain: Self-Supervised Gradients Improve Deep Frozen Representations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10964</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.10964v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper introduces FUNGI, Features from UNsupervised GradIents, a method to enhance the features of transformer encoders by leveraging self-supervised gradients. Our method is simple: given any pretrained model, we first compute gradients from various self-supervised objectives for each input. These gradients are projected to a lower dimension and then concatenated with the model's output embedding. The resulting features are evaluated on k-nearest neighbor classification over 11 datasets from vision, 5 from natural language processing, and 2 from audio. Across backbones spanning various sizes and pretraining strategies, FUNGI features provide consistent performance improvements over the embeddings. We also show that using FUNGI features can benefit linear classification, clustering and image retrieval, and that they significantly improve the retrieval-based in-context scene understanding abilities of pretrained models, for example improving upon DINO by +17% for semantic segmentation - without any training.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.10964v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Walter Simoncini, Spyros Gidaris, Andrei Bursuc, Yuki M. Asano</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SLVideo: A Sign Language Video Moment Retrieval Framework</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.15668</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.15668v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: SLVideo is a video moment retrieval system for Sign Language videos that incorporates facial expressions, addressing this gap in existing technology. The system extracts embedding representations for the hand and face signs from video frames to capture the signs in their entirety, enabling users to search for a specific sign language video segment with text queries. A collection of eight hours of annotated Portuguese Sign Language videos is used as the dataset, and a CLIP model is used to generate the embeddings. The initial results are promising in a zero-shot setting. In addition, SLVideo incorporates a thesaurus that enables users to search for similar signs to those retrieved, using the video segment embeddings, and also supports the edition and creation of video sign language annotations. Project web page: https://novasearch.github.io/SLVideo/</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.15668v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gon\c{c}alo Vinagre Martins, Jo\~ao Magalh\~aes, Afonso Quinaz, Carla Viegas, Sofia Cavaco</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-label Cluster Discrimination for Visual Representation Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.17331</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.17331v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Contrastive Language Image Pre-training (CLIP) has recently demonstrated success across various tasks due to superior feature representation empowered by image-text contrastive learning. However, the instance discrimination method used by CLIP can hardly encode the semantic structure of training data. To handle this limitation, cluster discrimination has been proposed through iterative cluster assignment and classification. Nevertheless, most cluster discrimination approaches only define a single pseudo-label for each image, neglecting multi-label signals in the image. In this paper, we propose a novel Multi-Label Cluster Discrimination method named MLCD to enhance representation learning. In the clustering step, we first cluster the large-scale LAION-400M dataset into one million centers based on off-the-shelf embedding features. Considering that natural images frequently contain multiple visual objects or attributes, we select the multiple closest centers as auxiliary class labels. In the discrimination step, we design a novel multi-label classification loss, which elegantly separates losses from positive classes and negative classes, and alleviates ambiguity on decision boundary. We validate the proposed multi-label cluster discrimination method with experiments on different scales of models and pre-training datasets. Experimental results show that our method achieves state-of-the-art performance on multiple downstream tasks including linear probe, zero-shot classification, and image-text retrieval. Code and models have been released at https://github.com/deepglint/unicom .</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.17331v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1007/978-3-031-73383-3_25</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Xiang An, Kaicheng Yang, Xiangzi Dai, Ziyong Feng, Jiankang Deng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BetterDepth: Plug-and-Play Diffusion Refiner for Zero-Shot Monocular Depth Estimation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.17952</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.17952v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: By training over large-scale datasets, zero-shot monocular depth estimation (MDE) methods show robust performance in the wild but often suffer from insufficient detail. Although recent diffusion-based MDE approaches exhibit a superior ability to extract details, they struggle in geometrically complex scenes that challenge their geometry prior, trained on less diverse 3D data. To leverage the complementary merits of both worlds, we propose BetterDepth to achieve geometrically correct affine-invariant MDE while capturing fine details. Specifically, BetterDepth is a conditional diffusion-based refiner that takes the prediction from pre-trained MDE models as depth conditioning, in which the global depth layout is well-captured, and iteratively refines details based on the input image. For the training of such a refiner, we propose global pre-alignment and local patch masking methods to ensure BetterDepth remains faithful to the depth conditioning while learning to add fine-grained scene details. With efficient training on small-scale synthetic datasets, BetterDepth achieves state-of-the-art zero-shot MDE performance on diverse public datasets and on in-the-wild scenes. Moreover, BetterDepth can improve the performance of other MDE models in a plug-and-play manner without further re-training.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.17952v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiang Zhang, Bingxin Ke, Hayko Riemenschneider, Nando Metzger, Anton Obukhov, Markus Gross, Konrad Schindler, Christopher Schroers</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Virchow2: Scaling Self-Supervised Mixed Magnification Models in Pathology</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00738</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00738v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Foundation models are rapidly being developed for computational pathology applications. However, it remains an open question which factors are most important for downstream performance with data scale and diversity, model size, and training algorithm all playing a role. In this work, we propose algorithmic modifications, tailored for pathology, and we present the result of scaling both data and model size, surpassing previous studies in both dimensions. We introduce three new models: Virchow2, a 632 million parameter vision transformer, Virchow2G, a 1.9 billion parameter vision transformer, and Virchow2G Mini, a 22 million parameter distillation of Virchow2G, each trained with 3.1 million histopathology whole slide images, with diverse tissues, originating institutions, and stains. We achieve state of the art performance on 12 tile-level tasks, as compared to the top performing competing models. Our results suggest that data diversity and domain-specific methods can outperform models that only scale in the number of parameters, but, on average, performance benefits from the combination of domain-specific methods, data scale, and model scale.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00738v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Eric Zimmermann, Eugene Vorontsov, Julian Viret, Adam Casson, Michal Zelechowski, George Shaikovski, Neil Tenenholtz, James Hall, David Klimstra, Razik Yousfi, Thomas Fuchs, Nicolo Fusi, Siqi Liu, Kristen Severson</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting Surgical Instrument Segmentation Without Human Intervention: A Graph Partitioning View</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14789</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14789v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Surgical instrument segmentation (SIS) on endoscopic images stands as a long-standing and essential task in the context of computer-assisted interventions for boosting minimally invasive surgery. Given the recent surge of deep learning methodologies and their data-hungry nature, training a neural predictive model based on massive expert-curated annotations has been dominating and served as an off-the-shelf approach in the field, which could, however, impose prohibitive burden to clinicians for preparing fine-grained pixel-wise labels corresponding to the collected surgical video frames. In this work, we propose an unsupervised method by reframing the video frame segmentation as a graph partitioning problem and regarding image pixels as graph nodes, which is significantly different from the previous efforts. A self-supervised pre-trained model is firstly leveraged as a feature extractor to capture high-level semantic features. Then, Laplacian matrixs are computed from the features and are eigendecomposed for graph partitioning. On the "deep" eigenvectors, a surgical video frame is meaningfully segmented into different modules such as tools and tissues, providing distinguishable semantic information like locations, classes, and relations. The segmentation problem can then be naturally tackled by applying clustering or threshold on the eigenvectors. Extensive experiments are conducted on various datasets (e.g., EndoVis2017, EndoVis2018, UCL, etc.) for different clinical endpoints. Across all the challenging scenarios, our method demonstrates outstanding performance and robustness higher than unsupervised state-of-the-art (SOTA) methods. The code is released at https://github.com/MingyuShengSMY/GraphClusteringSIS.git.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14789v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mingyu Sheng, Jianan Fan, Dongnan Liu, Ron Kikinis, Weidong Cai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IFAdapter: Instance Feature Control for Grounded Text-to-Image Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.08240</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.08240v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: While Text-to-Image (T2I) diffusion models excel at generating visually appealing images of individual instances, they struggle to accurately position and control the features generation of multiple instances. The Layout-to-Image (L2I) task was introduced to address the positioning challenges by incorporating bounding boxes as spatial control signals, but it still falls short in generating precise instance features. In response, we propose the Instance Feature Generation (IFG) task, which aims to ensure both positional accuracy and feature fidelity in generated instances. To address the IFG task, we introduce the Instance Feature Adapter (IFAdapter). The IFAdapter enhances feature depiction by incorporating additional appearance tokens and utilizing an Instance Semantic Map to align instance-level features with spatial locations. The IFAdapter guides the diffusion process as a plug-and-play module, making it adaptable to various community models. For evaluation, we contribute an IFG benchmark and develop a verification pipeline to objectively compare models' abilities to generate instances with accurate positioning and features. Experimental results demonstrate that IFAdapter outperforms other models in both quantitative and qualitative evaluations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.08240v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yinwei Wu, Xianpan Zhou, Bing Ma, Xuefeng Su, Kai Ma, Xinchao Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generalizing Alignment Paradigm of Text-to-Image Generation with Preferences through $f$-divergence Minimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.09774</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.09774v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Direct Preference Optimization (DPO) has recently expanded its successful application from aligning large language models (LLMs) to aligning text-to-image models with human preferences, which has generated considerable interest within the community. However, we have observed that these approaches rely solely on minimizing the reverse Kullback-Leibler divergence during alignment process between the fine-tuned model and the reference model, neglecting the incorporation of other divergence constraints. In this study, we focus on extending reverse Kullback-Leibler divergence in the alignment paradigm of text-to-image models to $f$-divergence, which aims to garner better alignment performance as well as good generation diversity. We provide the generalized formula of the alignment paradigm under the $f$-divergence condition and thoroughly analyze the impact of different divergence constraints on alignment process from the perspective of gradient fields. We conduct comprehensive evaluation on image-text alignment performance, human value alignment performance and generation diversity performance under different divergence constraints, and the results indicate that alignment based on Jensen-Shannon divergence achieves the best trade-off among them. The option of divergence employed for aligning text-to-image models significantly impacts the trade-off between alignment performance (especially human value alignment) and generation diversity, which highlights the necessity of selecting an appropriate divergence for practical applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.09774v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haoyuan Sun, Bo Xia, Yongzhe Chang, Xueqian Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TalkMosaic: Interactive PhotoMosaic with Multi-modal LLM Q&amp;A Interactions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.13941</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.13941v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We use images of cars of a wide range of varieties to compose an image of an animal such as a bird or a lion for the theme of environmental protection to maximize the information about cars in a single composed image and to raise the awareness about environmental challenges. We present a novel way of image interaction with an artistically-composed photomosaic image, in which a simple operation of "click and display" is used to demonstrate the interactive switch between a tile image in a photomosaic image and the corresponding original car image, which will be automatically saved on the Desktop. We build a multimodal custom GPT named TalkMosaic by incorporating car images information and the related knowledge to ChatGPT. By uploading the original car image to TalkMosaic, we can ask questions about the given car image and get the corresponding answers efficiently and effectively such as where to buy the tire in the car image that satisfies high environmental standards. We give an in-depth analysis on how to speed up the inference of multimodal LLM using sparse attention and quantization techniques with presented probabilistic FlashAttention (PrFlashAttention) and Staircase Adaptive Quantization (SAQ) methods. The implemented prototype demonstrates the feasibility and effectiveness of the presented approach.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.13941v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kevin Li, Fulu Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaussian Deja-vu: Creating Controllable 3D Gaussian Head-Avatars with Enhanced Generalization and Personalization Abilities</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.16147</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.16147v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advancements in 3D Gaussian Splatting (3DGS) have unlocked significant potential for modeling 3D head avatars, providing greater flexibility than mesh-based methods and more efficient rendering compared to NeRF-based approaches. Despite these advancements, the creation of controllable 3DGS-based head avatars remains time-intensive, often requiring tens of minutes to hours. To expedite this process, we here introduce the "Gaussian Deja-vu" framework, which first obtains a generalized model of the head avatar and then personalizes the result. The generalized model is trained on large 2D (synthetic and real) image datasets. This model provides a well-initialized 3D Gaussian head that is further refined using a monocular video to achieve the personalized head avatar. For personalizing, we propose learnable expression-aware rectification blendmaps to correct the initial 3D Gaussians, ensuring rapid convergence without the reliance on neural networks. Experiments demonstrate that the proposed method meets its objectives. It outperforms state-of-the-art 3D Gaussian head avatars in terms of photorealistic quality as well as reduces training time consumption to at least a quarter of the existing methods, producing the avatar in minutes.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.16147v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Peizhi Yan, Rabab Ward, Qiang Tang, Shan Du</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TFS-NeRF: Template-Free NeRF for Semantic 3D Reconstruction of Dynamic Scene</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.17459</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.17459v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Despite advancements in Neural Implicit models for 3D surface reconstruction, handling dynamic environments with arbitrary rigid, non-rigid, or deformable entities remains challenging. Many template-based methods are entity-specific, focusing on humans, while generic reconstruction methods adaptable to such dynamic scenes often require additional inputs like depth or optical flow or rely on pre-trained image features for reasonable outcomes. These methods typically use latent codes to capture frame-by-frame deformations. In contrast, some template-free methods bypass these requirements and adopt traditional LBS (Linear Blend Skinning) weights for a detailed representation of deformable object motions, although they involve complex optimizations leading to lengthy training times. To this end, as a remedy, this paper introduces TFS-NeRF, a template-free 3D semantic NeRF for dynamic scenes captured from sparse or single-view RGB videos, featuring interactions among various entities and more time-efficient than other LBS-based approaches. Our framework uses an Invertible Neural Network (INN) for LBS prediction, simplifying the training process. By disentangling the motions of multiple entities and optimizing per-entity skinning weights, our method efficiently generates accurate, semantically separable geometries. Extensive experiments demonstrate that our approach produces high-quality reconstructions of both deformable and non-deformable objects in complex interactions, with improved training efficiency compared to existing methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.17459v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sandika Biswas, Qianyi Wu, Biplab Banerjee, Hamid Rezatofighi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep neural network-based detection of counterfeit products from smartphone images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.05969</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.05969v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Counterfeit products such as drugs and vaccines as well as luxury items such as high-fashion handbags, watches, jewelry, garments, and cosmetics, represent significant direct losses of revenue to legitimate manufacturers and vendors, as well as indirect costs to societies at large. We present the world's first purely computer-vision-based system to combat such counterfeiting-one that does not require special security tags or other alterations to the products or modifications to supply chain tracking. Our deep neural network system shows high accuracy on branded garments from our first manufacturer tested (99.71% after 3.06% rejections) using images captured under natural, weakly controlled conditions, such as in retail stores, customs checkpoints, warehouses, and outdoors. Our system, suitably transfer trained on a small number of fake and genuine articles, should find application in additional product categories as well, for example fashion accessories, perfume boxes, medicines, and more.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.05969v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hugo Garcia-Cotte, Dorra Mellouli, Abdul Rehman, Li Wang, David G. Stork</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Degradation Oriented and Regularized Network for Blind Depth Super-Resolution</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.11666</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.11666v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent RGB-guided depth super-resolution methods have achieved impressive performance under the assumption of fixed and known degradation (e.g., bicubic downsampling). However, in real-world scenarios, captured depth data often suffer from unconventional and unknown degradation due to sensor limitations and complex imaging environments (e.g., low reflective surfaces, varying illumination). Consequently, the performance of these methods significantly declines when real-world degradation deviate from their assumptions. In this paper, we propose the Degradation Oriented and Regularized Network (DORNet), a novel framework designed to adaptively address unknown degradation in real-world scenes through implicit degradation representations. Our approach begins with the development of a self-supervised degradation learning strategy, which models the degradation representations of low-resolution depth data using routing selection-based degradation regularization. To facilitate effective RGB-D fusion, we further introduce a degradation-oriented feature transformation module that selectively propagates RGB content into the depth data based on the learned degradation priors. Extensive experimental results on both real and synthetic datasets demonstrate the superiority of our DORNet in handling unknown degradation, outperforming existing methods. The code is available at https://github.com/yanzq95/DORNet.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.11666v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhengxue Wang, Zhiqiang Yan, Jinshan Pan, Guangwei Gao, Kai Zhang, Jian Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing Webpage UIs for Text-Rich Visual Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.13824</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.13824v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Text-rich visual understanding-the ability to process environments where dense textual content is integrated with visuals-is crucial for multimodal large language models (MLLMs) to interact effectively with structured environments. To enhance this capability, we propose synthesizing general multimodal instructions from webpage UIs using text-based large language models (LLMs). Despite lacking direct visual input, text-based LLMs are able to process structured text representations from webpage accessibility trees. These instructions are then paired with UI screenshots to train multimodal models. We introduce MultiUI, a dataset containing 7.3 million samples from 1 million websites, covering diverse multimodal tasks and UI layouts. Models trained on MultiUI not only excel in web UI tasks-achieving up to a 48% improvement on VisualWebBench and a 19.1% boost in element accuracy on a web agent dataset Mind2Web-but also generalize surprisingly well to non-web UI tasks and even to non-UI domains, such as document understanding, OCR, and chart interpretation. These results highlight the broad applicability of web UI data for advancing text-rich visual understanding across various scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.13824v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junpeng Liu, Tianyue Ou, Yifan Song, Yuxiao Qu, Wai Lam, Chenyan Xiong, Wenhu Chen, Graham Neubig, Xiang Yue</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing Efficient Brain Tumor Multi-Class Classification -- New Insights from the Vision Mamba Model in Transfer Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.21872</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.21872v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Early and accurate diagnosis of brain tumors is crucial for improving patient survival rates. However, the detection and classification of brain tumors are challenging due to their diverse types and complex morphological characteristics. This study investigates the application of pre-trained models for brain tumor classification, with a particular focus on deploying the Mamba model. We fine-tuned several mainstream transfer learning models and applied them to the multi-class classification of brain tumors. By comparing these models to those trained from scratch, we demonstrated the significant advantages of transfer learning, especially in the medical imaging field, where annotated data is often limited. Notably, we introduced the Vision Mamba (Vim), a novel network architecture, and applied it for the first time in brain tumor classification, achieving exceptional classification accuracy. Experimental results indicate that the Vim model achieved 100% classification accuracy on an independent test set, emphasizing its potential for tumor classification tasks. These findings underscore the effectiveness of transfer learning in brain tumor classification and reveal that, compared to existing state-of-the-art models, the Vim model is lightweight, efficient, and highly accurate, offering a new perspective for clinical applications. Furthermore, the framework proposed in this study for brain tumor classification, based on transfer learning and the Vision Mamba model, is broadly applicable to other medical imaging classification problems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.21872v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yinyi Lai, Anbo Cao, Yuan Gao, Jiaqi Shang, Zongyu Li, Jia Guo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AIWR: Aerial Image Water Resource Dataset for Segmentation Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.01797</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.01797v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Effective water resource management is crucial in agricultural regions like northeastern Thailand, where limited water retention in sandy soils poses significant challenges. In response to this issue, the Aerial Image Water Resource (AIWR) dataset was developed, comprising 800 aerial images focused on natural and artificial water bodies in this region. The dataset was created using Bing Maps and follows the standards of the Fundamental Geographic Data Set (FGDS). It includes ground truth annotations validated by experts in remote sensing, making it an invaluable resource for researchers in geoinformatics, computer vision, and artificial intelligence. The AIWR dataset presents considerable challenges, such as segmentation due to variations in the size, color, shape, and similarity of water bodies, which often resemble other land use categories. The objective of the proposed dataset is to explore advanced AI-driven methods for water body segmentation, addressing the unique challenges posed by the dataset complexity and limited size. This dataset and related research contribute to the development of novel algorithms for water management, supporting sustainable agricultural practices in regions facing similar challenges.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.01797v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sangdaow Noppitak, Emmanuel Okafor, Olarik Surinta</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GVKF: Gaussian Voxel Kernel Functions for Highly Efficient Surface Reconstruction in Open Scenes</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.01853</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.01853v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this paper we present a novel method for efficient and effective 3D surface reconstruction in open scenes. Existing Neural Radiance Fields (NeRF) based works typically require extensive training and rendering time due to the adopted implicit representations. In contrast, 3D Gaussian splatting (3DGS) uses an explicit and discrete representation, hence the reconstructed surface is built by the huge number of Gaussian primitives, which leads to excessive memory consumption and rough surface details in sparse Gaussian areas. To address these issues, we propose Gaussian Voxel Kernel Functions (GVKF), which establish a continuous scene representation based on discrete 3DGS through kernel regression. The GVKF integrates fast 3DGS rasterization and highly effective scene implicit representations, achieving high-fidelity open scene surface reconstruction. Experiments on challenging scene datasets demonstrate the efficiency and effectiveness of our proposed GVKF, featuring with high reconstruction quality, real-time rendering speed, significant savings in storage and training memory consumption.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.01853v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gaochao Song, Chong Cheng, Hao Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digi2Real: Bridging the Realism Gap in Synthetic Data Face Recognition via Foundation Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.02188</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.02188v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The accuracy of face recognition systems has improved significantly in the past few years, thanks to the large amount of data collected and the advancement in neural network architectures. However, these large-scale datasets are often collected without explicit consent, raising ethical and privacy concerns. To address this, there have been proposals to use synthetic datasets for training face recognition models. Yet, such models still rely on real data to train the generative models and generally exhibit inferior performance compared to those trained on real datasets. One of these datasets, DigiFace, uses a graphics pipeline to generate different identities and different intra-class variations without using real data in training the models. However, the performance of this approach is poor on face recognition benchmarks, possibly due to the lack of realism in the images generated from the graphics pipeline. In this work, we introduce a novel framework for realism transfer aimed at enhancing the realism of synthetically generated face images. Our method leverages the large-scale face foundation model, and we adapt the pipeline for realism enhancement. By integrating the controllable aspects of the graphics pipeline with our realism enhancement technique, we generate a large amount of realistic variations-combining the advantages of both approaches. Our empirical evaluations demonstrate that models trained using our enhanced dataset significantly improve the performance of face recognition systems over the baseline. The source code and datasets will be made available publicly: https://www.idiap.ch/paper/digi2real</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.02188v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Anjith George, Sebastien Marcel</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FewViewGS: Gaussian Splatting with Few View Matching and Multi-stage Training</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.02229</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.02229v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The field of novel view synthesis from images has seen rapid advancements with the introduction of Neural Radiance Fields (NeRF) and more recently with 3D Gaussian Splatting. Gaussian Splatting became widely adopted due to its efficiency and ability to render novel views accurately. While Gaussian Splatting performs well when a sufficient amount of training images are available, its unstructured explicit representation tends to overfit in scenarios with sparse input images, resulting in poor rendering performance. To address this, we present a 3D Gaussian-based novel view synthesis method using sparse input images that can accurately render the scene from the viewpoints not covered by the training images. We propose a multi-stage training scheme with matching-based consistency constraints imposed on the novel views without relying on pre-trained depth estimation or diffusion models. This is achieved by using the matches of the available training images to supervise the generation of the novel views sampled between the training frames with color, geometry, and semantic losses. In addition, we introduce a locality preserving regularization for 3D Gaussians which removes rendering artifacts by preserving the local color structure of the scene. Evaluation on synthetic and real-world datasets demonstrates competitive or superior performance of our method in few-shot novel view synthesis compared to existing state-of-the-art methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.02229v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ruihong Yin, Vladimir Yugay, Yue Li, Sezer Karaoglu, Theo Gevers</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Classification Done Right for Vision-Language Pre-Training</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03313</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03313v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We introduce SuperClass, a super simple classification method for vision-language pre-training on image-text data. Unlike its contrastive counterpart CLIP who contrast with a text encoder, SuperClass directly utilizes tokenized raw text as supervised classification labels, without the need for additional text filtering or selection. Due to the absence of the text encoding as contrastive target, SuperClass does not require a text encoder and does not need to maintain a large batch size as CLIP does. SuperClass demonstrated superior performance on various downstream tasks, including classic computer vision benchmarks and vision language downstream tasks. We further explored the scaling behavior of SuperClass on model size, training length, or data size, and reported encouraging results and comparisons to CLIP. https://github.com/x-cls/superclass</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03313v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zilong Huang, Qinghao Ye, Bingyi Kang, Jiashi Feng, Haoqi Fan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>D3: Data Diversity Design for Systematic Generalization in Visual Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2309.08798</link>
      <description>arXiv:2309.08798v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Systematic generalization is a crucial aspect of intelligence, which refers to the ability to generalize to novel tasks by combining known subtasks and concepts. One critical factor that has been shown to influence systematic generalization is the diversity of training data. However, diversity can be defined in various ways, as data have many factors of variation. A more granular understanding of how different aspects of data diversity affect systematic generalization is lacking. We present new evidence in the problem of Visual Question Answering (VQA) that reveals that the diversity of simple tasks (i.e. tasks formed by a few subtasks and concepts) plays a key role in achieving systematic generalization. This implies that it may not be essential to gather a large and varied number of complex tasks, which could be costly to obtain. We demonstrate that this result is independent of the similarity between the training and testing data and applies to well-known families of neural network architectures for VQA (i.e. monolithic architectures and neural module networks). Additionally, we observe that neural module networks leverage all forms of data diversity we evaluated, while monolithic architectures require more extensive amounts of data to do so. These findings provide a first step towards understanding the interactions between data diversity design, neural network architectures, and systematic generalization capabilities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2309.08798v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Amir Rahimi, Vanessa D'Amario, Moyuru Yamada, Kentaro Takemoto, Tomotake Sasaki, Xavier Boix</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GD doesn't make the cut: Three ways that non-differentiability affects neural network training</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.08426</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.08426v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: This paper investigates the distinctions between gradient methods applied to non-differentiable functions (NGDMs) and classical gradient descents (GDs) designed for differentiable functions. First, we demonstrate significant differences in the convergence properties of NGDMs compared to GDs, challenging the applicability of the extensive neural network convergence literature based on $L-smoothness$ to non-smooth neural networks. Next, we demonstrate the paradoxical nature of NGDM solutions for $L_{1}$-regularized problems, showing that increasing the regularization penalty leads to an increase in the $L_{1}$ norm of optimal solutions in NGDMs. Consequently, we show that widely adopted $L_{1}$ penalization-based techniques for network pruning do not yield expected results. Additionally, we dispel the common belief that optimization algorithms like Adam and RMSProp perform similarly in non-differentiable contexts. Finally, we explore the Edge of Stability phenomenon, indicating its inapplicability even to Lipschitz continuous convex differentiable functions, leaving its relevance to non-convex non-differentiable neural networks inconclusive. Our analysis exposes misguided interpretations of NGDMs in widely referenced papers and texts due to an overreliance on strong smoothness assumptions, emphasizing the necessity for a nuanced understanding of foundational assumptions in the analysis of these systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.08426v4</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Siddharth Krishna Kumar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FedFMS: Exploring Federated Foundation Models for Medical Image Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.05408</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.05408v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Medical image segmentation is crucial for clinical diagnosis. The Segmentation Anything Model (SAM) serves as a powerful foundation model for visual segmentation and can be adapted for medical image segmentation. However, medical imaging data typically contain privacy-sensitive information, making it challenging to train foundation models with centralized storage and sharing. To date, there are few foundation models tailored for medical image deployment within the federated learning framework, and the segmentation performance, as well as the efficiency of communication and training, remain unexplored. In response to these issues, we developed Federated Foundation models for Medical image Segmentation (FedFMS), which includes the Federated SAM (FedSAM) and a communication and training-efficient Federated SAM with Medical SAM Adapter (FedMSA). Comprehensive experiments on diverse datasets are conducted to investigate the performance disparities between centralized training and federated learning across various configurations of FedFMS. The experiments revealed that FedFMS could achieve performance comparable to models trained via centralized training methods while maintaining privacy. Furthermore, FedMSA demonstrated the potential to enhance communication and training efficiency. Our model implementation codes are available at https://github.com/LIU-YUXI/FedFMS.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.05408v2</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.DC</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuxi Liu, Guibo Luo, Yuesheng Zhu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DeNetDM: Debiasing by Network Depth Modulation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.19863</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.19863v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Neural networks trained on biased datasets tend to inadvertently learn spurious correlations, hindering generalization. We formally prove that (1) samples that exhibit spurious correlations lie on a lower rank manifold relative to the ones that do not; and (2) the depth of a network acts as an implicit regularizer on the rank of the attribute subspace that is encoded in its representations. Leveraging these insights, we present DeNetDM, a novel debiasing method that uses network depth modulation as a way of developing robustness to spurious correlations. Using a training paradigm derived from Product of Experts, we create both biased and debiased branches with deep and shallow architectures and then distill knowledge to produce the target debiased model. Our method requires no bias annotations or explicit data augmentation while performing on par with approaches that require either or both. We demonstrate that DeNetDM outperforms existing debiasing techniques on both synthetic and real-world datasets by 5\%. The project page is available at https://vssilpa.github.io/denetdm/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.19863v4</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Silpa Vadakkeeveetil Sreelatha, Adarsh Kappiyath, Abhra Chaudhuri, Anjan Dutta</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChartInsights: Evaluating Multimodal Large Language Models for Low-Level Chart Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.07001</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.07001v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Chart question answering (ChartQA) tasks play a critical role in interpreting and extracting insights from visualization charts. While recent advancements in multimodal large language models (MLLMs) like GPT-4o have shown promise in high-level ChartQA tasks, such as chart captioning, their effectiveness in low-level ChartQA tasks (e.g., identifying correlations) remains underexplored. In this paper, we address this gap by evaluating MLLMs on low-level ChartQA using a newly curated dataset, ChartInsights, which consists of 22,347 (chart, task, query, answer) covering 10 data analysis tasks across 7 chart types. We systematically evaluate 19 advanced MLLMs, including 12 open-source and 7 closed-source models. The average accuracy rate across these models is 39.8%, with GPT-4o achieving the highest accuracy at 69.17%. To further explore the limitations of MLLMs in low-level ChartQA, we conduct experiments that alter visual elements of charts (e.g., changing color schemes, adding image noise) to assess their impact on the task effectiveness. Furthermore, we propose a new textual prompt strategy, Chain-of-Charts, tailored for low-level ChartQA tasks, which boosts performance by 14.41%, achieving an accuracy of 83.58%. Finally, incorporating a visual prompt strategy that directs attention to relevant visual elements further improves accuracy to 84.32%.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.07001v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yifan Wu, Lutao Yan, Leixian Shen, Yunhai Wang, Nan Tang, Yuyu Luo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DeTikZify: Synthesizing Graphics Programs for Scientific Figures and Sketches with TikZ</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.15306</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.15306v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Creating high-quality scientific figures can be time-consuming and challenging, even though sketching ideas on paper is relatively easy. Furthermore, recreating existing figures that are not stored in formats preserving semantic information is equally complex. To tackle this problem, we introduce DeTikZify, a novel multimodal language model that automatically synthesizes scientific figures as semantics-preserving TikZ graphics programs based on sketches and existing figures. To achieve this, we create three new datasets: DaTikZv2, the largest TikZ dataset to date, containing over 360k human-created TikZ graphics; SketchFig, a dataset that pairs hand-drawn sketches with their corresponding scientific figures; and MetaFig, a collection of diverse scientific figures and associated metadata. We train DeTikZify on MetaFig and DaTikZv2, along with synthetically generated sketches learned from SketchFig. We also introduce an MCTS-based inference algorithm that enables DeTikZify to iteratively refine its outputs without the need for additional training. Through both automatic and human evaluation, we demonstrate that DeTikZify outperforms commercial Claude 3 and GPT-4V in synthesizing TikZ programs, with the MCTS algorithm effectively boosting its performance. We make our code, models, and datasets publicly available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.15306v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jonas Belouadi, Simone Paolo Ponzetto, Steffen Eger</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DMPlug: A Plug-in Method for Solving Inverse Problems with Diffusion Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.16749</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.16749v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Pretrained diffusion models (DMs) have recently been popularly used in solving inverse problems (IPs). The existing methods mostly interleave iterative steps in the reverse diffusion process and iterative steps to bring the iterates closer to satisfying the measurement constraint. However, such interleaving methods struggle to produce final results that look like natural objects of interest (i.e., manifold feasibility) and fit the measurement (i.e., measurement feasibility), especially for nonlinear IPs. Moreover, their capabilities to deal with noisy IPs with unknown types and levels of measurement noise are unknown. In this paper, we advocate viewing the reverse process in DMs as a function and propose a novel plug-in method for solving IPs using pretrained DMs, dubbed DMPlug. DMPlug addresses the issues of manifold feasibility and measurement feasibility in a principled manner, and also shows great potential for being robust to unknown types and levels of noise. Through extensive experiments across various IP tasks, including two linear and three nonlinear IPs, we demonstrate that DMPlug consistently outperforms state-of-the-art methods, often by large margins especially for nonlinear IPs. The code is available at https://github.com/sun-umn/DMPlug.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.16749v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hengkang Wang, Xu Zhang, Taihui Li, Yuxiang Wan, Tiancong Chen, Ju Sun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CLIBD: Bridging Vision and Genomics for Biodiversity Monitoring at Scale</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.17537</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.17537v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Measuring biodiversity is crucial for understanding ecosystem health. While prior works have developed machine learning models for taxonomic classification of photographic images and DNA separately, in this work, we introduce a multimodal approach combining both, using CLIP-style contrastive learning to align images, barcode DNA, and text-based representations of taxonomic labels in a unified embedding space. This allows for accurate classification of both known and unknown insect species without task-specific fine-tuning, leveraging contrastive learning for the first time to fuse DNA and image data. Our method surpasses previous single-modality approaches in accuracy by over 8% on zero-shot learning tasks, showcasing its effectiveness in biodiversity studies.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.17537v3</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>ZeMing Gong, Austin T. Wang, Xiaoliang Huo, Joakim Bruslund Haurum, Scott C. Lowe, Graham W. Taylor, Angel X. Chang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interpretable Lightweight Transformer via Unrolling of Learned Graph Smoothness Priors</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.04090</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.04090v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We build interpretable and lightweight transformer-like neural networks by unrolling iterative optimization algorithms that minimize graph smoothness priors -- the quadratic graph Laplacian regularizer (GLR) and the $\ell_1$-norm graph total variation (GTV) -- subject to an interpolation constraint. The crucial insight is that a normalized signal-dependent graph learning module amounts to a variant of the basic self-attention mechanism in conventional transformers. Unlike "black-box" transformers that require learning of large key, query and value matrices to compute scaled dot products as affinities and subsequent output embeddings, resulting in huge parameter sets, our unrolled networks employ shallow CNNs to learn low-dimensional features per node to establish pairwise Mahalanobis distances and construct sparse similarity graphs. At each layer, given a learned graph, the target interpolated signal is simply a low-pass filtered output derived from the minimization of an assumed graph smoothness prior, leading to a dramatic reduction in parameter count. Experiments for two image interpolation applications verify the restoration performance, parameter efficiency and robustness to covariate shift of our graph-based unrolled networks compared to conventional transformers.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.04090v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>eess.SP</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tam Thuc Do, Parham Eftekhar, Seyed Alireza Hosseini, Gene Cheung, Philip Chou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anatomical Foundation Models for Brain MRIs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07079</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07079v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Deep Learning (DL) in neuroimaging has become increasingly relevant for detecting neurological conditions and neurodegenerative disorders. One of the most predominant biomarkers in neuroimaging is represented by brain age, which has been shown to be a good indicator for different conditions, such as Alzheimer's Disease. Using brain age for pretraining DL models in transfer learning settings has also recently shown promising results, especially when dealing with data scarcity of different conditions. On the other hand, anatomical information of brain MRIs (e.g. cortical thickness) can provide important information for learning good representations that can be transferred to many downstream tasks. In this work, we propose AnatCL, an anatomical foundation model for brain MRIs that i.) leverages anatomical information with a weakly contrastive learning approach and ii.) achieves state-of-the-art performances in many different downstream tasks. To validate our approach we consider 12 different downstream tasks for diagnosis classification, and prediction of 10 different clinical assessment scores. Pretrained models can be found at https://github.com/EIDOSLAB/AnatCL.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07079v2</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Carlo Alberto Barbano, Matteo Brunello, Benoit Dufumier, Marco Grangetto</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LADDER: Language Driven Slice Discovery and Error Rectification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07832</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07832v5 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Error slice discovery associates structured patterns with model errors. Existing methods discover error slices by clustering the error-prone samples with similar patterns or assigning discrete attributes to each sample for post-hoc analysis. While these methods aim for interpretability and easier mitigation through reweighting or rebalancing, they may not capture the full complexity of error patterns due to incomplete or missing attributes. Contrary to the existing approach, this paper utilizes the reasoning capabilities of the Large Language Model (LLM) to analyze complex error patterns and generate testable hypotheses. This paper proposes LADDER: Language Driven slice Discovery and Error Rectification. It first projects the model's representation into a language-aligned feature space (eg CLIP) to preserve semantics in the original model feature space. This ensures the accurate retrieval of sentences that highlight the model's errors. Next, the LLM utilizes the sentences and generates hypotheses to discover error slices. Finally, we mitigate the error by fine-tuning the classification head by creating a group-balanced dataset using the hypotheses. Our entire method does not require any attribute annotation, either explicitly or through external tagging models. We validate our method with \textbf{five} image classification datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07832v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shantanu Ghosh, Rayan Syed, Chenyu Wang, Clare B. Poynton, Shyam Visweswaran, Kayhan Batmanghelich</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BCDNet: A Fast Residual Neural Network For Invasive Ductal Carcinoma Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13800</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13800v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: It is of great significance to diagnose Invasive Ductal Carcinoma (IDC) in early stage, which is the most common subtype of breast cancer. Although the powerful models in the Computer-Aided Diagnosis (CAD) systems provide promising results, it is still difficult to integrate them into other medical devices or use them without sufficient computation resource. In this paper, we propose BCDNet, which firstly upsamples the input image by the residual block and use smaller convolutional block and a special MLP to learn features. BCDNet is proofed to effectively detect IDC in histopathological RGB images with an average accuracy of 91.6% and reduce training consumption effectively compared to ResNet 50 and ViT-B-16.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13800v3</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yujia Lin, Aiwei Lian, Mingyu Liao, Shuangjie Yuan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utilizing Large Language Models in an iterative paradigm with Domain feedback for Zero-shot Molecule optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.13147</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.13147v5 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Molecule optimization is a critical task in drug discovery to optimize desired properties of a given molecule through chemical modification. Despite Large Language Models (LLMs) holding the potential to efficiently simulate this task by using natural language to direct the optimization, straightforwardly utilizing shows limited performance. In this work, we facilitate utilizing LLMs in an iterative paradigm by proposing a simple yet highly effective domain feedback provider, namely $\text{Re}^3$DF. In detail, $\text{Re}^3$DF harnesses an external toolkit, RDKit, to handle the molecule hallucination, if the modified molecule is chemically invalid. Otherwise, its desired properties are computed and compared to the original one, establishing reliable domain feedback with correct direction and distance towards the objective, followed by a retrieved example, to explicitly guide the LLM to refine the modified molecule. We conduct experiments across both single- and multi-property objectives with 2 thresholds, where $\text{Re}^3$DF shows significant improvements. Particularly, for 20 single-property objectives, $\text{Re}^3$DF enhances Hit ratio by 16.95% and 20.76% under loose and strict thresholds, respectively. For 32 multi-property objectives, $\text{Re}^3$DF enhances Hit ratio by 6.04% and 5.25%.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.13147v5</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Khiem Le, Nitesh V. Chawla</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Document Parsing Unveiled: Techniques, Challenges, and Prospects for Structured Information Extraction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.21169</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.21169v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Document parsing is essential for converting unstructured and semi-structured documents-such as contracts, academic papers, and invoices-into structured, machine-readable data. Document parsing extract reliable structured data from unstructured inputs, providing huge convenience for numerous applications. Especially with recent achievements in Large Language Models, document parsing plays an indispensable role in both knowledge base construction and training data generation. This survey presents a comprehensive review of the current state of document parsing, covering key methodologies, from modular pipeline systems to end-to-end models driven by large vision-language models. Core components such as layout detection, content extraction (including text, tables, and mathematical expressions), and multi-modal data integration are examined in detail. Additionally, this paper discusses the challenges faced by modular document parsing systems and vision-language models in handling complex layouts, integrating multiple modules, and recognizing high-density text. It emphasizes the importance of developing larger and more diverse datasets and outlines future research directions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.21169v3</guid>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qintong Zhang, Victor Shea-Jay Huang, Bin Wang, Junyuan Zhang, Zhengren Wang, Hao Liang, Shawn Wang, Matthieu Lin, Conghui He, Wentao Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>bit2bit: 1-bit quanta video reconstruction via self-supervised photon prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.23247</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.23247v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Quanta image sensors, such as SPAD arrays, are an emerging sensor technology, producing 1-bit arrays representing photon detection events over exposures as short as a few nanoseconds. In practice, raw data are post-processed using heavy spatiotemporal binning to create more useful and interpretable images at the cost of degrading spatiotemporal resolution. In this work, we propose bit2bit, a new method for reconstructing high-quality image stacks at the original spatiotemporal resolution from sparse binary quanta image data. Inspired by recent work on Poisson denoising, we developed an algorithm that creates a dense image sequence from sparse binary photon data by predicting the photon arrival location probability distribution. However, due to the binary nature of the data, we show that the assumption of a Poisson distribution is inadequate. Instead, we model the process with a Bernoulli lattice process from the truncated Poisson. This leads to the proposal of a novel self-supervised solution based on a masked loss function. We evaluate our method using both simulated and real data. On simulated data from a conventional video, we achieve 34.35 mean PSNR with extremely photon-sparse binary input (&lt;0.06 photons per pixel per frame). We also present a novel dataset containing a wide range of real SPAD high-speed videos under various challenging imaging conditions. The scenes cover strong/weak ambient light, strong motion, ultra-fast events, etc., which will be made available to the community, on which we demonstrate the promise of our approach. Both reconstruction quality and throughput substantially surpass the state-of-the-art methods (e.g., Quanta Burst Photography (QBP)). Our approach significantly enhances the visualization and usability of the data, enabling the application of existing analysis techniques.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.23247v2</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yehe Liu, Alexander Krull, Hector Basevi, Ales Leonardis, Michael W. Jenkins</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advantages of Neural Population Coding for Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.00393</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.00393v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Scalar variables, e.g., the orientation of a shape in an image, are commonly predicted using a single output neuron in a neural network. In contrast, the mammalian cortex represents variables with a population of neurons. In this population code, each neuron is most active at its preferred value and shows partial activity for other values. Here, we investigate the benefit of using a population code for the output layer of a neural network. We compare population codes against single-neuron outputs and one-hot vectors. First, we show theoretically and in experiments with synthetic data that population codes improve robustness to input noise in networks of stacked linear layers. Second, we demonstrate the benefit of using population codes to encode ambiguous outputs, such as the pose of symmetric objects. Using the T-LESS dataset of feature-less real-world objects, we show that population codes improve the accuracy of predicting 3D object orientation from image input.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.00393v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Heiko Hoffmann</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ATM: Improving Model Merging by Alternating Tuning and Merging</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03055</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03055v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Model merging has recently emerged as a cost-efficient paradigm for multi-task learning. Among current approaches, task arithmetic stands out for its simplicity and effectiveness. In this paper, we motivate the effectiveness of task vectors by linking them to multi-task gradients. We show that in a single-epoch scenario, task vectors are mathematically equivalent to the gradients obtained via gradient descent in a multi-task setting, and still approximate these gradients in subsequent epochs. Furthermore, we show that task vectors perform optimally when equality is maintained, and their effectiveness is largely driven by the first epoch's gradient. Building on this insight, we propose viewing model merging as a single step in an iterative process that Alternates between Tuning and Merging (ATM). This method acts as a bridge between model merging and multi-task gradient descent, achieving state-of-the-art results with the same data and computational requirements. We extensively evaluate ATM across diverse settings, achieving up to 20% higher accuracy in computer vision and NLP tasks, compared to the best baselines. Finally, we provide both empirical and theoretical support for its effectiveness, demonstrating increased orthogonality between task vectors and proving that ATM minimizes an upper bound on the loss obtained by jointly finetuning all tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03055v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Luca Zhou, Daniele Solombrino, Donato Crisostomi, Maria Sofia Bucarelli, Fabrizio Silvestri, Emanuele Rodol\`a</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Grid Data: Exploring Graph Neural Networks for Earth Observation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03223</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03223v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Earth Observation (EO) data analysis has been significantly revolutionized by deep learning (DL), with applications typically limited to grid-like data structures. Graph Neural Networks (GNNs) emerge as an important innovation, propelling DL into the non-Euclidean domain. Naturally, GNNs can effectively tackle the challenges posed by diverse modalities, multiple sensors, and the heterogeneous nature of EO data. To introduce GNNs in the related domains, our review begins by offering fundamental knowledge on GNNs. Then, we summarize the generic problems in EO, to which GNNs can offer potential solutions. Following this, we explore a broad spectrum of GNNs' applications to scientific problems in Earth systems, covering areas such as weather and climate analysis, disaster management, air quality monitoring, agriculture, land cover classification, hydrological process modeling, and urban modeling. The rationale behind adopting GNNs in these fields is explained, alongside methodologies for organizing graphs and designing favorable architectures for various tasks. Furthermore, we highlight methodological challenges of implementing GNNs in these domains and possible solutions that could guide future research. While acknowledging that GNNs are not a universal solution, we conclude the paper by comparing them with other popular architectures like transformers and analyzing their potential synergies.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03223v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shan Zhao, Zhaiyu Chen, Zhitong Xiong, Yilei Shi, Sudipan Saha, Xiao Xiang Zhu</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
