<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL</link>
    <description>cs.CL updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 05:00:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Sunday</day>
      <day>Saturday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Gender Bias in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09826</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09826v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Gender bias in artificial intelligence has become an important issue, particularly in the context of language models used in communication-oriented applications. This study examines the extent to which Large Language Models (LLMs) exhibit gender bias in pronoun selection in occupational contexts. The analysis evaluates the models GPT-4, GPT-4o, PaLM 2 Text Bison and Gemini 1.0 Pro using a self-generated dataset. The jobs considered include a range of occupations, from those with a significant male presence to those with a notable female concentration, as well as jobs with a relatively equal gender distribution. Three different sentence processing methods were used to assess potential gender bias: masked tokens, unmasked sentences, and sentence completion. In addition, the LLMs suggested names of individuals in specific occupations, which were then examined for gender distribution. The results show a positive correlation between the models' pronoun choices and the gender distribution present in U.S. labor force data. Female pronouns were more often associated with female-dominated occupations, while male pronouns were more often associated with male-dominated occupations. Sentence completion showed the strongest correlation with actual gender distribution, while name generation resulted in a more balanced 'politically correct' gender distribution, albeit with notable variations in predominantly male or female occupations. Overall, the prompting method had a greater impact on gender distribution than the model selection itself, highlighting the complexity of addressing gender bias in LLMs. The findings highlight the importance of prompting in gender mapping.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09826v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Michael D\"oll, Markus D\"ohring, Andreas M\"uller</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Benchmark for Long-Form Medical Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09834</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09834v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: There is a lack of benchmarks for evaluating large language models (LLMs) in long-form medical question answering (QA). Most existing medical QA evaluation benchmarks focus on automatic metrics and multiple-choice questions. While valuable, these benchmarks fail to fully capture or assess the complexities of real-world clinical applications where LLMs are being deployed. Furthermore, existing studies on evaluating long-form answer generation in medical QA are primarily closed-source, lacking access to human medical expert annotations, which makes it difficult to reproduce results and enhance existing baselines. In this work, we introduce a new publicly available benchmark featuring real-world consumer medical questions with long-form answer evaluations annotated by medical doctors. We performed pairwise comparisons of responses from various open and closed-source medical and general-purpose LLMs based on criteria such as correctness, helpfulness, harmfulness, and bias. Additionally, we performed a comprehensive LLM-as-a-judge analysis to study the alignment between human judgments and LLMs. Our preliminary results highlight the strong potential of open LLMs in medical QA compared to leading closed models. Code &amp; Data: https://github.com/lavita-ai/medical-eval-sphere</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09834v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Pedram Hosseini, Jessica M. Sin, Bing Ren, Bryceton G. Thomas, Elnaz Nouri, Ali Farahanchi, Saeed Hassanpour</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KULCQ: An Unsupervised Keyword-based Utterance Level Clustering Quality Metric</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09853</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09853v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Intent discovery is crucial for both building new conversational agents and improving existing ones. While several approaches have been proposed for intent discovery, most rely on clustering to group similar utterances together. Traditional evaluation of these utterance clusters requires intent labels for each utterance, limiting scalability. Although some clustering quality metrics exist that do not require labeled data, they focus solely on cluster geometry while ignoring the linguistic nuances present in conversational transcripts. In this paper, we introduce Keyword-based Utterance Level Clustering Quality (KULCQ), an unsupervised metric that leverages keyword analysis to evaluate clustering quality. We demonstrate KULCQ's effectiveness by comparing it with existing unsupervised clustering metrics and validate its performance through comprehensive ablation studies. Our results show that KULCQ better captures semantic relationships in conversational data while maintaining consistency with geometric clustering principles.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09853v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Pranav Guruprasad, Negar Mokhberian, Nikhil Varghese, Chandra Khatri, Amol Kelkar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research on Domain-Specific Chinese Spelling Correction Method Based on Plugin Extension Modules</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09884</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09884v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper proposes a Chinese spelling correction method based on plugin extension modules, aimed at addressing the limitations of existing models in handling domain-specific texts. Traditional Chinese spelling correction models are typically trained on general-domain datasets, resulting in poor performance when encountering specialized terminology in domain-specific texts. To address this issue, we design an extension module that learns the features of domain-specific terminology, thereby enhancing the model's correction capabilities within specific domains. This extension module can provide domain knowledge to the model without compromising its general spelling correction performance, thus improving its accuracy in specialized fields. Experimental results demonstrate that after integrating extension modules for medical, legal, and official document domains, the model's correction performance is significantly improved compared to the baseline model without any extension modules.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09884v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaowu Zhang, Hongfei Zhao, Xuan Chang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Refined and Segmented Price Sentiment Indices from Survey Comments</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09937</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09937v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We aim to enhance a price sentiment index and to more precisely understand price trends from the perspective of not only consumers but also businesses. We extract comments related to prices from the Economy Watchers Survey conducted by the Cabinet Office of Japan and classify price trends using a large language model (LLM). We classify whether the survey sample reflects the perspective of consumers or businesses, and whether the comments pertain to goods or services by utilizing information on the fields of comments and the industries of respondents included in the Economy Watchers Survey. From these classified price-related comments, we construct price sentiment indices not only for a general purpose but also for more specific objectives by combining perspectives on consumers and prices, as well as goods and services. It becomes possible to achieve a more accurate classification of price directions by employing a LLM for classification. Furthermore, integrating the outputs of multiple LLMs suggests the potential for the better performance of the classification. The use of more accurately classified comments allows for the construction of an index with a higher correlation to existing indices than previous studies. We demonstrate that the correlation of the price index for consumers, which has a larger sample size, is further enhanced by selecting comments for aggregation based on the industry of the survey respondents.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09937v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>q-fin.CP</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Masahiro Suzuki, Hiroki Sakaji</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SlimLM: An Efficient Small Language Model for On-Device Document Assistance</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09944</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09944v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: While small language models (SLMs) show promises for mobile deployment, their real-world performance and applications on smartphones remains underexplored. We present SlimLM, a series of SLMs optimized for document assistance tasks on mobile devices. Through extensive experiments on a Samsung Galaxy S24, we identify the optimal trade-offs between model size (ranging from 125M to 7B parameters), context length, and inference time for efficient on-device processing. SlimLM is pre-trained on SlimPajama-627B and fine-tuned on DocAssist, our constructed dataset for summarization, question answering and suggestion tasks. Our smallest model demonstrates efficient performance on S24, while larger variants offer enhanced capabilities within mobile constraints. We evaluate SlimLM against existing SLMs, showing comparable or superior performance and offering a benchmark for future research in on-device language models. We also provide an Android application, offering practical insights into SLM deployment. Our findings provide valuable insights and illuminate the capabilities of running advanced language models on high-end smartphones, potentially reducing server costs and enhancing privacy through on-device processing.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09944v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Thang M. Pham, Phat T. Nguyen, Seunghyun Yoon, Viet Dac Lai, Franck Dernoncourt, Trung Bui</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LoRA-LiteE: A Computationally Efficient Framework for Chatbot Preference-Tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09947</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09947v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Effective preference tuning is pivotal in aligning chatbot responses with human expectations, enhancing user satisfaction and engagement. Traditional approaches, notably Reinforcement Learning from Human Feedback (RLHF) as employed in advanced models like GPT-4, have demonstrated considerable success in this domain. However, RLHF methods are often computationally intensive and resource-demanding, limiting their scalability and accessibility for broader applications. To address these challenges, this study introduces LoRA-Lite Ensemble (LoRA-LiteE), an innovative framework that combines Supervised Fine-tuning (SFT) with Low-Rank Adaptation (LoRA) and Ensemble Learning techniques to effectively aggregate predictions of lightweight models, which aim to achieve a balance between the performance and computational cost. Utilizing the Chatbot Arena benchmark dataset, we conduct a comprehensive comparative analysis among our LoRA-LiteE model, corresponding base models at different scales, and GPT-4 trained with RLHF. Our empirical results demonstrate that the proposed LoRA-LiteE model achieves comparable performance to un-finetuned GPT-4 and outperforms the single larger-scale models under limited resource constraints. These findings highlight that our LoRA-LiteE provides a feasible and efficient methodology for human preference prediction in chatbot systems, enhancing scalability and accessibility, and thereby broadening the applicability of preference-tuned chatbots in resource-constrained environments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09947v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yahe Yang, Chunliang Tao, Xiaojing Fan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Language Models as User-Agents for Evaluating Task-Oriented-Dialogue Systems</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09972</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09972v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Traditionally, offline datasets have been used to evaluate task-oriented dialogue (TOD) models. These datasets lack context awareness, making them suboptimal benchmarks for conversational systems. In contrast, user-agents, which are context-aware, can simulate the variability and unpredictability of human conversations, making them better alternatives as evaluators. Prior research has utilized large language models (LLMs) to develop user-agents. Our work builds upon this by using LLMs to create user-agents for the evaluation of TOD systems. This involves prompting an LLM, using in-context examples as guidance, and tracking the user-goal state. Our evaluation of diversity and task completion metrics for the user-agents shows improved performance with the use of better prompts. Additionally, we propose methodologies for the automatic evaluation of TOD models within this dynamic framework.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09972v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Taaha Kazi, Ruiliang Lyu, Sizhe Zhou, Dilek Hakkani-Tur, Gokhan Tur</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HistoLens: An LLM-Powered Framework for Multi-Layered Analysis of Historical Texts -- A Case Application of Yantie Lun</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09978</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09978v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper proposes HistoLens, a multi-layered analysis framework for historical texts based on Large Language Models (LLMs). Using the important Western Han dynasty text "Yantie Lun" as a case study, we demonstrate the framework's potential applications in historical research and education. HistoLens integrates NLP technology (especially LLMs), including named entity recognition, knowledge graph construction, and geographic information visualization. The paper showcases how HistoLens explores Western Han culture in "Yantie Lun" through multi-dimensional, visual, and quantitative methods, focusing particularly on the influence of Confucian and Legalist thoughts on political, economic, military, and ethnic. We also demonstrate how HistoLens constructs a machine teaching scenario using LLMs for explainable analysis, based on a dataset of Confucian and Legalist ideas extracted with LLM assistance. This approach offers novel and diverse perspectives for studying historical texts like "Yantie Lun" and provides new auxiliary tools for history education. The framework aims to equip historians and learners with LLM-assisted tools to facilitate in-depth, multi-layered analysis of historical texts and foster innovation in historical education.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09978v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yifan Zeng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orca: Enhancing Role-Playing Abilities of Large Language Models by Integrating Personality Traits</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.10006</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.10006v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models has catalyzed the development of personalized dialogue systems, numerous role-playing conversational agents have emerged. While previous research predominantly focused on enhancing the model's capability to follow instructions by designing character profiles, neglecting the psychological factors that drive human conversations. In this paper, we propose Orca, a framework for data processing and training LLMs of custom characters by integrating personality traits. Orca comprises four stages: (1) Personality traits inferring, leverage LLMs to infer user's BigFive personality trait reports and scores. (2) Data Augment, simulate user's profile, background story, and psychological activities. (3) Dataset construction, personality-conditioned instruction prompting (PCIP) to stimulate LLMs. (4) Modeling and Training, personality-conditioned instruction tuning (PTIT and PSIT), using the generated data to enhance existing open-source LLMs. We introduce OrcaBench, the first benchmark for evaluating the quality of content generated by LLMs on social platforms across multiple scales. Our experiments demonstrate that our proposed model achieves superior performance on this benchmark, demonstrating its excellence and effectiveness in perceiving personality traits that significantly improve role-playing abilities. Our Code is available at https://github.com/Aipura/Orca.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.10006v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuxuan Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Once More, With Feeling: Measuring Emotion of Acting Performances in Contemporary American Film</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.10018</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.10018v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Narrative film is a composition of writing, cinematography, editing, and performance. While much computational work has focused on the writing or visual style in film, we conduct in this paper a computational exploration of acting performance. Applying speech emotion recognition models and a variationist sociolinguistic analytical framework to a corpus of popular, contemporary American film, we find narrative structure, diachronic shifts, and genre- and dialogue-based constraints located in spoken performances.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.10018v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Naitian Zhou, David Bamman</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Information Extraction from Clinical Notes: Are We Ready to Switch to Large Language Models?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.10020</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.10020v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Backgrounds: Information extraction (IE) is critical in clinical natural language processing (NLP). While large language models (LLMs) excel on generative tasks, their performance on extractive tasks remains debated. Methods: We investigated Named Entity Recognition (NER) and Relation Extraction (RE) using 1,588 clinical notes from four sources (UT Physicians, MTSamples, MIMIC-III, and i2b2). We developed an annotated corpus covering 4 clinical entities and 16 modifiers, and compared instruction-tuned LLaMA-2 and LLaMA-3 against BiomedBERT in terms of performance, generalizability, computational resources, and throughput to BiomedBERT. Results: LLaMA models outperformed BiomedBERT across datasets. With sufficient training data, LLaMA showed modest improvements (1% on NER, 1.5-3.7% on RE); improvements were larger with limited training data. On unseen i2b2 data, LLaMA-3-70B outperformed BiomedBERT by 7% (F1) on NER and 4% on RE. However, LLaMA models required more computing resources and ran up to 28 times slower. We implemented "Kiwi," a clinical IE package featuring both models, available at https://kiwi.clinicalnlp.org/. Conclusion: This study is among the first to develop and evaluate a comprehensive clinical IE system using open-source LLMs. Results indicate that LLaMA models outperform BiomedBERT for clinical NER and RE but with higher computational costs and lower throughputs. These findings highlight that choosing between LLMs and traditional deep learning methods for clinical IE applications should remain task-specific, taking into account both performance metrics and practical considerations such as available computing resources and the intended use case scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.10020v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yan Hu, Xu Zuo, Yujia Zhou, Xueqing Peng, Jimin Huang, Vipina K. Keloth, Vincent J. Zhang, Ruey-Ling Weng, Qingyu Chen, Xiaoqian Jiang, Kirk E. Roberts, Hua Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Layer Importance and Hallucination Analysis in Large Language Models via Enhanced Activation Variance-Sparsity</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.10069</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.10069v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Evaluating the importance of different layers in large language models (LLMs) is crucial for optimizing model performance and interpretability. This paper first explores layer importance using the Activation Variance-Sparsity Score (AVSS), which combines normalized activation variance and sparsity to quantify each layer's contribution to overall model performance. By ranking layers based on AVSS and pruning the least impactful 25\%, our experiments on tasks such as question answering, language modeling, and sentiment classification show that over 90\% of the original performance is retained, highlighting potential redundancies in LLM architectures. Building on AVSS, we propose an enhanced version tailored to assess hallucination propensity across layers (EAVSS). This improved approach introduces Hallucination-Specific Activation Variance (HSAV) and Hallucination-Specific Sparsity (HSS) metrics, allowing precise identification of hallucination-prone layers. By incorporating contrastive learning on these layers, we effectively mitigate hallucination generation, contributing to more robust and efficient LLMs(The maximum performance improvement is 12\%). Our results on the NQ, SciQ, TriviaQA, TruthfulQA, and WikiQA datasets demonstrate the efficacy of this method, offering a comprehensive framework for both layer importance evaluation and hallucination mitigation in LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.10069v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.PF</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zichen Song, Sitan Huang, Yuxin Wu, Zhongfeng Kang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding The Effect Of Temperature On Alignment With Human Opinions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.10080</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.10080v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: With the increasing capabilities of LLMs, recent studies focus on understanding whose opinions are represented by them and how to effectively extract aligned opinion distributions. We conducted an empirical analysis of three straightforward methods for obtaining distributions and evaluated the results across a variety of metrics. Our findings suggest that sampling and log-probability approaches with simple parameter adjustments can return better aligned outputs in subjective tasks compared to direct prompting. Yet, assuming models reflect human opinions may be limiting, highlighting the need for further research on how human subjectivity affects model uncertainty.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.10080v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Maja Pavlovic, Massimo Poesio</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xmodel-1.5: An 1B-scale Multilingual LLM</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.10083</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.10083v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We introduce Xmodel-1.5, a novel 1-billion-parameter multilingual large model pretrained on approximately 2 trillion tokens. The model demonstrates strong performance across several languages, with particularly notable results in Thai, Arabic, and French, alongside its effectiveness in Chinese and English. In addition, we contribute to the research community by releasing a Thai evaluation dataset, which includes hundreds of questions annotated by students from Chulalongkorn University's School of Integrated Innovation. While the results are promising, we acknowledge that there is still room for improvement. We hope this work advances ongoing efforts in multilingual AI research and promotes better cross-linguistic understanding in various natural language processing tasks. Our models and code are publicly available on GitHub at https://github.com/XiaoduoAILab/XmodelLM.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.10083v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wang Qun, Liu Yang, Lin Qingquan, Jiang Ling</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Legal Evalutions and Challenges of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.10137</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.10137v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this paper, we review legal testing methods based on Large Language Models (LLMs), using the OPENAI o1 model as a case study to evaluate the performance of large models in applying legal provisions. We compare current state-of-the-art LLMs, including open-source, closed-source, and legal-specific models trained specifically for the legal domain. Systematic tests are conducted on English and Chinese legal cases, and the results are analyzed in depth. Through systematic testing of legal cases from common law systems and China, this paper explores the strengths and weaknesses of LLMs in understanding and applying legal texts, reasoning through legal issues, and predicting judgments. The experimental results highlight both the potential and limitations of LLMs in legal applications, particularly in terms of challenges related to the interpretation of legal language and the accuracy of legal reasoning. Finally, the paper provides a comprehensive analysis of the advantages and disadvantages of various types of models, offering valuable insights and references for the future application of AI in the legal field.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.10137v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiaqi Wang, Huan Zhao, Zhenyuan Yang, Peng Shu, Junhao Chen, Haobo Sun, Ruixi Liang, Shixin Li, Pengcheng Shi, Longjun Ma, Zongjia Liu, Zhengliang Liu, Tianyang Zhong, Yutong Zhang, Chong Ma, Xin Zhang, Tuo Zhang, Tianli Ding, Yudan Ren, Tianming Liu, Xi Jiang, Shu Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Effective Framework to Help Large Language Models Handle Numeric-involved Long-context Tasks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.10145</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.10145v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated remarkable capabilities in handling long texts and have almost perfect performance in traditional retrieval tasks. However, their performance significantly degrades when it comes to numerical calculations in the long-context. Numeric-involved long-context tasks typically cannot be addressed by current LLMs in normal settings due to their inherent limitations in simultaneously handling complex and massive information. Some CoT like prompting methods can improve accuracy but demands massive output tokens, which is costly and slow. To address this issue, we propose a workflow, which decompose a numeric-involved long-context task into 4 low-level subtasks: judging, extracting and processing with code and conclusion. The former 2 subtasks is relatively simple, which allows us to use smaller models for efficiently processing long context. When numerical calculations are required, we use code generated by LLMs to avoid the disadvantage of LLM not being good at calculations. The results in 2 numeric-involved long-context benchmarks demonstrate our workflow can not only improve accuracy, but also significantly reduce the cost of API calls.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.10145v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yijiong Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compound-QA: A Benchmark for Evaluating LLMs on Compound Questions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.10163</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.10163v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) demonstrate remarkable performance across various tasks, prompting researchers to develop diverse evaluation benchmarks. However, existing benchmarks typically measure the ability of LLMs to respond to individual questions, neglecting the complex interactions in real-world applications. In this paper, we introduce Compound Question Synthesis (CQ-Syn) to create the Compound-QA benchmark, focusing on compound questions with multiple sub-questions. This benchmark is derived from existing QA datasets, annotated with proprietary LLMs and verified by humans for accuracy. It encompasses five categories: Factual-Statement, Cause-and-Effect, Hypothetical-Analysis, Comparison-and-Selection, and Evaluation-and-Suggestion. It evaluates the LLM capability in terms of three dimensions including understanding, reasoning, and knowledge. Our assessment of eight open-source LLMs using Compound-QA reveals distinct patterns in their responses to compound questions, which are significantly poorer than those to non-compound questions. Additionally, we investigate various methods to enhance LLMs performance on compound questions. The results indicate that these approaches significantly improve the models' comprehension and reasoning abilities on compound questions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.10163v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yutao Hou, Yajing Luo, Zhiwen Ruan, Hongru Wang, Weifeng Ge, Yun Chen, Guanhua Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Increasing the Accessibility of Causal Domain Knowledge via Causal Information Extraction Methods: A Case Study in the Semiconductor Manufacturing Industry</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.10172</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.10172v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The extraction of causal information from textual data is crucial in the industry for identifying and mitigating potential failures, enhancing process efficiency, prompting quality improvements, and addressing various operational challenges. This paper presents a study on the development of automated methods for causal information extraction from actual industrial documents in the semiconductor manufacturing industry. The study proposes two types of causal information extraction methods, single-stage sequence tagging (SST) and multi-stage sequence tagging (MST), and evaluates their performance using existing documents from a semiconductor manufacturing company, including presentation slides and FMEA (Failure Mode and Effects Analysis) documents. The study also investigates the effect of representation learning on downstream tasks. The presented case study showcases that the proposed MST methods for extracting causal information from industrial documents are suitable for practical applications, especially for semi structured documents such as FMEAs, with a 93\% F1 score. Additionally, MST achieves a 73\% F1 score on texts extracted from presentation slides. Finally, the study highlights the importance of choosing a language model that is more aligned with the domain and in-domain fine-tuning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.10172v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Houssam Razouk, Leonie Benischke, Daniel Garber, Roman Kern</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entropy and type-token ratio in gigaword corpora</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.10227</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.10227v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Lexical diversity measures the vocabulary variation in texts. While its utility is evident for analyses in language change and applied linguistics, it is not yet clear how to operationalize this concept in a unique way. We here investigate entropy and text-token ratio, two widely employed metrics for lexical diversities, in six massive linguistic datasets in English, Spanish, and Turkish, consisting of books, news articles, and tweets. These gigaword corpora correspond to languages with distinct morphological features and differ in registers and genres, thus constituting a diverse testbed for a quantitative approach to lexical diversity. Strikingly, we find a functional relation between entropy and text-token ratio that holds across the corpora under consideration. Further, in the limit of large vocabularies we find an analytical expression that sheds light on the origin of this relation and its connection with both Zipf and Heaps laws. Our results then contribute to the theoretical understanding of text structure and offer practical implications for fields like natural language processing.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.10227v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>physics.soc-ph</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Pablo Rosillo-Rodes, Maxi San Miguel, David Sanchez</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measuring Non-Adversarial Reproduction of Training Data in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.10242</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.10242v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models memorize parts of their training data. Memorizing short snippets and facts is required to answer questions about the world and to be fluent in any language. But models have also been shown to reproduce long verbatim sequences of memorized text when prompted by a motivated adversary. In this work, we investigate an intermediate regime of memorization that we call non-adversarial reproduction, where we quantify the overlap between model responses and pretraining data when responding to natural and benign prompts. For a variety of innocuous prompt categories (e.g., writing a letter or a tutorial), we show that up to 15% of the text output by popular conversational language models overlaps with snippets from the Internet. In worst cases, we find generations where 100% of the content can be found exactly online. For the same tasks, we find that human-written text has far less overlap with Internet data. We further study whether prompting strategies can close this reproduction gap between models and humans. While appropriate prompting can reduce non-adversarial reproduction on average, we find that mitigating worst-case reproduction of training data requires stronger defenses -- even for benign interactions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.10242v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Michael Aerni, Javier Rando, Edoardo Debenedetti, Nicholas Carlini, Daphne Ippolito, Florian Tram\`er</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling Topological Structures in Text: A Comprehensive Survey of Topological Data Analysis Applications in NLP</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.10298</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.10298v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The surge of data available on the internet has led to the adoption of various computational methods to analyze and extract valuable insights from this wealth of information. Among these, the field of Machine Learning (ML) has thrived by leveraging data to extract meaningful insights. However, ML techniques face notable challenges when dealing with real-world data, often due to issues of imbalance, noise, insufficient labeling, and high dimensionality. To address these limitations, some researchers advocate for the adoption of Topological Data Analysis (TDA), a statistical approach that discerningly captures the intrinsic shape of data despite noise. Despite its potential, TDA has not gained as much traction within the Natural Language Processing (NLP) domain compared to structurally distinct areas like computer vision. Nevertheless, a dedicated community of researchers has been exploring the application of TDA in NLP, yielding 85 papers we comprehensively survey in this paper. Our findings categorize these efforts into theoretical and nontheoretical approaches. Theoretical approaches aim to explain linguistic phenomena from a topological viewpoint, while non-theoretical approaches merge TDA with ML features, utilizing diverse numerical representation techniques. We conclude by exploring the challenges and unresolved questions that persist in this niche field. Resources and a list of papers on this topic can be found at: https://github.com/AdaUchendu/AwesomeTDA4NLP.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.10298v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Adaku Uchendu, Thai Le</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emotion Detection in Reddit: Comparative Study of Machine Learning and Deep Learning Techniques</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.10328</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.10328v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Emotion detection is pivotal in human communication, as it significantly influences behavior, relationships, and decision-making processes. This study concentrates on text-based emotion detection by leveraging the GoEmotions dataset, which annotates Reddit comments with 27 distinct emotions. These emotions are subsequently mapped to Ekman's six basic categories: joy, anger, fear, sadness, disgust, and surprise. We employed a range of models for this task, including six machine learning models, three ensemble models, and a Long Short-Term Memory (LSTM) model to determine the optimal model for emotion detection. Results indicate that the Stacking classifier outperforms other models in accuracy and performance. We also benchmark our models against EmoBERTa, a pre-trained emotion detection model, with our Stacking classifier proving more effective. Finally, the Stacking classifier is deployed via a Streamlit web application, underscoring its potential for real-world applications in text-based emotion analysis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.10328v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Maliheh Alaeddini</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Survey of Event Causality Identification: Principles, Taxonomy, Challenges, and Assessment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.10371</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.10371v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Event Causality Identification (ECI) has become a crucial task in Natural Language Processing (NLP), aimed at automatically extracting causalities from textual data. In this survey, we systematically address the foundational principles, technical frameworks, and challenges of ECI, offering a comprehensive taxonomy to categorize and clarify current research methodologies, as well as a quantitative assessment of existing models. We first establish a conceptual framework for ECI, outlining key definitions, problem formulations, and evaluation standards. Our taxonomy classifies ECI methods according to the two primary tasks of sentence-level (SECI) and document-level (DECI) event causality identification. For SECI, we examine feature pattern-based matching, deep semantic encoding, causal knowledge pre-training and prompt-based fine-tuning, and external knowledge enhancement methods. For DECI, we highlight approaches focused on event graph reasoning and prompt-based techniques to address the complexity of cross-sentence causal inference. Additionally, we analyze the strengths, limitations, and open challenges of each approach. We further conduct an extensive quantitative evaluation of various ECI methods on two benchmark datasets. Finally, we explore future research directions, highlighting promising pathways to overcome current limitations and broaden ECI applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.10371v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zefan Zeng, Qing Cheng, Xingchen Hu, Yuehang Si, Zhong Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Automatic Evaluation of Task-Oriented Dialogue Flows</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.10416</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.10416v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Task-oriented dialogue systems rely on predefined conversation schemes (dialogue flows) often represented as directed acyclic graphs. These flows can be manually designed or automatically generated from previously recorded conversations. Due to variations in domain expertise or reliance on different sets of prior conversations, these dialogue flows can manifest in significantly different graph structures. Despite their importance, there is no standard method for evaluating the quality of dialogue flows. We introduce FuDGE (Fuzzy Dialogue-Graph Edit Distance), a novel metric that evaluates dialogue flows by assessing their structural complexity and representational coverage of the conversation data. FuDGE measures how well individual conversations align with a flow and, consequently, how well a set of conversations is represented by the flow overall. Through extensive experiments on manually configured flows and flows generated by automated techniques, we demonstrate the effectiveness of FuDGE and its evaluation framework. By standardizing and optimizing dialogue flows, FuDGE enables conversational designers and automated techniques to achieve higher levels of efficiency and automation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.10416v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mehrnoosh Mirtaheri, Nikhil Varghese, Chandra Khatri, Amol Kelkar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mitigating Hallucination in Multimodal Large Language Model via Hallucination-targeted Direct Preference Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.10436</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.10436v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) are known to hallucinate, which limits their practical applications. Recent works have attempted to apply Direct Preference Optimization (DPO) to enhance the performance of MLLMs, but have shown inconsistent improvements in mitigating hallucinations. To address this issue more effectively, we introduce Hallucination-targeted Direct Preference Optimization (HDPO) to reduce hallucinations in MLLMs. Unlike previous approaches, our method tackles hallucinations from their diverse forms and causes. Specifically, we develop three types of preference pair data targeting the following causes of MLLM hallucinations: (1) insufficient visual capabilities, (2) long context generation, and (3) multimodal conflicts. Experimental results demonstrate that our method achieves superior performance across multiple hallucination evaluation datasets, surpassing most state-of-the-art (SOTA) methods and highlighting the potential of our approach. Ablation studies and in-depth analyses further confirm the effectiveness of our method and suggest the potential for further improvements through scaling up.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.10436v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuhan Fu, Ruobing Xie, Xingwu Sun, Zhanhui Kang, Xirong Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the Reasoning Ability of Multimodal Large Language Models via Mixed Preference Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.10442</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.10442v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Existing open-source multimodal large language models (MLLMs) generally follow a training process involving pre-training and supervised fine-tuning. However, these models suffer from distribution shifts, which limit their multimodal reasoning, particularly in the Chain-of-Thought (CoT) performance. To address this, we introduce a preference optimization (PO) process to enhance the multimodal reasoning capabilities of MLLMs. Specifically, (1) on the data side, we design an automated preference data construction pipeline to create MMPR, a high-quality, large-scale multimodal reasoning preference dataset. and (2) on the model side, we explore integrating PO with MLLMs, developing a simple yet effective method, termed Mixed Preference Optimization (MPO), which boosts multimodal CoT performance. Our approach demonstrates improved performance across multiple benchmarks, particularly in multimodal reasoning tasks. Notably, our model, InternVL2-8B-MPO, achieves an accuracy of 67.0 on MathVista, outperforming InternVL2-8B by 8.7 points and achieving performance comparable to the 10x larger InternVL2-76B. We hope this study could inspire further advancements in MLLMs. Code, data, and model shall be publicly released.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.10442v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weiyun Wang, Zhe Chen, Wenhai Wang, Yue Cao, Yangzhou Liu, Zhangwei Gao, Jinguo Zhu, Xizhou Zhu, Lewei Lu, Yu Qiao, Jifeng Dai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the Predictive Capacity of ChatGPT for Academic Peer Review Outcomes Across Multiple Platforms</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09763</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09763v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: While previous studies have demonstrated that Large Language Models (LLMs) can predict peer review outcomes to some extent, this paper builds on that by introducing two new contexts and employing a more robust method - averaging multiple ChatGPT scores. The findings that averaging 30 ChatGPT predictions, based on reviewer guidelines and using only the submitted titles and abstracts, failed to predict peer review outcomes for F1000Research (Spearman's rho=0.00). However, it produced mostly weak positive correlations with the quality dimensions of SciPost Physics (rho=0.25 for validity, rho=0.25 for originality, rho=0.20 for significance, and rho = 0.08 for clarity) and a moderate positive correlation for papers from the International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR) (rho=0.38). Including the full text of articles significantly increased the correlation for ICLR (rho=0.46) and slightly improved it for F1000Research (rho=0.09), while it had variable effects on the four quality dimension correlations for SciPost LaTeX files. The use of chain-of-thought system prompts slightly increased the correlation for F1000Research (rho=0.10), marginally reduced it for ICLR (rho=0.37), and further decreased it for SciPost Physics (rho=0.16 for validity, rho=0.18 for originality, rho=0.18 for significance, and rho=0.05 for clarity). Overall, the results suggest that in some contexts, ChatGPT can produce weak pre-publication quality assessments. However, the effectiveness of these assessments and the optimal strategies for employing them vary considerably across different platforms, journals, and conferences. Additionally, the most suitable inputs for ChatGPT appear to differ depending on the platform.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09763v1</guid>
      <category>cs.DL</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mike Thelwall, Abdullah Yaghi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JRadiEvo: A Japanese Radiology Report Generation Model Enhanced by Evolutionary Optimization of Model Merging</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09933</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09933v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: With the rapid advancement of large language models (LLMs), foundational models (FMs) have seen significant advancements. Healthcare is one of the most crucial application areas for these FMs, given the significant time and effort required for physicians to analyze large volumes of patient data. Recent efforts have focused on adapting multimodal FMs to the medical domain through techniques like instruction-tuning, leading to the development of medical foundation models (MFMs). However, these approaches typically require large amounts of training data to effectively adapt models to the medical field. Moreover, most existing models are trained on English datasets, limiting their practicality in non-English-speaking regions where healthcare professionals and patients are not always fluent in English. The need for translation introduces additional costs and inefficiencies. To address these challenges, we propose a \textbf{J}apanese \textbf{Radi}ology report generation model enhanced by \textbf{Evo}lutionary optimization of model merging (JRadiEvo). This is the first attempt to extend a non-medical vision-language foundation model to the medical domain through evolutionary optimization of model merging. We successfully created a model that generates accurate Japanese reports from X-ray images using only 50 translated samples from publicly available data. This model, developed with highly efficient use of limited data, outperformed leading models from recent research trained on much larger datasets. Additionally, with only 8 billion parameters, this relatively compact foundation model can be deployed locally within hospitals, making it a practical solution for environments where APIs and other external services cannot be used due to strict privacy and security requirements.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09933v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.NE</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kaito Baba, Ryota Yagi, Junichiro Takahashi, Risa Kishikawa, Satoshi Kodera</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards unearthing neglected climate innovations from scientific literature using Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.10055</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.10055v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Climate change poses an urgent global threat, needing the rapid identification and deployment of innovative solutions. We hypothesise that many of these solutions already exist within scientific literature but remain underutilised. To address this gap, this study employs a curated dataset sourced from OpenAlex, a comprehensive repository of scientific papers. Utilising Large Language Models (LLMs), such as GPT4-o from OpenAI, we evaluate title-abstract pairs from scientific papers on seven dimensions, covering climate change mitigation potential, stage of technological development, and readiness for deployment. The outputs of the language models are then compared with human evaluations to assess their effectiveness in identifying promising yet overlooked climate innovations. Our findings suggest that these LLM-based models can effectively augment human expertise, uncovering climate solutions that are potentially impactful but with far greater speed, throughput and consistency. Here, we focused on UK-based solutions, but the workflow is region-agnostic. This work contributes to the discovery of neglected innovations in scientific literature and demonstrates the potential of AI in enhancing climate action strategies.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.10055v1</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>C\'esar Quilodr\'an-Casas, Christopher Waite, Nicole Alhadeff, Diyona Dsouza, Cathal Hughes, Larissa Kunstel-Tabet, Alyssa Gilbert</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CMATH: Cross-Modality Augmented Transformer with Hierarchical Variational Distillation for Multimodal Emotion Recognition in Conversation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.10060</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.10060v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Multimodal emotion recognition in conversation (MER) aims to accurately identify emotions in conversational utterances by integrating multimodal information. Previous methods usually treat multimodal information as equal quality and employ symmetric architectures to conduct multimodal fusion. However, in reality, the quality of different modalities usually varies considerably, and utilizing a symmetric architecture is difficult to accurately recognize conversational emotions when dealing with uneven modal information. Furthermore, fusing multi-modality information in a single granularity may fail to adequately integrate modal information, exacerbating the inaccuracy in emotion recognition. In this paper, we propose a novel Cross-Modality Augmented Transformer with Hierarchical Variational Distillation, called CMATH, which consists of two major components, i.e., Multimodal Interaction Fusion and Hierarchical Variational Distillation. The former is comprised of two submodules, including Modality Reconstruction and Cross-Modality Augmented Transformer (CMA-Transformer), where Modality Reconstruction focuses on obtaining high-quality compressed representation of each modality, and CMA-Transformer adopts an asymmetric fusion strategy which treats one modality as the central modality and takes others as auxiliary modalities. The latter first designs a variational fusion network to fuse the fine-grained representations learned by CMA- Transformer into a coarse-grained representations. Then, it introduces a hierarchical distillation framework to maintain the consistency between modality representations with different granularities. Experiments on the IEMOCAP and MELD datasets demonstrate that our proposed model outperforms previous state-of-the-art baselines. Implementation codes can be available at https://github.com/ cjw-MER/CMATH.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.10060v1</guid>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaofei Zhu, Jiawei Cheng, Zhou Yang, Zhuo Chen, Qingyang Wang, Jianfeng Yao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memorization in Attention-only Transformers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.10115</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.10115v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recent research has explored the memorization capacity of multi-head attention, but these findings are constrained by unrealistic limitations on the context size. We present a novel proof for language-based Transformers that extends the current hypothesis to any context size. Our approach improves upon the state-of-the-art by achieving more effective exact memorization with an attention layer, while also introducing the concept of approximate memorization of distributions. Through experimental validation, we demonstrate that our proposed bounds more accurately reflect the true memorization capacity of language models, and provide a precise comparison with prior work.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.10115v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>L\'eo Dana, Muni Sreenivas Pydi, Yann Chevaleyre</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prompting and Fine-tuning Large Language Models for Automated Code Review Comment Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.10129</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.10129v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Generating accurate code review comments remains a significant challenge due to the inherently diverse and non-unique nature of the task output. Large language models pretrained on both programming and natural language data tend to perform well in code-oriented tasks. However, large-scale pretraining is not always feasible due to its environmental impact and project-specific generalizability issues. In this work, first we fine-tune open-source Large language models (LLM) in parameter-efficient, quantized low-rank (QLoRA) fashion on consumer-grade hardware to improve review comment generation. Recent studies demonstrate the efficacy of augmenting semantic metadata information into prompts to boost performance in other code-related tasks. To explore this in code review activities, we also prompt proprietary, closed-source LLMs augmenting the input code patch with function call graphs and code summaries. Both of our strategies improve the review comment generation performance, with function call graph augmented few-shot prompting on the GPT-3.5 model surpassing the pretrained baseline by around 90% BLEU-4 score on the CodeReviewer dataset. Moreover, few-shot prompted Gemini-1.0 Pro, QLoRA fine-tuned Code Llama and Llama 3.1 models achieve competitive results (ranging from 25% to 83% performance improvement) on this task. An additional human evaluation study further validates our experimental findings, reflecting real-world developers' perceptions of LLM-generated code review comments based on relevant qualitative metrics.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.10129v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Md. Asif Haider, Ayesha Binte Mostofa, Sk. Sabit Bin Mosaddek, Anindya Iqbal, Toufique Ahmed</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the role of `Constitutions' for learning from AI feedback</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.10168</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.10168v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The growing capabilities of large language models (LLMs) have led to their use as substitutes for human feedback for training and assessing other LLMs. These methods often rely on `constitutions', written guidelines which a critic model uses to provide feedback and improve generations. We investigate how the choice of constitution affects feedback quality by using four different constitutions to improve patient-centered communication in medical interviews. In pairwise comparisons conducted by 215 human raters, we found that detailed constitutions led to better results regarding emotive qualities. However, none of the constitutions outperformed the baseline in learning more practically-oriented skills related to information gathering and provision. Our findings indicate that while detailed constitutions should be prioritised, there are possible limitations to the effectiveness of AI feedback as a reward signal in certain areas.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.10168v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Saskia Redgate, Andrew M. Bean, Adam Mahdi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scaling up the Evaluation of Collaborative Problem Solving: Promises and Challenges of Coding Chat Data with ChatGPT</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.10246</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.10246v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Collaborative problem solving (CPS) is widely recognized as a critical 21st century skill. Efficiently coding communication data is a big challenge in scaling up research on assessing CPS. This paper reports the findings on using ChatGPT to directly code CPS chat data by benchmarking performance across multiple datasets and coding frameworks. We found that ChatGPT-based coding outperformed human coding in tasks where the discussions were characterized by colloquial languages but fell short in tasks where the discussions dealt with specialized scientific terminology and contexts. The findings offer practical guidelines for researchers to develop strategies for efficient and scalable analysis of communication data from CPS tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.10246v1</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiangang Hao, Wenju Cui, Patrick Kyllonen, Emily Kerzabi, Lei Liu, Michael Flor</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Law for Post-training after Model Pruning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.10272</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.10272v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) based on the Transformer architecture are widely employed across various domains and tasks. However, their increasing size imposes significant hardware demands, limiting practical deployment. To mitigate this, model pruning techniques have been developed to create more efficient models while maintaining high performance. Despite this, post-training after pruning is crucial for performance recovery and can be resource-intensive. This paper investigates the post-training requirements of pruned LLMs and introduces a scaling law to determine the optimal amount of post-training data. Post-training experiments with the Llama-3 and Qwen-2.5 series models, pruned using depth pruning, width pruning, and 2:4 semi-structured pruning, show that higher pruning ratios necessitate more post-training data for performance recovery, whereas larger LLMs require less. The proposed scaling law predicts a model's loss based on its parameter counts before and after pruning, as well as the post-training token counts. Furthermore, we find that the scaling law established from smaller LLMs can be reliably extrapolated to larger LLMs. This work provides valuable insights into the post-training of pruned LLMs and offers a practical scaling law for optimizing post-training data usage.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.10272v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaodong Chen, Yuxuan Hu, Jing Zhang, Xiaokang Zhang, Cuiping Li, Hong Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Dawn of GUI Agent: A Preliminary Case Study with Claude 3.5 Computer Use</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.10323</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.10323v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The recently released model, Claude 3.5 Computer Use, stands out as the first frontier AI model to offer computer use in public beta as a graphical user interface (GUI) agent. As an early beta, its capability in the real-world complex environment remains unknown. In this case study to explore Claude 3.5 Computer Use, we curate and organize a collection of carefully designed tasks spanning a variety of domains and software. Observations from these cases demonstrate Claude 3.5 Computer Use's unprecedented ability in end-to-end language to desktop actions. Along with this study, we provide an out-of-the-box agent framework for deploying API-based GUI automation models with easy implementation. Our case studies aim to showcase a groundwork of capabilities and limitations of Claude 3.5 Computer Use with detailed analyses and bring to the fore questions about planning, action, and critic, which must be considered for future improvement. We hope this preliminary exploration will inspire future research into the GUI agent community. All the test cases in the paper can be tried through the project: https://github.com/showlab/computer_use_ootb.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.10323v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Siyuan Hu, Mingyu Ouyang, Difei Gao, Mike Zheng Shou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Safe Text-to-Image Generation: Simply Sanitize the Prompt Embedding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.10329</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.10329v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In recent years, text-to-image (T2I) generation models have made significant progress in generating high-quality images that align with text descriptions. However, these models also face the risk of unsafe generation, potentially producing harmful content that violates usage policies, such as explicit material. Existing safe generation methods typically focus on suppressing inappropriate content by erasing undesired concepts from visual representations, while neglecting to sanitize the textual representation. Although these methods help mitigate the risk of misuse to certain extent, their robustness remains insufficient when dealing with adversarial attacks.
  Given that semantic consistency between input text and output image is a fundamental requirement for T2I models, we identify that textual representations (i.e., prompt embeddings) are likely the primary source of unsafe generation. To this end, we propose a vision-agnostic safe generation framework, Embedding Sanitizer (ES), which focuses on erasing inappropriate concepts from prompt embeddings and uses the sanitized embeddings to guide the model for safe generation. ES is applied to the output of the text encoder as a plug-and-play module, enabling seamless integration with different T2I models as well as other safeguards. In addition, ES's unique scoring mechanism assigns a score to each token in the prompt to indicate its potential harmfulness, and dynamically adjusts the sanitization intensity to balance defensive performance and generation quality. Through extensive evaluation on five prompt benchmarks, our approach achieves state-of-the-art robustness by sanitizing the source (prompt embedding) of unsafe generation compared to nine baseline methods. It significantly outperforms existing safeguards in terms of interpretability and controllability while maintaining generation quality.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.10329v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Huming Qiu, Guanxu Chen, Mi Zhang, Min Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Features that Make a Difference: Leveraging Gradients for Improved Dictionary Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.10397</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.10397v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Sparse Autoencoders (SAEs) are a promising approach for extracting neural network representations by learning a sparse and overcomplete decomposition of the network's internal activations. However, SAEs are traditionally trained considering only activation values and not the effect those activations have on downstream computations. This limits the information available to learn features, and biases the autoencoder towards neglecting features which are represented with small activation values but strongly influence model outputs. To address this, we introduce Gradient SAEs (g-SAEs), which modify the $k$-sparse autoencoder architecture by augmenting the TopK activation function to rely on the gradients of the input activation when selecting the $k$ elements. For a given sparsity level, g-SAEs produce reconstructions that are more faithful to original network performance when propagated through the network. Additionally, we find evidence that g-SAEs learn latents that are on average more effective at steering models in arbitrary contexts. By considering the downstream effects of activations, our approach leverages the dual nature of neural network features as both $\textit{representations}$, retrospectively, and $\textit{actions}$, prospectively. While previous methods have approached the problem of feature discovery primarily focused on the former aspect, g-SAEs represent a step towards accounting for the latter as well.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.10397v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jeffrey Olmo, Jared Wilson, Max Forsey, Bryce Hepner, Thomas Vin Howe, David Wingate</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Llama Guard 3 Vision: Safeguarding Human-AI Image Understanding Conversations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.10414</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.10414v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We introduce Llama Guard 3 Vision, a multimodal LLM-based safeguard for human-AI conversations that involves image understanding: it can be used to safeguard content for both multimodal LLM inputs (prompt classification) and outputs (response classification). Unlike the previous text-only Llama Guard versions (Inan et al., 2023; Llama Team, 2024b,a), it is specifically designed to support image reasoning use cases and is optimized to detect harmful multimodal (text and image) prompts and text responses to these prompts. Llama Guard 3 Vision is fine-tuned on Llama 3.2-Vision and demonstrates strong performance on the internal benchmarks using the MLCommons taxonomy. We also test its robustness against adversarial attacks. We believe that Llama Guard 3 Vision serves as a good starting point to build more capable and robust content moderation tools for human-AI conversation with multimodal capabilities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.10414v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jianfeng Chi, Ujjwal Karn, Hongyuan Zhan, Eric Smith, Javier Rando, Yiming Zhang, Kate Plawiak, Zacharie Delpierre Coudert, Kartikeya Upasani, Mahesh Pasupuleti</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Dynamic LLM-Powered Agent Network for Task-Oriented Agent Collaboration</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.02170</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.02170v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent studies show that collaborating multiple large language model (LLM) powered agents is a promising way for task solving. However, current approaches are constrained by using a fixed number of agents and static communication structures. In this work, we propose automatically selecting a team of agents from candidates to collaborate in a dynamic communication structure toward different tasks and domains. Specifically, we build a framework named Dynamic LLM-Powered Agent Network ($\textbf{DyLAN}$) for LLM-powered agent collaboration, operating a two-stage paradigm: (1) Team Optimization and (2) Task Solving. During the first stage, we utilize an $\textit{agent selection}$ algorithm, based on an unsupervised metric called $\textit{Agent Importance Score}$, enabling the selection of best agents according to their contributions in a preliminary trial, oriented to the given task. Then, in the second stage, the selected agents collaborate dynamically according to the query. Empirically, we demonstrate that DyLAN outperforms strong baselines in code generation, decision-making, general reasoning, and arithmetic reasoning tasks with moderate computational cost. On specific subjects in MMLU, selecting a team of agents in the team optimization stage improves accuracy by up to 25.0% in DyLAN.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.02170v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zijun Liu, Yanzhe Zhang, Peng Li, Yang Liu, Diyi Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating and Enhancing Large Language Models for Conversational Reasoning on Knowledge Graphs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11282</link>
      <description>arXiv:2312.11282v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The development of large language models (LLMs) has been catalyzed by advancements in pre-training techniques. These models have demonstrated robust reasoning capabilities through manually designed prompts. In this work, we evaluate the conversational reasoning capabilities of the current state-of-the-art LLM (GPT-4) on knowledge graphs (KGs). However, the performance of LLMs is constrained due to a lack of KG environment awareness and the difficulties in developing effective optimization mechanisms for intermediary reasoning stages. We further introduce LLM-ARK, a LLM grounded KG reasoning agent designed to deliver precise and adaptable predictions on KG paths. LLM-ARK leverages Full Textual Environment (FTE) prompt to assimilate state information within each reasoning step. We reframe the challenge of multi-hop reasoning on the KG as a sequential decision-making task. Utilizing the Proximal Policy Optimization (PPO) online policy gradient reinforcement learning algorithm, our model is optimized to learn from rich reward signals. Additionally, we conduct an evaluation of our model and GPT-4 on the OpenDialKG dataset. The experimental results reveal that LLaMA-2-7B-ARK outperforms the current state-of-the-art model by 5.28 percentage points, with a performance rate of 36.39% on the target@1 evaluation metric. Meanwhile, GPT-4 scored 14.91%, further demonstrating the effectiveness of our method. Our code is available on GitHub (https://github.com/Aipura/LLM-ARK) for further access.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2312.11282v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuxuan Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security and Privacy Challenges of Large Language Models: A Survey</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.00888</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.00888v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated extraordinary capabilities and contributed to multiple fields, such as generating and summarizing text, language translation, and question-answering. Nowadays, LLM is becoming a very popular tool in computerized language processing tasks, with the capability to analyze complicated linguistic patterns and provide relevant and appropriate responses depending on the context. While offering significant advantages, these models are also vulnerable to security and privacy attacks, such as jailbreaking attacks, data poisoning attacks, and Personally Identifiable Information (PII) leakage attacks. This survey provides a thorough review of the security and privacy challenges of LLMs for both training data and users, along with the application-based risks in various domains, such as transportation, education, and healthcare. We assess the extent of LLM vulnerabilities, investigate emerging security and privacy attacks for LLMs, and review the potential defense mechanisms. Additionally, the survey outlines existing research gaps in this domain and highlights future research directions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.00888v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Badhan Chandra Das, M. Hadi Amini, Yanzhao Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mitigating the Linguistic Gap with Phonemic Representations for Robust Cross-lingual Transfer</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.14279</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.14279v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Approaches to improving multilingual language understanding often struggle with significant performance gaps between high-resource and low-resource languages. While there are efforts to align the languages in a single latent space to mitigate such gaps, how different input-level representations influence such gaps has not been investigated, particularly with phonemic inputs. We hypothesize that the performance gaps are affected by representation discrepancies between these languages, and revisit the use of phonemic representations as a means to mitigate these discrepancies. To demonstrate the effectiveness of phonemic representations, we present experiments on three representative cross-lingual tasks on 12 languages in total. The results show that phonemic representations exhibit higher similarities between languages compared to orthographic representations, and it consistently outperforms grapheme-based baseline model on languages that are relatively low-resourced. We present quantitative evidence from three cross-lingual tasks that demonstrate the effectiveness of phonemic representations, and it is further justified by a theoretical analysis of the cross-lingual performance gap.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.14279v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haeji Jung, Changdae Oh, Jooeon Kang, Jimin Sohn, Kyungwoo Song, Jinkyu Kim, David R. Mortensen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ORLM: A Customizable Framework in Training Large Models for Automated Optimization Modeling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.17743</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.17743v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Optimization modeling and solving play a critical role in the application of Operations Research (OR) tools to address real-world problems, yet they pose challenges and require extensive expertise from OR experts. With the advent of large language models (LLMs), new opportunities have emerged to streamline and automate these tasks. However, current research predominantly relies on closed-source LLMs such as GPT-4, along with extensive prompt engineering techniques. This reliance stems from the scarcity of high-quality training datasets for optimization modeling, resulting in elevated costs, prolonged processing times, and privacy concerns. To address these challenges, our work is the first to propose a viable path for training open-source LLMs that are capable of optimization modeling as well as developing and executing solver codes, eventually leading to a superior ability for automating optimization modeling and solving. Particularly, we introduce a semi-automated data synthesis framework designed for optimization modeling issues, named OR-Instruct. This framework merges the training data requirements of large models with the unique characteristics of optimization modeling problems, and allows for customizable enhancements tailored to specific scenarios or modeling types. To evaluate the performance of our proposed framework, we present the IndustryOR benchmark, the inaugural industrial standard for evaluating LLMs in solving practical OR problems. Utilizing data synthesized through OR-Instruct, we train various open-source LLMs with a capacity of 7 billion parameters (dubbed ORLMs). The resulting model demonstrates significantly enhanced optimization modeling capabilities, achieving state-of-the-art performance across the NL4OPT, MAMO, and IndustryOR benchmarks. Our code and data are available at \url{https://github.com/Cardinal-Operations/ORLM}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.17743v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CE</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chenyu Huang, Zhengyang Tang, Dongdong Ge, Shixi Hu, Ruoqing Jiang, Benyou Wang, Zizhuo Wang, Xin Zheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automated Clinical Data Extraction with Knowledge Conditioned LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.18027</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.18027v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The extraction of lung lesion information from clinical and medical imaging reports is crucial for research on and clinical care of lung-related diseases. Large language models (LLMs) can be effective at interpreting unstructured text in reports, but they often hallucinate due to a lack of domain-specific knowledge, leading to reduced accuracy and posing challenges for use in clinical settings. To address this, we propose a novel framework that aligns generated internal knowledge with external knowledge through in-context learning (ICL). Our framework employs a retriever to identify relevant units of internal or external knowledge and a grader to evaluate the truthfulness and helpfulness of the retrieved internal-knowledge rules, to align and update the knowledge bases. Experiments with expert-curated test datasets demonstrate that this ICL approach can increase the F1 score for key fields (lesion size, margin and solidity) by an average of 12.9% over existing ICL methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.18027v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Diya Li, Asim Kadav, Aijing Gao, Rui Li, Richard Bourgon</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KPC-cF: Aspect-Based Sentiment Analysis via Implicit-Feature Alignment with Corpus Filtering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.00342</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.00342v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Investigations into Aspect-Based Sentiment Analysis (ABSA) for Korean industrial reviews are notably lacking in the existing literature. Our research proposes an intuitive and effective framework for ABSA in low-resource languages such as Korean. It optimizes prediction labels by integrating translated benchmark and unlabeled Korean data. Using a model fine-tuned on translated data, we pseudo-labeled the actual Korean NLI set. Subsequently, we applied LaBSE and \MSP{}-based filtering to this pseudo-NLI set as implicit feature, enhancing Aspect Category Detection and Polarity determination through additional training. Incorporating dual filtering, this model bridged dataset gaps, achieving positive results in Korean ABSA with minimal resources. Through additional data injection pipelines, our approach aims to utilize high-resource data and construct effective models within communities, whether corporate or individual, in low-resource language countries. Compared to English ABSA, our framework showed an approximately 3\% difference in F1 scores and accuracy. We release the dataset and our code for Korean ABSA, at this link.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.00342v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kibeom Nam</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CLIMB: A Benchmark of Clinical Bias in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.05250</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.05250v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are increasingly applied to clinical decision-making. However, their potential to exhibit bias poses significant risks to clinical equity. Currently, there is a lack of benchmarks that systematically evaluate such clinical bias in LLMs. While in downstream tasks, some biases of LLMs can be avoided such as by instructing the model to answer "I'm not sure...", the internal bias hidden within the model still lacks deep studies. We introduce CLIMB (shorthand for A Benchmark of Clinical Bias in Large Language Models), a pioneering comprehensive benchmark to evaluate both intrinsic (within LLMs) and extrinsic (on downstream tasks) bias in LLMs for clinical decision tasks. Notably, for intrinsic bias, we introduce a novel metric, AssocMAD, to assess the disparities of LLMs across multiple demographic groups. Additionally, we leverage counterfactual intervention to evaluate extrinsic bias in a task of clinical diagnosis prediction. Our experiments across popular and medically adapted LLMs, particularly from the Mistral and LLaMA families, unveil prevalent behaviors with both intrinsic and extrinsic bias. This work underscores the critical need to mitigate clinical bias and sets a new standard for future evaluations of LLMs' clinical bias.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.05250v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yubo Zhang, Shudi Hou, Mingyu Derek Ma, Wei Wang, Muhao Chen, Jieyu Zhao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Methods of Automatic Matrix Language Determination for Code-Switched Speech</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.02521</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.02521v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Code-switching (CS) is the process of speakers interchanging between two or more languages which in the modern world becomes increasingly common. In order to better describe CS speech the Matrix Language Frame (MLF) theory introduces the concept of a Matrix Language, which is the language that provides the grammatical structure for a CS utterance. In this work the MLF theory was used to develop systems for Matrix Language Identity (MLID) determination. The MLID of English/Mandarin and English/Spanish CS text and speech was compared to acoustic language identity (LID), which is a typical way to identify a language in monolingual utterances. MLID predictors from audio show higher correlation with the textual principles than LID in all cases while also outperforming LID in an MLID recognition task based on F1 macro (60%) and correlation score (0.38). This novel approach has identified that non-English languages (Mandarin and Spanish) are preferred over the English language as the ML contrary to the monolingual choice of LID.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.02521v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>In Proceedings of the 2024 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing, pages 5791-5800, Miami, Florida, USA. Association for Computational Linguistics</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Olga Iakovenko, Thomas Hain</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hyper-multi-step: The Truth Behind Difficult Long-context Tasks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.04422</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.04422v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Long-context language models (LCLM), characterized by their extensive context window, is becoming increasingly popular. Meanwhile, many long-context benchmarks present challenging tasks that even the most advanced LCLMs struggle to complete. However, the underlying sources of various challenging long-context tasks have seldom been studied. To bridge this gap, we conduct experiments to indicate their difficulty stems primarily from two basic issues: "multi-matching retrieval," which requires the simultaneous retrieval of multiple items, and "logic-based retrieval," which necessitates logical judgment within retrieval criteria. These two problems, while seemingly straightforward, actually exceed the capabilities of LCLMs because they are proven to be hyper-multi-step (demanding numerous steps to solve) in nature. This finding could explain why LLMs struggle with more advanced long-context tasks, providing a more accurate perspective for rethinking solutions for them.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.04422v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yijiong Yu, Ma Xiufa, Fang Jianwei, Zhi Xu, Su Guangyao, Wang Jiancheng, Yongfeng Huang, Zhixiao Qi, Wei Wang, Weifeng Liu, Ran Chen, Ji Pei</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Does Vision-Language Adaptation Impact the Safety of Vision Language Models?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.07571</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.07571v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Vision-Language adaptation (VL adaptation) transforms Large Language Models (LLMs) into Large Vision-Language Models (LVLMs) for multimodal tasks, but this process often compromises the inherent safety capabilities embedded in the original LLMs. Despite potential harmfulness due to weakened safety measures, in-depth analysis on the effects of VL adaptation on safety remains under-explored. This study examines how VL adaptation influences safety and evaluates the impact of safety fine-tuning methods. Our analysis reveals that safety degradation occurs during VL adaptation, even when the training data is safe. While safety tuning techniques like supervised fine-tuning with safety datasets or reinforcement learning from human feedback mitigate some risks, they still lead to safety degradation and a reduction in helpfulness due to over-rejection issues. Further analysis of internal model weights suggests that VL adaptation may impact certain safety-related layers, potentially lowering overall safety levels. Additionally, our findings demonstrate that the objectives of VL adaptation and safety tuning are divergent, which often results in their simultaneous application being suboptimal. To address this, we suggest the weight merging approach as an optimal solution effectively reducing safety degradation while maintaining helpfulness. These insights help guide the development of more reliable and secure LVLMs for real-world applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.07571v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Seongyun Lee, Geewook Kim, Jiyeon Kim, Hyunji Lee, Hoyeon Chang, Sue Hyun Park, Minjoon Seo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geometry of orofacial neuromuscular signals: speech articulation decoding using surface electromyography</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.02591</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.02591v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Each year, millions of individuals lose the ability to speak intelligibly due to causes such as neuromuscular disease, stroke, trauma, and head/neck cancer surgery (e.g. laryngectomy) or treatment (e.g. radiotherapy toxicity to the speech articulators). Effective communication is crucial for daily activities, and losing the ability to speak leads to isolation, depression, anxiety, and a host of detrimental sequelae. Noninvasive surface electromyography (sEMG) has shown promise to restore speech output in these individuals. The goal is to collect sEMG signals from multiple articulatory sites as people silently produce speech and then decode the signals to enable fluent and natural communication. Currently, many fundamental properties of orofacial neuromuscular signals relating to speech articulation remain unanswered. They include questions relating to 1) the data structure of the orofacial sEMG signals, 2)the signal distribution shift of sEMG across individuals, 3) ability of sEMG signals to span the entire English language phonetic space during silent speech articulations, and 4) the generalization capability of non-invasive sEMG based silent speech interfaces. We address these questions through a series of experiments involving healthy human subjects. We show that sEMG signals evince graph data structure and that the signal distribution shift is given by a change of basis. Furthermore, we show that silently voiced articulations spanning the entire English language phonetic space can be decoded using small neural networks which can be trained with little data and that such architectures work well across individuals. To ensure transparency and reproducibility, we open-source all the data and codes used in this study.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.02591v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Harshavardhana T. Gowda, Zachary D. McNaughton, Lee M. Miller</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DriveThru: a Document Extraction Platform and Benchmark Datasets for Indonesian Local Language Archives</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09318</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09318v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Indonesia is one of the most diverse countries linguistically. However, despite this linguistic diversity, Indonesian languages remain underrepresented in Natural Language Processing (NLP) research and technologies. In the past two years, several efforts have been conducted to construct NLP resources for Indonesian languages. However, most of these efforts have been focused on creating manual resources thus difficult to scale to more languages. Although many Indonesian languages do not have a web presence, locally there are resources that document these languages well in printed forms such as books, magazines, and newspapers. Digitizing these existing resources will enable scaling of Indonesian language resource construction to many more languages. In this paper, we propose an alternative method of creating datasets by digitizing documents, which have not previously been used to build digital language resources in Indonesia. DriveThru is a platform for extracting document content utilizing Optical Character Recognition (OCR) techniques in its system to provide language resource building with less manual effort and cost. This paper also studies the utility of current state-of-the-art LLM for post-OCR correction to show the capability of increasing the character accuracy rate (CAR) and word accuracy rate (WAR) compared to off-the-shelf OCR.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09318v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mohammad Rifqi Farhansyah, Muhammad Zuhdi Fikri Johari, Afinzaki Amiral, Ayu Purwarianti, Kumara Ari Yuana, Derry Tanti Wijaya</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Realised Volatility Forecasting: Machine Learning via Financial Word Embedding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2108.00480</link>
      <description>arXiv:2108.00480v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: This study develops a financial word embedding using 15 years of business news. Our results show that this specialised language model produces more accurate results than general word embeddings, based on a financial benchmark we established. As an application, we incorporate this word embedding into a simple machine learning model to enhance the HAR model for forecasting realised volatility. This approach statistically and economically outperforms established econometric models. Using an explainable AI method, we also identify key phrases in business news that contribute significantly to volatility, offering insights into language patterns tied to market dynamics.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2108.00480v3</guid>
      <category>q-fin.CP</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.2139/ssrn.3895272</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Eghbal Rahimikia, Stefan Zohren, Ser-Huang Poon</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>REBORN: Reinforcement-Learned Boundary Segmentation with Iterative Training for Unsupervised ASR</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03988</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.03988v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Unsupervised automatic speech recognition (ASR) aims to learn the mapping between the speech signal and its corresponding textual transcription without the supervision of paired speech-text data. A word/phoneme in the speech signal is represented by a segment of speech signal with variable length and unknown boundary, and this segmental structure makes learning the mapping between speech and text challenging, especially without paired data. In this paper, we propose REBORN,Reinforcement-Learned Boundary Segmentation with Iterative Training for Unsupervised ASR. REBORN alternates between (1) training a segmentation model that predicts the boundaries of the segmental structures in speech signals and (2) training the phoneme prediction model, whose input is the speech feature segmented by the segmentation model, to predict a phoneme transcription. Since supervised data for training the segmentation model is not available, we use reinforcement learning to train the segmentation model to favor segmentations that yield phoneme sequence predictions with a lower perplexity. We conduct extensive experiments and find that under the same setting, REBORN outperforms all prior unsupervised ASR models on LibriSpeech, TIMIT, and five non-English languages in Multilingual LibriSpeech. We comprehensively analyze why the boundaries learned by REBORN improve the unsupervised ASR performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.03988v3</guid>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Liang-Hsuan Tseng, En-Pei Hu, Cheng-Han Chiang, Yuan Tseng, Hung-yi Lee, Lin-shan Lee, Shao-Hua Sun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MANTIS: Interleaved Multi-Image Instruction Tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.01483</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.01483v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large multimodal models (LMMs) have shown great results in single-image vision language tasks. However, their abilities to solve multi-image visual language tasks is yet to be improved. The existing LMMs like OpenFlamingo, Emu2, and Idefics gain their multi-image ability through pre-training on hundreds of millions of noisy interleaved image-text data from the web, which is neither efficient nor effective. In this paper, we aim to build strong multi-image LMMs via instruction tuning with academic-level resources. Therefore, we meticulously construct Mantis-Instruct containing 721K multi-image instruction data to train a family of Mantis models. The instruction tuning empowers Mantis with different multi-image skills like co-reference, comparison, reasoning, and temporal understanding. We evaluate Mantis on 8 multi-image benchmarks and 6 single-image benchmarks. Mantis-Idefics2 can achieve SoTA results on all the multi-image benchmarks and beat the strongest multi-image baseline, Idefics2-8B by an average of 13 absolute points. Notably, Idefics2-8B was pre-trained on 140M interleaved multi-image data, which is 200x larger than Mantis-Instruct. We observe that Mantis performs equivalently well on the held-in and held-out benchmarks, which shows its generalization ability. We further evaluate Mantis on single-image benchmarks and demonstrate that Mantis also maintains a strong single-image performance on par with CogVLM and Emu2. Our results show that multi-image abilities are not necessarily gained through massive pre-training, instead, they can be gained by low-cost instruction tuning. The training and evaluation of Mantis has paved the road for future work to improve LMMs' multi-image abilities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.01483v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Transactions on Machine Learning Research 2024</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Dongfu Jiang, Xuan He, Huaye Zeng, Cong Wei, Max Ku, Qian Liu, Wenhu Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Silicon Ceiling: Auditing GPT's Race and Gender Biases in Hiring</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.04412</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.04412v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are increasingly being introduced in workplace settings, with the goals of improving efficiency and fairness. However, concerns have arisen regarding these models' potential to reflect or exacerbate social biases and stereotypes. This study explores the potential impact of LLMs on hiring practices. To do so, we conduct an AI audit of race and gender biases in one commonly-used LLM, OpenAI's GPT-3.5, taking inspiration from the history of traditional offline resume audits. We conduct two studies using names with varied race and gender connotations: resume assessment (Study 1) and resume generation (Study 2). In Study 1, we ask GPT to score resumes with 32 different names (4 names for each combination of the 2 gender and 4 racial groups) and two anonymous options across 10 occupations and 3 evaluation tasks (overall rating, willingness to interview, and hireability). We find that the model reflects some biases based on stereotypes. In Study 2, we prompt GPT to create resumes (10 for each name) for fictitious job candidates. When generating resumes, GPT reveals underlying biases; women's resumes had occupations with less experience, while Asian and Hispanic resumes had immigrant markers, such as non-native English and non-U.S. education and work experiences. Our findings contribute to a growing body of literature on LLM biases, particularly in workplace contexts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.04412v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3689904.3694699</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Lena Armstrong, Abbey Liu, Stephen MacNeil, Dana\"e Metaxa</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Review of Large Language Models and Autonomous Agents in Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.01603</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.01603v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have emerged as powerful tools in chemistry, significantly impacting molecule design, property prediction, and synthesis optimization. This review highlights LLM capabilities in these domains and their potential to accelerate scientific discovery through automation. We also review LLM-based autonomous agents: LLMs with a broader set of tools to interact with their surrounding environment. These agents perform diverse tasks such as paper scraping, interfacing with automated laboratories, and synthesis planning. As agents are an emerging topic, we extend the scope of our review of agents beyond chemistry and discuss across any scientific domains. This review covers the recent history, current capabilities, and design of LLMs and autonomous agents, addressing specific challenges, opportunities, and future directions in chemistry. Key challenges include data quality and integration, model interpretability, and the need for standard benchmarks, while future directions point towards more sophisticated multi-modal agents and enhanced collaboration between agents and experimental methods. Due to the quick pace of this field, a repository has been built to keep track of the latest studies: https://github.com/ur-whitelab/LLMs-in-science.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.01603v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>physics.chem-ph</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mayk Caldas Ramos, Christopher J. Collison, Andrew D. White</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GPT-4V Cannot Generate Radiology Reports Yet</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.12176</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.12176v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: GPT-4V's purported strong multimodal abilities raise interests in using it to automate radiology report writing, but there lacks thorough evaluations. In this work, we perform a systematic evaluation of GPT-4V in generating radiology reports on two chest X-ray report datasets: MIMIC-CXR and IU X-Ray. We attempt to directly generate reports using GPT-4V through different prompting strategies and find that it fails terribly in both lexical metrics and clinical efficacy metrics. To understand the low performance, we decompose the task into two steps: 1) the medical image reasoning step of predicting medical condition labels from images; and 2) the report synthesis step of generating reports from (groundtruth) conditions. We show that GPT-4V's performance in image reasoning is consistently low across different prompts. In fact, the distributions of model-predicted labels remain constant regardless of which groundtruth conditions are present on the image, suggesting that the model is not interpreting chest X-rays meaningfully. Even when given groundtruth conditions in report synthesis, its generated reports are less correct and less natural-sounding than a finetuned LLaMA-2. Altogether, our findings cast doubt on the viability of using GPT-4V in a radiology workflow.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.12176v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuyang Jiang, Chacha Chen, Dang Nguyen, Benjamin M. Mervak, Chenhao Tan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VLEU: a Method for Automatic Evaluation for Generalizability of Text-to-Image Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.14704</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.14704v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Progress in Text-to-Image (T2I) models has significantly improved the generation of images from textual descriptions. However, existing evaluation metrics do not adequately assess the models' ability to handle a diverse range of textual prompts, which is crucial for their generalizability. To address this, we introduce a new metric called Visual Language Evaluation Understudy (VLEU). VLEU uses large language models to sample from the visual text domain, the set of all possible input texts for T2I models, to generate a wide variety of prompts. The images generated from these prompts are evaluated based on their alignment with the input text using the CLIP model.VLEU quantifies a model's generalizability by computing the Kullback-Leibler divergence between the marginal distribution of the visual text and the conditional distribution of the images generated by the model. This metric provides a quantitative way to compare different T2I models and track improvements during model finetuning. Our experiments demonstrate the effectiveness of VLEU in evaluating the generalization capability of various T2I models, positioning it as an essential metric for future research in text-to-image synthesis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.14704v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jingtao Cao, Zheng Zhang, Hongru Wang, Kam-Fai Wong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Large Language Models Truly Grasp Mathematics? An Empirical Exploration From Cognitive Psychology</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.14979</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.14979v5 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The cognitive mechanism by which Large Language Models (LLMs) solve mathematical problems remains a widely debated and unresolved issue. Currently, there is little interpretable experimental evidence that connects LLMs' problem-solving with human cognitive psychology.To determine if LLMs possess human-like mathematical reasoning, we modified the problems used in the human Cognitive Reflection Test (CRT). Our results show that, even with the use of Chains of Thought (CoT) prompts, mainstream LLMs, including the latest o1 model (noted for its reasoning capabilities), have a high error rate when solving these modified CRT problems. Specifically, the average accuracy rate dropped by up to 50% compared to the original questions.Further analysis of LLMs' incorrect answers suggests that they primarily rely on pattern matching from their training data, which aligns more with human intuition (System 1 thinking) rather than with human-like reasoning (System 2 thinking). This finding challenges the belief that LLMs have genuine mathematical reasoning abilities comparable to humans. As a result, this work may adjust overly optimistic views on LLMs' progress towards artificial general intelligence.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.14979v5</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wei Xie, Shuoyoucheng Ma, Zhenhua Wang, Enze Wang, Kai Chen, Xiaobing Sun, Baosheng Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying Large Language Models for Medicine: A Primer</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.18856</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.18856v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) represent a transformative class of AI tools capable of revolutionizing various aspects of healthcare by generating human-like responses across diverse contexts and adapting to novel tasks following human instructions. Their potential application spans a broad range of medical tasks, such as clinical documentation, matching patients to clinical trials, and answering medical questions. In this primer paper, we propose an actionable guideline to help healthcare professionals more efficiently utilize LLMs in their work, along with a set of best practices. This approach consists of several main phases, including formulating the task, choosing LLMs, prompt engineering, fine-tuning, and deployment. We start with the discussion of critical considerations in identifying healthcare tasks that align with the core capabilities of LLMs and selecting models based on the selected task and data, performance requirements, and model interface. We then review the strategies, such as prompt engineering and fine-tuning, to adapt standard LLMs to specialized medical tasks. Deployment considerations, including regulatory compliance, ethical guidelines, and continuous monitoring for fairness and bias, are also discussed. By providing a structured step-by-step methodology, this tutorial aims to equip healthcare professionals with the tools necessary to effectively integrate LLMs into clinical practice, ensuring that these powerful technologies are applied in a safe, reliable, and impactful manner.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.18856v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qiao Jin, Nicholas Wan, Robert Leaman, Shubo Tian, Zhizheng Wang, Yifan Yang, Zifeng Wang, Guangzhi Xiong, Po-Ting Lai, Qingqing Zhu, Benjamin Hou, Maame Sarfo-Gyamfi, Gongbo Zhang, Aidan Gilson, Balu Bhasuran, Zhe He, Aidong Zhang, Jimeng Sun, Chunhua Weng, Ronald M. Summers, Qingyu Chen, Yifan Peng, Zhiyong Lu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Communication Compression for Tensor Parallel LLM Inference</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09510</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09510v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have pushed the frontier of artificial intelligence but are comprised of hundreds of billions of parameters and operations. For faster inference latency, LLMs are deployed on multiple hardware accelerators through various Model Parallelism strategies. Our paper looks into the details on one such strategy - Tensor Parallel - and proposes to reduce latency by compressing inter-accelerator communication. We leverage fine grained quantization techniques to compress selected activations by 3.5 - 4.5x. Our proposed method leads up to 2x reduction of time-to-first-token (TTFT) with negligible model performance degradation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09510v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jan Hansen-Palmus, Michael Truong Le, Oliver Hausd\"orfer, Alok Verma</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
