<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL</link>
    <description>cs.CL updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 05:00:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Sunday</day>
      <day>Saturday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>CORRECT: Context- and Reference-Augmented Reasoning and Prompting for Fact-Checking</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09635</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09635v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Fact-checking the truthfulness of claims usually requires reasoning over multiple evidence sentences. Oftentimes, evidence sentences may not be always self-contained, and may require additional contexts and references from elsewhere to understand coreferential expressions, acronyms, and the scope of a reported finding. For example, evidence sentences from an academic paper may need contextual sentences in the paper and descriptions in its cited papers to determine the scope of a research discovery. However, most fact-checking models mainly focus on the reasoning within evidence sentences, and ignore the auxiliary contexts and references. To address this problem, we propose a novel method, Context- and Reference-augmented Reasoning and Prompting. For evidence reasoning, we construct a three-layer evidence graph with evidence, context, and reference layers. We design intra- and cross-layer reasoning to integrate three graph layers into a unified evidence embedding. For verdict prediction, we design evidence-conditioned prompt encoder, which produces unique prompt embeddings for each claim. These evidence-conditioned prompt embeddings and claims are unified for fact-checking. Experiments verify the strength of our model.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09635v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Delvin Ce Zhang, Dongwon Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reading between the Lines: Can LLMs Identify Cross-Cultural Communication Gaps?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09636</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09636v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In a rapidly globalizing and digital world, content such as book and product reviews created by people from diverse cultures are read and consumed by others from different corners of the world. In this paper, we investigate the extent and patterns of gaps in understandability of book reviews due to the presence of culturally-specific items and elements that might be alien to users from another culture. Our user-study on 57 book reviews from Goodreads reveal that 83\% of the reviews had at least one culture-specific difficult-to-understand element. We also evaluate the efficacy of GPT-4o in identifying such items, given the cultural background of the reader; the results are mixed, implying a significant scope for improvement. Our datasets are available here: https://github.com/sougata-ub/reading_between_lines</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09636v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sougata Saha, Saurabh Kumar Pandey, Harshit Gupta, Monojit Choudhury</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jailbreaking to Jailbreak</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09638</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09638v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Refusal training on Large Language Models (LLMs) prevents harmful outputs, yet this defense remains vulnerable to both automated and human-crafted jailbreaks. We present a novel LLM-as-red-teamer approach in which a human jailbreaks a refusal-trained LLM to make it willing to jailbreak itself or other LLMs. We refer to the jailbroken LLMs as $J_2$ attackers, which can systematically evaluate target models using various red teaming strategies and improve its performance via in-context learning from the previous failures. Our experiments demonstrate that Sonnet 3.5 and Gemini 1.5 pro outperform other LLMs as $J_2$, achieving 93.0% and 91.0% attack success rates (ASRs) respectively against GPT-4o (and similar results across other capable LLMs) on Harmbench. Our work not only introduces a scalable approach to strategic red teaming, drawing inspiration from human red teamers, but also highlights jailbreaking-to-jailbreak as an overlooked failure mode of the safeguard. Specifically, an LLM can bypass its own safeguards by employing a jailbroken version of itself that is willing to assist in further jailbreaking. To prevent any direct misuse with $J_2$, while advancing research in AI safety, we publicly share our methodology while keeping specific prompting details private.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09638v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jeremy Kritz, Vaughn Robinson, Robert Vacareanu, Bijan Varjavand, Michael Choi, Bobby Gogov, Scale Red Team, Summer Yue, Willow E. Primack, Zifan Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Online Social Support Detection in Spanish Social Media Texts</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09640</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09640v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The advent of social media has transformed communication, enabling individuals to share their experiences, seek support, and participate in diverse discussions. While extensive research has focused on identifying harmful content like hate speech, the recognition and promotion of positive and supportive interactions remain largely unexplored. This study proposes an innovative approach to detecting online social support in Spanish-language social media texts. We introduce the first annotated dataset specifically created for this task, comprising 3,189 YouTube comments classified as supportive or non-supportive. To address data imbalance, we employed GPT-4o to generate paraphrased comments and create a balanced dataset. We then evaluated social support classification using traditional machine learning models, deep learning architectures, and transformer-based models, including GPT-4o, but only on the unbalanced dataset. Subsequently, we utilized a transformer model to compare the performance between the balanced and unbalanced datasets. Our findings indicate that the balanced dataset yielded improved results for Task 2 (Individual and Group) and Task 3 (Nation, Other, LGBTQ, Black Community, Women, Religion), whereas GPT-4o performed best for Task 1 (Social Support and Non-Support). This study highlights the significance of fostering a supportive online environment and lays the groundwork for future research in automated social support detection.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09640v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Moein Shahiki Tash, Luis Ramos, Zahra Ahani, Raul Monroy, Olga kolesnikova, Hiram Calvo, Grigori Sidorov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Krutrim LLM: Multilingual Foundational Model for over a Billion People</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09642</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09642v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: India is a diverse society with unique challenges in developing AI systems, including linguistic diversity, oral traditions, data accessibility, and scalability. Existing foundation models are primarily trained on English, limiting their effectiveness for India's population. Indic languages comprise only 1 percent of Common Crawl corpora despite India representing 18 percent of the global population, leading to linguistic biases. Thousands of regional languages, dialects, and code mixing create additional representation challenges due to sparse training data.
  We introduce Krutrim LLM, a 2 trillion token multilingual model designed for India's linguistic landscape. It incorporates the largest known Indic dataset, mitigating data scarcity and ensuring balanced performance across dialects. Krutrim outperforms or matches state-of-the-art models on Indic benchmarks while maintaining competitive English performance. Despite being significantly smaller in training flops, Krutrim LLM matches or exceeds models like LLAMA-2 on 10 out of 16 tasks, with an average score of 0.57 versus 0.55. This evidences Krutrim's flexible multilingual fluency across diverse linguistic contexts.
  Krutrim is integrated with real-time search to improve factual accuracy in conversational AI applications. This enhances accessibility for over 1 billion users worldwide. Through intentional design choices addressing data imbalances, Krutrim LLM signifies meaningful progress in building ethical, globally representative AI models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09642v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aditya Kallappa, Palash Kamble, Abhinav Ravi, Akshat Patidar, Vinayak Dhruv, Deepak Kumar, Raghav Awasthi, Arveti Manjunath, Shubham Agarwal, Kumar Ashish, Gautam Bhargava, Chandra Khatri</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Argumentation to Deliberation: Perspectivized Stance Vectors for Fine-grained (Dis)agreement Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09644</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09644v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Debating over conflicting issues is a necessary first step towards resolving conflicts. However, intrinsic perspectives of an arguer are difficult to overcome by persuasive argumentation skills. Proceeding from a debate to a deliberative process, where we can identify actionable options for resolving a conflict requires a deeper analysis of arguments and the perspectives they are grounded in - as it is only from there that one can derive mutually agreeable resolution steps. In this work we develop a framework for a deliberative analysis of arguments in a computational argumentation setup. We conduct a fine-grained analysis of perspectivized stances expressed in the arguments of different arguers or stakeholders on a given issue, aiming not only to identify their opposing views, but also shared perspectives arising from their attitudes, values or needs. We formalize this analysis in Perspectivized Stance Vectors that characterize the individual perspectivized stances of all arguers on a given issue. We construct these vectors by determining issue- and argument-specific concepts, and predict an arguer's stance relative to each of them. The vectors allow us to measure a modulated (dis)agreement between arguers, structured by perspectives, which allows us to identify actionable points for conflict resolution, as a first step towards deliberation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09644v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Moritz Plenz, Philipp Heinisch, Janosch Gehring, Philipp Cimiano, Anette Frank</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From No to Know: Taxonomy, Challenges, and Opportunities for Negation Understanding in Multimodal Foundation Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09645</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09645v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Negation, a linguistic construct conveying absence, denial, or contradiction, poses significant challenges for multilingual multimodal foundation models. These models excel in tasks like machine translation, text-guided generation, image captioning, audio interactions, and video processing but often struggle to accurately interpret negation across diverse languages and cultural contexts. In this perspective paper, we propose a comprehensive taxonomy of negation constructs, illustrating how structural, semantic, and cultural factors influence multimodal foundation models. We present open research questions and highlight key challenges, emphasizing the importance of addressing these issues to achieve robust negation handling. Finally, we advocate for specialized benchmarks, language-specific tokenization, fine-grained attention mechanisms, and advanced multimodal architectures. These strategies can foster more adaptable and semantically precise multimodal foundation models, better equipped to navigate and accurately interpret the complexities of negation in multilingual, multimodal environments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09645v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mayank Vatsa, Aparna Bharati, Surbhi Mittal, Richa Singh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Language Shift or Maintenance? An Intergenerational Study of the Tibetan Community in Saudi Arabia</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09646</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09646v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The present study provides the first-ever report on the language shift from Tibetan to Arabic among descendants of Tibetan families who migrated from the Tibet region to Saudi Arabia around 70 years ago. The aim of this study was to determine whether three age groups had adopted different practices in terms of maintaining Tibetan or shifting to Hijazi Arabic. To this end, 96 male and female members of the Tibetan community responded to a questionnaire in which they were asked about their code choice in different domains (home, neighbourhood, friends and relatives, expressing emotion, and performing religious rituals). The data revealed significant intergenerational differences between members of the community in terms of the extent of the shift to Arabic, with Tibetan rarely used by younger members and older members making only slightly more use of it. The difference between the three age groups was significant, at a p-value of .001.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09646v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.36892/ijlls.v5i3.1407</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Sumaiyah Turkistani Mohammad Almoaily</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling Simplicities of Attention: Adaptive Long-Context Head Identification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09647</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09647v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The ability to process long contexts is crucial for many natural language processing tasks, yet it remains a significant challenge. While substantial progress has been made in enhancing the efficiency of attention mechanisms, there is still a gap in understanding how attention heads function in long-context settings. In this paper, we observe that while certain heads consistently attend to local information only, others swing between attending to local and long-context information depending on the query. This raises the question: can we identify which heads require long-context information to predict the next token accurately? We demonstrate that it's possible to predict which heads are crucial for long-context processing using only local keys. The core idea here is to exploit a simple model for the long-context scores via second moment approximations. These findings unveil simple properties of attention in the context of long sequences, and open the door to potentially significant gains in efficiency.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09647v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Konstantin Donhauser, Charles Arnal, Mohammad Pezeshki, Vivien Cabannes, David Lopez-Paz, Kartik Ahuja</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UKTA: Unified Korean Text Analyzer</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09648</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09648v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Evaluating writing quality is complex and time-consuming often delaying feedback to learners. While automated writing evaluation tools are effective for English, Korean automated writing evaluation tools face challenges due to their inability to address multi-view analysis, error propagation, and evaluation explainability. To overcome these challenges, we introduce UKTA (Unified Korean Text Analyzer), a comprehensive Korea text analysis and writing evaluation system. UKTA provides accurate low-level morpheme analysis, key lexical features for mid-level explainability, and transparent high-level rubric-based writing scores. Our approach enhances accuracy and quadratic weighted kappa over existing baseline, positioning UKTA as a leading multi-perspective tool for Korean text analysis and writing evaluation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09648v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Seokho Ahn, Junhyung Park, Ganghee Go, Chulhui Kim, Jiho Jung, Myung Sun Shin, Do-Guk Kim, Young-Duk Seo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Principled Data Selection for Alignment: The Hidden Risks of Difficult Examples</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09650</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09650v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The alignment of large language models (LLMs) often assumes that using more clean data yields better outcomes, overlooking the match between model capacity and example difficulty. Challenging this, we propose a new principle: Preference data vary in difficulty, and overly difficult examples hinder alignment, by exceeding the model's capacity. Through systematic experimentation, we validate this principle with three key findings: (1) preference examples vary in difficulty, as evidenced by consistent learning orders across alignment runs; (2) overly difficult examples significantly degrade performance across four LLMs and two datasets; and (3) the capacity of a model dictates its threshold for handling difficult examples, underscoring a critical relationship between data selection and model capacity. Building on this principle, we introduce Selective DPO, which filters out overly difficult examples. This simple adjustment improves alignment performance by 9-16% in win rates on the AlpacaEval 2 benchmark compared to the DPO baseline, suppressing a series of DPO variants with different algorithmic adjustments. Together, these results illuminate the importance of aligning data difficulty with model capacity, offering a transformative perspective for improving alignment strategies in LLMs. Code is available at https://github.com/glorgao/SelectiveDPO.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09650v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chengqian Gao, Haonan Li, Liu Liu, Zeke Xie, Peilin Zhao, Zhiqiang Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI-VERDE: A Gateway for Egalitarian Access to Large Language Model-Based Resources For Educational Institutions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09651</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09651v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present AI-VERDE, a unified LLM-as-a-platform service designed to facilitate seamless integration of commercial, cloud-hosted, and on-premise open LLMs in academic settings. AI-VERDE streamlines access management for instructional and research groups by providing features such as robust access control, privacy-preserving mechanisms, native Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) support, budget management for third-party LLM services, and both a conversational web interface and API access. In a pilot deployment at a large public university, AI-VERDE demonstrated significant engagement across diverse educational and research groups, enabling activities that would typically require substantial budgets for commercial LLM services with limited user and team management capabilities. To the best of our knowledge, AI-Verde is the first platform to address both academic and research needs for LLMs within an higher education institutional framework.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09651v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Paul Mithun, Enrique Noriega-Atala, Nirav Merchant, Edwin Skidmore</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neuro-Conceptual Artificial Intelligence: Integrating OPM with Deep Learning to Enhance Question Answering Quality</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09658</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09658v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Knowledge representation and reasoning are critical challenges in Artificial Intelligence (AI), particularly in integrating neural and symbolic approaches to achieve explainable and transparent AI systems. Traditional knowledge representation methods often fall short of capturing complex processes and state changes. We introduce Neuro-Conceptual Artificial Intelligence (NCAI), a specialization of the neuro-symbolic AI approach that integrates conceptual modeling using Object-Process Methodology (OPM) ISO 19450:2024 with deep learning to enhance question-answering (QA) quality. By converting natural language text into OPM models using in-context learning, NCAI leverages the expressive power of OPM to represent complex OPM elements-processes, objects, and states-beyond what traditional triplet-based knowledge graphs can easily capture. This rich structured knowledge representation improves reasoning transparency and answer accuracy in an OPM-QA system. We further propose transparency evaluation metrics to quantitatively measure how faithfully the predicted reasoning aligns with OPM-based conceptual logic. Our experiments demonstrate that NCAI outperforms traditional methods, highlighting its potential for advancing neuro-symbolic AI by providing rich knowledge representations, measurable transparency, and improved reasoning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09658v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING), 1-15, Jan. 2025</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Xin Kang, Veronika Shteingardt, Yuhan Wang, Dov Dori</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cancer Vaccine Adjuvant Name Recognition from Biomedical Literature using Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09659</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09659v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Motivation: An adjuvant is a chemical incorporated into vaccines that enhances their efficacy by improving the immune response. Identifying adjuvant names from cancer vaccine studies is essential for furthering research and enhancing immunotherapies. However, the manual curation from the constantly expanding biomedical literature poses significant challenges. This study explores the automated recognition of vaccine adjuvant names using Large Language Models (LLMs), specifically Generative Pretrained Transformers (GPT) and Large Language Model Meta AI (Llama). Methods: We utilized two datasets: 97 clinical trial records from AdjuvareDB and 290 abstracts annotated with the Vaccine Adjuvant Compendium (VAC). GPT-4o and Llama 3.2 were employed in zero-shot and few-shot learning paradigms with up to four examples per prompt. Prompts explicitly targeted adjuvant names, testing the impact of contextual information such as substances or interventions. Outputs underwent automated and manual validation for accuracy and consistency. Results: GPT-4o attained 100% Precision across all situations while exhibiting notable improve in Recall and F1-scores, particularly with incorporating interventions. On the VAC dataset, GPT-4o achieved a maximum F1-score of 77.32% with interventions, surpassing Llama-3.2-3B by approximately 2%. On the AdjuvareDB dataset, GPT-4o reached an F1-score of 81.67% for three-shot prompting with interventions, surpassing Llama-3.2-3 B's maximum F1-score of 65.62%. Conclusion: Our findings demonstrate that LLMs excel at identifying adjuvant names, including rare variations of naming representation. This study emphasizes the capability of LLMs to enhance cancer vaccine development by efficiently extracting insights. Future work aims to broaden the framework to encompass various biomedical literature and enhance model generalizability across various vaccines and adjuvants.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09659v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hasin Rehana, Jie Zheng, Leo Yeh, Benu Bansal, Nur Bengisu \c{C}am, Christianah Jemiyo, Brett McGregor, Arzucan \"Ozg\"ur, Yongqun He, Junguk Hur</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>k-LLMmeans: Summaries as Centroids for Interpretable and Scalable LLM-Based Text Clustering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09667</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09667v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We introduce k-LLMmeans, a novel modification of the k-means clustering algorithm that utilizes LLMs to generate textual summaries as cluster centroids, thereby capturing contextual and semantic nuances often lost when relying on purely numerical means of document embeddings. This modification preserves the properties of k-means while offering greater interpretability: the cluster centroid is represented by an LLM-generated summary, whose embedding guides cluster assignments. We also propose a mini-batch variant, enabling efficient online clustering for streaming text data and providing real-time interpretability of evolving cluster centroids. Through extensive simulations, we show that our methods outperform vanilla k-means on multiple metrics while incurring only modest LLM usage that does not scale with dataset size. Finally, We present a case study showcasing the interpretability of evolving cluster centroids in sequential text streams. As part of our evaluation, we compile a new dataset from StackExchange, offering a benchmark for text-stream clustering.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09667v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jairo Diaz-Rodriguez</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Science of Evaluating Foundation Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09670</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09670v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The emergent phenomena of large foundation models have revolutionized natural language processing. However, evaluating these models presents significant challenges due to their size, capabilities, and deployment across diverse applications. Existing literature often focuses on individual aspects, such as benchmark performance or specific tasks, but fails to provide a cohesive process that integrates the nuances of diverse use cases with broader ethical and operational considerations. This work focuses on three key aspects: (1) Formalizing the Evaluation Process by providing a structured framework tailored to specific use-case contexts, (2) Offering Actionable Tools and Frameworks such as checklists and templates to ensure thorough, reproducible, and practical evaluations, and (3) Surveying Recent Work with a targeted review of advancements in LLM evaluation, emphasizing real-world applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09670v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiayi Yuan, Jiamu Zhang, Andrew Wen, Xia Hu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Smarter LLMs Safer? Exploring Safety-Reasoning Trade-offs in Prompting and Fine-Tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09673</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09673v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated remarkable success across various NLP benchmarks. However, excelling in complex tasks that require nuanced reasoning and precise decision-making demands more than raw language proficiency--LLMs must reason, i.e., think logically, draw from past experiences, and synthesize information to reach conclusions and take action. To enhance reasoning abilities, approaches such as prompting and fine-tuning have been widely explored. While these methods have led to clear improvements in reasoning, their impact on LLM safety remains less understood. In this work, we investigate the interplay between reasoning and safety in LLMs. We highlight the latent safety risks that arise as reasoning capabilities improve, shedding light on previously overlooked vulnerabilities. At the same time, we explore how reasoning itself can be leveraged to enhance safety, uncovering potential mitigation strategies. By examining both the risks and opportunities in reasoning-driven LLM safety, our study provides valuable insights for developing models that are not only more capable but also more trustworthy in real-world deployments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09673v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ang Li, Yichuan Mo, Mingjie Li, Yifei Wang, Yisen Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Hidden Dimensions of LLM Alignment: A Multi-Dimensional Safety Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09674</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09674v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models' safety-aligned behaviors, such as refusing harmful queries, can be represented by linear directions in activation space. Previous research modeled safety behavior with a single direction, limiting mechanistic understanding to an isolated safety feature. In this work, we discover that safety-aligned behavior is jointly controlled by multi-dimensional directions. Namely, we study the vector space of representation shifts during safety fine-tuning on Llama 3 8B for refusing jailbreaks. By studying orthogonal directions in the space, we first find that a dominant direction governs the model's refusal behavior, while multiple smaller directions represent distinct and interpretable features like hypothetical narrative and role-playing. We then measure how different directions promote or suppress the dominant direction, showing the important role of secondary directions in shaping the model's refusal representation. Finally, we demonstrate that removing certain trigger tokens in harmful queries can mitigate these directions to bypass the learned safety capability, providing new insights on understanding safety alignment vulnerability from a multi-dimensional perspective. Code and artifacts are available at https://github.com/BMPixel/safety-residual-space.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09674v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenbo Pan, Zhichao Liu, Qiguang Chen, Xiangyang Zhou, Haining Yu, Xiaohua Jia</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-level Conflict-Aware Network for Multi-modal Sentiment Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09675</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09675v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Multimodal Sentiment Analysis (MSA) aims to recognize human emotions by exploiting textual, acoustic, and visual modalities, and thus how to make full use of the interactions between different modalities is a central challenge of MSA. Interaction contains alignment and conflict aspects. Current works mainly emphasize alignment and the inherent differences between unimodal modalities, neglecting the fact that there are also potential conflicts between bimodal combinations. Additionally, multi-task learning-based conflict modeling methods often rely on the unstable generated labels. To address these challenges, we propose a novel multi-level conflict-aware network (MCAN) for multimodal sentiment analysis, which progressively segregates alignment and conflict constituents from unimodal and bimodal representations, and further exploits the conflict constituents with the conflict modeling branch. In the conflict modeling branch, we conduct discrepancy constraints at both the representation and predicted output levels, avoiding dependence on the generated labels. Experimental results on the CMU-MOSI and CMU-MOSEI datasets demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed MCAN.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09675v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yubo Gao, Haotian Wu, Lei Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mind What You Ask For: Emotional and Rational Faces of Persuasion by Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09687</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09687v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Be careful what you ask for, you just might get it. This saying fits with the way large language models (LLMs) are trained, which, instead of being rewarded for correctness, are increasingly rewarded for pleasing the recipient. So, they are increasingly effective at persuading us that their answers are valuable. But what tricks do they use in this persuasion? In this study, we examine what are the psycholinguistic features of the responses used by twelve different language models. By grouping response content according to rational or emotional prompts and exploring social influence principles employed by LLMs, we ask whether and how we can mitigate the risks of LLM-driven mass misinformation. We position this study within the broader discourse on human-centred AI, emphasizing the need for interdisciplinary approaches to mitigate cognitive and societal risks posed by persuasive AI responses.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09687v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wiktoria Mieleszczenko-Kowszewicz, Beata Bajcar, Jolanta Babiak, Berenika Dyczek, Jakub \'Swistak, Przemys{\l}aw Biecek</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Language Models and Provenance Metadata for Determining the Relevance of Images and Videos in News Stories</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09689</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09689v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The most effective misinformation campaigns are multimodal, often combining text with images and videos taken out of context -- or fabricating them entirely -- to support a given narrative. Contemporary methods for detecting misinformation, whether in deepfakes or text articles, often miss the interplay between multiple modalities. Built around a large language model, the system proposed in this paper addresses these challenges. It analyzes both the article's text and the provenance metadata of included images and videos to determine whether they are relevant. We open-source the system prototype and interactive web interface.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09689v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tomas Peterka, Matyas Bohacek</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trust at Your Own Peril: A Mixed Methods Exploration of the Ability of Large Language Models to Generate Expert-Like Systems Engineering Artifacts and a Characterization of Failure Modes</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09690</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09690v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Multi-purpose Large Language Models (LLMs), a subset of generative Artificial Intelligence (AI), have recently made significant progress. While expectations for LLMs to assist systems engineering (SE) tasks are paramount; the interdisciplinary and complex nature of systems, along with the need to synthesize deep-domain knowledge and operational context, raise questions regarding the efficacy of LLMs to generate SE artifacts, particularly given that they are trained using data that is broadly available on the internet. To that end, we present results from an empirical exploration, where a human expert-generated SE artifact was taken as a benchmark, parsed, and fed into various LLMs through prompt engineering to generate segments of typical SE artifacts. This procedure was applied without any fine-tuning or calibration to document baseline LLM performance. We then adopted a two-fold mixed-methods approach to compare AI generated artifacts against the benchmark. First, we quantitatively compare the artifacts using natural language processing algorithms and find that when prompted carefully, the state-of-the-art algorithms cannot differentiate AI-generated artifacts from the human-expert benchmark. Second, we conduct a qualitative deep dive to investigate how they differ in terms of quality. We document that while the two-material appear very similar, AI generated artifacts exhibit serious failure modes that could be difficult to detect. We characterize these as: premature requirements definition, unsubstantiated numerical estimates, and propensity to overspecify. We contend that this study tells a cautionary tale about why the SE community must be more cautious adopting AI suggested feedback, at least when generated by multi-purpose LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09690v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Taylan G. Topcu, Mohammed Husain, Max Ofsa, Paul Wach</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FoNE: Precise Single-Token Number Embeddings via Fourier Features</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09741</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09741v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) typically represent numbers using multiple tokens, which requires the model to aggregate these tokens to interpret numerical values. This fragmentation makes both training and inference less efficient and adversely affects the model's performance on number-related tasks. Inspired by the observation that pre-trained LLMs internally learn Fourier-like features for number tokens, we propose Fourier Number Embedding (FoNE), a novel method that directly maps numbers into the embedding space with their Fourier features. FoNE encodes each number as a single token with only two embedding dimensions per digit, effectively capturing numerical values without fragmentation. This compact representation accelerates both training and inference. Compared to traditional subword and digit-wise embeddings, FoNE not only reduces computational overhead but also achieves higher accuracy across various numerical tasks including addition, subtraction and multiplication. On 6-digit decimal addition, FoNE requires 64$\times$ less data to achieve 99% accuracy than subword and digit-wise embeddings while using 3$\times$ and 6$\times$ fewer tokens per number, respectively. Furthermore, FoNE is the only method that yields 100% accuracy on over 100,000 test examples for addition, subtraction, and multiplication. The codes and visualization are available at https://fouriernumber.github.io/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09741v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tianyi Zhou, Deqing Fu, Mahdi Soltanolkotabi, Robin Jia, Vatsal Sharan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Partial Colexifications Improve Concept Embeddings</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09743</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09743v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: While the embedding of words has revolutionized the field of Natural Language Processing, the embedding of concepts has received much less attention so far. A dense and meaningful representation of concepts, however, could prove useful for several tasks in computational linguistics, especially those involving cross-linguistic data or sparse data from low resource languages. First methods that have been proposed so far embed concepts from automatically constructed colexification networks. While these approaches depart from automatically inferred polysemies, attested across a larger number of languages, they are restricted to the word level, ignoring lexical relations that would only hold for parts of the words in a given language. Building on recently introduced methods for the inference of partial colexifications, we show how they can be used to improve concept embeddings in meaningful ways. The learned embeddings are evaluated against lexical similarity ratings, recorded instances of semantic shift, and word association data. We show that in all evaluation tasks, the inclusion of partial colexifications lead to improved concept representations and better results. Our results further show that the learned embeddings are able to capture and represent different semantic relationships between concepts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09743v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Arne Rubehn, Johann-Mattis List</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Widespread Adoption of Large Language Model-Assisted Writing Across Society</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09747</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09747v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The recent advances in large language models (LLMs) attracted significant public and policymaker interest in its adoption patterns. In this paper, we systematically analyze LLM-assisted writing across four domains-consumer complaints, corporate communications, job postings, and international organization press releases-from January 2022 to September 2024. Our dataset includes 687,241 consumer complaints, 537,413 corporate press releases, 304.3 million job postings, and 15,919 United Nations (UN) press releases. Using a robust population-level statistical framework, we find that LLM usage surged following the release of ChatGPT in November 2022. By late 2024, roughly 18% of financial consumer complaint text appears to be LLM-assisted, with adoption patterns spread broadly across regions and slightly higher in urban areas. For corporate press releases, up to 24% of the text is attributable to LLMs. In job postings, LLM-assisted writing accounts for just below 10% in small firms, and is even more common among younger firms. UN press releases also reflect this trend, with nearly 14% of content being generated or modified by LLMs. Although adoption climbed rapidly post-ChatGPT, growth appears to have stabilized by 2024, reflecting either saturation in LLM adoption or increasing subtlety of more advanced models. Our study shows the emergence of a new reality in which firms, consumers and even international organizations substantially rely on generative AI for communications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09747v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weixin Liang, Yaohui Zhang, Mihai Codreanu, Jiayu Wang, Hancheng Cao, James Zou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prompt and circumstance: A word-by-word LLM prompting approach to interlinear glossing for low-resource languages</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09778</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09778v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Partly automated creation of interlinear glossed text (IGT) has the potential to assist in linguistic documentation. We argue that LLMs can make this process more accessible to linguists because of their capacity to follow natural-language instructions. We investigate the effectiveness of a retrieval-based LLM prompting approach to glossing, applied to the seven languages from the SIGMORPHON 2023 shared task. Our system beats the BERT-based shared task baseline for every language in the morpheme-level score category, and we show that a simple 3-best oracle has higher word-level scores than the challenge winner (a tuned sequence model) in five languages. In a case study on Tsez, we ask the LLM to automatically create and follow linguistic instructions, reducing errors on a confusing grammatical feature. Our results thus demonstrate the potential contributions which LLMs can make in interactive systems for glossing, both in making suggestions to human annotators and following directions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09778v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Micha Elsner, David Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INJONGO: A Multicultural Intent Detection and Slot-filling Dataset for 16 African Languages</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09814</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09814v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Slot-filling and intent detection are well-established tasks in Conversational AI. However, current large-scale benchmarks for these tasks often exclude evaluations of low-resource languages and rely on translations from English benchmarks, thereby predominantly reflecting Western-centric concepts. In this paper, we introduce Injongo -- a multicultural, open-source benchmark dataset for 16 African languages with utterances generated by native speakers across diverse domains, including banking, travel, home, and dining. Through extensive experiments, we benchmark the fine-tuning multilingual transformer models and the prompting large language models (LLMs), and show the advantage of leveraging African-cultural utterances over Western-centric utterances for improving cross-lingual transfer from the English language. Experimental results reveal that current LLMs struggle with the slot-filling task, with GPT-4o achieving an average performance of 26 F1-score. In contrast, intent detection performance is notably better, with an average accuracy of 70.6%, though it still falls behind the fine-tuning baselines. Compared to the English language, GPT-4o and fine-tuning baselines perform similarly on intent detection, achieving an accuracy of approximately 81%. Our findings suggest that the performance of LLMs is still behind for many low-resource African languages, and more work is needed to further improve their downstream performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09814v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hao Yu, Jesujoba O. Alabi, Andiswa Bukula, Jian Yun Zhuang, En-Shiun Annie Lee, Tadesse Kebede Guge, Israel Abebe Azime, Happy Buzaaba, Blessing Kudzaishe Sibanda, Godson K. Kalipe, Jonathan Mukiibi, Salomon Kabongo Kabenamualu, Mmasibidi Setaka, Lolwethu Ndolela, Nkiruka Odu, Rooweither Mabuya, Shamsuddeen Hassan Muhammad, Salomey Osei, Sokhar Samb, Juliet W. Murage, Dietrich Klakow, David Ifeoluwa Adelani</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Coherence Alignment for Large Language Model Representation Learning Through Tensor Field Convergence</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09815</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09815v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Representation learning plays a central role in structuring internal embeddings to capture the statistical properties of language, influencing the coherence and contextual consistency of generated text. Statistical Coherence Alignment is introduced as a method to enforce structured token representations through tensor field convergence, guiding embeddings to reflect statistical dependencies inherent in linguistic data. A mathematical framework is established to quantify coherence alignment, integrating a loss function that optimizes representational consistency across training iterations. Empirical evaluations demonstrate that applying coherence constraints improves perplexity, enhances classification accuracy, and refines rare word embeddings, contributing to a more stable representation space. Comparative analyses with baseline models reveal that the proposed method fosters a more interpretable internal structure, ensuring that embeddings retain contextual dependencies while mitigating representation collapse. The impact on coherence score distributions suggests that the alignment mechanism strengthens semantic integrity across diverse linguistic constructs, leading to a more balanced organization of learned embeddings. Computational assessments indicate that while the method introduces additional memory and training costs, the structured optimization process justifies the trade-offs in applications requiring heightened contextual fidelity. Experimental results validate the effectiveness of coherence alignment in optimizing token representations, providing insights into how statistical dependencies can be leveraged to improve language model training.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09815v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jonathan Gale, Godfrey Aldington, Harriet Thistlewood, Thomas Tattershall, Basil Wentworth, Vincent Enoasmo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Multitask Learning in Small Language Models Through Upside-Down Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09854</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09854v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this work, we demonstrate that small language models (SLMs), specifically a 100M parameter GPT-2 model, can achieve competitive performance in multitask prompt generation tasks while requiring only a fraction of the computational resources needed by large language models (LLMs). Through a novel combination of upside-down reinforcement learning and synthetic data distillation from a powerful LLM, Llama-3, we train an SLM that achieves relevance scores within 5% of state-of-the-art models, including Llama-3, Qwen2, and Mistral, despite being up to 80 times smaller, making it highly suitable for resource-constrained and real-time applications. This study highlights the potential of SLMs as efficient multitask learners in multimodal settings, providing a promising alternative to LLMs for scalable, low-latency deployments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09854v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yu-Chen Lin, Sanat Sharma, Hari Manikandan, Jayant Kumar, Tracy Holloway King, Jing Zheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Preliminary Exploration with GPT-4o Voice Mode</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09940</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09940v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: With the rise of multimodal large language models, GPT-4o stands out as a pioneering model, driving us to evaluate its capabilities. This report assesses GPT-4o across various tasks to analyze its audio processing and reasoning abilities. We find that GPT-4o exhibits strong knowledge in audio, speech, and music understanding, performing well in tasks like intent classification, spoken command classification, semantic and grammatical reasoning., multilingual speech recognition, and singing analysis. It also shows greater robustness against hallucinations than other large audio-language models (LALMs). However, it struggles with tasks such as audio duration prediction and instrument classification. Additionally, GPT-4o's safety mechanisms cause it to decline tasks like speaker identification, age classification, MOS prediction, and audio deepfake detection. Notably, the model exhibits a significantly different refusal rate when responding to speaker verification tasks on different datasets. This is likely due to variations in the accompanying instructions or the quality of the input audio, suggesting the sensitivity of its built-in safeguards. Finally, we acknowledge that model performance varies with evaluation protocols. This report only serves as a preliminary exploration of the current state of LALMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09940v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yu-Xiang Lin, Chih-Kai Yang, Wei-Chih Chen, Chen-An Li, Chien-yu Huang, Xuanjun Chen, Hung-yi Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KGGen: Extracting Knowledge Graphs from Plain Text with Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09956</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09956v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent interest in building foundation models for KGs has highlighted a fundamental challenge: knowledge-graph data is relatively scarce. The best-known KGs are primarily human-labeled, created by pattern-matching, or extracted using early NLP techniques. While human-generated KGs are in short supply, automatically extracted KGs are of questionable quality. We present a solution to this data scarcity problem in the form of a text-to-KG generator (KGGen), a package that uses language models to create high-quality graphs from plaintext. Unlike other KG extractors, KGGen clusters related entities to reduce sparsity in extracted KGs. KGGen is available as a Python library (\texttt{pip install kg-gen}), making it accessible to everyone. Along with KGGen, we release the first benchmark, Measure of of Information in Nodes and Edges (MINE), that tests an extractor's ability to produce a useful KG from plain text. We benchmark our new tool against existing extractors and demonstrate far superior performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09956v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Belinda Mo, Kyssen Yu, Joshua Kazdan, Proud Mpala, Lisa Yu, Chris Cundy, Charilaos Kanatsoulis, Sanmi Koyejo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LaRA: Benchmarking Retrieval-Augmented Generation and Long-Context LLMs - No Silver Bullet for LC or RAG Routing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09977</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09977v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Effectively incorporating external knowledge into Large Language Models (LLMs) is crucial for enhancing their capabilities and addressing real-world needs. Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) offers an effective method for achieving this by retrieving the most relevant fragments into LLMs. However, the advancements in context window size for LLMs offer an alternative approach, raising the question of whether RAG remains necessary for effectively handling external knowledge. Several existing studies provide inconclusive comparisons between RAG and long-context (LC) LLMs, largely due to limitations in the benchmark designs. In this paper, we present LaRA, a novel benchmark specifically designed to rigorously compare RAG and LC LLMs. LaRA encompasses 2,326 test cases across four practical QA task categories and three types of naturally occurring long texts. Through systematic evaluation of seven open-source and four proprietary LLMs, we find that the optimal choice between RAG and LC depends on a complex interplay of factors, including the model's parameter size, long-text capabilities, context length, task type, and the characteristics of the retrieved chunks. Our findings provide actionable guidelines for practitioners to effectively leverage both RAG and LC approaches in developing and deploying LLM applications. Our code and dataset is provided at: \href{https://github.com/likuanppd/LaRA}{\textbf{https://github.com/likuanppd/LaRA}}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09977v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kuan Li, Liwen Zhang, Yong Jiang, Pengjun Xie, Fei Huang, Shuai Wang, Minhao Cheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Language Diffusion Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09992</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09992v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Autoregressive models (ARMs) are widely regarded as the cornerstone of large language models (LLMs). We challenge this notion by introducing LLaDA, a diffusion model trained from scratch under the pre-training and supervised fine-tuning (SFT) paradigm. LLaDA models distributions through a forward data masking process and a reverse process, parameterized by a vanilla Transformer to predict masked tokens. By optimizing a likelihood bound, it provides a principled generative approach for probabilistic inference. Across extensive benchmarks, LLaDA demonstrates strong scalability, outperforming our self-constructed ARM baselines. Remarkably, LLaDA 8B is competitive with strong LLMs like LLaMA3 8B in in-context learning and, after SFT, exhibits impressive instruction-following abilities in case studies such as multi-turn dialogue. Moreover, LLaDA addresses the reversal curse, surpassing GPT-4o in a reversal poem completion task. Our findings establish diffusion models as a viable and promising alternative to ARMs, challenging the assumption that key LLM capabilities discussed above are inherently tied to ARMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09992v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shen Nie, Fengqi Zhu, Zebin You, Xiaolu Zhang, Jingyang Ou, Jun Hu, Jun Zhou, Yankai Lin, Ji-Rong Wen, Chongxuan Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EmbBERT-Q: Breaking Memory Barriers in Embedded NLP</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.10001</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.10001v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have revolutionized natural language processing, setting new standards across a wide range of applications. However, their relevant memory and computational demands make them impractical for deployment on technologically-constrained tiny devices such as wearable devices and Internet-of-Things units. To address this limitation, we introduce EmbBERT-Q, a novel tiny language model specifically designed for tiny devices with stringent memory constraints. EmbBERT-Q achieves state-of-the-art (SotA) accuracy in Natural Language Processing tasks in this scenario, with a total memory footprint (weights and activations) of just 781 kB, representing a 25x reduction in size with respect to SotA models. By combining architectural innovations with hardware-compatible 8-bit quantization, EmbBERT-Q consistently outperforms several baseline models scaled down to a 2 MB memory budget (i.e., the maximum memory typically available in tiny devices), including heavily compressed versions of BERT and MAMBA. Extensive experimental evaluations on both a selected benchmark dataset, TinyNLP, specifically curated to evaluate Tiny Language Models in NLP tasks and real-world scenarios, and the GLUE benchmark, demonstrate EmbBERT-Q ability to deliver competitive accuracy with respect to existing approaches, achieving an unmatched balance between memory and performance. To ensure the complete and immediate reproducibility of all our results, we release all code, scripts, and model checkpoints at https://github.com/RiccardoBravin/tiny-LLM.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.10001v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AR</category>
      <category>cs.DC</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Riccardo Bravin, Massimo Pavan, Hazem Hesham Yousef Shalby, Fabrizio Pittorino, Manuel Roveri</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SciClaimHunt: A Large Dataset for Evidence-based Scientific Claim Verification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.10003</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.10003v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Verifying scientific claims presents a significantly greater challenge than verifying political or news-related claims. Unlike the relatively broad audience for political claims, the users of scientific claim verification systems can vary widely, ranging from researchers testing specific hypotheses to everyday users seeking information on a medication. Additionally, the evidence for scientific claims is often highly complex, involving technical terminology and intricate domain-specific concepts that require specialized models for accurate verification. Despite considerable interest from the research community, there is a noticeable lack of large-scale scientific claim verification datasets to benchmark and train effective models. To bridge this gap, we introduce two large-scale datasets, SciClaimHunt and SciClaimHunt_Num, derived from scientific research papers. We propose several baseline models tailored for scientific claim verification to assess the effectiveness of these datasets. Additionally, we evaluate models trained on SciClaimHunt and SciClaimHunt_Num against existing scientific claim verification datasets to gauge their quality and reliability. Furthermore, we conduct human evaluations of the claims in proposed datasets and perform error analysis to assess the effectiveness of the proposed baseline models. Our findings indicate that SciClaimHunt and SciClaimHunt_Num serve as highly reliable resources for training models in scientific claim verification.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.10003v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sujit Kumar, Anshul Sharma, Siddharth Hemant Khincha, Gargi Shroff, Sanasam Ranbir Singh, Rahul Mishra</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic Lexical Manifold Construction in Large Language Models via Hierarchical Vector Field Interpolation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.10013</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.10013v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Hierarchical vector field interpolation introduces a structured probabilistic framework for lexical representation, ensuring that word embeddings transition smoothly across a continuous manifold rather than being constrained to discrete token mappings. The proposed methodology constructs a probabilistic function space where word representations adhere to topological consistency, mitigating representational discontinuities commonly observed in transformer-based embeddings. Empirical evaluations reveal that probabilistic constraints enhance lexical coherence by refining contextual relationships, leading to improvements in semantic stability across multiple linguistic distributions. The application of divergence minimization techniques ensures that interpolated embeddings maintain probabilistic consistency while preserving computational feasibility for large-scale implementations. Experimental findings demonstrate that interpolated lexical manifolds improve representation density alignment, reducing anisotropic distortions in contextual embedding distributions. Comparative analyses with standard transformer-based models highlight that structured interpolation yields more stable representations, particularly in tasks requiring fine-grained semantic differentiation. The statistical evaluation of embedding divergence confirms that probabilistic lexical manifolds reduce representational inconsistencies while maintaining coherence across varying scales of contextual abstraction. An assessment of computational efficiency reveals that while interpolation introduces minor processing overhead, the structured representation learning approach remains scalable for practical deployment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.10013v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Clive Pendleton, Ewan Harrington, Giles Fairbrother, Jasper Arkwright, Nigel Fenwick, Richard Katrix</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ORI: O Routing Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.10051</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.10051v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Single large language models (LLMs) often fall short when faced with the ever-growing range of tasks, making a single-model approach insufficient. We address this challenge by proposing ORI (O Routing Intelligence), a dynamic framework that leverages a set of LLMs. By intelligently routing incoming queries to the most suitable model, ORI not only improves task-specific accuracy, but also maintains efficiency. Comprehensive evaluations across diverse benchmarks demonstrate consistent accuracy gains while controlling computational overhead. By intelligently routing queries, ORI outperforms the strongest individual models by up to 2.7 points on MMLU and 1.8 points on MuSR, ties the top performance on ARC, and on BBH. These results underscore the benefits of a multi-model strategy and demonstrate how ORI's adaptive architecture can more effectively handle diverse tasks, offering a scalable, high-performance solution for a system of multiple large language models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.10051v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ahmad Shadid, Rahul Kumar, Mohit Mayank</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MTLM: an Innovative Language Model Training Paradigm for ASR</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.10058</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.10058v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Pre-training Transformer-based language models (LMs) on a large amount of text has proven crucial for improving automatic speech recognition (ASR) performance. Generally, traditional LMs are unidirectional and unable to access the context on the right. This paper proposes a method for training LMs that enable traditional unidirectional LMs to fully utilize left and right contexts. Compared with the unidirectional LMs, our LM facilitates ASR to transcribe hypotheses more consistently and in a more semantically unambiguous way, as it incorporates richer contextual representations. Finally, our experimental results on the LibriSpeech corpus demonstrate that our model outperforms traditional unidirectional LMs, whether n-best rescoring or shallow fusion is used as the decoding algorithm.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.10058v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qingliang Meng, Pengju Ren, Tian Li, Changsong Dai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Annotating Compositionality Scores for Irish Noun Compounds is Hard Work</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.10061</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.10061v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Noun compounds constitute a challenging construction for NLP applications, given their variability in idiomaticity and interpretation. In this paper, we present an analysis of compound nouns identified in Irish text of varied domains by expert annotators, focusing on compositionality as a key feature, but also domain specificity, as well as familiarity and confidence of the annotator giving the ratings. Our findings and the discussion that ensued contributes towards a greater understanding of how these constructions appear in Irish language, and how they might be treated separately from English noun compounds.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.10061v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Abigail Walsh, Teresa Clifford, Emma Daly, Jane Dunne, Brian Davis, Gear\'oid \'O Cleirc\'in</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hands-off Image Editing: Language-guided Editing without any Task-specific Labeling, Masking or even Training</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.10064</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.10064v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Instruction-guided image editing consists in taking an image and an instruction and deliverring that image altered according to that instruction. State-of-the-art approaches to this task suffer from the typical scaling up and domain adaptation hindrances related to supervision as they eventually resort to some kind of task-specific labelling, masking or training. We propose a novel approach that does without any such task-specific supervision and offers thus a better potential for improvement. Its assessment demonstrates that it is highly effective, achieving very competitive performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.10064v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Hands-off Image Editing: Language-guided Editing without any Task-specific Labeling, Masking or even Training (Santos et al., COLING 2025)</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Rodrigo Santos, Ant\'onio Branco, Jo\~ao Silva, Jo\~ao Rodrigues</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Small Models, Big Impact: Efficient Corpus and Graph-Based Adaptation of Small Multilingual Language Models for Low-Resource Languages</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.10140</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.10140v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Low-resource languages (LRLs) face significant challenges in natural language processing (NLP) due to limited data. While current state-of-the-art large language models (LLMs) still struggle with LRLs, smaller multilingual models (mLMs) such as mBERT and XLM-R offer greater promise due to a better fit of their capacity to low training data sizes. This study systematically investigates parameter-efficient adapter-based methods for adapting mLMs to LRLs, evaluating three architectures: Sequential Bottleneck, Invertible Bottleneck, and Low-Rank Adaptation. Using unstructured text from GlotCC and structured knowledge from ConceptNet, we show that small adaptation datasets (e.g., up to 1 GB of free-text or a few MB of knowledge graph data) yield gains in intrinsic (masked language modeling) and extrinsic tasks (topic classification, sentiment analysis, and named entity recognition). We find that Sequential Bottleneck adapters excel in language modeling, while Invertible Bottleneck adapters slightly outperform other methods on downstream tasks due to better embedding alignment and larger parameter counts. Adapter-based methods match or outperform full fine-tuning while using far fewer parameters, and smaller mLMs prove more effective for LRLs than massive LLMs like LLaMA-3, GPT-4, and DeepSeek-R1-based distilled models. While adaptation improves performance, pre-training data size remains the dominant factor, especially for languages with extensive pre-training coverage.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.10140v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Daniil Gurgurov, Ivan Vykopal, Josef van Genabith, Simon Ostermann</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prediction hubs are context-informed frequent tokens in LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.10201</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.10201v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Hubness, the tendency for few points to be among the nearest neighbours of a disproportionate number of other points, commonly arises when applying standard distance measures to high-dimensional data, often negatively impacting distance-based analysis. As autoregressive large language models (LLMs) operate on high-dimensional representations, we ask whether they are also affected by hubness. We first show, theoretically, that the only representation comparison operation performed by LLMs, namely that between context and unembedding vectors to determine continuation probabilities, is not characterized by the concentration of distances phenomenon that typically causes the appeareance of nuisance hubness. We then empirically show that this comparison still leads to a high degree of hubness, but the hubs in this case do not constitute a disturbance. They are rather the result of context-modulated frequent tokens often appearing in the pool of likely candidates for next token prediction. On the other hand, when other distance computations involving LLM representations are performed, we do not have the same theoretical guarantees, and, indeed, we see nuisance hubs appear. In summary, our work highlights, on the one hand, how hubness, while omnipresent in high-dimensional spaces, is not always a negative property that needs to be mitigated, and, on the other hand, it shows that various widely-used LLMs have developed a guessing strategy that consists in constantly assigning a high probability to frequent tokens.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.10201v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Beatrix M. G. Nielsen, Iuri Macocco, Marco Baroni</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Post-Training Quantization Benefit from an Additional QLoRA Integration?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.10202</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.10202v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have transformed natural language processing but pose significant challenges for real-world deployment. These models necessitate considerable computing resources, which can be costly and frequently unavailable. Model compression techniques such as quantization are often leveraged to alleviate resource demand, but they may have a negative impact on the generation quality. In this study, we explore the integration of 4-bit Post-training Quantization (PTQ) with QLoRA to address these issues. We demonstrate through extensive experiments that this integration outperforms standard PTQ, and in some cases even 16-bit full-parameter fine-tuning on LLMs, validated across proprietary and public datasets with different quantization algorithms. The results demonstrate the efficacy of PTQ-QLoRA integration, offering a viable solution for deploying powerful LLMs in resource-constrained environments without compromising on performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.10202v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiliang Zhu, Elena Khasanova, Cheng Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VisCon-100K: Leveraging Contextual Web Data for Fine-tuning Vision Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.10250</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.10250v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Vision-language models (VLMs) excel in various visual benchmarks but are often constrained by the lack of high-quality visual fine-tuning data. To address this challenge, we introduce VisCon-100K, a novel dataset derived from interleaved image-text web documents. Our approach transforms 45K web documents from the OBELICS dataset into 100K image conversation samples. We utilize GPT-4V to generate image-contextual captions and OpenChat 3.5 model to convert these captions into diverse free-form and multiple-choice question-answer pairs. Integrating this dataset for fine-tuning considerably enhances VLM performance across multiple benchmarks. Unlike methods that focus solely on fine-grained visual content, our approach leverages accompanying web context, yielding superior results. We also discover that a `leaky modality mix,' where conversation samples contain questions answerable from both the image and its contextual caption, outperforms non-leaky combinations of captions and Q\&amp;A pairs. VisCon-100k dataset shows strong performance with two popular VLM approaches: text-only large language model (LLM) aligned with a vision encoder using image captions data (ShareGPT4V-7b) and multimodally pretrained LLM (IDEFICS2-8b) using interleaved image-text data. In addition to releasing the VisCon-100K dataset, we provide a contextual captioner trained on this dataset, facilitating scalable fine-tuning data generation for future research and open-source applications. Using the same pipeline, but substituting our trained contextual captioner for GPT-4V, we also release the larger VisCon-1M dataset.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.10250v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gokul Karthik Kumar, Iheb Chaabane, Kebin Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Language Models and Synthetic Data for Monitoring Dataset Mentions in Research Papers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.10263</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.10263v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Tracking how data is mentioned and used in research papers provides critical insights for improving data discoverability, quality, and production. However, manually identifying and classifying dataset mentions across vast academic literature is resource-intensive and not scalable. This paper presents a machine learning framework that automates dataset mention detection across research domains by leveraging large language models (LLMs), synthetic data, and a two-stage fine-tuning process. We employ zero-shot extraction from research papers, an LLM-as-a-Judge for quality assessment, and a reasoning agent for refinement to generate a weakly supervised synthetic dataset. The Phi-3.5-mini instruct model is pre-fine-tuned on this dataset, followed by fine-tuning on a manually annotated subset. At inference, a ModernBERT-based classifier efficiently filters dataset mentions, reducing computational overhead while maintaining high recall. Evaluated on a held-out manually annotated sample, our fine-tuned model outperforms NuExtract-v1.5 and GLiNER-large-v2.1 in dataset extraction accuracy. Our results highlight how LLM-generated synthetic data can effectively address training data scarcity, improving generalization in low-resource settings. This framework offers a pathway toward scalable monitoring of dataset usage, enhancing transparency, and supporting researchers, funders, and policymakers in identifying data gaps and strengthening data accessibility for informed decision-making.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.10263v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.DB</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aivin V. Solatorio, Rafael Macalaba, James Liounis</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Large Language Models the future crowd workers of Linguistics?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.10266</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.10266v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Data elicitation from human participants is one of the core data collection strategies used in empirical linguistic research. The amount of participants in such studies may vary considerably, ranging from a handful to crowdsourcing dimensions. Even if they provide resourceful extensive data, both of these settings come alongside many disadvantages, such as low control of participants' attention during task completion, precarious working conditions in crowdsourcing environments, and time-consuming experimental designs. For these reasons, this research aims to answer the question of whether Large Language Models (LLMs) may overcome those obstacles if included in empirical linguistic pipelines. Two reproduction case studies are conducted to gain clarity into this matter: Cruz (2023) and Lombard et al. (2021). The two forced elicitation tasks, originally designed for human participants, are reproduced in the proposed framework with the help of OpenAI's GPT-4o-mini model. Its performance with our zero-shot prompting baseline shows the effectiveness and high versatility of LLMs, that tend to outperform human informants in linguistic tasks. The findings of the second replication further highlight the need to explore additional prompting techniques, such as Chain-of-Thought (CoT) prompting, which, in a second follow-up experiment, demonstrates higher alignment to human performance on both critical and filler items. Given the limited scale of this study, it is worthwhile to further explore the performance of LLMs in empirical Linguistics and in other future applications in the humanities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.10266v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Iris Ferrazzo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the Meta- and Object-Level Reasoning of Large Language Models for Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.10338</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.10338v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) excel in natural language tasks but still face challenges in Question Answering (QA) tasks requiring complex, multi-step reasoning. We outline the types of reasoning required in some of these tasks, and reframe them in terms of meta-level reasoning (akin to high-level strategic reasoning or planning) and object-level reasoning (embodied in lower-level tasks such as mathematical reasoning). Franklin, a novel dataset with requirements of meta- and object-level reasoning, is introduced and used along with three other datasets to evaluate four LLMs at question answering tasks requiring multiple steps of reasoning. Results from human annotation studies suggest LLMs demonstrate meta-level reasoning with high frequency, but struggle with object-level reasoning tasks in some of the datasets used. Additionally, evidence suggests that LLMs find the object-level reasoning required for the questions in the Franklin dataset challenging, yet they do exhibit strong performance with respect to the meta-level reasoning requirements.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.10338v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nick Ferguson, Liane Guillou, Alan Bundy, Kwabena Nuamah</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STAR: Spectral Truncation and Rescale for Model Merging</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.10339</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.10339v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Model merging is an efficient way of obtaining a multi-task model from several pretrained models without further fine-tuning, and it has gained attention in various domains, including natural language processing (NLP). Despite the efficiency, a key challenge in model merging is the seemingly inevitable decrease in task performance as the number of models increases. In this paper, we propose $\mathbf{S}$pectral $\mathbf{T}$runcation $\mathbf{A}$nd $\mathbf{R}$escale (STAR) that aims at mitigating ``merging conflicts'' by truncating small components in the respective spectral spaces, which is followed by an automatic parameter rescaling scheme to retain the nuclear norm of the original matrix. STAR requires no additional inference on original training data and is robust to hyperparamater choice. We demonstrate the effectiveness of STAR through extensive model merging cases on diverse NLP tasks. Specifically, STAR works robustly across varying model sizes, and can outperform baselines by 4.2$\%$ when merging 12 models on Flan-T5. Our code is publicly available at https://github.com/IBM/STAR.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.10339v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yu-Ang Lee, Ching-Yun Ko, Tejaswini Pedapati, I-Hsin Chung, Mi-Yen Yeh, Pin-Yu Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organize the Web: Constructing Domains Enhances Pre-Training Data Curation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.10341</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.10341v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Modern language models are trained on large, unstructured datasets consisting of trillions of tokens and obtained by crawling the web. The unstructured nature makes it difficult to reason about their contents and develop systematic approaches to data curation. In this paper, we unpack monolithic web corpora by developing taxonomies of their contents and organizing them into domains. We introduce WebOrganizer, a framework for organizing web pages in terms of both their topic and format. Using these two complementary notions of domains, we automatically annotate pre-training data by distilling annotations from a large language model into efficient classifiers. This allows us to study how data from different domains should be mixed to improve models on downstream tasks, and we show that we can combine insights about effective topics and formats to further boost performance. We demonstrate that our domain mixing also improves existing methods that select data based on quality. Furthermore, we study and compare how quality-based methods will implicitly change the domain mixture. Overall, our work demonstrates that constructing and mixing domains provides a valuable complement to quality-based data curation methods, opening new avenues for effective and insightful pre-training data curation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.10341v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alexander Wettig, Kyle Lo, Sewon Min, Hannaneh Hajishirzi, Danqi Chen, Luca Soldaini</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agentic Verification for Ambiguous Query Disambiguation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.10352</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.10352v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this work, we tackle the challenge of disambiguating queries in retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) to diverse yet answerable interpretations. State-of-the-arts follow a Diversify-then-Verify (DtV) pipeline, where diverse interpretations are generated by an LLM, later used as search queries to retrieve supporting passages. Such a process may introduce noise in either interpretations or retrieval, particularly in enterprise settings, where LLMs -- trained on static data -- may struggle with domain-specific disambiguations. Thus, a post-hoc verification phase is introduced to prune noises. Our distinction is to unify diversification with verification by incorporating feedback from retriever and generator early on. This joint approach improves both efficiency and robustness by reducing reliance on multiple retrieval and inference steps, which are susceptible to cascading errors. We validate the efficiency and effectiveness of our method, Verified-Diversification with Consolidation (VERDICT), on the widely adopted ASQA benchmark to achieve diverse yet verifiable interpretations. Empirical results show that VERDICT improves grounding-aware F1 score by an average of 23% over the strongest baseline across different backbone LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.10352v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Youngwon Lee, Seung-won Hwang, Ruofan Wu, Feng Yan, Danmei Xu, Moutasem Akkad, Zhewei Yao, Yuxiong He</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Multilingual LLM Pretraining with Model-Based Data Selection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.10361</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.10361v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Dataset curation has become a basis for strong large language model (LLM) performance. While various rule-based filtering heuristics exist for English and multilingual datasets, model-based filtering techniques have primarily focused on English. To address the disparity stemming from limited research on non-English languages, we propose a model-based filtering framework for multilingual datasets that aims to identify a diverse set of structured and knowledge-rich samples. Our approach emphasizes transparency, simplicity, and efficiency, leveraging Transformer- and FastText-based classifiers to ensure the broad accessibility of our technique and data. We conduct comprehensive ablation studies on the FineWeb-2 web crawl dataset across diverse language families, scripts, and resource availability to demonstrate the effectiveness of our method. Training a 1B-parameter Llama model for 70B and 119B tokens, our approach can match the baseline MMLU score with as little as 15% of the training tokens, while also improving across other benchmarks. These findings provide strong evidence for the generalizability of our approach to other languages. As a result, we extend our framework to 20 languages for which we release the refined pretraining datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.10361v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bettina Messmer, Vinko Sabol\v{c}ec, Martin Jaggi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OWLS: Scaling Laws for Multilingual Speech Recognition and Translation Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.10373</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.10373v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Neural scaling laws offer valuable insights for designing robust sequence processing architectures. While these laws have been extensively characterized in other modalities, their behavior in speech remains comparatively underexplored. In this work, we introduce OWLS, an open-access, reproducible suite of multilingual speech recognition and translation models spanning 0.25B to 18B parameters, with the 18B version being the largest speech model, to the best of our knowledge. OWLS leverages up to 360K hours of public speech data across 150 languages, enabling a systematic investigation into how data, model, and compute scaling each influence performance in multilingual speech tasks. We use OWLS to derive neural scaling laws, showing how final performance can be reliably predicted when scaling. One of our key findings is that scaling enhances performance on low-resource languages/dialects, helping to mitigate bias and improve the accessibility of speech technologies. Finally, we show how OWLS can be used to power new research directions by discovering emergent abilities in large-scale speech models. Model checkpoints will be released on https://huggingface.co/collections/espnet/owls-scaling-laws-for-speech-recognition-and-translation-67ab7f991c194065f057ce8d for future studies.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.10373v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>William Chen, Jinchuan Tian, Yifan Peng, Brian Yan, Chao-Han Huck Yang, Shinji Watanabe</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aspect-Oriented Summarization for Psychiatric Short-Term Readmission Prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.10388</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.10388v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent progress in large language models (LLMs) has enabled the automated processing of lengthy documents even without supervised training on a task-specific dataset. Yet, their zero-shot performance in complex tasks as opposed to straightforward information extraction tasks remains suboptimal. One feasible approach for tasks with lengthy, complex input is to first summarize the document and then apply supervised fine-tuning to the summary. However, the summarization process inevitably results in some loss of information. In this study we present a method for processing the summaries of long documents aimed to capture different important aspects of the original document. We hypothesize that LLM summaries generated with different aspect-oriented prompts contain different \textit{information signals}, and we propose methods to measure these differences. We introduce approaches to effectively integrate signals from these different summaries for supervised training of transformer models. We validate our hypotheses on a high-impact task -- 30-day readmission prediction from a psychiatric discharge -- using real-world data from four hospitals, and show that our proposed method increases the prediction performance for the complex task of predicting patient outcome.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.10388v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>WonJin Yoon, Boyu Ren, Spencer Thomas, Chanwhi Kim, Guergana Savova, Mei-Hua Hall, Timothy Miller</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MM-RLHF: The Next Step Forward in Multimodal LLM Alignment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.10391</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.10391v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Despite notable advancements in Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs), most state-of-the-art models have not undergone thorough alignment with human preferences. This gap exists because current alignment research has primarily achieved progress in specific areas (e.g., hallucination reduction), while the broader question of whether aligning models with human preferences can systematically enhance MLLM capability remains largely unexplored. To this end, we introduce MM-RLHF, a dataset containing $\mathbf{120k}$ fine-grained, human-annotated preference comparison pairs. This dataset represents a substantial advancement over existing resources, offering superior size, diversity, annotation granularity, and quality. Leveraging this dataset, we propose several key innovations to improve both the quality of reward models and the efficiency of alignment algorithms. Notably, we introduce a Critique-Based Reward Model, which generates critiques of model outputs before assigning scores, offering enhanced interpretability and more informative feedback compared to traditional scalar reward mechanisms. Additionally, we propose Dynamic Reward Scaling, a method that adjusts the loss weight of each sample according to the reward signal, thereby optimizing the use of high-quality comparison pairs. Our approach is rigorously evaluated across $\mathbf{10}$ distinct dimensions and $\mathbf{27}$ benchmarks, with results demonstrating significant and consistent improvements in model performance. Specifically, fine-tuning LLaVA-ov-7B with MM-RLHF and our alignment algorithm leads to a $\mathbf{19.5}$% increase in conversational abilities and a $\mathbf{60}$% improvement in safety.
  We have open-sourced the preference dataset, reward model, training and evaluation code, as well as reward modeling and safety benchmarks. For more details, please visit our project page: https://mm-rlhf.github.io.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.10391v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yi-Fan Zhang, Tao Yu, Haochen Tian, Chaoyou Fu, Peiyan Li, Jianshu Zeng, Wulin Xie, Yang Shi, Huanyu Zhang, Junkang Wu, Xue Wang, Yibo Hu, Bin Wen, Fan Yang, Zhang Zhang, Tingting Gao, Di Zhang, Liang Wang, Rong Jin, Tieniu Tan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meta-Cultural Competence: Climbing the Right Hill of Cultural Awareness</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09637</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09637v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Numerous recent studies have shown that Large Language Models (LLMs) are biased towards a Western and Anglo-centric worldview, which compromises their usefulness in non-Western cultural settings. However, "culture" is a complex, multifaceted topic, and its awareness, representation, and modeling in LLMs and LLM-based applications can be defined and measured in numerous ways. In this position paper, we ask what does it mean for an LLM to possess "cultural awareness", and through a thought experiment, which is an extension of the Octopus test proposed by Bender and Koller (2020), we argue that it is not cultural awareness or knowledge, rather meta-cultural competence, which is required of an LLM and LLM-based AI system that will make it useful across various, including completely unseen, cultures. We lay out the principles of meta-cultural competence AI systems, and discuss ways to measure and model those.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09637v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sougata Saha, Saurabh Kumar Pandey, Monojit Choudhury</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating GPT's Capability in Identifying Stages of Cognitive Impairment from Electronic Health Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09715</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09715v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Identifying cognitive impairment within electronic health records (EHRs) is crucial not only for timely diagnoses but also for facilitating research. Information about cognitive impairment often exists within unstructured clinician notes in EHRs, but manual chart reviews are both time-consuming and error-prone. To address this issue, our study evaluates an automated approach using zero-shot GPT-4o to determine stage of cognitive impairment in two different tasks. First, we evaluated the ability of GPT-4o to determine the global Clinical Dementia Rating (CDR) on specialist notes from 769 patients who visited the memory clinic at Massachusetts General Hospital (MGH), and achieved a weighted kappa score of 0.83. Second, we assessed GPT-4o's ability to differentiate between normal cognition, mild cognitive impairment (MCI), and dementia on all notes in a 3-year window from 860 Medicare patients. GPT-4o attained a weighted kappa score of 0.91 in comparison to specialist chart reviews and 0.96 on cases that the clinical adjudicators rated with high confidence. Our findings demonstrate GPT-4o's potential as a scalable chart review tool for creating research datasets and assisting diagnosis in clinical settings in the future.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09715v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yu Leng, Yingnan He, Colin Magdamo, Ana-Maria Vranceanu, Christine S. Ritchie, Shibani S. Mukerji, Lidia M. V. R. Moura, John R. Dickson, Deborah Blacker, Sudeshna Das</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making Them a Malicious Database: Exploiting Query Code to Jailbreak Aligned Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09723</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09723v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recent advances in large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated remarkable potential in the field of natural language processing. Unfortunately, LLMs face significant security and ethical risks. Although techniques such as safety alignment are developed for defense, prior researches reveal the possibility of bypassing such defenses through well-designed jailbreak attacks. In this paper, we propose QueryAttack, a novel framework to systematically examine the generalizability of safety alignment. By treating LLMs as knowledge databases, we translate malicious queries in natural language into code-style structured query to bypass the safety alignment mechanisms of LLMs. We conduct extensive experiments on mainstream LLMs, ant the results show that QueryAttack achieves high attack success rates (ASRs) across LLMs with different developers and capabilities. We also evaluate QueryAttack's performance against common defenses, confirming that it is difficult to mitigate with general defensive techniques. To defend against QueryAttack, we tailor a defense method which can reduce ASR by up to 64\% on GPT-4-1106. The code of QueryAttack can be found on https://anonymous.4open.science/r/QueryAttack-334B.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09723v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qingsong Zou, Jingyu Xiao, Qing Li, Zhi Yan, Yuhang Wang, Li Xu, Wenxuan Wang, Kuofeng Gao, Ruoyu Li, Yong Jiang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-Markovian Discrete Diffusion with Causal Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09767</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09767v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Discrete diffusion models have emerged as a flexible and controllable paradigm for structured sequence modeling, yet they still lag behind causal language models in expressiveness. To bridge the gap between two paradigms, we introduce CaDDi, a causal discrete diffusion model that unifies sequential and temporal modeling within a non-Markovian diffusion framework. Unlike conventional diffusion models that operate step by step with no access to prior states, CaDDi integrates the temporal trajectory, enabling more expressive and controllable generation. Our approach also treats causal language models as a special case, allowing seamless adoption of pretrained large language models (LLMs) for discrete diffusion without the need for architectural modifications. Empirically, we demonstrate that CaDDi outperforms state-of-the-art discrete diffusion models on both natural language and biological sequence tasks, narrowing the gap between diffusion-based methods and large-scale autoregressive transformers.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09767v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yangtian Zhang, Sizhuang He, Daniel Levine, Lawrence Zhao, David Zhang, Syed A Rizvi, Emanuele Zappala, Rex Ying, David van Dijk</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Acoustic Side-Channel Attacks on Keyboards Using Transformers and Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09782</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09782v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The increasing prevalence of microphones in everyday devices and the growing reliance on online services have amplified the risk of acoustic side-channel attacks (ASCAs) targeting keyboards. This study explores deep learning techniques, specifically vision transformers (VTs) and large language models (LLMs), to enhance the effectiveness and applicability of such attacks. We present substantial improvements over prior research, with the CoAtNet model achieving state-of-the-art performance. Our CoAtNet shows a 5.0% improvement for keystrokes recorded via smartphone (Phone) and 5.9% for those recorded via Zoom compared to previous benchmarks. We also evaluate transformer architectures and language models, with the best VT model matching CoAtNet's performance. A key advancement is the introduction of a noise mitigation method for real-world scenarios. By using LLMs for contextual understanding, we detect and correct erroneous keystrokes in noisy environments, enhancing ASCA performance. Additionally, fine-tuned lightweight language models with Low-Rank Adaptation (LoRA) deliver comparable performance to heavyweight models with 67X more parameters. This integration of VTs and LLMs improves the practical applicability of ASCA mitigation, marking the first use of these technologies to address ASCAs and error correction in real-world scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09782v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jin Hyun Park, Seyyed Ali Ayati, Yichen Cai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automated Hypothesis Validation with Agentic Sequential Falsifications</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09858</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09858v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Hypotheses are central to information acquisition, decision-making, and discovery. However, many real-world hypotheses are abstract, high-level statements that are difficult to validate directly. This challenge is further intensified by the rise of hypothesis generation from Large Language Models (LLMs), which are prone to hallucination and produce hypotheses in volumes that make manual validation impractical. Here we propose Popper, an agentic framework for rigorous automated validation of free-form hypotheses. Guided by Karl Popper's principle of falsification, Popper validates a hypothesis using LLM agents that design and execute falsification experiments targeting its measurable implications. A novel sequential testing framework ensures strict Type-I error control while actively gathering evidence from diverse observations, whether drawn from existing data or newly conducted procedures. We demonstrate Popper on six domains including biology, economics, and sociology. Popper delivers robust error control, high power, and scalability. Furthermore, compared to human scientists, Popper achieved comparable performance in validating complex biological hypotheses while reducing time by 10 folds, providing a scalable, rigorous solution for hypothesis validation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09858v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>q-bio.QM</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kexin Huang, Ying Jin, Ryan Li, Michael Y. Li, Emmanuel Cand\`es, Jure Leskovec</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solvable Dynamics of Self-Supervised Word Embeddings and the Emergence of Analogical Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09863</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09863v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The remarkable success of large language models relies on their ability to implicitly learn structured latent representations from the pretraining corpus. As a simpler surrogate for representation learning in language modeling, we study a class of solvable contrastive self-supervised algorithms which we term quadratic word embedding models. These models resemble the word2vec algorithm and perform similarly on downstream tasks. Our main contributions are analytical solutions for both the training dynamics (under certain hyperparameter choices) and the final word embeddings, given in terms of only the corpus statistics. Our solutions reveal that these models learn orthogonal linear subspaces one at a time, each one incrementing the effective rank of the embeddings until model capacity is saturated. Training on WikiText, we find that the top subspaces represent interpretable concepts. Finally, we use our dynamical theory to predict how and when models acquire the ability to complete analogies.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09863v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dhruva Karkada, James B. Simon, Yasaman Bahri, Michael R. DeWeese</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Taxonomy of Linguistic Expressions That Contribute To Anthropomorphism of Language Technologies</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09870</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09870v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recent attention to anthropomorphism -- the attribution of human-like qualities to non-human objects or entities -- of language technologies like LLMs has sparked renewed discussions about potential negative impacts of anthropomorphism. To productively discuss the impacts of this anthropomorphism and in what contexts it is appropriate, we need a shared vocabulary for the vast variety of ways that language can be anthropomorphic. In this work, we draw on existing literature and analyze empirical cases of user interactions with language technologies to develop a taxonomy of textual expressions that can contribute to anthropomorphism. We highlight challenges and tensions involved in understanding linguistic anthropomorphism, such as how all language is fundamentally human and how efforts to characterize and shift perceptions of humanness in machines can also dehumanize certain humans. We discuss ways that our taxonomy supports more precise and effective discussions of and decisions about anthropomorphism of language technologies.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09870v1</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3706598.3714038</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>ACM CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI 2025), Yokohama, Japan</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Alicia DeVrio, Myra Cheng, Lisa Egede, Alexandra Olteanu, Su Lin Blodgett</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MIR-Bench: Benchmarking LLM's Long-Context Intelligence via Many-Shot In-Context Inductive Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09933</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09933v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Inductive Reasoning (IR), the ability to summarize rules from examples and apply on new ones, has long been viewed as a primal ability for general intelligence and widely studied by cognitive science and AI researchers. Many benchmarks have been proposed to measure such ability for Large Language Models (LLMs); however, they focus on few-shot (usually $&lt;$10) setting and lack evaluation for aggregating many pieces of information from long contexts. On the other hand, the ever-growing context length of LLMs have brought forth the novel paradigm of many-shot In-Context Learning (ICL), which addresses new tasks with hundreds to thousands of examples without expensive and inefficient fine-tuning. However, many-shot evaluations are mostly focused on classification (a very limited aspect of IR), and popular long-context LLM tasks such as Needle-In-A-Haystack (NIAH) seldom require complicated intelligence for integrating many pieces of information. To fix the issues from both worlds, we propose MIR-Bench, the first many-shot in-context inductive reasoning benchmark that asks LLM to induce output via input-output examples from underlying functions with diverse data format. Based on MIR-Bench, we study many novel problems for inductive reasoning and many-shot ICL, including robustness against erroneous shots and the effect of Chain-of-Thought (CoT), and acquired insightful findings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09933v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kai Yan, Zhan Ling, Kang Liu, Yifan Yang, Ting-Han Fan, Lingfeng Shen, Zhengyin Du, Jiecao Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Supervised Learning for Neural Topic Models with Variance-Invariance-Covariance Regularization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09944</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09944v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In our study, we propose a self-supervised neural topic model (NTM) that combines the power of NTMs and regularized self-supervised learning methods to improve performance. NTMs use neural networks to learn latent topics hidden behind the words in documents, enabling greater flexibility and the ability to estimate more coherent topics compared to traditional topic models. On the other hand, some self-supervised learning methods use a joint embedding architecture with two identical networks that produce similar representations for two augmented versions of the same input. Regularizations are applied to these representations to prevent collapse, which would otherwise result in the networks outputting constant or redundant representations for all inputs. Our model enhances topic quality by explicitly regularizing latent topic representations of anchor and positive samples. We also introduced an adversarial data augmentation method to replace the heuristic sampling method. We further developed several variation models including those on the basis of an NTM that incorporates contrastive learning with both positive and negative samples. Experimental results on three datasets showed that our models outperformed baselines and state-of-the-art models both quantitatively and qualitatively.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09944v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weiran Xu, Kengo Hirami, Koji Eguchi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Valuation using Neural Networks for Efficient Instruction Fine-Tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09969</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09969v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Influence functions provide crucial insights into model training, but existing methods suffer from large computational costs and limited generalization. Particularly, recent works have proposed various metrics and algorithms to calculate the influence of data using language models, which do not scale well with large models and datasets. This is because of the expensive forward and backward passes required for computation, substantial memory requirements to store large models, and poor generalization of influence estimates to new data. In this paper, we explore the use of small neural networks -- which we refer to as the InfluenceNetwork -- to estimate influence values, achieving up to 99% cost reduction. Our evaluation demonstrates that influence values can be estimated with models just 0.0027% the size of full language models (we use 7B and 8B versions). We apply our algorithm of estimating influence values (called NN-CIFT: Neural Networks for effiCient Instruction Fine-Tuning) to the downstream task of subset selection for general instruction fine-tuning. In our study, we include four state-of-the-art influence functions and show no compromise in performance, despite large speedups, between NN-CIFT and the original influence functions. We provide an in-depth hyperparameter analyses of NN-CIFT. The code for our method can be found here: https://github.com/agarwalishika/NN-CIFT.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09969v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ishika Agarwal, Dilek Hakkani-Tur</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>X-Boundary: Establishing Exact Safety Boundary to Shield LLMs from Multi-Turn Jailbreaks without Compromising Usability</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09990</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09990v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Despite the rapid development of safety alignment techniques for LLMs, defending against multi-turn jailbreaks is still a challenging task. In this paper, we conduct a comprehensive comparison, revealing that some existing defense methods can improve the robustness of LLMs against multi-turn jailbreaks but compromise usability, i.e., reducing general capabilities or causing the over-refusal problem. From the perspective of mechanism interpretability of LLMs, we discover that these methods fail to establish a boundary that exactly distinguishes safe and harmful feature representations. Therefore, boundary-safe representations close to harmful representations are inevitably disrupted, leading to a decline in usability. To address this issue, we propose X-Boundary to push harmful representations away from boundary-safe representations and obtain an exact distinction boundary. In this way, harmful representations can be precisely erased without disrupting safe ones. Experimental results show that X-Boundary achieves state-of-the-art defense performance against multi-turn jailbreaks, while reducing the over-refusal rate by about 20% and maintaining nearly complete general capability. Furthermore, we theoretically prove and empirically verify that X-Boundary can accelerate the convergence process during training. Please see our code at: https://github.com/AI45Lab/X-Boundary.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09990v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoya Lu, Dongrui Liu, Yi Yu, Luxin Xu, Jing Shao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting Generalization Power of a DNN in Terms of Symbolic Interactions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.10162</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.10162v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This paper aims to analyze the generalization power of deep neural networks (DNNs) from the perspective of interactions. Unlike previous analysis of a DNN's generalization power in a highdimensional feature space, we find that the generalization power of a DNN can be explained as the generalization power of the interactions. We found that the generalizable interactions follow a decay-shaped distribution, while non-generalizable interactions follow a spindle-shaped distribution. Furthermore, our theory can effectively disentangle these two types of interactions from a DNN. We have verified that our theory can well match real interactions in a DNN in experiments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.10162v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lei Cheng, Junpeng Zhang, Qihan Ren, Quanshi Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Step-Video-T2V Technical Report: The Practice, Challenges, and Future of Video Foundation Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.10248</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.10248v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We present Step-Video-T2V, a state-of-the-art text-to-video pre-trained model with 30B parameters and the ability to generate videos up to 204 frames in length. A deep compression Variational Autoencoder, Video-VAE, is designed for video generation tasks, achieving 16x16 spatial and 8x temporal compression ratios, while maintaining exceptional video reconstruction quality. User prompts are encoded using two bilingual text encoders to handle both English and Chinese. A DiT with 3D full attention is trained using Flow Matching and is employed to denoise input noise into latent frames. A video-based DPO approach, Video-DPO, is applied to reduce artifacts and improve the visual quality of the generated videos. We also detail our training strategies and share key observations and insights. Step-Video-T2V's performance is evaluated on a novel video generation benchmark, Step-Video-T2V-Eval, demonstrating its state-of-the-art text-to-video quality when compared with both open-source and commercial engines. Additionally, we discuss the limitations of current diffusion-based model paradigm and outline future directions for video foundation models. We make both Step-Video-T2V and Step-Video-T2V-Eval available at https://github.com/stepfun-ai/Step-Video-T2V. The online version can be accessed from https://yuewen.cn/videos as well. Our goal is to accelerate the innovation of video foundation models and empower video content creators.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.10248v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Guoqing Ma, Haoyang Huang, Kun Yan, Liangyu Chen, Nan Duan, Shengming Yin, Changyi Wan, Ranchen Ming, Xiaoniu Song, Xing Chen, Yu Zhou, Deshan Sun, Deyu Zhou, Jian Zhou, Kaijun Tan, Kang An, Mei Chen, Wei Ji, Qiling Wu, Wen Sun, Xin Han, Yanan Wei, Zheng Ge, Aojie Li, Bin Wang, Bizhu Huang, Bo Wang, Brian Li, Changxing Miao, Chen Xu, Chenfei Wu, Chenguang Yu, Dapeng Shi, Dingyuan Hu, Enle Liu, Gang Yu, Ge Yang, Guanzhe Huang, Gulin Yan, Haiyang Feng, Hao Nie, Haonan Jia, Hanpeng Hu, Hanqi Chen, Haolong Yan, Heng Wang, Hongcheng Guo, Huilin Xiong, Huixin Xiong, Jiahao Gong, Jianchang Wu, Jiaoren Wu, Jie Wu, Jie Yang, Jiashuai Liu, Jiashuo Li, Jingyang Zhang, Junjing Guo, Junzhe Lin, Kaixiang Li, Lei Liu, Lei Xia, Liang Zhao, Liguo Tan, Liwen Huang, Liying Shi, Ming Li, Mingliang Li, Muhua Cheng, Na Wang, Qiaohui Chen, Qinglin He, Qiuyan Liang, Quan Sun, Ran Sun, Rui Wang, Shaoliang Pang, Shiliang Yang, Sitong Liu, Siqi Liu, Shuli Gao, Tiancheng Cao, Tianyu Wang, Weipeng Ming, Wenqing He, Xu Zhao, Xuelin Zhang, Xianfang Zeng, Xiaojia Liu, Xuan Yang, Yaqi Dai, Yanbo Yu, Yang Li, Yineng Deng, Yingming Wang, Yilei Wang, Yuanwei Lu, Yu Chen, Yu Luo, Yuchu Luo, Yuhe Yin, Yuheng Feng, Yuxiang Yang, Zecheng Tang, Zekai Zhang, Zidong Yang, Binxing Jiao, Jiansheng Chen, Jing Li, Shuchang Zhou, Xiangyu Zhang, Xinhao Zhang, Yibo Zhu, Heung-Yeung Shum, Daxin Jiang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DeltaProduct: Increasing the Expressivity of DeltaNet Through Products of Householders</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.10297</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.10297v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Linear Recurrent Neural Networks (linear RNNs) have emerged as competitive alternatives to Transformers for sequence modeling, offering efficient training and linear-time inference. However, existing architectures face a fundamental trade-off between expressivity and efficiency, dictated by the structure of their state-transition matrices. While diagonal matrices used in architectures like Mamba, GLA, or mLSTM yield fast runtime, they suffer from severely limited expressivity. To address this, recent architectures such as (Gated) DeltaNet and RWKVv7 adopted a diagonal plus rank-1 structure, allowing simultaneous token-channel mixing, which overcomes some expressivity limitations with only a slight decrease in training efficiency. Building on the interpretation of DeltaNet's recurrence as performing one step of online gradient descent per token on an associative recall loss, we introduce DeltaProduct, which instead takes multiple ($n_h$) steps per token. This naturally leads to diagonal plus rank-$n_h$ state-transition matrices, formed as products of $n_h$ generalized Householder transformations, providing a tunable mechanism to balance expressivity and efficiency and a stable recurrence. Through extensive experiments, we demonstrate that DeltaProduct achieves superior state-tracking and language modeling capabilities while exhibiting significantly improved length extrapolation compared to DeltaNet. Additionally, we also strengthen the theoretical foundation of DeltaNet's expressivity by proving that it can solve dihedral group word problems in just two layers.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.10297v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.FL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Julien Siems, Timur Carstensen, Arber Zela, Frank Hutter, Massimiliano Pontil, Riccardo Grazzi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unknown Word Detection for English as a Second Language (ESL) Learners Using Gaze and Pre-trained Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.10378</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.10378v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: English as a Second Language (ESL) learners often encounter unknown words that hinder their text comprehension. Automatically detecting these words as users read can enable computing systems to provide just-in-time definitions, synonyms, or contextual explanations, thereby helping users learn vocabulary in a natural and seamless manner. This paper presents EyeLingo, a transformer-based machine learning method that predicts the probability of unknown words based on text content and eye gaze trajectory in real time with high accuracy. A 20-participant user study revealed that our method can achieve an accuracy of 97.6%, and an F1-score of 71.1%. We implemented a real-time reading assistance prototype to show the effectiveness of EyeLingo. The user study shows improvement in willingness to use and usefulness compared to baseline methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.10378v1</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiexin Ding, Bowen Zhao, Yuntao Wang, Xinyun Liu, Rui Hao, Ishan Chatterjee, Yuanchun Shi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accuracy and Political Bias of News Source Credibility Ratings by Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2304.00228</link>
      <description>arXiv:2304.00228v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Search engines increasingly leverage large language models (LLMs) to generate direct answers, and AI chatbots now access the Internet for fresh data. As information curators for billions of users, LLMs must assess the accuracy and reliability of different sources. This paper audits nine widely used LLMs from three leading providers -- OpenAI, Google, and Meta -- to evaluate their ability to discern credible and high-quality information sources from low-credibility ones. We find that while LLMs can rate most tested news outlets, larger models more frequently refuse to provide ratings due to insufficient information, whereas smaller models are more prone to making errors in their ratings. For sources where ratings are provided, LLMs exhibit a high level of agreement among themselves (average Spearman's $\rho = 0.79$), but their ratings align only moderately with human expert evaluations (average $\rho = 0.50$). Analyzing news sources with different political leanings in the US, we observe a liberal bias in credibility ratings yielded by all LLMs in default configurations. Additionally, assigning partisan roles to LLMs consistently induces strong politically congruent bias in their ratings. These findings have important implications for the use of LLMs in curating news and political information.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2304.00228v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3717867.3717903</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Kai-Cheng Yang, Filippo Menczer</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GroundCocoa: A Benchmark for Evaluating Compositional &amp; Conditional Reasoning in Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.04237</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.04237v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The rapid progress of large language models (LLMs) has seen them excel and frequently surpass human performance on standard benchmarks. This has enabled many downstream applications, such as LLM agents, to rely on their reasoning to address complex task requirements. However, LLMs are known to unexpectedly falter in simple tasks and under seemingly straightforward circumstances - underscoring the need for better and more diverse evaluation setups to measure their true capabilities. To this end, we choose to study compositional and conditional reasoning, two aspects that are central to human cognition, and introduce GroundCocoa - a lexically diverse benchmark connecting these reasoning skills to the real-world problem of flight booking. Our task involves aligning detailed user preferences with available flight options presented in a multiple-choice format. Results indicate a significant disparity in performance among current state-of-the-art LLMs with even the best performing model, GPT-4 Turbo, not exceeding 67% accuracy despite advanced prompting techniques.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.04237v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Harsh Kohli, Sachin Kumar, Huan Sun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LeDex: Training LLMs to Better Self-Debug and Explain Code</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.18649</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.18649v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In the domain of code generation, self-debugging is crucial. It allows LLMs to refine their generated code based on execution feedback. This is particularly important because generating correct solutions in one attempt proves challenging for complex tasks. Prior works on self-debugging mostly focus on prompting methods by providing LLMs with few-shot examples, which work poorly on small open-sourced LLMs. In this work, we propose LeDex, a training framework that significantly improves the self-debugging capability of LLMs. Intuitively, we observe that a chain of explanations on the wrong code followed by code refinement helps LLMs better analyze the wrong code and do refinement. We thus propose an automated pipeline to collect a high-quality dataset for code explanation and refinement by generating a number of explanations and refinement trajectories from the LLM itself or a larger teacher model and filtering via execution verification. We perform supervised fine-tuning (SFT) and further reinforcement learning (RL) on both success and failure trajectories with a novel reward design considering code explanation and refinement quality. SFT improves the pass@1 by up to 15.92% and pass@10 by 9.30% over four benchmarks. RL training brings additional up to 3.54% improvement on pass@1 and 2.55% improvement on pass@10. The trained LLMs show iterative refinement ability and can keep refining code continuously. Lastly, our human evaluation shows that the LLMs trained with our framework generate more useful code explanations and help developers better understand bugs in source code.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.18649v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nan Jiang, Xiaopeng Li, Shiqi Wang, Qiang Zhou, Soneya Binta Hossain, Baishakhi Ray, Varun Kumar, Xiaofei Ma, Anoop Deoras</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Delving into LLM-assisted writing in biomedical publications through excess vocabulary</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07016</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.07016v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) like ChatGPT can generate and revise text with human-level performance. These models come with clear limitations: they can produce inaccurate information, reinforce existing biases, and be easily misused. Yet, many scientists use them for their scholarly writing. But how wide-spread is such LLM usage in the academic literature? To answer this question for the field of biomedical research, we present an unbiased, large-scale approach: we study vocabulary changes in over 15 million biomedical abstracts from 2010--2024 indexed by PubMed, and show how the appearance of LLMs led to an abrupt increase in the frequency of certain style words. This excess word analysis suggests that at least 13.5% of 2024 abstracts were processed with LLMs. This lower bound differed across disciplines, countries, and journals, reaching 40% for some subcorpora. We show that LLMs have had an unprecedented impact on scientific writing in biomedical research, surpassing the effect of major world events such as the Covid pandemic.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.07016v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.DL</category>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dmitry Kobak, Rita Gonz\'alez-M\'arquez, Em\H{o}ke-\'Agnes Horv\'at, Jan Lause</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RePrompt: Planning by Automatic Prompt Engineering for Large Language Models Agents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.11132</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.11132v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In the past year, large language models (LLMs) have had remarkable success in domains outside the traditional natural language processing, and their capacity is further expanded into the so-called LLM agents when connected with external tools. In all domains, the prompt to the LLMs has been shown to make a big difference in what the LLM would generate and thus affect the performance of the LLM agents. Therefore, automatic prompt engineering (APE) has become an important question for many researchers and users of LLMs. However, previous works in APE rely on a final checker to evaluate the performance of the given prompt -- a requirement that is hard to meet in the case of LLM agents, where intermediate feedback is easier to obtain, and the final evaluation could be expensive, inaccurate, or even missing. In this paper, we propose a novel method, \textsc{RePrompt}, which does a ``gradient descent"-like approach to optimize the step-by-step instructions in the prompts given to LLM agents, based on the chat history obtained from interactions and reflections with LLM agents. By leveraging intermediate feedback, \textsc{RePrompt} can optimize the prompt without the need for a final solution checker. We evaluate our approach on PDDL generation, TravelPlanner, and Meeting Planning to show that our method could generally improve performance for different reasoning tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.11132v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weizhe Chen, Sven Koenig, Bistra Dilkina</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Associative Recurrent Memory Transformer</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.04841</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.04841v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper addresses the challenge of creating a neural architecture for very long sequences that requires constant time for processing new information at each time step. Our approach, Associative Recurrent Memory Transformer (ARMT), is based on transformer self-attention for local context and segment-level recurrence for storage of task specific information distributed over a long context. We demonstrate that ARMT outperfors existing alternatives in associative retrieval tasks and sets a new performance record in the recent BABILong multi-task long-context benchmark by answering single-fact questions over 50 million tokens with an accuracy of 79.9%. The source code for training and evaluation is available on github.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.04841v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ivan Rodkin, Yuri Kuratov, Aydar Bulatov, Mikhail Burtsev</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Detect, Investigate, Judge and Determine: A Knowledge-guided Framework for Few-shot Fake News Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.08952</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.08952v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Few-Shot Fake News Detection (FS-FND) aims to distinguish inaccurate news from real ones in extremely low-resource scenarios. This task has garnered increased attention due to the widespread dissemination and harmful impact of fake news on social media. Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated competitive performance with the help of their rich prior knowledge and excellent in-context learning abilities. However, existing methods face significant limitations, such as the Understanding Ambiguity and Information Scarcity, which significantly undermine the potential of LLMs. To address these shortcomings, we propose a Dual-perspective Knowledge-guided Fake News Detection (DKFND) model, designed to enhance LLMs from both inside and outside perspectives. Specifically, DKFND first identifies the knowledge concepts of each news article through a Detection Module. Subsequently, DKFND creatively designs an Investigation Module to retrieve inside and outside valuable information concerning to the current news, followed by another Judge Module to evaluate the relevance and confidence of them. Finally, a Determination Module further derives two respective predictions and obtain the final result. Extensive experiments on two public datasets show the efficacy of our proposed method, particularly in low-resource settings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.08952v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ye Liu, Jiajun Zhu, Xukai Liu, Haoyu Tang, Yanghai Zhang, Kai Zhang, Xiaofang Zhou, Enhong Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Cross-Lingual Explanation of Artwork in Large-scale Vision Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.01584</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.01584v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: As the performance of Large-scale Vision Language Models (LVLMs) improves, they are increasingly capable of responding in multiple languages, and there is an expectation that the demand for explanations generated by LVLMs will grow. However, pre-training of Vision Encoder and the integrated training of LLMs with Vision Encoder are mainly conducted using English training data, leaving it uncertain whether LVLMs can completely handle their potential when generating explanations in languages other than English. In addition, multilingual QA benchmarks that create datasets using machine translation have cultural differences and biases, remaining issues for use as evaluation tasks. To address these challenges, this study created an extended dataset in multiple languages without relying on machine translation. This dataset that takes into account nuances and country-specific phrases was then used to evaluate the generation explanation abilities of LVLMs. Furthermore, this study examined whether Instruction-Tuning in resource-rich English improves performance in other languages. Our findings indicate that LVLMs perform worse in languages other than English compared to English. In addition, it was observed that LVLMs struggle to effectively manage the knowledge learned from English data. Our dataset is available at https://huggingface.co/datasets/naist-nlp/MultiExpArt</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.01584v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shintaro Ozaki, Kazuki Hayashi, Yusuke Sakai, Hidetaka Kamigaito, Katsuhiko Hayashi, Taro Watanabe</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Large Language Models Possess Sensitive to Sentiment?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.02370</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.02370v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have recently displayed their extraordinary capabilities in language understanding. However, how to comprehensively assess the sentiment capabilities of LLMs continues to be a challenge. This paper investigates the ability of LLMs to detect and react to sentiment in text modal. As the integration of LLMs into diverse applications is on the rise, it becomes highly critical to comprehend their sensitivity to emotional tone, as it can influence the user experience and the efficacy of sentiment-driven tasks. We conduct a series of experiments to evaluate the performance of several prominent LLMs in identifying and responding appropriately to sentiments like positive, negative, and neutral emotions. The models' outputs are analyzed across various sentiment benchmarks, and their responses are compared with human evaluations. Our discoveries indicate that although LLMs show a basic sensitivity to sentiment, there are substantial variations in their accuracy and consistency, emphasizing the requirement for further enhancements in their training processes to better capture subtle emotional cues. Take an example in our findings, in some cases, the models might wrongly classify a strongly positive sentiment as neutral, or fail to recognize sarcasm or irony in the text. Such misclassifications highlight the complexity of sentiment analysis and the areas where the models need to be refined. Another aspect is that different LLMs might perform differently on the same set of data, depending on their architecture and training datasets. This variance calls for a more in-depth study of the factors that contribute to the performance differences and how they can be optimized.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.02370v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yang Liu, Xichou Zhu, Zhou Shen, Yi Liu, Min Li, Yujun Chen, Benzi John, Zhenzhen Ma, Tao Hu, Zhi Li, Zhiyang Xu, Wei Luo, Junhui Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Privacy-Savvy Are Large Language Models? A Case Study on Compliance and Privacy Technical Review</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.02375</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.02375v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The recent advances in large language models (LLMs) have significantly expanded their applications across various fields such as language generation, summarization, and complex question answering. However, their application to privacy compliance and technical privacy reviews remains under-explored, raising critical concerns about their ability to adhere to global privacy standards and protect sensitive user data. This paper seeks to address this gap by providing a comprehensive case study evaluating LLMs' performance in privacy-related tasks such as privacy information extraction (PIE), legal and regulatory key point detection (KPD), and question answering (QA) with respect to privacy policies and data protection regulations. We introduce a Privacy Technical Review (PTR) framework, highlighting its role in mitigating privacy risks during the software development life-cycle. Through an empirical assessment, we investigate the capacity of several prominent LLMs, including BERT, GPT-3.5, GPT-4, and custom models, in executing privacy compliance checks and technical privacy reviews. Our experiments benchmark the models across multiple dimensions, focusing on their precision, recall, and F1-scores in extracting privacy-sensitive information and detecting key regulatory compliance points. While LLMs show promise in automating privacy reviews and identifying regulatory discrepancies, significant gaps persist in their ability to fully comply with evolving legal standards. We provide actionable recommendations for enhancing LLMs' capabilities in privacy compliance, emphasizing the need for robust model improvements and better integration with legal and regulatory requirements. This study underscores the growing importance of developing privacy-aware LLMs that can both support businesses in compliance efforts and safeguard user privacy rights.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.02375v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yang Liu, Xichou Zhu, Zhou Shen, Yi Liu, Min Li, Yujun Chen, Benzi John, Zhenzhen Ma, Tao Hu, Zhi Li, Bolong Yang, Manman Wang, Zongxing Xie, Peng Liu, Dan Cai, Junhui Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Programming Every Example: Lifting Pre-training Data Quality Like Experts at Scale</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.17115</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.17115v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language model pre-training has traditionally relied on human experts to craft heuristics for improving the corpora quality, resulting in numerous rules developed to date. However, these rules lack the flexibility to address the unique characteristics of individual example effectively. Meanwhile, applying tailored rules to every example is impractical for human experts. In this paper, we demonstrate that even small language models, with as few as 0.3B parameters, can exhibit substantial data refining capabilities comparable to those of human experts. We introduce Programming Every Example (ProX), a novel framework that treats data refinement as a programming task, enabling models to refine corpora by generating and executing fine-grained operations, such as string normalization, for each individual example at scale. Experimental results show that models pre-trained on ProX-curated data outperform either original data or data filtered by other selection methods by more than 2% across various downstream benchmarks. Its effectiveness spans various model sizes and pre-training corpora, including C4, RedPajama-V2, FineWeb, FineWeb-Edu, and DCLM. Furthermore, ProX exhibits significant potential in domain-specific continual pre-training: without domain specific design, models trained on OpenWebMath refined by ProX outperform human-crafted rule-based methods, improving average accuracy by 7.6% over Mistral-7B, with 14.6% for Llama-2-7B and 20.3% for CodeLlama-7B, all within 10B tokens to be comparable to models like Llemma-7B trained on 200B tokens. Further analysis highlights that ProX significantly saves training FLOPs, offering a promising path for efficient LLM pre-training. We are open-sourcing ProX with &gt;500B corpus, models, and sharing all training and implementation details for reproducible research and future innovation. Code: https://github.com/GAIR-NLP/ProX</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.17115v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fan Zhou, Zengzhi Wang, Qian Liu, Junlong Li, Pengfei Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>URIEL+: Enhancing Linguistic Inclusion and Usability in a Typological and Multilingual Knowledge Base</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.18472</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.18472v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: URIEL is a knowledge base offering geographical, phylogenetic, and typological vector representations for 7970 languages. It includes distance measures between these vectors for 4005 languages, which are accessible via the lang2vec tool. Despite being frequently cited, URIEL is limited in terms of linguistic inclusion and overall usability. To tackle these challenges, we introduce URIEL+, an enhanced version of URIEL and lang2vec that addresses these limitations. In addition to expanding typological feature coverage for 2898 languages, URIEL+ improves the user experience with robust, customizable distance calculations to better suit the needs of users. These upgrades also offer competitive performance on downstream tasks and provide distances that better align with linguistic distance studies.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.18472v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aditya Khan, Mason Shipton, David Anugraha, Kaiyao Duan, Phuong H. Hoang, Eric Khiu, A. Seza Do\u{g}ru\"oz, En-Shiun Annie Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PropaInsight: Toward Deeper Understanding of Propaganda in Terms of Techniques, Appeals, and Intent</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.18997</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.18997v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Propaganda plays a critical role in shaping public opinion and fueling disinformation. While existing research primarily focuses on identifying propaganda techniques, it lacks the ability to capture the broader motives and the impacts of such content. To address these challenges, we introduce propainsight, a conceptual framework grounded in foundational social science research, which systematically dissects propaganda into techniques, arousal appeals, and underlying intent. propainsight offers a more granular understanding of how propaganda operates across different contexts. Additionally, we present propagaze, a novel dataset that combines human-annotated data with high-quality synthetic data generated through a meticulously designed pipeline. Our experiments show that off-the-shelf LLMs struggle with propaganda analysis, but training with propagaze significantly improves performance. Fine-tuned Llama-7B-Chat achieves 203.4% higher text span IoU in technique identification and 66.2% higher BertScore in appeal analysis compared to 1-shot GPT-4-Turbo. Moreover, propagaze complements limited human-annotated data in data-sparse and cross-domain scenarios, showing its potential for comprehensive and generalizable propaganda analysis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.18997v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiateng Liu, Lin Ai, Zizhou Liu, Payam Karisani, Zheng Hui, May Fung, Preslav Nakov, Julia Hirschberg, Heng Ji</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Unified Approach to Routing and Cascading for LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.10347</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.10347v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The availability of a wide range of large language models (LLMs) embedded in various agentic systems has significantly increased the potential of model selection strategies to improve the cost-performance tradeoff. Existing strategies involve either routing, where a single model is chosen per query, or cascading, which sequentially runs increasingly larger models until a satisfactory answer is found. However, current approaches face three key limitations: they (1) lack formal proofs of optimality, (2) fail to identify the conditions under which these strategies are most effective to improve the cost-performance tradeoff, and (3) are unable to combine both paradigms for further improvements. To address these issues, we first derive a novel optimal strategy for cascading and prove the optimality of an existing routing strategy. Further, we propose cascade routing, a unified framework that integrates routing and cascading into a theoretically optimal strategy. Through our analysis, we identify good quality estimators as the critical factor for the success of model selection paradigms. Finally, in our experiments, we show that cascade routing consistently outperforms the individual approaches by a large margin and we analyze quality estimators to determine when routing and/or cascading are useful paradigms for model selection.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.10347v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jasper Dekoninck, Maximilian Baader, Martin Vechev</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Context-Aware or Context-Insensitive? Assessing LLMs' Performance in Document-Level Translation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.14391</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.14391v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are increasingly strong contenders in machine translation. In this work, we focus on document-level translation, where some words cannot be translated without context from outside the sentence. Specifically, we investigate the ability of prominent LLMs to utilize the document context during translation through a perturbation analysis (analyzing models' robustness to perturbed and randomized document context) and an attribution analysis (examining the contribution of relevant context to the translation). We conduct an extensive evaluation across nine LLMs from diverse model families and training paradigms, including translation-specialized LLMs, alongside two encoder-decoder transformer baselines. We find that LLMs' improved document-translation performance compared to encoder-decoder models is not reflected in pronoun translation performance. Our analysis highlight the need for context-aware finetuning of LLMs with a focus on relevant parts of the context to improve their reliability for document-level translation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.14391v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wafaa Mohammed, Vlad Niculae</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A distributional simplicity bias in the learning dynamics of transformers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.19637</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.19637v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The remarkable capability of over-parameterised neural networks to generalise effectively has been explained by invoking a ``simplicity bias'': neural networks prevent overfitting by initially learning simple classifiers before progressing to more complex, non-linear functions. While simplicity biases have been described theoretically and experimentally in feed-forward networks for supervised learning, the extent to which they also explain the remarkable success of transformers trained with self-supervised techniques remains unclear. In our study, we demonstrate that transformers, trained on natural language data, also display a simplicity bias. Specifically, they sequentially learn many-body interactions among input tokens, reaching a saturation point in the prediction error for low-degree interactions while continuing to learn high-degree interactions. To conduct this analysis, we develop a procedure to generate \textit{clones} of a given natural language data set, which rigorously capture the interactions between tokens up to a specified order. This approach opens up the possibilities of studying how interactions of different orders in the data affect learning, in natural language processing and beyond.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.19637v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Riccardo Rende, Federica Gerace, Alessandro Laio, Sebastian Goldt</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tulu 3: Pushing Frontiers in Open Language Model Post-Training</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.15124</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.15124v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Language model post-training is applied to refine behaviors and unlock new skills across a wide range of recent language models, but open recipes for applying these techniques lag behind proprietary ones. The underlying training data and recipes for post-training are simultaneously the most important pieces of the puzzle and the portion with the least transparency. To bridge this gap, we introduce Tulu 3, a family of fully-open state-of-the-art post-trained models, alongside its data, code, and training recipes, serving as a comprehensive guide for modern post-training techniques. Tulu 3, which builds on Llama 3.1 base models, achieves results surpassing the instruct versions of Llama 3.1, Qwen 2.5, Mistral, and even closed models such as GPT-4o-mini and Claude 3.5-Haiku. The training algorithms for our models include supervised finetuning (SFT), Direct Preference Optimization (DPO), and a novel method we call Reinforcement Learning with Verifiable Rewards (RLVR). With Tulu 3, we introduce a multi-task evaluation scheme for post-training recipes with development and unseen evaluations, standard benchmark implementations, and substantial decontamination of existing open datasets on said benchmarks. We conclude with analysis and discussion of training methods that did not reliably improve performance.
  In addition to the Tulu 3 model weights and demo, we release the complete recipe -- including datasets for diverse core skills, a robust toolkit for data curation and evaluation, the training code and infrastructure, and, most importantly, a detailed report for reproducing and further adapting the Tulu 3 approach to more domains.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.15124v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nathan Lambert, Jacob Morrison, Valentina Pyatkin, Shengyi Huang, Hamish Ivison, Faeze Brahman, Lester James V. Miranda, Alisa Liu, Nouha Dziri, Shane Lyu, Yuling Gu, Saumya Malik, Victoria Graf, Jena D. Hwang, Jiangjiang Yang, Ronan Le Bras, Oyvind Tafjord, Chris Wilhelm, Luca Soldaini, Noah A. Smith, Yizhong Wang, Pradeep Dasigi, Hannaneh Hajishirzi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Next Tokens via Second-to-Last Predictions with Generate and Refine</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.15661</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.15661v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Autoregressive language models like GPT aim to predict next tokens, while autoencoding models such as BERT are trained on tasks such as predicting masked tokens. We train a decoder-only architecture for predicting the second to last token for a sequence of tokens. Our approach yields higher computational training efficiency than BERT-style models by employing a structured deterministic approach to masking tokens. We use our model to improve the next token predictions of a standard GPT by combining both predictions in a ``generate-then-refine'' approach. We demonstrate on different variants of GPT-2 and different datasets that (not unexpectedly) second to last token predictions are much more accurate, i.e., more than 15\% higher accuracy than standard next token predictions. The ``generate-then-refine'' approach also demonstrates notable improvements in next-token predictions, yielding smaller yet consistent and significant gains.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.15661v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Intelligent Data Analysis (IDA), 2025</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Johannes Schneider</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preference Optimization for Reasoning with Pseudo Feedback</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.16345</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.16345v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Preference optimization techniques, such as Direct Preference Optimization (DPO), are frequently employed to enhance the reasoning capabilities of large language models (LLMs) in domains like mathematical reasoning and coding, typically following supervised fine-tuning. These methods rely on high-quality labels for reasoning tasks to generate preference pairs; however, the availability of reasoning datasets with human-verified labels is limited. In this study, we introduce a novel approach to generate pseudo feedback for reasoning tasks by framing the labeling of solutions to reason problems as an evaluation against associated test cases. We explore two forms of pseudo feedback based on test cases: one generated by frontier LLMs and the other by extending self-consistency to multi-test-case. We conduct experiments on both mathematical reasoning and coding tasks using pseudo feedback for preference optimization, and observe improvements across both tasks. Specifically, using Mathstral-7B as our base model, we improve MATH results from 58.3 to 68.6, surpassing both NuminaMath-72B and GPT-4-Turbo-1106-preview. In GSM8K and College Math, our scores increase from 85.6 to 90.3 and from 34.3 to 42.3, respectively. Building on Deepseek-coder-7B-v1.5, we achieve a score of 24.6 on LiveCodeBench (from 21.1), surpassing Claude-3-Haiku.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.16345v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fangkai Jiao, Geyang Guo, Xingxing Zhang, Nancy F. Chen, Shafiq Joty, Furu Wei</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forest-of-Thought: Scaling Test-Time Compute for Enhancing LLM Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09078</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09078v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated remarkable abilities across various language tasks, but solving complex reasoning problems remains a significant challenge. While existing methods, such as Chain-of-Thought (CoT) and Tree-of-Thought (ToT), enhance reasoning by decomposing problems or structuring prompts, they typically perform a single pass of reasoning and may fail to revisit flawed paths, compromising accuracy. To address this limitation, we propose a novel reasoning framework called Forest-of-Thought (FoT), which integrates multiple reasoning trees to leverage collective decision-making for solving complex logical problems. FoT employs sparse activation strategies to select the most relevant reasoning paths, improving both efficiency and accuracy. Additionally, we introduce a dynamic self-correction strategy that enables real-time error correction, along with consensus-guided decision-making strategies to optimize both correctness and computational resources. Experimental results demonstrate that the FoT framework, combined with these strategies, significantly enhances the reasoning capabilities of LLMs, enabling them to solve complex tasks with greater precision and efficiency.Code will be available at https://github.com/iamhankai/Forest-of-Thought.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09078v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhenni Bi, Kai Han, Chuanjian Liu, Yehui Tang, Yunhe Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SuperMerge: An Approach For Gradient-Based Model Merging</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10416</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10416v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models, such as ChatGPT, Claude, or LLaMA, are gigantic, monolithic, and possess the superpower to simultaneously support thousands of tasks. However, high-throughput applications often prefer smaller task-specific models because of their lower latency and cost. One challenge of using task-specific models is the incremental need for solving newer tasks after the model is already deployed for existing tasks. A straightforward solution requires fine-tuning the model again for both existing and new tasks, which is computationally expensive and time-consuming. To address this issue, we propose a model merging based approach called SUPERMERGE. SUPERMERGE is a gradient-based method to systematically merge several fine-tuned models trained on existing and new tasks. SUPERMERGE is designed to be lightweight and fast, and the merged model achieves similar performance to fully fine-tuned models on all tasks. Furthermore, we proposed a hierarchical model merging strategy to reduce the peak space requirement without sacrificing the performance of the merged model. We experimentally demonstrate that SUPERMERGE outperforms existing model merging methods on common natural language processing and computer vision tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10416v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haoyu Yang, Zheng Zhang, Saket Sathe</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RareAgents: Advancing Rare Disease Care through LLM-Empowered Multi-disciplinary Team</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.12475</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.12475v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Rare diseases, despite their low individual incidence, collectively impact around 300 million people worldwide due to the vast number of diseases. The involvement of multiple organs and systems, and the shortage of specialized doctors with relevant experience make diagnosing and treating rare diseases more challenging than common diseases. Recently, agents powered by large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated notable applications across various domains. In the medical field, some agent methods have outperformed direct prompts in question-answering tasks from medical examinations. However, current agent frameworks are not well-adapted to real-world clinical scenarios, especially those involving the complex demands of rare diseases. To bridge this gap, we introduce RareAgents, the first LLM-driven multi-disciplinary team framework designed specifically for the complex clinical context of rare diseases. RareAgents integrates advanced Multidisciplinary Team (MDT) coordination, memory mechanisms, and medical tools utilization, leveraging Llama-3.1-8B/70B as the base model. Experimental results show that RareAgents outperforms state-of-the-art domain-specific models, GPT-4o, and current agent frameworks in differential diagnosis and medication recommendation for rare diseases. Furthermore, we contribute a novel rare disease dataset, MIMIC-IV-Ext-Rare, to support further advancements in this field.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.12475v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xuanzhong Chen, Ye Jin, Xiaohao Mao, Lun Wang, Shuyang Zhang, Ting Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cross-Lingual Transfer of Debiasing and Detoxification in Multilingual LLMs: An Extensive Investigation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.14050</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.14050v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent generative large language models (LLMs) show remarkable performance in non-English languages, but when prompted in those languages they tend to express higher harmful social biases and toxicity levels. Prior work has shown that finetuning on specialized datasets can mitigate this behavior, and doing so in English can transfer to other languages. In this work, we investigate the impact of different finetuning methods on the model's bias and toxicity, but also on its ability to produce fluent and diverse text. We reduce biases by finetuning on curated non-harmful text, but find only direct preference optimization to be effective for mitigating toxicity. The mitigation caused by applying these methods in English also transfers to non-English languages. We find evidence that the extent to which transfer takes place can be predicted by the amount of data in a given language present in the model's pretraining data. However, this transfer of bias and toxicity mitigation often comes at the expense of decreased language generation ability in non-English languages, highlighting the importance of developing language-specific bias and toxicity mitigation methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.14050v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Vera Neplenbroek, Arianna Bisazza, Raquel Fern\'andez</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Refinement Strategies for LLM-based Product Attribute Value Extraction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01237</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01237v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Structured product data, in the form of attribute-value pairs, is essential for e-commerce platforms to support features such as faceted product search and attribute-based product comparison. However, vendors often provide unstructured product descriptions, making attribute value extraction necessary to ensure data consistency and usability. Large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated their potential for product attribute value extraction in few-shot scenarios. Recent research has shown that self-refinement techniques can improve the performance of LLMs on tasks such as code generation and text-to-SQL translation. For other tasks, the application of these techniques has resulted in increased costs due to processing additional tokens, without achieving any improvement in performance. This paper investigates applying two self-refinement techniques (error-based prompt rewriting and self-correction) to the product attribute value extraction task. The self-refinement techniques are evaluated across zero-shot, few-shot in-context learning, and fine-tuning scenarios using GPT-4o. The experiments show that both self-refinement techniques fail to significantly improve the extraction performance while substantially increasing processing costs. For scenarios with development data, fine-tuning yields the highest performance, while the ramp-up costs of fine-tuning are balanced out as the amount of product descriptions increases.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01237v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alexander Brinkmann, Christian Bizer</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graph-based Retrieval Augmented Generation for Dynamic Few-shot Text Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.02844</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.02844v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Text classification is a fundamental task in data mining, pivotal to various applications such as tabular understanding and recommendation. Although neural network-based models, such as CNN and BERT, have demonstrated remarkable performance in text classification, their effectiveness heavily relies on abundant labeled training data. This dependency makes these models less effective in dynamic few-shot text classification, where labeled data is scarce, and new target labels frequently appear based on application needs. Recently, large language models (LLMs) have shown promise due to their extensive pretraining and contextual understanding ability. Current approaches provide LLMs with text inputs, candidate labels, and additional side information (e.g., descriptions) to classify texts. However, their effectiveness is hindered by the increased input size and the noise introduced through side information processing. To address these limitations, we propose a graph-based online retrieval-augmented generation framework, namely GORAG, for dynamic few-shot text classification. Rather than treating each input independently, GORAG constructs and maintains a weighted graph by extracting side information across all target texts. In this graph, text keywords and labels are represented as nodes, with edges indicating the correlations between them. To model these correlations, GORAG employs an edge weighting mechanism to prioritize the importance and reliability of extracted information and dynamically retrieves relevant context using a minimum-cost spanning tree tailored for each text input. Empirical evaluations demonstrate that GORAG outperforms existing approaches by providing more comprehensive and precise contextual information.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.02844v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yubo Wang, Haoyang Li, Fei Teng, Lei Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MAGNET: Augmenting Generative Decoders with Representation Learning and Infilling Capabilities</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.08648</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.08648v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: While originally designed for unidirectional generative modeling, decoder-only large language models (LLMs) are increasingly being adapted for bidirectional modeling. However, unidirectional and bidirectional models are typically trained separately with distinct objectives (generation and representation learning). This separation overlooks the opportunity for developing a more versatile language model and for these objectives to complement each other. In this work, we propose MAGNET, a method for adapting decoder-only LLMs to generate robust representations and infill missing text spans. MAGNET employs three self-supervised training objectives and introduces an attention mechanism that combines bidirectional and causal attention, enabling unified training across all objectives. Our results demonstrate that LLMs adapted with MAGNET (1) surpass strong text encoders on token-level and sentence-level representation learning tasks, (2) generate contextually appropriate text infills by leveraging past and future contexts, (3) perform open-ended text generation without excessive repetition of words or phrases, and (4) preserve the knowledge and reasoning capability gained by the LLM during pretraining.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.08648v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Savya Khosla, Aditi Tiwari, Kushal Kafle, Simon Jenni, Handong Zhao, John Collomosse, Jing Shi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EvidenceMap: Learning Evidence Analysis to Unleash the Power of Small Language Models for Biomedical Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.12746</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.12746v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: When addressing professional questions in the biomedical domain, humans typically acquire multiple pieces of information as evidence and engage in multifaceted analysis to provide high-quality answers. Current LLM-based question answering methods lack a detailed definition and learning process for evidence analysis, leading to the risk of error propagation and hallucinations while using evidence. Although increasing the parameter size of LLMs can alleviate these issues, it also presents challenges in training and deployment with limited resources. In this study, we propose EvidenceMap, which aims to enable a tiny pre-trained language model to explicitly learn multiple aspects of biomedical evidence, including supportive evaluation, logical correlation and content summarization, thereby latently guiding a small generative model (around 3B parameters) to provide textual responses. Experimental results demonstrate that our method, learning evidence analysis by fine-tuning a model with only 66M parameters, exceeds the RAG method with an 8B LLM by 19.9% and 5.7% in reference-based quality and accuracy, respectively.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.12746v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chang Zong, Jian Wan, Siliang Tang, Lei Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating and Improving Graph to Text Generation with Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14497</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14497v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated immense potential across various tasks. However, research for exploring and improving the capabilities of LLMs in interpreting graph structures remains limited. To address this gap, we conduct a comprehensive evaluation of prompting current open-source LLMs on graph-to-text generation tasks. Although we explored the optimal prompting strategies and proposed a novel and effective diversity-difficulty-based few-shot sample selection method, we found that the improvements from tuning-free approaches were incremental, as LLMs struggle with planning on complex graphs, particularly those with a larger number of triplets. To further improve LLMs in planning with graph sequences and grounding in truth, we introduce a new graph-to-text dataset, PlanGTG, annotated with two sub-tasks: reordering and attribution. Through extensive automatic and human evaluations, we demonstrate significant improvements in the quality of generated text from both few-shot learning and fine-tuning perspectives using the PlanGTG dataset. Our study paves the way for new research directions in graph-to-text generation. PlanGTG datasets can be found in https://github.com/probe2/kg_text.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14497v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jie He, Yijun Yang, Wanqiu Long, Deyi Xiong, Victor Gutierrez-Basulto, Jeff Z. Pan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STATE ToxiCN: A Benchmark for Span-level Target-Aware Toxicity Extraction in Chinese Hate Speech Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.15451</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.15451v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The proliferation of hate speech has caused significant harm to society. The intensity and directionality of hate are closely tied to the target and argument it is associated with. However, research on hate speech detection in Chinese has lagged behind, and existing datasets lack span-level fine-grained annotations. Furthermore, the lack of research on Chinese hateful slang poses a significant challenge. In this paper, we provide a solution for fine-grained detection of Chinese hate speech. First, we construct a dataset containing Target-Argument-Hateful-Group quadruples (STATE ToxiCN), which is the first span-level Chinese hate speech dataset. Secondly, we evaluate the span-level hate speech detection performance of existing models using STATE ToxiCN. Finally, we conduct the first study on Chinese hateful slang and evaluate the ability of LLMs to detect such expressions. Our work contributes valuable resources and insights to advance span-level hate speech detection in Chinese.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.15451v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zewen Bai, Yuanyuan Sun, Shengdi Yin, Junyu Lu, Jingjie Zeng, Haohao Zhu, Liang Yang, Hongfei Lin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Echoes of Discord: Forecasting Hater Reactions to Counterspeech</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.16235</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.16235v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Hate speech (HS) erodes the inclusiveness of online users and propagates negativity and division. Counterspeech has been recognized as a way to mitigate the harmful consequences. While some research has investigated the impact of user-generated counterspeech on social media platforms, few have examined and modeled haters' reactions toward counterspeech, despite the immediate alteration of haters' attitudes being an important aspect of counterspeech. This study fills the gap by analyzing the impact of counterspeech from the hater's perspective, focusing on whether the counterspeech leads the hater to reenter the conversation and if the reentry is hateful. We compile the Reddit Echoes of Hate dataset (ReEco), which consists of triple-turn conversations featuring haters' reactions, to assess the impact of counterspeech. To predict haters' behaviors, we employ two strategies: a two-stage reaction predictor and a three-way classifier. The linguistic analysis sheds insights on the language of counterspeech to hate eliciting different haters' reactions. Experimental results demonstrate that the 3-way classification model outperforms the two-stage reaction predictor, which first predicts reentry and then determines the reentry type. We conclude the study with an assessment showing the most common errors identified by the best-performing model.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.16235v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoying Song, Sharon Lisseth Perez, Xinchen Yu, Eduardo Blanco, Lingzi Hong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reward-Guided Speculative Decoding for Efficient LLM Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.19324</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.19324v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We introduce Reward-Guided Speculative Decoding (RSD), a novel framework aimed at improving the efficiency of inference in large language models (LLMs). RSD synergistically combines a lightweight draft model with a more powerful target model, incorporating a controlled bias to prioritize high-reward outputs, in contrast to existing speculative decoding methods that enforce strict unbiasedness. RSD employs a process reward model to evaluate intermediate decoding steps and dynamically decide whether to invoke the target model, optimizing the trade-off between computational cost and output quality. We theoretically demonstrate that a threshold-based mixture strategy achieves an optimal balance between resource utilization and performance. Extensive evaluations on challenging reasoning benchmarks, including Olympiad-level tasks, show that RSD delivers significant efficiency gains against decoding with the target model only (up to 4.4x fewer FLOPs), while achieving significant better accuracy than parallel decoding method on average (up to +3.5). These results highlight RSD as a robust and cost-effective approach for deploying LLMs in resource-intensive scenarios. The code is available at https://github.com/BaohaoLiao/RSD.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.19324v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Baohao Liao, Yuhui Xu, Hanze Dong, Junnan Li, Christof Monz, Silvio Savarese, Doyen Sahoo, Caiming Xiong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ReFoRCE: A Text-to-SQL Agent with Self-Refinement, Format Restriction, and Column Exploration</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.00675</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.00675v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Text-to-SQL systems have unlocked easier access to critical data insights by enabling natural language queries over structured databases. However, deploying such systems in enterprise environments remains challenging due to factors such as large, complex schemas (&gt; 3000 columns), diverse SQL dialects (e.g., BigQuery, Snowflake) and sophisticated query requirements (e.g., transformation, analytics). Current state-of-the-art performance on the Spider 2.0 dataset -- a benchmark built to mimic such complex environments -- remains limited at 20%. Key limitations include inadequate instruction-following, poor long-context comprehension, weak self-refinement, and insufficient dialect-specific knowledge. To address these gaps, we propose ReFoRCE (Self-Refinement Agent with Format Restriction and Column Exploration) which introduces (1) table compression to mitigate long-context limitations (2) format restriction to ensure accurate answer format, and (3) iterative column exploration for enhanced schema understanding. Additionally, it employs self-refinement pipeline consisting of (1) parallelized workflows with voting mechanisms and (2) a Common Table Expression (CTE) based refinement approach to handle unresolved cases. ReFoRCE achieves state-of-the-art results scoring 31.26 on the Spider 2.0-Snow and scoring 30.35 on the Spider 2.0-Lite tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.00675v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Minghang Deng, Ashwin Ramachandran, Canwen Xu, Lanxiang Hu, Zhewei Yao, Anupam Datta, Hao Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syntriever: How to Train Your Retriever with Synthetic Data from LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.03824</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.03824v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: LLMs have boosted progress in many AI applications. Recently, there were attempts to distill the vast knowledge of LLMs into information retrieval systems. Those distillation methods mostly use output probabilities of LLMs which are unavailable in the latest black-box LLMs. We propose Syntriever, a training framework for retrievers using synthetic data from black-box LLMs. Syntriever consists of two stages. Firstly in the distillation stage, we synthesize relevant and plausibly irrelevant passages and augmented queries using chain-of-thoughts for the given queries. LLM is asked to self-verify the synthetic data for possible hallucinations, after which retrievers are trained with a loss designed to cluster the embeddings of relevant passages. Secondly in the alignment stage, we align the retriever with the preferences of LLMs. We propose a preference modeling called partial Plackett-Luce ranking to learn LLM preferences with regularization which prevents the model from deviating excessively from that trained in the distillation stage. Experiments show that Syntriever achieves state-of-the-art performances on benchmark datasets from various domains in nDCG@$K$. The code is available at \href{https://github.com/kmswin1/Syntriever}{https://github.com/kmswin1/Syntriever}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.03824v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Minsang Kim, Seungjun Baek</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prompt-based Depth Pruning of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.04348</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.04348v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Depth pruning aims to reduce the inference cost of a large language model without any hardware-specific complications, by simply removing several less important transformer blocks. However, our empirical findings suggest that the importance of a transformer block may be highly task-dependent -- a block that is crucial for a task can be removed without degrading the accuracy on another task. Based on this observation, we develop a dynamic depth pruning algorithm, coined PuDDing (Prompt-routed Dynamic Depth Pruning), which determines which blocks to omit from the model based on the input prompt. PuDDing operates by training a lightweight router to predict the best omission set among a set of options, where this option set has also been constructed in a data-driven manner. Empirical results on commonsense reasoning benchmarks demonstrate that PuDDing effectively accelerates the inference language models, and achieves better on-task performance than static depth pruning baselines.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.04348v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Juyun Wee, Minjae Park, Jaeho Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the Singular: The Essential Role of Multiple Generations in Effective Benchmark Evaluation and Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.08943</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.08943v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated significant utilities in real-world applications, exhibiting impressive capabilities in natural language processing and understanding. Benchmark evaluations are crucial for assessing the capabilities of LLMs as they can provide a comprehensive assessment of their strengths and weaknesses. However, current evaluation methods often overlook the inherent randomness of LLMs by employing deterministic generation strategies or relying on a single random sample, resulting in unaccounted sampling variance and unreliable benchmark score estimates. In this paper, we propose a hierarchical statistical model that provides a more comprehensive representation of the benchmarking process by incorporating both benchmark characteristics and LLM randomness. We show that leveraging multiple generations improves the accuracy of estimating the benchmark score and reduces variance. We also introduce $\mathbb P\left(\text{correct}\right)$, a prompt-level difficulty score based on correct ratios, providing fine-grained insights into individual prompts. Additionally, we create a data map that visualizes difficulty and semantic prompts, enabling error detection and quality control in benchmark construction.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.08943v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenbo Zhang, Hengrui Cai, Wenyu Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Adoption and Efficacy of Large Language Models: Evidence From Consumer Complaints in the Financial Industry</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.16466</link>
      <description>arXiv:2311.16466v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) are reshaping consumer decision-making, particularly in communication with firms, yet our understanding of their impact remains limited. This research explores the effect of LLMs on consumer complaints submitted to the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau from 2015 to 2024, documenting the adoption of LLMs for drafting complaints and evaluating the likelihood of obtaining relief from financial firms. We analyzed over 1 million complaints and identified a significant increase in LLM usage following the release of ChatGPT. We find that LLM usage is associated with an increased likelihood of obtaining relief from financial firms. To investigate this relationship, we employ an instrumental variable approach to mitigate endogeneity concerns around LLM adoption. Although instrumental variables suggest a potential causal link, they cannot fully capture all unobserved heterogeneity. To further establish this causal relationship, we conducted controlled experiments, which support that LLMs can enhance the clarity and persuasiveness of consumer narratives, thereby increasing the likelihood of obtaining relief. Our findings suggest that facilitating access to LLMs can help firms better understand consumer concerns and level the playing field among consumers. This underscores the importance of policies promoting technological accessibility, enabling all consumers to effectively voice their concerns.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2311.16466v4</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Minkyu Shin, Jin Kim, Jiwoong Shin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Verbalized Machine Learning: Revisiting Machine Learning with Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.04344</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.04344v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Motivated by the progress made by large language models (LLMs), we introduce the framework of verbalized machine learning (VML). In contrast to conventional machine learning (ML) models that are typically optimized over a continuous parameter space, VML constrains the parameter space to be human-interpretable natural language. Such a constraint leads to a new perspective of function approximation, where an LLM with a text prompt can be viewed as a function parameterized by the text prompt. Guided by this perspective, we revisit classical ML problems, such as regression and classification, and find that these problems can be solved by an LLM-parameterized learner and optimizer. The major advantages of VML include (1) easy encoding of inductive bias: prior knowledge about the problem and hypothesis class can be encoded in natural language and fed into the LLM-parameterized learner; (2) automatic model class selection: the optimizer can automatically select a model class based on data and verbalized prior knowledge, and it can update the model class during training; and (3) interpretable learner updates: the LLM-parameterized optimizer can provide explanations for why an update is performed. We empirically verify the effectiveness of VML, and hope that VML can serve as a stepping stone to stronger interpretability.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.04344v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tim Z. Xiao, Robert Bamler, Bernhard Sch\"olkopf, Weiyang Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Critical Look At Tokenwise Reward-Guided Text Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07780</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.07780v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) can be improved by aligning with human preferences through fine-tuning -- the so-called reinforcement learning from human feedback (RLHF). However, the cost of fine-tuning an LLM is prohibitive for many users. Due to their ability to bypass LLM fine-tuning, prediction-time tokenwise reward-guided text generation (RGTG) methods have recently been proposed. They use a reward model trained on full sequences to score partial sequences during decoding in a bid to steer the generation towards sequences with high rewards. However, these methods have so far been only heuristically motivated and poorly analyzed. In this work, we show that reward models trained on full sequences are not compatible with scoring partial sequences. To alleviate this issue, we propose to train a Bradley-Terry reward model on partial sequences explicitly, and autoregressively sample from the implied tokenwise policy during decoding time. We study the properties of this reward model and the resulting policy: we show that this policy is proportional to the ratio of two distinct RLHF policies. Our simple approach outperforms previous RGTG methods and performs similarly to strong offline baselines without large-scale LLM finetuning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.07780v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ahmad Rashid, Ruotian Wu, Julia Grosse, Agustinus Kristiadi, Pascal Poupart</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ResearchArena: Benchmarking Large Language Models' Ability to Collect and Organize Information as Research Agents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10291</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10291v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) excel across many natural language processing tasks but face challenges in domain-specific, analytical tasks such as conducting research surveys. This study introduces ResearchArena, a benchmark designed to evaluate LLMs' capabilities in conducting academic surveys$\unicode{x2013}$a foundational step in academic research. ResearchArena models the process in three stages: (1) information discovery, identifying relevant literature; (2) information selection, evaluating papers' relevance and impact; and (3) information organization, structuring knowledge into hierarchical frameworks such as mind-maps. Notably, mind-map construction is treated as a bonus task, reflecting its supplementary role in survey-writing. To support these evaluations, we construct an offline environment of 12M full-text academic papers and 7.9K survey papers. To ensure ethical compliance, we do not redistribute copyrighted materials; instead, we provide code to construct the environment from the Semantic Scholar Open Research Corpus (S2ORC). Preliminary evaluations reveal that LLM-based approaches underperform compared to simpler keyword-based retrieval methods, underscoring significant opportunities for advancing LLMs in autonomous research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10291v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hao Kang, Chenyan Xiong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abstraction Alignment: Comparing Model-Learned and Human-Encoded Conceptual Relationships</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.12543</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.12543v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: While interpretability methods identify a model's learned concepts, they overlook the relationships between concepts that make up its abstractions and inform its ability to generalize to new data. To assess whether models' have learned human-aligned abstractions, we introduce abstraction alignment, a methodology to compare model behavior against formal human knowledge. Abstraction alignment externalizes domain-specific human knowledge as an abstraction graph, a set of pertinent concepts spanning levels of abstraction. Using the abstraction graph as a ground truth, abstraction alignment measures the alignment of a model's behavior by determining how much of its uncertainty is accounted for by the human abstractions. By aggregating abstraction alignment across entire datasets, users can test alignment hypotheses, such as which human concepts the model has learned and where misalignments recur. In evaluations with experts, abstraction alignment differentiates seemingly similar errors, improves the verbosity of existing model-quality metrics, and uncovers improvements to current human abstractions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.12543v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3706598.3713406</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Angie Boggust, Hyemin Bang, Hendrik Strobelt, Arvind Satyanarayan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SELP: Generating Safe and Efficient Task Plans for Robot Agents with Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.19471</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.19471v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Despite significant advancements in large language models (LLMs) that enhance robot agents' understanding and execution of natural language (NL) commands, ensuring the agents adhere to user-specified constraints remains challenging, particularly for complex commands and long-horizon tasks. To address this challenge, we present three key insights, equivalence voting, constrained decoding, and domain-specific fine-tuning, which significantly enhance LLM planners' capability in handling complex tasks. Equivalence voting ensures consistency by generating and sampling multiple Linear Temporal Logic (LTL) formulas from NL commands, grouping equivalent LTL formulas, and selecting the majority group of formulas as the final LTL formula. Constrained decoding then uses the generated LTL formula to enforce the autoregressive inference of plans, ensuring the generated plans conform to the LTL. Domain-specific fine-tuning customizes LLMs to produce safe and efficient plans within specific task domains. Our approach, Safe Efficient LLM Planner (SELP), combines these insights to create LLM planners to generate plans adhering to user commands with high confidence. We demonstrate the effectiveness and generalizability of SELP across different robot agents and tasks, including drone navigation and robot manipulation. For drone navigation tasks, SELP outperforms state-of-the-art planners by 10.8% in safety rate (i.e., finishing tasks conforming to NL commands) and by 19.8% in plan efficiency. For robot manipulation tasks, SELP achieves 20.4% improvement in safety rate. Our datasets for evaluating NL-to-LTL and robot task planning will be released in github.com/lt-asset/selp.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.19471v2</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.FL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yi Wu, Zikang Xiong, Yiran Hu, Shreyash S. Iyengar, Nan Jiang, Aniket Bera, Lin Tan, Suresh Jagannathan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Reward Model Evaluation: Are We Barking up the Wrong Tree?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.05584</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.05584v5 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Reward Models (RMs) are crucial for aligning language models with human preferences. Currently, the evaluation of RMs depends on measuring accuracy against a validation set of manually annotated preference data. Although this method is straightforward and widely adopted, the relationship between RM accuracy and downstream policy performance remains under-explored. In this work, we conduct experiments in a synthetic setting to investigate how differences in RM measured by accuracy translate into gaps in optimized policy performance. Our findings reveal that while there is a weak positive correlation between accuracy and downstream performance, policies optimized towards RMs with similar accuracy can exhibit quite different performance. Moreover, we discover that the way of measuring accuracy significantly impacts its ability to predict the final policy performance. Through the lens of the Regressional Goodhart effect, we recognize that accuracy, when used for measuring RM quality, can fail to fully capture the potential RM overoptimization. This underscores the inadequacy of relying solely on accuracy to reflect their impact on policy optimization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.05584v5</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xueru Wen, Jie Lou, Yaojie Lu, Hongyu Lin, Xing Yu, Xinyu Lu, Ben He, Xianpei Han, Debing Zhang, Le Sun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MathGAP: Out-of-Distribution Evaluation on Problems with Arbitrarily Complex Proofs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.13502</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.13502v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) can solve arithmetic word problems with high accuracy, but little is known about how well they generalize to more complex problems. This is difficult to study, as (i) much of the available evaluation data has already been seen by the most capable models during training, and (ii) existing benchmarks do not capture how problem proofs may be arbitrarily complex in various ways. In this paper, we present a data-generation framework for evaluating LLMs on problems with arbitrarily complex arithmetic proofs, called MathGAP. MathGAP generates problem statements and chain-of-thought reasoning traces according to specifications about their arithmetic proof structure, enabling systematic studies on easy-to-hard generalization with respect to complexity of proof trees. Using MathGAP, we find that LLMs show a significant decrease in performance as proofs get deeper and wider. This effect is more pronounced in complex, nonlinear proof structures, which are challenging even for the most capable models. The models are also sensitive to simple changes in sentence ordering. However, they remain capable of solving some complex problems, suggesting that reasoning generalization is noisy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.13502v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Andreas Opedal, Haruki Shirakami, Bernhard Sch\"olkopf, Abulhair Saparov, Mrinmaya Sachan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MeNTi: Bridging Medical Calculator and LLM Agent with Nested Tool Calling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.13610</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.13610v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Integrating tools into Large Language Models (LLMs) has facilitated the widespread application. Despite this, in specialized downstream task contexts, reliance solely on tools is insufficient to fully address the complexities of the real world. This particularly restricts the effective deployment of LLMs in fields such as medicine. In this paper, we focus on the downstream tasks of medical calculators, which use standardized tests to assess an individual's health status. We introduce MeNTi, a universal agent architecture for LLMs. MeNTi integrates a specialized medical toolkit and employs meta-tool and nested calling mechanisms to enhance LLM tool utilization. Specifically, it achieves flexible tool selection and nested tool calling to address practical issues faced in intricate medical scenarios, including calculator selection, slot filling, and unit conversion. To assess the capabilities of LLMs for quantitative assessment throughout the clinical process of calculator scenarios, we introduce CalcQA. This benchmark requires LLMs to use medical calculators to perform calculations and assess patient health status. CalcQA is constructed by professional physicians and includes 100 case-calculator pairs, complemented by a toolkit of 281 medical tools. The experimental results demonstrate significant performance improvements with our framework. This research paves new directions for applying LLMs in demanding scenarios of medicine.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.13610v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yakun Zhu, Shaohang Wei, Xu Wang, Kui Xue, Xiaofan Zhang, Shaoting Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flaming-hot Initiation with Regular Execution Sampling for Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.21236</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.21236v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Since the release of ChatGPT, large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated remarkable capabilities across various domains. A key challenge in developing these general capabilities is efficiently sourcing diverse, high-quality data. This becomes especially critical in reasoning-related tasks with sandbox checkers, such as math or code, where the goal is to generate correct solutions to specific problems with higher probability. In this work, we introduce Flaming-hot Initiation with Regular Execution (FIRE) sampling, a simple yet highly effective method to efficiently find good responses. Our empirical findings show that FIRE sampling enhances inference-time generation quality and also benefits training in the alignment stage. Furthermore, we explore how FIRE sampling improves performance by promoting diversity and analyze the impact of employing FIRE at different positions within a response.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.21236v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weizhe Chen, Zhicheng Zhang, Guanlin Liu, Renjie Zheng, Wenlei Shi, Chen Dun, Zheng Wu, Xing Jin, Lin Yan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Graph's Apprentice: Teaching an LLM Low Level Knowledge for Circuit Quality Estimation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.00843</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.00843v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Logic synthesis is a crucial phase in the circuit design process, responsible for transforming hardware description language (HDL) designs into optimized netlists. However, traditional logic synthesis methods are computationally intensive, restricting their iterative use in refining chip designs. Recent advancements in large language models (LLMs), particularly those fine-tuned on programming languages, present a promising alternative. This work proposes augmenting LLMs with predictor networks trained to estimate circuit quality directly from HDL code. To enhance performance, the model is regularized using embeddings from graph neural networks (GNNs) trained on Look-Up Table (LUT) graphs, thereby incorporating lower-level circuit insights. The proposed method demonstrates superior performance compared to existing graph-based RTL-level estimation techniques on the established benchmark OpenABCD, while providing instant feedback on HDL code quality.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.00843v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.AR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Reza Moravej, Saurabh Bodhe, Zhanguang Zhang, Didier Chetelat, Dimitrios Tsaras, Yingxue Zhang, Hui-Ling Zhen, Jianye Hao, Mingxuan Yuan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SequentialBreak: Large Language Models Can be Fooled by Embedding Jailbreak Prompts into Sequential Prompt Chains</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.06426</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.06426v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: As the integration of the Large Language Models (LLMs) into various applications increases, so does their susceptibility to misuse, raising significant security concerns. Numerous jailbreak attacks have been proposed to assess the security defense of LLMs. Current jailbreak attacks mainly rely on scenario camouflage, prompt obfuscation, prompt optimization, and prompt iterative optimization to conceal malicious prompts. In particular, sequential prompt chains in a single query can lead LLMs to focus on certain prompts while ignoring others, facilitating context manipulation. This paper introduces SequentialBreak, a novel jailbreak attack that exploits this vulnerability. We discuss several scenarios, not limited to examples like Question Bank, Dialog Completion, and Game Environment, where the harmful prompt is embedded within benign ones that can fool LLMs into generating harmful responses. The distinct narrative structures of these scenarios show that SequentialBreak is flexible enough to adapt to various prompt formats beyond those discussed. Extensive experiments demonstrate that SequentialBreak uses only a single query to achieve a substantial gain of attack success rate over existing baselines against both open-source and closed-source models. Through our research, we highlight the urgent need for more robust and resilient safeguards to enhance LLM security and prevent potential misuse. All the result files and website associated with this research are available in this GitHub repository: https://anonymous.4open.science/r/JailBreakAttack-4F3B/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.06426v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bijoy Ahmed Saiem, MD Sadik Hossain Shanto, Rakib Ahsan, Md Rafi ur Rashid</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism and Emergence of Stacked Attention Heads in Multi-Layer Transformers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.12118</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.12118v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In this paper, I introduce the retrieval problem, a simple yet common reasoning task that can be solved only by transformers with a minimum number of layers, which grows logarithmically with the input size. I empirically show that large language models can solve the task under different prompting formulations without any fine-tuning. To understand how transformers solve the retrieval problem, I train several transformers on a minimal formulation. Successful learning occurs only under the presence of an implicit curriculum. I uncover the learned mechanisms by studying the attention maps in the trained transformers. I also study the training process, uncovering that attention heads always emerge in a specific sequence guided by the implicit curriculum.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.12118v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tiberiu Musat</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing and Boosting the Power of Fine-Grained Visual Recognition for Multi-modal Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.15140</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.15140v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Multi-modal large language models (MLLMs) have shown remarkable abilities in various visual understanding tasks. However, MLLMs still struggle with fine-grained visual recognition (FGVR), which aims to identify subordinate-level categories from images. This can negatively impact more advanced capabilities of MLLMs, such as object-centric visual question answering and reasoning. In our study, we revisit three quintessential capabilities of MLLMs for FGVR, including object information extraction, category knowledge reserve, object-category alignment, and position of the root cause as a misalignment problem. To address this issue, we present Finedefics, an MLLM that enhances the model's FGVR capability by incorporating informative attribute descriptions of objects into the training phase. We employ contrastive learning on object-attribute pairs and attribute-category pairs simultaneously and use examples from similar but incorrect categories as hard negatives, naturally bringing representations of visual objects and category names closer. Extensive evaluations across multiple popular FGVR datasets demonstrate that Finedefics outperforms existing MLLMs of comparable parameter sizes, showcasing its remarkable efficacy. The code is available at https://github.com/PKU-ICST-MIPL/Finedefics_ICLR2025.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.15140v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hulingxiao He, Geng Li, Zijun Geng, Jinglin Xu, Yuxin Peng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DiTAR: Diffusion Transformer Autoregressive Modeling for Speech Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.03930</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.03930v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Several recent studies have attempted to autoregressively generate continuous speech representations without discrete speech tokens by combining diffusion and autoregressive models, yet they often face challenges with excessive computational loads or suboptimal outcomes. In this work, we propose Diffusion Transformer Autoregressive Modeling (DiTAR), a patch-based autoregressive framework combining a language model with a diffusion transformer. This approach significantly enhances the efficacy of autoregressive models for continuous tokens and reduces computational demands. DiTAR utilizes a divide-and-conquer strategy for patch generation, where the language model processes aggregated patch embeddings and the diffusion transformer subsequently generates the next patch based on the output of the language model. For inference, we propose defining temperature as the time point of introducing noise during the reverse diffusion ODE to balance diversity and determinism. We also show in the extensive scaling analysis that DiTAR has superb scalability. In zero-shot speech generation, DiTAR achieves state-of-the-art performance in robustness, speaker similarity, and naturalness.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.03930v2</guid>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dongya Jia, Zhuo Chen, Jiawei Chen, Chenpeng Du, Jian Wu, Jian Cong, Xiaobin Zhuang, Chumin Li, Zhen Wei, Yuping Wang, Yuxuan Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 2021 Tokyo Olympics Multilingual News Article Dataset</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.06648</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.06648v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In this paper, we introduce a dataset of multilingual news articles covering the 2021 Tokyo Olympics. A total of 10,940 news articles were gathered from 1,918 different publishers, covering 1,350 sub-events of the 2021 Olympics, and published between July 1, 2021, and August 14, 2021. These articles are written in nine languages from different language families and in different scripts. To create the dataset, the raw news articles were first retrieved via a service that collects and analyzes news articles. Then, the articles were grouped using an online clustering algorithm, with each group containing articles reporting on the same sub-event. Finally, the groups were manually annotated and evaluated. The development of this dataset aims to provide a resource for evaluating the performance of multilingual news clustering algorithms, for which limited datasets are available. It can also be used to analyze the dynamics and events of the 2021 Tokyo Olympics from different perspectives. The dataset is available in CSV format and can be accessed from the CLARIN.SI repository.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.06648v2</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Erik Novak, Erik Calcina, Dunja Mladeni\'c, Marko Grobelnik</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EnigmaEval: A Benchmark of Long Multimodal Reasoning Challenges</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.08859</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.08859v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: As language models master existing reasoning benchmarks, we need new challenges to evaluate their cognitive frontiers. Puzzle-solving events are rich repositories of challenging multimodal problems that test a wide range of advanced reasoning and knowledge capabilities, making them a unique testbed for evaluating frontier language models. We introduce EnigmaEval, a dataset of problems and solutions derived from puzzle competitions and events that probes models' ability to perform implicit knowledge synthesis and multi-step deductive reasoning. Unlike existing reasoning and knowledge benchmarks, puzzle solving challenges models to discover hidden connections between seemingly unrelated pieces of information to uncover solution paths. The benchmark comprises 1184 puzzles of varying complexity -- each typically requiring teams of skilled solvers hours to days to complete -- with unambiguous, verifiable solutions that enable efficient evaluation. State-of-the-art language models achieve extremely low accuracy on these puzzles, even lower than other difficult benchmarks such as Humanity's Last Exam, unveiling models' shortcomings when challenged with problems requiring unstructured and lateral reasoning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.08859v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Clinton J. Wang, Dean Lee, Cristina Menghini, Johannes Mols, Jack Doughty, Adam Khoja, Jayson Lynch, Sean Hendryx, Summer Yue, Dan Hendrycks</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing GPT for Video Understanding: Zero-Shot Performance and Prompt Engineering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09573</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09573v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In this study, we tackle industry challenges in video content classification by exploring and optimizing GPT-based models for zero-shot classification across seven critical categories of video quality. We contribute a novel approach to improving GPT's performance through prompt optimization and policy refinement, demonstrating that simplifying complex policies significantly reduces false negatives. Additionally, we introduce a new decomposition-aggregation-based prompt engineering technique, which outperforms traditional single-prompt methods. These experiments, conducted on real industry problems, show that thoughtful prompt design can substantially enhance GPT's performance without additional finetuning, offering an effective and scalable solution for improving video classification systems across various domains in industry.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09573v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mark Beliaev, Victor Yang, Madhura Raju, Jiachen Sun, Xinghai Hu</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
