<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL</link>
    <description>cs.CL updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 05:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Saturday</day>
      <day>Sunday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing AI Safety Through the Fusion of Low Rank Adapters</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06208</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06208v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Instruction fine-tuning of large language models (LLMs) is a powerful method for improving task-specific performance, but it can inadvertently lead to a phenomenon where models generate harmful responses when faced with malicious prompts. In this paper, we explore Low-Rank Adapter Fusion (LoRA) as a means to mitigate these risks while preserving the model's ability to handle diverse instructions effectively. Through an extensive comparative analysis against established baselines using recognized benchmark datasets, we demonstrate a 42\% reduction in the harmfulness rate by leveraging LoRA fusion between a task adapter and a safety adapter, the latter of which is specifically trained on our safety dataset. However, we also observe exaggerated safety behaviour, where the model rejects safe prompts that closely resemble unsafe ones</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06208v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Satya Swaroop Gudipudi, Sreeram Vipparla, Harpreet Singh, Shashwat Goel, Ponnurangam Kumaraguru</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Applications of natural language processing in aviation safety: A review and qualitative analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06210</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06210v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This study explores using Natural Language Processing in aviation safety, focusing on machine learning algorithms to enhance safety measures. There are currently May 2024, 34 Scopus results from the keyword search natural language processing and aviation safety. Analyzing these studies allows us to uncover trends in the methodologies, findings and implications of NLP in aviation. Both qualitative and quantitative tools have been used to investigate the current state of literature on NLP for aviation safety. The qualitative analysis summarises the research motivations, objectives, and outcomes, showing how NLP can be utilized to help identify critical safety issues and improve aviation safety. This study also identifies research gaps and suggests areas for future exploration, providing practical recommendations for the aviation industry. We discuss challenges in implementing NLP in aviation safety, such as the need for large, annotated datasets, and the difficulty in interpreting complex models. We propose solutions like active learning for data annotation and explainable AI for model interpretation. Case studies demonstrate the successful application of NLP in improving aviation safety, highlighting its potential to make aviation safer and more efficient.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06210v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aziida Nanyonga, Keith Joiner, Ugur Turhan, Graham Wild</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FLAME: Financial Large-Language Model Assessment and Metrics Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06211</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06211v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: LLMs have revolutionized NLP and demonstrated potential across diverse domains. More and more financial LLMs have been introduced for finance-specific tasks, yet comprehensively assessing their value is still challenging. In this paper, we introduce FLAME, a comprehensive financial LLMs evaluation system in Chinese, which includes two core evaluation benchmarks: FLAME-Cer and FLAME-Sce. FLAME-Cer covers 14 types of authoritative financial certifications, including CPA, CFA, and FRM, with a total of approximately 16,000 carefully selected questions. All questions have been manually reviewed to ensure accuracy and representativeness. FLAME-Sce consists of 10 primary core financial business scenarios, 21 secondary financial business scenarios, and a comprehensive evaluation set of nearly 100 tertiary financial application tasks. We evaluate 6 representative LLMs, including GPT-4o, GLM-4, ERNIE-4.0, Qwen2.5, XuanYuan3, and the latest Baichuan4-Finance, revealing Baichuan4-Finance excels other LLMs in most tasks. By establishing a comprehensive and professional evaluation system, FLAME facilitates the advancement of financial LLMs in Chinese contexts. Instructions for participating in the evaluation are available on GitHub: https://github.com/FLAME-ruc/FLAME.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06211v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CE</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiayu Guo, Yu Guo, Martha Li, Songtao Tan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A partition cover approach to tokenization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06246</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06246v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Tokenization is the process of encoding strings into tokens from a fixed vocabulary of size $k$ and is widely utilized in Natural Language Processing applications. The leading tokenization algorithm today is Byte Pair Encoding (BPE), which formulates the tokenization problem as a compression problem and tackles it by performing sequences of merges. In this work, we formulate tokenization as an optimization objective, show that it is NP-hard via a simple reduction from vertex cover, and propose a polynomial-time greedy algorithm GreedTok. Our formulation naturally relaxes to the well-studied weighted maximum coverage problem which has a simple $(1 - 1/e)$-approximation algorithm GreedWMC. Through empirical evaluations on real-world corpora, we show that GreedTok outperforms BPE, while achieving a comparable objective score as GreedWMC (which could have achieved a higher score due to relaxation).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06246v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.DS</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jia Peng Lim, Davin Choo, Hady W. Lauw</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Evaluation of Sparse Autoencoders through the Representation of Polysemous Words</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06254</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06254v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Sparse autoencoders (SAEs) have gained a lot of attention as a promising tool to improve the interpretability of large language models (LLMs) by mapping the complex superposition of polysemantic neurons into monosemantic features and composing a sparse dictionary of words. However, traditional performance metrics like Mean Squared Error and L0 sparsity ignore the evaluation of the semantic representational power of SAEs -- whether they can acquire interpretable monosemantic features while preserving the semantic relationship of words. For instance, it is not obvious whether a learned sparse feature could distinguish different meanings in one word. In this paper, we propose a suite of evaluations for SAEs to analyze the quality of monosemantic features by focusing on polysemous words. Our findings reveal that SAEs developed to improve the MSE-L0 Pareto frontier may confuse interpretability, which does not necessarily enhance the extraction of monosemantic features. The analysis of SAEs with polysemous words can also figure out the internal mechanism of LLMs; deeper layers and the Attention module contribute to distinguishing polysemy in a word. Our semantics focused evaluation offers new insights into the polysemy and the existing SAE objective and contributes to the development of more practical SAEs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06254v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gouki Minegishi, Hiroki Furuta, Yusuke Iwasawa, Yutaka Matsuo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Matters for In-Context Learning: A Balancing Act of Look-up and In-Weight Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06256</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06256v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated impressive performance in various tasks, including In-Context Learning (ICL), where the model performs new tasks by conditioning solely on the examples provided in the context, without updating the model's weights. While prior research has explored the roles of pretraining data and model architecture, the key mechanism behind ICL remains unclear. In this work, we systematically uncover properties present in LLMs that support the emergence of ICL. To disambiguate these factors, we conduct a study with a controlled dataset and data sequences using a deep autoregressive model. We show that conceptual repetitions in the data sequences are crucial for ICL, more so than previously indicated training data properties like burstiness or long-tail distribution. Conceptual repetitions could refer to $n$-gram repetitions in textual data or exact image copies in image sequence data. Such repetitions also offer other previously overlooked benefits such as reduced transiency in ICL performance. Furthermore, we show that the emergence of ICL depends on balancing the in-weight learning objective with the in-context solving ability during training.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06256v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jelena Bratuli\'c, Sudhanshu Mittal, Christian Rupprecht, Thomas Brox</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AgoraSpeech: A multi-annotated comprehensive dataset of political discourse through the lens of humans and AI</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06265</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06265v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Political discourse datasets are important for gaining political insights, analyzing communication strategies or social science phenomena. Although numerous political discourse corpora exist, comprehensive, high-quality, annotated datasets are scarce. This is largely due to the substantial manual effort, multidisciplinarity, and expertise required for the nuanced annotation of rhetorical strategies and ideological contexts. In this paper, we present AgoraSpeech, a meticulously curated, high-quality dataset of 171 political speeches from six parties during the Greek national elections in 2023. The dataset includes annotations (per paragraph) for six natural language processing (NLP) tasks: text classification, topic identification, sentiment analysis, named entity recognition, polarization and populism detection. A two-step annotation was employed, starting with ChatGPT-generated annotations and followed by exhaustive human-in-the-loop validation. The dataset was initially used in a case study to provide insights during the pre-election period. However, it has general applicability by serving as a rich source of information for political and social scientists, journalists, or data scientists, while it can be used for benchmarking and fine-tuning NLP and large language models (LLMs).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06265v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Pavlos Sermpezis, Stelios Karamanidis, Eva Paraschou, Ilias Dimitriadis, Sofia Yfantidou, Filitsa-Ioanna Kouskouveli, Thanasis Troboukis, Kelly Kiki, Antonis Galanopoulos, Athena Vakali</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Environmental large language model Evaluation (ELLE) dataset: A Benchmark for Evaluating Generative AI applications in Eco-environment Domain</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06277</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06277v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Generative AI holds significant potential for ecological and environmental applications such as monitoring, data analysis, education, and policy support. However, its effectiveness is limited by the lack of a unified evaluation framework. To address this, we present the Environmental Large Language model Evaluation (ELLE) question answer (QA) dataset, the first benchmark designed to assess large language models and their applications in ecological and environmental sciences. The ELLE dataset includes 1,130 question answer pairs across 16 environmental topics, categorized by domain, difficulty, and type. This comprehensive dataset standardizes performance assessments in these fields, enabling consistent and objective comparisons of generative AI performance. By providing a dedicated evaluation tool, ELLE dataset promotes the development and application of generative AI technologies for sustainable environmental outcomes. The dataset and code are available at https://elle.ceeai.net/ and https://github.com/CEEAI/elle.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06277v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jing Guo, Nan Li, Ming Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Punctuation's Semantic Role between Brain and Transformers Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06278</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06278v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Contemporary neural networks intended for natural language processing (NLP) are not designed with specific linguistic rules. It suggests that they may acquire a general understanding of language. This attribute has led to extensive research in deciphering their internal representations. A pioneering method involves an experimental setup using human brain data to explore if a translation between brain and neural network representations can be established. Since this technique emerged, more sophisticated NLP models have been developed. In our study, we apply this method to evaluate four new NLP models aiming to identify the one most compatible with brain activity. Additionally, to explore how the brain comprehends text semantically, we alter the text by removing punctuation in four different ways to understand its impact on semantic processing by the human brain. Our findings indicate that the RoBERTa model aligns best with brain activity, outperforming BERT in accuracy according to our metrics. Furthermore, for BERT, higher accuracy was noted when punctuation was excluded, and increased context length did not significantly diminish accuracy compared to the original results with punctuation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06278v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zenon Lamprou, Frank Polick, Yashar Moshfeghi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MinMo: A Multimodal Large Language Model for Seamless Voice Interaction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06282</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06282v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent advancements in large language models (LLMs) and multimodal speech-text models have laid the groundwork for seamless voice interactions, enabling real-time, natural, and human-like conversations. Previous models for voice interactions are categorized as native and aligned. Native models integrate speech and text processing in one framework but struggle with issues like differing sequence lengths and insufficient pre-training. Aligned models maintain text LLM capabilities but are often limited by small datasets and a narrow focus on speech tasks. In this work, we introduce MinMo, a Multimodal Large Language Model with approximately 8B parameters for seamless voice interaction. We address the main limitations of prior aligned multimodal models. We train MinMo through multiple stages of speech-to-text alignment, text-to-speech alignment, speech-to-speech alignment, and duplex interaction alignment, on 1.4 million hours of diverse speech data and a broad range of speech tasks. After the multi-stage training, MinMo achieves state-of-the-art performance across various benchmarks for voice comprehension and generation while maintaining the capabilities of text LLMs, and also facilitates full-duplex conversation, that is, simultaneous two-way communication between the user and the system. Moreover, we propose a novel and simple voice decoder that outperforms prior models in voice generation. The enhanced instruction-following capabilities of MinMo supports controlling speech generation based on user instructions, with various nuances including emotions, dialects, and speaking rates, and mimicking specific voices. For MinMo, the speech-to-text latency is approximately 100ms, full-duplex latency is approximately 600ms in theory and 800ms in practice. The MinMo project web page is https://funaudiollm.github.io/minmo, and the code and models will be released soon.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06282v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qian Chen, Yafeng Chen, Yanni Chen, Mengzhe Chen, Yingda Chen, Chong Deng, Zhihao Du, Ruize Gao, Changfeng Gao, Zhifu Gao, Yabin Li, Xiang Lv, Jiaqing Liu, Haoneng Luo, Bin Ma, Chongjia Ni, Xian Shi, Jialong Tang, Hui Wang, Hao Wang, Wen Wang, Yuxuan Wang, Yunlan Xu, Fan Yu, Zhijie Yan, Yexin Yang, Baosong Yang, Xian Yang, Guanrou Yang, Tianyu Zhao, Qinglin Zhang, Shiliang Zhang, Nan Zhao, Pei Zhang, Chong Zhang, Jinren Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bactrainus: Optimizing Large Language Models for Multi-hop Complex Question Answering Tasks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06286</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06286v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In recent years, the use of large language models (LLMs) has significantly increased, and these models have demonstrated remarkable performance in a variety of general language tasks. However, the evaluation of their performance in domain-specific tasks, particularly those requiring deep natural language understanding, has received less attention. In this research, we evaluate the ability of large language models in performing domain-specific tasks, focusing on the multi-hop question answering (MHQA) problem using the HotpotQA dataset. This task, due to its requirement for reasoning and combining information from multiple textual sources, serves as a challenging benchmark for assessing the language comprehension capabilities of these models. To tackle this problem, we have designed a two-stage selector-reader architecture, where each stage utilizes an independent LLM. In addition, methods such as Chain of Thought (CoT) and question decomposition have been employed to investigate their impact on improving the model's performance. The results of the study show that the integration of large language models with these techniques can lead to up to a 4% improvement in F1 score for finding answers, providing evidence of the models' ability to handle domain-specific tasks and their understanding of complex language.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06286v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Iman Barati, Arash Ghafouri, Behrouz Minaei-Bidgoli</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Language Models Share Representations of Latent Grammatical Concepts Across Typologically Diverse Languages</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06346</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06346v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Human bilinguals often use similar brain regions to process multiple languages, depending on when they learned their second language and their proficiency. In large language models (LLMs), how are multiple languages learned and encoded? In this work, we explore the extent to which LLMs share representations of morphosyntactic concepts such as grammatical number, gender, and tense across languages. We train sparse autoencoders on Llama-3-8B and Aya-23-8B, and demonstrate that abstract grammatical concepts are often encoded in feature directions shared across many languages. We use causal interventions to verify the multilingual nature of these representations; specifically, we show that ablating only multilingual features decreases classifier performance to near-chance across languages. We then use these features to precisely modify model behavior in a machine translation task; this demonstrates both the generality and selectivity of these feature's roles in the network. Our findings suggest that even models trained predominantly on English data can develop robust, cross-lingual abstractions of morphosyntactic concepts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06346v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jannik Brinkmann, Chris Wendler, Christian Bartelt, Aaron Mueller</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gender-Neutral Large Language Models for Medical Applications: Reducing Bias in PubMed Abstracts</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06365</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06365v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper presents a pipeline for mitigating gender bias in large language models (LLMs) used in medical literature by neutralizing gendered occupational pronouns. A dataset of 379,000 PubMed abstracts from 1965-1980 was processed to identify and modify pronouns tied to professions. We developed a BERT-based model, ``Modern Occupational Bias Elimination with Refined Training,'' or ``MOBERT,'' trained on these neutralized abstracts, and compared its performance with ``1965Bert,'' trained on the original dataset. MOBERT achieved a 70\% inclusive replacement rate, while 1965Bert reached only 4\%. A further analysis of MOBERT revealed that pronoun replacement accuracy correlated with the frequency of occupational terms in the training data. We propose expanding the dataset and refining the pipeline to improve performance and ensure more equitable language modeling in medical applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06365v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Elizabeth Schaefer, Kirk Roberts</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AFRIDOC-MT: Document-level MT Corpus for African Languages</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06374</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06374v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper introduces AFRIDOC-MT, a document-level multi-parallel translation dataset covering English and five African languages: Amharic, Hausa, Swahili, Yor\`ub\'a, and Zulu. The dataset comprises 334 health and 271 information technology news documents, all human-translated from English to these languages. We conduct document-level translation benchmark experiments by evaluating neural machine translation (NMT) models and large language models (LLMs) for translations between English and these languages, at both the sentence and pseudo-document levels. These outputs are realigned to form complete documents for evaluation. Our results indicate that NLLB-200 achieved the best average performance among the standard NMT models, while GPT-4o outperformed general-purpose LLMs. Fine-tuning selected models led to substantial performance gains, but models trained on sentences struggled to generalize effectively to longer documents. Furthermore, our analysis reveals that some LLMs exhibit issues such as under-generation, repetition of words or phrases, and off-target translations, especially for African languages.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06374v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jesujoba O. Alabi, Israel Abebe Azime, Miaoran Zhang, Cristina Espa\~na-Bonet, Rachel Bawden, Dawei Zhu, David Ifeoluwa Adelani, Clement Oyeleke Odoje, Idris Akinade, Iffat Maab, Davis David, Shamsuddeen Hassan Muhammad, Neo Putini, David O. Ademuyiwa, Andrew Caines, Dietrich Klakow</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamics of "Spontaneous" Topic Changes in Next Token Prediction with Self-Attention</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06382</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06382v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Human cognition can spontaneously shift conversation topics, often triggered by emotional or contextual signals. In contrast, self-attention-based language models depend on structured statistical cues from input tokens for next-token prediction, lacking this spontaneity. Motivated by this distinction, we investigate the factors that influence the next-token prediction to change the topic of the input sequence. We define concepts of topic continuity, ambiguous sequences, and change of topic, based on defining a topic as a set of token priority graphs (TPGs). Using a simplified single-layer self-attention architecture, we derive analytical characterizations of topic changes. Specifically, we demonstrate that (1) the model maintains the priority order of tokens related to the input topic, (2) a topic change occurs only if lower-priority tokens outnumber all higher-priority tokens of the input topic, and (3) unlike human cognition, longer context lengths and overlapping topics reduce the likelihood of spontaneous redirection. These insights highlight differences between human cognition and self-attention-based models in navigating topic changes and underscore the challenges in designing conversational AI capable of handling "spontaneous" conversations more naturally. To our knowledge, this is the first work to address these questions in such close relation to human conversation and thought.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06382v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mumin Jia, Jairo Diaz-Rodriguez</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tensor Product Attention Is All You Need</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06425</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06425v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Scaling language models to handle longer input sequences typically necessitates large key-value (KV) caches, resulting in substantial memory overhead during inference. In this paper, we propose Tensor Product Attention (TPA), a novel attention mechanism that uses tensor decompositions to represent queries, keys, and values compactly, significantly shrinking KV cache size at inference time. By factorizing these representations into contextual low-rank components (contextual factorization) and seamlessly integrating with RoPE, TPA achieves improved model quality alongside memory efficiency. Based on TPA, we introduce the Tensor ProducT ATTenTion Transformer (T6), a new model architecture for sequence modeling. Through extensive empirical evaluation of language modeling tasks, we demonstrate that T6 exceeds the performance of standard Transformer baselines including MHA, MQA, GQA, and MLA across various metrics, including perplexity and a range of renowned evaluation benchmarks. Notably, TPAs memory efficiency enables the processing of significantly longer sequences under fixed resource constraints, addressing a critical scalability challenge in modern language models. The code is available at https://github.com/tensorgi/T6.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06425v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yifan Zhang, Yifeng Liu, Huizhuo Yuan, Zhen Qin, Yang Yuan, Quanquan Gu, Andrew Chi-Chih Yao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthetic Feature Augmentation Improves Generalization Performance of Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06434</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06434v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Training and fine-tuning deep learning models, especially large language models (LLMs), on limited and imbalanced datasets poses substantial challenges. These issues often result in poor generalization, where models overfit to dominant classes and underperform on minority classes, leading to biased predictions and reduced robustness in real-world applications. To overcome these challenges, we propose augmenting features in the embedding space by generating synthetic samples using a range of techniques. By upsampling underrepresented classes, this method improves model performance and alleviates data imbalance. We validate the effectiveness of this approach across multiple open-source text classification benchmarks, demonstrating its potential to enhance model robustness and generalization in imbalanced data scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06434v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ashok Choudhary, Cornelius Thiels, Hojjat Salehinejad</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>O1 Replication Journey -- Part 3: Inference-time Scaling for Medical Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06458</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06458v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Building upon our previous investigations of O1 replication (Part 1: Journey Learning [Qin et al., 2024] and Part 2: Distillation [Huang et al., 2024]), this work explores the potential of inference-time scaling in large language models (LLMs) for medical reasoning tasks, ranging from diagnostic decision-making to treatment planning. Through extensive experiments on medical benchmarks of varying complexity (MedQA, Medbullets, and JAMA Clinical Challenges), our investigation reveals several key insights: (1) Increasing inference time does lead to improved performance. With a modest training set of 500 samples, our model yields substantial performance improvements of 6%-11%. (2) Task complexity directly correlates with the required length of reasoning chains, confirming the necessity of extended thought processes for challenging problems. (3) The differential diagnoses generated by our model adhere to the principles of the hypothetico-deductive method, producing a list of potential conditions that may explain a patient's symptoms and systematically narrowing these possibilities by evaluating the evidence. These findings demonstrate the promising synergy between inference-time scaling and journey learning in advancing LLMs' real-world clinical reasoning capabilities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06458v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhongzhen Huang, Gui Geng, Shengyi Hua, Zhen Huang, Haoyang Zou, Shaoting Zhang, Pengfei Liu, Xiaofan Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MedCT: A Clinical Terminology Graph for Generative AI Applications in Healthcare</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06465</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06465v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We introduce the world's first clinical terminology for the Chinese healthcare community, namely MedCT, accompanied by a clinical foundation model MedBERT and an entity linking model MedLink. The MedCT system enables standardized and programmable representation of Chinese clinical data, successively stimulating the development of new medicines, treatment pathways, and better patient outcomes for the populous Chinese community. Moreover, the MedCT knowledge graph provides a principled mechanism to minimize the hallucination problem of large language models (LLMs), therefore achieving significant levels of accuracy and safety in LLM-based clinical applications. By leveraging the LLMs' emergent capabilities of generativeness and expressiveness, we were able to rapidly built a production-quality terminology system and deployed to real-world clinical field within three months, while classical terminologies like SNOMED CT have gone through more than twenty years development. Our experiments show that the MedCT system achieves state-of-the-art (SOTA) performance in semantic matching and entity linking tasks, not only for Chinese but also for English. We also conducted a longitudinal field experiment by applying MedCT and LLMs in a representative spectrum of clinical tasks, including electronic health record (EHR) auto-generation and medical document search for diagnostic decision making. Our study shows a multitude of values of MedCT for clinical workflows and patient outcomes, especially in the new genre of clinical LLM applications. We present our approach in sufficient engineering detail, such that implementing a clinical terminology for other non-English societies should be readily reproducible. We openly release our terminology, models and algorithms, along with real-world clinical datasets for the development.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06465v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ye Chen, Dongdong Huang, Haoyun Xu, Cong Fu, Lin Sheng, Qingli Zhou, Yuqiang Shen, Kai Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retrieval-Augmented Dialogue Knowledge Aggregation for Expressive Conversational Speech Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06467</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06467v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Conversational speech synthesis (CSS) aims to take the current dialogue (CD) history as a reference to synthesize expressive speech that aligns with the conversational style. Unlike CD, stored dialogue (SD) contains preserved dialogue fragments from earlier stages of user-agent interaction, which include style expression knowledge relevant to scenarios similar to those in CD. Note that this knowledge plays a significant role in enabling the agent to synthesize expressive conversational speech that generates empathetic feedback. However, prior research has overlooked this aspect. To address this issue, we propose a novel Retrieval-Augmented Dialogue Knowledge Aggregation scheme for expressive CSS, termed RADKA-CSS, which includes three main components: 1) To effectively retrieve dialogues from SD that are similar to CD in terms of both semantic and style. First, we build a stored dialogue semantic-style database (SDSSD) which includes the text and audio samples. Then, we design a multi-attribute retrieval scheme to match the dialogue semantic and style vectors of the CD with the stored dialogue semantic and style vectors in the SDSSD, retrieving the most similar dialogues. 2) To effectively utilize the style knowledge from CD and SD, we propose adopting the multi-granularity graph structure to encode the dialogue and introducing a multi-source style knowledge aggregation mechanism. 3) Finally, the aggregated style knowledge are fed into the speech synthesizer to help the agent synthesize expressive speech that aligns with the conversational style. We conducted a comprehensive and in-depth experiment based on the DailyTalk dataset, which is a benchmarking dataset for the CSS task.
  Both objective and subjective evaluations demonstrate that RADKA-CSS outperforms baseline models in expressiveness rendering. Code and audio samples can be found at: https://github.com/Coder-jzq/RADKA-CSS.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06467v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rui Liu, Zhenqi Jia, Feilong Bao, Haizhou Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Token Probability Guided RAG for Telecom Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06468</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06468v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have garnered significant attention for their impressive general-purpose capabilities. For applications requiring intricate domain knowledge, Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) has shown a distinct advantage in incorporating domain-specific information into LLMs. However, existing RAG research has not fully addressed the challenges of Multiple Choice Question Answering (MCQA) in telecommunications, particularly in terms of retrieval quality and mitigating hallucinations. To tackle these challenges, we propose a novel first token probability guided RAG framework. This framework leverages confidence scores to optimize key hyperparameters, such as chunk number and chunk window size, while dynamically adjusting the context. Our method starts by retrieving the most relevant chunks and generates a single token as the potential answer. The probabilities of all options are then normalized to serve as confidence scores, which guide the dynamic adjustment of the context. By iteratively optimizing the hyperparameters based on these confidence scores, we can continuously improve RAG performance. We conducted experiments to validate the effectiveness of our framework, demonstrating its potential to enhance accuracy in domain-specific MCQA tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06468v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tingwei Chen, Jiayi Chen, Zijian Zhao, Haolong Chen, Liang Zhang, Guangxu Zhu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sequential Classification of Aviation Safety Occurrences with Natural Language Processing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06490</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06490v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Safety is a critical aspect of the air transport system given even slight operational anomalies can result in serious consequences. To reduce the chances of aviation safety occurrences, accidents and incidents are reported to establish the root cause, propose safety recommendations etc. However, analysis narratives of the pre-accident events are presented using human-understandable, raw, unstructured, text that a computer system cannot understand. The ability to classify and categorise safety occurrences from their textual narratives would help aviation industry stakeholders make informed safety-critical decisions. To classify and categorise safety occurrences, we applied natural language processing (NLP) and AI (Artificial Intelligence) models to process text narratives. The study aimed to answer the question. How well can the damage level caused to the aircraft in a safety occurrence be inferred from the text narrative using natural language processing. The classification performance of various deep learning models including LSTM, BLSTM, GRU, sRNN, and combinations of these models including LSTM and GRU, BLSTM+GRU, sRNN and LSTM, sRNN and BLSTM, sRNN and GRU, sRNN and BLSTM and GRU, and sRNN and LSTM and GRU was evaluated on a set of 27,000 safety occurrence reports from the NTSB. The results of this study indicate that all models investigated performed competitively well recording an accuracy of over 87.9% which is well above the random guess of 25% for a four-class classification problem. Also, the models recorded high precision, recall, and F1 scores above 80%, 88%, and 85%, respectively. sRNN slightly outperformed other single models in terms of recall (90%) and accuracy (90%) while LSTM reported slightly better performance in terms of precision (87%).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06490v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aziida Nanyonga, Hassan Wasswa, Ugur Turhan, Oleksandra Molloy, Graham Wild</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing the Role of Context in Forecasting with Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06496</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06496v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This study evaluates the forecasting performance of recent language models (LLMs) on binary forecasting questions. We first introduce a novel dataset of over 600 binary forecasting questions, augmented with related news articles and their concise question-related summaries. We then explore the impact of input prompts with varying level of context on forecasting performance. The results indicate that incorporating news articles significantly improves performance, while using few-shot examples leads to a decline in accuracy. We find that larger models consistently outperform smaller models, highlighting the potential of LLMs in enhancing automated forecasting.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06496v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gerrit Mutschlechner, Adam Jatowt</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PASS: Presentation Automation for Slide Generation and Speech</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06497</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06497v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In today's fast-paced world, effective presentations have become an essential tool for communication in both online and offline meetings. The crafting of a compelling presentation requires significant time and effort, from gathering key insights to designing slides that convey information clearly and concisely. However, despite the wealth of resources available, people often find themselves manually extracting crucial points, analyzing data, and organizing content in a way that ensures clarity and impact. Furthermore, a successful presentation goes beyond just the slides; it demands rehearsal and the ability to weave a captivating narrative to fully engage the audience. Although there has been some exploration of automating document-to-slide generation, existing research is largely centered on converting research papers. In addition, automation of the delivery of these presentations has yet to be addressed. We introduce PASS, a pipeline used to generate slides from general Word documents, going beyond just research papers, which also automates the oral delivery of the generated slides. PASS analyzes user documents to create a dynamic, engaging presentation with an AI-generated voice. Additionally, we developed an LLM-based evaluation metric to assess our pipeline across three critical dimensions of presentations: relevance, coherence, and redundancy. The data and codes are available at https://github.com/AggarwalTushar/PASS.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06497v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tushar Aggarwal, Aarohi Bhand</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tuning Large Language Models for Improving Factuality in Legal Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06521</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06521v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Hallucination, or the generation of incorrect or fabricated information, remains a critical challenge in large language models (LLMs), particularly in high-stake domains such as legal question answering (QA). In order to mitigate the hallucination rate in legal QA, we first introduce a benchmark called LegalHalBench and three automatic metrics to evaluate the common hallucinations when LLMs answer legal questions. We then propose a hallucination mitigation method that integrates behavior cloning and a novel Hard Sample-aware Iterative Direct Preference Optimization (HIPO). We conduct extensive real-data experiments to validate the effectiveness of our approach. Our results demonstrate remarkable improvements in various metrics, including the newly proposed Non-Hallucinated Statute Rate, Statute Relevance Rate, Legal Claim Truthfulness, as well as traditional metrics such as METEOR, BERTScore, ROUGE-L, and win rates.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06521v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yinghao Hu, Leilei Gan, Wenyi Xiao, Kun Kuang, Fei Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dispersion Measures as Predictors of Lexical Decision Time, Word Familiarity, and Lexical Complexity</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06536</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06536v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Various measures of dispersion have been proposed to paint a fuller picture of a word's distribution in a corpus, but only little has been done to validate them externally. We evaluate a wide range of dispersion measures as predictors of lexical decision time, word familiarity, and lexical complexity in five diverse languages. We find that the logarithm of range is not only a better predictor than log-frequency across all tasks and languages, but that it is also the most powerful additional variable to log-frequency, consistently outperforming the more complex dispersion measures. We discuss the effects of corpus part granularity and logarithmic transformation, shedding light on contradictory results of previous studies.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06536v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Adam Nohejl, Taro Watanabe</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Survey on Spoken Italian Datasets and Corpora</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06557</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06557v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Spoken language datasets are vital for advancing linguistic research, Natural Language Processing, and speech technology. However, resources dedicated to Italian, a linguistically rich and diverse Romance language, remain underexplored compared to major languages like English or Mandarin. This survey provides a comprehensive analysis of 66 spoken Italian datasets, highlighting their characteristics, methodologies, and applications. The datasets are categorized by speech type, source and context, and demographic and linguistic features, with a focus on their utility in fields such as Automatic Speech Recognition, emotion detection, and education. Challenges related to dataset scarcity, representativeness, and accessibility are discussed alongside recommendations for enhancing dataset creation and utilization. The full dataset inventory is publicly accessible via GitHub and archived on Zenodo, serving as a valuable resource for researchers and developers. By addressing current gaps and proposing future directions, this work aims to support the advancement of Italian speech technologies and linguistic research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06557v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.DL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Marco Giordano, Claudia Rinaldi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Natural Language Processing and Deep Learning Models to Classify Phase of Flight in Aviation Safety Occurrences</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06564</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06564v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The air transport system recognizes the criticality of safety, as even minor anomalies can have severe consequences. Reporting accidents and incidents play a vital role in identifying their causes and proposing safety recommendations. However, the narratives describing pre-accident events are presented in unstructured text that is not easily understood by computer systems. Classifying and categorizing safety occurrences based on these narratives can support informed decision-making by aviation industry stakeholders. In this study, researchers applied natural language processing (NLP) and artificial intelligence (AI) models to process text narratives to classify the flight phases of safety occurrences. The classification performance of two deep learning models, ResNet and sRNN was evaluated, using an initial dataset of 27,000 safety occurrence reports from the NTSB. The results demonstrated good performance, with both models achieving an accuracy exceeding 68%, well above the random guess rate of 14% for a seven-class classification problem. The models also exhibited high precision, recall, and F1 scores. The sRNN model greatly outperformed the simplified ResNet model architecture used in this study. These findings indicate that NLP and deep learning models can infer the flight phase from raw text narratives, enabling effective analysis of safety occurrences.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06564v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aziida Nanyonga, Hassan Wasswa, Oleksandra Molloy, Ugur Turhan, Graham Wild</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ACORD: An Expert-Annotated Retrieval Dataset for Legal Contract Drafting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06582</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06582v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Information retrieval, specifically contract clause retrieval, is foundational to contract drafting because lawyers rarely draft contracts from scratch; instead, they locate and revise the most relevant precedent. We introduce the Atticus Clause Retrieval Dataset (ACORD), the first retrieval benchmark for contract drafting fully annotated by experts. ACORD focuses on complex contract clauses such as Limitation of Liability, Indemnification, Change of Control, and Most Favored Nation. It includes 114 queries and over 126,000 query-clause pairs, each ranked on a scale from 1 to 5 stars. The task is to find the most relevant precedent clauses to a query. The bi-encoder retriever paired with pointwise LLMs re-rankers shows promising results. However, substantial improvements are still needed to effectively manage the complex legal work typically undertaken by lawyers. As the first retrieval benchmark for contract drafting annotated by experts, ACORD can serve as a valuable IR benchmark for the NLP community.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06582v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Steven H. Wang, Maksim Zubkov, Kexin Fan, Sarah Harrell, Yuyang Sun, Wei Chen, Andreas Plesner, Roger Wattenhofer</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChemAgent: Self-updating Library in Large Language Models Improves Chemical Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06590</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06590v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Chemical reasoning usually involves complex, multi-step processes that demand precise calculations, where even minor errors can lead to cascading failures. Furthermore, large language models (LLMs) encounter difficulties handling domain-specific formulas, executing reasoning steps accurately, and integrating code effectively when tackling chemical reasoning tasks. To address these challenges, we present ChemAgent, a novel framework designed to improve the performance of LLMs through a dynamic, self-updating library. This library is developed by decomposing chemical tasks into sub-tasks and compiling these sub-tasks into a structured collection that can be referenced for future queries. Then, when presented with a new problem, ChemAgent retrieves and refines pertinent information from the library, which we call memory, facilitating effective task decomposition and the generation of solutions. Our method designs three types of memory and a library-enhanced reasoning component, enabling LLMs to improve over time through experience. Experimental results on four chemical reasoning datasets from SciBench demonstrate that ChemAgent achieves performance gains of up to 46% (GPT-4), significantly outperforming existing methods. Our findings suggest substantial potential for future applications, including tasks such as drug discovery and materials science. Our code can be found at https://github.com/gersteinlab/chemagent</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06590v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiangru Tang, Tianyu Hu, Muyang Ye, Yanjun Shao, Xunjian Yin, Siru Ouyang, Wangchunshu Zhou, Pan Lu, Zhuosheng Zhang, Yilun Zhao, Arman Cohan, Mark Gerstein</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual use issues in the field of Natural Language Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06636</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06636v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This report documents the results of a recent survey in the SIGGEN community, focusing on Dual Use issues in Natural Language Generation (NLG). SIGGEN is the Special Interest Group (SIG) of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL) for researchers working on NLG. The survey was prompted by the ACL executive board, which asked all SIGs to provide an overview of dual use issues within their respective subfields. The survey was sent out in October 2024 and the results were processed in January 2025. With 23 respondents, the survey is presumably not representative of all SIGGEN members, but at least this document offers a helpful resource for future discussions.
  This report is open to feedback from the SIGGEN community. Let me know if you have any questions or comments!</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06636v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Emiel van Miltenburg</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Down Semantic Leakage: Investigating Associative Bias in Smaller Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06638</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06638v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Semantic leakage is a phenomenon recently introduced by Gonen et al. (2024). It refers to a situation in which associations learnt from the training data emerge in language model generations in an unexpected and sometimes undesired way. Prior work has focused on leakage in large language models (7B+ parameters). In this study, I use Qwen2.5 model family to explore whether smaller models, ranging from 500M to 7B parameters, demonstrate less semantic leakage due to their limited capacity for capturing complex associations. Building on the previous dataset from Gonen et al. (2024), I introduce a new dataset of color-focused prompts, categorized into specific types of semantic associations, to systematically evaluate the models' performance. Results indicate that smaller models exhibit less semantic leakage overall, although this trend is not strictly linear, with medium-sized models sometimes surpassing larger ones in leaking behavior. The dataset, the model generations, and the evaluation code are publicly available at https://github.com/smilni/semantic_leakage_project.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06638v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Veronika Smilga</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FocalPO: Enhancing Preference Optimizing by Focusing on Correct Preference Rankings</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06645</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06645v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Efficient preference optimization algorithms such as Direct Preference Optimization (DPO) have become a popular approach in aligning large language models (LLMs) with human preferences. These algorithms implicitly treat the LLM as a reward model, and focus on training it to correct misranked preference pairs. However, recent work~\citep{chen2024preference} empirically finds that DPO training \textit{rarely improves these misranked preference pairs}, despite its gradient emphasizing on these cases. We introduce FocalPO, a DPO variant that instead \textit{down-weighs} misranked preference pairs and prioritizes enhancing the model's understanding of pairs that it can already rank correctly. Inspired by Focal Loss used in vision tasks, FocalPO achieves this by adding a modulating factor to dynamically scale DPO loss. Our experiment demonstrates that FocalPO surpasses DPO and its variants on popular benchmarks like Alpaca Eval 2.0 using Mistral-Base-7B and Llama-3-Instruct-8B. Additionally, we empirically reveals how FocalPO affects training on correct and incorrect sample groups, further underscoring its effectiveness.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06645v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tong Liu, Xiao Yu, Wenxuan Zhou, Jindong Gu, Volker Tresp</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TAPO: Task-Referenced Adaptation for Prompt Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06689</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06689v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Prompt engineering can significantly improve the performance of large language models (LLMs), with automated prompt optimization (APO) gaining significant attention due to the time-consuming and laborious nature of manual prompt design. However, much of the existing work in APO overlooks task-specific characteristics, resulting in prompts that lack domain specificity and are not well-suited for task-specific optimization. In this paper, we introduce TAPO, a multitask-aware prompt optimization framework composed of three key modules. First, a task-aware metric selection module is proposed to enhance task-specific prompt generation capabilities. Second, we present a multi-metrics evaluation module to jointly evaluate prompts from multiple perspectives. Third, an evolution-based optimization framework is introduced for automatic prompt refinement, which improves adaptability across various tasks. Extensive experiments on six datasets demonstrate the effectiveness of our approach, and our code is publicly available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06689v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenxin Luo, Weirui Wang, Xiaopeng Li, Weibo Zhou, Pengyue Jia, Xiangyu Zhao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ZNO-Eval: Benchmarking reasoning capabilities of large language models in Ukrainian</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06715</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06715v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: As the usage of large language models for problems outside of simple text understanding or generation increases, assessing their abilities and limitations becomes crucial. While significant progress has been made in this area over the last few years, most research has focused on benchmarking English, leaving other languages underexplored. This makes evaluating the reasoning and robustness level of language models in Ukrainian particularly challenging. The purpose of this work is to establish a comprehensive benchmark for the reasoning capabilities evaluation of large language models in the Ukrainian language. This paper presents the ZNO-Eval benchmark based on real exam tasks from Ukraine's standardized educational testing system: the External Independent Evaluation and the National Multi-subject Test. With single-answer options, multiple-choice, matching, and open-ended questions from diverse subjects, including Ukrainian language, mathematics, history, and geography, this dataset paves the way toward a thorough analysis of reasoning capabilities across different domains and complexities. Evaluation of several well-known language models, such as GPT-3.5-Turbo, GPT-4o, GPT-4-Turbo, Mistral Large, Claude 3 Opus, and Gemini-1.5 Pro on this benchmark demonstrated the superiority of GPT-4o in both common knowledge reasoning and intricate language tasks. At the same time, Gemini Pro and GPT-4 Turbo excelled in the arithmetic domain, leading in single-answer and open-ended math problems. While all models were close to max performance in text-only common knowledge tasks like history and geography, there still is a gap for Ukrainian language and math, thus highlighting the importance of developing specialized language benchmarks for more accurate assessments of model capabilities and limitations across different languages and contexts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06715v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.15276/ict.01.2024.27</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>X International conference "Informatics. Culture. Technology." (2024) 185-191</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Mykyta Syromiatnikov, Victoria Ruvinskaya, Anastasiya Troynina</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measuring the Robustness of Reference-Free Dialogue Evaluation Systems</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06728</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06728v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Advancements in dialogue systems powered by large language models (LLMs) have outpaced the development of reliable evaluation metrics, particularly for diverse and creative responses. We present a benchmark for evaluating the robustness of reference-free dialogue metrics against four categories of adversarial attacks: speaker tag prefixes, static responses, ungrammatical responses, and repeated conversational context. We analyze metrics such as DialogRPT, UniEval, and PromptEval -- a prompt-based method leveraging LLMs -- across grounded and ungrounded datasets. By examining both their correlation with human judgment and susceptibility to adversarial attacks, we find that these two axes are not always aligned; metrics that appear to be equivalent when judged by traditional benchmarks may, in fact, vary in their scores of adversarial responses. These findings motivate the development of nuanced evaluation frameworks to address real-world dialogue challenges.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06728v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Justin Vasselli, Adam Nohejl, Taro Watanabe</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Better Prompt Compression Without Multi-Layer Perceptrons</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06730</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06730v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Prompt compression is a promising approach to speeding up language model inference without altering the generative model. Prior works compress prompts into smaller sequences of learned tokens using an encoder that is trained as a LowRank Adaptation (LoRA) of the inference language model. However, we show that the encoder does not need to keep the original language model's architecture to achieve useful compression. We introduce the Attention-Only Compressor (AOC), which learns a prompt compression encoder after removing the multilayer perceptron (MLP) layers in the Transformer blocks of a language model, resulting in an encoder with roughly 67% less parameters compared to the original model. Intriguingly we find that, across a range of compression ratios up to 480x, AOC can better regenerate prompts and outperform a baseline compression encoder that is a LoRA of the inference language model without removing MLP layers. These results demonstrate that the architecture of prompt compression encoders does not need to be identical to that of the original decoder language model, paving the way for further research into architectures and approaches for prompt compression.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06730v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Edouardo Honig, Andrew Lizarraga, Zijun Frank Zhang, Ying Nian Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Divide-and-Conquer for Fine-Grained Alignment in LLM-Based Medical Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06741</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06741v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In the rapidly evolving landscape of large language models (LLMs) for medical applications, ensuring the reliability and accuracy of these models in clinical settings is paramount. Existing benchmarks often focus on fixed-format tasks like multiple-choice QA, which fail to capture the complexity of real-world clinical diagnostics. Moreover, traditional evaluation metrics and LLM-based evaluators struggle with misalignment, often providing oversimplified assessments that do not adequately reflect human judgment. To address these challenges, we introduce HDCEval, a Hierarchical Divide-and-Conquer Evaluation framework tailored for fine-grained alignment in medical evaluation. HDCEval is built on a set of fine-grained medical evaluation guidelines developed in collaboration with professional doctors, encompassing Patient Question Relevance, Medical Knowledge Correctness, and Expression. The framework decomposes complex evaluation tasks into specialized subtasks, each evaluated by expert models trained through Attribute-Driven Token Optimization (ADTO) on a meticulously curated preference dataset. This hierarchical approach ensures that each aspect of the evaluation is handled with expert precision, leading to a significant improvement in alignment with human evaluators.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06741v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shunfan Zheng, Xiechi Zhang, Gerard de Melo, Xiaoling Wang, Linlin Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Padding Tone: A Mechanistic Analysis of Padding Tokens in T2I Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06751</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06751v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Text-to-image (T2I) diffusion models rely on encoded prompts to guide the image generation process. Typically, these prompts are extended to a fixed length by adding padding tokens before text encoding. Despite being a default practice, the influence of padding tokens on the image generation process has not been investigated. In this work, we conduct the first in-depth analysis of the role padding tokens play in T2I models. We develop two causal techniques to analyze how information is encoded in the representation of tokens across different components of the T2I pipeline. Using these techniques, we investigate when and how padding tokens impact the image generation process. Our findings reveal three distinct scenarios: padding tokens may affect the model's output during text encoding, during the diffusion process, or be effectively ignored. Moreover, we identify key relationships between these scenarios and the model's architecture (cross or self-attention) and its training process (frozen or trained text encoder). These insights contribute to a deeper understanding of the mechanisms of padding tokens, potentially informing future model design and training practices in T2I systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06751v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Michael Toker, Ido Galil, Hadas Orgad, Rinon Gal, Yoad Tewel, Gal Chechik, Yonatan Belinkov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the Fairness Gap: Enhancing Pre-trained Models with LLM-Generated Sentences</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06795</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06795v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Pre-trained language models (PLMs) are trained on data that inherently contains gender biases, leading to undesirable impacts. Traditional debiasing methods often rely on external corpora, which may lack quality, diversity, or demographic balance, affecting the effectiveness of debiasing. With the rise of large language models and their extensive knowledge, we propose enhancing fairness (Fair-Gender) in PLMs by absorbing coherent, attribute-balanced, and semantically rich sentences. However, these sentences cannot be directly used for debiasing due to alignment issues and the risk of negative transfer. We address this by applying causal analysis to estimate causal effects, filtering out unaligned sentences, and identifying aligned ones for incorporation into PLMs, thereby ensuring positive transfer. Experiments show that our approach significantly reduces gender biases in PLMs while preserving their language expressiveness.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06795v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Liu Yu, Ludie Guo, Ping Kuang, Fan Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Event Argument Extraction with Enriched Prompts</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06825</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06825v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This work aims to delve deeper into prompt-based event argument extraction (EAE) models. We explore the impact of incorporating various types of information into the prompt on model performance, including trigger, other role arguments for the same event, and role arguments across multiple events within the same document. Further, we provide the best possible performance that the prompt-based EAE model can attain and demonstrate such models can be further optimized from the perspective of the training objective. Experiments are carried out on three small language models and two large language models in RAMS.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06825v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chen Liang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehensive Evaluation of Large Language Models on Mental Illnesses in Arabic Context</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06859</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06859v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Mental health disorders pose a growing public health concern in the Arab world, emphasizing the need for accessible diagnostic and intervention tools. Large language models (LLMs) offer a promising approach, but their application in Arabic contexts faces challenges including limited labeled datasets, linguistic complexity, and translation biases. This study comprehensively evaluates 8 LLMs, including general multi-lingual models, as well as bi-lingual ones, on diverse mental health datasets (such as AraDepSu, Dreaddit, MedMCQA), investigating the impact of prompt design, language configuration (native Arabic vs. translated English, and vice versa), and few-shot prompting on diagnostic performance. We find that prompt engineering significantly influences LLM scores mainly due to reduced instruction following, with our structured prompt outperforming a less structured variant on multi-class datasets, with an average difference of 14.5\%. While language influence on performance was modest, model selection proved crucial: Phi-3.5 MoE excelled in balanced accuracy, particularly for binary classification, while Mistral NeMo showed superior performance in mean absolute error for severity prediction tasks. Few-shot prompting consistently improved performance, with particularly substantial gains observed for GPT-4o Mini on multi-class classification, boosting accuracy by an average factor of 1.58. These findings underscore the importance of prompt optimization, multilingual analysis, and few-shot learning for developing culturally sensitive and effective LLM-based mental health tools for Arabic-speaking populations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06859v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Noureldin Zahran, Aya E. Fouda, Radwa J. Hanafy, Mohammed E. Fouda</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Language Fusion for Parameter-Efficient Cross-lingual Transfer</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06892</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06892v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Limited availability of multilingual text corpora for training language models often leads to poor performance on downstream tasks due to undertrained representation spaces for languages other than English. This 'under-representation' has motivated recent cross-lingual transfer methods to leverage the English representation space by e.g. mixing English and 'non-English' tokens at the input level or extending model parameters to accommodate new languages. However, these approaches often come at the cost of increased computational complexity. We propose Fusion forLanguage Representations (FLARE) in adapters, a novel method that enhances representation quality and downstream performance for languages other than English while maintaining parameter efficiency. FLARE integrates source and target language representations within low-rank (LoRA) adapters using lightweight linear transformations, maintaining parameter efficiency while improving transfer performance. A series of experiments across representative cross-lingual natural language understanding tasks, including natural language inference, question-answering and sentiment analysis, demonstrate FLARE's effectiveness. FLARE achieves performance improvements of 4.9% for Llama 3.1 and 2.2% for Gemma~2 compared to standard LoRA fine-tuning on question-answering tasks, as measured by the exact match metric.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06892v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Philipp Borchert, Ivan Vuli\'c, Marie-Francine Moens, Jochen De Weerdt</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing Large Language Models for Disaster Management: A Survey</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06932</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06932v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have revolutionized scientific research with their exceptional capabilities and transformed various fields. Among their practical applications, LLMs have been playing a crucial role in mitigating threats to human life, infrastructure, and the environment. Despite growing research in disaster LLMs, there remains a lack of systematic review and in-depth analysis of LLMs for natural disaster management. To address the gap, this paper presents a comprehensive survey of existing LLMs in natural disaster management, along with a taxonomy that categorizes existing works based on disaster phases and application scenarios. By collecting public datasets and identifying key challenges and opportunities, this study aims to guide the professional community in developing advanced LLMs for disaster management to enhance the resilience against natural disasters.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06932v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhenyu Lei, Yushun Dong, Weiyu Li, Rong Ding, Qi Wang, Jundong Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ViSoLex: An Open-Source Repository for Vietnamese Social Media Lexical Normalization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.07020</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.07020v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: ViSoLex is an open-source system designed to address the unique challenges of lexical normalization for Vietnamese social media text. The platform provides two core services: Non-Standard Word (NSW) Lookup and Lexical Normalization, enabling users to retrieve standard forms of informal language and standardize text containing NSWs. ViSoLex's architecture integrates pre-trained language models and weakly supervised learning techniques to ensure accurate and efficient normalization, overcoming the scarcity of labeled data in Vietnamese. This paper details the system's design, functionality, and its applications for researchers and non-technical users. Additionally, ViSoLex offers a flexible, customizable framework that can be adapted to various datasets and research requirements. By publishing the source code, ViSoLex aims to contribute to the development of more robust Vietnamese natural language processing tools and encourage further research in lexical normalization. Future directions include expanding the system's capabilities for additional languages and improving the handling of more complex non-standard linguistic patterns.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.07020v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Anh Thi-Hoang Nguyen, Dung Ha Nguyen, Kiet Van Nguyen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Text-To-Image Generation via Multilingual Prompting in Large Multimodal Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.07086</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.07086v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Previous work on augmenting large multimodal models (LMMs) for text-to-image (T2I) generation has focused on enriching the input space of in-context learning (ICL). This includes providing a few demonstrations and optimizing image descriptions to be more detailed and logical. However, as demand for more complex and flexible image descriptions grows, enhancing comprehension of input text within the ICL paradigm remains a critical yet underexplored area. In this work, we extend this line of research by constructing parallel multilingual prompts aimed at harnessing the multilingual capabilities of LMMs. More specifically, we translate the input text into several languages and provide the models with both the original text and the translations. Experiments on two LMMs across 3 benchmarks show that our method, PMT2I, achieves superior performance in general, compositional, and fine-grained assessments, especially in human preference alignment. Additionally, with its advantage of generating more diverse images, PMT2I significantly outperforms baseline prompts when incorporated with reranking methods. Our code and parallel multilingual data can be found at https://github.com/takagi97/PMT2I.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.07086v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yongyu Mu, Hengyu Li, Junxin Wang, Xiaoxuan Zhou, Chenglong Wang, Yingfeng Luo, Qiaozhi He, Tong Xiao, Guocheng Chen, Jingbo Zhu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AdaCS: Adaptive Normalization for Enhanced Code-Switching ASR</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.07102</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.07102v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Intra-sentential code-switching (CS) refers to the alternation between languages that happens within a single utterance and is a significant challenge for Automatic Speech Recognition (ASR) systems. For example, when a Vietnamese speaker uses foreign proper names or specialized terms within their speech. ASR systems often struggle to accurately transcribe intra-sentential CS due to their training on monolingual data and the unpredictable nature of CS. This issue is even more pronounced for low-resource languages, where limited data availability hinders the development of robust models. In this study, we propose AdaCS, a normalization model integrates an adaptive bias attention module (BAM) into encoder-decoder network. This novel approach provides a robust solution to CS ASR in unseen domains, thereby significantly enhancing our contribution to the field. By utilizing BAM to both identify and normalize CS phrases, AdaCS enhances its adaptive capabilities with a biased list of words provided during inference. Our method demonstrates impressive performance and the ability to handle unseen CS phrases across various domains. Experiments show that AdaCS outperforms previous state-of-the-art method on Vietnamese CS ASR normalization by considerable WER reduction of 56.2% and 36.8% on the two proposed test sets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.07102v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>The Chuong Chu, Vu Tuan Dat Pham, Kien Dao, Hoang Nguyen, Quoc Hung Truong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ListConRanker: A Contrastive Text Reranker with Listwise Encoding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.07111</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.07111v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Reranker models aim to re-rank the passages based on the semantics similarity between the given query and passages, which have recently received more attention due to the wide application of the Retrieval-Augmented Generation. Most previous methods apply pointwise encoding, meaning that it can only encode the context of the query for each passage input into the model. However, for the reranker model, given a query, the comparison results between passages are even more important, which is called listwise encoding. Besides, previous models are trained using the cross-entropy loss function, which leads to issues of unsmooth gradient changes during training and low training efficiency. To address these issues, we propose a novel Listwise-encoded Contrastive text reRanker (ListConRanker). It can help the passage to be compared with other passages during the encoding process, and enhance the contrastive information between positive examples and between positive and negative examples. At the same time, we use the circle loss to train the model to increase the flexibility of gradients and solve the problem of training efficiency. Experimental results show that ListConRanker achieves state-of-the-art performance on the reranking benchmark of Chinese Massive Text Embedding Benchmark, including the cMedQA1.0, cMedQA2.0, MMarcoReranking, and T2Reranking datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.07111v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junlong Liu, Yue Ma, Ruihui Zhao, Junhao Zheng, Qianli Ma, Yangyang Kang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When lies are mostly truthful: automated verbal deception detection for embedded lies</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.07217</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.07217v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Background: Verbal deception detection research relies on narratives and commonly assumes statements as truthful or deceptive. A more realistic perspective acknowledges that the veracity of statements exists on a continuum with truthful and deceptive parts being embedded within the same statement. However, research on embedded lies has been lagging behind. Methods: We collected a novel dataset of 2,088 truthful and deceptive statements with annotated embedded lies. Using a within-subjects design, participants provided a truthful account of an autobiographical event. They then rewrote their statement in a deceptive manner by including embedded lies, which they highlighted afterwards and judged on lie centrality, deceptiveness, and source. Results: We show that a fined-tuned language model (Llama-3-8B) can classify truthful statements and those containing embedded lies with 64% accuracy. Individual differences, linguistic properties and explainability analysis suggest that the challenge of moving the dial towards embedded lies stems from their resemblance to truthful statements. Typical deceptive statements consisted of 2/3 truthful information and 1/3 embedded lies, largely derived from past personal experiences and with minimal linguistic differences with their truthful counterparts. Conclusion: We present this dataset as a novel resource to address this challenge and foster research on embedded lies in verbal deception detection.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.07217v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Riccardo Loconte, Bennett Kleinberg</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative analysis of optical character recognition methods for S\'ami texts from the National Library of Norway</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.07300</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.07300v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Optical Character Recognition (OCR) is crucial to the National Library of Norway's (NLN) digitisation process as it converts scanned documents into machine-readable text. However, for the S\'ami documents in NLN's collection, the OCR accuracy is insufficient. Given that OCR quality affects downstream processes, evaluating and improving OCR for text written in S\'ami languages is necessary to make these resources accessible. To address this need, this work fine-tunes and evaluates three established OCR approaches, Transkribus, Tesseract and TrOCR, for transcribing S\'ami texts from NLN's collection. Our results show that Transkribus and TrOCR outperform Tesseract on this task, while Tesseract achieves superior performance on an out-of-domain dataset. Furthermore, we show that fine-tuning pre-trained models and supplementing manual annotations with machine annotations and synthetic text images can yield accurate OCR for S\'ami languages, even with a moderate amount of manually annotated data.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.07300v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tita Enstad, Trond Trosterud, Marie Iversdatter R{\o}sok, Yngvil Beyer, Marie Roald</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Lessons of Developing Process Reward Models in Mathematical Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.07301</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.07301v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Process Reward Models (PRMs) emerge as a promising approach for process supervision in mathematical reasoning of Large Language Models (LLMs), which aim to identify and mitigate intermediate errors in the reasoning processes. However, the development of effective PRMs faces significant challenges, particularly in data annotation and evaluation methodologies. In this paper, through extensive experiments, we demonstrate that commonly used Monte Carlo (MC) estimation-based data synthesis for PRMs typically yields inferior performance and generalization compared to LLM-as-a-judge and human annotation methods. MC estimation relies on completion models to evaluate current-step correctness, leading to inaccurate step verification. Furthermore, we identify potential biases in conventional Best-of-N (BoN) evaluation strategies for PRMs: (1) The unreliable policy models generate responses with correct answers but flawed processes, leading to a misalignment between the evaluation criteria of BoN and the PRM objectives of process verification. (2) The tolerance of PRMs of such responses leads to inflated BoN scores. (3) Existing PRMs have a significant proportion of minimum scores concentrated on the final answer steps, revealing the shift from process to outcome-based assessment in BoN Optimized PRMs. To address these challenges, we develop a consensus filtering mechanism that effectively integrates MC estimation with LLM-as-a-judge and advocates a more comprehensive evaluation framework that combines response-level and step-level metrics. Based on the mechanisms, we significantly improve both model performance and data efficiency in the BoN evaluation and the step-wise error identification task. Finally, we release a new state-of-the-art PRM that outperforms existing open-source alternatives and provides practical guidelines for future research in building process supervision models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.07301v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhenru Zhang, Chujie Zheng, Yangzhen Wu, Beichen Zhang, Runji Lin, Bowen Yu, Dayiheng Liu, Jingren Zhou, Junyang Lin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FinerWeb-10BT: Refining Web Data with LLM-Based Line-Level Filtering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.07314</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.07314v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Data quality is crucial for training Large Language Models (LLMs). Traditional heuristic filters often miss low-quality text or mistakenly remove valuable content. In this paper, we introduce an LLM-based line-level filtering method to enhance training data quality. We use GPT-4o mini to label a 20,000-document sample from FineWeb at the line level, allowing the model to create descriptive labels for low-quality lines. These labels are grouped into nine main categories, and we train a DeBERTa-v3 classifier to scale the filtering to a 10B-token subset of FineWeb. To test the impact of our filtering, we train GPT-2 models on both the original and the filtered datasets. The results show that models trained on the filtered data achieve higher accuracy on the HellaSwag benchmark and reach their performance targets faster, even with up to 25\% less data. This demonstrates that LLM-based line-level filtering can significantly improve data quality and training efficiency for LLMs. We release our quality-annotated dataset, FinerWeb-10BT, and the codebase to support further work in this area.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.07314v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Erik Henriksson, Otto Tarkka, Filip Ginter</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emergent effects of scaling on the functional hierarchies within large language models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.07359</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.07359v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language model (LLM) architectures are often described as functionally hierarchical: Early layers process syntax, middle layers begin to parse semantics, and late layers integrate information. The present work revisits these ideas. This research submits simple texts to an LLM (e.g., "A church and organ") and extracts the resulting activations. Then, for each layer, support vector machines and ridge regressions are fit to predict a text's label and thus examine whether a given layer encodes some information. Analyses using a small model (Llama-3.2-3b; 28 layers) partly bolster the common hierarchical perspective: Item-level semantics are most strongly represented early (layers 2-7), then two-item relations (layers 8-12), and then four-item analogies (layers 10-15). Afterward, the representation of items and simple relations gradually decreases in deeper layers that focus on more global information. However, several findings run counter to a steady hierarchy view: First, although deep layers can represent document-wide abstractions, deep layers also compress information from early portions of the context window without meaningful abstraction. Second, when examining a larger model (Llama-3.3-70b-Instruct), stark fluctuations in abstraction level appear: As depth increases, two-item relations and four-item analogies initially increase in their representation, then markedly decrease, and afterward increase again momentarily. This peculiar pattern consistently emerges across several experiments. Third, another emergent effect of scaling is coordination between the attention mechanisms of adjacent layers. Across multiple experiments using the larger model, adjacent layers fluctuate between what information they each specialize in representing. In sum, an abstraction hierarchy often manifests across layers, but large models also deviate from this structure in curious ways.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.07359v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Paul C. Bogdan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Retrieval-Augmented Generation: A Study of Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.07391</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.07391v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) systems have recently shown remarkable advancements by integrating retrieval mechanisms into language models, enhancing their ability to produce more accurate and contextually relevant responses. However, the influence of various components and configurations within RAG systems remains underexplored. A comprehensive understanding of these elements is essential for tailoring RAG systems to complex retrieval tasks and ensuring optimal performance across diverse applications. In this paper, we develop several advanced RAG system designs that incorporate query expansion, various novel retrieval strategies, and a novel Contrastive In-Context Learning RAG. Our study systematically investigates key factors, including language model size, prompt design, document chunk size, knowledge base size, retrieval stride, query expansion techniques, Contrastive In-Context Learning knowledge bases, multilingual knowledge bases, and Focus Mode retrieving relevant context at sentence-level. Through extensive experimentation, we provide a detailed analysis of how these factors influence response quality. Our findings offer actionable insights for developing RAG systems, striking a balance between contextual richness and retrieval-generation efficiency, thereby paving the way for more adaptable and high-performing RAG frameworks in diverse real-world scenarios. Our code and implementation details are publicly available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.07391v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Siran Li, Linus Stenzel, Carsten Eickhoff, Seyed Ali Bahrainian</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TiEBe: A Benchmark for Assessing the Current Knowledge of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.07482</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.07482v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In a rapidly evolving knowledge landscape and the increasing adoption of large language models, a need has emerged to keep these models continuously updated with current events. While existing benchmarks evaluate general factual recall, they often overlook two critical aspects: the ability of models to integrate evolving knowledge through continual learning and the significant regional disparities in their performance. To address these gaps, we introduce the Timely Events Benchmark (TiEBe), a dataset containing over 11,000 question-answer pairs focused on globally and regionally significant events. TiEBe leverages structured retrospective data from Wikipedia, enabling continuous updates to assess LLMs' knowledge of evolving global affairs and their understanding of events across different regions. Our benchmark demonstrates that LLMs exhibit substantial geographic disparities in factual recall, emphasizing the need for more balanced global knowledge representation. Furthermore, TiEBe serves as a tool for evaluating continual learning strategies, providing insights into models' ability to acquire new information without forgetting past knowledge.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.07482v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Thales Sales Almeida, Giovana Kerche Bon\'as, Jo\~ao Guilherme Alves Santos, Hugo Abonizio, Rodrigo Nogueira</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating Large Language Models in Inferring Personality Traits from User Conversations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.07532</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.07532v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) are demonstrating remarkable human like capabilities across diverse domains, including psychological assessment. This study evaluates whether LLMs, specifically GPT-4o and GPT-4o mini, can infer Big Five personality traits and generate Big Five Inventory-10 (BFI-10) item scores from user conversations under zero-shot prompting conditions. Our findings reveal that incorporating an intermediate step--prompting for BFI-10 item scores before calculating traits--enhances accuracy and aligns more closely with the gold standard than direct trait inference. This structured approach underscores the importance of leveraging psychological frameworks in improving predictive precision. Additionally, a group comparison based on depressive symptom presence revealed differential model performance. Participants were categorized into two groups: those experiencing at least one depressive symptom and those without symptoms. GPT-4o mini demonstrated heightened sensitivity to depression-related shifts in traits such as Neuroticism and Conscientiousness within the symptom-present group, whereas GPT-4o exhibited strengths in nuanced interpretation across groups. These findings underscore the potential of LLMs to analyze real-world psychological data effectively, offering a valuable foundation for interdisciplinary research at the intersection of artificial intelligence and psychology.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.07532v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jianfeng Zhu, Ruoming Jin, Karin G. Coifman</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Imagine while Reasoning in Space: Multimodal Visualization-of-Thought</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.07542</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.07542v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Chain-of-Thought (CoT) prompting has proven highly effective for enhancing complex reasoning in Large Language Models (LLMs) and Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs). Yet, it struggles in complex spatial reasoning tasks. Nonetheless, human cognition extends beyond language alone, enabling the remarkable capability to think in both words and images. Inspired by this mechanism, we propose a new reasoning paradigm, Multimodal Visualization-of-Thought (MVoT). It enables visual thinking in MLLMs by generating image visualizations of their reasoning traces. To ensure high-quality visualization, we introduce token discrepancy loss into autoregressive MLLMs. This innovation significantly improves both visual coherence and fidelity. We validate this approach through several dynamic spatial reasoning tasks. Experimental results reveal that MVoT demonstrates competitive performance across tasks. Moreover, it exhibits robust and reliable improvements in the most challenging scenarios where CoT fails. Ultimately, MVoT establishes new possibilities for complex reasoning tasks where visual thinking can effectively complement verbal reasoning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.07542v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chengzu Li, Wenshan Wu, Huanyu Zhang, Yan Xia, Shaoguang Mao, Li Dong, Ivan Vuli\'c, Furu Wei</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WebWalker: Benchmarking LLMs in Web Traversal</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.07572</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.07572v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) demonstrates remarkable performance across tasks in open-domain question-answering. However, traditional search engines may retrieve shallow content, limiting the ability of LLMs to handle complex, multi-layered information. To address it, we introduce WebWalkerQA, a benchmark designed to assess the ability of LLMs to perform web traversal. It evaluates the capacity of LLMs to traverse a website's subpages to extract high-quality data systematically. We propose WebWalker, which is a multi-agent framework that mimics human-like web navigation through an explore-critic paradigm. Extensive experimental results show that WebWalkerQA is challenging and demonstrates the effectiveness of RAG combined with WebWalker, through the horizontal and vertical integration in real-world scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.07572v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jialong Wu, Wenbiao Yin, Yong Jiang, Zhenglin Wang, Zekun Xi, Runnan Fang, Deyu Zhou, Pengjun Xie, Fei Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Multimodal Social Agent</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06189</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06189v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In recent years, large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated remarkable progress in common-sense reasoning tasks. This ability is fundamental to understanding social dynamics, interactions, and communication. However, the potential of integrating computers with these social capabilities is still relatively unexplored. However, the potential of integrating computers with these social capabilities is still relatively unexplored. This paper introduces MuSA, a multimodal LLM-based agent that analyzes text-rich social content tailored to address selected human-centric content analysis tasks, such as question answering, visual question answering, title generation, and categorization. It uses planning, reasoning, acting, optimizing, criticizing, and refining strategies to complete a task. Our approach demonstrates that MuSA can automate and improve social content analysis, helping decision-making processes across various applications. We have evaluated our agent's capabilities in question answering, title generation, and content categorization tasks. MuSA performs substantially better than our baselines.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06189v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Athina Bikaki, Ioannis A. Kakadiaris</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Edge Intelligence and LLMs to Advance 6G-Enabled Internet of Automated Defense Vehicles</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06205</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06205v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The evolution of Artificial Intelligence (AI) and its subset Deep Learning (DL), has profoundly impacted numerous domains, including autonomous driving. The integration of autonomous driving in military settings reduces human casualties and enables precise and safe execution of missions in hazardous environments while allowing for reliable logistics support without the risks associated with fatigue-related errors. However, relying on autonomous driving solely requires an advanced decision-making model that is adaptable and optimum in any situation. Considering the presence of numerous interconnected autonomous vehicles in mission-critical scenarios, Ultra-Reliable Low Latency Communication (URLLC) is vital for ensuring seamless coordination, real-time data exchange, and instantaneous response to dynamic driving environments. The advent of 6G strengthens the Internet of Automated Defense Vehicles (IoADV) concept within the realm of Internet of Military Defense Things (IoMDT) by enabling robust connectivity, crucial for real-time data exchange, advanced navigation, and enhanced safety features through IoADV interactions. On the other hand, a critical advancement in this space is using pre-trained Generative Large Language Models (LLMs) for decision-making and communication optimization for autonomous driving. Hence, this work presents opportunities and challenges with a vision of realizing the full potential of these technologies in critical defense applications, especially through the advancement of IoADV and its role in enhancing autonomous military operations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06205v1</guid>
      <category>cs.NI</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Murat Arda Onsu, Poonam Lohan, Burak Kantarci</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fitting Different Interactive Information: Joint Classification of Emotion and Intention</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06215</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06215v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This paper is the first-place solution for ICASSP MEIJU@2025 Track I, which focuses on low-resource multimodal emotion and intention recognition. How to effectively utilize a large amount of unlabeled data, while ensuring the mutual promotion of different difficulty levels tasks in the interaction stage, these two points become the key to the competition. In this paper, pseudo-label labeling is carried out on the model trained with labeled data, and samples with high confidence and their labels are selected to alleviate the problem of low resources. At the same time, the characteristic of easy represented ability of intention recognition found in the experiment is used to make mutually promote with emotion recognition under different attention heads, and higher performance of intention recognition is achieved through fusion. Finally, under the refined processing data, we achieve the score of 0.5532 in the Test set, and win the championship of the track.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06215v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xinger Li, Zhiqiang Zhong, Bo Huang, Yang Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>$\text{Transformer}^2$: Self-adaptive LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06252</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06252v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Self-adaptive large language models (LLMs) aim to solve the challenges posed by traditional fine-tuning methods, which are often computationally intensive and static in their ability to handle diverse tasks. We introduce \implname, a novel self-adaptation framework that adapts LLMs for unseen tasks in real-time by selectively adjusting only the singular components of their weight matrices. During inference, \implname employs a two-pass mechanism: first, a dispatch system identifies the task properties, and then task-specific "expert" vectors, trained using reinforcement learning, are dynamically mixed to obtain targeted behavior for the incoming prompt. Our method outperforms ubiquitous approaches such as LoRA, with fewer parameters and greater efficiency. \implname demonstrates versatility across different LLM architectures and modalities, including vision-language tasks. \implname represents a significant leap forward, offering a scalable, efficient solution for enhancing the adaptability and task-specific performance of LLMs, paving the way for truly dynamic, self-organizing AI systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06252v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qi Sun, Edoardo Cetin, Yujin Tang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polarized Patterns of Language Toxicity and Sentiment of Debunking Posts on Social Media</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06274</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06274v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Here's a condensed 1920-character version: The rise of misinformation and fake news in online political discourse poses significant challenges to democratic processes and public engagement. While debunking efforts aim to counteract misinformation and foster fact-based dialogue, these discussions often involve language toxicity and emotional polarization. We examined over 86 million debunking tweets and more than 4 million Reddit debunking comments to investigate the relationship between language toxicity, pessimism, and social polarization in debunking efforts. Focusing on discussions of the 2016 and 2020 U.S. presidential elections and the QAnon conspiracy theory, our analysis reveals three key findings: (1) peripheral participants (1-degree users) play a disproportionate role in shaping toxic discourse, driven by lower community accountability and emotional expression; (2) platform mechanisms significantly influence polarization, with Twitter amplifying partisan differences and Reddit fostering higher overall toxicity due to its structured, community-driven interactions; and (3) a negative correlation exists between language toxicity and pessimism, with increased interaction reducing toxicity, especially on Reddit. We show that platform architecture affects informational complexity of user interactions, with Twitter promoting concentrated, uniform discourse and Reddit encouraging diverse, complex communication. Our findings highlight the importance of user engagement patterns, platform dynamics, and emotional expressions in shaping polarization in debunking discourse. This study offers insights for policymakers and platform designers to mitigate harmful effects and promote healthier online discussions, with implications for understanding misinformation, hate speech, and political polarization in digital environments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06274v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wentao Xu, Wenlu Fan, Shiqian Lu, Tenghao Li, Bin Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PROEMO: Prompt-Driven Text-to-Speech Synthesis Based on Emotion and Intensity Control</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06276</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06276v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Speech synthesis has significantly advanced from statistical methods to deep neural network architectures, leading to various text-to-speech (TTS) models that closely mimic human speech patterns. However, capturing nuances such as emotion and style in speech synthesis is challenging. To address this challenge, we introduce an approach centered on prompt-based emotion control. The proposed architecture incorporates emotion and intensity control across multi-speakers. Furthermore, we leverage large language models (LLMs) to manipulate speech prosody while preserving linguistic content. Using embedding emotional cues, regulating intensity levels, and guiding prosodic variations with prompts, our approach infuses synthesized speech with human-like expressiveness and variability. Lastly, we demonstrate the effectiveness of our approach through a systematic exploration of the control mechanisms mentioned above.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06276v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shaozuo Zhang, Ambuj Mehrish, Yingting Li, Soujanya Poria</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dafny as Verification-Aware Intermediate Language for Code Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06283</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06283v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Using large language models (LLMs) to generate source code from natural language prompts is a popular and promising idea with a wide range of applications. One of its limitations is that the generated code can be faulty at times, often in a subtle way, despite being presented to the user as correct. In this paper, we explore ways in which formal methods can assist with increasing the quality of code generated by an LLM. Instead of emitting code in a target language directly, we propose that the user guides the LLM to first generate an opaque intermediate representation, in the verification-aware language Dafny, that can be automatically validated for correctness against agreed on specifications. The correct Dafny program is then compiled to the target language and returned to the user. All user-system interactions throughout the procedure occur via natural language; Dafny code is never exposed. We describe our current prototype and report on its performance on the HumanEval Python code generation benchmarks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06283v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LO</category>
      <category>cs.PL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yue Chen Li, Stefan Zetzsche, Siva Somayyajula</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding How Paper Writers Use AI-Generated Captions in Figure Caption Writing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06317</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06317v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Figures and their captions play a key role in scientific publications. However, despite their importance, many captions in published papers are poorly crafted, largely due to a lack of attention by paper authors. While prior AI research has explored caption generation, it has mainly focused on reader-centered use cases, where users evaluate generated captions rather than actively integrating them into their writing. This paper addresses this gap by investigating how paper authors incorporate AI-generated captions into their writing process through a user study involving 18 participants. Each participant rewrote captions for two figures from their own recently published work, using captions generated by state-of-the-art AI models as a resource. By analyzing video recordings of the writing process through interaction analysis, we observed that participants often began by copying and refining AI-generated captions. Paper writers favored longer, detail-rich captions that integrated textual and visual elements but found current AI models less effective for complex figures. These findings highlight the nuanced and diverse nature of figure caption composition, revealing design opportunities for AI systems to better support the challenges of academic writing.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06317v1</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ho Yin (Sam),  Ng, Ting-Yao Hsu, Jiyoo Min, Sungchul Kim, Ryan A. Rossi, Tong Yu, Hyunggu Jung, Ting-Hao 'Kenneth' Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TTS-Transducer: End-to-End Speech Synthesis with Neural Transducer</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06320</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06320v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This work introduces TTS-Transducer - a novel architecture for text-to-speech, leveraging the strengths of audio codec models and neural transducers. Transducers, renowned for their superior quality and robustness in speech recognition, are employed to learn monotonic alignments and allow for avoiding using explicit duration predictors. Neural audio codecs efficiently compress audio into discrete codes, revealing the possibility of applying text modeling approaches to speech generation. However, the complexity of predicting multiple tokens per frame from several codebooks, as necessitated by audio codec models with residual quantizers, poses a significant challenge. The proposed system first uses a transducer architecture to learn monotonic alignments between tokenized text and speech codec tokens for the first codebook. Next, a non-autoregressive Transformer predicts the remaining codes using the alignment extracted from transducer loss. The proposed system is trained end-to-end. We show that TTS-Transducer is a competitive and robust alternative to contemporary TTS systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06320v1</guid>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Vladimir Bataev, Subhankar Ghosh, Vitaly Lavrukhin, Jason Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Pre-trained LLMs for Multivariate Time Series Forecasting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06386</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06386v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Pre-trained Large Language Models (LLMs) encapsulate large amounts of knowledge and take enormous amounts of compute to train. We make use of this resource, together with the observation that LLMs are able to transfer knowledge and performance from one domain or even modality to another seemingly-unrelated area, to help with multivariate demand time series forecasting. Attention in transformer-based methods requires something worth attending to -- more than just samples of a time-series. We explore different methods to map multivariate input time series into the LLM token embedding space. In particular, our novel multivariate patching strategy to embed time series features into decoder-only pre-trained Transformers produces results competitive with state-of-the-art time series forecasting models. We also use recently-developed weight-based diagnostics to validate our findings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06386v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Malcolm L. Wolff, Shenghao Yang, Kari Torkkola, Michael W. Mahoney</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speech Recognition for Automatically Assessing Afrikaans and isiXhosa Preschool Oral Narratives</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06478</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06478v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We develop automatic speech recognition (ASR) systems for stories told by Afrikaans and isiXhosa preschool children. Oral narratives provide a way to assess children's language development before they learn to read. We consider a range of prior child-speech ASR strategies to determine which is best suited to this unique setting. Using Whisper and only 5 minutes of transcribed in-domain child speech, we find that additional in-domain adult data (adult speech matching the story domain) provides the biggest improvement, especially when coupled with voice conversion. Semi-supervised learning also helps for both languages, while parameter-efficient fine-tuning helps on Afrikaans but not on isiXhosa (which is under-represented in the Whisper model). Few child-speech studies look at non-English data, and even fewer at the preschool ages of 4 and 5. Our work therefore represents a unique validation of a wide range of previous child-speech ASR strategies in an under-explored setting.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06478v1</guid>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Christiaan Jacobs, Annelien Smith, Daleen Klop, Ond\v{r}ej Klejch, Febe de Wet, Herman Kamper</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ladder-residual: parallelism-aware architecture for accelerating large model inference with communication overlapping</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06589</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06589v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large language model inference is both memory-intensive and time-consuming, often requiring distributed algorithms to efficiently scale. Various model parallelism strategies are used in multi-gpu training and inference to partition computation across multiple devices, reducing memory load and computation time. However, using model parallelism necessitates communication of information between GPUs, which has been a major bottleneck and limits the gains obtained by scaling up the number of devices. We introduce Ladder Residual, a simple architectural modification applicable to all residual-based models that enables straightforward overlapping that effectively hides the latency of communication. Our insight is that in addition to systems optimization, one can also redesign the model architecture to decouple communication from computation. While Ladder Residual can allow communication-computation decoupling in conventional parallelism patterns, we focus on Tensor Parallelism in this paper, which is particularly bottlenecked by its heavy communication. For a Transformer model with 70B parameters, applying Ladder Residual to all its layers can achieve 30% end-to-end wall clock speed up at inference time with TP sharding over 8 devices. We refer the resulting Transformer model as the Ladder Transformer. We train a 1B and 3B Ladder Transformer from scratch and observe comparable performance to a standard dense transformer baseline. We also show that it is possible to convert parts of the Llama-3.1 8B model to our Ladder Residual architecture with minimal accuracy degradation by only retraining for 3B tokens.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06589v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.DC</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Muru Zhang, Mayank Mishra, Zhongzhu Zhou, William Brandon, Jue Wang, Yoon Kim, Jonathan Ragan-Kelley, Shuaiwen Leon Song, Ben Athiwaratkun, Tri Dao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EmoXpt: Analyzing Emotional Variances in Human Comments and LLM-Generated Responses</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06597</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06597v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The widespread adoption of generative AI has generated diverse opinions, with individuals expressing both support and criticism of its applications. This study investigates the emotional dynamics surrounding generative AI by analyzing human tweets referencing terms such as ChatGPT, OpenAI, Copilot, and LLMs. To further understand the emotional intelligence of ChatGPT, we examine its responses to selected tweets, highlighting differences in sentiment between human comments and LLM-generated responses. We introduce EmoXpt, a sentiment analysis framework designed to assess both human perspectives on generative AI and the sentiment embedded in ChatGPT's responses. Unlike prior studies that focus exclusively on human sentiment, EmoXpt uniquely evaluates the emotional expression of ChatGPT. Experimental results demonstrate that LLM-generated responses are notably more efficient, cohesive, and consistently positive than human responses.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06597v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shireesh Reddy Pyreddy, Tarannum Shaila Zaman</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Magnitude of Categories of Texts Enriched by Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06662</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06662v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The purpose of this article is twofold. Firstly, we use the next-token probabilities given by a language model to explicitly define a $[0,1]$-enrichment of a category of texts in natural language, in the sense of Bradley, Terilla, and Vlassopoulos. We consider explicitly the terminating conditions for text generation and determine when the enrichment itself can be interpreted as a probability over texts. Secondly, we compute the M\"obius function and the magnitude of an associated generalized metric space $\mathcal{M}$ of texts using a combinatorial version of these quantities recently introduced by Vigneaux. The magnitude function $f(t)$ of $\mathcal{M}$ is a sum over texts $x$ (prompts) of the Tsallis $t$-entropies of the next-token probability distributions $p(-|x)$ plus the cardinality of the model's possible outputs. The derivative of $f$ at $t=1$ recovers a sum of Shannon entropies, which justifies seeing magnitude as a partition function. Following Leinster and Schulman, we also express the magnitude function of $\mathcal M$ as an Euler characteristic of magnitude homology and provide an explicit description of the zeroeth and first magnitude homology groups.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06662v1</guid>
      <category>math.CT</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tai-Danae Bradley, Juan Pablo Vigneaux</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultra Memory-Efficient On-FPGA Training of Transformers via Tensor-Compressed Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06663</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06663v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Transformer models have achieved state-of-the-art performance across a wide range of machine learning tasks. There is growing interest in training transformers on resource-constrained edge devices due to considerations such as privacy, domain adaptation, and on-device scientific machine learning. However, the significant computational and memory demands required for transformer training often exceed the capabilities of an edge device. Leveraging low-rank tensor compression, this paper presents the first on-FPGA accelerator for end-to-end transformer training. On the algorithm side, we present a bi-directional contraction flow for tensorized transformer training, significantly reducing the computational FLOPS and intra-layer memory costs compared to existing tensor operations. On the hardware side, we store all highly compressed model parameters and gradient information on chip, creating an on-chip-memory-only framework for each stage in training. This reduces off-chip communication and minimizes latency and energy costs. Additionally, we implement custom computing kernels for each training stage and employ intra-layer parallelism and pipe-lining to further enhance run-time and memory efficiency. Through experiments on transformer models within $36.7$ to $93.5$ MB using FP-32 data formats on the ATIS dataset, our tensorized FPGA accelerator could conduct single-batch end-to-end training on the AMD Alevo U50 FPGA, with a memory budget of less than $6$-MB BRAM and $22.5$-MB URAM. Compared to uncompressed training on the NVIDIA RTX 3090 GPU, our on-FPGA training achieves a memory reduction of $30\times$ to $51\times$. Our FPGA accelerator also achieves up to $3.6\times$ less energy cost per epoch compared with tensor Transformer training on an NVIDIA RTX 3090 GPU.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06663v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiayi Tian (Callie), Jinming Lu (Callie), Hai Li (Callie), Xiangwei Wang (Callie),  Cong (Callie),  Hao, Ian Young, Zheng Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tuning ChatGPT for Automatic Scoring of Written Scientific Explanations in Chinese</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06704</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06704v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The development of explanations for scientific phenomena is essential in science assessment, but scoring student-written explanations remains challenging and resource-intensive. Large language models (LLMs) have shown promise in addressing this issue, particularly in alphabetic languages like English. However, their applicability to logographic languages is less explored. This study investigates the potential of fine-tuning ChatGPT, a leading LLM, to automatically score scientific explanations written in Chinese. Student responses to seven scientific explanation tasks were collected and automatically scored, with scoring accuracy examined in relation to reasoning complexity using the Kendall correlation. A qualitative analysis explored how linguistic features influenced scoring accuracy. The results show that domain-specific adaptation enables ChatGPT to score Chinese scientific explanations with accuracy. However, scoring accuracy correlates with reasoning complexity: a negative correlation for lower-level responses and a positive one for higher-level responses. The model overrates complex reasoning in low-level responses with intricate sentence structures and underrates high-level responses using concise causal reasoning. These correlations stem from linguistic features--simplicity and clarity enhance accuracy for lower-level responses, while comprehensiveness improves accuracy for higher-level ones. Simpler, shorter responses tend to score more accurately at lower levels, whereas longer, information-rich responses yield better accuracy at higher levels. These findings demonstrate the effectiveness of LLMs in automatic scoring within a Chinese context and emphasize the importance of linguistic features and reasoning complexity in fine-tuning scoring models for educational assessments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06704v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jie Yang, Ehsan Latif, Yuze He, Xiaoming Zhai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ZOQO: Zero-Order Quantized Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06736</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06736v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The increasing computational and memory demands in deep learning present significant challenges, especially in resource-constrained environments. We introduce a zero-order quantized optimization (ZOQO) method designed for training models with quantized parameters and operations. Our approach leverages zero-order approximations of the gradient sign and adapts the learning process to maintain the parameters' quantization without the need for full-precision gradient calculations. We demonstrate the effectiveness of ZOQO through experiments in fine-tuning of large language models and black-box adversarial attacks. Despite the limitations of zero-order and quantized operations training, our method achieves competitive performance compared to full-precision methods, highlighting its potential for low-resource environments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06736v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Noga Bar, Raja Giryes</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3DCoMPaT200: Language-Grounded Compositional Understanding of Parts and Materials of 3D Shapes</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06785</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06785v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Understanding objects in 3D at the part level is essential for humans and robots to navigate and interact with the environment. Current datasets for part-level 3D object understanding encompass a limited range of categories. For instance, the ShapeNet-Part and PartNet datasets only include 16, and 24 object categories respectively. The 3DCoMPaT dataset, specifically designed for compositional understanding of parts and materials, contains only 42 object categories. To foster richer and fine-grained part-level 3D understanding, we introduce 3DCoMPaT200, a large-scale dataset tailored for compositional understanding of object parts and materials, with 200 object categories with $\approx$5 times larger object vocabulary compared to 3DCoMPaT and $\approx$ 4 times larger part categories. Concretely, 3DCoMPaT200 significantly expands upon 3DCoMPaT, featuring 1,031 fine-grained part categories and 293 distinct material classes for compositional application to 3D object parts. Additionally, to address the complexities of compositional 3D modeling, we propose a novel task of Compositional Part Shape Retrieval using ULIP to provide a strong 3D foundational model for 3D Compositional Understanding. This method evaluates the model shape retrieval performance given one, three, or six parts described in text format. These results show that the model's performance improves with an increasing number of style compositions, highlighting the critical role of the compositional dataset. Such results underscore the dataset's effectiveness in enhancing models' capability to understand complex 3D shapes from a compositional perspective. Code and Data can be found at http://github.com/3DCoMPaT200/3DCoMPaT200</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06785v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mahmoud Ahmed, Xiang Li, Arpit Prajapati, Mohamed Elhoseiny</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Cross-Lingual Phonetic Representation of Low-Resource Languages Through Language Similarity Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06810</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06810v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This paper examines how linguistic similarity affects cross-lingual phonetic representation in speech processing for low-resource languages, emphasizing effective source language selection. Previous cross-lingual research has used various source languages to enhance performance for the target low-resource language without thorough consideration of selection. Our study stands out by providing an in-depth analysis of language selection, supported by a practical approach to assess phonetic proximity among multiple language families. We investigate how within-family similarity impacts performance in multilingual training, which aids in understanding language dynamics. We also evaluate the effect of using phonologically similar languages, regardless of family. For the phoneme recognition task, utilizing phonologically similar languages consistently achieves a relative improvement of 55.6% over monolingual training, even surpassing the performance of a large-scale self-supervised learning model. Multilingual training within the same language family demonstrates that higher phonological similarity enhances performance, while lower similarity results in degraded performance compared to monolingual training.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06810v1</guid>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Minu Kim, Kangwook Jang, Hoirin Kim</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correcting Annotator Bias in Training Data: Population-Aligned Instance Replication (PAIR)</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06826</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06826v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Models trained on crowdsourced labels may not reflect broader population views when annotator pools are not representative. Since collecting representative labels is challenging, we propose Population-Aligned Instance Replication (PAIR), a method to address this bias through statistical adjustment. Using a simulation study of hate speech and offensive language detection, we create two types of annotators with different labeling tendencies and generate datasets with varying proportions of the types. Models trained on unbalanced annotator pools show poor calibration compared to those trained on representative data. However, PAIR, which duplicates labels from underrepresented annotator groups to match population proportions, significantly reduces bias without requiring new data collection. These results suggest statistical techniques from survey research can help align model training with target populations even when representative annotator pools are unavailable. We conclude with three practical recommendations for improving training data quality.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06826v1</guid>
      <category>stat.ME</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Stephanie Eckman, Bolei Ma, Christoph Kern, Rob Chew, Barbara Plank, Frauke Kreuter</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLMs Model Non-WEIRD Populations: Experiments with Synthetic Cultural Agents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06834</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06834v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Despite its importance, studying economic behavior across diverse, non-WEIRD (Western, Educated, Industrialized, Rich, and Democratic) populations presents significant challenges. We address this issue by introducing a novel methodology that uses Large Language Models (LLMs) to create synthetic cultural agents (SCAs) representing these populations. We subject these SCAs to classic behavioral experiments, including the dictator and ultimatum games. Our results demonstrate substantial cross-cultural variability in experimental behavior. Notably, for populations with available data, SCAs' behaviors qualitatively resemble those of real human subjects. For unstudied populations, our method can generate novel, testable hypotheses about economic behavior. By integrating AI into experimental economics, this approach offers an effective and ethical method to pilot experiments and refine protocols for hard-to-reach populations. Our study provides a new tool for cross-cultural economic studies and demonstrates how LLMs can help experimental behavioral research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06834v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>econ.GN</category>
      <category>q-fin.EC</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Augusto Gonzalez-Bonorino (Pomona College Economics Department), Monica Capra (Claremont Graduate University Economics Department, University of Arizona Center for the Philosophy of Freedom), Emilio Pantoja (Pitzer College Economics and Computer Science Department)</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPAM: Spike-Aware Adam with Momentum Reset for Stable LLM Training</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06842</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06842v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated exceptional performance across diverse tasks, yet their training remains highly resource-intensive and susceptible to critical challenges such as training instability. A predominant source of this instability stems from gradient and loss spikes, which disrupt the learning process, often leading to costly interventions like checkpoint recovery and experiment restarts, further amplifying inefficiencies. This paper presents a comprehensive investigation into gradient spikes observed during LLM training, revealing their prevalence across multiple architectures and datasets. Our analysis shows that these spikes can be up to $1000\times$ larger than typical gradients, substantially deteriorating model performance. To address this issue, we propose Spike-Aware Adam with Momentum Reset SPAM, a novel optimizer designed to counteract gradient spikes through momentum reset and spike-aware gradient clipping. Extensive experiments, including both pre-training and fine-tuning, demonstrate that SPAM consistently surpasses Adam and its variants across various tasks, including (1) LLM pre-training from 60M to 1B, (2) 4-bit LLM pre-training,(3) reinforcement learning, and (4) Time Series Forecasting. Additionally, SPAM facilitates memory-efficient training by enabling sparse momentum, where only a subset of momentum terms are maintained and updated. When operating under memory constraints, SPAM outperforms state-of-the-art memory-efficient optimizers such as GaLore and Adam-Mini. Our work underscores the importance of mitigating gradient spikes in LLM training and introduces an effective optimization strategy that enhances both training stability and resource efficiency at scale. Code is available at https://github.com/TianjinYellow/SPAM-Optimizer.git</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06842v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tianjin Huang, Ziquan Zhu, Gaojie Jin, Lu Liu, Zhangyang Wang, Shiwei Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A General Framework for Inference-time Scaling and Steering of Diffusion Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06848</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06848v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Diffusion models produce impressive results in modalities ranging from images and video to protein design and text. However, generating samples with user-specified properties remains a challenge. Recent research proposes fine-tuning models to maximize rewards that capture desired properties, but these methods require expensive training and are prone to mode collapse. In this work, we propose Feynman Kac (FK) steering, an inference-time framework for steering diffusion models with reward functions. FK steering works by sampling a system of multiple interacting diffusion processes, called particles, and resampling particles at intermediate steps based on scores computed using functions called potentials. Potentials are defined using rewards for intermediate states and are selected such that a high value indicates that the particle will yield a high-reward sample. We explore various choices of potentials, intermediate rewards, and samplers. We evaluate FK steering on text-to-image and text diffusion models. For steering text-to-image models with a human preference reward, we find that FK steering a 0.8B parameter model outperforms a 2.6B parameter fine-tuned model on prompt fidelity, with faster sampling and no training. For steering text diffusion models with rewards for text quality and specific text attributes, we find that FK steering generates lower perplexity, more linguistically acceptable outputs and enables gradient-free control of attributes like toxicity. Our results demonstrate that inference-time scaling and steering of diffusion models, even with off-the-shelf rewards, can provide significant sample quality gains and controllability benefits. Code is available at https://github.com/zacharyhorvitz/Fk-Diffusion-Steering .</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06848v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Raghav Singhal, Zachary Horvitz, Ryan Teehan, Mengye Ren, Zhou Yu, Kathleen McKeown, Rajesh Ranganath</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transfer Learning of Tabular Data by Finetuning Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06863</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06863v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Despite the artificial intelligence (AI) revolution, deep learning has yet to achieve much success with tabular data due to heterogeneous feature space and limited sample sizes without viable transfer learning. The new era of generative AI, powered by large language models (LLM), brings unprecedented learning opportunities to diverse data and domains. This paper investigates the effectiveness of an LLM application programming interface (API) and transfer learning of LLM in tabular data classification. LLM APIs respond to input text prompts with tokenized data and instructions, whereas transfer learning finetunes an LLM for a target classification task. This paper proposes an end-to-end finetuning of LLM to demonstrate cross-data transfer learning on ten benchmark data sets when large pre-trained tabular data models do not exist to facilitate transfer learning. The proposed LLM finetuning method outperforms state-of-the-art machine and deep learning methods on tabular data with less than ten features - a standard feature size for tabular data sets. The transfer learning approach uses a fraction of the computational cost of other deep learning or API-based solutions while ensuring competitive or superior classification performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06863v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shourav B. Rabbani, Ibna Kowsar, Manar D. Samad</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Causal Claims in Economics</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06873</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06873v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We analyze over 44,000 NBER and CEPR working papers from 1980 to 2023 using a custom language model to construct knowledge graphs that map economic concepts and their relationships. We distinguish between general claims and those documented via causal inference methods (e.g., DiD, IV, RDD, RCTs). We document a substantial rise in the share of causal claims-from roughly 4% in 1990 to nearly 28% in 2020-reflecting the growing influence of the "credibility revolution." We find that causal narrative complexity (e.g., the depth of causal chains) strongly predicts both publication in top-5 journals and higher citation counts, whereas non-causal complexity tends to be uncorrelated or negatively associated with these outcomes. Novelty is also pivotal for top-5 publication, but only when grounded in credible causal methods: introducing genuinely new causal edges or paths markedly increases both the likelihood of acceptance at leading outlets and long-run citations, while non-causal novelty exhibits weak or even negative effects. Papers engaging with central, widely recognized concepts tend to attract more citations, highlighting a divergence between factors driving publication success and long-term academic impact. Finally, bridging underexplored concept pairs is rewarded primarily when grounded in causal methods, yet such gap filling exhibits no consistent link with future citations. Overall, our findings suggest that methodological rigor and causal innovation are key drivers of academic recognition, but sustained impact may require balancing novel contributions with conceptual integration into established economic discourse.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06873v1</guid>
      <category>econ.GN</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <category>q-fin.EC</category>
      <category>stat.ME</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Prashant Garg, Thiemo Fetzer</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Risk-Averse Finetuning of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06911</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06911v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We consider the challenge of mitigating the generation of negative or toxic content by the Large Language Models (LLMs) in response to certain prompts. We propose integrating risk-averse principles into LLM fine-tuning to minimize the occurrence of harmful outputs, particularly rare but significant events. By optimizing the risk measure of Conditional Value at Risk (CVaR), our methodology trains LLMs to exhibit superior performance in avoiding toxic outputs while maintaining effectiveness in generative tasks. Empirical evaluations on sentiment modification and toxicity mitigation tasks demonstrate the efficacy of risk-averse reinforcement learning with human feedback (RLHF) in promoting a safer and more constructive online discourse environment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06911v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sapana Chaudhary, Ujwal Dinesha, Dileep Kalathil, Srinivas Shakkottai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LEO: Boosting Mixture of Vision Encoders for Multimodal Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06986</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06986v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Enhanced visual understanding serves as a cornerstone for multimodal large language models (MLLMs). Recent hybrid MLLMs incorporate a mixture of vision experts to address the limitations of using a single vision encoder and excessively long visual tokens. Despite the progress of these MLLMs, a research gap remains in effectively integrating diverse vision encoders. This work explores fusion strategies of visual tokens for hybrid MLLMs, leading to the design of LEO, a novel MLLM with a dual-branch vision encoder framework that incorporates a post-adaptation fusion strategy and adaptive tiling: for each segmented tile of the input images, LEO sequentially interleaves the visual tokens from its two vision encoders. Extensive evaluation across 13 vision-language benchmarks reveals that LEO outperforms state-of-the-art open-source MLLMs and hybrid MLLMs on the majority of tasks. Furthermore, we show that LEO can be adapted to the specialized domain of autonomous driving without altering the model architecture or training recipe, achieving competitive performance compared to existing baselines. The code and model will be publicly available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06986v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mozhgan Nasr Azadani, James Riddell, Sean Sedwards, Krzysztof Czarnecki</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging ASIC AI Chips for Homomorphic Encryption</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.07047</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.07047v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Cloud-based services are making the outsourcing of sensitive client data increasingly common. Although homomorphic encryption (HE) offers strong privacy guarantee, it requires substantially more resources than computing on plaintext, often leading to unacceptably large latencies in getting the results. HE accelerators have emerged to mitigate this latency issue, but with the high cost of ASICs. In this paper we show that HE primitives can be converted to AI operators and accelerated on existing ASIC AI accelerators, like TPUs, which are already widely deployed in the cloud. Adapting such accelerators for HE requires (1) supporting modular multiplication, (2) high-precision arithmetic in software, and (3) efficient mapping on matrix engines. We introduce the CROSS compiler (1) to adopt Barrett reduction to provide modular reduction support using multiplier and adder, (2) Basis Aligned Transformation (BAT) to convert high-precision multiplication as low-precision matrix-vector multiplication, (3) Matrix Aligned Transformation (MAT) to covert vectorized modular operation with reduction into matrix multiplication that can be efficiently processed on 2D spatial matrix engine. Our evaluation of CROSS on a Google TPUv4 demonstrates significant performance improvements, with up to 161x and 5x speedup compared to the previous work on many-core CPUs and V100. The kernel-level codes are open-sourced at https://github.com/google/jaxite.git.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.07047v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.AR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.PL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jianming Tong, Tianhao Huang, Leo de Castro, Anirudh Itagi, Jingtian Dang, Anupam Golder, Asra Ali, Jevin Jiang,  Arvind, G. Edward Suh, Tushar Krishna</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research on the Online Update Method for Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) Model with Incremental Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.07063</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.07063v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In the contemporary context of rapid advancements in information technology and the exponential growth of data volume, language models are confronted with significant challenges in effectively navigating the dynamic and ever-evolving information landscape to update and adapt to novel knowledge in real time. In this work, an online update method is proposed, which is based on the existing Retrieval Enhanced Generation (RAG) model with multiple innovation mechanisms. Firstly, the dynamic memory is used to capture the emerging data samples, and then gradually integrate them into the core model through a tunable knowledge distillation strategy. At the same time, hierarchical indexing and multi-layer gating mechanism are introduced into the retrieval module to ensure that the retrieved content is more targeted and accurate. Finally, a multi-stage network structure is established for different types of inputs in the generation stage, and cross-attention matching and screening are carried out on the intermediate representations of each stage to ensure the effective integration and iterative update of new and old knowledge. Experimental results show that the proposed method is better than the existing mainstream comparison models in terms of knowledge retention and inference accuracy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.07063v1</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuxin Fan, Yuxiang Wang, Lipeng Liu, Xirui Tang, Na Sun, Zidong Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BIOMEDICA: An Open Biomedical Image-Caption Archive, Dataset, and Vision-Language Models Derived from Scientific Literature</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.07171</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.07171v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The development of vision-language models (VLMs) is driven by large-scale and diverse multimodal datasets. However, progress toward generalist biomedical VLMs is limited by the lack of annotated, publicly accessible datasets across biology and medicine. Existing efforts are restricted to narrow domains, missing the full diversity of biomedical knowledge encoded in scientific literature. To address this gap, we introduce BIOMEDICA, a scalable, open-source framework to extract, annotate, and serialize the entirety of the PubMed Central Open Access subset into an easy-to-use, publicly accessible dataset.Our framework produces a comprehensive archive with over 24 million unique image-text pairs from over 6 million articles. Metadata and expert-guided annotations are also provided. We demonstrate the utility and accessibility of our resource by releasing BMCA-CLIP, a suite of CLIP-style models continuously pre-trained on the BIOMEDICA dataset via streaming, eliminating the need to download 27 TB of data locally.On average, our models achieve state-of-the-art performance across 40 tasks - spanning pathology, radiology, ophthalmology, dermatology, surgery, molecular biology, parasitology, and cell biology - excelling in zero-shot classification with a 6.56% average improvement (as high as 29.8% and 17.5% in dermatology and ophthalmology, respectively), and stronger image-text retrieval, all while using 10x less compute. To foster reproducibility and collaboration, we release our codebase and dataset for the broader research community.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.07171v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alejandro Lozano, Min Woo Sun, James Burgess, Liangyu Chen, Jeffrey J Nirschl, Jeffrey Gu, Ivan Lopez, Josiah Aklilu, Austin Wolfgang Katzer, Collin Chiu, Anita Rau, Xiaohan Wang, Yuhui Zhang, Alfred Seunghoon Song, Robert Tibshirani, Serena Yeung-Levy</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Vision-Language Models Evaluate Handwritten Math?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.07244</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.07244v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recent advancements in Vision-Language Models (VLMs) have opened new possibilities in automatic grading of handwritten student responses, particularly in mathematics. However, a comprehensive study to test the ability of VLMs to evaluate and reason over handwritten content remains absent. To address this gap, we introduce FERMAT, a benchmark designed to assess the ability of VLMs to detect, localize and correct errors in handwritten mathematical content. FERMAT spans four key error dimensions - computational, conceptual, notational, and presentation - and comprises over 2,200 handwritten math solutions derived from 609 manually curated problems from grades 7-12 with intentionally introduced perturbations. Using FERMAT we benchmark nine VLMs across three tasks: error detection, localization, and correction. Our results reveal significant shortcomings in current VLMs in reasoning over handwritten text, with Gemini-1.5-Pro achieving the highest error correction rate (77%). We also observed that some models struggle with processing handwritten content, as their accuracy improves when handwritten inputs are replaced with printed text or images. These findings highlight the limitations of current VLMs and reveal new avenues for improvement. We release FERMAT and all the associated resources in the open-source to drive further research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.07244v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Oikantik Nath, Hanani Bathina, Mohammed Safi Ur Rahman Khan, Mitesh M. Khapra</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Audio-CoT: Exploring Chain-of-Thought Reasoning in Large Audio Language Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.07246</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.07246v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large Audio-Language Models (LALMs) have demonstrated remarkable performance in tasks involving audio perception and understanding, such as speech recognition and audio captioning. However, their reasoning capabilities - critical for solving complex real-world problems - remain underexplored. In this work, we conduct the first exploration into integrating Chain-of-Thought (CoT) reasoning into LALMs to enhance their reasoning ability across auditory modalities. We evaluate representative CoT methods, analyzing their performance in both information extraction and reasoning tasks across sound, music, and speech domains. Our findings reveal that CoT methods significantly improve performance on easy and medium tasks but encounter challenges with hard tasks, where reasoning chains can confuse the model rather than improve accuracy. Additionally, we identify a positive correlation between reasoning path length and accuracy, demonstrating the potential of scaling inference for advanced instruction-following and reasoning. This study not only highlights the promise of CoT in enhancing LALM reasoning capabilities but also identifies key limitations and provides actionable directions for future research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.07246v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ziyang Ma, Zhuo Chen, Yuping Wang, Eng Siong Chng, Xie Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joint Automatic Speech Recognition And Structure Learning For Better Speech Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.07329</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.07329v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Spoken language understanding (SLU) is a structure prediction task in the field of speech. Recently, many works on SLU that treat it as a sequence-to-sequence task have achieved great success. However, This method is not suitable for simultaneous speech recognition and understanding. In this paper, we propose a joint speech recognition and structure learning framework (JSRSL), an end-to-end SLU model based on span, which can accurately transcribe speech and extract structured content simultaneously. We conduct experiments on name entity recognition and intent classification using the Chinese dataset AISHELL-NER and the English dataset SLURP. The results show that our proposed method not only outperforms the traditional sequence-to-sequence method in both transcription and extraction capabilities but also achieves state-of-the-art performance on the two datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.07329v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiliang Hu, Zuchao Li, Mengjia Shen, Haojun Ai, Sheng Li, Jun Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parallel Key-Value Cache Fusion for Position Invariant RAG</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.07523</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.07523v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recent advancements in Large Language Models (LLMs) underscore the necessity of Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) to leverage external information. However, LLMs are sensitive to the position of relevant information within contexts and tend to generate incorrect responses when such information is placed in the middle, known as `Lost in the Middle' phenomenon. In this paper, we introduce a framework that generates consistent outputs for decoder-only models, irrespective of the input context order. Experimental results for three open domain question answering tasks demonstrate position invariance, where the model is not sensitive to input context order, and superior robustness to irrelevent passages compared to prevailing approaches for RAG pipelines.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.07523v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Philhoon Oh, Jinwoo Shin, James Thorne</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SST-EM: Advanced Metrics for Evaluating Semantic, Spatial and Temporal Aspects in Video Editing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.07554</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.07554v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Video editing models have advanced significantly, but evaluating their performance remains challenging. Traditional metrics, such as CLIP text and image scores, often fall short: text scores are limited by inadequate training data and hierarchical dependencies, while image scores fail to assess temporal consistency. We present SST-EM (Semantic, Spatial, and Temporal Evaluation Metric), a novel evaluation framework that leverages modern Vision-Language Models (VLMs), Object Detection, and Temporal Consistency checks. SST-EM comprises four components: (1) semantic extraction from frames using a VLM, (2) primary object tracking with Object Detection, (3) focused object refinement via an LLM agent, and (4) temporal consistency assessment using a Vision Transformer (ViT). These components are integrated into a unified metric with weights derived from human evaluations and regression analysis. The name SST-EM reflects its focus on Semantic, Spatial, and Temporal aspects of video evaluation. SST-EM provides a comprehensive evaluation of semantic fidelity and temporal smoothness in video editing. The source code is available in the \textbf{\href{https://github.com/custommetrics-sst/SST_CustomEvaluationMetrics.git}{GitHub Repository}}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.07554v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Varun Biyyala, Bharat Chanderprakash Kathuria, Jialu Li, Youshan Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Privacy-Preserving Prompt Tuning for Large Language Model Services</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2305.06212</link>
      <description>arXiv:2305.06212v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Prompt tuning provides an efficient way for users to customize Large Language Models (LLMs) with their private data in the emerging LLM service scenario. However, the sensitive nature of private data brings the need for privacy preservation in LLM service customization. Based on prompt tuning, we propose Privacy-Preserving Prompt Tuning (RAPT), a framework that provides privacy guarantees for LLM services. \textsc{rapt} adopts a local privacy setting, allowing users to privatize their data locally with local differential privacy. As prompt tuning performs poorly when directly trained on privatized data, we introduce a novel privatized token reconstruction task that is trained jointly with the downstream task, allowing LLMs to learn better task-dependent representations. Despite the simplicity of our framework, experiments show that RAPT achieves competitive performance across tasks while providing privacy guarantees against adversaries.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2305.06212v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yansong Li, Zhixing Tan, Yang Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlling Equational Reasoning in Large Language Models with Prompt Interventions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2307.09998</link>
      <description>arXiv:2307.09998v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper investigates how hallucination rates in Large Language Models (LLMs) may be controlled via a symbolic data generation framework, exploring a fundamental relationship between the rate of certain mathematical errors and types of input intervention. Specifically, we systematically generate data for a derivation generation task using a symbolic engine, applying targeted interventions to prompts to perturb features of mathematical derivations such as the surface forms of symbols, equational tree structures, and mathematical context. We then evaluate the effect of prompt interventions across a range of LLMs including fine-tuned T5 models, GPT, and LLaMa-based models. Our experiments suggest that T5-Large can outperform the few-shot performance of GPT-4 on various evaluation sets generated via the framework. However, an extensive evaluation based on human analysis, template-based error detection, and text generation metrics reveals model weaknesses beyond what the reference-based metrics singularly describe. We use these results to tie characteristic distributional footprints of interventions to the human evaluation of LLM derivation quality, potentially leading to significant control over fine-grained mathematical capabilities of language models with respect to specific types of errors.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2307.09998v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>math.HO</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jordan Meadows, Marco Valentino, Andre Freitas</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward Adaptive Large Language Models Structured Pruning via Hybrid-grained Weight Importance Assessment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.10799</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.10799v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Structured pruning for large language models (LLMs) has garnered significant academic interest due to its ability to efficiently compress and accelerate LLMs by eliminating redundant weight groups at a coarse-grained granularity. Current structured pruning methods for LLMs typically depend on a singular granularity for assessing weight importance, resulting in notable performance degradation in downstream tasks. Intriguingly, our empirical investigations reveal that utilizing unstructured pruning, which achieves better performance retention by pruning weights at a finer granularity, \emph{i.e.}, individual weights, yields significantly varied sparse LLM structures when juxtaposed to structured pruning. This suggests that evaluating both holistic and individual assessment for weight importance is essential for LLM pruning. Building on this insight, we introduce the Hybrid-grained Weight Importance Assessment (HyWIA), a novel method that merges fine-grained and coarse-grained evaluations of weight importance for the pruning of LLMs. Leveraging an attention mechanism, HyWIA adaptively determines the optimal blend of granularity in weight importance assessments in an end-to-end pruning manner. Extensive experiments on LLaMA-V1/V2, Vicuna, Baichuan, and Bloom across various benchmarks demonstrate the effectiveness of HyWIA in pruning LLMs. For example, HyWIA surpasses the cutting-edge LLM-Pruner by an average margin of 2.82% in accuracy across seven downstream tasks when pruning LLaMA-7B by 50%.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.10799v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jun Liu, Zhenglun Kong, Pu Zhao, Changdi Yang, Hao Tang, Xuan Shen, Geng Yuan, Wei Niu, Wenbin Zhang, Xue Lin, Dong Huang, Yanzhi Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Balancing Class Accuracies for Language Models in Inference Time via Nonlinear Integer Programming</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.07623</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.07623v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models are good knowledge bases but struggle to perform equally well for all classes in simple text classification tasks. This paper investigates a fundamental inference-time problem in language models: imbalanced class accuracies. We find what's underneath the issue is a tendency to over-predict some classes while under-predicting some others, for both base LLMs and more sophisticatedly trained, larger chat LLMs. This class accuracy imbalance is difficult to solve from the root via ``better'' pre-training or fine-tuning strategies, but we show it can be effectively mitigated via inference-time optimization. To this end, we conceptualize and quantify the over- and under-prediction issue as the Contextual Oddity Bias (COBias), and propose the Debiasing as Nonlinear Integer Programming (DNIP) model to correct in-context learned class probabilities based on minimizing COBias and maximizing overall accuracy, without LLM parameter update. Considering that the DNIP model implicitly contains non-differentiable elements, we therefore use the simulated annealing algorithm to solve. We perform extensive evaluations on three LLMs across seven NLP classification tasks, in different prompting settings. Results show that DNIP simultaneously achieves significant COBias reduction (-27%) and accuracy improvement (+12%) over the conventional ICL approach, suggesting that inference-time mitigation of class accuracy imbalance is a promising direction to push forward LLM performances.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.07623v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ruixi Lin, Yang You</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Zero-Shot Chinese-English Code-Switching ASR with kNN-CTC and Gated Monolingual Datastores</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.03814</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.03814v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The kNN-CTC model has proven to be effective for monolingual automatic speech recognition (ASR). However, its direct application to multilingual scenarios like code-switching, presents challenges. Although there is potential for performance improvement, a kNN-CTC model utilizing a single bilingual datastore can inadvertently introduce undesirable noise from the alternative language. To address this, we propose a novel kNN-CTC-based code-switching ASR (CS-ASR) framework that employs dual monolingual datastores and a gated datastore selection mechanism to reduce noise interference. Our method selects the appropriate datastore for decoding each frame, ensuring the injection of language-specific information into the ASR process. We apply this framework to cutting-edge CTC-based models, developing an advanced CS-ASR system. Extensive experiments demonstrate the remarkable effectiveness of our gated datastore mechanism in enhancing the performance of zero-shot Chinese-English CS-ASR.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.03814v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiaming Zhou, Shiwan Zhao, Hui Wang, Tian-Hao Zhang, Haoqin Sun, Xuechen Wang, Yong Qin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Languages are Easy to Language-Model? A Perspective from Learning Probabilistic Regular Languages</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.04289</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.04289v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: What can large language models learn? By definition, language models (LM) are distributions over strings. Therefore, an intuitive way of addressing the above question is to formalize it as a matter of learnability of classes of distributions over strings. While prior work in this direction focused on assessing the theoretical limits, in contrast, we seek to understand the empirical learnability. Unlike prior empirical work, we evaluate neural LMs on their home turf-learning probabilistic languages-rather than as classifiers of formal languages. In particular, we investigate the learnability of regular LMs (RLMs) by RNN and Transformer LMs. We empirically test the learnability of RLMs as a function of various complexity parameters of the RLM and the hidden state size of the neural LM. We find that the RLM rank, which corresponds to the size of linear space spanned by the logits of its conditional distributions, and the expected length of sampled strings are strong and significant predictors of learnability for both RNNs and Transformers. Several other predictors also reach significance, but with differing patterns between RNNs and Transformers.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.04289v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nadav Borenstein, Anej Svete, Robin Chan, Josef Valvoda, Franz Nowak, Isabelle Augenstein, Eleanor Chodroff, Ryan Cotterell</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>II-Bench: An Image Implication Understanding Benchmark for Multimodal Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.05862</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.05862v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The rapid advancements in the development of multimodal large language models (MLLMs) have consistently led to new breakthroughs on various benchmarks. In response, numerous challenging and comprehensive benchmarks have been proposed to more accurately assess the capabilities of MLLMs. However, there is a dearth of exploration of the higher-order perceptual capabilities of MLLMs. To fill this gap, we propose the Image Implication understanding Benchmark, II-Bench, which aims to evaluate the model's higher-order perception of images. Through extensive experiments on II-Bench across multiple MLLMs, we have made significant findings. Initially, a substantial gap is observed between the performance of MLLMs and humans on II-Bench. The pinnacle accuracy of MLLMs attains 74.8%, whereas human accuracy averages 90%, peaking at an impressive 98%. Subsequently, MLLMs perform worse on abstract and complex images, suggesting limitations in their ability to understand high-level semantics and capture image details. Finally, it is observed that most models exhibit enhanced accuracy when image sentiment polarity hints are incorporated into the prompts. This observation underscores a notable deficiency in their inherent understanding of image sentiment. We believe that II-Bench will inspire the community to develop the next generation of MLLMs, advancing the journey towards expert artificial general intelligence (AGI). II-Bench is publicly available at https://huggingface.co/datasets/m-a-p/II-Bench.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.05862v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ziqiang Liu, Feiteng Fang, Xi Feng, Xinrun Du, Chenhao Zhang, Zekun Wang, Yuelin Bai, Qixuan Zhao, Liyang Fan, Chengguang Gan, Hongquan Lin, Jiaming Li, Yuansheng Ni, Haihong Wu, Yaswanth Narsupalli, Zhigang Zheng, Chengming Li, Xiping Hu, Ruifeng Xu, Xiaojun Chen, Min Yang, Jiaheng Liu, Ruibo Liu, Wenhao Huang, Ge Zhang, Shiwen Ni</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Encoder vs Decoder: Comparative Analysis of Encoder and Decoder Language Models on Multilingual NLU Tasks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.13469</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.13469v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper explores the performance of encoder and decoder language models on multilingual Natural Language Understanding (NLU) tasks, with a broad focus on Germanic languages. Building upon the ScandEval benchmark, initially restricted to evaluating encoder models, we extend the evaluation framework to include decoder models. We introduce a method for evaluating decoder models on NLU tasks and apply it to the languages Danish, Swedish, Norwegian, Icelandic, Faroese, German, Dutch, and English. Through a series of experiments and analyses, we also address research questions regarding the comparative performance of encoder and decoder models, the impact of NLU task types, and the variation across language resources. Our findings reveal that encoder models can achieve significantly better NLU performance than decoder models despite having orders of magnitude fewer parameters. Additionally, we investigate the correlation between decoders and task performance via a UMAP analysis, shedding light on the unique capabilities of decoder and encoder models. This study contributes to a deeper understanding of language model paradigms in NLU tasks and provides valuable insights for model selection and evaluation in multilingual settings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.13469v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dan Saattrup Nielsen, Kenneth Enevoldsen, Peter Schneider-Kamp</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Understanding Multi-Task Learning (Generalization) of LLMs via Detecting and Exploring Task-Specific Neurons</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.06488</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.06488v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: While large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated superior multi-task capabilities, understanding the learning mechanisms behind this is still a challenging problem. In this paper, we attempt to understand such mechanisms from the perspective of neurons. Specifically, we detect task-sensitive neurons in LLMs via gradient attribution on task-specific data. Through extensive deactivation and fine-tuning experiments, we demonstrate that the detected neurons are highly correlated with the given task, which we term as task-specific neurons. With these identified task-specific neurons, we delve into two common problems in multi-task learning and continuous learning: Generalization and Catastrophic Forgetting. We find that the overlap of task-specific neurons is strongly associated with generalization and specialization across tasks. Interestingly, at certain layers of LLMs, there is a high similarity in the parameters of different task-specific neurons, and such similarity is highly correlated with the generalization performance. Inspired by these findings, we propose a neuron-level continuous fine-tuning method that only fine-tunes the current task-specific neurons during continuous learning, and extensive experiments demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed method. Our study provides insights into the interpretability of LLMs in multi-task learning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.06488v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yongqi Leng, Deyi Xiong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPIQA: A Dataset for Multimodal Question Answering on Scientific Papers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.09413</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.09413v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Seeking answers to questions within long scientific research articles is a crucial area of study that aids readers in quickly addressing their inquiries. However, existing question-answering (QA) datasets based on scientific papers are limited in scale and focus solely on textual content. We introduce SPIQA (Scientific Paper Image Question Answering), the first large-scale QA dataset specifically designed to interpret complex figures and tables within the context of scientific research articles across various domains of computer science. Leveraging the breadth of expertise and ability of multimodal large language models (MLLMs) to understand figures, we employ automatic and manual curation to create the dataset. We craft an information-seeking task on interleaved images and text that involves multiple images covering plots, charts, tables, schematic diagrams, and result visualizations. SPIQA comprises 270K questions divided into training, validation, and three different evaluation splits. Through extensive experiments with 12 prominent foundational models, we evaluate the ability of current multimodal systems to comprehend the nuanced aspects of research articles. Additionally, we propose a Chain-of-Thought (CoT) evaluation strategy with in-context retrieval that allows fine-grained, step-by-step assessment and improves model performance. We further explore the upper bounds of performance enhancement with additional textual information, highlighting its promising potential for future research and the dataset's impact on revolutionizing how we interact with scientific literature.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.09413v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shraman Pramanick, Rama Chellappa, Subhashini Venugopalan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DiReCT: Diagnostic Reasoning for Clinical Notes via Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.01933</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.01933v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have recently showcased remarkable capabilities, spanning a wide range of tasks and applications, including those in the medical domain. Models like GPT-4 excel in medical question answering but may face challenges in the lack of interpretability when handling complex tasks in real clinical settings. We thus introduce the diagnostic reasoning dataset for clinical notes (DiReCT), aiming at evaluating the reasoning ability and interpretability of LLMs compared to human doctors. It contains 511 clinical notes, each meticulously annotated by physicians, detailing the diagnostic reasoning process from observations in a clinical note to the final diagnosis. Additionally, a diagnostic knowledge graph is provided to offer essential knowledge for reasoning, which may not be covered in the training data of existing LLMs. Evaluations of leading LLMs on DiReCT bring out a significant gap between their reasoning ability and that of human doctors, highlighting the critical need for models that can reason effectively in real-world clinical scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.01933v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bowen Wang, Jiuyang Chang, Yiming Qian, Guoxin Chen, Junhao Chen, Zhouqiang Jiang, Jiahao Zhang, Yuta Nakashima, Hajime Nagahara</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge in Superposition: Unveiling the Failures of Lifelong Knowledge Editing for Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07413</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07413v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Knowledge editing aims to update outdated or incorrect knowledge in large language models (LLMs). However, current knowledge editing methods have limited scalability for lifelong editing. This study explores the fundamental reason why knowledge editing fails in lifelong editing. We begin with the closed-form solution derived from linear associative memory, which underpins state-of-the-art knowledge editing methods. We extend the solution from single editing to lifelong editing, and through rigorous mathematical derivation, identify an interference term in the final solution, suggesting that editing knowledge may impact irrelevant knowledge. Further analysis of the interference term reveals a close relationship with superposition between knowledge representations. When knowledge superposition does not exist in language models, the interference term vanishes, allowing for lossless knowledge editing. Experiments across numerous language models reveal that knowledge superposition is universal, exhibiting high kurtosis, zero mean, and heavy-tailed distributions with clear scaling laws. Ultimately, by combining theory and experiments, we demonstrate that knowledge superposition is the fundamental reason for the failure of lifelong editing. Moreover, this is the first study to investigate knowledge editing from the perspective of superposition and provides a comprehensive observation of superposition across numerous real-world language models. Code available at https://github.com/ChenhuiHu/knowledge_in_superposition.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07413v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chenhui Hu, Pengfei Cao, Yubo Chen, Kang Liu, Jun Zhao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Small Language Models can Outperform Humans in Short Creative Writing: A Study Comparing SLMs with Humans and LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.11547</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.11547v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this paper, we evaluate the creative fiction writing abilities of a fine-tuned small language model (SLM), BART-large, and compare its performance to human writers and two large language models (LLMs): GPT-3.5 and GPT-4o. Our evaluation consists of two experiments: (i) a human study in which 68 participants rated short stories from humans and the SLM on grammaticality, relevance, creativity, and attractiveness, and (ii) a qualitative linguistic analysis examining the textual characteristics of stories produced by each model. In the first experiment, BART-large outscored average human writers overall (2.11 vs. 1.85), a 14% relative improvement, though the slight human advantage in creativity was not statistically significant. In the second experiment, qualitative analysis showed that while GPT-4o demonstrated near-perfect coherence and used less cliche phrases, it tended to produce more predictable language, with only 3% of its synopses featuring surprising associations (compared to 15% for BART). These findings highlight how model size and fine-tuning influence the balance between creativity, fluency, and coherence in creative writing tasks, and demonstrate that smaller models can, in certain contexts, rival both humans and larger models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.11547v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Guillermo Marco, Luz Rello, Julio Gonzalo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MIO: A Foundation Model on Multimodal Tokens</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.17692</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.17692v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this paper, we introduce MIO, a novel foundation model built on multimodal tokens, capable of understanding and generating speech, text, images, and videos in an end-to-end, autoregressive manner. While the emergence of large language models (LLMs) and multimodal large language models (MM-LLMs) propels advancements in artificial general intelligence through their versatile capabilities, they still lack true any-to-any understanding and generation. Recently, the release of GPT-4o has showcased the remarkable potential of any-to-any LLMs for complex real-world tasks, enabling omnidirectional input and output across images, speech, and text. However, it is closed-source and does not support the generation of multimodal interleaved sequences. To address this gap, we present MIO, which is trained on a mixture of discrete tokens across four modalities using causal multimodal modeling. MIO undergoes a four-stage training process: (1) alignment pre-training, (2) interleaved pre-training, (3) speech-enhanced pre-training, and (4) comprehensive supervised fine-tuning on diverse textual, visual, and speech tasks. Our experimental results indicate that MIO exhibits competitive, and in some cases superior, performance compared to previous dual-modal baselines, any-to-any model baselines, and even modality-specific baselines. Moreover, MIO demonstrates advanced capabilities inherent to its any-to-any feature, such as interleaved video-text generation, chain-of-visual-thought reasoning, visual guideline generation, instructional image editing, etc.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.17692v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zekun Wang, King Zhu, Chunpu Xu, Wangchunshu Zhou, Jiaheng Liu, Yibo Zhang, Jiashuo Wang, Ning Shi, Siyu Li, Yizhi Li, Haoran Que, Zhaoxiang Zhang, Yuanxing Zhang, Ge Zhang, Ke Xu, Jie Fu, Wenhao Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessment and manipulation of latent constructs in pre-trained language models using psychometric scales</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.19655</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.19655v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Human-like personality traits have recently been discovered in large language models, raising the hypothesis that their (known and as yet undiscovered) biases conform with human latent psychological constructs. While large conversational models may be tricked into answering psychometric questionnaires, the latent psychological constructs of thousands of simpler transformers, trained for other tasks, cannot be assessed because appropriate psychometric methods are currently lacking. Here, we show how standard psychological questionnaires can be reformulated into natural language inference prompts, and we provide a code library to support the psychometric assessment of arbitrary models. We demonstrate, using a sample of 88 publicly available models, the existence of human-like mental health-related constructs (including anxiety, depression, and Sense of Coherence) which conform with standard theories in human psychology and show similar correlations and mitigation strategies. The ability to interpret and rectify the performance of language models by using psychological tools can boost the development of more explainable, controllable, and trustworthy models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.19655v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Maor Reuben, Ortal Slobodin, Aviad Elyshar, Idan-Chaim Cohen, Orna Braun-Lewensohn, Odeya Cohen, Rami Puzis</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Film Subtitles: Is YouTube the Best Approximation of Spoken Vocabulary?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.03240</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.03240v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Word frequency is a key variable in psycholinguistics, useful for modeling human familiarity with words even in the era of large language models (LLMs). Frequency in film subtitles has proved to be a particularly good approximation of everyday language exposure. For many languages, however, film subtitles are not easily available, or are overwhelmingly translated from English. We demonstrate that frequencies extracted from carefully processed YouTube subtitles provide an approximation comparable to, and often better than, the best currently available resources. Moreover, they are available for languages for which a high-quality subtitle or speech corpus does not exist. We use YouTube subtitles to construct frequency norms for five diverse languages, Chinese, English, Indonesian, Japanese, and Spanish, and evaluate their correlation with lexical decision time, word familiarity, and lexical complexity. In addition to being strongly correlated with two psycholinguistic variables, a simple linear regression on the new frequencies achieves a new high score on a lexical complexity prediction task in English and Japanese, surpassing both models trained on film subtitle frequencies and the LLM GPT-4. Our code, the frequency lists, fastText word embeddings, and statistical language models are freely available at https://github.com/naist-nlp/tubelex.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.03240v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Adam Nohejl, Frederikus Hudi, Eunike Andriani Kardinata, Shintaro Ozaki, Maria Angelica Riera Machin, Hongyu Sun, Justin Vasselli, Taro Watanabe</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI as Humanity's Salieri: Quantifying Linguistic Creativity of Language Models via Systematic Attribution of Machine Text against Web Text</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.04265</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.04265v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Creativity has long been considered one of the most difficult aspect of human intelligence for AI to mimic. However, the rise of Large Language Models (LLMs), like ChatGPT, has raised questions about whether AI can match or even surpass human creativity. We present CREATIVITY INDEX as the first step to quantify the linguistic creativity of a text by reconstructing it from existing text snippets on the web. CREATIVITY INDEX is motivated by the hypothesis that the seemingly remarkable creativity of LLMs may be attributable in large part to the creativity of human-written texts on the web. To compute CREATIVITY INDEX efficiently, we introduce DJ SEARCH, a novel dynamic programming algorithm that can search verbatim and near-verbatim matches of text snippets from a given document against the web. Experiments reveal that the CREATIVITY INDEX of professional human authors is on average 66.2% higher than that of LLMs, and that alignment reduces the CREATIVITY INDEX of LLMs by an average of 30.1%. In addition, we find that distinguished authors like Hemingway exhibit measurably higher CREATIVITY INDEX compared to other human writers. Finally, we demonstrate that CREATIVITY INDEX can be used as a surprisingly effective criterion for zero-shot machine text detection, surpassing the strongest existing zero-shot system, DetectGPT, by a significant margin of 30.2%, and even outperforming the strongest supervised system, GhostBuster, in five out of six domains.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.04265v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ximing Lu, Melanie Sclar, Skyler Hallinan, Niloofar Mireshghallah, Jiacheng Liu, Seungju Han, Allyson Ettinger, Liwei Jiang, Khyathi Chandu, Nouha Dziri, Yejin Choi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FlatQuant: Flatness Matters for LLM Quantization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.09426</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.09426v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recently, quantization has been widely used for the compression and acceleration of large language models~(LLMs). Due to the outliers in LLMs, it is crucial to flatten weights and activations to minimize quantization error with the equally spaced quantization points. Prior research explores various pre-quantization transformations to suppress outliers, such as per-channel scaling and Hadamard transformation. However, we observe that these transformed weights and activations can still remain steep and outspread. In this paper, we propose FlatQuant (Fast and Learnable Affine Transformation), a new post-training quantization approach to enhance flatness of weights and activations. Our approach identifies optimal affine transformations tailored to each linear layer, calibrated in hours via a lightweight objective. To reduce runtime overhead, we apply Kronecker decomposition to the transformation matrices, and fuse all operations in FlatQuant into a single kernel. Extensive experiments show that FlatQuant sets up a new state-of-the-art quantization benchmark. For instance, it achieves less than $\textbf{1}\%$ accuracy drop for W4A4 quantization on the LLaMA-3-70B model, surpassing SpinQuant by $\textbf{7.5}\%$. For inference latency, FlatQuant reduces the slowdown induced by pre-quantization transformation from 0.26x of QuaRot to merely $\textbf{0.07x}$, bringing up to $\textbf{2.3x}$ speedup for prefill and $\textbf{1.7x}$ speedup for decoding, respectively. Code is available at: \url{https://github.com/ruikangliu/FlatQuant}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.09426v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuxuan Sun, Ruikang Liu, Haoli Bai, Han Bao, Kang Zhao, Yuening Li, Jiaxin Hu, Xianzhi Yu, Lu Hou, Chun Yuan, Xin Jiang, Wulong Liu, Jun Yao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accurate and Regret-aware Numerical Problem Solver for Tabular Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.12846</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.12846v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Question answering on free-form tables (a.k.a. TableQA) is a challenging task because of the flexible structure and complex schema of tables. Recent studies use Large Language Models (LLMs) for this task, exploiting their capability in understanding the questions and tabular data, which are typically given in natural language and contain many textual fields, respectively. While this approach has shown promising results, it overlooks the challenges brought by numerical values which are common in tabular data, and LLMs are known to struggle with such values. We aim to address this issue, and we propose a model named TabLaP that uses LLMs as a planner rather than an answer generator. This approach exploits LLMs' capability in multi-step reasoning while leaving the actual numerical calculations to a Python interpreter for accurate calculation. Recognizing the inaccurate nature of LLMs, we further make a first attempt to quantify the trustworthiness of the answers produced by TabLaP, such that users can use TabLaP in a regret-aware manner. Experimental results on two benchmark datasets show that TabLaP is substantially more accurate than the state-of-the-art models, improving the answer accuracy by 5.7% and 5.8% on the two datasets, respectively.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.12846v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuxiang Wang, Jianzhong Qi, Junhao Gan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DefVerify: Do Hate Speech Models Reflect Their Dataset's Definition?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.15911</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.15911v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: When building a predictive model, it is often difficult to ensure that application-specific requirements are encoded by the model that will eventually be deployed. Consider researchers working on hate speech detection. They will have an idea of what is considered hate speech, but building a model that reflects their view accurately requires preserving those ideals throughout the workflow of data set construction and model training. Complications such as sampling bias, annotation bias, and model misspecification almost always arise, possibly resulting in a gap between the application specification and the model's actual behavior upon deployment. To address this issue for hate speech detection, we propose DefVerify: a 3-step procedure that (i) encodes a user-specified definition of hate speech, (ii) quantifies to what extent the model reflects the intended definition, and (iii) tries to identify the point of failure in the workflow. We use DefVerify to find gaps between definition and model behavior when applied to six popular hate speech benchmark datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.15911v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Urja Khurana, Eric Nalisnick, Antske Fokkens</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Backpropagation of the Wave Network</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.06989</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.06989v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper provides an in-depth analysis of Wave Network, a novel token representation method derived from the Wave Network, designed to capture both global and local semantics of input text through wave-inspired complex vectors. In complex vector token representation, each token is represented with a magnitude component, capturing the global semantics of the entire input text, and a phase component, encoding the relationships between individual tokens and the global semantics. Building on prior research that demonstrated the effectiveness of wave-like operations, such as interference and modulation, during forward propagation, this study investigates the convergence behavior, backpropagation characteristics, and embedding independence within the Token2Wave framework. A detailed computational complexity analysis shows that Token2Wave can significantly reduce video memory usage and training time compared to BERT. Gradient comparisons for the [CLS] token, total input text, and classifier parameters further highlight Token2Wave's unique characteristics. This research offers new insights into wave-based token representations, demonstrating their potential to enable efficient and computationally friendly language model architectures.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.06989v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xin Zhang, Victor S. Sheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Multimodal LLMs: the Mechanistic Interpretability of Llava in Visual Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.10950</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.10950v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Understanding the mechanisms behind Large Language Models (LLMs) is crucial for designing improved models and strategies. While recent studies have yielded valuable insights into the mechanisms of textual LLMs, the mechanisms of Multi-modal Large Language Models (MLLMs) remain underexplored. In this paper, we apply mechanistic interpretability methods to analyze the visual question answering (VQA) mechanisms in the first MLLM, Llava. We compare the mechanisms between VQA and textual QA (TQA) in color answering tasks and find that: a) VQA exhibits a mechanism similar to the in-context learning mechanism observed in TQA; b) the visual features exhibit significant interpretability when projecting the visual embeddings into the embedding space; and c) Llava enhances the existing capabilities of the corresponding textual LLM Vicuna during visual instruction tuning. Based on these findings, we develop an interpretability tool to help users and researchers identify important visual locations for final predictions, aiding in the understanding of visual hallucination. Our method demonstrates faster and more effective results compared to existing interpretability approaches. Code: \url{https://github.com/zepingyu0512/llava-mechanism}</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.10950v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zeping Yu, Sophia Ananiadou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eradicating Social Biases in Sentiment Analysis using Semantic Blinding and Semantic Propagation Graph Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.12493</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.12493v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper introduces the Semantic Propagation Graph Neural Network (SProp GNN), a machine learning sentiment analysis (SA) architecture that relies exclusively on syntactic structures and word-level emotional cues to predict emotions in text. By semantically blinding the model to information about specific words, it is robust to social biases such as political or gender bias that have been plaguing previous machine learning-based SA systems. The SProp GNN shows performance superior to lexicon-based alternatives such as VADER (Valence Aware Dictionary and Sentiment Reasoner) and EmoAtlas on two different prediction tasks, and across two languages. Additionally, it approaches the accuracy of transformer-based models while significantly reducing bias in emotion prediction tasks. By offering improved explainability and reducing bias, the SProp GNN bridges the methodological gap between interpretable lexicon approaches and powerful, yet often opaque, deep learning models, offering a robust tool for fair and effective emotion analysis in understanding human behavior through text.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.12493v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hubert Plisiecki</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Profiling Bias in LLMs: Stereotype Dimensions in Contextual Word Embeddings</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.16527</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.16527v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are the foundation of the current successes of artificial intelligence (AI), however, they are unavoidably biased. To effectively communicate the risks and encourage mitigation efforts these models need adequate and intuitive descriptions of their discriminatory properties, appropriate for all audiences of AI. We suggest bias profiles with respect to stereotype dimensions based on dictionaries from social psychology research. Along these dimensions we investigate gender bias in contextual embeddings, across contexts and layers, and generate stereotype profiles for twelve different LLMs, demonstrating their intuition and use case for exposing and visualizing bias.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.16527v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Carolin M. Schuster, Maria-Alexandra Dinisor, Shashwat Ghatiwala, Georg Groh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don't Command, Cultivate: An Exploratory Study of System-2 Alignment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.17075</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.17075v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The o1 system card identifies the o1 models as the most robust within OpenAI, with their defining characteristic being the progression from rapid, intuitive thinking to slower, more deliberate reasoning. This observation motivated us to investigate the influence of System-2 thinking patterns on model safety. In our preliminary research, we conducted safety evaluations of the o1 model, including complex jailbreak attack scenarios using adversarial natural language prompts and mathematical encoding prompts. Our findings indicate that the o1 model demonstrates relatively improved safety performance; however, it still exhibits vulnerabilities, particularly against jailbreak attacks employing mathematical encoding. Through detailed case analysis, we identified specific patterns in the o1 model's responses. We also explored the alignment of System-2 safety in open-source models using prompt engineering and supervised fine-tuning techniques. Experimental results show that some simple methods to encourage the model to carefully scrutinize user requests are beneficial for model safety. Additionally, we proposed a implementation plan for process supervision to enhance safety alignment. The implementation details and experimental results will be provided in future versions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.17075v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuhang Wang, Yuxiang Zhang, Yanxu Zhu, Xinyan Wen, Jitao Sang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Critical Tokens Matter: Token-Level Contrastive Estimation Enhances LLM's Reasoning Capability</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.19943</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.19943v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Mathematical reasoning tasks pose significant challenges for large language models (LLMs) because they require precise logical deduction and sequence analysis. In this work, we introduce the concept of critical tokens -- elements within reasoning trajectories that significantly influence incorrect outcomes. We present a novel framework for identifying these tokens through rollout sampling and demonstrate their substantial divergence from traditional error tokens. Through extensive experiments on datasets such as GSM8K and MATH500, we show that identifying and replacing critical tokens significantly improves model accuracy. We propose an efficient methodology for pinpointing these tokens in large-scale datasets using contrastive estimation and extend this framework to enhance model training processes with direct preference optimization (DPO). Experimental results on GSM8K and MATH500 benchmarks with the widely used models Llama-3 (8B and 70B) and Deepseek-math (7B) demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed approach, cDPO. Our results underscore the potential of leveraging critical tokens to reduce errors in reasoning tasks, advancing the development of AI systems capable of robust logical deduction. Our code, annotated datasets, and trained models are available at https://github.com/chenzhiling9954/Critical-Tokens-Matter to support and encourage future research in this promising field.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.19943v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zicheng Lin, Tian Liang, Jiahao Xu, Qiuzhi Lin, Xing Wang, Ruilin Luo, Chufan Shi, Siheng Li, Yujiu Yang, Zhaopeng Tu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MAG-V: A Multi-Agent Framework for Synthetic Data Generation and Verification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.04494</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.04494v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Extending the capabilities of Large Language Models (LLMs) with functions or tools for environment interaction has led to the emergence of the agent paradigm. In industry, training an LLM is not always feasible because of the scarcity of domain data, legal holds on proprietary customer data, rapidly changing business requirements, and the need to prototype new assistants. Agents provide an elegant solution to the above by relying on the zero-shot reasoning abilities of the underlying LLM and utilizing tools to explore and reason over customer data and respond to user requests. However, there are two concerns here: (I) acquiring large scale customer queries for agent testing is time-consuming, and (II) high reliance on the tool call sequence (or trajectory) followed by the agent to respond to user queries may lead to unexpected or incorrect behavior. To address this, we propose MAG-V, a multi-agent framework to first generate a dataset of questions that mimic customer queries; and second, reverse-engineer alternate questions from the responses for trajectory verification. Initial results indicate that our synthetic data can improve agent performance on actual customer queries. Furthermore, our trajectory verification methodology, inspired by distant supervision and using traditional machine learning (ML) models, outperforms a GPT-4o judge baseline by 11% accuracy and matches the performance of a GPT-4 judge on our constructed dataset. Overall, our approach is a step towards unifying diverse task agents into a cohesive framework for achieving an aligned objective.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.04494v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Saptarshi Sengupta, Harsh Vashistha, Kristal Curtis, Akshay Mallipeddi, Abhinav Mathur, Joseph Ross, Liang Gou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mitigating Out-of-Entity Errors in Named Entity Recognition: A Sentence-Level Strategy</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.08434</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.08434v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Many previous models of named entity recognition (NER) suffer from the problem of Out-of-Entity (OOE), i.e., the tokens in the entity mentions of the test samples have not appeared in the training samples, which hinders the achievement of satisfactory performance. To improve OOE-NER performance, in this paper, we propose a new framework, namely S+NER, which fully leverages sentence-level information. Our S+NER achieves better OOE-NER performance mainly due to the following two particular designs. 1) It first exploits the pre-trained language model's capability of understanding the target entity's sentence-level context with a template set. 2) Then, it refines the sentence-level representation based on the positive and negative templates, through a contrastive learning strategy and template pooling method, to obtain better NER results. Our extensive experiments on five benchmark datasets have demonstrated that, our S+NER outperforms some state-of-the-art OOE-NER models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.08434v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Guochao Jiang, Ziqin Luo, Chengwei Hu, Zepeng Ding, Deqing Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identifying and Manipulating Personality Traits in LLMs Through Activation Engineering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10427</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10427v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The field of large language models (LLMs) has grown rapidly in recent years, driven by the desire for better efficiency, interpretability, and safe use. Building on the novel approach of "activation engineering," this study explores personality modification in LLMs, drawing inspiration from research like Refusal in LLMs Is Mediated by a Single Direction (arXiv:2406.11717) and Steering Llama 2 via Contrastive Activation Addition (arXiv:2312.06681). We leverage activation engineering to develop a method for identifying and adjusting activation directions related to personality traits, which may allow for dynamic LLM personality fine-tuning. This work aims to further our understanding of LLM interpretability while examining the ethical implications of such developments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10427v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rumi A. Allbert, James K. Wiles, Vlad Grankovsky</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VaeDiff-DocRE: End-to-end Data Augmentation Framework for Document-level Relation Extraction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.13503</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.13503v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Document-level Relation Extraction (DocRE) aims to identify relationships between entity pairs within a document. However, most existing methods assume a uniform label distribution, resulting in suboptimal performance on real-world, imbalanced datasets. To tackle this challenge, we propose a novel data augmentation approach using generative models to enhance data from the embedding space. Our method leverages the Variational Autoencoder (VAE) architecture to capture all relation-wise distributions formed by entity pair representations and augment data for underrepresented relations. To better capture the multi-label nature of DocRE, we parameterize the VAE's latent space with a Diffusion Model. Additionally, we introduce a hierarchical training framework to integrate the proposed VAE-based augmentation module into DocRE systems. Experiments on two benchmark datasets demonstrate that our method outperforms state-of-the-art models, effectively addressing the long-tail distribution problem in DocRE.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.13503v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Khai Phan Tran, Wen Hua, Xue Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LiveIdeaBench: Evaluating LLMs' Scientific Creativity and Idea Generation with Minimal Context</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.17596</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.17596v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: While Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated remarkable capabilities in scientific tasks, existing evaluation frameworks primarily assess their performance using rich contextual inputs, overlooking their ability to generate novel ideas from minimal information. We introduce LiveIdeaBench, a comprehensive benchmark that evaluates LLMs' scientific creativity and divergent thinking capabilities using single-keyword prompts. Drawing from Guilford's creativity theory, our framework employs a dynamic panel of state-of-the-art LLMs to assess generated ideas across four key dimensions: originality, feasibility, fluency, and flexibility. Through extensive experimentation with 20 leading models across 1,180 keywords spanning 18 scientific domains, we reveal that scientific creative ability shows distinct patterns from general intelligence metrics. Notably, our results demonstrate that models like QwQ-32B-preview achieve comparable creative performance to top-tier models like o1-preview, despite significant gaps in their general intelligence scores. These findings highlight the importance of specialized evaluation frameworks for scientific creativity and suggest that the development of creative capabilities in LLMs may follow different trajectories than traditional problem-solving abilities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.17596v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kai Ruan, Xuan Wang, Jixiang Hong, Peng Wang, Yang Liu, Hao Sun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Global AI Inclusivity: A Large-Scale Multilingual Terminology Dataset (GIST)</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18367</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18367v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The field of machine translation has achieved significant advancements, yet domain-specific terminology translation, particularly in AI, remains challenging. We introduce GIST, a large-scale multilingual AI terminology dataset containing 5K terms extracted from top AI conference papers spanning 2000 to 2023. The terms are translated into Arabic, Chinese, French, Japanese, and Russian using a hybrid framework that combines LLMs for extraction with human expertise for translation. The dataset's quality is benchmarked against existing resources, demonstrating superior translation accuracy through crowdsourced evaluation. GIST is integrated into translation workflows using post-translation refinement methods that require no retraining, where LLM prompting consistently improves BLEU and COMET scores. A web demonstration on the ACL Anthology platform highlights its practical application, showcasing improved accessibility for non-English speakers. This work aims to address critical gaps in AI terminology resources and fosters global inclusivity and collaboration in AI research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18367v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiarui Liu, Iman Ouzzani, Wenkai Li, Lechen Zhang, Tianyue Ou, Houda Bouamor, Zhijing Jin, Mona Diab</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HADES: Hardware Accelerated Decoding for Efficient Speculation in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.19925</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.19925v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have revolutionized natural language processing by understanding and generating human-like text. However, the increasing demand for more sophisticated LLMs presents significant computational challenges due to their scale and complexity. This paper introduces Hardware Accelerated Decoding (HADES), a novel approach to enhance the performance and energy efficiency of LLMs. We address the design of an LLM accelerator with hardware-level speculative decoding support, a concept not previously explored in existing literature. Our work demonstrates how speculative decoding can significantly improve the efficiency of LLM operations, paving the way for more advanced and practical applications of these models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.19925v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.AR</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ze Yang, Yihong Jin, Xinhe Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GliLem: Leveraging GliNER for Contextualized Lemmatization in Estonian</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.20597</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.20597v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We present GliLem -- a novel hybrid lemmatization system for Estonian that enhances the highly accurate rule-based morphological analyzer Vabamorf with an external disambiguation module based on GliNER -- an open vocabulary NER model that is able to match text spans with text labels in natural language. We leverage the flexibility of a pre-trained GliNER model to improve the lemmatization accuracy of Vabamorf by 10% compared to its original disambiguation module and achieve an improvement over the token classification-based baseline. To measure the impact of improvements in lemmatization accuracy on the information retrieval downstream task, we first created an information retrieval dataset for Estonian by automatically translating the DBpedia-Entity dataset from English. We benchmark several token normalization approaches, including lemmatization, on the created dataset using the BM25 algorithm. We observe a substantial improvement in IR metrics when using lemmatization over simplistic stemming. The benefits of improving lemma disambiguation accuracy manifest in small but consistent improvement in the IR recall measure, especially in the setting of high k.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.20597v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aleksei Dorkin, Kairit Sirts</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TrustRAG: Enhancing Robustness and Trustworthiness in RAG</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.00879</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.00879v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) systems enhance large language models (LLMs) by integrating external knowledge sources, enabling more accurate and contextually relevant responses tailored to user queries. However, these systems remain vulnerable to corpus poisoning attacks that can significantly degrade LLM performance through the injection of malicious content. To address these challenges, we propose TrustRAG, a robust framework that systematically filters compromised and irrelevant contents before they are retrieved for generation. Our approach implements a two-stage defense mechanism: At the first stage, it employs K-means clustering to identify potential attack patterns in retrieved documents using cosine similarity and ROUGE metrics as guidance, effectively isolating suspicious content. Secondly, it performs a self-assessment which detects malicious documents and resolves discrepancies between the model's internal knowledge and external information. TrustRAG functions as a plug-and-play, training-free module that integrates seamlessly with any language model, whether open or closed-source. In addition, TrustRAG maintains high contextual relevance while strengthening defenses against corpus poisoning attacks. Through extensive experimental validation, we demonstrate that TrustRAG delivers substantial improvements in retrieval accuracy, efficiency, and attack resistance compared to existing approaches across multiple model architectures and datasets. We have made TrustRAG available as open-source software at \url{https://github.com/HuichiZhou/TrustRAG}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.00879v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Huichi Zhou, Kin-Hei Lee, Zhonghao Zhan, Yue Chen, Zhenhao Li, Zhaoyang Wang, Hamed Haddadi, Emine Yilmaz</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing Singlish Understanding: Bridging the Gap with Datasets and Multimodal Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01034</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01034v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Singlish, a Creole language rooted in English, is a key focus in linguistic research within multilingual and multicultural contexts. However, its spoken form remains underexplored, limiting insights into its linguistic structure and applications. To address this gap, we standardize and annotate the largest spoken Singlish corpus, introducing the Multitask National Speech Corpus (MNSC). These datasets support diverse tasks, including Automatic Speech Recognition (ASR), Spoken Question Answering (SQA), Spoken Dialogue Summarization (SDS), and Paralinguistic Question Answering (PQA). We release standardized splits and a human-verified test set to facilitate further research. Additionally, we propose SingAudioLLM, a multi-task multimodal model leveraging multimodal large language models to handle these tasks concurrently. Experiments reveal our models adaptability to Singlish context, achieving state-of-the-art performance and outperforming prior models by 10-30% in comparison with other AudioLLMs and cascaded solutions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01034v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bin Wang, Xunlong Zou, Shuo Sun, Wenyu Zhang, Yingxu He, Zhuohan Liu, Chengwei Wei, Nancy F. Chen, AiTi Aw</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Step-by-Step Mastery: Enhancing Soft Constraint Following Ability of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04945</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04945v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: It is crucial for large language models (LLMs) to follow instructions that involve multiple constraints. However, soft constraints are semantically related and difficult to verify through automated methods. These constraints remain a significant challenge for LLMs. To enhance the ability of LLMs to follow soft constraints, we initially design a pipeline to obtain high-quality outputs automatically. Additionally, to fully utilize the acquired data, we introduce a training paradigm based on curriculum learning. We experimentally evaluate the effectiveness of our methods in improving LLMs' soft constraint following ability and analyze the factors driving the improvements. The datasets and code are publicly available at https://github.com/Rainier-rq/FollowSoftConstraints.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04945v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qingyu Ren, Jie Zeng, Qianyu He, Jiaqing Liang, Yanghua Xiao, Weikang Zhou, Zeye Sun, Fei Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Migician: Revealing the Magic of Free-Form Multi-Image Grounding in Multimodal Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.05767</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.05767v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The recent advancement of Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) has significantly improved their fine-grained perception of single images and general comprehension across multiple images. However, existing MLLMs still face challenges in achieving precise grounding in complex multi-image scenarios. To address this, we first explore a Chain-of-Thought (CoT) framework that integrates single-image grounding with multi-image comprehension. While partially effective, it remains unstable and struggles to capture abstract visual information due to its non-end-to-end nature. Therefore, we introduce Migician, the first multi-image grounding model capable of performing free-form and accurate grounding across multiple images. To support this, we present the MGrounding-630k dataset, which comprises data for several multi-image grounding tasks derived from existing datasets, along with newly generated free-form grounding instruction-following data. Furthermore, we propose MIG-Bench, a comprehensive benchmark specifically designed for evaluating multi-image grounding capabilities. Experimental results demonstrate that our model achieves significantly superior multi-image grounding capabilities, outperforming the best existing MLLMs by 21.61% and even surpassing much larger 70B models. Our code, model, dataset, and benchmark are fully open-sourced at https://migician-vg.github.io/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.05767v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>You Li, Heyu Huang, Chi Chen, Kaiyu Huang, Chao Huang, Zonghao Guo, Zhiyuan Liu, Jinan Xu, Yuhua Li, Ruixuan Li, Maosong Sun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ConSim: Measuring Concept-Based Explanations' Effectiveness with Automated Simulatability</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.05855</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.05855v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Concept-based explanations work by mapping complex model computations to human-understandable concepts. Evaluating such explanations is very difficult, as it includes not only the quality of the induced space of possible concepts but also how effectively the chosen concepts are communicated to users. Existing evaluation metrics often focus solely on the former, neglecting the latter.    We introduce an evaluation framework for measuring concept explanations via automated simulatability: a simulator's ability to predict the explained model's outputs based on the provided explanations. This approach accounts for both the concept space and its interpretation in an end-to-end evaluation. Human studies for simulatability are notoriously difficult to enact, particularly at the scale of a wide, comprehensive empirical evaluation (which is the subject of this work). We propose using large language models (LLMs) as simulators to approximate the evaluation and report various analyses to make such approximations reliable. Our method allows for scalable and consistent evaluation across various models and datasets. We report a comprehensive empirical evaluation using this framework and show that LLMs provide consistent rankings of explanation methods. Code available at https://github.com/AnonymousConSim/ConSim.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.05855v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Antonin Poch\'e (IRIT), Alon Jacovi (CERCO UMR5549, ANITI), Agustin Martin Picard (CERCO UMR5549, ANITI), Victor Boutin (CERCO UMR5549, ANITI), Fanny Jourdan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChatGPT Needs SPADE (Sustainability, PrivAcy, Digital divide, and Ethics) Evaluation: A Review</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2305.03123</link>
      <description>arXiv:2305.03123v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: ChatGPT is another large language model (LLM) vastly available for the consumers on their devices but due to its performance and ability to converse effectively, it has gained a huge popularity amongst research as well as industrial community. Recently, many studies have been published to show the effectiveness, efficiency, integration, and sentiments of chatGPT and other LLMs. In contrast, this study focuses on the important aspects that are mostly overlooked, i.e. sustainability, privacy, digital divide, and ethics and suggests that not only chatGPT but every subsequent entry in the category of conversational bots should undergo Sustainability, PrivAcy, Digital divide, and Ethics (SPADE) evaluation. This paper discusses in detail the issues and concerns raised over chatGPT in line with aforementioned characteristics. We also discuss the recent EU AI Act briefly in accordance with the SPADE evaluation. We support our hypothesis by some preliminary data collection and visualizations along with hypothesized facts. We also suggest mitigations and recommendations for each of the concerns. Furthermore, we also suggest some policies and recommendations for EU AI policy act concerning ethics, digital divide, and sustainability</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2305.03123v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1007/s12559-024-10285-1</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Cognitive Computation, 2024</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Sunder Ali Khowaja, Parus Khuwaja, Kapal Dev, Weizheng Wang, Lewis Nkenyereye</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quilt-1M: One Million Image-Text Pairs for Histopathology</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2306.11207</link>
      <description>arXiv:2306.11207v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Recent accelerations in multi-modal applications have been made possible with the plethora of image and text data available online. However, the scarcity of analogous data in the medical field, specifically in histopathology, has slowed comparable progress. To enable similar representation learning for histopathology, we turn to YouTube, an untapped resource of videos, offering $1,087$ hours of valuable educational histopathology videos from expert clinicians. From YouTube, we curate QUILT: a large-scale vision-language dataset consisting of $802, 144$ image and text pairs. QUILT was automatically curated using a mixture of models, including large language models, handcrafted algorithms, human knowledge databases, and automatic speech recognition. In comparison, the most comprehensive datasets curated for histopathology amass only around $200$K samples. We combine QUILT with datasets from other sources, including Twitter, research papers, and the internet in general, to create an even larger dataset: QUILT-1M, with $1$M paired image-text samples, marking it as the largest vision-language histopathology dataset to date. We demonstrate the value of QUILT-1M by fine-tuning a pre-trained CLIP model. Our model outperforms state-of-the-art models on both zero-shot and linear probing tasks for classifying new histopathology images across $13$ diverse patch-level datasets of $8$ different sub-pathologies and cross-modal retrieval tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2306.11207v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wisdom Oluchi Ikezogwo, Mehmet Saygin Seyfioglu, Fatemeh Ghezloo, Dylan Stefan Chan Geva, Fatwir Sheikh Mohammed, Pavan Kumar Anand, Ranjay Krishna, Linda Shapiro</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Effectiveness of ASR Representations in Real-world Noisy Speech Emotion Recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.07093</link>
      <description>arXiv:2311.07093v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: This paper proposes an efficient attempt to noisy speech emotion recognition (NSER). Conventional NSER approaches have proven effective in mitigating the impact of artificial noise sources, such as white Gaussian noise, but are limited to non-stationary noises in real-world environments due to their complexity and uncertainty. To overcome this limitation, we introduce a new method for NSER by adopting the automatic speech recognition (ASR) model as a noise-robust feature extractor to eliminate non-vocal information in noisy speech. We first obtain intermediate layer information from the ASR model as a feature representation for emotional speech and then apply this representation for the downstream NSER task. Our experimental results show that 1) the proposed method achieves better NSER performance compared with the conventional noise reduction method, 2) outperforms self-supervised learning approaches, and 3) even outperforms text-based approaches using ASR transcription or the ground truth transcription of noisy speech.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2311.07093v3</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaohan Shi, Jiajun He, Xingfeng Li, Tomoki Toda</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quilt-LLaVA: Visual Instruction Tuning by Extracting Localized Narratives from Open-Source Histopathology Videos</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.04746</link>
      <description>arXiv:2312.04746v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Diagnosis in histopathology requires a global whole slide images (WSIs) analysis, requiring pathologists to compound evidence from different WSI patches. The gigapixel scale of WSIs poses a challenge for histopathology multi-modal models. Training multi-model models for histopathology requires instruction tuning datasets, which currently contain information for individual image patches, without a spatial grounding of the concepts within each patch and without a wider view of the WSI. Therefore, they lack sufficient diagnostic capacity for histopathology. To bridge this gap, we introduce Quilt-Instruct, a large-scale dataset of 107,131 histopathology-specific instruction question/answer pairs, grounded within diagnostically relevant image patches that make up the WSI. Our dataset is collected by leveraging educational histopathology videos from YouTube, which provides spatial localization of narrations by automatically extracting the narrators' cursor positions. Quilt-Instruct supports contextual reasoning by extracting diagnosis and supporting facts from the entire WSI. Using Quilt-Instruct, we train Quilt-LLaVA, which can reason beyond the given single image patch, enabling diagnostic reasoning across patches. To evaluate Quilt-LLaVA, we propose a comprehensive evaluation dataset created from 985 images and 1283 human-generated question-answers. We also thoroughly evaluate Quilt-LLaVA using public histopathology datasets, where Quilt-LLaVA significantly outperforms SOTA by over 10% on relative GPT-4 score and 4% and 9% on open and closed set VQA. Our code, data, and model are publicly accessible at quilt-llava.github.io.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2312.04746v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mehmet Saygin Seyfioglu, Wisdom O. Ikezogwo, Fatemeh Ghezloo, Ranjay Krishna, Linda Shapiro</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Prompt Learning for Weakly-Supervised Semantic Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.11791</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.11791v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Weakly-Supervised Semantic Segmentation (WSSS) aims to train segmentation models using image data with only image-level supervision. Since precise pixel-level annotations are not accessible, existing methods typically focus on producing pseudo masks for training segmentation models by refining CAM-like heatmaps. However, the produced heatmaps may capture only the discriminative image regions of object categories or the associated co-occurring backgrounds. To address the issues, we propose a Semantic Prompt Learning for WSSS (SemPLeS) framework, which learns to effectively prompt the CLIP latent space to enhance the semantic alignment between the segmented regions and the target object categories. More specifically, we propose Contrastive Prompt Learning and Prompt-guided Semantic Refinement to learn the prompts that adequately describe and suppress the co-occurring backgrounds associated with each object category. In this way, SemPLeS can perform better semantic alignment between object regions and class labels, resulting in desired pseudo masks for training segmentation models. The proposed SemPLeS framework achieves competitive performance on standard WSSS benchmarks, PASCAL VOC 2012 and MS COCO 2014, and shows compatibility with other WSSS methods. Code: https://github.com/NVlabs/SemPLeS.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.11791v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ci-Siang Lin, Chien-Yi Wang, Yu-Chiang Frank Wang, Min-Hung Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DropBP: Accelerating Fine-Tuning of Large Language Models by Dropping Backward Propagation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.17812</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.17812v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have achieved significant success across various domains. However, training these LLMs typically involves substantial memory and computational costs during both forward and backward propagation. While parameter-efficient fine-tuning (PEFT) considerably reduces the training memory associated with parameters, it does not address the significant computational costs and activation memory. In this paper, we propose Dropping Backward Propagation (DropBP), a novel approach designed to reduce computational costs and activation memory while maintaining accuracy. DropBP randomly drops layers during backward propagation, which is essentially equivalent to training shallow submodules generated by undropped layers and residual connections. Additionally, DropBP calculates the sensitivity of each layer to assign an appropriate drop rate, thereby stabilizing the training process. DropBP is not only applicable to full fine-tuning but can also be orthogonally integrated with all types of PEFT by dropping layers during backward propagation. Specifically, DropBP can reduce training time by 44% with comparable accuracy to the baseline, accelerate convergence to the same perplexity by 1.5x, and enable training with a sequence length 6.2x larger on a single NVIDIA-A100 GPU. Furthermore, our DropBP enabled a throughput increase of 79% on a NVIDIA A100 GPU and 117% on an Intel Gaudi2 HPU. The code is available at https://github.com/WooSunghyeon/dropbp.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.17812v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sunghyeon Woo, Baeseong Park, Byeongwook Kim, Minjung Jo, Se Jung Kwon, Dongsuk Jeon, Dongsoo Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Images are Achilles' Heel of Alignment: Exploiting Visual Vulnerabilities for Jailbreaking Multimodal Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.09792</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.09792v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In this paper, we study the harmlessness alignment problem of multimodal large language models (MLLMs). We conduct a systematic empirical analysis of the harmlessness performance of representative MLLMs and reveal that the image input poses the alignment vulnerability of MLLMs. Inspired by this, we propose a novel jailbreak method named HADES, which hides and amplifies the harmfulness of the malicious intent within the text input, using meticulously crafted images. Experimental results show that HADES can effectively jailbreak existing MLLMs, which achieves an average Attack Success Rate (ASR) of 90.26% for LLaVA-1.5 and 71.60% for Gemini Pro Vision. Our code and data are available at https://github.com/RUCAIBox/HADES.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.09792v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yifan Li, Hangyu Guo, Kun Zhou, Wayne Xin Zhao, Ji-Rong Wen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are LLMs Good Cryptic Crossword Solvers?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.12094</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.12094v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Cryptic crosswords are puzzles that rely not only on general knowledge but also on the solver's ability to manipulate language on different levels and deal with various types of wordplay. Previous research suggests that solving such puzzles is a challenge even for modern NLP models. However, the abilities of large language models (LLMs) have not yet been tested on this task. In this paper, we establish the benchmark results for three popular LLMs -- LLaMA2, Mistral, and ChatGPT -- showing that their performance on this task is still far from that of humans.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.12094v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Abdelrahman Sadallah, Daria Kotova, Ekaterina Kochmar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linear Attention Sequence Parallelism</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.02882</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.02882v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Sequence parallelism (SP) serves as a prevalent strategy to handle long sequences that exceed the memory limit of a single device. However, for linear sequence modeling methods like linear attention, existing SP approaches do not take advantage of their right-product-first feature, resulting in sub-optimal communication efficiency and usability. In this paper, we introduce Linear Attention Sequence Parallelism (LASP), an efficient SP approach designed for linear attention-based transformer models. Specifically, we design an efficient point-to-point ring-style communication mechanism to leverage the right-product kernel trick of linear attention, which sharply decreases the communication overhead, comparing with existing SP methods. We enhance the computation efficiency of LASP by performing kernel fusion and intermediate state caching, making the implementation of LASP hardware-friendly on GPUs. Furthermore, we meticulously ensure the compatibility of sequence-level LASP with all types of batch-level data parallel methods, which is vital for distributed training on large clusters with very-long sequences. We also discuss the generalization of LASP on other linear sequence modeling methods. Extensive experiments on linear attention-based models are conducted with varying sequence lengths from 2K to 4096K. LASP scales sequence length up to 4096K on 128 GPUs, which is 8$\times$ longer than existing SP methods. The code is available at https://github.com/OpenNLPLab/LASP.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.02882v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weigao Sun, Zhen Qin, Dong Li, Xuyang Shen, Yu Qiao, Yiran Zhong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are queries and keys always relevant? A case study on Transformer wave functions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.18874</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.18874v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The dot product attention mechanism, originally designed for natural language processing tasks, is a cornerstone of modern Transformers. It adeptly captures semantic relationships between word pairs in sentences by computing a similarity overlap between queries and keys. In this work, we explore the suitability of Transformers, focusing on their attention mechanisms, in the specific domain of the parametrization of variational wave functions to approximate ground states of quantum many-body spin Hamiltonians. Specifically, we perform numerical simulations on the two-dimensional $J_1$-$J_2$ Heisenberg model, a common benchmark in the field of quantum many-body systems on lattice. By comparing the performance of standard attention mechanisms with a simplified version that excludes queries and keys, relying solely on positions, we achieve competitive results while reducing computational cost and parameter usage. Furthermore, through the analysis of the attention maps generated by standard attention mechanisms, we show that the attention weights become effectively input-independent at the end of the optimization. We support the numerical results with analytical calculations, providing physical insights of why queries and keys should be, in principle, omitted from the attention mechanism when studying large systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.18874v2</guid>
      <category>cond-mat.dis-nn</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>physics.comp-ph</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1088/2632-2153/ada1a0</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Mach. Learn.: Sci. Technol. 6 010501 (2024)</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Riccardo Rende, Luciano Loris Viteritti</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ObfuscaTune: Obfuscated Offsite Fine-tuning and Inference of Proprietary LLMs on Private Datasets</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.02960</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.02960v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: This work addresses the timely yet underexplored problem of performing inference and finetuning of a proprietary LLM owned by a model provider entity on the confidential/private data of another data owner entity, in a way that ensures the confidentiality of both the model and the data. Hereby, the finetuning is conducted offsite, i.e., on the computation infrastructure of a third-party cloud provider. We tackle this problem by proposing ObfuscaTune, a novel, efficient and fully utility-preserving approach that combines a simple yet effective obfuscation technique with an efficient usage of confidential computing (only 5% of the model parameters are placed on TEE). We empirically demonstrate the effectiveness of ObfuscaTune by validating it on GPT-2 models with different sizes on four NLP benchmark datasets. Finally, we compare to a na\"ive version of our approach to highlight the necessity of using random matrices with low condition numbers in our approach to reduce errors induced by the obfuscation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.02960v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ahmed Frikha, Nassim Walha, Ricardo Mendes, Krishna Kanth Nakka, Xue Jiang, Xuebing Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Text-to-Game Engine for UGC-Based Role-Playing Games</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.08195</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.08195v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The transition from professionally generated content (PGC) to user-generated content (UGC) has reshaped various media formats, encompassing formats such as text and video. With rapid advancements in generative AI, a similar transformation is set to redefine the gaming industry, particularly within the domain of role-playing games (RPGs). This paper introduces a novel framework for a text-to-game engine that leverages foundation models to transform simple textual inputs into intricate, multi-modal RPG experiences. The engine dynamically generates game narratives, integrating text, visuals, and mechanics, while adapting characters, environments, and gameplay in realtime based on player interactions. To evaluate and demonstrate the feasibility and versatility of this framework, we developed the 'Zagii' game engine. Zagii has successfully powered hundreds of RPG games across diverse genres and facilitated tens of thousands of online gameplay sessions, showcasing its scalability and adaptability. These results highlight the framework's effectiveness and its potential to foster a more open and democratized approach to game development. Our work underscores the transformative role of generative AI in reshaping the gaming lifecycle and advancing the boundaries of interactive entertainment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.08195v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lei Zhang, Xuezheng Peng, Shuyi Yang, Feiyang Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MLLM-CompBench: A Comparative Reasoning Benchmark for Multimodal LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.16837</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.16837v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The ability to compare objects, scenes, or situations is crucial for effective decision-making and problem-solving in everyday life. For instance, comparing the freshness of apples enables better choices during grocery shopping while comparing sofa designs helps optimize the aesthetics of our living space. Despite its significance, the comparative capability is largely unexplored in artificial general intelligence (AGI). In this paper, we introduce MLLM-CompBench, a benchmark designed to evaluate the comparative reasoning capability of multimodal large language models (MLLMs). MLLM-CompBench mines and pairs images through visually oriented questions covering eight dimensions of relative comparison: visual attribute, existence, state, emotion, temporality, spatiality, quantity, and quality. We curate a collection of around 40K image pairs using metadata from diverse vision datasets and CLIP similarity scores. These image pairs span a broad array of visual domains, including animals, fashion, sports, and both outdoor and indoor scenes. The questions are carefully crafted to discern relative characteristics between two images and are labeled by human annotators for accuracy and relevance. We use MLLM-CompBench to evaluate recent MLLMs, including GPT-4V(ision), Gemini-Pro, and LLaVA-1.6. Our results reveal notable shortcomings in their comparative abilities. We believe MLLM-COMPBENCH not only sheds light on these limitations but also establishes a solid foundation for future enhancements in the comparative capability of MLLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.16837v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jihyung Kil, Zheda Mai, Justin Lee, Zihe Wang, Kerrie Cheng, Lemeng Wang, Ye Liu, Arpita Chowdhury, Wei-Lun Chao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Power of LLM Uncertainty for Active In-Context Example Selection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09172</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.09172v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have shown remarkable performance across a wide range of downstream tasks. However, it is challenging for users to discern whether the responses of LLM are generated with certainty or are fabricated to meet user expectations. In this paper, we introduce Uncertainty Tripartite Testing Paradigm (Unc-TTP), a novel method for classifying LLM uncertainty by leveraging output inconsistency. Specifically, Unc-TTP performs three rounds of sampling under varying label injection interference, enumerating all possible outcomes, and uses the degree of output inconsistency as the indicator of the LLM's intrinsic uncertainty. To validate the effectiveness of this inconsistency-defined uncertainty, we draw inspiration from Active Learning, comparing the informativeness of actively selected in-context examples. Our experiments show that uncertainty examples selected via Unc-TTP are more informative than certainty examples. Furthermore, the Unc-TTP-guided uncertainty-based active example selection strategy outperforms existing methods, highlighting its effectiveness in classifying LLM uncertainty and enhancing in-context learning. This work not only underscores the potential of inconsistency-based uncertainty classification for both open- and closed-source LLMs but also presents a practical approach for leveraging uncertainty to improve LLM performance in real-world tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.09172v4</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hsiu-Yuan Huang, Zichen Wu, Yutong Yang, Junzhao Zhang, Yunfang Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explainable Artificial Intelligence: A Survey of Needs, Techniques, Applications, and Future Direction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.00265</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.00265v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Artificial intelligence models encounter significant challenges due to their black-box nature, particularly in safety-critical domains such as healthcare, finance, and autonomous vehicles. Explainable Artificial Intelligence (XAI) addresses these challenges by providing explanations for how these models make decisions and predictions, ensuring transparency, accountability, and fairness. Existing studies have examined the fundamental concepts of XAI, its general principles, and the scope of XAI techniques. However, there remains a gap in the literature as there are no comprehensive reviews that delve into the detailed mathematical representations, design methodologies of XAI models, and other associated aspects. This paper provides a comprehensive literature review encompassing common terminologies and definitions, the need for XAI, beneficiaries of XAI, a taxonomy of XAI methods, and the application of XAI methods in different application areas. The survey is aimed at XAI researchers, XAI practitioners, AI model developers, and XAI beneficiaries who are interested in enhancing the trustworthiness, transparency, accountability, and fairness of their AI models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.00265v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Melkamu Mersha, Khang Lam, Joseph Wood, Ali AlShami, Jugal Kalita</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explaining Datasets in Words: Statistical Models with Natural Language Parameters</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.08466</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.08466v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: To make sense of massive data, we often fit simplified models and then interpret the parameters; for example, we cluster the text embeddings and then interpret the mean parameters of each cluster. However, these parameters are often high-dimensional and hard to interpret. To make model parameters directly interpretable, we introduce a family of statistical models -- including clustering, time series, and classification models -- parameterized by natural language predicates. For example, a cluster of text about COVID could be parameterized by the predicate "discusses COVID". To learn these statistical models effectively, we develop a model-agnostic algorithm that optimizes continuous relaxations of predicate parameters with gradient descent and discretizes them by prompting language models (LMs). Finally, we apply our framework to a wide range of problems: taxonomizing user chat dialogues, characterizing how they evolve across time, finding categories where one language model is better than the other, clustering math problems based on subareas, and explaining visual features in memorable images. Our framework is highly versatile, applicable to both textual and visual domains, can be easily steered to focus on specific properties (e.g. subareas), and explains sophisticated concepts that classical methods (e.g. n-gram analysis) struggle to produce.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.08466v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ruiqi Zhong, Heng Wang, Dan Klein, Jacob Steinhardt</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Bayesian Interpretation of Adaptive Low-Rank Adaptation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.10673</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.10673v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Motivated by the sensitivity-based importance score of the adaptive low-rank adaptation (AdaLoRA), we utilize more theoretically supported metrics, including the signal-to-noise ratio (SNR), along with the Improved Variational Online Newton (IVON) optimizer, for adaptive parameter budget allocation. The resulting Bayesian counterpart not only has matched or surpassed the performance of using the sensitivity-based importance metric but is also a faster alternative to AdaLoRA with Adam. Our theoretical analysis reveals a significant connection between the two metrics, providing a Bayesian perspective on the efficacy of sensitivity as an importance score. Furthermore, our findings suggest that the magnitude, rather than the variance, is the primary indicator of the importance of parameters.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.10673v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haolin Chen, Philip N. Garner</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unsupervised Word Discovery: Boundary Detection with Clustering vs. Dynamic Programming</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.14486</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.14486v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We look at the long-standing problem of segmenting unlabeled speech into word-like segments and clustering these into a lexicon. Several previous methods use a scoring model coupled with dynamic programming to find an optimal segmentation. Here we propose a much simpler strategy: we predict word boundaries using the dissimilarity between adjacent self-supervised features, then we cluster the predicted segments to construct a lexicon. For a fair comparison, we update the older ES-KMeans dynamic programming method with better features and boundary constraints. On the five-language ZeroSpeech benchmarks, our simple approach gives similar state-of-the-art results compared to the new ES-KMeans+ method, while being almost five times faster. Project webpage: https://s-malan.github.io/prom-seg-clus.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.14486v2</guid>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Simon Malan, Benjamin van Niekerk, Herman Kamper</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Are They Doing? Joint Audio-Speech Co-Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.14526</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.14526v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In audio and speech processing, tasks usually focus on either the audio or speech modality, even when both sounds and human speech are present in the same audio clip. Recent Auditory Large Language Models (ALLMs) have made it possible to process audio and speech simultaneously within a single model, leading to further considerations of joint audio-speech tasks.
  In this paper, we establish a novel benchmark to investigate how well ALLMs can perform joint audio-speech processing. Specifically, we introduce Joint Audio-Speech Co-Reasoning (JASCO), a novel task that unifies audio and speech processing, strictly requiring co-reasoning across both modalities. We also release a scene-reasoning dataset called "What Are They Doing". Additionally, we provide deeper insights into the models' behaviors by analyzing their dependence on each modality.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.14526v2</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yingzhi Wang, Pooneh Mousavi, Artem Ploujnikov, Mirco Ravanelli</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FineCops-Ref: A new Dataset and Task for Fine-Grained Compositional Referring Expression Comprehension</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.14750</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.14750v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Referring Expression Comprehension (REC) is a crucial cross-modal task that objectively evaluates the capabilities of language understanding, image comprehension, and language-to-image grounding. Consequently, it serves as an ideal testing ground for Multi-modal Large Language Models (MLLMs). In pursuit of this goal, we have established a new REC dataset characterized by two key features: Firstly, it is designed with controllable varying levels of difficulty, necessitating multi-level fine-grained reasoning across object categories, attributes, and multi-hop relationships. Secondly, it includes negative text and images created through fine-grained editing and generation based on existing data, thereby testing the model's ability to correctly reject scenarios where the target object is not visible in the image--an essential aspect often overlooked in existing datasets and approaches. Utilizing this high-quality dataset, we conducted comprehensive evaluations of both state-of-the-art specialist models and MLLMs. Our findings indicate that there remains a significant gap in achieving satisfactory grounding performance. We anticipate that our dataset will inspire new approaches to enhance visual reasoning and develop more advanced cross-modal interaction strategies, ultimately unlocking the full potential of MLLMs. Our code and the datasets are available at https://github.com/liujunzhuo/FineCops-Ref.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.14750v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junzhuo Liu, Xuzheng Yang, Weiwei Li, Peng Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Movie2Story: A framework for understanding videos and telling stories in the form of novel text</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.14965</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.14965v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In recent years, large-scale models have achieved significant advancements, accompanied by the emergence of numerous high-quality benchmarks for evaluating various aspects of their comprehension abilities. However, most existing benchmarks primarily focus on spatial understanding in static image tasks. While some benchmarks extend evaluations to temporal tasks, they fall short in assessing text generation under complex contexts involving long videos and rich auxiliary information. To address this limitation, we propose a novel benchmark: the Multi-modal Story Generation Benchmark (MSBench), designed to evaluate text generation capabilities in scenarios enriched with auxiliary information. Our work introduces an innovative automatic dataset generation method to ensure the availability of accurate auxiliary information. On one hand, we leverage existing datasets and apply automated processes to generate new evaluation datasets, significantly reducing manual efforts. On the other hand, we refine auxiliary data through systematic filtering and utilize state-of-the-art models to ensure the fairness and accuracy of the ground-truth datasets. Our experiments reveal that current Multi-modal Large Language Models (MLLMs) perform suboptimally under the proposed evaluation metrics, highlighting significant gaps in their capabilities. To address these challenges, we propose a novel model architecture and methodology to better handle the overall process, demonstrating improvements on our benchmark.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.14965v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kangning Li, Zheyang Jia, Anyu Ying</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
