<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL</link>
    <description>cs.CL updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 05:00:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Sunday</day>
      <day>Saturday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering Competency Gaps in Large Language Models and Their Benchmarks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20638</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20638v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The evaluation of large language models (LLMs) relies heavily on standardized benchmarks. These benchmarks provide useful aggregated metrics for a given capability, but those aggregated metrics can obscure (i) particular sub-areas where the LLMs are weak ("model gaps") and (ii) imbalanced coverage in the benchmarks themselves ("benchmark gaps"). We propose a new method that uses sparse autoencoders (SAEs) to automatically uncover both types of gaps. By extracting SAE concept activations and computing saliency-weighted performance scores across benchmark data, the method grounds evaluation in the model's internal representations and enables comparison across benchmarks. As examples demonstrating our approach, we applied the method to two popular open-source models and ten benchmarks. We found that these models consistently underperformed on concepts that stand in contrast to sycophantic behaviors (e.g., politely refusing a request or asserting boundaries) and concepts connected to safety discussions. These model gaps align with observations previously surfaced in the literature; our automated, unsupervised method was able to recover them without manual supervision. We also observed benchmark gaps: many of the evaluated benchmarks over-represented concepts related to obedience, authority, or instruction-following, while missing core concepts that should fall within their intended scope. In sum, our method offers a representation-grounded approach to evaluation, enabling concept-level decomposition of benchmark scores. Rather than replacing conventional aggregated metrics, CG complements them by providing a concept-level decomposition that can reveal why a model scored as it did and how benchmarks could evolve to better reflect their intended scope. Code is available at https://competency-gaps.github.io.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20638v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Matyas Bohacek, Nino Scherrer, Nicholas Dufour, Thomas Leung, Christoph Bregler, Stephanie C. Y. Chan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SA-DiffuSeq: Addressing Computational and Scalability Challenges in Long-Document Generation with Sparse Attention</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20724</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20724v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Diffusion based approaches to long form text generation suffer from prohibitive computational cost and memory overhead as sequence length increases. We introduce SA-DiffuSeq, a diffusion framework that integrates sparse attention to fundamentally improve scalability for long document modeling. By selectively allocating attention within the diffusion process, SA-DiffuSeq significantly reduces computational complexity while maintaining semantic coherence and generation quality. A key component of our method is a soft absorbing state tailored to sparse attention dynamics, which stabilizes diffusion trajectories and accelerates sequence reconstruction. This design improves sampling efficiency and enhances precision in long range dependency modeling. Extensive experiments demonstrate that SA-DiffuSeq consistently surpasses state of the art diffusion baselines in both training efficiency and sampling speed, with especially strong gains on extended sequences. These properties make SA-DiffuSeq well suited for demanding long form applications such as scientific writing, large scale code generation, and multi turn long context dialogue. Overall, our results indicate that incorporating structured sparsity into diffusion models is a promising direction for efficient and expressive long text generation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20724v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alexandros Christoforos, Chadbourne Davis</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TokSuite: Measuring the Impact of Tokenizer Choice on Language Model Behavior</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20757</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20757v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Tokenizers provide the fundamental basis through which text is represented and processed by language models (LMs). Despite the importance of tokenization, its role in LM performance and behavior is poorly understood due to the challenge of measuring the impact of tokenization in isolation. To address this need, we present TokSuite, a collection of models and a benchmark that supports research into tokenization's influence on LMs. Specifically, we train fourteen models that use different tokenizers but are otherwise identical using the same architecture, dataset, training budget, and initialization. Additionally, we curate and release a new benchmark that specifically measures model performance subject to real-world perturbations that are likely to influence tokenization. Together, TokSuite allows robust decoupling of the influence of a model's tokenizer, supporting a series of novel findings that elucidate the respective benefits and shortcomings of a wide range of popular tokenizers.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20757v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>G\"ul Sena Alt{\i}nta\c{s}, Malikeh Ehghaghi, Brian Lester, Fengyuan Liu, Wanru Zhao, Marco Ciccone, Colin Raffel</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adversarial Training for Failure-Sensitive User Simulation in Mental Health Dialogue Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20773</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20773v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Realistic user simulation is crucial for training and evaluating task-oriented dialogue (TOD) systems, yet creating simulators that accurately replicate human behavior remains challenging. A key property of effective simulators is their ability to expose failure modes of the systems they evaluate. We present an adversarial training framework that iteratively improves user simulator realism through a competitive dynamic between a generator (user simulator) and a discriminator. Applied to mental health support chatbots, our approach demonstrates that fine-tuned simulators dramatically outperform zero-shot base models at surfacing system issues, and adversarial training further enhances diversity, distributional alignment, and predictive validity. The resulting simulator achieves a strong correlation between simulated and real failure occurrence rates across diverse chatbot configurations while maintaining low distributional divergence of failure modes. Discriminator accuracy decreases drastically after three adversarial iterations, suggesting improved realism. These results provide evidence that adversarial training is a promising approach for creating realistic user simulators in mental health support TOD domains, enabling rapid, reliable, and cost-effective system evaluation before deployment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20773v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ziyi Zhu, Olivier Tieleman, Caitlin A. Stamatis, Luka Smyth, Thomas D. Hull, Daniel R. Cahn, Matteo Malgaroli</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Language Models Approach Expert Pedagogical Quality in Math Tutoring but Differ in Instructional and Linguistic Profiles</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20780</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20780v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent work has explored the use of large language models for generating tutoring responses in mathematics, yet it remains unclear how closely their instructional behavior aligns with expert human practice. We examine this question using a controlled, turn-level comparison in which expert human tutors, novice human tutors, and multiple large language models respond to the same set of math remediation conversation turns. We examine both instructional strategies and linguistic characteristics of tutoring responses, including restating and revoicing, pressing for accuracy, lexical diversity, readability, politeness, and agency. We find that large language models approach expert levels of perceived pedagogical quality on average but exhibit systematic differences in their instructional and linguistic profiles. In particular, large language models tend to underuse restating and revoicing strategies characteristic of expert human tutors, while producing longer, more lexically diverse, and more polite responses. Statistical analyses show that restating and revoicing, lexical diversity, and pressing for accuracy are positively associated with perceived pedagogical quality, whereas higher levels of agentic and polite language are negatively associated. Overall, recent large language models exhibit levels of perceived pedagogical quality comparable to expert human tutors, while relying on different instructional and linguistic strategies. These findings underscore the value of analyzing instructional strategies and linguistic characteristics when evaluating tutoring responses across human tutors and intelligent tutoring systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20780v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ramatu Oiza Abdulsalam, Segun Aroyehun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating Model Editing for Unlearning in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20794</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20794v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Machine unlearning aims to remove unwanted information from a model, but many methods are inefficient for LLMs with large numbers of parameters or fail to fully remove the intended information without degrading performance on knowledge that should be retained. Model editing algorithms solve a similar problem of changing information in models, but they focus on redirecting inputs to a new target rather than removing that information altogether. In this work, we explore the editing algorithms ROME, IKE, and WISE and design new editing targets for an unlearning setting. Through this investigation, we show that model editing approaches can exceed baseline unlearning methods in terms of quality of forgetting depending on the setting. Like traditional unlearning techniques, they struggle to encapsulate the scope of what is to be unlearned without damage to the overall model performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20794v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shariqah Hossain, Lalana Kagal</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measuring Mechanistic Independence: Can Bias Be Removed Without Erasing Demographics?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20796</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20796v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We investigate how independent demographic bias mechanisms are from general demographic recognition in language models. Using a multi-task evaluation setup where demographics are associated with names, professions, and education levels, we measure whether models can be debiased while preserving demographic detection capabilities. We compare attribution-based and correlation-based methods for locating bias features. We find that targeted sparse autoencoder feature ablations in Gemma-2-9B reduce bias without degrading recognition performance: attribution-based ablations mitigate race and gender profession stereotypes while preserving name recognition accuracy, whereas correlation-based ablations are more effective for education bias. Qualitative analysis further reveals that removing attribution features in education tasks induces ``prior collapse'', thus increasing overall bias. This highlights the need for dimension-specific interventions. Overall, our results show that demographic bias arises from task-specific mechanisms rather than absolute demographic markers, and that mechanistic inference-time interventions can enable surgical debiasing without compromising core model capabilities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20796v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhengyang Shan, Aaron Mueller</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Deception: When Reasoning Models Can't Compute an Addition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20812</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20812v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are increasingly used in situations where human values are at stake, such as decision-making tasks that involve reasoning when performed by humans. We investigate the so-called reasoning capabilities of LLMs over novel symbolic representations by introducing an experimental framework that tests their ability to process and manipulate unfamiliar symbols. We introduce semantic deceptions: situations in which symbols carry misleading semantic associations due to their form, such as being embedded in specific contexts, designed to probe whether LLMs can maintain symbolic abstraction or whether they default to exploiting learned semantic associations. We redefine standard digits and mathematical operators using novel symbols, and task LLMs with solving simple calculations expressed in this altered notation. The objective is: (1) to assess LLMs' capacity for abstraction and manipulation of arbitrary symbol systems; (2) to evaluate their ability to resist misleading semantic cues that conflict with the task's symbolic logic. Through experiments with four LLMs we show that semantic cues can significantly deteriorate reasoning models' performance on very simple tasks. They reveal limitations in current LLMs' ability for symbolic manipulations and highlight a tendency to over-rely on surface-level semantics, suggesting that chain-of-thoughts may amplify reliance on statistical correlations. Even in situations where LLMs seem to correctly follow instructions, semantic cues still impact basic capabilities. These limitations raise ethical and societal concerns, undermining the widespread and pernicious tendency to attribute reasoning abilities to LLMs and suggesting how LLMs might fail, in particular in decision-making contexts where robust symbolic reasoning is essential and should not be compromised by residual semantic associations inherited from the model's training.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20812v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nathani\"el de Leeuw, Marceau Nahon, Mathis Reymond, Raja Chatila, Mehdi Khamassi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EssayCBM: Rubric-Aligned Concept Bottleneck Models for Transparent Essay Grading</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20817</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20817v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Understanding how automated grading systems evaluate essays remains a significant challenge for educators and students, especially when large language models function as black boxes. We introduce EssayCBM, a rubric-aligned framework that prioritizes interpretability in essay assessment. Instead of predicting grades directly from text, EssayCBM evaluates eight writing concepts, such as Thesis Clarity and Evidence Use, through dedicated prediction heads on an encoder. These concept scores form a transparent bottleneck, and a lightweight network computes the final grade using only concepts. Instructors can adjust concept predictions and instantly view the updated grade, enabling accountable human-in-the-loop evaluation. EssayCBM matches black-box performance while offering actionable, concept-level feedback through an intuitive web interface.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20817v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kumar Satvik Chaudhary, Chengshuai Zhao, Fan Zhang, Yung Hin Tse, Garima Agrawal, Yuli Deng, Huan Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MediEval: A Unified Medical Benchmark for Patient-Contextual and Knowledge-Grounded Reasoning in LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20822</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20822v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) are increasingly applied to medicine, yet their adoption is limited by concerns over reliability and safety. Existing evaluations either test factual medical knowledge in isolation or assess patient-level reasoning without verifying correctness, leaving a critical gap. We introduce MediEval, a benchmark that links MIMIC-IV electronic health records (EHRs) to a unified knowledge base built from UMLS and other biomedical vocabularies. MediEval generates diverse factual and counterfactual medical statements within real patient contexts, enabling systematic evaluation across a 4-quadrant framework that jointly considers knowledge grounding and contextual consistency. Using this framework, we identify critical failure modes, including hallucinated support and truth inversion, that current proprietary, open-source, and domain-specific LLMs frequently exhibit. To address these risks, we propose Counterfactual Risk-Aware Fine-tuning (CoRFu), a DPO-based method with an asymmetric penalty targeting unsafe confusions. CoRFu improves by +16.4 macro-F1 points over the base model and eliminates truth inversion errors, demonstrating both higher accuracy and substantially greater safety.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20822v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhan Qu, Michael F\"arber</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nemotron 3 Nano: Open, Efficient Mixture-of-Experts Hybrid Mamba-Transformer Model for Agentic Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20848</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20848v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present Nemotron 3 Nano 30B-A3B, a Mixture-of-Experts hybrid Mamba-Transformer language model. Nemotron 3 Nano was pretrained on 25 trillion text tokens, including more than 3 trillion new unique tokens over Nemotron 2, followed by supervised fine tuning and large-scale RL on diverse environments. Nemotron 3 Nano achieves better accuracy than our previous generation Nemotron 2 Nano while activating less than half of the parameters per forward pass. It achieves up to 3.3x higher inference throughput than similarly-sized open models like GPT-OSS-20B and Qwen3-30B-A3B-Thinking-2507, while also being more accurate on popular benchmarks. Nemotron 3 Nano demonstrates enhanced agentic, reasoning, and chat abilities and supports context lengths up to 1M tokens. We release both our pretrained Nemotron 3 Nano 30B-A3B Base and post-trained Nemotron 3 Nano 30B-A3B checkpoints on Hugging Face.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20848v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator> NVIDIA,  :, Aaron Blakeman, Aaron Grattafiori, Aarti Basant, Abhibha Gupta, Abhinav Khattar, Adi Renduchintala, Aditya Vavre, Akanksha Shukla, Akhiad Bercovich, Aleksander Ficek, Aleksandr Shaposhnikov, Alex Kondratenko, Alexander Bukharin, Alexandre Milesi, Ali Taghibakhshi, Alisa Liu, Amelia Barton, Ameya Sunil Mahabaleshwarkar, Amir Klein, Amit Zuker, Amnon Geifman, Amy Shen, Anahita Bhiwandiwalla, Andrew Tao, Ann Guan, Anubhav Mandarwal, Arham Mehta, Ashwath Aithal, Ashwin Poojary, Asif Ahamed, Asma Kuriparambil Thekkumpate, Ayush Dattagupta, Banghua Zhu, Bardiya Sadeghi, Barnaby Simkin, Ben Lanir, Benedikt Schifferer, Besmira Nushi, Bilal Kartal, Bita Darvish Rouhani, Boris Ginsburg, Brandon Norick, Brandon Soubasis, Branislav Kisacanin, Brian Yu, Bryan Catanzaro, Carlo del Mundo, Chantal Hwang, Charles Wang, Cheng-Ping Hsieh, Chenghao Zhang, Chenhan Yu, Chetan Mungekar, Chintan Patel, Chris Alexiuk, Christopher Parisien, Collin Neale, Damon Mosk-Aoyama, Dan Su, Dane Corneil, Daniel Afrimi, Daniel Rohrer, Daniel Serebrenik, Daria Gitman, Daria Levy, Darko Stosic, David Mosallanezhad, Deepak Narayanan, Dhruv Nathawani, Dima Rekesh, Dina Yared, Divyanshu Kakwani, Dong Ahn, Duncan Riach, Dusan Stosic, Edgar Minasyan, Edward Lin, Eileen Long, Eileen Peters Long, Elena Lantz, Ellie Evans, Elliott Ning, Eric Chung, Eric Harper, Eric Tramel, Erick Galinkin, Erik Pounds, Evan Briones, Evelina Bakhturina, Faisal Ladhak, Fay Wang, Fei Jia, Felipe Soares, Feng Chen, Ferenc Galko, Frankie Siino, Gal Hubara Agam, Ganesh Ajjanagadde, Gantavya Bhatt, Gargi Prasad, George Armstrong, Gerald Shen, Gorkem Batmaz, Grigor Nalbandyan, Haifeng Qian, Harsh Sharma, Hayley Ross, Helen Ngo, Herman Sahota, Hexin Wang, Himanshu Soni, Hiren Upadhyay, Huizi Mao, Huy C Nguyen, Huy Q Nguyen, Iain Cunningham, Ido Shahaf, Igor Gitman, Ilya Loshchilov, Ivan Moshkov, Izzy Putterman, Jan Kautz, Jane Polak Scowcroft, Jared Casper, Jatin Mitra, Jeffrey Glick, Jenny Chen, Jesse Oliver, Jian Zhang, Jiaqi Zeng, Jie Lou, Jimmy Zhang, Jining Huang, Joey Conway, Joey Guman, John Kamalu, Johnny Greco, Jonathan Cohen, Joseph Jennings, Joyjit Daw, Julien Veron Vialard, Junkeun Yi, Jupinder Parmar, Kai Xu, Kan Zhu, Kari Briski, Katherine Cheung, Katherine Luna, Keshav Santhanam, Kevin Shih, Kezhi Kong, Khushi Bhardwaj, Krishna C. Puvvada, Krzysztof Pawelec, Kumar Anik, Lawrence McAfee, Laya Sleiman, Leon Derczynski, Li Ding, Lucas Liebenwein, Luis Vega, Maanu Grover, Maarten Van Segbroeck, Maer Rodrigues de Melo, Makesh Narsimhan Sreedhar, Manoj Kilaru, Maor Ashkenazi, Marc Romeijn, Mark Cai, Markus Kliegl, Maryam Moosaei, Matvei Novikov, Mehrzad Samadi, Melissa Corpuz, Mengru Wang, Meredith Price, Michael Boone, Michael Evans, Miguel Martinez, Mike Chrzanowski, Mohammad Shoeybi, Mostofa Patwary, Nabin Mulepati, Natalie Hereth, Nave Assaf, Negar Habibi, Neta Zmora, Netanel Haber, Nicola Sessions, Nidhi Bhatia, Nikhil Jukar, Nikki Pope, Nikolai Ludwig, Nima Tajbakhsh, Nirmal Juluru, Oleksii Hrinchuk, Oleksii Kuchaiev, Olivier Delalleau, Oluwatobi Olabiyi, Omer Ullman Argov, Ouye Xie, Parth Chadha, Pasha Shamis, Pavlo Molchanov, Pawel Morkisz, Peter Dykas, Peter Jin, Pinky Xu, Piotr Januszewski, Pranav Prashant Thombre, Prasoon Varshney, Pritam Gundecha, Qing Miao, Rabeeh Karimi Mahabadi, Ran El-Yaniv, Ran Zilberstein, Rasoul Shafipour, Rich Harang, Rick Izzo, Rima Shahbazyan, Rishabh Garg, Ritika Borkar, Ritu Gala, Riyad Islam, Roger Waleffe, Rohit Watve, Roi Koren, Ruoxi Zhang, Russell J. Hewett, Ryan Prenger, Ryan Timbrook, Sadegh Mahdavi, Sahil Modi, Samuel Kriman, Sanjay Kariyappa, Sanjeev Satheesh, Saori Kaji, Satish Pasumarthi, Sean Narentharen, Sean Narenthiran, Seonmyeong Bak, Sergey Kashirsky, Seth Poulos, Shahar Mor, Shanmugam Ramasamy, Shantanu Acharya, Shaona Ghosh, Sharath Turuvekere Sreenivas, Shelby Thomas, Shiqing Fan, Shreya Gopal, Shrimai Prabhumoye, Shubham Pachori, Shubham Toshniwal, Shuoyang Ding, Siddharth Singh, Simeng Sun, Smita Ithape, Somshubra Majumdar, Soumye Singhal, Stefania Alborghetti, Stephen Ge, Sugam Dipak Devare, Sumeet Kumar Barua, Suseella Panguluri, Suyog Gupta, Sweta Priyadarshi, Syeda Nahida Akter, Tan Bui, Teodor-Dumitru Ene, Terry Kong, Thanh Do, Tijmen Blankevoort, Tom Balough, Tomer Asida, Tomer Bar Natan, Tugrul Konuk, Twinkle Vashishth, Udi Karpas, Ushnish De, Vahid Noorozi, Vahid Noroozi, Venkat Srinivasan, Venmugil Elango, Vijay Korthikanti, Vitaly Kurin, Vitaly Lavrukhin, Wanli Jiang, Wasi Uddin Ahmad, Wei Du, Wei Ping, Wenfei Zhou, Will Jennings, William Zhang, Wojciech Prazuch, Xiaowei Ren, Yashaswi Karnati, Yejin Choi, Yev Meyer, Yi-Fu Wu, Yian Zhang, Ying Lin, Yonatan Geifman, Yonggan Fu, Yoshi Subara, Yoshi Suhara, Yubo Gao, Zach Moshe, Zhen Dong, Zihan Liu, Zijia Chen, Zijie Yan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How important is Recall for Measuring Retrieval Quality?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20854</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20854v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In realistic retrieval settings with large and evolving knowledge bases, the total number of documents relevant to a query is typically unknown, and recall cannot be computed. In this paper, we evaluate several established strategies for handling this limitation by measuring the correlation between retrieval quality metrics and LLM-based judgments of response quality, where responses are generated from the retrieved documents. We conduct experiments across multiple datasets with a relatively low number of relevant documents (2-15). We also introduce a simple retrieval quality measure that performs well without requiring knowledge of the total number of relevant documents.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20854v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shelly Schwartz, Oleg Vasilyev, Randy Sawaya</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NVIDIA Nemotron 3: Efficient and Open Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20856</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20856v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We introduce the Nemotron 3 family of models - Nano, Super, and Ultra. These models deliver strong agentic, reasoning, and conversational capabilities. The Nemotron 3 family uses a Mixture-of-Experts hybrid Mamba-Transformer architecture to provide best-in-class throughput and context lengths of up to 1M tokens. Super and Ultra models are trained with NVFP4 and incorporate LatentMoE, a novel approach that improves model quality. The two larger models also include MTP layers for faster text generation. All Nemotron 3 models are post-trained using multi-environment reinforcement learning enabling reasoning, multi-step tool use, and support granular reasoning budget control. Nano, the smallest model, outperforms comparable models in accuracy while remaining extremely cost-efficient for inference. Super is optimized for collaborative agents and high-volume workloads such as IT ticket automation. Ultra, the largest model, provides state-of-the-art accuracy and reasoning performance. Nano is released together with its technical report and this white paper, while Super and Ultra will follow in the coming months. We will openly release the model weights, pre- and post-training software, recipes, and all data for which we hold redistribution rights.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20856v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator> NVIDIA,  :, Aaron Blakeman, Aaron Grattafiori, Aarti Basant, Abhibha Gupta, Abhinav Khattar, Adi Renduchintala, Aditya Vavre, Akanksha Shukla, Akhiad Bercovich, Aleksander Ficek, Aleksandr Shaposhnikov, Alex Kondratenko, Alexander Bukharin, Alexandre Milesi, Ali Taghibakhshi, Alisa Liu, Amelia Barton, Ameya Sunil Mahabaleshwarkar, Amir Klein, Amit Zuker, Amnon Geifman, Amy Shen, Anahita Bhiwandiwalla, Andrew Tao, Anjulie Agrusa, Ankur Verma, Ann Guan, Anubhav Mandarwal, Arham Mehta, Ashwath Aithal, Ashwin Poojary, Asif Ahamed, Asit Mishra, Asma Kuriparambil Thekkumpate, Ayush Dattagupta, Banghua Zhu, Bardiya Sadeghi, Barnaby Simkin, Ben Lanir, Benedikt Schifferer, Besmira Nushi, Bilal Kartal, Bita Darvish Rouhani, Boris Ginsburg, Brandon Norick, Brandon Soubasis, Branislav Kisacanin, Brian Yu, Bryan Catanzaro, Carlo del Mundo, Chantal Hwang, Charles Wang, Cheng-Ping Hsieh, Chenghao Zhang, Chenhan Yu, Chetan Mungekar, Chintan Patel, Chris Alexiuk, Christopher Parisien, Collin Neale, Cyril Meurillon, Damon Mosk-Aoyama, Dan Su, Dane Corneil, Daniel Afrimi, Daniel Lo, Daniel Rohrer, Daniel Serebrenik, Daria Gitman, Daria Levy, Darko Stosic, David Mosallanezhad, Deepak Narayanan, Dhruv Nathawani, Dima Rekesh, Dina Yared, Divyanshu Kakwani, Dong Ahn, Duncan Riach, Dusan Stosic, Edgar Minasyan, Edward Lin, Eileen Long, Eileen Peters Long, Elad Segal, Elena Lantz, Ellie Evans, Elliott Ning, Eric Chung, Eric Harper, Eric Tramel, Erick Galinkin, Erik Pounds, Evan Briones, Evelina Bakhturina, Evgeny Tsykunov, Faisal Ladhak, Fay Wang, Fei Jia, Felipe Soares, Feng Chen, Ferenc Galko, Frank Sun, Frankie Siino, Gal Hubara Agam, Ganesh Ajjanagadde, Gantavya Bhatt, Gargi Prasad, George Armstrong, Gerald Shen, Gorkem Batmaz, Grigor Nalbandyan, Haifeng Qian, Harsh Sharma, Hayley Ross, Helen Ngo, Herbert Hum, Herman Sahota, Hexin Wang, Himanshu Soni, Hiren Upadhyay, Huizi Mao, Huy C Nguyen, Huy Q Nguyen, Iain Cunningham, Ido Galil, Ido Shahaf, Igor Gitman, Ilya Loshchilov, Itamar Schen, Itay Levy, Ivan Moshkov, Izik Golan, Izzy Putterman, Jan Kautz, Jane Polak Scowcroft, Jared Casper, Jatin Mitra, Jeffrey Glick, Jenny Chen, Jesse Oliver, Jian Zhang, Jiaqi Zeng, Jie Lou, Jimmy Zhang, Jinhang Choi, Jining Huang, Joey Conway, Joey Guman, John Kamalu, Johnny Greco, Jonathan Cohen, Joseph Jennings, Joyjit Daw, Julien Veron Vialard, Junkeun Yi, Jupinder Parmar, Kai Xu, Kan Zhu, Kari Briski, Katherine Cheung, Katherine Luna, Keith Wyss, Keshav Santhanam, Kevin Shih, Kezhi Kong, Khushi Bhardwaj, Kirthi Shankar, Krishna C. Puvvada, Krzysztof Pawelec, Kumar Anik, Lawrence McAfee, Laya Sleiman, Leon Derczynski, Li Ding, Lizzie Wei, Lucas Liebenwein, Luis Vega, Maanu Grover, Maarten Van Segbroeck, Maer Rodrigues de Melo, Mahdi Nazemi, Makesh Narsimhan Sreedhar, Manoj Kilaru, Maor Ashkenazi, Marc Romeijn, Marcin Chochowski, Mark Cai, Markus Kliegl, Maryam Moosaei, Matt Kulka, Matvei Novikov, Mehrzad Samadi, Melissa Corpuz, Mengru Wang, Meredith Price, Michael Andersch, Michael Boone, Michael Evans, Miguel Martinez, Mikail Khona, Mike Chrzanowski, Minseok Lee, Mohammad Dabbah, Mohammad Shoeybi, Mostofa Patwary, Nabin Mulepati, Najeeb Nabwani, Natalie Hereth, Nave Assaf, Negar Habibi, Neta Zmora, Netanel Haber, Nicola Sessions, Nidhi Bhatia, Nikhil Jukar, Nikki Pope, Nikolai Ludwig, Nima Tajbakhsh, Nir Ailon, Nirmal Juluru, Nishant Sharma, Oleksii Hrinchuk, Oleksii Kuchaiev, Olivier Delalleau, Oluwatobi Olabiyi, Omer Ullman Argov, Omri Puny, Oren Tropp, Ouye Xie, Parth Chadha, Pasha Shamis, Paul Gibbons, Pavlo Molchanov, Pawel Morkisz, Peter Dykas, Peter Jin, Pinky Xu, Piotr Januszewski, Pranav Prashant Thombre, Prasoon Varshney, Pritam Gundecha, Przemek Tredak, Qing Miao, Qiyu Wan, Rabeeh Karimi Mahabadi, Rachit Garg, Ran El-Yaniv, Ran Zilberstein, Rasoul Shafipour, Rich Harang, Rick Izzo, Rima Shahbazyan, Rishabh Garg, Ritika Borkar, Ritu Gala, Riyad Islam, Robert Hesse, Roger Waleffe, Rohit Watve, Roi Koren, Ruoxi Zhang, Russell Hewett, Russell J. Hewett, Ryan Prenger, Ryan Timbrook, Sadegh Mahdavi, Sahil Modi, Samuel Kriman, Sangkug Lim, Sanjay Kariyappa, Sanjeev Satheesh, Saori Kaji, Satish Pasumarthi, Saurav Muralidharan, Sean Narentharen, Sean Narenthiran, Seonmyeong Bak, Sergey Kashirsky, Seth Poulos, Shahar Mor, Shanmugam Ramasamy, Shantanu Acharya, Shaona Ghosh, Sharath Turuvekere Sreenivas, Shelby Thomas, Shiqing Fan, Shreya Gopal, Shrimai Prabhumoye, Shubham Pachori, Shubham Toshniwal, Shuoyang Ding, Siddharth Singh, Simeng Sun, Smita Ithape, Somshubra Majumdar, Soumye Singhal, Stas Sergienko, Stefania Alborghetti, Stephen Ge, Sugam Dipak Devare, Sumeet Kumar Barua, Suseella Panguluri, Suyog Gupta, Sweta Priyadarshi, Syeda Nahida Akter, Tan Bui, Teodor-Dumitru Ene, Terry Kong, Thanh Do, Tijmen Blankevoort, Tim Moon, Tom Balough, Tomer Asida, Tomer Bar Natan, Tomer Ronen, Tugrul Konuk, Twinkle Vashishth, Udi Karpas, Ushnish De, Vahid Noorozi, Vahid Noroozi, Venkat Srinivasan, Venmugil Elango, Victor Cui, Vijay Korthikanti, Vinay Rao, Vitaly Kurin, Vitaly Lavrukhin, Vladimir Anisimov, Wanli Jiang, Wasi Uddin Ahmad, Wei Du, Wei Ping, Wenfei Zhou, Will Jennings, William Zhang, Wojciech Prazuch, Xiaowei Ren, Yashaswi Karnati, Yejin Choi, Yev Meyer, Yi-Fu Wu, Yian Zhang, Yigong Qin, Ying Lin, Yonatan Geifman, Yonggan Fu, Yoshi Subara, Yoshi Suhara, Yubo Gao, Zach Moshe, Zhen Dong, Zhongbo Zhu, Zihan Liu, Zijia Chen, Zijie Yan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Architectural Trade-offs in Small Language Models Under Compute Constraints</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20877</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20877v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present a systematic empirical study of small language models under strict compute constraints, analyzing how architectural choices and training budget interact to determine performance. Starting from a linear next-token predictor, we progressively introduce nonlinearities, self-attention, and multi-layer transformer architectures, evaluating each on character-level modeling of Tiny Shakespeare and word-level modeling of Penn Treebank (PTB) and WikiText-2. We compare models using test negative log-likelihood (NLL), parameter count, and approximate training FLOPs to characterize accuracy-efficiency trade-offs. Our results show that attention-based models dominate MLPs in per-FLOP efficiency even at small scale, while increasing depth or context without sufficient optimization can degrade performance. We further examine rotary positional embeddings (RoPE), finding that architectural techniques successful in large language models do not necessarily transfer to small-model regimes.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20877v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shivraj Singh Bhatti</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where Did This Sentence Come From? Tracing Provenance in LLM Reasoning Distillation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20908</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20908v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Reasoning distillation has attracted increasing attention. It typically leverages a large teacher model to generate reasoning paths, which are then used to fine-tune a student model so that it mimics the teacher's behavior in training contexts. However, previous approaches have lacked a detailed analysis of the origins of the distilled model's capabilities. It remains unclear whether the student can maintain consistent behaviors with the teacher in novel test-time contexts, or whether it regresses to its original output patterns, raising concerns about the generalization of distillation models. To analyse this question, we introduce a cross-model Reasoning Distillation Provenance Tracing framework. For each action (e.g., a sentence) produced by the distilled model, we obtain the predictive probabilities assigned by the teacher, the original student, and the distilled model under the same context. By comparing these probabilities, we classify each action into different categories. By systematically disentangling the provenance of each action, we experimentally demonstrate that, in test-time contexts, the distilled model can indeed generate teacher-originated actions, which correlate with and plausibly explain observed performance on distilled model. Building on this analysis, we further propose a teacher-guided data selection method. Unlike prior approach that rely on heuristics, our method directly compares teacher-student divergences on the training data, providing a principled selection criterion. We validate the effectiveness of our approach across multiple representative teacher models and diverse student models. The results highlight the utility of our provenance-tracing framework and underscore its promise for reasoning distillation. We hope to share Reasoning Distillation Provenance Tracing and our insights into reasoning distillation with the community.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20908v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kaiyuan Liu, Shaotian Yan, Rui Miao, Bing Wang, Chen Shen, Jun Zhang, Jieping Ye</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Foundation Model-based Evaluation of Neuropsychiatric Disorders: A Lifespan-Inclusive, Multi-Modal, and Multi-Lingual Study</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20948</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20948v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Neuropsychiatric disorders, such as Alzheimer's disease (AD), depression, and autism spectrum disorder (ASD), are characterized by linguistic and acoustic abnormalities, offering potential biomarkers for early detection. Despite the promise of multi-modal approaches, challenges like multi-lingual generalization and the absence of a unified evaluation framework persist. To address these gaps, we propose FEND (Foundation model-based Evaluation of Neuropsychiatric Disorders), a comprehensive multi-modal framework integrating speech and text modalities for detecting AD, depression, and ASD across the lifespan. Leveraging 13 multi-lingual datasets spanning English, Chinese, Greek, French, and Dutch, we systematically evaluate multi-modal fusion performance. Our results show that multi-modal fusion excels in AD and depression detection but underperforms in ASD due to dataset heterogeneity. We also identify modality imbalance as a prevalent issue, where multi-modal fusion fails to surpass the best mono-modal models. Cross-corpus experiments reveal robust performance in task- and language-consistent scenarios but noticeable degradation in multi-lingual and task-heterogeneous settings. By providing extensive benchmarks and a detailed analysis of performance-influencing factors, FEND advances the field of automated, lifespan-inclusive, and multi-lingual neuropsychiatric disorder assessment. We encourage researchers to adopt the FEND framework for fair comparisons and reproducible research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20948v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhongren Dong, Haotian Guo, Weixiang Xu, Huan Zhao, Zixing Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neural Probe-Based Hallucination Detection for Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20949</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20949v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models(LLMs) excel at text generation and knowledge question-answering tasks, but they are prone to generating hallucinated content, severely limiting their application in high-risk domains. Current hallucination detection methods based on uncertainty estimation and external knowledge retrieval suffer from the limitation that they still produce erroneous content at high confidence levels and rely heavily on retrieval efficiency and knowledge coverage. In contrast, probe methods that leverage the model's hidden-layer states offer real-time and lightweight advantages. However, traditional linear probes struggle to capture nonlinear structures in deep semantic spaces.To overcome these limitations, we propose a neural network-based framework for token-level hallucination detection. By freezing language model parameters, we employ lightweight MLP probes to perform nonlinear modeling of high-level hidden states. A multi-objective joint loss function is designed to enhance detection stability and semantic disambiguity. Additionally, we establish a layer position-probe performance response model, using Bayesian optimization to automatically search for optimal probe insertion layers and achieve superior training results.Experimental results on LongFact, HealthBench, and TriviaQA demonstrate that MLP probes significantly outperform state-of-the-art methods in accuracy, recall, and detection capability under low false-positive conditions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20949v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shize Liang, Hongzhi Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MultiMind at SemEval-2025 Task 7: Crosslingual Fact-Checked Claim Retrieval via Multi-Source Alignment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20950</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20950v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper presents our system for SemEval-2025 Task 7: Multilingual and Crosslingual Fact-Checked Claim Retrieval. In an era where misinformation spreads rapidly, effective fact-checking is increasingly critical. We introduce TriAligner, a novel approach that leverages a dual-encoder architecture with contrastive learning and incorporates both native and English translations across different modalities. Our method effectively retrieves claims across multiple languages by learning the relative importance of different sources in alignment. To enhance robustness, we employ efficient data preprocessing and augmentation using large language models while incorporating hard negative sampling to improve representation learning. We evaluate our approach on monolingual and crosslingual benchmarks, demonstrating significant improvements in retrieval accuracy and fact-checking performance over baselines.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20950v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mohammad Mahdi Abootorabi, Alireza Ghahramani Kure, Mohammadali Mohammadkhani, Sina Elahimanesh, Mohammad Ali Ali Panah</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflection Pretraining Enables Token-Level Self-Correction in Biological Sequence Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20954</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20954v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Chain-of-Thought (CoT) prompting has significantly advanced task-solving capabilities in natural language processing with large language models. Unlike standard prompting, CoT encourages the model to generate intermediate reasoning steps, non-answer tokens, that help guide the model toward more accurate final outputs. These intermediate steps enable more complex reasoning processes such as error correction, memory management, future planning, and self-reflection. However, applying CoT to non-natural language domains, such as protein and RNA language models, is not yet possible, primarily due to the limited expressiveness of their token spaces (e.g., amino acid tokens). In this work, we propose and define the concept of language expressiveness: the ability of a given language, using its tokens and grammar, to encode information. We show that the limited expressiveness of protein language severely restricts the applicability of CoT-style reasoning. To overcome this, we introduce reflection pretraining, for the first time in a biological sequence model, which enables the model to engage in intermediate reasoning through the generation of auxiliary "thinking tokens" beyond simple answer tokens. Theoretically, we demonstrate that our augmented token set significantly enhances biological language expressiveness, thereby improving the overall reasoning capacity of the model. Experimentally, our pretraining approach teaches protein models to self-correct and leads to substantial performance gains compared to standard pretraining.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20954v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiang Zhang, Jiaqi Wei, Yuejin Yang, Zijie Qiu, Yuhan Chen, Zhiqiang Gao, Muhammad Abdul-Mageed, Laks V. S. Lakshmanan, Wanli Ouyang, Chenyu You, Siqi Sun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Replication of LLM Mistakes in Medical Conversations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20983</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20983v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are increasingly evaluated in clinical settings using multi-dimensional rubrics which quantify reasoning quality, safety, and patient-centeredness. Yet, replicating specific mistakes in other LLM models is not straightforward and often requires manual effort. We introduce MedMistake, an automatic pipeline that extracts mistakes LLMs make in patient-doctor conversations and converts them into a benchmark of single-shot QA pairs. Our pipeline (1) creates complex, conversational data between an LLM patient and LLM doctor, (2) runs an evaluation with a committee of 2 LLM judges across a variety of dimensions and (3) creates simplified single-shot QA scenarios from those mistakes. We release MedMistake-All, a dataset of 3,390 single-shot QA pairs where GPT-5 and Gemini 2.5 Pro are currently failing to answer correctly, as judged by two LLM judges. We used medical experts to validate a subset of 211/3390 questions (MedMistake-Bench), which we used to run a final evaluation of 12 frontier LLMs: Claude Opus 4.5, Claude Sonnet 4.5, DeepSeek-Chat, Gemini 2.5 Pro, Gemini 3 Pro, GPT-4o, GPT-5, GPT-5.1, GPT-5.2, Grok 4, Grok 4.1, Mistral Large. We found that GPT models, Claude and Grok obtained the best performance on MedMistake-Bench. We release both the doctor-validated benchmark (MedMistake-Bench), as well as the full dataset (MedMistake-All) at https://huggingface.co/datasets/TheLumos/MedicalMistakeBenchmark.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20983v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Oleksii Proniakin, Diego Fajardo, Ruslan Nazarenko, Razvan Marinescu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distilling the Essence: Efficient Reasoning Distillation via Sequence Truncation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21002</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21002v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Distilling the reasoning capabilities from a large language model (LLM) to a smaller student model often involves training on substantial amounts of reasoning data. However, distillation over lengthy sequences with prompt (P), chain-of-thought (CoT), and answer (A) segments makes the process computationally expensive. In this work, we investigate how the allocation of supervision across different segments (P, CoT, A) affects student performance. Our analysis shows that selective knowledge distillation over only the CoT tokens can be effective when the prompt and answer information is encompassed by it. Building on this insight, we establish a truncation protocol to quantify computation-quality tradeoffs as a function of sequence length. We observe that training on only the first $50\%$ of tokens of every training sequence can retain, on average, $\approx94\%$ of full-sequence performance on math benchmarks while reducing training time, memory usage, and FLOPs by about $50\%$ each. These findings suggest that reasoning distillation benefits from prioritizing early reasoning tokens and provides a simple lever for computation-quality tradeoffs. Codes are available at https://github.com/weiruichen01/distilling-the-essence.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21002v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wei-Rui Chen, Vignesh Kothapalli, Ata Fatahibaarzi, Hejian Sang, Shao Tang, Qingquan Song, Zhipeng Wang, Muhammad Abdul-Mageed</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Supervised Fine-Tuning: Emphasizing Key Answer Tokens for Improved LLM Accuracy</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21017</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21017v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: With the rapid advancement of Large Language Models (LLMs), the Chain-of-Thought (CoT) component has become significant for complex reasoning tasks. However, in conventional Supervised Fine-Tuning (SFT), the model could allocate disproportionately more attention to CoT sequences with excessive length. This reduces focus on the much shorter but essential Key portion-the final answer, whose correctness directly determines task success and evaluation quality. To address this limitation, we propose SFTKey, a two-stage training scheme. In the first stage, conventional SFT is applied to ensure proper output format, while in the second stage, only the Key portion is fine-tuned to improve accuracy. Extensive experiments across multiple benchmarks and model families demonstrate that SFTKey achieves an average accuracy improvement exceeding 5\% over conventional SFT, while preserving the ability to generate correct formats. Overall, this study advances LLM fine-tuning by explicitly balancing CoT learning with additional optimization on answer-relevant tokens.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21017v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaofeng Shi, Qian Kou, Yuduo Li, Hua Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Refinement with LLMs for Graph Representations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21106</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21106v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Graph-structured data exhibit substantial heterogeneity in where their predictive signals originate: in some domains, node-level semantics dominate, while in others, structural patterns play a central role. This structure-semantics heterogeneity implies that no graph learning model with a fixed inductive bias can generalize optimally across diverse graph domains. However, most existing methods address this challenge from the model side by incrementally injecting new inductive biases, which remains fundamentally limited given the open-ended diversity of real-world graphs. In this work, we take a data-centric perspective and treat node semantics as a task-adaptive variable. We propose a Data-Adaptive Semantic Refinement framework DAS for graph representation learning, which couples a fixed graph neural network (GNN) and a large language model (LLM) in a closed feedback loop. The GNN provides implicit supervisory signals to guide the semantic refinement of LLM, and the refined semantics are fed back to update the same graph learner. We evaluate our approach on both text-rich and text-free graphs. Results show consistent improvements on structure-dominated graphs while remaining competitive on semantics-rich graphs, demonstrating the effectiveness of data-centric semantic adaptation under structure-semantics heterogeneity.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21106v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Safal Thapaliya, Zehong Wang, Jiazheng Li, Ziming Li, Yanfang Ye, Chuxu Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semi-Supervised Learning for Large Language Models Safety and Content Moderation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21107</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21107v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Safety for Large Language Models (LLMs) has been an ongoing research focus since their emergence and is even more relevant nowadays with the increasing capacity of those models. Currently, there are several guardrails in place for all public LLMs and multiple proposed datasets for training safety classifiers. However, training these safety classifiers relies on large quantities of labeled data, which can be problematic to acquire, prone to labeling errors, or often include synthetic data. To address these issues, we suggest a different approach: utilizing semi-supervised learning techniques, which leverage both labeled and unlabeled data, to improve the performance on the safety task. We analyze the improvements that these techniques can offer for both prompts given to Large Language Models and the responses to those requests. Moreover, since augmentation is the central part of semi-supervised algorithms, we demonstrate the importance of using task-specific augmentations, which significantly increase the performance when compared to general-purpose augmentation techniques.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21107v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Eduard Stefan Dinuta, Iustin Sirbu, Traian Rebedea</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ClarifyMT-Bench: Benchmarking and Improving Multi-Turn Clarification for Conversational Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21120</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21120v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are increasingly deployed as conversational assistants in open-domain, multi-turn settings, where users often provide incomplete or ambiguous information. However, existing LLM-focused clarification benchmarks primarily assume single-turn interactions or cooperative users, limiting their ability to evaluate clarification behavior in realistic settings. We introduce \textbf{ClarifyMT-Bench}, a benchmark for multi-turn clarification grounded in a five-dimensional ambiguity taxonomy and a set of six behaviorally diverse simulated user personas. Through a hybrid LLM-human pipeline, we construct 6,120 multi-turn dialogues capturing diverse ambiguity sources and interaction patterns. Evaluating ten representative LLMs uncovers a consistent under-clarification bias: LLMs tend to answer prematurely, and performance degrades as dialogue depth increases. To mitigate this, we propose \textbf{ClarifyAgent}, an agentic approach that decomposes clarification into perception, forecasting, tracking, and planning, substantially improving robustness across ambiguity conditions. ClarifyMT-Bench establishes a reproducible foundation for studying when LLMs should ask, when they should answer, and how to navigate ambiguity in real-world human-LLM interactions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21120v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sichun Luo, Yi Huang, Mukai Li, Shichang Meng, Fengyuan Liu, Zefa Hu, Junlan Feng, Qi Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SpidR-Adapt: A Universal Speech Representation Model for Few-Shot Adaptation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21204</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21204v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Human infants, with only a few hundred hours of speech exposure, acquire basic units of new languages, highlighting a striking efficiency gap compared to the data-hungry self-supervised speech models. To address this gap, this paper introduces SpidR-Adapt for rapid adaptation to new languages using minimal unlabeled data. We cast such low-resource speech representation learning as a meta-learning problem and construct a multi-task adaptive pre-training (MAdaPT) protocol which formulates the adaptation process as a bi-level optimization framework. To enable scalable meta-training under this framework, we propose a novel heuristic solution, first-order bi-level optimization (FOBLO), avoiding heavy computation costs. Finally, we stabilize meta-training by using a robust initialization through interleaved supervision which alternates self-supervised and supervised objectives. Empirically, SpidR-Adapt achieves rapid gains in phonemic discriminability (ABX) and spoken language modeling (sWUGGY, sBLIMP, tSC), improving over in-domain language models after training on less than 1h of target-language audio, over $100\times$ more data-efficient than standard training. These findings highlight a practical, architecture-agnostic path toward biologically inspired, data-efficient representations. We open-source the training code and model checkpoints at https://github.com/facebookresearch/spidr-adapt.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21204v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mahi Luthra, Jiayi Shen, Maxime Poli, Angelo Ortiz, Yosuke Higuchi, Youssef Benchekroun, Martin Gleize, Charles-Eric Saint-James, Dongyan Lin, Phillip Rust, Angel Villar, Surya Parimi, Vanessa Stark, Rashel Moritz, Juan Pino, Yann LeCun, Emmanuel Dupoux</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SMART SLM: Structured Memory and Reasoning Transformer, A Small Language Model for Accurate Document Assistance</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21280</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21280v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The user of Engineering Manuals (EM) finds it difficult to read EM s because they are long, have a dense format which includes written documents, step by step procedures, and standard parameter lists for engineering equipment. Off the shelf transformers, especially compact ones, treat this material as a flat stream of tokens. This approach leads to confident but incorrect numeric answers and forces the models to memorize separate facts inefficiently. SMART (Structured Memory and Reasoning Transformer) offers a different and practical solution to the above problem. SMART structures its processing by using a hierarchical approach, and is based upon three main job categories (1) A syntax-aware Fact Extractor (Grammarian) Tree LSTM which extracts facts as subject relation object relations from EM sentences (2) A compact indexed memory MANN (Memory Augmented Neural Network) that indexes these Rational Subject Relation Objects as 384 dimensional vectors that are associated with the source of the information, and (3) A 6 layer Transformer that learns to fuse the previously retrieved facts into its generated response. The entire SMART model utilizes 45.51M parameters, which is 64% less than GPT-2 (124M) and 69% less than BERT (133M), and it achieves a 21.3% higher accuracy than GPT-2, indicating that SMART fits the data better with the least amount of processing requirements. SMART employs dual modes of inference an indexed fast path for known documents (sub-second answer times) and an indexed dynamic path assisted by RAGs for new uploads (FAISS Top 20 results with memory severed at 64 slots). In real world deployment, this framework leads to more well supported results with reduced hallucinations than comparable small transformer models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21280v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Divij Dudeja, Mayukha Pal</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parallel Token Prediction for Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21323</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21323v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We propose Parallel Token Prediction (PTP), a universal framework for parallel sequence generation in language models. PTP jointly predicts multiple dependent tokens in a single transformer call by incorporating the sampling procedure into the model. This reduces the latency bottleneck of autoregressive decoding, and avoids the restrictive independence assumptions common in existing multi-token prediction methods. We prove that PTP can represent arbitrary autoregressive sequence distributions. PTP is trained either by distilling an existing model or through inverse autoregressive training without a teacher. Experimentally, we achieve state-of-the-art speculative decoding performance on Vicuna-7B by accepting over four tokens per step on Spec-Bench. The universality of our framework indicates that parallel generation of long sequences is feasible without loss of modeling power.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21323v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Felix Draxler, Justus Will, Farrin Marouf Sofian, Theofanis Karaletsos, Sameer Singh, Stephan Mandt</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your Reasoning Benchmark May Not Test Reasoning: Revealing Perception Bottleneck in Abstract Reasoning Benchmarks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21329</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21329v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Reasoning benchmarks such as the Abstraction and Reasoning Corpus (ARC) and ARC-AGI are widely used to assess progress in artificial intelligence and are often interpreted as probes of core, so-called ``fluid'' reasoning abilities. Despite their apparent simplicity for humans, these tasks remain challenging for frontier vision-language models (VLMs), a gap commonly attributed to deficiencies in machine reasoning. We challenge this interpretation and hypothesize that the gap arises primarily from limitations in visual perception rather than from shortcomings in inductive reasoning.
  To verify this hypothesis, we introduce a two-stage experimental pipeline that explicitly separates perception and reasoning. In the perception stage, each image is independently converted into a natural-language description, while in the reasoning stage a model induces and applies rules using these descriptions. This design prevents leakage of cross-image inductive signals and isolates reasoning from perception bottlenecks. Across three ARC-style datasets, Mini-ARC, ACRE, and Bongard-LOGO, we show that the perception capability is the dominant factor underlying the observed performance gap by comparing the two-stage pipeline with against standard end-to-end one-stage evaluation. Manual inspection of reasoning traces in the VLM outputs further reveals that approximately 80 percent of model failures stem from perception errors. Together, these results demonstrate that ARC-style benchmarks conflate perceptual and reasoning challenges and that observed performance gaps may overstate deficiencies in machine reasoning. Our findings underscore the need for evaluation protocols that disentangle perception from reasoning when assessing progress in machine intelligence.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21329v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xinhe Wang, Jin Huang, Xingjian Zhang, Tianhao Wang, Jiaqi W. Ma</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>C2LLM Technical Report: A New Frontier in Code Retrieval via Adaptive Cross-Attention Pooling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21332</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21332v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present C2LLM - Contrastive Code Large Language Models, a family of code embedding models in both 0.5B and 7B sizes. Building upon Qwen-2.5-Coder backbones, C2LLM adopts a Pooling by Multihead Attention (PMA) module for generating sequence embedding from token embeddings, effectively 1) utilizing the LLM's causal representations acquired during pretraining, while also 2) being able to aggregate information from all tokens in the sequence, breaking the information bottleneck in EOS-based sequence embeddings, and 3) supporting flexible adaptation of embedding dimension, serving as an alternative to MRL. Trained on three million publicly available data, C2LLM models set new records on MTEB-Code among models of similar sizes, with C2LLM-7B ranking 1st on the overall leaderboard.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21332v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jin Qin, Zihan Liao, Ziyin Zhang, Hang Yu, Peng Di, Rui Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Decoding Paths in Masked Diffusion Models by Quantifying Uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21336</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21336v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Masked Diffusion Models (MDMs) offer flexible, non-autoregressive generation, but this freedom introduces a challenge: final output quality is highly sensitive to the decoding order. We are the first to formalize this issue, attributing the variability in output quality to the cumulative predictive uncertainty along a generative path. To quantify this uncertainty, we introduce Denoising Entropy, a computable metric that serves as an internal signal for evaluating generative process. Leveraging this metric, we propose two algorithms designed to optimize the decoding path: a post-hoc selection method and a real-time guidance strategy. Experiments demonstrate that our entropy-guided methods significantly improve generation quality, consistently boosting accuracy on challenging reasoning, planning, and code benchmarks. Our work establishes Denoising Entropy as a principled tool for understanding and controlling generation, effectively turning the uncertainty in MDMs from a liability into a key advantage for discovering high-quality solutions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21336v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ziyu Chen, Xinbei Jiang, Peng Sun, Tao Lin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MegaRAG: Multimodal Knowledge Graph-Based Retrieval Augmented Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20626</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20626v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) enables large language models (LLMs) to dynamically access external information, which is powerful for answering questions over previously unseen documents. Nonetheless, they struggle with high-level conceptual understanding and holistic comprehension due to limited context windows, which constrain their ability to perform deep reasoning over long-form, domain-specific content such as full-length books. To solve this problem, knowledge graphs (KGs) have been leveraged to provide entity-centric structure and hierarchical summaries, offering more structured support for reasoning. However, existing KG-based RAG solutions remain restricted to text-only inputs and fail to leverage the complementary insights provided by other modalities such as vision. On the other hand, reasoning from visual documents requires textual, visual, and spatial cues into structured, hierarchical concepts. To address this issue, we introduce a multimodal knowledge graph-based RAG that enables cross-modal reasoning for better content understanding. Our method incorporates visual cues into the construction of knowledge graphs, the retrieval phase, and the answer generation process. Experimental results across both global and fine-grained question answering tasks show that our approach consistently outperforms existing RAG-based approaches on both textual and multimodal corpora.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20626v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chi-Hsiang Hsiao, Yi-Cheng Wang, Tzung-Sheng Lin, Yi-Ren Yeh, Chu-Song Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zero-Training Temporal Drift Detection for Transformer Sentiment Models: A Comprehensive Analysis on Authentic Social Media Streams</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20631</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20631v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We present a comprehensive zero-training temporal drift analysis of transformer-based sentiment models validated on authentic social media data from major real-world events. Through systematic evaluation across three transformer architectures and rigorous statistical validation on 12,279 authentic social media posts, we demonstrate significant model instability with accuracy drops reaching 23.4% during event-driven periods. Our analysis reveals maximum confidence drops of 13.0% (Bootstrap 95% CI: [9.1%, 16.5%]) with strong correlation to actual performance degradation. We introduce four novel drift metrics that outperform embedding-based baselines while maintaining computational efficiency suitable for production deployment. Statistical validation across multiple events confirms robust detection capabilities with practical significance exceeding industry monitoring thresholds. This zero-training methodology enables immediate deployment for real-time sentiment monitoring systems and provides new insights into transformer model behavior during dynamic content periods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20631v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aayam Bansal, Ishaan Gangwani</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Real Time Detection and Quantitative Analysis of Spurious Forgetting in Continual Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20634</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20634v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Catastrophic forgetting remains a fundamental challenge in continual learning for large language models. Recent work revealed that performance degradation may stem from spurious forgetting caused by task alignment disruption rather than true knowledge loss. However, this work only qualitatively describes alignment, relies on post-hoc analysis, and lacks automatic distinction mechanisms.
  We introduce the shallow versus deep alignment framework, providing the first quantitative characterization of alignment depth. We identify that current task alignment approaches suffer from shallow alignment - maintained only over the first few output tokens (approximately 3-5) - making models vulnerable to forgetting. This explains why spurious forgetting occurs, why it is reversible, and why fine-tuning attacks are effective.
  We propose a comprehensive framework addressing all gaps: (1) quantitative metrics (0-1 scale) to measure alignment depth across token positions; (2) real-time detection methods for identifying shallow alignment during training; (3) specialized analysis tools for visualization and recovery prediction; and (4) adaptive mitigation strategies that automatically distinguish forgetting types and promote deep alignment. Extensive experiments on multiple datasets and model architectures (Qwen2.5-3B to Qwen2.5-32B) demonstrate 86.2-90.6% identification accuracy and show that promoting deep alignment improves robustness against forgetting by 3.3-7.1% over baselines.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20634v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weiwei Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automated Red-Teaming Framework for Large Language Model Security Assessment: A Comprehensive Attack Generation and Detection System</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20677</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20677v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: As large language models (LLMs) are increasingly deployed in high-stakes domains, ensuring their security and alignment has become a critical challenge. Existing red-teaming practices depend heavily on manual testing, which limits scalability and fails to comprehensively cover the vast space of potential adversarial behaviors. This paper introduces an automated red-teaming framework that systematically generates, executes, and evaluates adversarial prompts to uncover security vulnerabilities in LLMs. Our framework integrates meta-prompting-based attack synthesis, multi-modal vulnerability detection, and standardized evaluation protocols spanning six major threat categories -- reward hacking, deceptive alignment, data exfiltration, sandbagging, inappropriate tool use, and chain-of-thought manipulation. Experiments on the GPT-OSS-20B model reveal 47 distinct vulnerabilities, including 21 high-severity and 12 novel attack patterns, achieving a $3.9\times$ improvement in vulnerability discovery rate over manual expert testing while maintaining 89\% detection accuracy. These results demonstrate the framework's effectiveness in enabling scalable, systematic, and reproducible AI safety evaluations. By providing actionable insights for improving alignment robustness, this work advances the state of automated LLM red-teaming and contributes to the broader goal of building secure and trustworthy AI systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20677v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhang Wei, Peilu Hu, Shengning Lang, Hao Yan, Li Mei, Yichao Zhang, Chen Yang, Junfeng Hao, Zhimo Han</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PHOTON: Hierarchical Autoregressive Modeling for Lightspeed and Memory-Efficient Language Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20687</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20687v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Transformers operate as horizontal token-by-token scanners; at each generation step, the model attends to an ever-growing sequence of token-level states. This access pattern increases prefill latency and makes long-context decoding increasingly memory-bound, as KV-cache reads and writes dominate inference throughput rather than arithmetic computation. We propose Parallel Hierarchical Operation for Top-down Networks (PHOTON), a hierarchical autoregressive model that replaces flat scanning with vertical, multi-resolution context access. PHOTON maintains a hierarchy of latent streams: a bottom-up encoder progressively compresses tokens into low-rate contextual states, while lightweight top-down decoders reconstruct fine-grained token representations. Experimental results show that PHOTON is superior to competitive Transformer-based language models regarding the throughput-quality trade-off, offering significant advantages in long-context and multi-query tasks. This reduces decode-time KV-cache traffic, yielding up to $10^{3}\times$ higher throughput per unit memory.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20687v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.DC</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuma Ichikawa, Naoya Takagi, Takumi Nakagawa, Yuzi Kanazawa, Akira Sakai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AgentMath: Empowering Mathematical Reasoning for Large Language Models via Tool-Augmented Agent</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20745</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20745v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large Reasoning Models (LRMs) like o3 and DeepSeek-R1 have achieved remarkable progress in natural language reasoning with long chain-of-thought. However, they remain computationally inefficient and struggle with accuracy when solving problems requiring complex mathematical operations. In this work, we present AgentMath, an agent framework that seamlessly integrates language models' reasoning capabilities with code interpreters' computational precision to efficiently tackle complex mathematical problems. Our approach introduces three key innovations: (1) An automated method that converts natural language chain-of-thought into structured tool-augmented trajectories, generating high-quality supervised fine-tuning (SFT) data to alleviate data scarcity; (2) A novel agentic reinforcement learning (RL) paradigm that dynamically interleaves natural language generation with real-time code execution. This enables models to autonomously learn optimal tool-use strategies through multi-round interactive feedback, while fostering emergent capabilities in code refinement and error correction; (3) An efficient training system incorporating innovative techniques, including request-level asynchronous rollout scheduling, agentic partial rollout, and prefix-aware weighted load balancing, achieving 4-5x speedup and making efficient RL training feasible on ultra-long sequences with scenarios with massive tool calls.Extensive evaluations show that AgentMath achieves state-of-the-art performance on challenging mathematical competition benchmarks including AIME24, AIME25, and HMMT25. Specifically, AgentMath-30B-A3B attains 90.6%, 86.4%, and 73.8% accuracy respectively, achieving advanced capabilities.These results validate the effectiveness of our approach and pave the way for building more sophisticated and scalable mathematical reasoning agents.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20745v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haipeng Luo, Huawen Feng, Qingfeng Sun, Can Xu, Kai Zheng, Yufei Wang, Tao Yang, Han Hu, Yansong Tang, Di Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generalization of RLVR Using Causal Reasoning as a Testbed</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20760</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20760v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Reinforcement learning with verifiable rewards (RLVR) has emerged as a promising paradigm for post-training large language models (LLMs) on complex reasoning tasks. Yet, the conditions under which RLVR yields robust generalization remain poorly understood. This paper provides an empirical study of RLVR generalization in the setting of probabilistic inference over causal graphical models. This setting offers two natural axes along which to examine generalization: (i) the level of the probabilistic query -- associational, interventional, or counterfactual -- and (ii) the structural complexity of the query, measured by the size of its relevant subgraph. We construct datasets of causal graphs and queries spanning these difficulty axes and fine-tune Qwen-2.5-Instruct models using RLVR or supervised fine-tuning (SFT). We vary both the model scale (3B-32B) and the query level included in training. We find that RLVR yields stronger within-level and across-level generalization than SFT, but only for specific combinations of model size and training query level. Further analysis shows that RLVR's effectiveness depends on the model's initial reasoning competence. With sufficient initial competence, RLVR improves an LLM's marginalization strategy and reduces errors in intermediate probability calculations, producing substantial accuracy gains, particularly on more complex queries. These findings show that RLVR can improve specific causal reasoning subskills, with its benefits emerging only when the model has sufficient initial competence.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20760v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Brian Lu, Hongyu Zhao, Shuo Sun, Hao Peng, Rui Ding, Hongyuan Mei</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoding Predictive Inference in Visual Language Processing via Spatiotemporal Neural Coherence</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20929</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20929v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Human language processing relies on the brain's capacity for predictive inference. We present a machine learning framework for decoding neural (EEG) responses to dynamic visual language stimuli in Deaf signers. Using coherence between neural signals and optical flow-derived motion features, we construct spatiotemporal representations of predictive neural dynamics. Through entropy-based feature selection, we identify frequency-specific neural signatures that differentiate interpretable linguistic input from linguistically disrupted (time-reversed) stimuli. Our results reveal distributed left-hemispheric and frontal low-frequency coherence as key features in language comprehension, with experience-dependent neural signatures correlating with age. This work demonstrates a novel multimodal approach for probing experience-driven generative models of perception in the brain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20929v1</guid>
      <category>q-bio.NC</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sean C. Borneman, Julia Krebs, Ronnie B. Wilbur, Evie A. Malaia</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transductive Visual Programming: Evolving Tool Libraries from Experience for Spatial Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20934</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20934v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Spatial reasoning in 3D scenes requires precise geometric calculations that challenge vision-language models. Visual programming addresses this by decomposing problems into steps calling specialized tools, yet existing methods rely on either fixed toolsets or speculative tool induction before solving problems, resulting in suboptimal programs and poor utilization of induced tools. We present Transductive Visual Programming (TVP), a novel framework that builds new tools from its own experience rather than speculation. TVP first solves problems using basic tools while accumulating experiential solutions into an Example Library, then abstracts recurring patterns from these programs into reusable higher-level tools for an evolving Tool Library. This allows TVP to tackle new problems with increasingly powerful tools learned from experience. On Omni3D-Bench, TVP achieves state-of-the-art performance, outperforming GPT-4o by 22% and the previous best visual programming system by 11%. Our transductively learned tools are used 5x more frequently as core program dependency than inductively created ones, demonstrating more effective tool discovery and reuse. The evolved tools also show strong generalization to unseen spatial tasks, achieving superior performance on benchmarks from SpatialScore-Hard collection without any testset-specific modification. Our work establishes experience-driven transductive tool creation as a powerful paradigm for building self-evolving visual programming agents that effectively tackle challenging spatial reasoning tasks. We release our code at https://transductive-visualprogram.github.io/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20934v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shengguang Wu, Xiaohan Wang, Yuhui Zhang, Hao Zhu, Serena Yeung-Levy</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Context: Large Language Models Failure to Grasp Users Intent</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21110</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21110v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Current Large Language Models (LLMs) safety approaches focus on explicitly harmful content while overlooking a critical vulnerability: the inability to understand context and recognize user intent. This creates exploitable vulnerabilities that malicious users can systematically leverage to circumvent safety mechanisms. We empirically evaluate multiple state-of-the-art LLMs, including ChatGPT, Claude, Gemini, and DeepSeek. Our analysis demonstrates the circumvention of reliable safety mechanisms through emotional framing, progressive revelation, and academic justification techniques. Notably, reasoning-enabled configurations amplified rather than mitigated the effectiveness of exploitation, increasing factual precision while failing to interrogate the underlying intent. The exception was Claude Opus 4.1, which prioritized intent detection over information provision in some use cases. This pattern reveals that current architectural designs create systematic vulnerabilities. These limitations require paradigmatic shifts toward contextual understanding and intent recognition as core safety capabilities rather than post-hoc protective mechanisms.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21110v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ahmed M. Hussain, Salahuddin Salahuddin, Panos Papadimitratos</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ReaSeq: Unleashing World Knowledge via Reasoning for Sequential Modeling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21257</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21257v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Industrial recommender systems face two fundamental limitations under the log-driven paradigm: (1) knowledge poverty in ID-based item representations that causes brittle interest modeling under data sparsity, and (2) systemic blindness to beyond-log user interests that constrains model performance within platform boundaries. These limitations stem from an over-reliance on shallow interaction statistics and close-looped feedback while neglecting the rich world knowledge about product semantics and cross-domain behavioral patterns that Large Language Models have learned from vast corpora.
  To address these challenges, we introduce ReaSeq, a reasoning-enhanced framework that leverages world knowledge in Large Language Models to address both limitations through explicit and implicit reasoning. Specifically, ReaSeq employs explicit Chain-of-Thought reasoning via multi-agent collaboration to distill structured product knowledge into semantically enriched item representations, and latent reasoning via Diffusion Large Language Models to infer plausible beyond-log behaviors. Deployed on Taobao's ranking system serving hundreds of millions of users, ReaSeq achieves substantial gains: &gt;6.0% in IPV and CTR, &gt;2.9% in Orders, and &gt;2.5% in GMV, validating the effectiveness of world-knowledge-enhanced reasoning over purely log-driven approaches.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21257v1</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chuan Wang, Gaoming Yang, Han Wu, Jiakai Tang, Jiahao Yu, Jian Wu, Jianwu Hu, Junjun Zheng, Shuwen Xiao, Yeqiu Yang, Yuning Jiang, Ahjol Nurlanbek, Binbin Cao, Bo Zheng, Fangmei Zhu, Gaoming Zhou, Huimin Yi, Huiping Chu, Jin Huang, Jinzhe Shan, Kenan Cui, Longbin Li, Silu Zhou, Wen Chen, Xia Ming, Xiang Gao, Xin Yao, Xingyu Wen, Yan Zhang, Yiwen Hu, Yulin Wang, Ziheng Bao, Zongyuan Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measuring all the noises of LLM Evals</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21326</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21326v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Separating signal from noise is central to experimental science. Applying well-established statistical method effectively to LLM evals requires consideration of their unique noise characteristics. We clearly define and measure three types of noise: prediction noise from generating different answers on a given question, data noise from sampling questions, and their combined total noise following the law of total variance. To emphasize relative comparisons and gain statistical power, we propose the all-pairs paired method, which applies the paired analysis to all pairs of LLMs and measures all the noise components based on millions of question-level predictions across many evals and settings. These measurements revealed clear patterns. First, each eval exhibits a characteristic and highly predictable total noise level across all model pairs. Second, paired prediction noise typically exceeds paired data noise, which means reducing prediction noise by averaging can significantly increase statistical power. These findings enable practitioners to assess significance without custom testing and to detect much smaller effects in controlled experiments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21326v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sida Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Neural Question Generation using World Knowledge</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/1909.03716</link>
      <description>arXiv:1909.03716v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this paper, we propose a method for incorporating world knowledge (linked entities and fine-grained entity types) into a neural question generation model. This world knowledge helps to encode additional information related to the entities present in the passage required to generate human-like questions. We evaluate our models on both SQuAD and MS MARCO to demonstrate the usefulness of the world knowledge features. The proposed world knowledge enriched question generation model is able to outperform the vanilla neural question generation model by 1.37 and 1.59 absolute BLEU 4 score on SQuAD and MS MARCO test dataset respectively.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:1909.03716v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Deepak Gupta, Kaheer Suleman, Mahmoud Adada, Andrew McNamara, Justin Harris</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sequence to Sequence Reward Modeling: Improving RLHF by Language Feedback</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.00162</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.00162v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Aligning the behavior of Large language models (LLMs) with human intentions and values remains a critical challenge. Reinforcement learning from human feedback (RLHF) aligns LLMs by training a reward model (RM) on human preferences and fine-tuning the LLMs to maximize RM feedback. Despite its effectiveness and popularity, RLHF is prone to biased local optimization. It means RM fails to provide feedback that accurately aligns with human preference, causing LLMs to explore unexpected generalizations, and failing to achieve alignment objectives. To mitigate this issue, we propose a novel \textit{sequence-to-sequence (seq2seq) reward modeling} method. Its key insight is that learning from language feedback rather than scalar feedback improves RLHF without additional annotations. We replaced the reward modeling target from binary maximum likelihood estimation (MLE) with sequence MLE. This method enables richer and fine-grained language feedback without additional annotations, models, or training stages. Our experiments demonstrated its effectiveness, specifically, reducing the refusal-to-response paradigm in single-turn safety dialogues and the long-response bias in text summarization tasks. We provide further analysis that seq2seq RM improves RLHF performance across 2B and 7B LLMs on 3 NLP tasks, achieving an average win rate of 76.9\%. We further show that seq2seq RM can still improve the performance of RLHF under out-of-distribution prompts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.00162v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiayi Zhou, Jiaming Ji, Juntao Dai, Dong Li, Yaodong Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CAKE: Cascading and Adaptive KV Cache Eviction with Layer Preferences</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.12491</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.12491v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) excel at processing long sequences, boosting demand for key-value (KV) caching. While recent efforts to evict KV cache have alleviated the inference burden, they often fail to allocate resources rationally across layers with different attention patterns. In this paper, we introduce Cascading and Adaptive KV cache Eviction (CAKE), a novel approach that frames KV cache eviction as a "cake-slicing problem." CAKE assesses layer-specific preferences by considering attention dynamics in both spatial and temporal dimensions, allocates rational cache size for layers accordingly, and manages memory constraints in a cascading manner. This approach enables a global view of cache allocation, adaptively distributing resources across diverse attention mechanisms while maintaining memory budgets. CAKE also employs a new eviction indicator that considers the shifting importance of tokens over time, addressing limitations in existing methods that overlook temporal dynamics. Comprehensive experiments on LongBench and NeedleBench show that CAKE maintains model performance with only 3.2% of the KV cache and consistently outperforms current baselines across various models and memory constraints, particularly in low-memory settings. Additionally, CAKE achieves over 10x speedup in decoding latency compared to full cache when processing contexts of 128K tokens with FlashAttention-2. Our code is available at https://github.com/antgroup/cakekv.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.12491v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ziran Qin, Yuchen Cao, Mingbao Lin, Wen Hu, Shixuan Fan, Ke Cheng, Weiyao Lin, Jianguo Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Detect, Explain, Escalate: Sustainable Dialogue Breakdown Management for LLM Agents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.18839</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.18839v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated substantial capabilities in conversational AI applications, yet their susceptibility to dialogue breakdowns poses significant challenges to deployment reliability and user trust. This paper introduces a "Detect, Explain, Escalate" framework to manage dialogue breakdowns in LLM-powered agents, emphasizing resource-efficient operation. Our approach integrates two key strategies: (1) We fine-tune a compact 8B-parameter model, augmented with teacher-generated reasoning traces, which serves as an efficient real-time breakdown detector and explainer. This model demonstrates robust classification and calibration on English and Japanese dialogues, and generalizes to the BETOLD dataset, improving accuracy by 7% over its baseline. (2) We systematically evaluate frontier LLMs using advanced prompting (few-shot, chain-of-thought, analogical reasoning) for high-fidelity breakdown assessment. These are integrated into an "escalation" architecture where our efficient detector defers to larger models only when necessary, substantially reducing operational costs and computational overhead. Our fine-tuned model and prompting strategies achieve state-of-the-art performance on DBDC5 and strong results on BETOLD, outperforming specialized classifiers on DBDC5 and narrowing the performance gap to larger proprietary models. The proposed monitor-escalate pipeline reduces inference costs by 54%, providing a cost-effective and interpretable solution for robust conversational AI in high-impact domains. Code and models will be publicly released.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.18839v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Abdellah Ghassel, Xianzhi Li, Xiaodan Zhu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Memory in LLM based Agents: Representations, Operations, and Emerging Topics</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00675</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00675v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Memory is fundamental to large language model (LLM)-based agents, but existing surveys emphasize application-level use (e.g., personalized dialogue), while overlooking the atomic operations governing memory dynamics. This work categorizes memory into parametric (implicit in model weights) and contextual (explicit external data, structured/unstructured) forms, and defines six core operations: Consolidation, Updating, Indexing, Forgetting, Retrieval, and Condensation. Mapping these dimensions reveals four key research topics: long-term, long-context, parametric modification, and multi-source memory. The taxonomy provides a structured view of memory-related research, benchmarks, and tools, clarifying functional interactions in LLM-based agents and guiding future advancements. The datasets, papers, and tools are publicly available at https://github.com/Elvin-Yiming-Du/Survey_Memory_in_AI.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00675v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yiming Du, Wenyu Huang, Danna Zheng, Zhaowei Wang, Sebastien Montella, Mirella Lapata, Kam-Fai Wong, Jeff Z. Pan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Pruning Improve Reasoning? Revisiting Long-CoT Compression with Capability in Mind for Better Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.14582</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.14582v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Long chain-of-thought (Long-CoT) reasoning improves accuracy in LLMs, yet its verbose, self-reflective style often hinders effective distillation into small language models (SLMs). We revisit Long-CoT compression through the lens of capability alignment and ask: Can pruning improve reasoning? We propose Prune-on-Logic, a structure-aware framework that transforms Long-CoT into logic graphs and selectively prunes low-utility reasoning steps under self-verification constraints. Through systematic analysis across three pruning strategies targeting entire chains, core reasoning, and verification, we find that verification pruning consistently improves accuracy while reducing token usage, whereas pruning reasoning steps or indiscriminate pruning degrades performance. Our study reveals that effective pruning aligns supervision with model capacity rather than merely shortening inputs. Gains hold across tasks, model scales, and CoT capability, with larger models benefiting more from pruning due to richer but more redundant reasoning. Our empirical findings highlight pruning as a structural optimization strategy for aligning CoT reasoning with SLM capacity.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.14582v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shangziqi Zhao, Jiahao Yuan, Jinyang Wu, Zhenglin Wang, Guisong Yang, Usman Naseem</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Efficiency Frontiers of Thinking Budget in Medical Reasoning: Scaling Laws between Computational Resources and Reasoning Quality</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.12140</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.12140v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This study presents the first comprehensive evaluation of thinking budget mechanisms in medical reasoning tasks, revealing fundamental scaling laws between computational resources and reasoning quality. We systematically evaluated two major model families, Qwen3 (1.7B to 235B parameters) and DeepSeek-R1 (1.5B to 70B parameters), across 15 medical datasets spanning diverse specialties and difficulty levels. Through controlled experiments with thinking budgets ranging from zero to unlimited tokens, we establish logarithmic scaling relationships where accuracy improvements follow a predictable pattern with both thinking budget and model size. Our findings identify three distinct efficiency regimes: high-efficiency (0 to 256 tokens) suitable for real-time applications, balanced (256 to 512 tokens) offering optimal cost-performance tradeoffs for routine clinical support, and high-accuracy (above 512 tokens) justified only for critical diagnostic tasks. Notably, smaller models demonstrate disproportionately larger benefits from extended thinking, with 15 to 20% improvements compared to 5 to 10% for larger models, suggesting a complementary relationship where thinking budget provides greater relative benefits for capacity-constrained models. Domain-specific patterns emerge clearly, with neurology and gastroenterology requiring significantly deeper reasoning processes than cardiovascular or respiratory medicine. The consistency between Qwen3 native thinking budget API and our proposed truncation method for DeepSeek-R1 validates the generalizability of thinking budget concepts across architectures. These results establish thinking budget control as a critical mechanism for optimizing medical AI systems, enabling dynamic resource allocation aligned with clinical needs while maintaining the transparency essential for healthcare deployment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.12140v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ziqian Bi, Lu Chen, Junhao Song, Hongying Luo, Enze Ge, Junmin Huang, Tianyang Wang, Keyu Chen, Chia Xin Liang, Zihan Wei, Huafeng Liu, Chunjie Tian, Jibin Guan, Joe Yeong, Yongzhi Xu, Peng Wang, Xinyuan Song, Junfeng Hao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GAICo: A Deployed and Extensible Framework for Evaluating Diverse and Multimodal Generative AI Outputs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.16753</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.16753v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The rapid proliferation of Generative AI (GenAI) into diverse, high-stakes domains necessitates robust and reproducible evaluation methods. However, practitioners often resort to ad-hoc, non-standardized scripts, as common metrics are often unsuitable for specialized, structured outputs (e.g., automated plans, time-series) or holistic comparison across modalities (e.g., text, audio, and image). This fragmentation hinders comparability and slows AI system development. To address this challenge, we present GAICo (Generative AI Comparator): a deployed, open-source Python library that streamlines and standardizes GenAI output comparison. GAICo provides a unified, extensible framework supporting a comprehensive suite of reference-based metrics for unstructured text, specialized structured data formats, and multimedia (images, audio). Its architecture features a high-level API for rapid, end-to-end analysis, from multi-model comparison to visualization and reporting, alongside direct metric access for granular control. We demonstrate GAICo's utility through a detailed case study evaluating and debugging complex, multi-modal AI Travel Assistant pipelines. GAICo empowers AI researchers and developers to efficiently assess system performance, make evaluation reproducible, improve development velocity, and ultimately build more trustworthy AI systems, aligning with the goal of moving faster and safer in AI deployment. Since its release on PyPI in Jun 2025, the tool has been downloaded over 13K times, across versions, by Aug 2025, demonstrating growing community interest.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.16753v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nitin Gupta, Pallav Koppisetti, Kausik Lakkaraju, Biplav Srivastava</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning to Compress: Unlocking the Potential of Large Language Models for Text Representation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17129</link>
      <description>arXiv:2511.17129v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Text representation plays a critical role in tasks like clustering, retrieval, and other downstream applications. With the emergence of large language models (LLMs), there is increasing interest in harnessing their capabilities for this purpose. However, most of the LLMs are inherently causal and optimized for next-token prediction, making them suboptimal for producing holistic representations. To address this, recent studies introduced pretext tasks to adapt LLMs for text representation. Most of these tasks, however, rely on token-level prediction objectives, such as the masked next-token prediction (MNTP) used in LLM2Vec. In this work, we explore the untapped potential of context compression as a pretext task for unsupervised adaptation of LLMs. During compression pre-training, the model learns to generate compact memory tokens, which substitute the whole context for downstream sequence prediction. Experiments demonstrate that a well-designed compression objective can significantly enhance LLM-based text representations, outperforming models trained with token-level pretext tasks. Further improvements through contrastive learning produce a strong representation model (LLM2Comp) that outperforms contemporary LLM-based text encoders on a wide range of tasks while being more sample-efficient, requiring significantly less training data. Code is available at https://github.com/longtaizi13579/LLM2Comp.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2511.17129v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yeqin Zhang, Yizheng Zhao, Chen Hu, Binxing Jiao, Daxin Jiang, Ruihang Miao, Cam-Tu Nguyen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>47B Mixture-of-Experts Beats 671B Dense Models on Chinese Medical Examinations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.21701</link>
      <description>arXiv:2511.21701v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The rapid advancement of large language models(LLMs) has prompted significant interest in their potential applications in medical domains. This paper presents a comprehensive benchmark evaluation of 27 state-of-the-art LLMs on Chinese medical examination questions, encompassing seven medical specialties across two professional levels. We introduce a robust evaluation framework that assesses model performance on 2,800 carefully curated questions from cardiovascular, gastroenterology, hematology, infectious diseases, nephrology, neurology, and respiratory medicine domains. Our dataset distinguishes between attending physician and senior physician difficulty levels, providing nuanced insights into model capabilities across varying complexity. Our empirical analysis reveals substantial performance variations among models, with Mixtral-8x7B achieving the highest overall accuracy of 74.25%, followed by DeepSeek-R1-671B at 64.07%. Notably, we observe no consistent correlation between model size and performance, as evidenced by the strong performance of smaller mixture-of-experts architectures. The evaluation demonstrates significant performance gaps between medical specialties, with models generally performing better on cardiovascular and neurology questions compared to gastroenterology and nephrology domains. Furthermore, our analysis indicates minimal performance degradation between attending and senior physician levels for top-performing models, suggesting robust generalization capabilities. This benchmark provides critical insights for the deployment of LLMs in medical education and clinical decision support systems, highlighting both the promise and current limitations of these technologies in specialized medical contexts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2511.21701v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chiung-Yi Tseng, Danyang Zhang, Tianyang Wang, Hongying Luo, Lu Chen, Junming Huang, Jibin Guan, Junfeng Hao, Junhao Song, Xinyuan Song, Ziqian Bi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ART: Adaptive Response Tuning Framework -- A Multi-Agent Tournament-Based Approach to LLM Response Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.00617</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.00617v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated remarkable capabilities in natural language understanding and generation. However, single-model responses often exhibit inconsistencies, hallucinations, and varying quality across different query domains. This paper presents ART (Adaptive Response Tuning), a novel framework that employs tournament-style ELO ranking and multi-agent reasoning to systematically optimize LLM outputs. By enabling multiple LLM agents to compete, critique, and collaborate through structured tournament workflows, ART produces consensus responses that outperform individual model outputs. Our framework introduces configurable tournament parameters, dynamic agent selection, and multiple consensus fusion strategies. Experimental evaluations demonstrate significant improvements in response accuracy, coherence, and reliability compared to baseline single-model approaches. The ART framework provides a scalable, production-ready solution for applications requiring high-quality, vetted LLM responses, achieving an 8.4% improvement in overall quality metrics and R^2 values exceeding 0.96 in ELO rating convergence.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.00617v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Omer Jauhar Khan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VLegal-Bench: Cognitively Grounded Benchmark for Vietnamese Legal Reasoning of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.14554</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.14554v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The rapid advancement of large language models (LLMs) has enabled new possibilities for applying artificial intelligence within the legal domain. Nonetheless, the complexity, hierarchical organization, and frequent revisions of Vietnamese legislation pose considerable challenges for evaluating how well these models interpret and utilize legal knowledge. To address this gap, the Vietnamese Legal Benchmark (VLegal-Bench) is introduced, the first comprehensive benchmark designed to systematically assess LLMs on Vietnamese legal tasks. Informed by Bloom's cognitive taxonomy, VLegal-Bench encompasses multiple levels of legal understanding through tasks designed to reflect practical usage scenarios. The benchmark comprises 10,450 samples generated through a rigorous annotation pipeline, where legal experts label and cross-validate each instance using our annotation system to ensure every sample is grounded in authoritative legal documents and mirrors real-world legal assistant workflows, including general legal questions and answers, retrieval-augmented generation, multi-step reasoning, and scenario-based problem solving tailored to Vietnamese law. By providing a standardized, transparent, and cognitively informed evaluation framework, VLegal-Bench establishes a solid foundation for assessing LLM performance in Vietnamese legal contexts and supports the development of more reliable, interpretable, and ethically aligned AI-assisted legal systems. To facilitate access and reproducibility, we provide a public landing page for this benchmark at https://vilegalbench.cmcai.vn/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.14554v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nguyen Tien Dong, Minh-Anh Nguyen, Thanh Dat Hoang, Nguyen Tuan Ngoc, Dao Xuan Quang Minh, Phan Phi Hai, Nguyen Thi Ngoc Anh, Dang Van Tu, Binh Vu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>T5Gemma 2: Seeing, Reading, and Understanding Longer</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.14856</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.14856v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We introduce T5Gemma 2, the next generation of the T5Gemma family of lightweight open encoder-decoder models, featuring strong multilingual, multimodal and long-context capabilities. T5Gemma 2 follows the adaptation recipe (via UL2) in T5Gemma -- adapting a pretrained decoder-only model into an encoder-decoder model, and extends it from text-only regime to multimodal based on the Gemma 3 models. We further propose two methods to improve the efficiency: tied word embedding that shares all embeddings across encoder and decoder, and merged attention that unifies decoder self- and cross-attention into a single joint module. Experiments demonstrate the generality of the adaptation strategy over architectures and modalities as well as the unique strength of the encoder-decoder architecture on long context modeling. Similar to T5Gemma, T5Gemma 2 yields comparable or better pretraining performance and significantly improved post-training performance than its Gemma 3 counterpart. We release the pretrained models (270M-270M, 1B-1B and 4B-4B) to the community for future research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.14856v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Biao Zhang, Paul Suganthan, Ga\"el Liu, Ilya Philippov, Sahil Dua, Ben Hora, Kat Black, Gus Martins, Omar Sanseviero, Shreya Pathak, Cassidy Hardin, Francesco Visin, Jiageng Zhang, Kathleen Kenealy, Qin Yin, Xiaodan Song, Olivier Lacombe, Armand Joulin, Tris Warkentin, Adam Roberts</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hearing to Translate: The Effectiveness of Speech Modality Integration into LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.16378</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.16378v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: As Large Language Models (LLMs) expand beyond text, integrating speech as a native modality has given rise to SpeechLLMs, which aim to translate spoken language directly, thereby bypassing traditional transcription-based pipelines. Whether this integration improves speech-to-text translation quality over established cascaded architectures, however, remains an open question. We present Hearing to Translate, the first comprehensive test suite rigorously benchmarking 5 state-of-the-art SpeechLLMs against 16 strong direct and cascade systems that couple leading speech foundation models (SFM), with multilingual LLMs. Our analysis spans 16 benchmarks, 13 language pairs, and 9 challenging conditions, including disfluent, noisy, and long-form speech. Across this extensive evaluation, we find that cascaded systems remain the most reliable overall, while current SpeechLLMs only match cascades in selected settings and SFMs lag behind both, highlighting that integrating an LLM, either within the model or in a pipeline, is essential for high-quality speech translation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.16378v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sara Papi, Javier Garcia Gilabert, Zachary Hopton, Vil\'em Zouhar, Carlos Escolano, Gerard I. G\'allego, Jorge Iranzo-S\'anchez, Ahrii Kim, Dominik Mach\'a\v{c}ek, Patricia Schmidtova, Maike Z\"ufle</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When F1 Fails: Granularity-Aware Evaluation for Dialogue Topic Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.17083</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.17083v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Dialogue topic segmentation supports summarization, retrieval, memory management, and conversational continuity. Despite decades of work, evaluation practice remains dominated by strict boundary matching and F1-based metrics. Modern large language model (LLM) based conversational systems increasingly rely on segmentation to manage conversation history beyond fixed context windows. In such systems, unstructured context accumulation degrades efficiency and coherence.
  This paper introduces an evaluation framework that reports boundary density and segment alignment diagnostics (purity and coverage) alongside window-tolerant F1 (W-F1). By separating boundary scoring from boundary selection, we evaluate segmentation quality across density regimes rather than at a single operating point. Cross-dataset evaluation shows that reported performance differences often reflect annotation granularity mismatch rather than boundary placement quality alone.
  We evaluate structurally distinct segmentation strategies across eight dialogue datasets spanning task-oriented, open-domain, meeting-style, and synthetic interactions. Boundary-based metrics are strongly coupled to boundary density: threshold sweeps produce larger W-F1 changes than switching between methods. These findings support viewing topic segmentation as a granularity selection problem rather than prediction of a single correct boundary set. This motivates separating boundary scoring from boundary selection for analyzing and tuning segmentation under varying annotation granularities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.17083v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Michael H. Coen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward Human-Centered AI-Assisted Terminology Work</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.18859</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.18859v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The rapid diffusion of generative artificial intelligence is transforming terminology work. While this technology promises gains in efficiency, its unstructured adoption risks weakening professional autonomy, amplifying bias, and eroding linguistic and conceptual diversity. This paper argues that a human-centered approach to artificial intelligence has become a necessity for terminology work. Building on research in artificial intelligence and translation studies, it proposes a human-centered framework that conceptualizes artificial intelligence as a means of amplifying the terminologist's capabilities, rather than replacing them. The framework is organized around three interrelated dimensions: the augmented terminologist, ethical AI, and human-centered design. Together, these dimensions emphasize the compatibility of high automation with strong human control, the central role of terminologists in bias mitigation, and the importance of designing AI tools and workflows around the needs, values, and well-being of the terminologist. The paper concludes by stressing that current choices in AI adoption will shape not only terminological practice, but also the preservation of accuracy, adequacy, and diversity in terminology and specialized knowledge.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.18859v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Antonio San Martin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>M$^3$KG-RAG: Multi-hop Multimodal Knowledge Graph-enhanced Retrieval-Augmented Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20136</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20136v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) has recently been extended to multimodal settings, connecting multimodal large language models (MLLMs) with vast corpora of external knowledge such as multimodal knowledge graphs (MMKGs). Despite their recent success, multimodal RAG in the audio-visual domain remains challenging due to 1) limited modality coverage and multi-hop connectivity of existing MMKGs, and 2) retrieval based solely on similarity in a shared multimodal embedding space, which fails to filter out off-topic or redundant knowledge. To address these limitations, we propose M$^3$KG-RAG, a Multi-hop Multimodal Knowledge Graph-enhanced RAG that retrieves query-aligned audio-visual knowledge from MMKGs, improving reasoning depth and answer faithfulness in MLLMs. Specifically, we devise a lightweight multi-agent pipeline to construct multi-hop MMKG (M$^3$KG), which contains context-enriched triplets of multimodal entities, enabling modality-wise retrieval based on input queries. Furthermore, we introduce GRASP (Grounded Retrieval And Selective Pruning), which ensures precise entity grounding to the query, evaluates answer-supporting relevance, and prunes redundant context to retain only knowledge essential for response generation. Extensive experiments across diverse multimodal benchmarks demonstrate that M$^3$KG-RAG significantly enhances MLLMs' multimodal reasoning and grounding over existing approaches.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20136v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hyeongcheol Park, Jiyoung Seo, Jaewon Mun, Hogun Park, Wonmin Byeon, Sung June Kim, Hyeonsoo Im, JeungSub Lee, Sangpil Kim</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Step-DeepResearch Technical Report</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20491</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20491v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: As LLMs shift toward autonomous agents, Deep Research has emerged as a pivotal metric. However, existing academic benchmarks like BrowseComp often fail to meet real-world demands for open-ended research, which requires robust skills in intent recognition, long-horizon decision-making, and cross-source verification. To address this, we introduce Step-DeepResearch, a cost-effective, end-to-end agent. We propose a Data Synthesis Strategy Based on Atomic Capabilities to reinforce planning and report writing, combined with a progressive training path from agentic mid-training to SFT and RL. Enhanced by a Checklist-style Judger, this approach significantly improves robustness. Furthermore, to bridge the evaluation gap in the Chinese domain, we establish ADR-Bench for realistic deep research scenarios. Experimental results show that Step-DeepResearch (32B) scores 61.4% on Scale AI Research Rubrics. On ADR-Bench, it significantly outperforms comparable models and rivals SOTA closed-source models like OpenAI and Gemini DeepResearch. These findings prove that refined training enables medium-sized models to achieve expert-level capabilities at industry-leading cost-efficiency.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20491v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chen Hu, Haikuo Du, Heng Wang, Lin Lin, Mingrui Chen, Peng Liu, Ruihang Miao, Tianchi Yue, Wang You, Wei Ji, Wei Yuan, Wenjin Deng, Xiaojian Yuan, Xiaoyun Zhang, Xiangyu Liu, Xikai Liu, Yanming Xu, Yicheng Cao, Yifei Zhang, Yongyao Wang, Yubo Shu, Yurong Zhang, Yuxiang Zhang, Zheng Gong, Zhichao Chang, Binyan Li, Dan Ma, Furong Jia, Hongyuan Wang, Jiayu Liu, Jing Bai, Junlan Liu, Manjiao Liu, Na Wang, Qiuping Wu, Qinxin Du, Shiwei Li, Wen Sun, Yifeng Gong, Yonglin Chen, Yuling Zhao, Yuxuan Lin, Ziqi Ren, Zixuan Wang, Aihu Zhang, Brian Li, Buyun Ma, Kang An, Li Xie, Mingliang Li, Pan Li, Shidong Yang, Xi Chen, Xiaojia Liu, Yuchu Luo, Yuan Song, YuanHao Ding, Yuanwei Liang, Zexi Li, Zhaoning Zhang, Zixin Zhang, Binxing Jiao, Daxin Jiang, Jiansheng Chen, Jing Li, Xiangyu Zhang, Yibo Zhu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reward Is Enough: LLMs Are In-Context Reinforcement Learners</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.06303</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.06303v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Reinforcement learning (RL) is a framework for solving sequential decision-making problems. In this work, we demonstrate that, surprisingly, RL emerges during the inference time of large language models (LLMs), a phenomenon we term in-context RL (ICRL). To reveal this capability, we introduce a simple multi-round prompting framework, we call ICRL prompting, for inference-time self-improvement. The goal of ICRL prompting is to guide LLMs to perform reinforcement learning during inference for self-improvement on a given task. After each response, the model receives numerical scalar feedback, denoted as a reward. In the next round, we prompt the LLM again together with a context that concatenates all prior responses and their associated rewards. We consistently observe that response quality improves as the context grows. In other words, the LLM can optimize scalar reward signals during inference, exhibiting behavior analogous to reinforcement learning. We evaluate ICRL prompting on Game of 24, creative writing, ScienceWorld, and Olympiad-level math competitions (AIME and HMMT), demonstrating significant improvements over baselines such as Self-Refine and Reflexion. Notably, even when the reward signals are generated by the same LLM, ICRL prompting still improves performance, highlighting a promising new paradigm for test-time scaling.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.06303v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kefan Song, Amir Moeini, Peng Wang, Lei Gong, Rohan Chandra, Yanjun Qi, Shangtong Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChainReaction: Causal Chain-Guided Reasoning for Modular and Explainable Causal-Why Video Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.21010</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.21010v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Existing Causal-Why Video Question Answering (VideoQA) models often struggle with higher-order reasoning, relying on opaque, monolithic pipelines that entangle video understanding, causal inference, and answer generation. These black-box approaches offer limited interpretability and tend to depend on shallow heuristics. We propose a novel, modular paradigm that explicitly decouples causal reasoning from answer generation, introducing natural language causal chains as interpretable intermediate representations. Inspired by human cognitive models, these structured cause-effect sequences bridge low-level video content with high-level causal reasoning, enabling transparent and logically coherent inference. Our two-stage architecture comprises a Causal Chain Extractor (CCE) that generates causal chains from video-question pairs, and a Causal Chain-Driven Answerer (CCDA) that derives answers grounded in these chains. To address the lack of annotated reasoning traces, we introduce a scalable method for generating accurate causal chains from existing datasets. We construct human verified causal chains for 46K samples. We also propose CauCo, a new evaluation metric for causality-oriented captioning. Experiments on three large-scale benchmarks demonstrate that our approach not only outperforms state-of-the-art models, but also yields substantial gains in explainability, user trust, and generalization -- positioning the CCE as a reusable causal reasoning engine across diverse domains. Project page: https://paritoshparmar.github.io/chainreaction/</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.21010v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Paritosh Parmar, Eric Peh, Basura Fernando</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RSCC: A Large-Scale Remote Sensing Change Caption Dataset for Disaster Events</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.01907</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.01907v5 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Remote sensing is critical for disaster monitoring, yet existing datasets lack temporal image pairs and detailed textual annotations. While single-snapshot imagery dominates current resources, it fails to capture dynamic disaster impacts over time. To address this gap, we introduce the Remote Sensing Change Caption (RSCC) dataset, a large-scale benchmark comprising 62,351 pre-/post-disaster image pairs (spanning earthquakes, floods, wildfires, and more) paired with rich, human-like change captions. By bridging the temporal and semantic divide in remote sensing data, RSCC enables robust training and evaluation of vision-language models for disaster-aware bi-temporal understanding. Our results highlight RSCC's ability to facilitate detailed disaster-related analysis, paving the way for more accurate, interpretable, and scalable vision-language applications in remote sensing. Code and dataset are available at https://github.com/Bili-Sakura/RSCC.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.01907v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhenyuan Chen, Chenxi Wang, Ningyu Zhang, Feng Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GaussianVision: Vision-Language Alignment from Compressed Image Representations using 2D Gaussian Splatting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.22615</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.22615v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Modern vision language pipelines are driven by RGB vision encoders trained on massive image text corpora. While these pipelines have enabled impressive zero-shot capabilities and strong transfer across tasks, they still inherit two structural inefficiencies from the pixel domain: (i) transmitting dense RGB images from edge devices to the cloud is energy-intensive and costly, and (ii) patch-based tokenization explodes sequence length, stressing attention budgets and context limits. We explore 2D Gaussian Splatting (2DGS) as an alternative visual substrate for alignment: a compact, spatially adaptive representation that parameterizes images by a set of colored anisotropic Gaussians. We develop a scalable 2DGS pipeline with structured initialization, luminance-aware pruning, and batched CUDA kernels, achieving over 90x faster fitting and about 97% GPU utilization compared to prior implementations. We further adapt contrastive language-image pre-training (CLIP) to 2DGS by reusing a frozen RGB-based transformer backbone with a lightweight splat-aware input stem and a perceiver resampler, training only 9.7% to 13.8% of the total parameters. On a 12.8M dataset from DataComp, GS encoders yield competitive zero-shot performance on 38 datasets from the CLIP benchmark while compressing inputs 3x to 23.5x relative to pixels. Our results establish 2DGS as a viable multimodal substrate, pinpoint architectural bottlenecks, and open a path toward representations that are both semantically powerful and transmission-efficient for edge-cloud learning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.22615v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yasmine Omri, Connor Ding, Tsachy Weissman, Thierry Tambe</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thinking-Free Policy Initialization Makes Distilled Reasoning Models More Effective and Efficient Reasoners</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.26226</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.26226v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Reinforcement Learning with Verifiable Reward (RLVR) effectively solves complex tasks but demands extremely long context lengths during training, leading to substantial computational costs. While multi-stage training can partially mitigate this, starting with overly short contexts often causes irreversible performance degradation, ultimately failing to reduce overall training compute significantly. In this paper, we introduce **T**hinking-**F**ree **P**olicy **I**nitialization (**TFPI**), a simple yet effective adaptation to RLVR that bridges long Chain-of-Thought (CoT) distillation and standard RLVR. TFPI employs a simple *ThinkFree* operation, explicitly discarding the thinking content via a direct *&lt;/think&gt;* append, to reduce token usage during inference. Training with *ThinkFree*-adapted inputs improves performance and lowers token consumption, even in the original slow-thinking mode. Extensive experiments across various benchmarks have shown that TFPI accelerates RL convergence, achieves a higher performance ceiling, and yields more token-efficient reasoning models without specialized rewards or complex training designs. With TFPI only, we train a 4B model to reach 89.0% accuracy on AIME24 and 65.5% on LiveCodeBench using less than 4K H20 hours.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.26226v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xin Xu, Cliveb AI, Kai Yang, Tianhao Chen, Yang Wang, Saiyong Yang, Can Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don't Pass@k: A Bayesian Framework for Large Language Model Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.04265</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.04265v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Pass$@k$ is widely used to report performance for LLM reasoning, but it often yields unstable, misleading rankings, especially when the number of trials (samples) is limited and compute is constrained. We present a principled Bayesian evaluation framework that replaces Pass$@k$ and average accuracy over $N$ trials (avg$@N$) with posterior estimates of a model's underlying success probability and credible intervals, yielding stable rankings and a transparent decision rule for differences. Evaluation outcomes are modeled as categorical (not just 0/1) with a Dirichlet prior, giving closed-form expressions for the posterior mean and uncertainty of any weighted rubric and enabling the use of prior evidence when appropriate. Theoretically, under a uniform prior, the Bayesian posterior mean is order-equivalent to average accuracy (Pass$@1$), explaining its empirical robustness while adding principled uncertainty. Empirically, in simulations with known ground-truth success rates and on AIME'24/'25, HMMT'25, and BrUMO'25, the Bayesian/avg procedure achieves faster convergence and greater rank stability than Pass$@k$ and recent variants, enabling reliable comparisons at far smaller sample counts. The framework clarifies when observed gaps are statistically meaningful (non-overlapping credible intervals) versus noise, and it naturally extends to graded, rubric-based evaluations. Together, these results recommend replacing Pass$@k$ for LLM evaluation and ranking with a posterior-based, compute-efficient protocol that unifies binary and non-binary evaluation while making uncertainty explicit. Code is available at https://github.com/mohsenhariri/scorio</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.04265v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>math.ST</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <category>stat.TH</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mohsen Hariri, Amirhossein Samandar, Michael Hinczewski, Vipin Chaudhary</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VCB Bench: An Evaluation Benchmark for Audio-Grounded Large Language Model Conversational Agents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.11098</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.11098v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Recent advances in large audio language models (LALMs) have greatly enhanced multimodal conversational systems. However, existing benchmarks remain limited -- they are mainly English-centric, rely on synthetic speech, and lack comprehensive, discriminative evaluation across multiple dimensions. To address these gaps, we present Voice Chat Bot Bench (VCB Bench) -- a high-quality Chinese benchmark built entirely on real human speech. VCB Bench evaluates LALMs from three complementary perspectives: instruction following (including speech-level control beyond text commands), knowledge understanding (general knowledge, reasoning, and daily dialogue), and robustness (stability under perturbations in content, environment, and speaker traits). Experiments on representative LALMs reveal notable performance gaps and highlight future directions for improvement. VCB Bench provides a reproducible and fine-grained evaluation framework, offering standardized methodology and practical insights for advancing Chinese voice conversational models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.11098v2</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiliang Hu, Wenfu Wang, Zuchao Li, Chenxing Li, Yiyang Zhao, Hanzhao Li, Liqiang Zhang, Meng Yu, Dong Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>O3SLM: Open Weight, Open Data, and Open Vocabulary Sketch-Language Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.14368</link>
      <description>arXiv:2511.14368v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: While Large Vision Language Models (LVLMs) are increasingly deployed in real-world applications, their ability to interpret abstract visual inputs remains limited. Specifically, they struggle to comprehend hand-drawn sketches, a modality that offers an intuitive means of expressing concepts that are difficult to describe textually. We identify the primary bottleneck as the absence of a large-scale dataset that jointly models sketches, photorealistic images, and corresponding natural language instructions. To address this, we present two key contributions: (1) a new, large-scale dataset of image-sketch-instruction triplets designed to facilitate both pretraining and instruction tuning, and (2) O3SLM, an LVLM trained on this dataset. Comprehensive evaluations on multiple sketch-based tasks: (a) object localization, (b) counting, (c) image retrieval i.e., (SBIR and fine-grained SBIR), and (d) visual question answering (VQA); while incorporating the three existing sketch datasets, namely QuickDraw!, Sketchy, and Tu Berlin, along with our generated SketchVCL dataset, show that O3SLM achieves state-of-the-art performance, substantially outperforming existing LVLMs in sketch comprehension and reasoning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2511.14368v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rishi Gupta, Mukilan Karuppasamy, Shyam Marjit, Aditay Tripathi, Anirban Chakraborty</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLaDA2.0: Scaling Up Diffusion Language Models to 100B</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.15745</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.15745v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: This paper presents LLaDA2.0 -- a tuple of discrete diffusion large language models (dLLM) scaling up to 100B total parameters through systematic conversion from auto-regressive (AR) models -- establishing a new paradigm for frontier-scale deployment. Instead of costly training from scratch, LLaDA2.0 upholds knowledge inheritance, progressive adaption and efficiency-aware design principle, and seamless converts a pre-trained AR model into dLLM with a novel 3-phase block-level WSD based training scheme: progressive increasing block-size in block diffusion (warm-up), large-scale full-sequence diffusion (stable) and reverting back to compact-size block diffusion (decay). Along with post-training alignment with SFT and DPO, we obtain LLaDA2.0-mini (16B) and LLaDA2.0-flash (100B), two instruction-tuned Mixture-of-Experts (MoE) variants optimized for practical deployment. By preserving the advantages of parallel decoding, these models deliver superior performance and efficiency at the frontier scale. Both models were open-sourced.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.15745v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tiwei Bie, Maosong Cao, Kun Chen, Lun Du, Mingliang Gong, Zhuochen Gong, Yanmei Gu, Jiaqi Hu, Zenan Huang, Zhenzhong Lan, Chengxi Li, Chongxuan Li, Jianguo Li, Zehuan Li, Huabin Liu, Lin Liu, Guoshan Lu, Xiaocheng Lu, Yuxin Ma, Jianfeng Tan, Lanning Wei, Ji-Rong Wen, Yipeng Xing, Xiaolu Zhang, Junbo Zhao, Da Zheng, Jun Zhou, Junlin Zhou, Zhanchao Zhou, Liwang Zhu, Yihong Zhuang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Code2Doc: A Quality-First Curated Dataset for Code Documentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.18748</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.18748v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The performance of automatic code documentation generation models depends critically on the quality of the training data used for supervision. However, most existing code documentation datasets are constructed through large scale scraping of public repositories with limited quality control. As a result, they often contain noisy documentation, extensive duplication, and increasing contamination from AI generated content. These issues weaken the supervision signal available to learning-based models and complicate evaluation.
  We introduce Code2Doc, a quality-first curated dataset for function-level code documentation generation. Code2Doc consists of 13,358 high-quality function-documentation pairs extracted from widely used open-source repositories spanning five programming languages: Python, Java, TypeScript, JavaScript, and C++. The dataset is constructed using a four-stage curation pipeline that enforces documentation completeness and clarity, filters functions based on structural and complexity criteria, removes exact and near-duplicate code, and identifies documentation likely to be AI generated. Starting from 52,069 extracted candidates, only 25.6% satisfy all quality constraints.
  We provide a detailed analysis of the resulting dataset, which achieves a mean documentation quality score of 6.93 out of 10. Overall, 86.9% of samples contain explicit type annotations, and only 2.9% are flagged as potentially AI generated. Baseline experiments show that fine-tuning a large language model on Code2Doc yields relative improvements of 29.47% in BLEU and 24.04% in ROUGE-L over zero shot performance, despite the modest dataset size. We release both the dataset and the full curation pipeline to support reproducible research on automatic code documentation generation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.18748v2</guid>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Recep Kaan Karaman, Meftun Akarsu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coherence in the brain unfolds across separable temporal regimes</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20481</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20481v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Coherence in language requires the brain to satisfy two competing temporal demands: gradual accumulation of meaning across extended context and rapid reconfiguration of representations at event boundaries. Despite their centrality to language and thought, how these processes are implemented in the human brain during naturalistic listening remains unclear. Here, we tested whether these two processes can be captured by annotation-free drift and shift signals and whether their neural expression dissociates across large-scale cortical systems. These signals were derived from a large language model (LLM) and formalized contextual drift and event shifts directly from the narrative input. To enable high-precision voxelwise encoding models with stable parameter estimates, we densely sampled one healthy adult across more than 7 hours of listening to thirteen crime stories while collecting ultra high-field (7T) BOLD data. We then modeled the feature-informed hemodynamic response using a regularized encoding framework validated on independent stories. Drift predictions were prevalent in default-mode network hubs, whereas shift predictions were evident bilaterally in the primary auditory cortex and language association cortex. Furthermore, activity in default-mode and parietal networks was best explained by a signal capturing how meaning accumulates and gradually fades over the course of the narrative. Together, these findings show that coherence during language comprehension is implemented through dissociable neural regimes of slow contextual integration and rapid event-driven reconfiguration, offering a mechanistic entry point for understanding disturbances of language coherence in psychiatric disorders.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20481v2</guid>
      <category>q-bio.NC</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Davide Stauba, Finn Rabe, Akhil Misra, Yves Pauli, Roya H\"uppi, Ni Yang, Nils Lang, Lars Michels, Victoria Edkins, Sascha Fr\"uhholz, Iris Sommer, Wolfram Hinzen, Philipp Homan</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
