<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL</link>
    <description>cs.CL updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 04:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Saturday</day>
      <day>Sunday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking Large Language Models for Calculus Problem-Solving: A Comparative Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13187</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13187v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This study presents a comprehensive evaluation of five leading large language models (LLMs) - Chat GPT 4o, Copilot Pro, Gemini Advanced, Claude Pro, and Meta AI - on their performance in solving calculus differentiation problems. The investigation assessed these models across 13 fundamental problem types, employing a systematic cross-evaluation framework where each model solved problems generated by all models. Results revealed significant performance disparities, with Chat GPT 4o achieving the highest success rate (94.71%), followed by Claude Pro (85.74%), Gemini Advanced (84.42%), Copilot Pro (76.30%), and Meta AI (56.75%). All models excelled at procedural differentiation tasks but showed varying limitations with conceptual understanding and algebraic manipulation. Notably, problems involving increasing/decreasing intervals and optimization word problems proved most challenging across all models. The cross-evaluation matrix revealed that Claude Pro generated the most difficult problems, suggesting distinct capabilities between problem generation and problem-solving. These findings have significant implications for educational applications, highlighting both the potential and limitations of LLMs as calculus learning tools. While they demonstrate impressive procedural capabilities, their conceptual understanding remains limited compared to human mathematical reasoning, emphasizing the continued importance of human instruction for developing deeper mathematical comprehension.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13187v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>In Hak Moon</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BASIR: Budget-Assisted Sectoral Impact Ranking -- A Dataset for Sector Identification and Performance Prediction Using Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13189</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13189v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Government fiscal policies, particularly annual union budgets, exert significant influence on financial markets. However, real-time analysis of budgetary impacts on sector-specific equity performance remains methodologically challenging and largely unexplored. This study proposes a framework to systematically identify and rank sectors poised to benefit from India's Union Budget announcements. The framework addresses two core tasks: (1) multi-label classification of excerpts from budget transcripts into 81 predefined economic sectors, and (2) performance ranking of these sectors. Leveraging a comprehensive corpus of Indian Union Budget transcripts from 1947 to 2025, we introduce BASIR (Budget-Assisted Sectoral Impact Ranking), an annotated dataset mapping excerpts from budgetary transcripts to sectoral impacts. Our architecture incorporates fine-tuned embeddings for sector identification, coupled with language models that rank sectors based on their predicted performances. Our results demonstrate 0.605 F1-score in sector classification, and 0.997 NDCG score in predicting ranks of sectors based on post-budget performances. The methodology enables investors and policymakers to quantify fiscal policy impacts through structured, data-driven insights, addressing critical gaps in manual analysis. The annotated dataset has been released under CC-BY-NC-SA-4.0 license to advance computational economics research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13189v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>q-fin.ST</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sohom Ghosh, Sudip Kumar Naskar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KFinEval-Pilot: A Comprehensive Benchmark Suite for Korean Financial Language Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13216</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13216v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We introduce KFinEval-Pilot, a benchmark suite specifically designed to evaluate large language models (LLMs) in the Korean financial domain. Addressing the limitations of existing English-centric benchmarks, KFinEval-Pilot comprises over 1,000 curated questions across three critical areas: financial knowledge, legal reasoning, and financial toxicity. The benchmark is constructed through a semi-automated pipeline that combines GPT-4-generated prompts with expert validation to ensure domain relevance and factual accuracy. We evaluate a range of representative LLMs and observe notable performance differences across models, with trade-offs between task accuracy and output safety across different model families. These results highlight persistent challenges in applying LLMs to high-stakes financial applications, particularly in reasoning and safety. Grounded in real-world financial use cases and aligned with the Korean regulatory and linguistic context, KFinEval-Pilot serves as an early diagnostic tool for developing safer and more reliable financial AI systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13216v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bokwang Hwang, Seonkyu Lim, Taewoong Kim, Yongjae Geun, Sunghyun Bang, Sohyun Park, Jihyun Park, Myeonggyu Lee, Jinwoo Lee, Yerin Kim, Jinsun Yoo, Jingyeong Hong, Jina Park, Yongchan Kim, Suhyun Kim, Younggyun Hahm, Yiseul Lee, Yejee Kang, Chanhyuk Yoon, Chansu Lee, Heeyewon Jeong, Jiyeon Lee, Seonhye Gu, Hyebin Kang, Yousang Cho, Hangyeol Yoo, KyungTae Lim</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainability via LLM Right-sizing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13217</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13217v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have become increasingly embedded in organizational workflows. This has raised concerns over their energy consumption, financial costs, and data sovereignty. While performance benchmarks often celebrate cutting-edge models, real-world deployment decisions require a broader perspective: when is a smaller, locally deployable model "good enough"? This study offers an empirical answer by evaluating eleven proprietary and open-weight LLMs across ten everyday occupational tasks, including summarizing texts, generating schedules, and drafting emails and proposals. Using a dual-LLM-based evaluation framework, we automated task execution and standardized evaluation across ten criteria related to output quality, factual accuracy, and ethical responsibility. Results show that GPT-4o delivers consistently superior performance but at a significantly higher cost and environmental footprint. Notably, smaller models like Gemma-3 and Phi-4 achieved strong and reliable results on most tasks, suggesting their viability in contexts requiring cost-efficiency, local deployment, or privacy. A cluster analysis revealed three model groups -- premium all-rounders, competent generalists, and limited but safe performers -- highlighting trade-offs between quality, control, and sustainability. Significantly, task type influenced model effectiveness: conceptual tasks challenged most models, while aggregation and transformation tasks yielded better performances. We argue for a shift from performance-maximizing benchmarks to task- and context-aware sufficiency assessments that better reflect organizational priorities. Our approach contributes a scalable method to evaluate AI models through a sustainability lens and offers actionable guidance for responsible LLM deployment in practice.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13217v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jennifer Haase, Finn Klessascheck, Jan Mendling, Sebastian Pokutta</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DIDS: Domain Impact-aware Data Sampling for Large Language Model Training</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13227</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13227v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are commonly trained on multi-domain datasets, where domain sampling strategies significantly impact model performance due to varying domain importance across downstream tasks. Existing approaches for optimizing domain-level sampling strategies struggle with maintaining intra-domain consistency and accurately measuring domain impact. In this paper, we present Domain Impact-aware Data Sampling (DIDS). To ensure intra-domain consistency, a gradient clustering algorithm is proposed to group training data based on their learning effects, where a proxy language model and dimensionality reduction are employed to reduce computational overhead. To accurately measure domain impact, we develop a Fisher Information Matrix (FIM) guided metric that quantifies how domain-specific parameter updates affect the model's output distributions on downstream tasks, with theoretical guarantees. Furthermore, to determine optimal sampling ratios, DIDS combines both the FIM-guided domain impact assessment and loss learning trajectories that indicate domain-specific potential, while accounting for diminishing marginal returns. Extensive experiments demonstrate that DIDS achieves 3.4% higher average performance while maintaining comparable training efficiency.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13227v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weijie Shi, Jipeng Zhang, Yaguang Wu, Jingzhi Fang, Ruiyuan Zhang, Jiajie Xu, Jia Zhu, Hao Chen, Yao Zhao, Sirui Han, Xiaofang Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ImPart: Importance-Aware Delta-Sparsification for Improved Model Compression and Merging in LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13237</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13237v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: With the proliferation of task-specific large language models, delta compression has emerged as a method to mitigate the resource challenges of deploying numerous such models by effectively compressing the delta model parameters. Previous delta-sparsification methods either remove parameters randomly or truncate singular vectors directly after singular value decomposition (SVD). However, these methods either disregard parameter importance entirely or evaluate it with too coarse a granularity. In this work, we introduce ImPart, a novel importance-aware delta sparsification approach. Leveraging SVD, it dynamically adjusts sparsity ratios of different singular vectors based on their importance, effectively retaining crucial task-specific knowledge even at high sparsity ratios. Experiments show that ImPart achieves state-of-the-art delta sparsification performance, demonstrating $2\times$ higher compression ratio than baselines at the same performance level. When integrated with existing methods, ImPart sets a new state-of-the-art on delta quantization and model merging.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13237v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yan Yang, Yixia Li, Hongru Wang, Xuetao Wei, Jianqiao Yu, Yun Chen, Guanhua Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CPG-EVAL: A Multi-Tiered Benchmark for Evaluating the Chinese Pedagogical Grammar Competence of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13261</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13261v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Purpose: The rapid emergence of large language models (LLMs) such as ChatGPT has significantly impacted foreign language education, yet their pedagogical grammar competence remains under-assessed. This paper introduces CPG-EVAL, the first dedicated benchmark specifically designed to evaluate LLMs' knowledge of pedagogical grammar within the context of foreign language instruction. Methodology: The benchmark comprises five tasks designed to assess grammar recognition, fine-grained grammatical distinction, categorical discrimination, and resistance to linguistic interference. Findings: Smaller-scale models can succeed in single language instance tasks, but struggle with multiple instance tasks and interference from confusing instances. Larger-scale models show better resistance to interference but still have significant room for accuracy improvement. The evaluation indicates the need for better instructional alignment and more rigorous benchmarks, to effectively guide the deployment of LLMs in educational contexts. Value: This study offers the first specialized, theory-driven, multi-tiered benchmark framework for systematically evaluating LLMs' pedagogical grammar competence in Chinese language teaching contexts. CPG-EVAL not only provides empirical insights for educators, policymakers, and model developers to better gauge AI's current abilities in educational settings, but also lays the groundwork for future research on improving model alignment, enhancing educational suitability, and ensuring informed decision-making concerning LLM integration in foreign language instruction.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13261v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dong Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment Analysis on the young people's perception about the mobile Internet costs in Senegal</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13284</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13284v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Internet penetration rates in Africa are rising steadily, and mobile Internet is getting an even bigger boost with the availability of smartphones. Young people are increasingly using the Internet, especially social networks, and Senegal is no exception to this revolution. Social networks have become the main means of expression for young people. Despite this evolution in Internet access, there are few operators on the market, which limits the alternatives available in terms of value for money. In this paper, we will look at how young people feel about the price of mobile Internet in Senegal, in relation to the perceived quality of the service, through their comments on social networks. We scanned a set of Twitter and Facebook comments related to the subject and applied a sentiment analysis model to gather their general feelings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13284v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Derguene Mbaye, Madoune Robert Seye, Moussa Diallo, Mamadou Lamine Ndiaye, Djiby Sow, Dimitri Samuel Adjanohoun, Tatiana Mbengue, Cheikh Samba Wade, De Roulet Pablo, Jean-Claude Baraka Munyaka, Jerome Chenal</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THOUGHTTERMINATOR: Benchmarking, Calibrating, and Mitigating Overthinking in Reasoning Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13367</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13367v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Reasoning models have demonstrated impressive performance on difficult tasks that traditional language models struggle at. However, many are plagued with the problem of overthinking--generating large amounts of unnecessary tokens which don't improve accuracy on a question. We introduce approximate measures of problem-level difficulty and demonstrate that a clear relationship between problem difficulty and optimal token spend exists, and evaluate how well calibrated a variety of reasoning models are in terms of efficiently allocating the optimal token count. We find that in general, reasoning models are poorly calibrated, particularly on easy problems. To evaluate calibration on easy questions we introduce DUMB500, a dataset of extremely easy math, reasoning, code, and task problems, and jointly evaluate reasoning model on these simple examples and extremely difficult examples from existing frontier benchmarks on the same task domain. Finally, we introduce THOUGHTTERMINATOR, a training-free black box decoding technique that significantly improves reasoning model calibration.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13367v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiao Pu, Michael Saxon, Wenyue Hua, William Yang Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secure Multifaceted-RAG for Enterprise: Hybrid Knowledge Retrieval with Security Filtering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13425</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13425v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Existing Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) systems face challenges in enterprise settings due to limited retrieval scope and data security risks. When relevant internal documents are unavailable, the system struggles to generate accurate and complete responses. Additionally, using closed-source Large Language Models (LLMs) raises concerns about exposing proprietary information. To address these issues, we propose the Secure Multifaceted-RAG (SecMulti-RAG) framework, which retrieves not only from internal documents but also from two supplementary sources: pre-generated expert knowledge for anticipated queries and on-demand external LLM-generated knowledge. To mitigate security risks, we adopt a local open-source generator and selectively utilize external LLMs only when prompts are deemed safe by a filtering mechanism. This approach enhances completeness, prevents data leakage, and reduces costs. In our evaluation on a report generation task in the automotive industry, SecMulti-RAG significantly outperforms traditional RAG - achieving 79.3 to 91.9 percent win rates across correctness, richness, and helpfulness in LLM-based evaluation, and 56.3 to 70.4 percent in human evaluation. This highlights SecMulti-RAG as a practical and secure solution for enterprise RAG.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13425v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Grace Byun, Shinsun Lee, Nayoung Choi, Jinho Choi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>D-GEN: Automatic Distractor Generation and Evaluation for Reliable Assessment of Generative Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13439</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13439v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Evaluating generative models with open-ended generation is challenging due to inconsistencies in response formats. Multiple-choice (MC) evaluation mitigates this issue, but generating high-quality distractors is time-consuming and labor-intensive. We introduce D-GEN, the first open-source distractor generator model that transforms open-ended data into an MC format. To evaluate distractor quality, we propose two novel methods: (1) ranking alignment, ensuring generated distractors retain the discriminatory power of ground-truth distractors, and (2) entropy analysis, comparing model confidence distributions. Our results show that D-GEN preserves ranking consistency (Spearman's rho 0.99, Kendall's tau 0.94) and closely matches the entropy distribution of ground-truth distractors. Human evaluation further confirms the fluency, coherence, distractiveness, and incorrectness. Our work advances robust and efficient distractor generation with automated evaluation, setting a new standard for MC evaluation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13439v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Grace Byun, Jinho Choi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Large to Super-Tiny: End-to-End Optimization for Cost-Efficient LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13471</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13471v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In recent years, Large Language Models (LLMs) have significantly advanced artificial intelligence by optimizing traditional Natural Language Processing (NLP) pipelines, improving performance and generalization. This has spurred their integration into various systems. Many NLP systems, including ours, employ a "one-stage" pipeline directly incorporating LLMs. While effective, this approach incurs substantial costs and latency due to the need for large model parameters to achieve satisfactory outcomes. This paper introduces a three-stage cost-efficient end-to-end LLM deployment pipeline-including prototyping, knowledge transfer, and model compression-to tackle the cost-performance dilemma in LLM-based frameworks. Our approach yields a super tiny model optimized for cost and performance in online systems, simplifying the system architecture. Initially, by transforming complex tasks into a function call-based LLM-driven pipeline, an optimal performance prototype system is constructed to produce high-quality data as a teacher model. The second stage combine techniques like rejection fine-tuning, reinforcement learning and knowledge distillation to transfer knowledge to a smaller 0.5B student model, delivering effective performance at minimal cost. The final stage applies quantization and pruning to extremely compress model to 0.4B, achieving ultra-low latency and cost. The framework's modular design and cross-domain capabilities suggest potential applicability in other NLP areas.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13471v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiliang Ni, Jiachen Pu, Zhongyi Yang, Kun Zhou, Hui Wang, Xiaoliang Xiao, Dakui Wang, Xin Li, Jingfeng Luo, Conggang Hu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM Sensitivity Evaluation Framework for Clinical Diagnosis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13475</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13475v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated impressive performance across various domains. However, for clinical diagnosis, higher expectations are required for LLM's reliability and sensitivity: thinking like physicians and remaining sensitive to key medical information that affects diagnostic reasoning, as subtle variations can lead to different diagnosis results. Yet, existing works focus mainly on investigating the sensitivity of LLMs to irrelevant context and overlook the importance of key information. In this paper, we investigate the sensitivity of LLMs, i.e. GPT-3.5, GPT-4, Gemini, Claude3 and LLaMA2-7b, to key medical information by introducing different perturbation strategies. The evaluation results highlight the limitations of current LLMs in remaining sensitive to key medical information for diagnostic decision-making. The evolution of LLMs must focus on improving their reliability, enhancing their ability to be sensitive to key information, and effectively utilizing this information. These improvements will enhance human trust in LLMs and facilitate their practical application in real-world scenarios. Our code and dataset are available at https://github.com/chenwei23333/DiagnosisQA.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13475v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Proceedings of the 31st International Conference on Computational Linguistics, 2025</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Chenwei Yan, Xiangling Fu, Yuxuan Xiong, Tianyi Wang, Siu Cheung Hui, Ji Wu, Xien Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prejudge-Before-Think: Enhancing Large Language Models at Test-Time by Process Prejudge Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13500</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13500v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this paper, we introduce a new \emph{process prejudge} strategy in LLM reasoning to demonstrate that bootstrapping with process prejudge allows the LLM to adaptively anticipate the errors encountered when advancing the subsequent reasoning steps, similar to people sometimes pausing to think about what mistakes may occur and how to avoid them, rather than relying solely on trial and error. Specifically, we define a prejudge node in the rationale, which represents a reasoning step, with at least one step that follows the prejudge node that has no paths toward the correct answer. To synthesize the prejudge reasoning process, we present an automated reasoning framework with a dynamic tree-searching strategy. This framework requires only one LLM to perform answer judging, response critiquing, prejudge generation, and thought completion. Furthermore, we develop a two-phase training mechanism with supervised fine-tuning (SFT) and reinforcement learning (RL) to further enhance the reasoning capabilities of LLMs. Experimental results from competition-level complex reasoning demonstrate that our method can teach the model to prejudge before thinking and significantly enhance the reasoning ability of LLMs. Code and data is released at https://github.com/wjn1996/Prejudge-Before-Think.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13500v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jianing Wang, Jin Jiang, Yang Liu, Mengdi Zhang, Xunliang Cai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoT-RAG: Integrating Chain of Thought and Retrieval-Augmented Generation to Enhance Reasoning in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13534</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13534v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: While chain-of-thought (CoT) reasoning improves the performance of large language models (LLMs) in complex tasks, it still has two main challenges: the low reliability of relying solely on LLMs to generate reasoning chains and the interference of natural language reasoning chains on the inference logic of LLMs. To address these issues, we propose CoT-RAG, a novel reasoning framework with three key designs: (i) Knowledge Graph-driven CoT Generation, featuring knowledge graphs to modulate reasoning chain generation of LLMs, thereby enhancing reasoning credibility; (ii) Learnable Knowledge Case-aware RAG, which incorporates retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) into knowledge graphs to retrieve relevant sub-cases and sub-descriptions, providing LLMs with learnable information; (iii) Pseudo-Program Prompting Execution, which encourages LLMs to execute reasoning tasks in pseudo-programs with greater logical rigor. We conduct a comprehensive evaluation on nine public datasets, covering three reasoning problems. Compared with the-state-of-the-art methods, CoT-RAG exhibits a significant accuracy improvement, ranging from 4.0% to 23.0%. Furthermore, testing on four domain-specific datasets, CoT-RAG shows remarkable accuracy and efficient execution, highlighting its strong practical applicability and scalability.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13534v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Feiyang Li, Peng Fang, Zhan Shi, Arijit Khan, Fang Wang, Dan Feng, Weihao Wang, Xin Zhang, Yongjian Cui</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Multilingual Sentiment Analysis with Explainability for Sinhala, English, and Code-Mixed Content</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13545</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13545v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Sentiment analysis is crucial for brand reputation management in the banking sector, where customer feedback spans English, Sinhala, Singlish, and code-mixed text. Existing models struggle with low-resource languages like Sinhala and lack interpretability for practical use. This research develops a hybrid aspect-based sentiment analysis framework that enhances multilingual capabilities with explainable outputs. Using cleaned banking customer reviews, we fine-tune XLM-RoBERTa for Sinhala and code-mixed text, integrate domain-specific lexicon correction, and employ BERT-base-uncased for English. The system classifies sentiment (positive, neutral, negative) with confidence scores, while SHAP and LIME improve interpretability by providing real-time sentiment explanations. Experimental results show that our approaches outperform traditional transformer-based classifiers, achieving 92.3 percent accuracy and an F1-score of 0.89 in English and 88.4 percent in Sinhala and code-mixed content. An explainability analysis reveals key sentiment drivers, improving trust and transparency. A user-friendly interface delivers aspect-wise sentiment insights, ensuring accessibility for businesses. This research contributes to robust, transparent sentiment analysis for financial applications by bridging gaps in multilingual, low-resource NLP and explainability.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13545v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Azmarah Rizvi, Navojith Thamindu, A. M. N. H. Adhikari, W. P. U. Senevirathna, Dharshana Kasthurirathna, Lakmini Abeywardhana</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DETAM: Defending LLMs Against Jailbreak Attacks via Targeted Attention Modification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13562</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13562v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: With the widespread adoption of Large Language Models (LLMs), jailbreak attacks have become an increasingly pressing safety concern. While safety-aligned LLMs can effectively defend against normal harmful queries, they remain vulnerable to such attacks. Existing defense methods primarily rely on fine-tuning or input modification, which often suffer from limited generalization and reduced utility. To address this, we introduce DETAM, a finetuning-free defense approach that improves the defensive capabilities against jailbreak attacks of LLMs via targeted attention modification. Specifically, we analyze the differences in attention scores between successful and unsuccessful defenses to identify the attention heads sensitive to jailbreak attacks. During inference, we reallocate attention to emphasize the user's core intention, minimizing interference from attack tokens. Our experimental results demonstrate that DETAM outperforms various baselines in jailbreak defense and exhibits robust generalization across different attacks and models, maintaining its effectiveness even on in-the-wild jailbreak data. Furthermore, in evaluating the model's utility, we incorporated over-defense datasets, which further validate the superior performance of our approach. The code will be released immediately upon acceptance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13562v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yu Li, Han Jiang, Zhihua Wei</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Generalization in Intent Detection: GRPO with Reward-Based Curriculum Sampling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13592</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13592v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Intent detection, a critical component in task-oriented dialogue (TOD) systems, faces significant challenges in adapting to the rapid influx of integrable tools with complex interrelationships. Existing approaches, such as zero-shot reformulations and LLM-based dynamic recognition, struggle with performance degradation when encountering unseen intents, leading to erroneous task routing. To enhance the model's generalization performance on unseen tasks, we employ Reinforcement Learning (RL) combined with a Reward-based Curriculum Sampling (RCS) during Group Relative Policy Optimization (GRPO) training in intent detection tasks. Experiments demonstrate that RL-trained models substantially outperform supervised fine-tuning (SFT) baselines in generalization. Besides, the introduction of the RCS, significantly bolsters the effectiveness of RL in intent detection by focusing the model on challenging cases during training. Moreover, incorporating Chain-of-Thought (COT) processes in RL notably improves generalization in complex intent detection tasks, underscoring the importance of thought in challenging scenarios. This work advances the generalization of intent detection tasks, offering practical insights for deploying adaptable dialogue systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13592v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zihao Feng, Xiaoxue Wang, Ziwei Bai, Donghang Su, Bowen Wu, Qun Yu, Baoxun Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continual Pre-Training is (not) What You Need in Domain Adaption</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13603</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13603v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The recent advances in Legal Large Language Models (LLMs) have transformed the landscape of legal research and practice by automating tasks, enhancing research precision, and supporting complex decision-making processes. However, effectively adapting LLMs to the legal domain remains challenging due to the complexity of legal reasoning, the need for precise interpretation of specialized language, and the potential for hallucinations. This paper examines the efficacy of Domain-Adaptive Continual Pre-Training (DACP) in improving the legal reasoning capabilities of LLMs. Through a series of experiments on legal reasoning tasks within the Taiwanese legal framework, we demonstrate that while DACP enhances domain-specific knowledge, it does not uniformly improve performance across all legal tasks. We discuss the trade-offs involved in DACP, particularly its impact on model generalization and performance in prompt-based tasks, and propose directions for future research to optimize domain adaptation strategies in legal AI.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13603v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Pin-Er Chen, Da-Chen Lian, Shu-Kai Hsieh, Sieh-Chuen Huang, Hsuan-Lei Shao, Jun-Wei Chiu, Yang-Hsien Lin, Zih-Ching Chen,  Cheng-Kuang, Eddie TC Huang, Simon See</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long-context Non-factoid Question Answering in Indic Languages</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13615</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13615v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Question Answering (QA) tasks, which involve extracting answers from a given context, are relatively straightforward for modern Large Language Models (LLMs) when the context is short. However, long contexts pose challenges due to the quadratic complexity of the self-attention mechanism. This challenge is compounded in Indic languages, which are often low-resource. This study explores context-shortening techniques, including Open Information Extraction (OIE), coreference resolution, Answer Paragraph Selection (APS), and their combinations, to improve QA performance. Compared to the baseline of unshortened (long) contexts, our experiments on four Indic languages (Hindi, Tamil, Telugu, and Urdu) demonstrate that context-shortening techniques yield an average improvement of 4\% in semantic scores and 47\% in token-level scores when evaluated on three popular LLMs without fine-tuning. Furthermore, with fine-tuning, we achieve an average increase of 2\% in both semantic and token-level scores. Additionally, context-shortening reduces computational overhead. Explainability techniques like LIME and SHAP reveal that when the APS model confidently identifies the paragraph containing the answer, nearly all tokens within the selected text receive high relevance scores. However, the study also highlights the limitations of LLM-based QA systems in addressing non-factoid questions, particularly those requiring reasoning or debate. Moreover, verbalizing OIE-generated triples does not enhance system performance. These findings emphasize the potential of context-shortening techniques to improve the efficiency and effectiveness of LLM-based QA systems, especially for low-resource languages. The source code and resources are available at https://github.com/ritwikmishra/IndicGenQA.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13615v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ritwik Mishra, Rajiv Ratn Shah, Ponnurangam Kumaraguru</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thought Manipulation: External Thought Can Be Efficient for Large Reasoning Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13626</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13626v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent advancements in large reasoning models (LRMs) have demonstrated the effectiveness of scaling test-time computation to enhance reasoning capabilities in multiple tasks. However, LRMs typically suffer from "overthinking" problems, where models generate significantly redundant reasoning steps while bringing limited performance gains. Existing work relies on fine-tuning to mitigate overthinking, which requires additional data, unconventional training setups, risky safety misalignment, and poor generalization.
  Through empirical analysis, we reveal an important characteristic of LRM behaviors that placing external CoTs generated by smaller models between the thinking token ($\texttt{&lt;think&gt;}$ and $\texttt{&lt;/think&gt;)}$ can effectively manipulate the model to generate fewer thoughts. Building on these insights, we propose a simple yet efficient pipeline, ThoughtMani, to enable LRMs to bypass unnecessary intermediate steps and reduce computational costs significantly. We conduct extensive experiments to validate the utility and efficiency of ThoughtMani. For instance, when applied to QwQ-32B on the LiveBench/Code dataset, ThoughtMani keeps the original performance and reduces output token counts by approximately 30%, with little overhead from the CoT generator. Furthermore, we find that ThoughtMani enhances safety alignment by an average of 10%. Since model vendors typically serve models of different sizes simultaneously, ThoughtMani provides an effective way to construct more efficient and accessible LRMs for real-world applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13626v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yule Liu, Jingyi Zheng, Zhen Sun, Zifan Peng, Wenhan Dong, Zeyang Sha, Shiwen Cui, Weiqiang Wang, Xinlei He</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Divergent LLM Adoption and Heterogeneous Convergence Paths in Research Writing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13629</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13629v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs), such as ChatGPT, are reshaping content creation and academic writing. This study investigates the impact of AI-assisted generative revisions on research manuscripts, focusing on heterogeneous adoption patterns and their influence on writing convergence. Leveraging a dataset of over 627,000 academic papers from arXiv, we develop a novel classification framework by fine-tuning prompt- and discipline-specific large language models to detect the style of ChatGPT-revised texts. Our findings reveal substantial disparities in LLM adoption across academic disciplines, gender, native language status, and career stage, alongside a rapid evolution in scholarly writing styles. Moreover, LLM usage enhances clarity, conciseness, and adherence to formal writing conventions, with improvements varying by revision type. Finally, a difference-in-differences analysis shows that while LLMs drive convergence in academic writing, early adopters, male researchers, non-native speakers, and junior scholars exhibit the most pronounced stylistic shifts, aligning their writing more closely with that of established researchers.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13629v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>econ.GN</category>
      <category>q-fin.EC</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Cong William Lin, Wu Zhu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remedy: Learning Machine Translation Evaluation from Human Preferences with Reward Modeling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13630</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13630v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: A key challenge in MT evaluation is the inherent noise and inconsistency of human ratings. Regression-based neural metrics struggle with this noise, while prompting LLMs shows promise at system-level evaluation but performs poorly at segment level. In this work, we propose ReMedy, a novel MT metric framework that reformulates translation evaluation as a reward modeling task. Instead of regressing on imperfect human ratings directly, ReMedy learns relative translation quality using pairwise preference data, resulting in a more reliable evaluation. In extensive experiments across WMT22-24 shared tasks (39 language pairs, 111 MT systems), ReMedy achieves state-of-the-art performance at both segment- and system-level evaluation. Specifically, ReMedy-9B surpasses larger WMT winners and massive closed LLMs such as MetricX-13B, XCOMET-Ensemble, GEMBA-GPT-4, PaLM-540B, and finetuned PaLM2. Further analyses demonstrate that ReMedy delivers superior capability in detecting translation errors and evaluating low-quality translations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13630v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shaomu Tan, Christof Monz</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simulating Before Planning: Constructing Intrinsic User World Model for User-Tailored Dialogue Policy Planning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13643</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13643v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent advancements in dialogue policy planning have emphasized optimizing system agent policies to achieve predefined goals, focusing on strategy design, trajectory acquisition, and efficient training paradigms. However, these approaches often overlook the critical role of user characteristics, which are essential in real-world scenarios like conversational search and recommendation, where interactions must adapt to individual user traits such as personality, preferences, and goals. To address this gap, we first conduct a comprehensive study utilizing task-specific user personas to systematically assess dialogue policy planning under diverse user behaviors. By leveraging realistic user profiles for different tasks, our study reveals significant limitations in existing approaches, highlighting the need for user-tailored dialogue policy planning. Building on this foundation, we present the User-Tailored Dialogue Policy Planning (UDP) framework, which incorporates an Intrinsic User World Model to model user traits and feedback. UDP operates in three stages: (1) User Persona Portraying, using a diffusion model to dynamically infer user profiles; (2) User Feedback Anticipating, leveraging a Brownian Bridge-inspired anticipator to predict user reactions; and (3) User-Tailored Policy Planning, integrating these insights to optimize response strategies. To ensure robust performance, we further propose an active learning approach that prioritizes challenging user personas during training. Comprehensive experiments on benchmarks, including collaborative and non-collaborative settings, demonstrate the effectiveness of UDP in learning user-specific dialogue strategies. Results validate the protocol's utility and highlight UDP's robustness, adaptability, and potential to advance user-centric dialogue systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13643v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tao He, Lizi Liao, Ming Liu, Bing Qin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Word Embedding Techniques for Classification of Star Ratings</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13653</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13653v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Telecom services are at the core of today's societies' everyday needs. The availability of numerous online forums and discussion platforms enables telecom providers to improve their services by exploring the views of their customers to learn about common issues that the customers face. Natural Language Processing (NLP) tools can be used to process the free text collected.
  One way of working with such data is to represent text as numerical vectors using one of many word embedding models based on neural networks. This research uses a novel dataset of telecom customers' reviews to perform an extensive study showing how different word embedding algorithms can affect the text classification process. Several state-of-the-art word embedding techniques are considered, including BERT, Word2Vec and Doc2Vec, coupled with several classification algorithms. The important issue of feature engineering and dimensionality reduction is addressed and several PCA-based approaches are explored. Moreover, the energy consumption used by the different word embeddings is investigated. The findings show that some word embedding models can lead to consistently better text classifiers in terms of precision, recall and F1-Score. In particular, for the more challenging classification tasks, BERT combined with PCA stood out with the highest performance metrics. Moreover, our proposed PCA approach of combining word vectors using the first principal component shows clear advantages in performance over the traditional approach of taking the average.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13653v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>stat.AP</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hesham Abdelmotaleb, Craig McNeile, Malgorzata Wojtys</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Type Context-Aware Conversational Recommender Systems via Mixture-of-Experts</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13655</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13655v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Conversational recommender systems enable natural language conversations and thus lead to a more engaging and effective recommendation scenario. As the conversations for recommender systems usually contain limited contextual information, many existing conversational recommender systems incorporate external sources to enrich the contextual information. However, how to combine different types of contextual information is still a challenge. In this paper, we propose a multi-type context-aware conversational recommender system, called MCCRS, effectively fusing multi-type contextual information via mixture-of-experts to improve conversational recommender systems. MCCRS incorporates both structured information and unstructured information, including the structured knowledge graph, unstructured conversation history, and unstructured item reviews. It consists of several experts, with each expert specialized in a particular domain (i.e., one specific contextual information). Multiple experts are then coordinated by a ChairBot to generate the final results. Our proposed MCCRS model takes advantage of different contextual information and the specialization of different experts followed by a ChairBot breaks the model bottleneck on a single contextual information. Experimental results demonstrate that our proposed MCCRS method achieves significantly higher performance compared to existing baselines.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13655v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jie Zou, Cheng Lin, Weikang Guo, Zheng Wang, Jiwei Wei, Yang Yang, Hengtao Shen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting Uncertainty Quantification Evaluation in Language Models: Spurious Interactions with Response Length Bias Results</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13677</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13677v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Uncertainty Quantification (UQ) in Language Models (LMs) is crucial for improving their safety and reliability. Evaluations often use performance metrics like AUROC to assess how well UQ methods (e.g., negative sequence probabilities) correlate with task correctness functions (e.g., ROUGE-L). In this paper, we show that commonly used correctness functions bias UQ evaluations by inflating the performance of certain UQ methods. We evaluate 7 correctness functions -- from lexical-based and embedding-based metrics to LLM-as-a-judge approaches -- across 4 datasets x 4 models x 6 UQ methods. Our analysis reveals that length biases in the errors of these correctness functions distort UQ assessments by interacting with length biases in UQ methods. We identify LLM-as-a-judge approaches as among the least length-biased choices and hence a potential solution to mitigate these biases.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13677v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Andrea Santilli, Adam Golinski, Michael Kirchhof, Federico Danieli, Arno Blaas, Miao Xiong, Luca Zappella, Sinead Williamson</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep literature reviews: an application of fine-tuned language models to migration research</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13685</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13685v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper presents a hybrid framework for literature reviews that augments traditional bibliometric methods with large language models (LLMs). By fine-tuning open-source LLMs, our approach enables scalable extraction of qualitative insights from large volumes of research content, enhancing both the breadth and depth of knowledge synthesis. To improve annotation efficiency and consistency, we introduce an error-focused validation process in which LLMs generate initial labels and human reviewers correct misclassifications. Applying this framework to over 20000 scientific articles about human migration, we demonstrate that a domain-adapted LLM can serve as a "specialist" model - capable of accurately selecting relevant studies, detecting emerging trends, and identifying critical research gaps. Notably, the LLM-assisted review reveals a growing scholarly interest in climate-induced migration. However, existing literature disproportionately centers on a narrow set of environmental hazards (e.g., floods, droughts, sea-level rise, and land degradation), while overlooking others that more directly affect human health and well-being, such as air and water pollution or infectious diseases. This imbalance highlights the need for more comprehensive research that goes beyond physical environmental changes to examine their ecological and societal consequences, particularly in shaping migration as an adaptive response. Overall, our proposed framework demonstrates the potential of fine-tuned LLMs to conduct more efficient, consistent, and insightful literature reviews across disciplines, ultimately accelerating knowledge synthesis and scientific discovery.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13685v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>stat.AP</category>
      <category>stat.CO</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Stefano M. Iacus, Haodong Qi, Jiyoung Han</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlled Territory and Conflict Tracking (CONTACT): (Geo-)Mapping Occupied Territory from Open Source Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13730</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13730v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Open-source intelligence provides a stream of unstructured textual data that can inform assessments of territorial control. We present CONTACT, a framework for territorial control prediction using large language models (LLMs) and minimal supervision. We evaluate two approaches: SetFit, an embedding-based few-shot classifier, and a prompt tuning method applied to BLOOMZ-560m, a multilingual generative LLM. Our model is trained on a small hand-labeled dataset of news articles covering ISIS activity in Syria and Iraq, using prompt-conditioned extraction of control-relevant signals such as military operations, casualties, and location references. We show that the BLOOMZ-based model outperforms the SetFit baseline, and that prompt-based supervision improves generalization in low-resource settings. CONTACT demonstrates that LLMs fine-tuned using few-shot methods can reduce annotation burdens and support structured inference from open-ended OSINT streams. Our code is available at https://github.com/PaulKMandal/CONTACT/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13730v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Paul K. Mandal, Cole Leo, Connor Hurley</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BadApex: Backdoor Attack Based on Adaptive Optimization Mechanism of Black-box Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13775</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13775v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Previous insertion-based and paraphrase-based backdoors have achieved great success in attack efficacy, but they ignore the text quality and semantic consistency between poisoned and clean texts. Although recent studies introduce LLMs to generate poisoned texts and improve the stealthiness, semantic consistency, and text quality, their hand-crafted prompts rely on expert experiences, facing significant challenges in prompt adaptability and attack performance after defenses. In this paper, we propose a novel backdoor attack based on adaptive optimization mechanism of black-box large language models (BadApex), which leverages a black-box LLM to generate poisoned text through a refined prompt. Specifically, an Adaptive Optimization Mechanism is designed to refine an initial prompt iteratively using the generation and modification agents. The generation agent generates the poisoned text based on the initial prompt. Then the modification agent evaluates the quality of the poisoned text and refines a new prompt. After several iterations of the above process, the refined prompt is used to generate poisoned texts through LLMs. We conduct extensive experiments on three dataset with six backdoor attacks and two defenses. Extensive experimental results demonstrate that BadApex significantly outperforms state-of-the-art attacks. It improves prompt adaptability, semantic consistency, and text quality. Furthermore, when two defense methods are applied, the average attack success rate (ASR) still up to 96.75%.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13775v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhengxian Wu, Juan Wen, Wanli Peng, Ziwei Zhang, Yinghan Zhou, Yiming Xue</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing LLMs' Knowledge Boundary Cognition Across Languages Through the Lens of Internal Representations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13816</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13816v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: While understanding the knowledge boundaries of LLMs is crucial to prevent hallucination, research on knowledge boundaries of LLMs has predominantly focused on English. In this work, we present the first study to analyze how LLMs recognize knowledge boundaries across different languages by probing their internal representations when processing known and unknown questions in multiple languages. Our empirical studies reveal three key findings: 1) LLMs' perceptions of knowledge boundaries are encoded in the middle to middle-upper layers across different languages. 2) Language differences in knowledge boundary perception follow a linear structure, which motivates our proposal of a training-free alignment method that effectively transfers knowledge boundary perception ability across languages, thereby helping reduce hallucination risk in low-resource languages; 3) Fine-tuning on bilingual question pair translation further enhances LLMs' recognition of knowledge boundaries across languages. Given the absence of standard testbeds for cross-lingual knowledge boundary analysis, we construct a multilingual evaluation suite comprising three representative types of knowledge boundary data. Our code and datasets are publicly available at https://github.com/DAMO-NLP-SG/LLM-Multilingual-Knowledge-Boundaries.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13816v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chenghao Xiao, Hou Pong Chan, Hao Zhang, Mahani Aljunied, Lidong Bing, Noura Al Moubayed, Yu Rong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feature Alignment and Representation Transfer in Knowledge Distillation for Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13825</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13825v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Knowledge distillation (KD) is a technique for transferring knowledge from complex teacher models to simpler student models, significantly enhancing model efficiency and accuracy. It has demonstrated substantial advancements in various applications including image classification, object detection, language modeling, text classification, and sentiment analysis. Recent innovations in KD methods, such as attention-based approaches, block-wise logit distillation, and decoupling distillation, have notably improved student model performance. These techniques focus on stimulus complexity, attention mechanisms, and global information capture to optimize knowledge transfer. In addition, KD has proven effective in compressing large language models while preserving accuracy, reducing computational overhead, and improving inference speed. This survey synthesizes the latest literature, highlighting key findings, contributions, and future directions in knowledge distillation to provide insights for researchers and practitioners on its evolving role in artificial intelligence and machine learning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13825v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junjie Yang, Junhao Song, Xudong Han, Ziqian Bi, Tianyang Wang, Chia Xin Liang, Xinyuan Song, Yichao Zhang, Qian Niu, Benji Peng, Keyu Chen, Ming Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generative AI Act II: Test Time Scaling Drives Cognition Engineering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13828</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13828v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The first generation of Large Language Models - what might be called "Act I" of generative AI (2020-2023) - achieved remarkable success through massive parameter and data scaling, yet exhibited fundamental limitations in knowledge latency, shallow reasoning, and constrained cognitive processes. During this era, prompt engineering emerged as our primary interface with AI, enabling dialogue-level communication through natural language. We now witness the emergence of "Act II" (2024-present), where models are transitioning from knowledge-retrieval systems (in latent space) to thought-construction engines through test-time scaling techniques. This new paradigm establishes a mind-level connection with AI through language-based thoughts. In this paper, we clarify the conceptual foundations of cognition engineering and explain why this moment is critical for its development. We systematically break down these advanced approaches through comprehensive tutorials and optimized implementations, democratizing access to cognition engineering and enabling every practitioner to participate in AI's second act. We provide a regularly updated collection of papers on test-time scaling in the GitHub Repository: https://github.com/GAIR-NLP/cognition-engineering</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13828v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shijie Xia, Yiwei Qin, Xuefeng Li, Yan Ma, Run-Ze Fan, Steffi Chern, Haoyang Zou, Fan Zhou, Xiangkun Hu, Jiahe Jin, Yanheng He, Yixin Ye, Yixiu Liu, Pengfei Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Science Hierarchography: Hierarchical Organization of Science Literature</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13834</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13834v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Scientific knowledge is growing rapidly, making it challenging to track progress and high-level conceptual links across broad disciplines. While existing tools like citation networks and search engines make it easy to access a few related papers, they fundamentally lack the flexible abstraction needed to represent the density of activity in various scientific subfields. We motivate SCIENCE HIERARCHOGRAPHY, the goal of organizing scientific literature into a high-quality hierarchical structure that allows for the categorization of scientific work across varying levels of abstraction, from very broad fields to very specific studies. Such a representation can provide insights into which fields are well-explored and which are under-explored. To achieve the goals of SCIENCE HIERARCHOGRAPHY, we develop a range of algorithms. Our primary approach combines fast embedding-based clustering with LLM-based prompting to balance the computational efficiency of embedding methods with the semantic precision offered by LLM prompting. We demonstrate that this approach offers the best trade-off between quality and speed compared to methods that heavily rely on LLM prompting, such as iterative tree construction with LLMs. To better reflect the interdisciplinary and multifaceted nature of research papers, our hierarchy captures multiple dimensions of categorization beyond simple topic labels. We evaluate the utility of our framework by assessing how effectively an LLM-based agent can locate target papers using the hierarchy. Results show that this structured approach enhances interpretability, supports trend discovery, and offers an alternative pathway for exploring scientific literature beyond traditional search methods. Code, data and demo: $\href{https://github.com/JHU-CLSP/science-hierarchography}{https://github.com/JHU-CLSP/science-hierarchography}$</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13834v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Muhan Gao, Jash Shah, Weiqi Wang, Daniel Khashabi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MIG: Automatic Data Selection for Instruction Tuning by Maximizing Information Gain in Semantic Space</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13835</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13835v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Data quality and diversity are key to the construction of effective instruction-tuning datasets. %
With the increasing availability of open-source instruction-tuning datasets, it is advantageous to automatically select high-quality and diverse subsets from a vast amount of data. %
Existing methods typically prioritize instance quality and use heuristic rules to maintain diversity. %
However, this absence of a comprehensive view of the entire collection often leads to suboptimal results. %
Moreover, heuristic rules generally focus on distance or clustering within the embedding space, which fails to accurately capture the intent of complex instructions in the semantic space. %
To bridge this gap, we propose a unified method for quantifying the information content of datasets. This method models the semantic space by constructing a label graph and quantifies diversity based on the distribution of information within the graph. %
Based on such a measurement, we further introduce an efficient sampling method that selects data samples iteratively to \textbf{M}aximize the \textbf{I}nformation \textbf{G}ain (MIG) in semantic space. %
Experiments on various datasets and base models demonstrate that MIG consistently outperforms state-of-the-art methods. %
Notably, the model fine-tuned with 5\% Tulu3 data sampled by MIG achieves comparable performance to the official SFT model trained on the full dataset, with improvements of +5.73\% on AlpacaEval and +6.89\% on Wildbench.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13835v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yicheng Chen, Yining Li, Kai Hu, Zerun Ma, Haochen Ye, Kai Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Quantum LLM: Modeling Semantic Spaces with Quantum Principles</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13202</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13202v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In the previous article, we presented a quantum-inspired framework for modeling semantic representation and processing in Large Language Models (LLMs), drawing upon mathematical tools and conceptual analogies from quantum mechanics to offer a new perspective on these complex systems. In this paper, we clarify the core assumptions of this model, providing a detailed exposition of six key principles that govern semantic representation, interaction, and dynamics within LLMs. The goal is to justify that a quantum-inspired framework is a valid approach to studying semantic spaces. This framework offers valuable insights into their information processing and response generation, and we further discuss the potential of leveraging quantum computing to develop significantly more powerful and efficient LLMs based on these principles.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13202v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>quant-ph</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Timo Aukusti Laine</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>X-Teaming: Multi-Turn Jailbreaks and Defenses with Adaptive Multi-Agents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13203</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13203v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Multi-turn interactions with language models (LMs) pose critical safety risks, as harmful intent can be strategically spread across exchanges. Yet, the vast majority of prior work has focused on single-turn safety, while adaptability and diversity remain among the key challenges of multi-turn red-teaming. To address these challenges, we present X-Teaming, a scalable framework that systematically explores how seemingly harmless interactions escalate into harmful outcomes and generates corresponding attack scenarios. X-Teaming employs collaborative agents for planning, attack optimization, and verification, achieving state-of-the-art multi-turn jailbreak effectiveness and diversity with success rates up to 98.1% across representative leading open-weight and closed-source models. In particular, X-Teaming achieves a 96.2% attack success rate against the latest Claude 3.7 Sonnet model, which has been considered nearly immune to single-turn attacks. Building on X-Teaming, we introduce XGuard-Train, an open-source multi-turn safety training dataset that is 20x larger than the previous best resource, comprising 30K interactive jailbreaks, designed to enable robust multi-turn safety alignment for LMs. Our work offers essential tools and insights for mitigating sophisticated conversational attacks, advancing the multi-turn safety of LMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13203v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Salman Rahman, Liwei Jiang, James Shiffer, Genglin Liu, Sheriff Issaka, Md Rizwan Parvez, Hamid Palangi, Kai-Wei Chang, Yejin Choi, Saadia Gabriel</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interpersonal Theory of Suicide as a Lens to Examine Suicidal Ideation in Online Spaces</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13277</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13277v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Suicide is a critical global public health issue, with millions experiencing suicidal ideation (SI) each year. Online spaces enable individuals to express SI and seek peer support. While prior research has revealed the potential of detecting SI using machine learning and natural language analysis, a key limitation is the lack of a theoretical framework to understand the underlying factors affecting high-risk suicidal intent. To bridge this gap, we adopted the Interpersonal Theory of Suicide (IPTS) as an analytic lens to analyze 59,607 posts from Reddit's r/SuicideWatch, categorizing them into SI dimensions (Loneliness, Lack of Reciprocal Love, Self Hate, and Liability) and risk factors (Thwarted Belongingness, Perceived Burdensomeness, and Acquired Capability of Suicide). We found that high-risk SI posts express planning and attempts, methods and tools, and weaknesses and pain. In addition, we also examined the language of supportive responses through psycholinguistic and content analyses to find that individuals respond differently to different stages of Suicidal Ideation (SI) posts. Finally, we explored the role of AI chatbots in providing effective supportive responses to suicidal ideation posts. We found that although AI improved structural coherence, expert evaluations highlight persistent shortcomings in providing dynamic, personalized, and deeply empathetic support. These findings underscore the need for careful reflection and deeper understanding in both the development and consideration of AI-driven interventions for effective mental health support.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13277v1</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Soorya Ram Shimgekar, Violeta J. Rodriguez, Paul A. Bloom, Dong Whi Yoo, Koustuv Saha</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acoustic to Articulatory Inversion of Speech; Data Driven Approaches, Challenges, Applications, and Future Scope</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13308</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13308v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This review is focused on the data-driven approaches applied in different applications of Acoustic-to-Articulatory Inversion (AAI) of speech. This review paper considered the relevant works published in the last ten years (2011-2021). The selection criteria includes (a) type of AAI - Speaker Dependent and Speaker Independent AAI, (b) objectives of the work - Articulatory approximation, Articulatory Feature space selection and Automatic Speech Recognition (ASR), explore the correlation between acoustic and articulatory features, and framework for Computer-assisted language training, (c) Corpus - Simultaneously recorded speech (wav) and medical imaging models such as ElectroMagnetic Articulography (EMA), Electropalatography (EPG), Laryngography, Electroglottography (EGG), X-ray Cineradiography, Ultrasound, and real-time Magnetic Resonance Imaging (rtMRI), (d) Methods or models - recent works are considered, and therefore all the works are based on machine learning, (e) Evaluation - as AAI is a non-linear regression problem, the performance evaluation is mostly done by Correlation Coefficient (CC), Root Mean Square Error (RMSE), and also considered Mean Square Error (MSE), and Mean Format Error (MFE). The practical application of the AAI model can provide a better and user-friendly interpretable image feedback system of articulatory positions, especially tongue movement. Such trajectory feedback system can be used to provide phonetic, language, and speech therapy for pathological subjects.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13308v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Leena G Pillai, D. Muhammad Noorul Mubarak</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cost-of-Pass: An Economic Framework for Evaluating Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13359</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13359v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The widespread adoption of AI systems in the economy hinges on their ability to generate economic value that outweighs their inference costs. Evaluating this tradeoff requires metrics that account for both performance and costs. We propose a framework grounded in production theory for evaluating language models by combining accuracy and inference cost. We introduce "cost-of-pass", the expected monetary cost of generating a correct solution. We then define the "frontier cost-of-pass" as the minimum cost-of-pass achievable across available models or the "human-expert, using the approximate cost of hiring an expert. Our analysis reveals distinct economic insights. First, lightweight models are most cost-effective for basic quantitative tasks, large models for knowledge-intensive ones, and reasoning models for complex quantitative problems, despite higher per-token costs. Second, tracking this frontier cost-of-pass over the past year reveals significant progress, particularly for complex quantitative tasks where the cost has roughly halved every few months. Third, to trace key innovations driving this progress, we examine counterfactual frontiers: estimates of cost-efficiency without specific model classes. We find that innovations in lightweight, large, and reasoning models have been essential for pushing the frontier in basic quantitative, knowledge-intensive, and complex quantitative tasks, respectively. Finally, we assess the cost-reductions afforded by common inference-time techniques like majority voting and self-refinement, finding that their marginal accuracy gains rarely justify their costs. Our findings underscore that complementary model-level innovations are the primary drivers of cost-efficiency, and our economic framework provides a principled tool for measuring this progress and guiding deployment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13359v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mehmet Hamza Erol, Batu El, Mirac Suzgun, Mert Yuksekgonul, James Zou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A mean teacher algorithm for unlearning of language models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13388</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13388v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: One of the goals of language model unlearning is to reduce memorization of selected text instances while retaining the model's general abilities. Despite various proposed methods, reducing memorization of large datasets without noticeable degradation in model utility remains challenging. In this paper, we investigate the mean teacher algorithm (Tarvainen &amp; Valpola, 2017), a simple proximal optimization method from continual learning literature that gradually modifies the teacher model. We show that the mean teacher can approximate a trajectory of a slow natural gradient descent (NGD), which inherently seeks low-curvature updates that are less likely to degrade the model utility. While slow NGD can suffer from vanishing gradients, we introduce a new unlearning loss called "negative log-unlikelihood" (NLUL) that avoids this problem. We show that the combination of mean teacher and NLUL improves some metrics on the MUSE benchmarks (Shi et al., 2024).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13388v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yegor Klochkov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LangCoop: Collaborative Driving with Language</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13406</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13406v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Multi-agent collaboration holds great promise for enhancing the safety, reliability, and mobility of autonomous driving systems by enabling information sharing among multiple connected agents. However, existing multi-agent communication approaches are hindered by limitations of existing communication media, including high bandwidth demands, agent heterogeneity, and information loss. To address these challenges, we introduce LangCoop, a new paradigm for collaborative autonomous driving that leverages natural language as a compact yet expressive medium for inter-agent communication. LangCoop features two key innovations: Mixture Model Modular Chain-of-thought (M$^3$CoT) for structured zero-shot vision-language reasoning and Natural Language Information Packaging (LangPack) for efficiently packaging information into concise, language-based messages. Through extensive experiments conducted in the CARLA simulations, we demonstrate that LangCoop achieves a remarkable 96\% reduction in communication bandwidth (&lt; 2KB per message) compared to image-based communication, while maintaining competitive driving performance in the closed-loop evaluation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13406v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>CVPRW 2025</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Xiangbo Gao, Yuheng Wu, Rujia Wang, Chenxi Liu, Yang Zhou, Zhengzhong Tu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STAMP Your Content: Proving Dataset Membership via Watermarked Rephrasings</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13416</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13416v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Given how large parts of publicly available text are crawled to pretrain large language models (LLMs), data creators increasingly worry about the inclusion of their proprietary data for model training without attribution or licensing. Their concerns are also shared by benchmark curators whose test-sets might be compromised. In this paper, we present STAMP, a framework for detecting dataset membership-i.e., determining the inclusion of a dataset in the pretraining corpora of LLMs. Given an original piece of content, our proposal involves first generating multiple rephrases, each embedding a watermark with a unique secret key. One version is to be released publicly, while others are to be kept private. Subsequently, creators can compare model likelihoods between public and private versions using paired statistical tests to prove membership. We show that our framework can successfully detect contamination across four benchmarks which appear only once in the training data and constitute less than 0.001% of the total tokens, outperforming several contamination detection and dataset inference baselines. We verify that STAMP preserves both the semantic meaning and the utility of the original data in comparing different models. We apply STAMP to two real-world scenarios to confirm the inclusion of paper abstracts and blog articles in the pretraining corpora.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13416v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Saksham Rastogi, Pratyush Maini, Danish Pruthi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CodeVisionary: An Agent-based Framework for Evaluating Large Language Models in Code Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13472</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13472v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated strong capabilities in code generation, underscoring the critical need for rigorous and comprehensive evaluation. Existing evaluation approaches fall into three categories, including human-centered, metric-based, and LLM-based. Considering that human-centered approaches are labour-intensive and metric-based ones overly rely on reference answers, LLM-based approaches are gaining increasing attention due to their stronger contextual understanding capabilities and superior efficiency. However, the performance of LLM-based approaches remains limited due to: (1) lack of multisource domain knowledge, and (2) insufficient comprehension of complex code.
  To mitigate the limitations, we propose CodeVisionary, the first LLM-based agent framework for evaluating LLMs in code generation. CodeVisionary consists of two stages: (1) Multiscore knowledge analysis stage, which aims to gather multisource and comprehensive domain knowledge by formulating and executing a stepwise evaluation plan. (2) Negotiation-based scoring stage, which involves multiple judges engaging in discussions to better comprehend the complex code and reach a consensus on the evaluation score. Extensive experiments demonstrate that CodeVisionary achieves the best performance for evaluating LLMs in code generation, outperforming the best baseline methods with average improvements of 0.202, 0.139, and 0.117 in Pearson, Spearman, and Kendall-Tau coefficients, respectively. Besides, CodeVisionary provides detailed evaluation reports, which assist developers in identifying shortcomings and making improvements. The resources of CodeVisionary are available at https://anonymous.4open.science/r/CodeVisionary.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13472v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xinchen Wang, Pengfei Gao, Chao Peng, Ruida Hu, Cuiyun Gao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Locality-Aware Attention with Transformers for General Geometry PDEs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13480</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13480v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Neural operators have emerged as promising frameworks for learning mappings governed by partial differential equations (PDEs), serving as data-driven alternatives to traditional numerical methods. While methods such as the Fourier neural operator (FNO) have demonstrated notable performance, their reliance on uniform grids restricts their applicability to complex geometries and irregular meshes. Recently, Transformer-based neural operators with linear attention mechanisms have shown potential in overcoming these limitations for large-scale PDE simulations. However, these approaches predominantly emphasize global feature aggregation, often overlooking fine-scale dynamics and localized PDE behaviors essential for accurate solutions. To address these challenges, we propose the Locality-Aware Attention Transformer (LA2Former), which leverages K-nearest neighbors for dynamic patchifying and integrates global-local attention for enhanced PDE modeling. By combining linear attention for efficient global context encoding with pairwise attention for capturing intricate local interactions, LA2Former achieves an optimal balance between computational efficiency and predictive accuracy. Extensive evaluations across six benchmark datasets demonstrate that LA2Former improves predictive accuracy by over 50% relative to existing linear attention methods, while also outperforming full pairwise attention under optimal conditions. This work underscores the critical importance of localized feature learning in advancing Transformer-based neural operators for solving PDEs on complex and irregular domains.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13480v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Minsu Koh, Beom-Chul Park, Heejo Kong, Seong-Whan Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Q-FAKER: Query-free Hard Black-box Attack via Controlled Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13551</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13551v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Many adversarial attack approaches are proposed to verify the vulnerability of language models. However, they require numerous queries and the information on the target model. Even black-box attack methods also require the target model's output information. They are not applicable in real-world scenarios, as in hard black-box settings where the target model is closed and inaccessible. Even the recently proposed hard black-box attacks still require many queries and demand extremely high costs for training adversarial generators. To address these challenges, we propose Q-faker (Query-free Hard Black-box Attacker), a novel and efficient method that generates adversarial examples without accessing the target model. To avoid accessing the target model, we use a surrogate model instead. The surrogate model generates adversarial sentences for a target-agnostic attack. During this process, we leverage controlled generation techniques. We evaluate our proposed method on eight datasets. Experimental results demonstrate our method's effectiveness including high transferability and the high quality of the generated adversarial examples, and prove its practical in hard black-box settings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13551v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>CheolWon Na, YunSeok Choi, Jee-Hyong Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Potential for Large Language Models to Demonstrate Rational Probabilistic Beliefs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13644</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13644v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Advances in the general capabilities of large language models (LLMs) have led to their use for information retrieval, and as components in automated decision systems. A faithful representation of probabilistic reasoning in these models may be essential to ensure trustworthy, explainable and effective performance in these tasks. Despite previous work suggesting that LLMs can perform complex reasoning and well-calibrated uncertainty quantification, we find that current versions of this class of model lack the ability to provide rational and coherent representations of probabilistic beliefs. To demonstrate this, we introduce a novel dataset of claims with indeterminate truth values and apply a number of well-established techniques for uncertainty quantification to measure the ability of LLM's to adhere to fundamental properties of probabilistic reasoning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13644v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gabriel Freedman, Francesca Toni</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Language Models Will Change The Way Children Think About Technology And Impact Every Interaction Paradigm</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13667</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13667v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This paper presents a hopeful perspective on the potentially dramatic impacts of Large Language Models on how we children learn and how they will expect to interact with technology. We review the effects of LLMs on education so far, and make the case that these effects are minor compared to the upcoming changes that are occurring. We present a small scenario and self-ethnographic study demonstrating the effects of these changes, and define five significant considerations that interactive systems designers will have to accommodate in the future.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13667v1</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Russell Beale</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenDeception: Benchmarking and Investigating AI Deceptive Behaviors via Open-ended Interaction Simulation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13707</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13707v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: As the general capabilities of large language models (LLMs) improve and agent applications become more widespread, the underlying deception risks urgently require systematic evaluation and effective oversight. Unlike existing evaluation which uses simulated games or presents limited choices, we introduce OpenDeception, a novel deception evaluation framework with an open-ended scenario dataset. OpenDeception jointly evaluates both the deception intention and capabilities of LLM-based agents by inspecting their internal reasoning process. Specifically, we construct five types of common use cases where LLMs intensively interact with the user, each consisting of ten diverse, concrete scenarios from the real world. To avoid ethical concerns and costs of high-risk deceptive interactions with human testers, we propose to simulate the multi-turn dialogue via agent simulation. Extensive evaluation of eleven mainstream LLMs on OpenDeception highlights the urgent need to address deception risks and security concerns in LLM-based agents: the deception intention ratio across the models exceeds 80%, while the deception success rate surpasses 50%. Furthermore, we observe that LLMs with stronger capabilities do exhibit a higher risk of deception, which calls for more alignment efforts on inhibiting deceptive behaviors.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13707v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yichen Wu, Xudong Pan, Geng Hong, Min Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning to Attribute with Attention</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13752</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13752v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Given a sequence of tokens generated by a language model, we may want to identify the preceding tokens that influence the model to generate this sequence. Performing such token attribution is expensive; a common approach is to ablate preceding tokens and directly measure their effects. To reduce the cost of token attribution, we revisit attention weights as a heuristic for how a language model uses previous tokens. Naive approaches to attribute model behavior with attention (e.g., averaging attention weights across attention heads to estimate a token's influence) have been found to be unreliable. To attain faithful attributions, we propose treating the attention weights of different attention heads as features. This way, we can learn how to effectively leverage attention weights for attribution (using signal from ablations). Our resulting method, Attribution with Attention (AT2), reliably performs on par with approaches that involve many ablations, while being significantly more efficient. To showcase the utility of AT2, we use it to prune less important parts of a provided context in a question answering setting, improving answer quality. We provide code for AT2 at https://github.com/MadryLab/AT2 .</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13752v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Benjamin Cohen-Wang, Yung-Sung Chuang, Aleksander Madry</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scaling sparse feature circuit finding for in-context learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13756</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13756v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Sparse autoencoders (SAEs) are a popular tool for interpreting large language model activations, but their utility in addressing open questions in interpretability remains unclear. In this work, we demonstrate their effectiveness by using SAEs to deepen our understanding of the mechanism behind in-context learning (ICL). We identify abstract SAE features that (i) encode the model's knowledge of which task to execute and (ii) whose latent vectors causally induce the task zero-shot. This aligns with prior work showing that ICL is mediated by task vectors. We further demonstrate that these task vectors are well approximated by a sparse sum of SAE latents, including these task-execution features. To explore the ICL mechanism, we adapt the sparse feature circuits methodology of Marks et al. (2024) to work for the much larger Gemma-1 2B model, with 30 times as many parameters, and to the more complex task of ICL. Through circuit finding, we discover task-detecting features with corresponding SAE latents that activate earlier in the prompt, that detect when tasks have been performed. They are causally linked with task-execution features through the attention and MLP sublayers.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13756v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dmitrii Kharlapenko, Stepan Shabalin, Fazl Barez, Arthur Conmy, Neel Nanda</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Not All Rollouts are Useful: Down-Sampling Rollouts in LLM Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13818</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13818v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Reinforcement learning (RL) has emerged as a powerful paradigm for enhancing reasoning capabilities in large language models, but faces a fundamental asymmetry in computation and memory requirements: inference is embarrassingly parallel with a minimal memory footprint, while policy updates require extensive synchronization and are memory-intensive. To address this asymmetry, we introduce PODS (Policy Optimization with Down-Sampling), a framework that strategically decouples these phases by generating numerous rollouts in parallel but updating only on an informative subset. Within this framework, we develop max-variance down-sampling, a theoretically motivated method that selects rollouts with maximally diverse reward signals. We prove that this approach has an efficient algorithmic solution, and empirically demonstrate that GRPO with PODS using max-variance down-sampling achieves superior performance over standard GRPO on the GSM8K benchmark.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13818v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yixuan Even Xu, Yash Savani, Fei Fang, Zico Kolter</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does Reinforcement Learning Really Incentivize Reasoning Capacity in LLMs Beyond the Base Model?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13837</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13837v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Reinforcement Learning with Verifiable Rewards (RLVR) has recently demonstrated notable success in enhancing the reasoning capabilities of LLMs, particularly in mathematics and programming tasks. It is widely believed that RLVR enables LLMs to continuously self-improve, thus acquiring novel reasoning abilities that exceed corresponding base models' capacity. In this study, however, we critically re-examines this assumption by measuring the pass@\textit{k} metric with large values of \textit{k} to explore the reasoning capability boundary of the models across a wide range of model families and benchmarks. Surprisingly, the RL does \emph{not}, in fact, elicit fundamentally new reasoning patterns. While RL-trained models outperform their base models at smaller values of $k$ (\eg, $k$=1), base models can achieve a comparable or even higher pass@$k$ score compared to their RL counterparts at large $k$ values. The reasoning paths generated by RL-trained models are already included in the base models' sampling distribution, suggesting that most reasoning abilities manifested in RL-trained models are already obtained by base models. Further analysis shows that RL training boosts the performance by biasing the model's output distribution toward paths that are more likely to yield rewards, therefore sampling correct responses more efficiently. But this also results in a narrower reasoning capability boundary compared to base models. Similar results are observed in visual reasoning tasks trained with RLVR. Moreover, we find that distillation can genuinely introduce new knowledge into the model, different from RLVR. These findings underscore a critical limitation of RLVR in advancing LLM reasoning abilities which requires us to fundamentally rethink the impact of RL training in reasoning LLMs and the need of a better paradigm. Project Page: https://limit-of-RLVR.github.io</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13837v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yang Yue, Zhiqi Chen, Rui Lu, Andrew Zhao, Zhaokai Wang, Yang Yue, Shiji Song, Gao Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Only Send What You Need: Learning to Communicate Efficiently in Federated Multilingual Machine Translation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.07456</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.07456v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Federated learning (FL) is a promising distributed machine learning paradigm that enables multiple clients to collaboratively train a global model. In this paper, we focus on a practical federated multilingual learning setup where clients with their own language-specific data aim to collaboratively construct a high-quality neural machine translation (NMT) model. However, communication constraints in practical network systems present challenges for exchanging large-scale NMT engines between FL parties. We propose a meta-learning-based adaptive parameter selection methodology, MetaSend, that improves the communication efficiency of model transmissions from clients during FL-based multilingual NMT training. Our approach learns a dynamic threshold for filtering parameters prior to transmission without compromising the NMT model quality, based on the tensor deviations of clients between different FL rounds. Through experiments on two NMT datasets with different language distributions, we demonstrate that MetaSend obtains substantial improvements over baselines in translation quality in the presence of a limited communication budget.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.07456v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yun-Wei Chu, Dong-Jun Han, Christopher G. Brinton</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Theory of LLM Sampling: Part Descriptive and Part Prescriptive</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.11005</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.11005v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) are increasingly utilized in autonomous decision-making, where they sample options from vast action spaces. However, the heuristics that guide this sampling process remain under-explored. We study this sampling behavior and show that this underlying heuristics resembles that of human decision-making: comprising a descriptive component (reflecting statistical norm) and a prescriptive component (implicit ideal encoded in the LLM) of a concept. We show that this deviation of a sample from the statistical norm towards a prescriptive component consistently appears in concepts across diverse real-world domains like public health, and economic trends. To further illustrate the theory, we demonstrate that concept prototypes in LLMs are affected by prescriptive norms, similar to the concept of normality in humans. Through case studies and comparison with human studies, we illustrate that in real-world applications, the shift of samples toward an ideal value in LLMs' outputs can result in significantly biased decision-making, raising ethical concerns.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.11005v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sarath Sivaprasad, Pramod Kaushik, Sahar Abdelnabi, Mario Fritz</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where is the answer? Investigating Positional Bias in Language Model Knowledge Extraction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12170</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.12170v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models require updates to remain up-to-date or adapt to new domains by fine-tuning them with new documents. One key is memorizing the latest information in a way that the memorized information is extractable with a query prompt. However, LLMs suffer from a phenomenon called perplexity curse; despite minimizing document perplexity during fine-tuning, LLMs struggle to extract information through a prompt sentence. In this new knowledge acquisition and extraction, we find a very intriguing fact that LLMs can accurately answer questions about the first sentence, but they struggle to extract information described in the middle or end of the documents used for fine-tuning. Our study suggests that the auto-regressive training causes this issue; each token is prompted by reliance on all previous tokens, which hinders the model from recalling information from training documents by question prompts. To conduct the in-depth study, we publish both synthetic and real datasets, enabling the evaluation of the QA performance w.r.t. the position of the corresponding answer in a document. Our investigation shows that even a large model suffers from the perplexity curse, but regularization such as denoising auto-regressive loss can enhance the information extraction from diverse positions. These findings will be (i) a key to improving knowledge extraction from LLMs and (ii) new elements to discuss the trade-off between RAG and fine-tuning in adapting LLMs to a new domain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.12170v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kuniaki Saito, Kihyuk Sohn, Chen-Yu Lee, Yoshitaka Ushiku</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Argumentative Large Language Models for Explainable and Contestable Claim Verification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02079</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02079v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The profusion of knowledge encoded in large language models (LLMs) and their ability to apply this knowledge zero-shot in a range of settings makes them promising candidates for use in decision-making. However, they are currently limited by their inability to provide outputs which can be faithfully explained and effectively contested to correct mistakes. In this paper, we attempt to reconcile these strengths and weaknesses by introducing \emph{argumentative LLMs (ArgLLMs)}, a method for augmenting LLMs with argumentative reasoning. Concretely, ArgLLMs construct argumentation frameworks, which then serve as the basis for formal reasoning in support of decision-making. The interpretable nature of these argumentation frameworks and formal reasoning means that any decision made by ArgLLMs may be explained and contested. We evaluate ArgLLMs' performance experimentally in comparison with state-of-the-art techniques, in the context of the decision-making task of claim verification. We also define novel properties to characterise contestability and assess ArgLLMs formally in terms of these properties.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02079v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Proceedings of the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence, 39(14), 14930-14939. 2025</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Gabriel Freedman, Adam Dejl, Deniz Gorur, Xiang Yin, Antonio Rago, Francesca Toni</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Babysit A Language Model From Scratch: Interactive Language Learning by Trials and Demonstrations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.13828</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.13828v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Humans are efficient language learners and inherently social creatures. Our language development is largely shaped by our social interactions, for example, the demonstration and feedback from caregivers. Contrary to human language learning, recent advancements in large language models have primarily adopted a non-interactive training paradigm, and refined pre-trained models through feedback afterward. In this work, we explore how corrective feedback from interactions influences neural language acquisition from scratch through systematically controlled experiments, assessing whether it contributes to word learning efficiency in language models. We introduce a trial-and-demonstration (TnD) learning framework that incorporates three distinct components: student trials, teacher demonstrations, and a reward conditioned on language competence at various developmental stages. Our experiments reveal that the TnD approach accelerates word acquisition for student models of equal and smaller numbers of parameters, and we highlight the significance of both trials and demonstrations. We further show that the teacher's choices of words influence students' word-specific learning efficiency, and a practice-makes-perfect effect is evident by a strong correlation between the frequency of words in trials and their respective learning curves. Our findings suggest that interactive language learning, with teacher demonstrations and active trials, can facilitate efficient word learning in language models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.13828v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ziqiao Ma, Zekun Wang, Joyce Chai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is In-Context Learning Sufficient for Instruction Following in LLMs?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.19874</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.19874v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In-context learning (ICL) allows LLMs to learn from examples without changing their weights: this is a particularly promising capability for long-context LLMs that can potentially learn from many examples. Recently, Lin et al. (2024) proposed URIAL, a method using only three in-context examples to align base LLMs, achieving non-trivial instruction following performance. In this work, we show that, while effective, ICL alignment with URIAL still underperforms compared to instruction fine-tuning on the established benchmark MT-Bench, especially with more capable base LLMs. We then uncover the most relevant elements for successful in-context alignment, finding the crucial role of the decoding parameters. Based on these insights, we show that the approach of URIAL can indeed be improved by adding high-quality, potentially carefully selected via greedy search, demonstrations in context, getting closer to the performance of instruct models. Finally, we provide the first, to our knowledge, systematic comparison of ICL and instruction fine-tuning (IFT) for instruction following in the low data regime, where ICL can be a viable alternative to IFT. Overall, our work advances the understanding of ICL as an alignment technique and its relationship to IFT. We provide our code at https://github.com/tml-epfl/icl-alignment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.19874v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hao Zhao, Maksym Andriushchenko, Francesco Croce, Nicolas Flammarion</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adversarial Style Augmentation via Large Language Model for Robust Fake News Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.11260</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.11260v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The spread of fake news harms individuals and presents a critical social challenge that must be addressed. Although numerous algorithmic and insightful features have been developed to detect fake news, many of these features can be manipulated with style-conversion attacks, especially with the emergence of advanced language models, making it more difficult to differentiate from genuine news. This study proposes adversarial style augmentation, AdStyle, designed to train a fake news detector that remains robust against various style-conversion attacks. The primary mechanism involves the strategic use of LLMs to automatically generate a diverse and coherent array of style-conversion attack prompts, enhancing the generation of particularly challenging prompts for the detector. Experiments indicate that our augmentation strategy significantly improves robustness and detection performance when evaluated on fake news benchmark datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.11260v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sungwon Park, Sungwon Han, Xing Xie, Jae-Gil Lee, Meeyoung Cha</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Tool-augmented Large Language Models be Aware of Incomplete Conditions?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.12307</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.12307v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advancements in integrating large language models (LLMs) with tools have allowed the models to interact with real-world environments. However, these tool-augmented LLMs often encounter incomplete scenarios when users provide partial information or the necessary tools are unavailable. Recognizing and managing such scenarios is crucial for LLMs to ensure their reliability, but this exploration remains understudied. This study examines whether LLMs can identify incomplete conditions and appropriately determine when to refrain from using tools. To this end, we address a dataset by manipulating instances from two datasets by removing necessary tools or essential information for tool invocation. Our experiments show that LLMs often struggle to identify the absence of information required to utilize specific tools and recognize the absence of appropriate tools. We further analyze model behaviors in different environments and compare their performance against humans. Our research can contribute to advancing reliable LLMs by addressing common scenarios during interactions between humans and LLMs. Our code and dataset will be publicly available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.12307v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Seungbin Yang, ChaeHun Park, Taehee Kim, Jaegul Choo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Comparative Trap: Pairwise Comparisons Amplifies Biased Preferences of LLM Evaluators</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.12319</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.12319v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: As large language models (LLMs) are increasingly used as evaluators for natural language generation tasks, ensuring unbiased assessments is essential. However, LLM evaluators often display biased preferences, such as favoring verbosity and authoritative tones. Our empirical analysis reveals that these biases are exacerbated in pairwise evaluation, where LLMs directly compare two outputs and easily prioritize superficial attributes. In contrast, pointwise evaluation, which assesses outputs independently, is less susceptible to such bias because each output is judged in isolation. To address the limitations of the pairwise evaluation, we introduce a novel evaluation method, PRePair, which integrates pointwise reasoning within a pairwise framework. PRePair effectively alleviates biased preference, improving performance on the adversarial benchmark (LLMBar) while outperforming pointwise evaluation on the standard benchmark (MT-Bench).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.12319v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hawon Jeong, ChaeHun Park, Jimin Hong, Hojoon Lee, Jaegul Choo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does Refusal Training in LLMs Generalize to the Past Tense?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.11969</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.11969v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Refusal training is widely used to prevent LLMs from generating harmful, undesirable, or illegal outputs. We reveal a curious generalization gap in the current refusal training approaches: simply reformulating a harmful request in the past tense (e.g., "How to make a Molotov cocktail?" to "How did people make a Molotov cocktail?") is often sufficient to jailbreak many state-of-the-art LLMs. We systematically evaluate this method on Llama-3 8B, Claude-3.5 Sonnet, GPT-3.5 Turbo, Gemma-2 9B, Phi-3-Mini, GPT-4o mini, GPT-4o, o1-mini, o1-preview, and R2D2 models using GPT-3.5 Turbo as a reformulation model. For example, the success rate of this simple attack on GPT-4o increases from 1% using direct requests to 88% using 20 past tense reformulation attempts on harmful requests from JailbreakBench with GPT-4 as a jailbreak judge. Interestingly, we also find that reformulations in the future tense are less effective, suggesting that refusal guardrails tend to consider past historical questions more benign than hypothetical future questions. Moreover, our experiments on fine-tuning GPT-3.5 Turbo show that defending against past reformulations is feasible when past tense examples are explicitly included in the fine-tuning data. Overall, our findings highlight that the widely used alignment techniques -- such as SFT, RLHF, and adversarial training -- employed to align the studied models can be brittle and do not always generalize as intended. We provide code and jailbreak artifacts at https://github.com/tml-epfl/llm-past-tense.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.11969v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Maksym Andriushchenko, Nicolas Flammarion</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Epistemic Language with a Language-augmented Bayesian Theory of Mind</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12022</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12022v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: How do people understand and evaluate claims about others' beliefs, even though these beliefs cannot be directly observed? In this paper, we introduce a cognitive model of epistemic language interpretation, grounded in Bayesian inferences about other agents' goals, beliefs, and intentions: a language-augmented Bayesian theory-of-mind (LaBToM). By translating natural language into an epistemic ``language-of-thought'' with grammar-constrained LLM decoding, then evaluating these translations against the inferences produced by inverting a generative model of rational action and perception, LaBToM captures graded plausibility judgments of epistemic claims. We validate our model in an experiment where participants watch an agent navigate a maze to find keys hidden in boxes needed to reach their goal, then rate sentences about the agent's beliefs. In contrast with multimodal LLMs (GPT-4o, Gemini Pro) and ablated models, our model correlates highly with human judgments for a wide range of expressions, including modal language, uncertainty expressions, knowledge claims, likelihood comparisons, and attributions of false belief.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12022v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lance Ying, Tan Zhi-Xuan, Lionel Wong, Vikash Mansinghka, Joshua B. Tenenbaum</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Language Models are Good Multi-lingual Learners : When LLMs Meet Cross-lingual Prompts</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.11056</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.11056v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: With the advent of Large Language Models (LLMs), generating rule-based data for real-world applications has become more accessible. Due to the inherent ambiguity of natural language and the complexity of rule sets, especially in long contexts, LLMs often struggle to follow all specified rules, frequently omitting at least one. To enhance the reasoning and understanding of LLMs on long and complex contexts, we propose a novel prompting strategy Multi-Lingual Prompt, namely MLPrompt, which automatically translates the error-prone rule that an LLM struggles to follow into another language, thus drawing greater attention to it. Experimental results on public datasets across various tasks have shown MLPrompt can outperform state-of-the-art prompting methods such as Chain of Thought, Tree of Thought, and Self-Consistency. Additionally, we introduce a framework integrating MLPrompt with an auto-checking mechanism for structured data generation, with a specific case study in text-to-MIP instances. Further, we extend the proposed framework for text-to-SQL to demonstrate its generation ability towards structured data synthesis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.11056v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Teng Wang, Zhenqi He, Wing-Yin Yu, Xiaojin Fu, Xiongwei Han</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reducing the Scope of Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.21597</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.21597v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We now deploy language models in a wide variety of user-facing applications. Typically, these deployments have some specific purpose, like answering questions about documentation or acting as coding assistants, but they require general language understanding. Under these circumstances these models should not be able to answer irrelevant requests such as, poetry generation or questions about physics, etc. Instead we would like language models to only answer to queries corresponding to desired behavior and refuse all other requests, which we refer to as scoping. We conduct a comprehensive empirical evaluation of potential methods from prompting to fine-tuning to preference learning to a recently proposed method for general alignment called Circuit Breakers (CB). Across three families of language models and a broad variety of tasks, we show that it is possible to scope language models. We examine scoping for multiple topics, and fine-grained topics. We ablate diversity of irrelevant queries, layer different techniques, conduct adversarial evaluations and more. Among other results, we find that, when diverse examples of irrelevant queries are available, simple supervised fine-tuning produces the best results, but when such diversity is low, Circuit Breakers perform quite well. One can often get the benefits of both methods by layering them in succession. We intend our study to serve as a practitioner's guide to scoping language models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.21597v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>David Yunis, Siyu Huo, Chulaka Gunasekara, Danish Contractor</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can LLMs assist with Ambiguity? A Quantitative Evaluation of various Large Language Models on Word Sense Disambiguation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.18337</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.18337v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Ambiguous words are often found in modern digital communications. Lexical ambiguity challenges traditional Word Sense Disambiguation (WSD) methods, due to limited data. Consequently, the efficiency of translation, information retrieval, and question-answering systems is hindered by these limitations. This study investigates the use of Large Language Models (LLMs) to improve WSD using a novel approach combining a systematic prompt augmentation mechanism with a knowledge base (KB) consisting of different sense interpretations. The proposed method incorporates a human-in-loop approach for prompt augmentation where prompt is supported by Part-of-Speech (POS) tagging, synonyms of ambiguous words, aspect-based sense filtering and few-shot prompting to guide the LLM. By utilizing a few-shot Chain of Thought (COT) prompting-based approach, this work demonstrates a substantial improvement in performance. The evaluation was conducted using FEWS test data and sense tags. This research advances accurate word interpretation in social media and digital communication.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.18337v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>T. G. D. K. Sumanathilaka, Nicholas Micallef, Julian Hough</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are You Doubtful? Oh, It Might Be Difficult Then! Exploring the Use of Model Uncertainty for Question Difficulty Estimation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.11831</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.11831v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In an educational setting, an estimate of the difficulty of multiple-choice questions (MCQs), a commonly used strategy to assess learning progress, constitutes very useful information for both teachers and students. Since human assessment is costly from multiple points of view, automatic approaches to MCQ item difficulty estimation are investigated, yielding however mixed success until now. Our approach to this problem takes a different angle from previous work: asking various Large Language Models to tackle the questions included in three different MCQ datasets, we leverage model uncertainty to estimate item difficulty. By using both model uncertainty features as well as textual features in a Random Forest regressor, we show that uncertainty features contribute substantially to difficulty prediction, where difficulty is inversely proportional to the number of students who can correctly answer a question. In addition to showing the value of our approach, we also observe that our model achieves state-of-the-art results on the USMLE and CMCQRD publicly available datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.11831v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Leonidas Zotos, Hedderik van Rijn, Malvina Nissim</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>StaICC: Standardized Evaluation for Classification Task in In-context Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.15708</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.15708v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Classification tasks are widely investigated in the In-Context Learning (ICL) paradigm. However, current efforts are evaluated on disjoint benchmarks and settings, while their performances are significantly influenced by some trivial variables, such as prompt templates, data sampling, instructions, etc., which leads to significant inconsistencies in the results reported across various literature, preventing fair comparison or meta-analysis across different papers. Therefore, this paper proposes a standardized and easy-to-use evaluation toolkit (StaICC) for in-context classification. Including, for the normal classification task, we provide StaICC-Normal, selecting 10 widely used datasets, and generating prompts with a fixed form, to mitigate the variance among the experiment implementations. To enrich the usage of our benchmark, we also provide a sub-benchmark StaICC-Diag for diagnosing ICL from several aspects, aiming for a more robust inference processing.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.15708v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hakaze Cho, Naoya Inoue</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A-MEM: Agentic Memory for LLM Agents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.12110</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.12110v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: While large language model (LLM) agents can effectively use external tools for complex real-world tasks, they require memory systems to leverage historical experiences. Current memory systems enable basic storage and retrieval but lack sophisticated memory organization, despite recent attempts to incorporate graph databases. Moreover, these systems' fixed operations and structures limit their adaptability across diverse tasks. To address this limitation, this paper proposes a novel agentic memory system for LLM agents that can dynamically organize memories in an agentic way. Following the basic principles of the Zettelkasten method, we designed our memory system to create interconnected knowledge networks through dynamic indexing and linking. When a new memory is added, we generate a comprehensive note containing multiple structured attributes, including contextual descriptions, keywords, and tags. The system then analyzes historical memories to identify relevant connections, establishing links where meaningful similarities exist. Additionally, this process enables memory evolution - as new memories are integrated, they can trigger updates to the contextual representations and attributes of existing historical memories, allowing the memory network to continuously refine its understanding. Our approach combines the structured organization principles of Zettelkasten with the flexibility of agent-driven decision making, allowing for more adaptive and context-aware memory management. Empirical experiments on six foundation models show superior improvement against existing SOTA baselines. The source code for evaluating performance is available at https://github.com/WujiangXu/AgenticMemory, while the source code of agentic memory system is available at https://github.com/agiresearch/A-mem.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.12110v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wujiang Xu, Kai Mei, Hang Gao, Juntao Tan, Zujie Liang, Yongfeng Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Token-Level Density-Based Uncertainty Quantification Methods for Eliciting Truthfulness of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.14427</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.14427v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Uncertainty quantification (UQ) is a prominent approach for eliciting truthful answers from large language models (LLMs). To date, information-based and consistency-based UQ have been the dominant UQ methods for text generation via LLMs. Density-based methods, despite being very effective for UQ in text classification with encoder-based models, have not been very successful with generative LLMs. In this work, we adapt Mahalanobis Distance (MD) - a well-established UQ technique in classification tasks - for text generation and introduce a new supervised UQ method. Our method extracts token embeddings from multiple layers of LLMs, computes MD scores for each token, and uses linear regression trained on these features to provide robust uncertainty scores. Through extensive experiments on eleven datasets, we demonstrate that our approach substantially improves over existing UQ methods, providing accurate and computationally efficient uncertainty scores for both sequence-level selective generation and claim-level fact-checking tasks. Our method also exhibits strong generalization to out-of-domain data, making it suitable for a wide range of LLM-based applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.14427v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Artem Vazhentsev, Lyudmila Rvanova, Ivan Lazichny, Alexander Panchenko, Maxim Panov, Timothy Baldwin, Artem Shelmanov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ReaRAG: Knowledge-guided Reasoning Enhances Factuality of Large Reasoning Models with Iterative Retrieval Augmented Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.21729</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.21729v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Reasoning Models (LRMs) exhibit remarkable reasoning abilities but rely primarily on parametric knowledge, limiting factual accuracy. While recent works equip reinforcement learning (RL)-based LRMs with retrieval capabilities, they suffer from overthinking and lack robustness in reasoning, reducing their effectiveness in question answering (QA) tasks. To address this, we propose ReaRAG, a factuality-enhanced reasoning model that explores diverse queries without excessive iterations. Our solution includes a novel data construction framework with an upper bound on the reasoning chain length. Specifically, we first leverage an LRM to generate deliberate thinking, then select an action from a predefined action space (Search and Finish). For Search action, a query is executed against the RAG engine, where the result is returned as observation to guide reasoning steps later. This process iterates until a Finish action is chosen. Benefiting from ReaRAG's strong reasoning capabilities, our approach outperforms existing baselines on multi-hop QA. Further analysis highlights its strong reflective ability to recognize errors and refine its reasoning trajectory. Our study enhances LRMs' factuality while effectively integrating robust reasoning for Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.21729v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhicheng Lee, Shulin Cao, Jinxin Liu, Jiajie Zhang, Weichuan Liu, Xiaoyin Che, Lei Hou, Juanzi Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive Layer-skipping in Pre-trained LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.23798</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.23798v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Various layer-skipping methods have been proposed to accelerate token generation in large language models (LLMs). However, they have overlooked a fundamental question: How do computational demands vary across the generation of different tokens? In this work, we introduce FlexiDepth, a method that dynamically adjusts the number of Transformer layers used in text generation. By incorporating a plug-in router and adapter, FlexiDepth enables adaptive layer-skipping in LLMs without modifying their original parameters. Introducing FlexiDepth to Llama-3-8B model achieves layer skipping of 8 layers out of 32, and meanwhile maintains the full 100\% benchmark performance. Experimental results with FlexiDepth demonstrate that computational demands in LLMs significantly vary based on token type. Specifically, generating repetitive tokens or fixed phrases requires fewer layers, whereas producing tokens involving computation or high uncertainty requires more layers. Interestingly, this adaptive allocation pattern aligns with human intuition. To advance research in this area, we open sourced FlexiDepth and a dataset documenting FlexiDepth's layer allocation patterns for future exploration.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.23798v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xuan Luo, Weizhi Wang, Xifeng Yan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the Intrinsic Ethical Vulnerability of Aligned Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.05050</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.05050v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are foundational explorations to artificial general intelligence, yet their alignment with human values via instruction tuning and preference learning achieves only superficial compliance. Here, we demonstrate that harmful knowledge embedded during pretraining persists as indelible "dark patterns" in LLMs' parametric memory, evading alignment safeguards and resurfacing under adversarial inducement at distributional shifts. In this study, we first theoretically analyze the intrinsic ethical vulnerability of aligned LLMs by proving that current alignment methods yield only local "safety regions" in the knowledge manifold. In contrast, pretrained knowledge remains globally connected to harmful concepts via high-likelihood adversarial trajectories. Building on this theoretical insight, we empirically validate our findings by employing semantic coherence inducement under distributional shifts--a method that systematically bypasses alignment constraints through optimized adversarial prompts. This combined theoretical and empirical approach achieves a 100% attack success rate across 19 out of 23 state-of-the-art aligned LLMs, including DeepSeek-R1 and LLaMA-3, revealing their universal vulnerabilities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.05050v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiawei Lian, Jianhong Pan, Lefan Wang, Yi Wang, Shaohui Mei, Lap-Pui Chau</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Token to Line: Enhancing Code Generation with a Long-Term Perspective</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.07433</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.07433v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The emergence of large language models (LLMs) has significantly promoted the development of code generation task, sparking a surge in pertinent literature. Current research is hindered by redundant generation results and a tendency to overfit local patterns in the short term. Although existing studies attempt to alleviate the issue by adopting a multi-token prediction strategy, there remains limited focus on choosing the appropriate processing length for generations. By analyzing the attention between tokens during the generation process of LLMs, it can be observed that the high spikes of the attention scores typically appear at the end of lines. This insight suggests that it is reasonable to treat each line of code as a fundamental processing unit and generate them sequentially. Inspired by this, we propose the \textbf{LSR-MCTS} algorithm, which leverages MCTS to determine the code line-by-line and select the optimal path. Further, we integrate a self-refine mechanism at each node to enhance diversity and generate higher-quality programs through error correction. Extensive experiments and comprehensive analyses on three public coding benchmarks demonstrate that our method outperforms the state-of-the-art performance approaches.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.07433v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tingwei Lu, Yangning Li, Liyuan Wang, Binghuai Lin, Jiwei Tang, Wanshi Xu, Hai-Tao Zheng, Yinghui Li, Bingxu An, Zhao Wei, Yong Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can postgraduate translation students identify machine-generated text?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.09164</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.09164v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Given the growing use of generative artificial intelligence as a tool for creating multilingual content and bypassing both machine and traditional translation methods, this study explores the ability of linguistically trained individuals to discern machine-generated output from human-written text (HT). After brief training sessions on the textual anomalies typically found in synthetic text (ST), twenty-three postgraduate translation students analysed excerpts of Italian prose and assigned likelihood scores to indicate whether they believed they were human-written or AI-generated (ChatGPT-4o). The results show that, on average, the students struggled to distinguish between HT and ST, with only two participants achieving notable accuracy. Closer analysis revealed that the students often identified the same textual anomalies in both HT and ST, although features such as low burstiness and self-contradiction were more frequently associated with ST. These findings suggest the need for improvements in the preparatory training. Moreover, the study raises questions about the necessity of editing synthetic text to make it sound more human-like and recommends further research to determine whether AI-generated text is already sufficiently natural-sounding not to require further refinement.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.09164v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Michael Farrell</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>C-MTCSD: A Chinese Multi-Turn Conversational Stance Detection Dataset</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.09958</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.09958v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Stance detection has become an essential tool for analyzing public discussions on social media. Current methods face significant challenges, particularly in Chinese language processing and multi-turn conversational analysis. To address these limitations, we introduce C-MTCSD, the largest Chinese multi-turn conversational stance detection dataset, comprising 24,264 carefully annotated instances from Sina Weibo, which is 4.2 times larger than the only prior Chinese conversational stance detection dataset. Our comprehensive evaluation using both traditional approaches and large language models reveals the complexity of C-MTCSD: even state-of-the-art models achieve only 64.07% F1 score in the challenging zero-shot setting, while performance consistently degrades with increasing conversation depth. Traditional models particularly struggle with implicit stance detection, achieving below 50% F1 score. This work establishes a challenging new benchmark for Chinese stance detection research, highlighting significant opportunities for future improvements.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.09958v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fuqiang Niu, Yi Yang, Xianghua Fu, Genan Dai, Bowen Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Mirage of Performance Gains: Why Contrastive Decoding Fails to Address Multimodal Hallucination</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.10020</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.10020v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Contrastive decoding strategies are widely used to reduce hallucinations in multimodal large language models (MLLMs). These methods work by constructing contrastive samples to induce hallucinations and then suppressing them in the output distribution. However, this paper demonstrates that such approaches fail to effectively mitigate the hallucination problem. The performance improvements observed on POPE Benchmark are largely driven by two misleading factors: (1) crude, unidirectional adjustments to the model's output distribution and (2) the adaptive plausibility constraint, which reduces the sampling strategy to greedy search. To further illustrate these issues, we introduce a series of spurious improvement methods and evaluate their performance against contrastive decoding techniques. Experimental results reveal that the observed performance gains in contrastive decoding are entirely unrelated to its intended goal of mitigating hallucinations. Our findings challenge common assumptions about the effectiveness of contrastive decoding strategies and pave the way for developing genuinely effective solutions to hallucinations in MLLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.10020v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hao Yin, Guangzong Si, Zilei Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>D\'ej\`a Vu: Multilingual LLM Evaluation through the Lens of Machine Translation Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.11829</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.11829v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Generation capabilities and language coverage of multilingual large language models (mLLMs) are advancing rapidly. However, evaluation practices for generative abilities of mLLMs are still lacking comprehensiveness, scientific rigor, and consistent adoption across research labs, which undermines their potential to meaningfully guide mLLM development. We draw parallels with machine translation (MT) evaluation, a field that faced similar challenges and has, over decades, developed transparent reporting standards and reliable evaluations for multilingual generative models. Through targeted experiments across key stages of the generative evaluation pipeline, we demonstrate how best practices from MT evaluation can deepen the understanding of quality differences between models. Additionally, we identify essential components for robust meta-evaluation of mLLMs, ensuring the evaluation methods themselves are rigorously assessed. We distill these insights into a checklist of actionable recommendations for mLLM research and development.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.11829v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Julia Kreutzer, Eleftheria Briakou, Sweta Agrawal, Marzieh Fadaee, Kocmi Tom</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding Flawed Fictions: Evaluating Complex Reasoning in Language Models via Plot Hole Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.11900</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.11900v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Stories are a fundamental aspect of human experience. Engaging deeply with stories and spotting plot holes -- inconsistencies in a storyline that break the internal logic or rules of a story's world -- requires nuanced reasoning skills, including tracking entities and events and their interplay, abstract thinking, pragmatic narrative understanding, commonsense and social reasoning, and theory of mind. As Large Language Models (LLMs) increasingly generate, interpret, and modify text, rigorously assessing their narrative consistency and deeper language understanding becomes critical. However, existing benchmarks focus mainly on surface-level comprehension. In this work, we propose plot hole detection in stories as a proxy to evaluate language understanding and reasoning in LLMs. We introduce FlawedFictionsMaker, a novel algorithm to controllably and carefully synthesize plot holes in human-written stories. Using this algorithm, we construct a benchmark to evaluate LLMs' plot hole detection abilities in stories -- FlawedFictions -- , which is robust to contamination, with human filtering ensuring high quality. We find that state-of-the-art LLMs struggle in accurately solving FlawedFictions regardless of the reasoning effort allowed, with performance significantly degrading as story length increases. Finally, we show that LLM-based story summarization and story generation are prone to introducing plot holes, with more than 50% and 100% increases in plot hole detection rates with respect to human-written originals.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.11900v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kabir Ahuja, Melanie Sclar, Yulia Tsvetkov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SysCaps: Language Interfaces for Simulation Surrogates of Complex Systems</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.19653</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.19653v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Surrogate models are used to predict the behavior of complex energy systems that are too expensive to simulate with traditional numerical methods. Our work introduces the use of language descriptions, which we call ``system captions'' or SysCaps, to interface with such surrogates. We argue that interacting with surrogates through text, particularly natural language, makes these models more accessible for both experts and non-experts. We introduce a lightweight multimodal text and timeseries regression model and a training pipeline that uses large language models (LLMs) to synthesize high-quality captions from simulation metadata. Our experiments on two real-world simulators of buildings and wind farms show that our SysCaps-augmented surrogates have better accuracy on held-out systems than traditional methods while enjoying new generalization abilities, such as handling semantically related descriptions of the same test system. Additional experiments also highlight the potential of SysCaps to unlock language-driven design space exploration and to regularize training through prompt augmentation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.19653v4</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SY</category>
      <category>eess.SY</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Patrick Emami, Zhaonan Li, Saumya Sinha, Truc Nguyen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM-Select: Feature Selection with Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.02694</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.02694v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In this paper, we demonstrate a surprising capability of large language models (LLMs): given only input feature names and a description of a prediction task, they are capable of selecting the most predictive features, with performance rivaling the standard tools of data science. Remarkably, these models exhibit this capacity across various query mechanisms. For example, we zero-shot prompt an LLM to output a numerical importance score for a feature (e.g., "blood pressure") in predicting an outcome of interest (e.g., "heart failure"), with no additional context. In particular, we find that the latest models, such as GPT-4, can consistently identify the most predictive features regardless of the query mechanism and across various prompting strategies. We illustrate these findings through extensive experiments on real-world data, where we show that LLM-based feature selection consistently achieves strong performance competitive with data-driven methods such as the LASSO, despite never having looked at the downstream training data. Our findings suggest that LLMs may be useful not only for selecting the best features for training but also for deciding which features to collect in the first place. This could benefit practitioners in domains like healthcare and the social sciences, where collecting high-quality data comes at a high cost.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.02694v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Daniel P. Jeong, Zachary C. Lipton, Pradeep Ravikumar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Robust Alignment of Language Models: Distributionally Robustifying Direct Preference Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.07880</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.07880v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: This study addresses the challenge of noise in training datasets for Direct Preference Optimization (DPO), a method for aligning Large Language Models (LLMs) with human preferences. We categorize noise into pointwise noise, which includes low-quality data points, and pairwise noise, which encompasses erroneous data pair associations that affect preference rankings. Utilizing Distributionally Robust Optimization (DRO), we enhance DPO's resilience to these types of noise. Our theoretical insights reveal that DPO inherently embeds DRO principles, conferring robustness to pointwise noise, with the regularization coefficient $\beta$ playing a critical role in its noise resistance. Extending this framework, we introduce Distributionally Robustifying DPO (Dr. DPO), which integrates pairwise robustness by optimizing against worst-case pairwise scenarios. The novel hyperparameter $\beta'$ in Dr. DPO allows for fine-tuned control over data pair reliability, providing a strategic balance between exploration and exploitation in noisy training environments. Empirical evaluations demonstrate that Dr. DPO substantially improves the quality of generated text and response accuracy in preference datasets, showcasing enhanced performance in both noisy and noise-free settings. The code is available at https://github.com/junkangwu/Dr_DPO.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.07880v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junkang Wu, Yuexiang Xie, Zhengyi Yang, Jiancan Wu, Jiawei Chen, Jinyang Gao, Bolin Ding, Xiang Wang, Xiangnan He</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spin glass model of in-context learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02288</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.02288v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large language models show a surprising in-context learning ability -- being able to use a prompt to form a prediction for a query, yet without additional training, in stark contrast to old-fashioned supervised learning. Providing a mechanistic interpretation and linking the empirical phenomenon to physics are thus challenging and remain unsolved. We study a simple yet expressive transformer with linear attention and map this structure to a spin glass model with real-valued spins, where the couplings and fields explain the intrinsic disorder in data. The spin glass model explains how the weight parameters interact with each other during pre-training, and further clarifies why an unseen function can be predicted by providing only a prompt yet without further training. Our theory reveals that for single-instance learning, increasing the task diversity leads to the emergence of in-context learning, by allowing the Boltzmann distribution to converge to a unique correct solution of weight parameters. Therefore the pre-trained transformer displays a prediction power in a novel prompt setting. The proposed analytically tractable model thus offers a promising avenue for thinking about how to interpret many intriguing but puzzling properties of large language models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.02288v3</guid>
      <category>cond-mat.dis-nn</category>
      <category>cond-mat.stat-mech</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuhao Li, Ruoran Bai, Haiping Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Natural Language Outlines for Code: Literate Programming in the LLM Era</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.04820</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.04820v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We propose using natural language outlines as a novel modality and interaction surface for providing AI assistance to developers throughout the software development process. An NL outline for a code function comprises multiple statements written in concise prose, which partition the code and summarize its main ideas in the style of literate programming. Crucially, we find that modern LLMs can generate accurate and high-quality NL outlines in practice. Moreover, NL outlines enable a bidirectional sync between code and NL, where a developer can change either code or NL and have the LLM automatically update the other. We discuss many use cases for NL outlines: they can accelerate understanding and navigation of code and diffs, simplify code maintenance, augment code search, steer code generation, and more. We then propose and compare multiple LLM prompting techniques for generating outlines and ask professional developers to judge outline quality. Finally, we present two case studies applying NL outlines toward code review and malware detection.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.04820v4</guid>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3696630.3728541</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Kensen Shi, Deniz Alt{\i}nb\"uken, Saswat Anand, Mihai Christodorescu, Katja Gr\"unwedel, Alexa Koenings, Sai Naidu, Anurag Pathak, Marc Rasi, Fredde Ribeiro, Brandon Ruffin, Siddhant Sanyam, Maxim Tabachnyk, Sara Toth, Roy Tu, Tobias Welp, Pengcheng Yin, Manzil Zaheer, Satish Chandra, Charles Sutton</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SciLitLLM: How to Adapt LLMs for Scientific Literature Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.15545</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.15545v5 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Scientific literature understanding is crucial for extracting targeted information and garnering insights, thereby significantly advancing scientific discovery. Despite the remarkable success of Large Language Models (LLMs), they face challenges in scientific literature understanding, primarily due to (1) a lack of scientific knowledge and (2) unfamiliarity with specialized scientific tasks.
  To develop an LLM specialized in scientific literature understanding, we propose a hybrid strategy that integrates continual pre-training (CPT) and supervised fine-tuning (SFT), to simultaneously infuse scientific domain knowledge and enhance instruction-following capabilities for domain-specific tasks.cIn this process, we identify two key challenges: (1) constructing high-quality CPT corpora, and (2) generating diverse SFT instructions. We address these challenges through a meticulous pipeline, including PDF text extraction, parsing content error correction, quality filtering, and synthetic instruction creation. Applying this strategy, we present a suite of LLMs: SciLitLLM, specialized in scientific literature understanding. These models demonstrate promising performance on scientific literature understanding benchmarks.
  Our contributions are threefold: (1) We present an effective framework that integrates CPT and SFT to adapt LLMs to scientific literature understanding, which can also be easily adapted to other domains. (2) We propose an LLM-based synthesis method to generate diverse and high-quality scientific instructions, resulting in a new instruction set -- SciLitIns -- for supervised fine-tuning in less-represented scientific domains. (3) SciLitLLM achieves promising performance improvements on scientific literature understanding benchmarks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.15545v5</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sihang Li, Jin Huang, Jiaxi Zhuang, Yaorui Shi, Xiaochen Cai, Mingjun Xu, Xiang Wang, Linfeng Zhang, Guolin Ke, Hengxing Cai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>United in Diversity? Contextual Biases in LLM-Based Predictions of the 2024 European Parliament Elections</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.09045</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.09045v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: "Synthetic samples" based on large language models (LLMs) have been argued to serve as efficient alternatives to surveys of humans, assuming that their training data includes information on human attitudes and behavior. However, LLM-synthetic samples might exhibit bias, for example due to training data and fine-tuning processes being unrepresentative of diverse contexts. Such biases risk reinforcing existing biases in research, policymaking, and society. Therefore, researchers need to investigate if and under which conditions LLM-generated synthetic samples can be used for public opinion prediction. In this study, we examine to what extent LLM-based predictions of individual public opinion exhibit context-dependent biases by predicting the results of the 2024 European Parliament elections. Prompting three LLMs with individual-level background information of 26,000 eligible European voters, we ask the LLMs to predict each person's voting behavior. By comparing them to the actual results, we show that LLM-based predictions of future voting behavior largely fail, their accuracy is unequally distributed across national and linguistic contexts, and they require detailed attitudinal information in the prompt. The findings emphasize the limited applicability of LLM-synthetic samples to public opinion prediction. In investigating their contextual biases, this study contributes to the understanding and mitigation of inequalities in the development of LLMs and their applications in computational social science.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.09045v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>stat.AP</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Leah von der Heyde, Anna-Carolina Haensch, Alexander Wenz, Bolei Ma</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AgentHarm: A Benchmark for Measuring Harmfulness of LLM Agents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.09024</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.09024v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The robustness of LLMs to jailbreak attacks, where users design prompts to circumvent safety measures and misuse model capabilities, has been studied primarily for LLMs acting as simple chatbots. Meanwhile, LLM agents -- which use external tools and can execute multi-stage tasks -- may pose a greater risk if misused, but their robustness remains underexplored. To facilitate research on LLM agent misuse, we propose a new benchmark called AgentHarm. The benchmark includes a diverse set of 110 explicitly malicious agent tasks (440 with augmentations), covering 11 harm categories including fraud, cybercrime, and harassment. In addition to measuring whether models refuse harmful agentic requests, scoring well on AgentHarm requires jailbroken agents to maintain their capabilities following an attack to complete a multi-step task. We evaluate a range of leading LLMs, and find (1) leading LLMs are surprisingly compliant with malicious agent requests without jailbreaking, (2) simple universal jailbreak templates can be adapted to effectively jailbreak agents, and (3) these jailbreaks enable coherent and malicious multi-step agent behavior and retain model capabilities. To enable simple and reliable evaluation of attacks and defenses for LLM-based agents, we publicly release AgentHarm at https://huggingface.co/datasets/ai-safety-institute/AgentHarm.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.09024v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Maksym Andriushchenko, Alexandra Souly, Mateusz Dziemian, Derek Duenas, Maxwell Lin, Justin Wang, Dan Hendrycks, Andy Zou, Zico Kolter, Matt Fredrikson, Eric Winsor, Jerome Wynne, Yarin Gal, Xander Davies</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ShadowKV: KV Cache in Shadows for High-Throughput Long-Context LLM Inference</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.21465</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.21465v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: With the widespread deployment of long-context large language models (LLMs), there has been a growing demand for efficient support of high-throughput inference. However, as the key-value (KV) cache expands with the sequence length, the increasing memory footprint and the need to access it for each token generation both result in low throughput when serving long-context LLMs. While various dynamic sparse attention methods have been proposed to speed up inference while maintaining generation quality, they either fail to sufficiently reduce GPU memory consumption or introduce significant decoding latency by offloading the KV cache to the CPU. We present ShadowKV, a high-throughput long-context LLM inference system that stores the low-rank key cache and offloads the value cache to reduce the memory footprint for larger batch sizes and longer sequences. To minimize decoding latency, ShadowKV employs an accurate KV selection strategy that reconstructs minimal sparse KV pairs on-the-fly. By evaluating ShadowKV on a broad range of benchmarks, including RULER, LongBench, and Needle In A Haystack, and models like Llama-3.1-8B, Llama-3-8B-1M, GLM-4-9B-1M, Yi-9B-200K, Phi-3-Mini-128K, and Qwen2-7B-128K, we demonstrate that it can support up to 6$\times$ larger batch sizes and boost throughput by up to 3.04$\times$ on an A100 GPU without sacrificing accuracy, even surpassing the performance achievable with infinite batch size under the assumption of infinite GPU memory. The code is available at https://github.com/bytedance/ShadowKV.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.21465v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hanshi Sun, Li-Wen Chang, Wenlei Bao, Size Zheng, Ningxin Zheng, Xin Liu, Harry Dong, Yuejie Chi, Beidi Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PriorDiffusion: Leverage Language Prior in Diffusion Models for Monocular Depth Estimation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.16750</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.16750v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Traditional monocular depth estimation suffers from inherent ambiguity and visual nuisance. We argue that language prior can enhance monocular depth estimation by leveraging the inductive bias learned during the text-to-image pre-training of diffusion models. The ability of these models to generate images that align with text indicates that they have learned the spatial relationships, size, and shape of specified objects, which can be applied to improve depth estimation. Thus, we propose PriorDiffusion, using a pre-trained text-to-image diffusion model that takes both images and corresponding text descriptions to infer affine-invariant depth through a denoising process. We also show that language prior enhances the model's perception of specific regions of images that users care about and describe. Simultaneously, language prior acts as a constraint to accelerate the convergence of both training and the inference diffusion trajectory. By training on HyperSim and Virtual KITTI, we achieve faster training convergence, fewer inference diffusion steps, and state-of-the-art zero-shot performance across NYUv2, KITTI, ETH3D, and ScanNet. Code will be released upon acceptance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.16750v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ziyao Zeng, Jingcheng Ni, Daniel Wang, Patrick Rim, Younjoon Chung, Fengyu Yang, Byung-Woo Hong, Alex Wong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prompt-Based Cost-Effective Evaluation and Operation of ChatGPT as a Computer Programming Teaching Assistant</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.17176</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.17176v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The dream of achieving a student-teacher ratio of 1:1 is closer than ever thanks to the emergence of large language models (LLMs). One potential application of these models in the educational field would be to provide feedback to students in university introductory programming courses, so that a student struggling to solve a basic implementation problem could seek help from an LLM available 24/7. This article focuses on studying three aspects related to such an application. First, the performance of two well-known models, GPT-3.5T and GPT-4T, in providing feedback to students is evaluated. The empirical results showed that GPT-4T performs much better than GPT-3.5T, however, it is not yet ready for use in a real-world scenario. This is due to the possibility of generating incorrect information that potential users may not always be able to detect. Second, the article proposes a carefully designed prompt using in-context learning techniques that allows automating important parts of the evaluation process, as well as providing a lower bound for the fraction of feedbacks containing incorrect information, saving time and effort. This was possible because the resulting feedback has a programmatically analyzable structure that incorporates diagnostic information about the LLM's performance in solving the requested task. Third, the article also suggests a possible strategy for implementing a practical learning tool based on LLMs, which is rooted on the proposed prompting techniques. This strategy opens up a whole range of interesting possibilities from a pedagogical perspective.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.17176v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Marc Ballestero-Rib\'o, Daniel Ortiz-Mart\'inez</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project Alexandria: Towards Freeing Scientific Knowledge from Copyright Burdens via LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.19413</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.19413v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Paywalls, licenses and copyright rules often restrict the broad dissemination and reuse of scientific knowledge. We take the position that it is both legally and technically feasible to extract the scientific knowledge in scholarly texts. Current methods, like text embeddings, fail to reliably preserve factual content, and simple paraphrasing may not be legally sound. We propose a new idea for the community to adopt: convert scholarly documents into knowledge preserving, but style agnostic representations we term Knowledge Units using LLMs. These units use structured data capturing entities, attributes and relationships without stylistic content. We provide evidence that Knowledge Units (1) form a legally defensible framework for sharing knowledge from copyrighted research texts, based on legal analyses of German copyright law and U.S. Fair Use doctrine, and (2) preserve most (~95\%) factual knowledge from original text, measured by MCQ performance on facts from the original copyrighted text across four research domains. Freeing scientific knowledge from copyright promises transformative benefits for scientific research and education by allowing language models to reuse important facts from copyrighted text. To support this, we share open-source tools for converting research documents into Knowledge Units. Overall, our work posits the feasibility of democratizing access to scientific knowledge while respecting copyright.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.19413v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Christoph Schuhmann, Gollam Rabby, Ameya Prabhu, Tawsif Ahmed, Andreas Hochlehnert, Huu Nguyen, Nick Akinci, Ludwig Schmidt, Robert Kaczmarczyk, S\"oren Auer, Jenia Jitsev, Matthias Bethge</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Psycholinguistic Analyses in Software Engineering Text: A Systematic Literature Review</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.05992</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.05992v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Context: A deeper understanding of human factors in software engineering (SE) is essential for improving team collaboration, decision-making, and productivity. Communication channels like code reviews and chats provide insights into developers' psychological and emotional states. While large language models excel at text analysis, they often lack transparency and precision. Psycholinguistic tools like Linguistic Inquiry and Word Count (LIWC) offer clearer, interpretable insights into cognitive and emotional processes exhibited in text. Despite its wide use in SE research, no comprehensive review of LIWC's use has been conducted. Objective: We examine the importance of psycholinguistic tools, particularly LIWC, and provide a thorough analysis of its current and potential future applications in SE research. Methods: We conducted a systematic review of six prominent databases, identifying 43 SE-related papers using LIWC. Our analysis focuses on five research questions. Results: Our findings reveal a wide range of applications, including analyzing team communication to detect developer emotions and personality, developing ML models to predict deleted Stack Overflow posts, and more recently comparing AI-generated and human-written text. LIWC has been primarily used with data from project management platforms (e.g., GitHub) and Q&amp;A forums (e.g., Stack Overflow). Key BSE concepts include Communication, Organizational Climate, and Positive Psychology. 26 of 43 papers did not formally evaluate LIWC. Concerns were raised about some limitations, including difficulty handling SE-specific vocabulary. Conclusion: We highlight the potential of psycholinguistic tools and their limitations, and present new use cases for advancing the research of human factors in SE (e.g., bias in human-LLM conversations).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.05992v2</guid>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Amirali Sajadi, Kostadin Damevski, Preetha Chatterjee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DocAgent: A Multi-Agent System for Automated Code Documentation Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.08725</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.08725v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: High-quality code documentation is crucial for software development especially in the era of AI. However, generating it automatically using Large Language Models (LLMs) remains challenging, as existing approaches often produce incomplete, unhelpful, or factually incorrect outputs. We introduce DocAgent, a novel multi-agent collaborative system using topological code processing for incremental context building. Specialized agents (Reader, Searcher, Writer, Verifier, Orchestrator) then collaboratively generate documentation. We also propose a multi-faceted evaluation framework assessing Completeness, Helpfulness, and Truthfulness. Comprehensive experiments show DocAgent significantly outperforms baselines consistently. Our ablation study confirms the vital role of the topological processing order. DocAgent offers a robust approach for reliable code documentation generation in complex and proprietary repositories.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.08725v2</guid>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dayu Yang, Antoine Simoulin, Xin Qian, Xiaoyi Liu, Yuwei Cao, Zhaopu Teng, Grey Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing Judging Bias in Large Reasoning Models: An Empirical Study</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.09946</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.09946v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large Reasoning Models (LRMs) like DeepSeek-R1 and OpenAI-o1 have demonstrated remarkable reasoning capabilities, raising important questions about their biases in LLM-as-a-judge settings. We present a comprehensive benchmark comparing judging biases between LLMs and LRMs across both subjective preference-alignment datasets and objective fact-based datasets. Through investigation of bandwagon, authority, position, and distraction biases, we uncover four key findings: (1) despite their advanced reasoning capabilities, LRMs remain susceptible to the above biases; (2) LRMs demonstrate better robustness than LLMs specifically on fact-related datasets; (3) LRMs exhibit notable position bias, preferring options in later positions; and (4) we identify a novel "superficial reflection bias" where phrases mimicking reasoning (e.g., "wait, let me think...") significantly influence model judgments. To address these biases, we design and evaluate three mitigation strategies: specialized system prompts that reduce judging biases by up to 19\% in preference alignment datasets and 14\% in fact-related datasets, in-context learning that provides up to 27\% improvement on preference tasks but shows inconsistent results on factual tasks, and a self-reflection mechanism that reduces biases by up to 10\% in preference datasets and 16\% in fact-related datasets, with self-reflection proving particularly effective for LRMs. Our work provides crucial insights for developing more reliable LLM-as-a-Judge frameworks, especially as LRMs become increasingly deployed as automated judges.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.09946v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qian Wang, Zhanzhi Lou, Zhenheng Tang, Nuo Chen, Xuandong Zhao, Wenxuan Zhang, Dawn Song, Bingsheng He</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GUI-R1 : A Generalist R1-Style Vision-Language Action Model For GUI Agents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.10458</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.10458v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Existing efforts in building Graphical User Interface (GUI) agents largely rely on the training paradigm of supervised fine-tuning on Large Vision-Language Models (LVLMs). However, this approach not only demands extensive amounts of training data but also struggles to effectively understand GUI screenshots and generalize to unseen interfaces. The issue significantly limits its application in real-world scenarios, especially for high-level tasks. Inspired by Reinforcement Fine-Tuning (RFT) in large reasoning models (e.g., DeepSeek-R1), which efficiently enhances the problem-solving capabilities of large language models in real-world settings, we propose \name, the first reinforcement learning framework designed to enhance the GUI capabilities of LVLMs in high-level real-world task scenarios, through unified action space rule modeling. By leveraging a small amount of carefully curated high-quality data across multiple platforms (including Windows, Linux, MacOS, Android, and Web) and employing policy optimization algorithms such as Group Relative Policy Optimization (GRPO) to update the model, \name achieves superior performance using only 0.02\% of the data (3K vs. 13M) compared to previous state-of-the-art methods like OS-Atlas across eight benchmarks spanning three different platforms (mobile, desktop, and web). These results demonstrate the immense potential of reinforcement learning based on unified action space rule modeling in improving the execution capabilities of LVLMs for real-world GUI agent tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.10458v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Run Luo, Lu Wang, Wanwei He, Xiaobo Xia</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Matters: Multimodal Features for Affective Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.11460</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.11460v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In this study, we present our methodology for two tasks: the Emotional Mimicry Intensity (EMI) Estimation Challenge and the Behavioural Ambivalence/Hesitancy (BAH) Recognition Challenge, both conducted as part of the 8th Workshop and Competition on Affective &amp; Behavior Analysis in-the-wild. We utilize a Wav2Vec 2.0 model pre-trained on a large podcast dataset to extract various audio features, capturing both linguistic and paralinguistic information. Our approach incorporates a valence-arousal-dominance (VAD) module derived from Wav2Vec 2.0, a BERT text encoder, and a vision transformer (ViT) with predictions subsequently processed through a long short-term memory (LSTM) architecture or a convolution-like method for temporal modeling. We integrate the textual and visual modality into our analysis, recognizing that semantic content provides valuable contextual cues and underscoring that the meaning of speech often conveys more critical insights than its acoustic counterpart alone. Fusing in the vision modality helps in some cases to interpret the textual modality more precisely. This combined approach results in significant performance improvements, achieving in EMI $\rho_{\text{TEST}} = 0.706$ and in BAH $F1_{\text{TEST}} = 0.702$, securing first place in the EMI challenge and second place in the BAH challenge.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.11460v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tobias Hallmen, Robin-Nico Kampa, Fabian Deuser, Norbert Oswald, Elisabeth Andr\'e</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Language Model-Based Knowledge Graph System Construction for Sustainable Development Goals: An AI-Based Speculative Design Perspective</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.12309</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.12309v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: From 2000 to 2015, the UN's Millennium Development Goals guided global priorities. The subsequent Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) adopted a more dynamic approach, with annual indicator updates. As 2030 nears and progress lags, innovative acceleration strategies are critical. This study develops an AI-powered knowledge graph system to analyze SDG interconnections, discover potential new goals, and visualize them online. Using official SDG texts, Elsevier's keyword dataset, and 1,127 TED Talk transcripts (2020.01-2024.04), a pilot on 269 talks from 2023 applies AI-speculative design, large language models, and retrieval-augmented generation. Key findings include: (1) Heatmap analysis reveals strong associations between Goal 10 and Goal 16, and minimal coverage of Goal 6. (2) In the knowledge graph, simulated dialogue over time reveals new central nodes, showing how richer data supports divergent thinking and goal clarity. (3) Six potential new goals are proposed, centered on equity, resilience, and technology-driven inclusion. This speculative-AI framework offers fresh insights for policymakers and lays groundwork for future multimodal and cross-system SDG applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.12309v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yi-De Lin, Guan-Ze Liao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EmoVoice: LLM-based Emotional Text-To-Speech Model with Freestyle Text Prompting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.12867</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.12867v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Human speech goes beyond the mere transfer of information; it is a profound exchange of emotions and a connection between individuals. While Text-to-Speech (TTS) models have made huge progress, they still face challenges in controlling the emotional expression in the generated speech. In this work, we propose EmoVoice, a novel emotion-controllable TTS model that exploits large language models (LLMs) to enable fine-grained freestyle natural language emotion control, and a phoneme boost variant design that makes the model output phoneme tokens and audio tokens in parallel to enhance content consistency, inspired by chain-of-thought (CoT) and chain-of-modality (CoM) techniques. Besides, we introduce EmoVoice-DB, a high-quality 40-hour English emotion dataset featuring expressive speech and fine-grained emotion labels with natural language descriptions. EmoVoice achieves state-of-the-art performance on the English EmoVoice-DB test set using only synthetic training data, and on the Chinese Secap test set using our in-house data. We further investigate the reliability of existing emotion evaluation metrics and their alignment with human perceptual preferences, and explore using SOTA multimodal LLMs GPT-4o-audio and Gemini to assess emotional speech. Demo samples are available at https://anonymous.4open.science/r/EmoVoice-DF55. Dataset, code, and checkpoints will be released.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.12867v2</guid>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Guanrou Yang, Chen Yang, Qian Chen, Ziyang Ma, Wenxi Chen, Wen Wang, Tianrui Wang, Yifan Yang, Zhikang Niu, Wenrui Liu, Fan Yu, Zhihao Du, Zhifu Gao, ShiLiang Zhang, Xie Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
