<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL</link>
    <description>cs.CL updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 01:20:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Sunday</day>
      <day>Saturday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>From Image Captioning to Visual Storytelling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14045</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14045v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Visual Storytelling is a challenging multimodal task between Vision &amp; Language, where the purpose is to generate a story for a stream of images. Its difficulty lies on the fact that the story should be both grounded to the image sequence but also narrative and coherent. The aim of this work is to balance between these aspects, by treating Visual Storytelling as a superset of Image Captioning, an approach quite different compared to most of prior relevant studies. This means that we firstly employ a vision-to-language model for obtaining captions of the input images, and then, these captions are transformed into coherent narratives using language-to-language methods. Our multifarious evaluation shows that integrating captioning and storytelling under a unified framework, has a positive impact on the quality of the produced stories. In addition, compared to numerous previous studies, this approach accelerates training time and makes our framework readily reusable and reproducible by anyone interested. Lastly, we propose a new metric/tool, named ideality, that can be used to simulate how far some results are from an oracle model, and we apply it to emulate human-likeness in visual storytelling.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14045v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Admitos Passadakis, Yingjin Song, Albert Gatt</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking Sociolinguistic Diversity in Swahili NLP: A Taxonomy-Guided Approach</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14051</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14051v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We introduce the first taxonomy-guided evaluation of Swahili NLP, addressing gaps in sociolinguistic diversity. Drawing on health-related psychometric tasks, we collect a dataset of 2,170 free-text responses from Kenyan speakers. The data exhibits tribal influences, urban vernacular, code-mixing, and loanwords. We develop a structured taxonomy and use it as a lens for examining model prediction errors across pre-trained and instruction-tuned language models. Our findings advance culturally grounded evaluation frameworks and highlight the role of sociolinguistic variation in shaping model performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14051v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kezia Oketch, John P. Lalor, Ahmed Abbasi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contrastive Analysis of Constituent Order Preferences Within Adverbial Roles in English and Chinese News: A Large-Language-Model-Driven Approach</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14054</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14054v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Based on comparable English-Chinese news corpora annotated by Large Language Model (LLM), this paper attempts to explore the differences in constituent order of English-Chinese news from the perspective of functional chunks with adverbial roles, and analyze their typical positional preferences and distribution patterns. It is found that: (1) English news prefers linear narrative of core information first, and functional chunks are mostly post-positioned, while Chinese news prefers overall presentation mode of background first, and functional chunks are often pre-positioned; (2) In SVO structure, both English and Chinese news show differences in the distribution of functional chunks, but the tendency of Chinese pre-positioning is more significant, while that of English post-positioning is relatively mild; (3) When function blocks are co-occurring, both English and Chinese news show high flexibility, and the order adjustment is driven by information and pragmatic purposes. The study reveals that word order has both systematic preference and dynamic adaptability, providing new empirical support for contrastive study of English-Chinese information structure.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14054v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yiran Rex Ma</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>T-REX: Table -- Refute or Entail eXplainer</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14055</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14055v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Verifying textual claims against structured tabular data is a critical yet challenging task in Natural Language Processing with broad real-world impact. While recent advances in Large Language Models (LLMs) have enabled significant progress in table fact-checking, current solutions remain inaccessible to non-experts. We introduce T-REX (T-REX: Table -- Refute or Entail eXplainer), the first live, interactive tool for claim verification over multimodal, multilingual tables using state-of-the-art instruction-tuned reasoning LLMs. Designed for accuracy and transparency, T-REX empowers non-experts by providing access to advanced fact-checking technology. The system is openly available online.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14055v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tim Luka Horstmann, Baptiste Geisenberger, Mehwish Alam</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confidence Estimation for Text-to-SQL in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14056</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14056v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Confidence estimation for text-to-SQL aims to assess the reliability of model-generated SQL queries without having access to gold answers. We study this problem in the context of large language models (LLMs), where access to model weights and gradients is often constrained. We explore both black-box and white-box confidence estimation strategies, evaluating their effectiveness on cross-domain text-to-SQL benchmarks. Our evaluation highlights the superior performance of consistency-based methods among black-box models and the advantage of SQL-syntax-aware approaches for interpreting LLM logits in white-box settings. Furthermore, we show that execution-based grounding of queries provides a valuable supplementary signal, improving the effectiveness of both approaches.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14056v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.DB</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sepideh Entezari Maleki, Mohammadreza Pourreza, Davood Rafiei</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing and Mitigating Data Memorization Risks in Fine-Tuned Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14062</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14062v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated remarkable capabilities across diverse natural language processing tasks, but their tendency to memorize training data poses significant privacy risks, particularly during fine-tuning processes. This paper presents a comprehensive empirical analysis of data memorization in fine-tuned LLMs and introduces a novel multi-layered privacy protection framework. Through controlled experiments on modern LLM architectures including GPT-2, Phi-3, and Gemma-2, we demonstrate that fine-tuning with repeated sensitive data increases privacy leakage rates from baseline levels of 0-5% to 60-75%, representing a 64.2% average increase across tested models. We propose and rigorously evaluate four complementary privacy protection methods: semantic data deduplication, differential privacy during generation, entropy-based filtering, and pattern-based content filtering. Our experimental results show that these techniques can reduce data leakage to 0% while maintaining 94.7% of original model utility.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14062v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Badrinath Ramakrishnan, Akshaya Balaji</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Punctuation and Predicates in Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14067</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14067v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this paper we explore where information is collected and how it is propagated throughout layers in large language models (LLMs). We begin by examining the surprising computational importance of punctuation tokens which previous work has identified as attention sinks and memory aids. Using intervention-based techniques, we evaluate the necessity and sufficiency (for preserving model performance) of punctuation tokens across layers in GPT-2, DeepSeek, and Gemma. Our results show stark model-specific differences: for GPT-2, punctuation is both necessary and sufficient in multiple layers, while this holds far less in DeepSeek and not at all in Gemma. Extending beyond punctuation, we ask whether LLMs process different components of input (e.g., subjects, adjectives, punctuation, full sentences) by forming early static summaries reused across the network, or if the model remains sensitive to changes in these components across layers. Extending beyond punctuation, we investigate whether different reasoning rules are processed differently by LLMs. In particular, through interchange intervention and layer-swapping experiments, we find that conditional statements (if, then), and universal quantification (for all) are processed very differently. Our findings offer new insight into the internal mechanisms of punctuation usage and reasoning in LLMs and have implications for interpretability.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14067v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sonakshi Chauhan, Maheep Chaudhary, Koby Choy, Samuel Nellessen, Nandi Schoots</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DLLMQuant: Quantizing Diffusion-based Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14090</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14090v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Diffusion-based large language models (DLLMs) have shown promise for non-autoregressive text generation, but their deployment is constrained by large model sizes and heavy computational costs. Post-training quantization (PTQ), a widely used method for compressing and accelerating Large Language Models (LLMs), suffers from severe accuracy degradation and reduced generalization performance when directly applied to DLLMs (e.g., AWQ suffers a 16% accuracy drop on LLADA under W4A4). This paper explores how DLLMs' key mechanisms - dynamic masking, iterative generation, bidirectional attention - clash with quantization. We identify three core issues: 1) Iterative generation and dynamic masking ratios lead to distinct token distributions across decoding steps, which are not adequately captured by existing PTQ calibration methods; 2) Quantization errors are accumulated and amplified progressively during iteration in DLLMs, causing quantized models to perform worse as decoding steps progress; 3) Unmasked tokens stabilize while masked remain probabilistic, making overall feature distribution incompatible with existing PTQ methods. To address these issues, we propose DLLMQuant, a PTQ framework tailored for DLLMs, which incorporates three novel techniques: 1) Temporal-Mask Adaptive Sampling (TMAS), a calibration method that accounts for both time and mask factors, with the capacity to capture distributions across timesteps. 2) Interaction-Aware Activation Quantization (IA-AQ), which utilizes bidirectional attention's interaction signals to dynamically allocate quantization resources. 3) Certainty-Guided Quantization (CGQ), which integrates mask status and token scores as key weighting criteria into error compensation, making weight quantization more suitable for DLLMs. Experiments show that DLLMQuant achieves significant performance gains while enhancing efficiency.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14090v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chen Xu, Dawei Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MMReview: A Multidisciplinary and Multimodal Benchmark for LLM-Based Peer Review Automation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14146</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14146v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: With the rapid growth of academic publications, peer review has become an essential yet time-consuming responsibility within the research community. Large Language Models (LLMs) have increasingly been adopted to assist in the generation of review comments; however, current LLM-based review tasks lack a unified evaluation benchmark to rigorously assess the models' ability to produce comprehensive, accurate, and human-aligned assessments, particularly in scenarios involving multimodal content such as figures and tables. To address this gap, we propose \textbf{MMReview}, a comprehensive benchmark that spans multiple disciplines and modalities. MMReview includes multimodal content and expert-written review comments for 240 papers across 17 research domains within four major academic disciplines: Artificial Intelligence, Natural Sciences, Engineering Sciences, and Social Sciences. We design a total of 13 tasks grouped into four core categories, aimed at evaluating the performance of LLMs and Multimodal LLMs (MLLMs) in step-wise review generation, outcome formulation, alignment with human preferences, and robustness to adversarial input manipulation. Extensive experiments conducted on 16 open-source models and 5 advanced closed-source models demonstrate the thoroughness of the benchmark. We envision MMReview as a critical step toward establishing a standardized foundation for the development of automated peer review systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14146v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xian Gao, Jiacheng Ruan, Zongyun Zhang, Jingsheng Gao, Ting Liu, Yuzhuo Fu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DPad: Efficient Diffusion Language Models with Suffix Dropout</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14148</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14148v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Diffusion-based Large Language Models (dLLMs) parallelize text generation by framing decoding as a denoising process, but suffer from high computational overhead since they predict all future suffix tokens at each step while retaining only a small fraction. We propose Diffusion Scratchpad (DPad), a training-free method that restricts attention to a small set of nearby suffix tokens, preserving fidelity while eliminating redundancy. DPad integrates two strategies: (i) a sliding window, which maintains a fixed-length suffix window, and (ii) distance-decay dropout, which deterministically removes distant suffix tokens before attention computation. This simple design is compatible with existing optimizations such as prefix caching and can be implemented with only a few lines of code. Comprehensive evaluations across multiple benchmarks on LLaDA-1.5 and Dream models demonstrate that DPad delivers up to $\mathbf{61.4\times}$ speedup over vanilla dLLMs while maintaining comparable accuracy, highlighting its potential for efficient and scalable long-sequence inference. Our code is available at https://github.com/Crys-Chen/DPad.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14148v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xinhua Chen, Sitao Huang, Cong Guo, Chiyue Wei, Yintao He, Jianyi Zhang, Hai "Hellen" Li, Yiran Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparing energy consumption and accuracy in text classification inference</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14170</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14170v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The increasing deployment of large language models (LLMs) in natural language processing (NLP) tasks raises concerns about energy efficiency and sustainability. While prior research has largely focused on energy consumption during model training, the inference phase has received comparatively less attention. This study systematically evaluates the trade-offs between model accuracy and energy consumption in text classification inference across various model architectures and hardware configurations. Our empirical analysis shows that the best-performing model in terms of accuracy can also be energy-efficient, while larger LLMs tend to consume significantly more energy with lower classification accuracy. We observe substantial variability in inference energy consumption ($&lt;$mWh to $&gt;$kWh), influenced by model type, model size, and hardware specifications. Additionally, we find a strong correlation between inference energy consumption and model runtime, indicating that execution time can serve as a practical proxy for energy usage in settings where direct measurement is not feasible. These findings have implications for sustainable AI development, providing actionable insights for researchers, industry practitioners, and policymakers seeking to balance performance and resource efficiency in NLP applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14170v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Johannes Zschache, Tilman Hartwig</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let's Use ChatGPT To Write Our Paper! Benchmarking LLMs To Write the Introduction of a Research Paper</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14273</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14273v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: As researchers increasingly adopt LLMs as writing assistants, generating high-quality research paper introductions remains both challenging and essential. We introduce Scientific Introduction Generation (SciIG), a task that evaluates LLMs' ability to produce coherent introductions from titles, abstracts, and related works. Curating new datasets from NAACL 2025 and ICLR 2025 papers, we assess five state-of-the-art models, including both open-source (DeepSeek-v3, Gemma-3-12B, LLaMA 4-Maverick, MistralAI Small 3.1) and closed-source GPT-4o systems, across multiple dimensions: lexical overlap, semantic similarity, content coverage, faithfulness, consistency, citation correctness, and narrative quality. Our comprehensive framework combines automated metrics with LLM-as-a-judge evaluations. Results demonstrate LLaMA-4 Maverick's superior performance on most metrics, particularly in semantic similarity and faithfulness. Moreover, three-shot prompting consistently outperforms fewer-shot approaches. These findings provide practical insights into developing effective research writing assistants and set realistic expectations for LLM-assisted academic writing. To foster reproducibility and future research, we will publicly release all code and datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14273v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Krishna Garg, Firoz Shaikh, Sambaran Bandyopadhyay, Cornelia Caragea</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disentangling concept semantics via multilingual averaging in Sparse Autoencoders</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14275</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14275v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Connecting LLMs with formal knowledge representation and reasoning is a promising approach to address their shortcomings. Embeddings and sparse autoencoders are widely used to represent textual content, but the semantics are entangled with syntactic and language-specific information. We propose a method that isolates concept semantics in Large Langue Models by averaging concept activations derived via Sparse Autoencoders. We create English text representations from OWL ontology classes, translate the English into French and Chinese and then pass these texts as prompts to the Gemma 2B LLM. Using the open source Gemma Scope suite of Sparse Autoencoders, we obtain concept activations for each class and language version. We average the different language activations to derive a conceptual average. We then correlate the conceptual averages with a ground truth mapping between ontology classes. Our results give a strong indication that the conceptual average aligns to the true relationship between classes when compared with a single language by itself. The result hints at a new technique which enables mechanistic interpretation of internal network states with higher accuracy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14275v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Cliff O'Reilly, Ernesto Jimenez-Ruiz, Tillman Weyde</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GRILE: A Benchmark for Grammar Reasoning and Explanation in Romanian LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14279</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14279v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: LLMs (Large language models) have revolutionized NLP (Natural Language Processing), yet their pedagogical value for low-resource languages remains unclear. We present GRILE (Grammar Romanian Inference and Language Explanations) , the first open benchmark of 1,151 multiple-choice questions harvested from Romanian high-stakes exams (National Evaluation, Baccalaureate, university admissions). GRILE enables us to probe two complementary abilities of seven state-of-the-art multilingual and Romanian-specific LLMs: (i) selecting the correct answer, and (ii) producing linguistically accurate explanations. While Gemini 2.5 Pro reaches 83% accuracy, most open-weight models stay below 65%, and 48% of their explanations contain factual or pedagogical flaws according to expert review. A detailed error analysis pinpoints systematic weaknesses in morphology and in applying the latest DOOM3 orthographic norms. All data, code and a public web demo are released to catalyze future research. Our findings expose open challenges for trustworthy educational NLP in low-resource settings and establish GRILE as a new test-bed for controllable explanation generation and evaluation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14279v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Adrian-Marius Dumitran, Alexandra-Mihaela Danila, Angela-Liliana Dumitran</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tokens with Meaning: A Hybrid Tokenization Approach for NLP</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14292</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14292v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Tokenization plays a pivotal role in natural language processing (NLP), shaping how text is segmented and interpreted by language models. While subword methods such as Byte Pair Encoding (BPE) and WordPiece have been effective, they often struggle with morphologically rich and agglutinative languages because they rely on frequency rather than linguistic structure. We introduce a hybrid tokenization framework that combines rule-based morphological analysis with statistical subword segmentation. The method uses phonological normalization, root-affix dictionaries, and a novel algorithm that balances morpheme preservation with vocabulary efficiency. It assigns shared identifiers to phonologically variant affixes (e.g., -ler and -lar) and altered root forms (e.g., kitap vs. kitab{\i}), reducing redundancy while maintaining semantic integrity. Special tokens are added for whitespace and case, including an UPPERCASE marker to avoid vocabulary inflation from capitalization. BPE is integrated for out-of-vocabulary coverage without harming morphological coherence. On the TR-MMLU benchmark, the tokenizer achieves the highest Turkish Token Percentage (90.29\%) and Pure Token Percentage (85.8\%). Comparisons with tokenizers from LLaMA, Gemma, and GPT show more linguistically meaningful and coherent tokens. Although demonstrated on Turkish, the approach is language-independent and adaptable to other languages, offering a practical path toward more interpretable and effective multilingual NLP systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14292v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>M. Ali Bayram, Ali Arda Fincan, Ahmet Semih G\"um\"u\c{s}, Sercan Karaka\c{s}, Banu Diri, Sava\c{s} Y{\i}ld{\i}r{\i}m, Demircan \c{C}elik</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Joint Multitask Model for Morpho-Syntactic Parsing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14307</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14307v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present a joint multitask model for the UniDive 2025 Morpho-Syntactic Parsing shared task, where systems predict both morphological and syntactic analyses following novel UD annotation scheme. Our system uses a shared XLM-RoBERTa encoder with three specialized decoders for content word identification, dependency parsing, and morphosyntactic feature prediction. Our model achieves the best overall performance on the shared task's leaderboard covering nine typologically diverse languages, with an average MSLAS score of 78.7 percent, LAS of 80.1 percent, and Feats F1 of 90.3 percent. Our ablation studies show that matching the task's gold tokenization and content word identification are crucial to model performance. Error analysis reveals that our model struggles with core grammatical cases (particularly Nom-Acc) and nominal features across languages.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14307v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Demian Inostroza, Mel Mistica, Ekaterina Vylomova, Chris Guest, Kemal Kurniawan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zero-knowledge LLM hallucination detection and mitigation through fine-grained cross-model consistency</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14314</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14314v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated impressive capabilities across diverse tasks, but they remain susceptible to hallucinations--generating content that appears plausible but contains factual inaccuracies. We present Finch-Zk, a black-box framework that leverages FINe-grained Cross-model consistency to detect and mitigate Hallucinations in LLM outputs without requiring external knowledge sources. Finch-Zk introduces two key innovations: 1) a cross-model consistency checking strategy that reveals fine-grained inaccuracies by comparing responses generated by diverse models from semantically-equivalent prompts, and 2) a targeted mitigation technique that applies precise corrections to problematic segments while preserving accurate content. Experiments on the FELM dataset show Finch-Zk improves hallucination detection F1 scores by 6-39\% compared to existing approaches. For mitigation, Finch-Zk achieves 7-8 absolute percentage points improvement in answer accuracy on the GPQA-diamond dataset when applied to state-of-the-art models like Llama 4 Maverick and Claude 4 Sonnet. Extensive evaluation across multiple models demonstrates that Finch-Zk provides a practical, deployment-ready safeguard for enhancing factual reliability in production LLM systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14314v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aman Goel, Daniel Schwartz, Yanjun Qi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SurveyGen-I: Consistent Scientific Survey Generation with Evolving Plans and Memory-Guided Writing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14317</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14317v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Survey papers play a critical role in scientific communication by consolidating progress across a field. Recent advances in Large Language Models (LLMs) offer a promising solution by automating key steps in the survey-generation pipeline, such as retrieval, structuring, and summarization. However, existing LLM-based approaches often struggle with maintaining coherence across long, multi-section surveys and providing comprehensive citation coverage. To address these limitations, we introduce SurveyGen-I, an automatic survey generation framework that combines coarse-to-fine retrieval, adaptive planning, and memory-guided generation. SurveyGen-I first performs survey-level retrieval to construct the initial outline and writing plan, and then dynamically refines both during generation through a memory mechanism that stores previously written content and terminology, ensuring coherence across subsections. When the system detects insufficient context, it triggers fine-grained subsection-level retrieval. During generation, SurveyGen-I leverages this memory mechanism to maintain coherence across subsections. Experiments across four scientific domains demonstrate that SurveyGen-I consistently outperforms previous works in content quality, consistency, and citation coverage.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14317v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jing Chen, Zhiheng Yang, Yixian Shen, Jie Liu, Adam Belloum, Chrysa Papagainni, Paola Grosso</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Semantic Similarity: Reducing Unnecessary API Calls via Behavior-Aligned Retriever</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14323</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14323v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Tool-augmented large language models (LLMs) leverage external functions to extend their capabilities, but inaccurate function calls can lead to inefficiencies and increased costs.Existing methods address this challenge by fine-tuning LLMs or using demonstration-based prompting, yet they often suffer from high training overhead and fail to account for inconsistent demonstration samples, which misguide the model's invocation behavior. In this paper, we trained a behavior-aligned retriever (BAR), which provides behaviorally consistent demonstrations to help LLMs make more accurate tool-using decisions. To train the BAR, we construct a corpus including different function-calling behaviors, i.e., calling or non-calling.We use the contrastive learning framework to train the BAR with customized positive/negative pairs and a dual-negative contrastive loss, ensuring robust retrieval of behaviorally consistent examples.Experiments demonstrate that our approach significantly reduces erroneous function calls while maintaining high task performance, offering a cost-effective and efficient solution for tool-augmented LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14323v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yixin Chen, Ying Xiong, Shangyu Wu, Yufei Cui, Xue Liu, Nan Guan, Chun Jason Xue</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ISCA: A Framework for Interview-Style Conversational Agents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14344</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14344v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present a low-compute non-generative system for implementing interview-style conversational agents which can be used to facilitate qualitative data collection through controlled interactions and quantitative analysis. Use cases include applications to tracking attitude formation or behavior change, where control or standardization over the conversational flow is desired. We show how our system can be easily adjusted through an online administrative panel to create new interviews, making the tool accessible without coding. Two case studies are presented as example applications, one regarding the Expressive Interviewing system for COVID-19 and the other a semi-structured interview to survey public opinion on emerging neurotechnology. Our code is open-source, allowing others to build off of our work and develop extensions for additional functionality.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14344v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Charles Welch, Allison Lahnala, Vasudha Varadarajan, Lucie Flek, Rada Mihalcea, J. Lomax Boyd, Jo\~ao Sedoc</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ZPD-SCA: Unveiling the Blind Spots of LLMs in Assessing Students' Cognitive Abilities</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14377</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14377v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated potential in educational applications, yet their capacity to accurately assess the cognitive alignment of reading materials with students' developmental stages remains insufficiently explored. This gap is particularly critical given the foundational educational principle of the Zone of Proximal Development (ZPD), which emphasizes the need to match learning resources with Students' Cognitive Abilities (SCA). Despite the importance of this alignment, there is a notable absence of comprehensive studies investigating LLMs' ability to evaluate reading comprehension difficulty across different student age groups, especially in the context of Chinese language education. To fill this gap, we introduce ZPD-SCA, a novel benchmark specifically designed to assess stage-level Chinese reading comprehension difficulty. The benchmark is annotated by 60 Special Grade teachers, a group that represents the top 0.15% of all in-service teachers nationwide. Experimental results reveal that LLMs perform poorly in zero-shot learning scenarios, with Qwen-max and GLM even falling below the probability of random guessing. When provided with in-context examples, LLMs performance improves substantially, with some models achieving nearly double the accuracy of their zero-shot baselines. These results reveal that LLMs possess emerging abilities to assess reading difficulty, while also exposing limitations in their current training for educationally aligned judgment. Notably, even the best-performing models display systematic directional biases, suggesting difficulties in accurately aligning material difficulty with SCA. Furthermore, significant variations in model performance across different genres underscore the complexity of task. We envision that ZPD-SCA can provide a foundation for evaluating and improving LLMs in cognitively aligned educational applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14377v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenhan Dong, Zhen Sun, Yuemeng Zhao, Zifan Peng, Jun Wu, Jingyi Zheng, Yule Liu, Xinlei He, Yu Wang, Ruiming Wang, Xinyi Huang, Lei Mo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Credence Calibration Game? Calibrating Large Language Models through Structured Play</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14390</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14390v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: As Large Language Models (LLMs) are increasingly deployed in decision-critical domains, it becomes essential to ensure that their confidence estimates faithfully correspond to their actual correctness. Existing calibration methods have primarily focused on post-hoc adjustments or auxiliary model training; however, many of these approaches necessitate additional supervision or parameter updates. In this work, we propose a novel prompt-based calibration framework inspired by the Credence Calibration Game. Our method establishes a structured interaction loop wherein LLMs receive feedback based on the alignment of their predicted confidence with correctness. Through feedback-driven prompting and natural language summaries of prior performance, our framework dynamically improves model calibration. Extensive experiments across models and game configurations demonstrate consistent improvements in evaluation metrics. Our results highlight the potential of game-based prompting as an effective strategy for LLM calibration. Code and data are available at https://anonymous.4open.science/r/LLM-Calibration/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14390v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ke Fang, Tianyi Zhao, Lu Cheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DEPTH: Hallucination-Free Relation Extraction via Dependency-Aware Sentence Simplification and Two-tiered Hierarchical Refinement</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14391</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14391v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Relation extraction enables the construction of structured knowledge for many downstream applications. While large language models (LLMs) have shown great promise in this domain, most existing methods concentrate on relation classification, which predicts the semantic relation type between a related entity pair. However, we observe that LLMs often struggle to reliably determine whether a relation exists, especially in cases involving complex sentence structures or intricate semantics, which leads to spurious predictions. Such hallucinations can introduce noisy edges in knowledge graphs, compromising the integrity of structured knowledge and downstream reliability. To address these challenges, we propose DEPTH, a framework that integrates Dependency-aware sEntence simPlification and Two-tiered Hierarchical refinement into the relation extraction pipeline. Given a sentence and its candidate entity pairs, DEPTH operates in two stages: (1) the Grounding module extracts relations for each pair by leveraging their shortest dependency path, distilling the sentence into a minimal yet coherent relational context that reduces syntactic noise while preserving key semantics; (2) the Refinement module aggregates all local predictions and revises them based on a holistic understanding of the sentence, correcting omissions and inconsistencies. We further introduce a causality-driven reward model that mitigates reward hacking by disentangling spurious correlations, enabling robust fine-tuning via reinforcement learning with human feedback. Experiments on six benchmarks demonstrate that DEPTH reduces the average hallucination rate to 7.0\% while achieving a 17.2\% improvement in average F1 score over state-of-the-art baselines.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14391v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yupei Yang, Fan Feng, Lin Yang, Wanxi Deng, Lin Qu, Biwei Huang, Shikui Tu, Lei Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cognitive Surgery: The Awakening of Implicit Territorial Awareness in LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14408</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14408v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have been shown to possess a degree of self-recognition capability-the ability to identify whether a given text was generated by themselves. Prior work has demonstrated that this capability is reliably expressed under the Pair Presentation Paradigm (PPP), where the model is presented with two texts and asked to choose which one it authored. However, performance deteriorates sharply under the Individual Presentation Paradigm (IPP), where the model is given a single text to judge authorship. Although this phenomenon has been observed, its underlying causes have not been systematically analyzed. In this paper, we first replicate existing findings to confirm that LLMs struggle to distinguish self- from other-generated text under IPP. We then investigate the reasons for this failure and attribute it to a phenomenon we term Implicit Territorial Awareness (ITA)-the model's latent ability to distinguish self- and other-texts in representational space, which remains unexpressed in its output behavior. To awaken the ITA of LLMs, we propose Cognitive Surgery (CoSur), a novel framework comprising four main modules: representation extraction, territory construction, authorship discrimination and cognitive editing. Experimental results demonstrate that our proposed method improves the performance of three different LLMs in the IPP scenario, achieving average accuracies of 83.25%, 66.19%, and 88.01%, respectively.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14408v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yinghan Zhou, Weifeng Zhu, Juan Wen, Wanli Peng, Zhengxian Wu, Yiming Xue</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Graph-Infused Fine-Tuning for Structured Reasoning in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14427</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14427v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper addresses the problems of missing reasoning chains and insufficient entity-level semantic understanding in large language models when dealing with tasks that require structured knowledge. It proposes a fine-tuning algorithm framework based on knowledge graph injection. The method builds on pretrained language models and introduces structured graph information for auxiliary learning. A graph neural network is used to encode entities and their relations, constructing a graph-based semantic representation. A fusion mechanism is then designed to jointly model the knowledge graph embeddings with the contextual representations from the language model. To enhance the robustness of knowledge integration, a gating mechanism is introduced to dynamically balance the contributions of linguistic semantics and structural knowledge. This effectively mitigates conflicts between different representational spaces. During training, a joint loss function is constructed to account for both task performance and structural alignment objectives. This helps improve the accuracy of entity prediction and semantic reasoning. The study also includes a series of systematic sensitivity experiments. It evaluates the effects of learning rate, graph coverage, and structural perturbations on model performance. The results further validate the effectiveness and stability of the proposed method across tasks such as entity recognition, question answering, and language generation. Experimental findings show that the proposed structure-aware fine-tuning framework significantly enhances the model's ability to represent complex semantic units. It demonstrates better semantic consistency and contextual logic modeling in scenarios involving structural reasoning and entity extraction.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14427v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wuyang Zhang, Yexin Tian, Xiandong Meng, Mengjie Wang, Junliang Du</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NVIDIA Nemotron Nano 2: An Accurate and Efficient Hybrid Mamba-Transformer Reasoning Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14444</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14444v2 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We introduce Nemotron-Nano-9B-v2, a hybrid Mamba-Transformer language model designed to increase throughput for reasoning workloads while achieving state-of-the-art accuracy compared to similarly-sized models. Nemotron-Nano-9B-v2 builds on the Nemotron-H architecture, in which the majority of the self-attention layers in the common Transformer architecture are replaced with Mamba-2 layers, to achieve improved inference speed when generating the long thinking traces needed for reasoning. We create Nemotron-Nano-9B-v2 by first pre-training a 12-billion-parameter model (Nemotron-Nano-12B-v2-Base) on 20 trillion tokens using an FP8 training recipe. After aligning Nemotron-Nano-12B-v2-Base, we employ the Minitron strategy to compress and distill the model with the goal of enabling inference on up to 128k tokens on a single NVIDIA A10G GPU (22GiB of memory, bfloat16 precision). Compared to existing similarly-sized models (e.g., Qwen3-8B), we show that Nemotron-Nano-9B-v2 achieves on-par or better accuracy on reasoning benchmarks while achieving up to 6x higher inference throughput in reasoning settings like 8k input and 16k output tokens. We are releasing Nemotron-Nano-9B-v2, Nemotron-Nano12B-v2-Base, and Nemotron-Nano-9B-v2-Base checkpoints along with the majority of our pre- and post-training datasets on Hugging Face.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14444v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator> NVIDIA,  :, Aarti Basant, Abhijit Khairnar, Abhijit Paithankar, Abhinav Khattar, Adithya Renduchintala, Aditya Malte, Akhiad Bercovich, Akshay Hazare, Alejandra Rico, Aleksander Ficek, Alex Kondratenko, Alex Shaposhnikov, Alexander Bukharin, Ali Taghibakhshi, Amelia Barton, Ameya Sunil Mahabaleshwarkar, Amy Shen, Andrew Tao, Ann Guan, Anna Shors, Anubhav Mandarwal, Arham Mehta, Arun Venkatesan, Ashton Sharabiani, Ashwath Aithal, Ashwin Poojary, Ayush Dattagupta, Balaram Buddharaju, Banghua Zhu, Barnaby Simkin, Bilal Kartal, Bita Darvish Rouhani, Bobby Chen, Boris Ginsburg, Brandon Norick, Brian Yu, Bryan Catanzaro, Charles Wang, Charlie Truong, Chetan Mungekar, Chintan Patel, Chris Alexiuk, Christian Munley, Christopher Parisien, Dan Su, Daniel Afrimi, Daniel Korzekwa, Daniel Rohrer, Daria Gitman, David Mosallanezhad, Deepak Narayanan, Dima Rekesh, Dina Yared, Dmytro Pykhtar, Dong Ahn, Duncan Riach, Eileen Long, Elliott Ning, Eric Chung, Erick Galinkin, Evelina Bakhturina, Gargi Prasad, Gerald Shen, Haifeng Qian, Haim Elisha, Harsh Sharma, Hayley Ross, Helen Ngo, Herman Sahota, Hexin Wang, Hoo Chang Shin, Hua Huang, Iain Cunningham, Igor Gitman, Ivan Moshkov, Jaehun Jung, Jan Kautz, Jane Polak Scowcroft, Jared Casper, Jian Zhang, Jiaqi Zeng, Jimmy Zhang, Jinze Xue, Jocelyn Huang, Joey Conway, John Kamalu, Jonathan Cohen, Joseph Jennings, Julien Veron Vialard, Junkeun Yi, Jupinder Parmar, Kari Briski, Katherine Cheung, Katherine Luna, Keith Wyss, Keshav Santhanam, Kezhi Kong, Krzysztof Pawelec, Kumar Anik, Kunlun Li, Kushan Ahmadian, Lawrence McAfee, Laya Sleiman, Leon Derczynski, Luis Vega, Maer Rodrigues de Melo, Makesh Narsimhan Sreedhar, Marcin Chochowski, Mark Cai, Markus Kliegl, Marta Stepniewska-Dziubinska, Matvei Novikov, Mehrzad Samadi, Meredith Price, Meriem Boubdir, Michael Boone, Michael Evans, Michal Bien, Michal Zawalski, Miguel Martinez, Mike Chrzanowski, Mohammad Shoeybi, Mostofa Patwary, Namit Dhameja, Nave Assaf, Negar Habibi, Nidhi Bhatia, Nikki Pope, Nima Tajbakhsh, Nirmal Kumar Juluru, Oleg Rybakov, Oleksii Hrinchuk, Oleksii Kuchaiev, Oluwatobi Olabiyi, Pablo Ribalta, Padmavathy Subramanian, Parth Chadha, Pavlo Molchanov, Peter Dykas, Peter Jin, Piotr Bialecki, Piotr Januszewski, Pradeep Thalasta, Prashant Gaikwad, Prasoon Varshney, Pritam Gundecha, Przemek Tredak, Rabeeh Karimi Mahabadi, Rajen Patel, Ran El-Yaniv, Ranjit Rajan, Ria Cheruvu, Rima Shahbazyan, Ritika Borkar, Ritu Gala, Roger Waleffe, Ruoxi Zhang, Russell J. Hewett, Ryan Prenger, Sahil Jain, Samuel Kriman, Sanjeev Satheesh, Saori Kaji, Sarah Yurick, Saurav Muralidharan, Sean Narenthiran, Seonmyeong Bak, Sepehr Sameni, Seungju Han, Shanmugam Ramasamy, Shaona Ghosh, Sharath Turuvekere Sreenivas, Shelby Thomas, Shizhe Diao, Shreya Gopal, Shrimai Prabhumoye, Shubham Toshniwal, Shuoyang Ding, Siddharth Singh, Siddhartha Jain, Somshubra Majumdar, Soumye Singhal, Stefania Alborghetti, Syeda Nahida Akter, Terry Kong, Tim Moon, Tomasz Hliwiak, Tomer Asida, Tony Wang, Tugrul Konuk, Twinkle Vashishth, Tyler Poon, Udi Karpas, Vahid Noroozi, Venkat Srinivasan, Vijay Korthikanti, Vikram Fugro, Vineeth Kalluru, Vitaly Kurin, Vitaly Lavrukhin, Wasi Uddin Ahmad, Wei Du, Wonmin Byeon, Ximing Lu, Xin Dong, Yashaswi Karnati, Yejin Choi, Yian Zhang, Ying Lin, Yonggan Fu, Yoshi Suhara, Zhen Dong, Zhiyu Li, Zhongbo Zhu, Zijia Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In2x at WMT25 Translation Task</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14472</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14472v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper presents the open-system submission by the In2x research team for the WMT25 General Machine Translation Shared Task. Our submission focuses on Japanese-related translation tasks, aiming to explore a generalizable paradigm for extending large language models (LLMs) to other languages. This paradigm encompasses aspects such as data construction methods and reward model design. The ultimate goal is to enable large language model systems to achieve exceptional performance in low-resource or less commonly spoken languages.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14472v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lei Pang, Hanyi Mao, Quanjia Xiao, HaiXiao Liu, Xiangyi Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reasoning is about giving reasons</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14488</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14488v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Convincing someone of the truth value of a premise requires understanding and articulating the core logical structure of the argument which proves or disproves the premise. Understanding the logical structure of an argument refers to understanding the underlying "reasons" which make up the proof or disproof of the premise - as a function of the "logical atoms" in the argument. While it has been shown that transformers can "chain" rules to derive simple arguments, the challenge of articulating the "reasons" remains. Not only do current approaches to chaining rules suffer in terms of their interpretability, they are also quite constrained in their ability to accommodate extensions to theoretically equivalent reasoning tasks - a model trained to chain rules cannot support abduction or identify contradictions. In this work we suggest addressing these shortcomings by identifying an intermediate representation (which we call the Representation of the Logical Structure (RLS) of the argument) that possesses an understanding of the logical structure of a natural language argument - the logical atoms in the argument and the rules incorporating them. Given the logical structure, reasoning is deterministic and easy to compute. Therefore, our approach supports all forms of reasoning that depend on the logical structure of the natural language argument, including arbitrary depths of reasoning, on-the-fly mistake rectification and interactive discussion with respect to an argument. We show that we can identify and extract the logical structure of natural language arguments in three popular reasoning datasets with high accuracies, thus supporting explanation generation and extending the reasoning capabilities significantly.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14488v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Krunal Shah, Dan Roth</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EmoTale: An Enacted Speech-emotion Dataset in Danish</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14548</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14548v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: While multiple emotional speech corpora exist for commonly spoken languages, there is a lack of functional datasets for smaller (spoken) languages, such as Danish. To our knowledge, Danish Emotional Speech (DES), published in 1997, is the only other database of Danish emotional speech. We present EmoTale; a corpus comprising Danish and English speech recordings with their associated enacted emotion annotations. We demonstrate the validity of the dataset by investigating and presenting its predictive power using speech emotion recognition (SER) models. We develop SER models for EmoTale and the reference datasets using self-supervised speech model (SSLM) embeddings and the openSMILE feature extractor. We find the embeddings superior to the hand-crafted features. The best model achieves an unweighted average recall (UAR) of 64.1% on the EmoTale corpus using leave-one-speaker-out cross-validation, comparable to the performance on DES.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14548v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Maja J. Hjuler, Harald V. Skat-R{\o}rdam, Line H. Clemmensen, Sneha Das</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Skeletal and Signer Noise Reduction in Sign Language Production via Quaternion-Based Pose Encoding and Contrastive Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14574</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14574v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: One of the main challenges in neural sign language production (SLP) lies in the high intra-class variability of signs, arising from signer morphology and stylistic variety in the training data. To improve robustness to such variations, we propose two enhancements to the standard Progressive Transformers (PT) architecture (Saunders et al., 2020). First, we encode poses using bone rotations in quaternion space and train with a geodesic loss to improve the accuracy and clarity of angular joint movements. Second, we introduce a contrastive loss to structure decoder embeddings by semantic similarity, using either gloss overlap or SBERT-based sentence similarity, aiming to filter out anatomical and stylistic features that do not convey relevant semantic information. On the Phoenix14T dataset, the contrastive loss alone yields a 16% improvement in Probability of Correct Keypoint over the PT baseline. When combined with quaternion-based pose encoding, the model achieves a 6% reduction in Mean Bone Angle Error. These results point to the benefit of incorporating skeletal structure modeling and semantically guided contrastive objectives on sign pose representations into the training of Transformer-based SLP models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14574v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>SLTAT 2025: 9th Workshop on Sign Language Translation and Avatar Technologies, Sep 2025, Berlin, Germany</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Guilhem Faur\'e (MULTISPEECH), Mostafa Sadeghi (MULTISPEECH), Sam Bigeard (MULTISPEECH), Slim Ouni (LORIA, MULTISPEECH)</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Filling the Gap for Uzbek: Creating Translation Resources for Southern Uzbek</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14586</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14586v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Southern Uzbek (uzs) is a Turkic language variety spoken by around 5 million people in Afghanistan and differs significantly from Northern Uzbek (uzn) in phonology, lexicon, and orthography. Despite the large number of speakers, Southern Uzbek is underrepresented in natural language processing. We present new resources for Southern Uzbek machine translation, including a 997-sentence FLORES+ dev set, 39,994 parallel sentences from dictionary, literary, and web sources, and a fine-tuned NLLB-200 model (lutfiy). We also propose a post-processing method for restoring Arabic-script half-space characters, which improves handling of morphological boundaries. All datasets, models, and tools are released publicly to support future work on Southern Uzbek and other low-resource languages.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14586v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mukhammadsaid Mamasaidov, Azizullah Aral, Abror Shopulatov, Mironshoh Inomjonov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continuous sentiment scores for literary and multilingual contexts</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14620</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14620v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Sentiment Analysis is widely used to quantify sentiment in text, but its application to literary texts poses unique challenges due to figurative language, stylistic ambiguity, as well as sentiment evocation strategies. Traditional dictionary-based tools often underperform, especially for low-resource languages, and transformer models, while promising, typically output coarse categorical labels that limit fine-grained analysis. We introduce a novel continuous sentiment scoring method based on concept vector projection, trained on multilingual literary data, which more effectively captures nuanced sentiment expressions across genres, languages, and historical periods. Our approach outperforms existing tools on English and Danish texts, producing sentiment scores whose distribution closely matches human ratings, enabling more accurate analysis and sentiment arc modeling in literature.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14620v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Laurits Lyngbaek, Pascale Feldkamp, Yuri Bizzoni, Kristoffer Nielbo, Kenneth Enevoldsen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving in-context learning with a better scoring function</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14685</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14685v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) exhibit a remarkable capacity to learn by analogy, known as in-context learning (ICL). However, recent studies have revealed limitations in this ability. In this paper, we examine these limitations on tasks involving first-order quantifiers such as {\em all} and {\em some}, as well as on ICL with linear functions. We identify Softmax, the scoring function in attention mechanism, as a contributing factor to these constraints. To address this, we propose \textbf{scaled signed averaging (SSA)}, a novel alternative to Softmax. Empirical results show that SSA dramatically improves performance on our target tasks. Furthermore, we evaluate both encoder-only and decoder-only transformers models with SSA, demonstrating that they match or exceed their Softmax-based counterparts across a variety of linguistic probing tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14685v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Omar Naim, Swarnadeep Bhar, J\'er\^ome Bolte, Nicholas Asher</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ShizhenGPT: Towards Multimodal LLMs for Traditional Chinese Medicine</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14706</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14706v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Despite the success of large language models (LLMs) in various domains, their potential in Traditional Chinese Medicine (TCM) remains largely underexplored due to two critical barriers: (1) the scarcity of high-quality TCM data and (2) the inherently multimodal nature of TCM diagnostics, which involve looking, listening, smelling, and pulse-taking. These sensory-rich modalities are beyond the scope of conventional LLMs. To address these challenges, we present ShizhenGPT, the first multimodal LLM tailored for TCM. To overcome data scarcity, we curate the largest TCM dataset to date, comprising 100GB+ of text and 200GB+ of multimodal data, including 1.2M images, 200 hours of audio, and physiological signals. ShizhenGPT is pretrained and instruction-tuned to achieve deep TCM knowledge and multimodal reasoning. For evaluation, we collect recent national TCM qualification exams and build a visual benchmark for Medicinal Recognition and Visual Diagnosis. Experiments demonstrate that ShizhenGPT outperforms comparable-scale LLMs and competes with larger proprietary models. Moreover, it leads in TCM visual understanding among existing multimodal LLMs and demonstrates unified perception across modalities like sound, pulse, smell, and vision, paving the way toward holistic multimodal perception and diagnosis in TCM. Datasets, models, and code are publicly available. We hope this work will inspire further exploration in this field.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14706v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junying Chen, Zhenyang Cai, Zhiheng Liu, Yunjin Yang, Rongsheng Wang, Qingying Xiao, Xiangyi Feng, Zhan Su, Jing Guo, Xiang Wan, Guangjun Yu, Haizhou Li, Benyou Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Digital Sous Chef -- A Comparative Study on Fine-Tuning Language Models for Recipe Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14718</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14718v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We established a rigorous benchmark for text-based recipe generation, a fundamental task in natural language generation. We present a comprehensive comparative study contrasting a fine-tuned GPT-2 large (774M) model against the GPT-2 small (124M) model and traditional LSTM/RNN baselines on the 5-cuisine corpus from RecipeDB. Our key contribution is a targeted tokenization strategy that augments the vocabulary with 23 common fraction tokens and custom structural markers. This approach addresses a critical limitation of generic tokenizers by preserving essential recipe structures and precise numerical quantities, thereby enhancing domain specificity. Performance is evaluated using a comprehensive suite of seven automatic metrics spanning fluency (BLEU-4, METEOR), coherence (ROUGE-L), semantic relevance (BERTScore), and diversity. Our experiments show that the large transformer-based approach yields a &gt;20% relative improvement in BERTScore (F1) (0.92 vs 0.72) over the best recurrent baseline, while reducing perplexity by 69.8%. We conclude with a discussion of remaining challenges, particularly regarding factual accuracy, and outline how this foundational study paves the way for integrating real-world constraints and multi-modal inputs in advanced recipe generation research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14718v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shubham Pundhir, Ganesh Bagler</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transplant Then Regenerate: A New Paradigm for Text Data Augmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14723</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14723v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Data augmentation is a critical technique in deep learning. Traditional methods like Back-translation typically focus on lexical-level rephrasing, which primarily produces variations with the same semantics. While large language models (LLMs) have enhanced text augmentation by their "knowledge emergence" capability, controlling the style and structure of these outputs remains challenging and requires meticulous prompt engineering. In this paper, we propose LMTransplant, a novel text augmentation paradigm leveraging LLMs. The core idea of LMTransplant is transplant-then-regenerate: incorporating seed text into a context expanded by LLM, and asking the LLM to regenerate a variant based on the expanded context. This strategy allows the model to create more diverse and creative content-level variants by fully leveraging the knowledge embedded in LLMs, while preserving the core attributes of the original text. We evaluate LMTransplant across various text-related tasks, demonstrating its superior performance over existing text augmentation methods. Moreover, LMTransplant demonstrates exceptional scalability as the size of augmented data grows.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14723v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Guangzhan Wang, Hongyu Zhang, Beijun Shen, Xiaodong Gu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Multilingual and Code-Switched Alignment in LLMs via Synthetic Natural Language Inference</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14735</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14735v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are increasingly applied in multilingual contexts, yet their capacity for consistent, logically grounded alignment across languages remains underexplored. We present a controlled evaluation framework for multilingual natural language inference (NLI) that generates synthetic, logic-based premise-hypothesis pairs and translates them into a typologically diverse set of languages. This design enables precise control over semantic relations and allows testing in both monolingual and mixed-language (code-switched) conditions. Surprisingly, code-switching does not degrade, and can even improve, performance, suggesting that translation-induced lexical variation may serve as a regularization signal. We validate semantic preservation through embedding-based similarity analyses and cross-lingual alignment visualizations, confirming the fidelity of translated pairs. Our findings expose both the potential and the brittleness of current LLM cross-lingual reasoning, and identify code-switching as a promising lever for improving multilingual robustness. Code available at: https://github.com/KurbanIntelligenceLab/nli-stress-testing</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14735v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Samir Abdaljalil, Erchin Serpedin, Khalid Qaraqe, Hasan Kurban</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TransLLM: A Unified Multi-Task Foundation Framework for Urban Transportation via Learnable Prompting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14782</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14782v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Urban transportation systems encounter diverse challenges across multiple tasks, such as traffic forecasting, electric vehicle (EV) charging demand prediction, and taxi dispatch. Existing approaches suffer from two key limitations: small-scale deep learning models are task-specific and data-hungry, limiting their generalizability across diverse scenarios, while large language models (LLMs), despite offering flexibility through natural language interfaces, struggle with structured spatiotemporal data and numerical reasoning in transportation domains. To address these limitations, we propose TransLLM, a unified foundation framework that integrates spatiotemporal modeling with large language models through learnable prompt composition. Our approach features a lightweight spatiotemporal encoder that captures complex dependencies via dilated temporal convolutions and dual-adjacency graph attention networks, seamlessly interfacing with LLMs through structured embeddings. A novel instance-level prompt routing mechanism, trained via reinforcement learning, dynamically personalizes prompts based on input characteristics, moving beyond fixed task-specific templates. The framework operates by encoding spatiotemporal patterns into contextual representations, dynamically composing personalized prompts to guide LLM reasoning, and projecting the resulting representations through specialized output layers to generate task-specific predictions. Experiments across seven datasets and three tasks demonstrate the exceptional effectiveness of TransLLM in both supervised and zero-shot settings. Compared to ten baseline models, it delivers competitive performance on both regression and planning problems, showing strong generalization and cross-task adaptability. Our code is available at https://github.com/BiYunying/TransLLM.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14782v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiaming Leng, Yunying Bi, Chuan Qin, Bing Yin, Yanyong Zhang, Chao Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Retrieval-Augmented Generation vs. Long-Context Input for Clinical Reasoning over EHRs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14817</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14817v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Electronic health records (EHRs) are long, noisy, and often redundant, posing a major challenge for the clinicians who must navigate them. Large language models (LLMs) offer a promising solution for extracting and reasoning over this unstructured text, but the length of clinical notes often exceeds even state-of-the-art models' extended context windows. Retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) offers an alternative by retrieving task-relevant passages from across the entire EHR, potentially reducing the amount of required input tokens. In this work, we propose three clinical tasks designed to be replicable across health systems with minimal effort: 1) extracting imaging procedures, 2) generating timelines of antibiotic use, and 3) identifying key diagnoses. Using EHRs from actual hospitalized patients, we test three state-of-the-art LLMs with varying amounts of provided context, using either targeted text retrieval or the most recent clinical notes. We find that RAG closely matches or exceeds the performance of using recent notes, and approaches the performance of using the models' full context while requiring drastically fewer input tokens. Our results suggest that RAG remains a competitive and efficient approach even as newer models become capable of handling increasingly longer amounts of text.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14817v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Skatje Myers, Dmitriy Dligach, Timothy A. Miller, Samantha Barr, Yanjun Gao, Matthew Churpek, Anoop Mayampurath, Majid Afshar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long Chain-of-Thought Reasoning Across Languages</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14828</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14828v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Scaling inference through long chains-of-thought (CoTs) has unlocked impressive reasoning capabilities in large language models (LLMs), yet the reasoning process remains almost exclusively English-centric. We construct translated versions of two popular English reasoning datasets, fine-tune Qwen 2.5 (7B) and Qwen 3 (8B) models, and present a systematic study of long CoT generation across French, Japanese, Latvian, and Swahili. Our experiments reveal three key findings. First, the efficacy of using English as a pivot language varies by language: it provides no benefit for French, improves performance when used as the reasoning language for Japanese and Latvian, and proves insufficient for Swahili where both task comprehension and reasoning remain poor. Second, extensive multilingual pretraining in Qwen 3 narrows but does not eliminate the cross-lingual performance gap. A lightweight fine-tune using only 1k traces still improves performance by over 30\% in Swahili. Third, data quality versus scale trade-offs are language dependent: small, carefully curated datasets suffice for English and French, whereas larger but noisier corpora prove more effective for Swahili and Latvian. Together, these results clarify when and why long CoTs transfer across languages and provide translated datasets to foster equitable multilingual reasoning research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14828v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Josh Barua, Seun Eisape, Kayo Yin, Alane Suhr</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MedReseacher-R1: Expert-Level Medical Deep Researcher via A Knowledge-Informed Trajectory Synthesis Framework</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14880</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14880v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent developments in Large Language Model (LLM)-based agents have shown impressive capabilities spanning multiple domains, exemplified by deep research systems that demonstrate superior performance on complex information-seeking and synthesis tasks. While general-purpose deep research agents have shown impressive capabilities, they struggle significantly with medical domain challenges, as evidenced by leading proprietary systems achieving limited accuracy on complex medical benchmarks. The key limitations are: (1) the model lacks sufficient dense medical knowledge for clinical reasoning, and (2) the framework is constrained by the absence of specialized retrieval tools tailored for medical contexts.We present a medical deep research agent that addresses these challenges through two core innovations. First, we develop a novel data synthesis framework using medical knowledge graphs, extracting the longest chains from subgraphs around rare medical entities to generate complex multi-hop question-answer pairs. Second, we integrate a custom-built private medical retrieval engine alongside general-purpose tools, enabling accurate medical information synthesis. Our approach generates 2100+ diverse trajectories across 12 medical specialties, each averaging 4.2 tool interactions.Through a two-stage training paradigm combining supervised fine-tuning and online reinforcement learning with composite rewards, our MedResearcher-R1-32B model demonstrates exceptional performance, establishing new state-of-the-art results on medical benchmarks while maintaining competitive performance on general deep research tasks. Our work demonstrates that strategic domain-specific innovations in architecture, tool design, and training data construction can enable smaller open-source models to outperform much larger proprietary systems in specialized domains.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14880v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ailing Yu, Lan Yao, Jingnan Liu, Zhe Chen, Jiajun Yin, Yuan Wang, Xinhao Liao, Zhiling Ye, Ji Li, Yun Yue, Hansong Xiao, Hualei Zhou, Chunxiao Guo, Peng Wei, Jinjie Gu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantization Meets dLLMs: A Systematic Study of Post-training Quantization for Diffusion LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14896</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14896v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent advances in diffusion large language models (dLLMs) have introduced a promising alternative to autoregressive (AR) LLMs for natural language generation tasks, leveraging full attention and denoising-based decoding strategies. However, the deployment of these models on edge devices remains challenging due to their massive parameter scale and high resource demands. While post-training quantization (PTQ) has emerged as a widely adopted technique for compressing AR LLMs, its applicability to dLLMs remains largely unexplored. In this work, we present the first systematic study on quantizing diffusion-based language models. We begin by identifying the presence of activation outliers, characterized by abnormally large activation values that dominate the dynamic range. These outliers pose a key challenge to low-bit quantization, as they make it difficult to preserve precision for the majority of values. More importantly, we implement state-of-the-art PTQ methods and conduct a comprehensive evaluation across multiple task types and model variants. Our analysis is structured along four key dimensions: bit-width, quantization method, task category, and model type. Through this multi-perspective evaluation, we offer practical insights into the quantization behavior of dLLMs under different configurations. We hope our findings provide a foundation for future research in efficient dLLM deployment. All codes and experimental setups will be released to support the community.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14896v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haokun Lin, Haobo Xu, Yichen Wu, Ziyu Guo, Renrui Zhang, Zhichao Lu, Ying Wei, Qingfu Zhang, Zhenan Sun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RAG-Boost: Retrieval-Augmented Generation Enhanced LLM-based Speech Recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14048</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14048v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In this paper, we propose RAG-Boost (ST-ShinozakiLab Task I system), which enhances the baseline LLM-based ASR system of the MLC-SLM Challenge (task I) with a retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) module on the fly. Each partial ASR hypothesis queries a vector store of audio-text pairs and domain terms, and the retrieved results are fused with the live ASR hypotheses to fix recognition errors. The fused hypotheses are passed to the LLM, yielding improved responses.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14048v1</guid>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Pengcheng Wang, Sheng Li, Takahiro Shinozaki</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MahaTTS: A Unified Framework for Multilingual Text-to-Speech Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14049</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14049v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Current Text-to-Speech models pose a multilingual challenge, where most of the models traditionally focus on English and European languages, thereby hurting the potential to provide access to information to many more people. To address this gap, we introduce MahaTTS-v2 a Multilingual Multi-speaker Text-To-Speech (TTS) system that has excellent multilingual expressive capabilities in Indic languages. The model has been trained on around 20K hours of data specifically focused on Indian languages. Our approach leverages Wav2Vec2.0 tokens for semantic extraction, and a Language Model (LM) for text-to-semantic modeling. Additionally, we have used a Conditional Flow Model (CFM) for semantics to melspectogram generation. The experimental results indicate the effectiveness of the proposed approach over other frameworks. Our code is available at https://github.com/dubverse-ai/MahaTTSv2</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14049v1</guid>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jaskaran Singh, Amartya Roy Chowdhury, Raghav Prabhakar, Varshul C. W</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FinAgentBench: A Benchmark Dataset for Agentic Retrieval in Financial Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14052</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14052v2 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Accurate information retrieval (IR) is critical in the financial domain, where investors must identify relevant information from large collections of documents. Traditional IR methods-whether sparse or dense-often fall short in retrieval accuracy, as it requires not only capturing semantic similarity but also performing fine-grained reasoning over document structure and domain-specific knowledge. Recent advances in large language models (LLMs) have opened up new opportunities for retrieval with multi-step reasoning, where the model ranks passages through iterative reasoning about which information is most relevant to a given query. However, there exists no benchmark to evaluate such capabilities in the financial domain. To address this gap, we introduce FinAgentBench, the first large-scale benchmark for evaluating retrieval with multi-step reasoning in finance -- a setting we term agentic retrieval. The benchmark consists of 3,429 expert-annotated examples on S&amp;P-100 listed firms and assesses whether LLM agents can (1) identify the most relevant document type among candidates, and (2) pinpoint the key passage within the selected document. Our evaluation framework explicitly separates these two reasoning steps to address context limitations. This design enables to provide a quantitative basis for understanding retrieval-centric LLM behavior in finance. We evaluate a suite of state-of-the-art models and further demonstrated how targeted fine-tuning can significantly improve agentic retrieval performance. Our benchmark provides a foundation for studying retrieval-centric LLM behavior in complex, domain-specific tasks for finance. We will release the dataset publicly upon acceptance of the paper and plan to expand and share dataset for the full S&amp;P 500 and beyond.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14052v2</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chanyeol Choi, Jihoon Kwon, Alejandro Lopez-Lira, Chaewoon Kim, Minjae Kim, Juneha Hwang, Jaeseon Ha, Hojun Choi, Suyeol Yun, Yongjin Kim, Yongjae Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two Birds with One Stone: Multi-Task Detection and Attribution of LLM-Generated Text</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14190</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14190v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs), such as GPT-4 and Llama, have demonstrated remarkable abilities in generating natural language. However, they also pose security and integrity challenges. Existing countermeasures primarily focus on distinguishing AI-generated content from human-written text, with most solutions tailored for English. Meanwhile, authorship attribution--determining which specific LLM produced a given text--has received comparatively little attention despite its importance in forensic analysis. In this paper, we present DA-MTL, a multi-task learning framework that simultaneously addresses both text detection and authorship attribution. We evaluate DA-MTL on nine datasets and four backbone models, demonstrating its strong performance across multiple languages and LLM sources. Our framework captures each task's unique characteristics and shares insights between them, which boosts performance in both tasks. Additionally, we conduct a thorough analysis of cross-modal and cross-lingual patterns and assess the framework's robustness against adversarial obfuscation techniques. Our findings offer valuable insights into LLM behavior and the generalization of both detection and authorship attribution.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14190v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zixin Rao, Youssef Mohamed, Shang Liu, Zeyan Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measuring LLM Code Generation Stability via Structural Entropy</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14288</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14288v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Assessing the stability of code generation from large language models (LLMs) is essential for judging their reliability in real-world development. We extend prior "structural-entropy concepts" to the program domain by pairing entropy with abstract syntax tree (AST) analysis. For any fixed prompt, we collect the multiset of depth-bounded subtrees of AST in each generated program and treat their relative frequencies as a probability distribution. We then measure stability in two complementary ways: (i) Jensen-Shannon divergence, a symmetric, bounded indicator of structural overlap, and (ii) a Structural Cross-Entropy ratio that highlights missing high-probability patterns. Both metrics admit structural-only and token-aware variants, enabling separate views on control-flow shape and identifier-level variability. Unlike pass@k, BLEU, or CodeBLEU, our metrics are reference-free, language-agnostic, and execution-independent. We benchmark several leading LLMs on standard code generation tasks, demonstrating that AST-driven structural entropy reveals nuances in model consistency and robustness. The method runs in O(n,d) time with no external tests, providing a lightweight addition to the code-generation evaluation toolkit.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14288v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yewei Song, Tiezhu Sun, Xunzhu Tang, Prateek Rajput, Tegawende F. Bissyande, Jacques Klein</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MultiFuzz: A Dense Retrieval-based Multi-Agent System for Network Protocol Fuzzing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14300</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14300v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Traditional protocol fuzzing techniques, such as those employed by AFL-based systems, often lack effectiveness due to a limited semantic understanding of complex protocol grammars and rigid seed mutation strategies. Recent works, such as ChatAFL, have integrated Large Language Models (LLMs) to guide protocol fuzzing and address these limitations, pushing protocol fuzzers to wider exploration of the protocol state space. But ChatAFL still faces issues like unreliable output, LLM hallucinations, and assumptions of LLM knowledge about protocol specifications. This paper introduces MultiFuzz, a novel dense retrieval-based multi-agent system designed to overcome these limitations by integrating semantic-aware context retrieval, specialized agents, and structured tool-assisted reasoning. MultiFuzz utilizes agentic chunks of protocol documentation (RFC Documents) to build embeddings in a vector database for a retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) pipeline, enabling agents to generate more reliable and structured outputs, enhancing the fuzzer in mutating protocol messages with enhanced state coverage and adherence to syntactic constraints. The framework decomposes the fuzzing process into modular groups of agents that collaborate through chain-of-thought reasoning to dynamically adapt fuzzing strategies based on the retrieved contextual knowledge. Experimental evaluations on the Real-Time Streaming Protocol (RTSP) demonstrate that MultiFuzz significantly improves branch coverage and explores deeper protocol states and transitions over state-of-the-art (SOTA) fuzzers such as NSFuzz, AFLNet, and ChatAFL. By combining dense retrieval, agentic coordination, and language model reasoning, MultiFuzz establishes a new paradigm in autonomous protocol fuzzing, offering a scalable and extensible foundation for future research in intelligent agentic-based fuzzing systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14300v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <category>cs.NI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Youssef Maklad, Fares Wael, Ali Hamdi, Wael Elsersy, Khaled Shaban</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GLASS: Test-Time Acceleration for LLMs via Global-Local Neural Importance Aggregation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14302</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14302v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Deploying Large Language Models (LLMs) on edge hardware demands aggressive, prompt-aware dynamic pruning to reduce computation without degrading quality. Static or predictor-based schemes either lock in a single sparsity pattern or incur extra runtime overhead, and recent zero-shot methods that rely on statistics from a single prompt fail on short prompt and/or long generation scenarios. We introduce A/I-GLASS: Activation- and Impact-based Global-Local neural importance Aggregation for feed-forward network SparSification, two training-free methods that dynamically select FFN units using a rank-aggregation of prompt local and model-intrinsic global neuron statistics. Empirical results across multiple LLMs and benchmarks demonstrate that GLASS significantly outperforms prior training-free methods, particularly in challenging long-form generation scenarios, without relying on auxiliary predictors or adding any inference overhead.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14302v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Amirmohsen Sattarifard, Sepehr Lavasani, Ehsan Imani, Kunlin Zhang, Hanlin Xu, Fengyu Sun, Negar Hassanpour, Chao Gao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DuPO: Enabling Reliable LLM Self-Verification via Dual Preference Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14460</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14460v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We present DuPO, a dual learning-based preference optimization framework that generates annotation-free feedback via a generalized duality. DuPO addresses two key limitations: Reinforcement Learning with Verifiable Rewards (RLVR)'s reliance on costly labels and applicability restricted to verifiable tasks, and traditional dual learning's restriction to strictly dual task pairs (e.g., translation and back-translation). Specifically, DuPO decomposes a primal task's input into known and unknown components, then constructs its dual task to reconstruct the unknown part using the primal output and known information (e.g., reversing math solutions to recover hidden variables), broadening applicability to non-invertible tasks. The quality of this reconstruction serves as a self-supervised reward to optimize the primal task, synergizing with LLMs' ability to instantiate both tasks via a single model. Empirically, DuPO achieves substantial gains across diverse tasks: it enhances the average translation quality by 2.13 COMET over 756 directions, boosts the mathematical reasoning accuracy by an average of 6.4 points on three challenge benchmarks, and enhances performance by 9.3 points as an inference-time reranker (trading computation for accuracy). These results position DuPO as a scalable, general, and annotation-free paradigm for LLM optimization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14460v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shuaijie She, Yu Bao, Yu Lu, Lu Xu, Tao Li, Wenhao Zhu, Shujian Huang, Shanbo Cheng, Lu Lu, Yuxuan Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who Sees What? Structured Thought-Action Sequences for Epistemic Reasoning in LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14564</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14564v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recent advances in large language models (LLMs) and reasoning frameworks have opened new possibilities for improving the perspective -taking capabilities of autonomous agents. However, tasks that involve active perception, collaborative reasoning, and perspective taking (understanding what another agent can see or knows) pose persistent challenges for current LLM-based systems. This study investigates the potential of structured examples derived from transformed solution graphs generated by the Fast Downward planner to improve the performance of LLM-based agents within a ReAct framework. We propose a structured solution-processing pipeline that generates three distinct categories of examples: optimal goal paths (G-type), informative node paths (E-type), and step-by-step optimal decision sequences contrasting alternative actions (L-type). These solutions are further converted into ``thought-action'' examples by prompting an LLM to explicitly articulate the reasoning behind each decision. While L-type examples slightly reduce clarification requests and overall action steps, they do not yield consistent improvements. Agents are successful in tasks requiring basic attentional filtering but struggle in scenarios that required mentalising about occluded spaces or weighing the costs of epistemic actions. These findings suggest that structured examples alone are insufficient for robust perspective-taking, underscoring the need for explicit belief tracking, cost modelling, and richer environments to enable socially grounded collaboration in LLM-based agents.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14564v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Luca Annese, Sabrina Patania, Silvia Serino, Tom Foulsham, Silvia Rossi, Azzurra Ruggeri, Dimitri Ognibene</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MCP-Universe: Benchmarking Large Language Models with Real-World Model Context Protocol Servers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14704</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14704v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The Model Context Protocol has emerged as a transformative standard for connecting large language models to external data sources and tools, rapidly gaining adoption across major AI providers and development platforms. However, existing benchmarks are overly simplistic and fail to capture real application challenges such as long-horizon reasoning and large, unfamiliar tool spaces. To address this critical gap, we introduce MCP-Universe, the first comprehensive benchmark specifically designed to evaluate LLMs in realistic and hard tasks through interaction with real-world MCP servers. Our benchmark encompasses 6 core domains spanning 11 different MCP servers: Location Navigation, Repository Management, Financial Analysis, 3D Design, Browser Automation, and Web Searching. To ensure rigorous evaluation, we implement execution-based evaluators, including format evaluators for agent format compliance, static evaluators for time-invariant content matching, and dynamic evaluators that automatically retrieve real-time ground truth for temporally sensitive tasks. Through extensive evaluation of leading LLMs, we find that even SOTA models such as GPT-5 (43.72%), Grok-4 (33.33%) and Claude-4.0-Sonnet (29.44%) exhibit significant performance limitations. In addition, our benchmark poses a significant long-context challenge for LLM agents, as the number of input tokens increases rapidly with the number of interaction steps. Moreover, it introduces an unknown-tools challenge, as LLM agents often lack familiarity with the precise usage of the MCP servers. Notably, enterprise-level agents like Cursor cannot achieve better performance than standard ReAct frameworks. Beyond evaluation, we open-source our extensible evaluation framework with UI support, enabling researchers and practitioners to seamlessly integrate new agents and MCP servers while fostering innovation in the rapidly evolving MCP ecosystem.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14704v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ziyang Luo, Zhiqi Shen, Wenzhuo Yang, Zirui Zhao, Prathyusha Jwalapuram, Amrita Saha, Doyen Sahoo, Silvio Savarese, Caiming Xiong, Junnan Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Privileged Self-Access Matters for Introspection in AI</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14802</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14802v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Whether AI models can introspect is an increasingly important practical question. But there is no consensus on how introspection is to be defined. Beginning from a recently proposed ''lightweight'' definition, we argue instead for a thicker one. According to our proposal, introspection in AI is any process which yields information about internal states through a process more reliable than one with equal or lower computational cost available to a third party. Using experiments where LLMs reason about their internal temperature parameters, we show they can appear to have lightweight introspection while failing to meaningfully introspect per our proposed definition.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14802v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Siyuan Song, Harvey Lederman, Jennifer Hu, Kyle Mahowald</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Prompting Brain: Neurocognitive Markers of Expertise in Guiding Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14869</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14869v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Prompt engineering has rapidly emerged as a critical skill for effective interaction with large language models (LLMs). However, the cognitive and neural underpinnings of this expertise remain largely unexplored. This paper presents findings from a cross-sectional pilot fMRI study investigating differences in brain functional connectivity and network activity between experts and intermediate prompt engineers. Our results reveal distinct neural signatures associated with higher prompt engineering literacy, including increased functional connectivity in brain regions such as the left middle temporal gyrus and the left frontal pole, as well as altered power-frequency dynamics in key cognitive networks. These findings offer initial insights into the neurobiological basis of prompt engineering proficiency. We discuss the implications of these neurocognitive markers in Natural Language Processing (NLP). Understanding the neural basis of human expertise in interacting with LLMs can inform the design of more intuitive human-AI interfaces, contribute to cognitive models of LLM interaction, and potentially guide the development of AI systems that better align with human cognitive workflows. This interdisciplinary approach aims to bridge the gap between human cognition and machine intelligence, fostering a deeper understanding of how humans learn and adapt to complex AI systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14869v1</guid>
      <category>q-bio.NC</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hend Al-Khalifa, Raneem Almansour, Layan Abdulrahman Alhuasini, Alanood Alsaleh, Mohamad-Hani Temsah,  Mohamad-Hani_Temsah, Ashwag Rafea S Alruwaili</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Community: An Open World for Humans, Robots, and Society</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14893</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14893v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The rapid progress in AI and Robotics may lead to a profound societal transformation, as humans and robots begin to coexist within shared communities, introducing both opportunities and challenges. To explore this future, we present Virtual Community-an open-world platform for humans, robots, and society-built on a universal physics engine and grounded in real-world 3D scenes. With Virtual Community, we aim to study embodied social intelligence at scale: 1) How robots can intelligently cooperate or compete; 2) How humans develop social relations and build community; 3) More importantly, how intelligent robots and humans can co-exist in an open world. To support these, Virtual Community features: 1) An open-source multi-agent physics simulator that supports robots, humans, and their interactions within a society; 2) A large-scale, real-world aligned community generation pipeline, including vast outdoor space, diverse indoor scenes, and a community of grounded agents with rich characters and appearances. Leveraging Virtual Community, we propose two novel challenges. The Community Planning Challenge evaluates multi-agent reasoning and planning ability in open-world settings, such as cooperating to help agents with daily activities and efficiently connecting other agents. The Community Robot Challenge requires multiple heterogeneous robots to collaborate in solving complex open-world tasks. We evaluate various baselines on these tasks and demonstrate the challenges in both high-level open-world task planning and low-level cooperation controls. We hope that Virtual Community will unlock further study of human-robot coexistence within open-world environments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14893v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qinhong Zhou, Hongxin Zhang, Xiangye Lin, Zheyuan Zhang, Yutian Chen, Wenjun Liu, Zunzhe Zhang, Sunli Chen, Lixing Fang, Qiushi Lyu, Xinyu Sun, Jincheng Yang, Zeyuan Wang, Bao Chi Dang, Zhehuan Chen, Daksha Ladia, Jiageng Liu, Chuang Gan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>G-LLaVA: Solving Geometric Problem with Multi-Modal Large Language Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11370</link>
      <description>arXiv:2312.11370v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have shown remarkable proficiency in human-level reasoning and generation capabilities, which encourages extensive research on their application in mathematical problem solving. However, current work has been largely focused on text-based mathematical problems, with limited investigation in problems involving geometric information. Addressing this gap, we aim to enable LLMs to solve geometric problems by understanding image input. We first analyze the limitations of current Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) in this area: they struggle to accurately comprehending basic geometric elements and their relationships. To overcome these challenges, we take advantage of the unique characteristics of geometric problems (such as unique geometric logical form, and geometric scalability) and the capacity of the textual LLMs to build an enriched multimodal geometry dataset based on existing data. The augmented dataset, Geo170K, contains more than 170K geometric image-caption and question-answer pairs. Utilizing our constructed Geo170K dataset, we develop G-LLaVA, which demonstrates exceptional performance in solving geometric problems, significantly outperforming GPT-4-V on the MathVista benchmark with only 7B parameters.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2312.11370v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiahui Gao, Renjie Pi, Jipeng Zhang, Jiacheng Ye, Wanjun Zhong, Yufei Wang, Lanqing Hong, Jianhua Han, Hang Xu, Zhenguo Li, Lingpeng Kong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social Debiasing for Fair Multi-modal LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06569</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06569v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Multi-modal Large Language Models (MLLMs) have dramatically advanced the research field and delivered powerful vision-language understanding capabilities. However, these models often inherit deep-rooted social biases from their training data, leading to uncomfortable responses with respect to attributes such as race and gender. This paper addresses the issue of social biases in MLLMs by i) introducing a comprehensive counterfactual dataset with multiple social concepts (CMSC), which complements existing datasets by providing 18 diverse and balanced social concepts; and ii) proposing a counter-stereotype debiasing (CSD) strategy that mitigates social biases in MLLMs by leveraging the opposites of prevalent stereotypes. CSD incorporates both a novel bias-aware data sampling method and a loss rescaling method, enabling the model to effectively reduce biases. We conduct extensive experiments with four prevalent MLLM architectures. The results demonstrate the advantage of the CMSC dataset and the edge of CSD strategy in reducing social biases compared to existing competing methods, without compromising the overall performance on general multi-modal reasoning benchmarks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06569v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Harry Cheng, Yangyang Guo, Qingpei Guo, Ming Yang, Tian Gan, Weili Guan, Liqiang Nie</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Source2Synth: Synthetic Data Generation and Curation Grounded in Real Data Sources</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.08239</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.08239v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Synthetic data generation has recently emerged as a promising approach for enhancing the capabilities of large language models (LLMs) without the need for expensive human annotations. However, existing methods often generate data that can be low quality or contrived. In this paper, we introduce Source2Synth, a scalable approach for synthetic data generation and curation that is grounded in real-world data sources. Source2Synth takes as input a custom data source and produces synthetic data examples with intermediate reasoning steps. Our method improves the dataset quality by discarding low-quality generations based on their answerability. We demonstrate the generality of this approach by applying it to two tasks that leverage two different types of data: multi-hop question answering (MHQA), where we test complex reasoning abilities leveraging documents, and tabular question answering (TQA), where we test tool usage leveraging tables. Our method improves performance by 25.51% for TQA on WikiSQL and 22.57% for MHQA on HotpotQA compared to the fine-tuned baselines.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.08239v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alisia Lupidi, Carlos Gemmell, Nicola Cancedda, Jane Dwivedi-Yu, Jason Weston, Jakob Foerster, Roberta Raileanu, Maria Lomeli</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deliberate Reasoning in Language Models as Structure-Aware Planning with an Accurate World Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.03136</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.03136v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Enhancing the reasoning capabilities of language models (LMs) remains a key challenge, especially for tasks that require complex, multi-step decision-making where existing Chain-of-Thought (CoT) approaches struggle with consistency and verification. In this paper, we propose a novel reasoning framework, referred to as Structure-aware Planning with an Accurate World Model (SWAP), that integrates structured knowledge representation with learned planning. Unlike prior methods that rely purely on natural language reasoning, SWAP leverages entailment graphs to encode structured dependencies and enable symbolic verification of intermediate steps. To systematically construct and update the graph, SWAP employs a policy model to propose candidate expansions and a world model to predict structural updates. To improve accuracy, the world model generates multiple alternative updates, and a discriminator re-ranks them based on plausibility. To encourage diverse exploration, we introduce Diversity-based Modelling (DM), which samples candidates from the remaining probability mass after removing previously sampled candidates from the original policy distribution. Additionally, SWAP improves the discrimination accuracy through Contrastive Ranking (CR), which directly compares candidates within prompts and incorporates meta-knowledge to improve ranking quality. We evaluate SWAP across diverse reasoning-intensive benchmarks including math reasoning, logical reasoning, and coding tasks. Extensive experiments demonstrate that SWAP significantly improves upon the base models and consistently outperforms existing reasoning methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.03136v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Siheng Xiong, Ali Payani, Yuan Yang, Faramarz Fekri</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChuLo: Chunk-Level Key Information Representation for Long Document Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.11119</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.11119v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Transformer-based models have achieved remarkable success in various Natural Language Processing (NLP) tasks, yet their ability to handle long documents is constrained by computational limitations. Traditional approaches, such as truncating inputs, sparse self-attention, and chunking, attempt to mitigate these issues, but they often lead to information loss and hinder the model's ability to capture long-range dependencies. In this paper, we introduce ChuLo, a novel chunk representation method for long document understanding that addresses these limitations. Our ChuLo groups input tokens using unsupervised keyphrase extraction, emphasizing semantically important keyphrase based chunks to retain core document content while reducing input length. This approach minimizes information loss and improves the efficiency of Transformer-based models. Preserving all tokens in long document understanding, especially token classification tasks, is important to ensure that fine-grained annotations, which depend on the entire sequence context, are not lost. We evaluate our method on multiple long document classification tasks and long document token classification tasks, demonstrating its effectiveness through comprehensive qualitative and quantitative analysis. Our implementation is open-sourced on https://github.com/adlnlp/Chulo.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.11119v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yan Li, Soyeon Caren Han, Yue Dai, Feiqi Cao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Little Human Data Goes A Long Way</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.13098</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.13098v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Faced with an expensive human annotation process, creators of NLP systems increasingly turn to synthetic data generation. While this method shows promise, the extent to which synthetic data can replace human annotation is poorly understood. We investigate the use of synthetic data in Fact Verification (FV) and Question Answering (QA) by studying the effects of incrementally replacing human generated data with synthetic points on eight diverse datasets. Strikingly, replacing up to 90% of the training data only marginally decreases performance, but replacing the final 10% leads to severe declines. We find that models trained on purely synthetic data can be reliably improved by including as few as 125 human generated data points. We show that matching the performance gain of just a little additional human data (only 200 points) requires an order of magnitude more synthetic data and estimate price ratios at which human annotation would be a more cost-effective solution. Our results suggest that even when human annotation at scale is infeasible, there is great value to having a small proportion of the dataset being human generated.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.13098v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dhananjay Ashok, Jonathan May</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SLED: Self Logits Evolution Decoding for Improving Factuality in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.02433</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.02433v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated remarkable capabilities, but their outputs can sometimes be unreliable or factually incorrect. To address this, we introduce Self Logits Evolution Decoding (SLED), a novel decoding framework that enhances the truthfulness of LLMs without relying on external knowledge bases or requiring further fine-tuning. From an optimization perspective, our SLED framework leverages the latent knowledge embedded within the LLM by contrasting the output logits from the final layer with those from early layers. It then utilizes an approximate gradient approach to enable latent knowledge to guide the self-refinement of outputs, thereby effectively improving factual accuracy. Extensive experiments have been conducted on established benchmarks across a diverse range of model families (Gemma, Qwen, Mixtral, gpt-oss) and scales (from 1B to 45B), including more advanced architectural configurations such as the mixture of experts (MoE). Our evaluation spans a wide variety of tasks and the results demonstrate that SLED consistently improves factual accuracy compared to existing decoding methods while maintaining natural language fluency and negligible latency overhead. Furthermore, it can be flexibly combined with other decoding methods to further enhance their performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.02433v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jianyi Zhang, Da-Cheng Juan, Cyrus Rashtchian, Chun-Sung Ferng, Heinrich Jiang, Yiran Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retrieval-Augmented Semantic Parsing: Improving Generalization with Lexical Knowledge</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10207</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10207v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Open-domain semantic parsing remains a challenging task, as neural models often rely on heuristics and struggle to handle unseen concepts. In this paper, we investigate the potential of large language models (LLMs) for this task and introduce Retrieval-Augmented Semantic Parsing (RASP), a simple yet effective approach that integrates external symbolic knowledge into the parsing process. Our experiments not only show that LLMs outperform previous encoder-decoder baselines for semantic parsing, but that RASP further enhances their ability to predict unseen concepts, nearly doubling the performance of previous models on out-of-distribution concepts. These findings highlight the promise of leveraging large language models and retrieval mechanisms for robust and open-domain semantic parsing.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10207v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiao Zhang, Qianru Meng, Johan Bos</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Task-Oriented Automatic Fact-Checking with Frame-Semantics</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.13288</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.13288v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We propose a novel paradigm for automatic fact-checking that leverages frame semantics to enhance the structured understanding of claims and guide the process of fact-checking them. To support this, we introduce a pilot dataset of real-world claims extracted from PolitiFact, specifically annotated for large-scale structured data. This dataset underpins two case studies: the first investigates voting-related claims using the Vote semantic frame, while the second explores various semantic frames based on data sources from the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD). Our findings demonstrate the effectiveness of frame semantics in improving evidence retrieval and explainability for fact-checking. Finally, we conducted a survey of frames evoked in fact-checked claims, identifying high-impact frames to guide future work in this direction.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.13288v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.18653/v1/2025.findings-acl.711</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics: ACL 2025, pages 13825-13842, Vienna, Austria. Association for Computational Linguistics</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Jacob Devasier, Rishabh Mediratta, Akshith Putta, Chengkai Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Natural Language Generation from Visual Events: State-of-the-Art and Key Open Questions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.13034</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.13034v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In recent years, a substantial body of work in visually grounded natural language processing has focused on real-life multimodal scenarios such as describing content depicted in images or videos. However, comparatively less attention has been devoted to study the nature and degree of interaction between the different modalities in these scenarios. In this paper, we argue that any task dealing with natural language generation from sequences of images or frames is an instance of the broader, more general problem of modeling the intricate relationships between visual events unfolding over time and the features of the language used to interpret, describe, or narrate them. Therefore, solving these tasks requires models to be capable of identifying and managing such intricacies. We consider five seemingly different tasks, which we argue are compelling instances of this broader multimodal problem. Subsequently, we survey the modeling and evaluation approaches adopted for these tasks in recent years and examine the common set of challenges these tasks pose. Building on this perspective, we identify key open questions and propose several research directions for future investigation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.13034v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aditya K Surikuchi, Raquel Fern\'andez, Sandro Pezzelle</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing Language Multi-Agent Learning with Credit Re-Assignment for Interactive Environment Generalization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.14496</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.14496v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: LLM-based agents have made significant advancements in interactive environments, such as mobile operations and web browsing, and other domains beyond computer using. Current multi-agent systems universally excel in performance, compared to single agents, but struggle with generalization across environments due to predefined roles and inadequate strategies for generalizing language agents. The challenge of achieving both strong performance and good generalization has hindered the progress of multi-agent systems for interactive environments. To address these issues, we propose CollabUIAgents, a multi-agent reinforcement learning framework with a novel multi-agent credit re-assignment (CR) strategy, assigning process rewards with LLMs rather than environment-specific rewards and learning with synthesized preference data, in order to foster generalizable, collaborative behaviors among the role-free agents' policies. Empirical results show that our framework improves both performance and cross-environment generalizability of multi-agent systems. Moreover, our 7B-parameter system achieves results on par with or exceed strong closed-source models, and the LLM that guides the CR. We also provide insights in using granular CR rewards effectively for environment generalization, and accommodating trained LLMs in multi-agent systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.14496v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhitao He, Zijun Liu, Peng Li, Yi R. Fung, Ming Yan, Ji Zhang, Fei Huang, Yang Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JudgeLRM: Large Reasoning Models as a Judge</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.00050</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.00050v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The rise of Large Language Models (LLMs) as evaluators offers a scalable alternative to human annotation, yet existing Supervised Fine-Tuning (SFT) for judges approaches often fall short in domains requiring complex reasoning. In this work, we investigate whether LLM judges truly benefit from enhanced reasoning capabilities. Through a detailed analysis of reasoning requirements across evaluation tasks, we reveal a negative correlation between SFT performance gains and the proportion of reasoning-demanding samples - highlighting the limitations of SFT in such scenarios. To address this, we introduce JudgeLRM, a family of judgment-oriented LLMs trained using reinforcement learning (RL) with judge-wise, outcome-driven rewards. JudgeLRM models consistently outperform both SFT-tuned and state-of-the-art reasoning models. Notably, JudgeLRM-3B surpasses GPT-4, and JudgeLRM-7B outperforms DeepSeek-R1 by 2.79% in F1 score, particularly excelling in judge tasks requiring deep reasoning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.00050v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nuo Chen, Zhiyuan Hu, Qingyun Zou, Jiaying Wu, Qian Wang, Bryan Hooi, Bingsheng He</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chain of Correction for Full-text Speech Recognition with Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.01519</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.01519v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Full-text error correction with Large Language Models (LLMs) for Automatic Speech Recognition (ASR) is attracting increased attention for its ability to address a wide range of error types, such as punctuation restoration and inverse text normalization, across long context. However, challenges remain regarding stability, controllability, completeness, and fluency. To mitigate these issues, this paper proposes the Chain of Correction (CoC), which uses a multi-turn chat format to correct errors segment by segment, guided by pre-recognized text and full-text context for better semantic understanding. Utilizing the open-sourced ChFT dataset, we fine-tune a pre-trained LLM to evaluate CoC's performance. Experiments show that CoC significantly outperforms baseline and benchmark systems in correcting full-text ASR outputs. We also analyze correction thresholds to balance under-correction and over-rephrasing, extrapolate CoC on extra-long ASR outputs, and explore using other types of information to guide error correction.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.01519v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhiyuan Tang, Dong Wang, Zhikai Zhou, Yong Liu, Shen Huang, Shidong Shang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Chart-to-Code Generation in MLLM via Dual Preference-Guided Refinement</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.02906</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.02906v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Translating chart images into executable plotting scripts-referred to as the chart-to-code generation task-requires Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) to perform fine-grained visual parsing, precise code synthesis, and robust cross-modal reasoning. However, this task is inherently under-constrained: multiple valid code implementations can produce the same visual chart, and evaluation must consider both code correctness and visual fidelity across diverse dimensions. This makes it difficult to learn accurate and generalizable mappings through standard supervised fine-tuning. To address these challenges, we propose a dual preference-guided refinement framework that combines a feedback-driven, dual-modality reward mechanism with iterative preference learning. Our approach introduces a structured variant generation strategy and a visual reward model to efficiently produce high-quality, aspect-aware preference pairs-making preference collection scalable and supervision more targeted. These preferences are used in an offline reinforcement learning setup to optimize the model toward multi-dimensional fidelity. Experimental results show that our framework significantly enhances the performance of general-purpose open-source MLLMs, enabling them to generate high-quality plotting code that rivals specialized chart-centric models and even some proprietary systems. The code and datasets are publicly available at https://github.com/Zhihan72/Chart2Code.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.02906v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhihan Zhang, Yixin Cao, Lizi Liao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hallucinations and Key Information Extraction in Medical Texts: A Comprehensive Assessment of Open-Source Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.19061</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.19061v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Clinical summarization is crucial in healthcare as it distills complex medical data into digestible information, enhancing patient understanding and care management. Large language models (LLMs) have shown significant potential in automating and improving the accuracy of such summarizations due to their advanced natural language understanding capabilities. These models are particularly applicable in the context of summarizing medical/clinical texts, where precise and concise information transfer is essential. In this paper, we investigate the effectiveness of open-source LLMs in extracting key events from discharge reports, including admission reasons, major in-hospital events, and critical follow-up actions. In addition, we also assess the prevalence of various types of hallucinations in the summaries produced by these models. Detecting hallucinations is vital as it directly influences the reliability of the information, potentially affecting patient care and treatment outcomes. We conduct comprehensive simulations to rigorously evaluate the performance of these models, further probing the accuracy and fidelity of the extracted content in clinical summarization. Our results reveal that while the LLMs (e.g., Qwen2.5 and DeepSeek-v2) perform quite well in capturing admission reasons and hospitalization events, they are generally less consistent when it comes to identifying follow-up recommendations, highlighting broader challenges in leveraging LLMs for comprehensive summarization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.19061v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Anindya Bijoy Das, Shibbir Ahmed, Shahnewaz Karim Sakib</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncertainty Quantification for Language Models: A Suite of Black-Box, White-Box, LLM Judge, and Ensemble Scorers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.19254</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.19254v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Hallucinations are a persistent problem with Large Language Models (LLMs). As these models become increasingly used in high-stakes domains, such as healthcare and finance, the need for effective hallucination detection is crucial. To this end, we outline a versatile framework for zero-resource hallucination detection that practitioners can apply to real-world use cases. To achieve this, we adapt a variety of existing uncertainty quantification (UQ) techniques, including black-box UQ, white-box UQ, and LLM-as-a-Judge, transforming them as necessary into standardized response-level confidence scores ranging from 0 to 1. To enhance flexibility, we propose a tunable ensemble approach that incorporates any combination of the individual confidence scores. This approach enables practitioners to optimize the ensemble for a specific use case for improved performance. To streamline implementation, the full suite of scorers is offered in this paper's companion Python toolkit, UQLM. To evaluate the performance of the various scorers, we conduct an extensive set of experiments using several LLM question-answering benchmarks. We find that our tunable ensemble typically surpasses its individual components and outperforms existing hallucination detection methods. Our results demonstrate the benefits of customized hallucination detection strategies for improving the accuracy and reliability of LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.19254v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dylan Bouchard, Mohit Singh Chauhan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Critique-GRPO: Advancing LLM Reasoning with Natural Language and Numerical Feedback</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.03106</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.03106v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advances in reinforcement learning (RL) with numerical feedback, such as scalar rewards, have significantly enhanced the complex reasoning capabilities of large language models (LLMs). Despite this success, we identify three key challenges encountered by RL with solely numerical feedback: performance plateaus, limited effectiveness of spontaneous self-reflection, and persistent failures. We then demonstrate that RL-finetuned models, even after exhibiting performance plateaus, can generate correct refinements on persistently failed problems by leveraging natural language feedback in the form of critiques. Building on this insight, we propose Critique-GRPO, an online RL framework that integrates both natural language and numerical feedback for effective policy optimization. Critique-GRPO enables LLMs to learn from initial responses and critique-guided self-refinements simultaneously while maintaining exploration. Additionally, we employ a shaping function to amplify learning from correct, especially unfamiliar, refinements and penalize incorrect ones. Extensive experiments with Qwen2.5-7B-Base, Qwen2.5-Math-7B-Base, and Qwen3-8B demonstrate that Critique-GRPO consistently outperforms supervised learning and RL-based fine-tuning methods across eight challenging mathematical, STEM, and general reasoning tasks. Specifically, Critique-GRPO improves average pass@1 scores across all compared methods by approximately +4.4% on Qwen2.5-7B-Base and +3.8% on Qwen3-8B. Notably, Critique-GRPO enables effective self-improvement through self-critiquing, achieving significant gains over GRPO, e.g., +16.7% pass@1 improvement on AIME 2024.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.03106v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoying Zhang, Hao Sun, Yipeng Zhang, Kaituo Feng, Chaochao Lu, Chao Yang, Helen Meng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Customizing Speech Recognition Model with Large Language Model Feedback</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.11091</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.11091v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Automatic speech recognition (ASR) systems have achieved strong performance on general transcription tasks. However, they continue to struggle with recognizing rare named entities and adapting to domain mismatches. In contrast, large language models (LLMs), trained on massive internet-scale datasets, are often more effective across a wide range of domains. In this work, we propose a reinforcement learning based approach for unsupervised domain adaptation, leveraging unlabeled data to enhance transcription quality, particularly the named entities affected by domain mismatch, through feedback from a LLM. Given contextual information, our framework employs a LLM as the reward model to score the hypotheses from the ASR model. These scores serve as reward signals to fine-tune the ASR model via reinforcement learning. Our method achieves a 21\% improvement on entity word error rate over conventional self-training methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.11091v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shaoshi Ling, Guoli Ye</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Temporal Sensitivity of Large Language Model for Recommendation with Counterfactual Tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.03047</link>
      <description>arXiv:2507.03047v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advances have applied large language models (LLMs) to sequential recommendation, leveraging their pre-training knowledge and reasoning capabilities to provide more personalized user experiences. However, existing LLM-based methods fail to sufficiently leverage the rich temporal information inherent in users' historical interaction sequences, stemming from fundamental architectural constraints: LLMs process information through self-attention mechanisms that lack inherent sequence ordering and rely on position embeddings designed primarily for natural language rather than user interaction sequences. This limitation significantly impairs their ability to capture the evolution of user preferences over time and predict future interests accurately.
  To address this critical gap, we propose \underline{C}ounterfactual \underline{E}nhanced \underline{T}emporal Framework for LLM-Based \underline{Rec}ommendation (CETRec). CETRec is grounded in causal inference principles, which allow it to isolate and measure the specific impact of temporal information on recommendation outcomes. Combined with our counterfactual tuning task derived from causal analysis, CETRec effectively enhances LLMs' awareness of both absolute order (how recently items were interacted with) and relative order (the sequential relationships between items). Extensive experiments on real-world datasets demonstrate the effectiveness of our CETRec. Our code is available at https://anonymous.4open.science/r/CETRec-B9CE/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2507.03047v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yutian Liu, Zhengyi Yang, Jiancan Wu, Xiang Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Applying Text Embedding Models for Efficient Analysis in Labeled Property Graphs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.10772</link>
      <description>arXiv:2507.10772v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Labeled property graphs often contain rich textual attributes that can enhance analytical tasks when properly leveraged. This work explores the use of pretrained text embedding models to enable efficient semantic analysis in such graphs. By embedding textual node and edge properties, we support downstream tasks including node classification and relation prediction with improved contextual understanding. Our approach integrates language model embeddings into the graph pipeline without altering its structure, demonstrating that textual semantics can significantly enhance the accuracy and interpretability of property graph analysis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2507.10772v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Michal Podstawski</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Each to Their Own: Exploring the Optimal Embedding in RAG</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.17442</link>
      <description>arXiv:2507.17442v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recently, as Large Language Models (LLMs) have fundamentally impacted various fields, the methods for incorporating up-to-date information into LLMs or adding external knowledge to construct domain-specific models have garnered wide attention. Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG), serving as an inference-time scaling method, is notable for its low cost and minimal effort for parameter tuning. However, due to heterogeneous training data and model architecture, the variant embedding models used in RAG exhibit different benefits across various areas, often leading to different similarity calculation results and, consequently, varying response quality from LLMs. To address this problem, we propose and examine two approaches to enhance RAG by combining the benefits of multiple embedding models, named Mixture-Embedding RAG and Confident RAG. Mixture-Embedding RAG simply sorts and selects retrievals from multiple embedding models based on standardized similarity; however, it does not outperform vanilla RAG. In contrast, Confident RAG generates responses multiple times using different embedding models and then selects the responses with the highest confidence level, demonstrating average improvements of approximately 10% and 5% over vanilla LLMs and RAG, respectively. The consistent results across different LLMs and embedding models indicate that Confident RAG is an efficient plug-and-play approach for various domains. We will release our code upon publication.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2507.17442v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shiting Chen, Zijian Zhao, Jinsong Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is neural semantic parsing good at ellipsis resolution, or isn't it?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.00121</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.00121v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Neural semantic parsers have shown good overall performance for a variety of linguistic phenomena, reaching semantic matching scores of more than 90%. But how do such parsers perform on strongly context-sensitive phenomena, where large pieces of semantic information need to be duplicated to form a meaningful semantic representation? A case in point is English verb phrase ellipsis, a construct where entire verb phrases can be abbreviated by a single auxiliary verb. Are the otherwise known as powerful semantic parsers able to deal with ellipsis or aren't they? We constructed a corpus of 120 cases of ellipsis with their fully resolved meaning representation and used this as a challenge set for a large battery of neural semantic parsers. Although these parsers performed very well on the standard test set, they failed in the instances with ellipsis. Data augmentation helped improve the parsing results. The reason for the difficulty of parsing elided phrases is not that copying semantic material is hard, but that usually occur in linguistically complicated contexts causing most of the parsing errors.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.00121v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiao Zhang, Johan bos</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Turn Puzzles: Evaluating Interactive Reasoning and Strategic Dialogue in LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.10142</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.10142v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) excel at solving problems with clear and complete statements, but often struggle with nuanced environments or interactive tasks which are common in most real-world scenarios. This highlights the critical need for developing LLMs that can effectively engage in logically consistent multi-turn dialogue, seek information and reason with incomplete data. To this end, we introduce a novel benchmark comprising a suite of multi-turn tasks each designed to test specific reasoning, interactive dialogue, and information-seeking abilities. These tasks have deterministic scoring mechanisms, thus eliminating the need for human intervention. Evaluating frontier models on our benchmark reveals significant headroom. Our analysis shows that most errors emerge from poor instruction following, reasoning failures, and poor planning. This benchmark provides valuable insights into the strengths and weaknesses of current LLMs in handling complex, interactive scenarios and offers a robust platform for future research aimed at improving these critical capabilities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.10142v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kartikeya Badola, Jonathan Simon, Arian Hosseini, Sara Marie Mc Carthy, Tsendsuren Munkhdalai, Abhimanyu Goyal, Tom\'a\v{s} Ko\v{c}isk\'y, Shyam Upadhyay, Bahare Fatemi, Mehran Kazemi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating Transcription Normalization in the Faetar ASR Benchmark</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.11771</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.11771v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We examine the role of transcription inconsistencies in the Faetar Automatic Speech Recognition benchmark, a challenging low-resource ASR benchmark. With the help of a small, hand-constructed lexicon, we conclude that find that, while inconsistencies do exist in the transcriptions, they are not the main challenge in the task. We also demonstrate that bigram word-based language modelling is of no added benefit, but that constraining decoding to a finite lexicon can be beneficial. The task remains extremely difficult.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.11771v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Leo Peckham, Michael Ong, Naomi Nagy, Ewan Dunbar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STEM: Efficient Relative Capability Evaluation of LLMs through Structured Transition Samples</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.12096</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.12096v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Evaluating large language models (LLMs) has become increasingly challenging as model capabilities advance rapidly. While recent models often achieve higher scores on standard benchmarks, these improvements do not consistently reflect enhanced real-world reasoning capabilities. Moreover, widespread overfitting to public benchmarks and the high computational cost of full evaluations have made it both expensive and less effective to distinguish meaningful differences between models. To address these challenges, we propose the \textbf{S}tructured \textbf{T}ransition \textbf{E}valuation \textbf{M}ethod (STEM), a lightweight and interpretable evaluation framework for efficiently estimating the relative capabilities of LLMs. STEM identifies \textit{significant transition samples} (STS) by analyzing consistent performance transitions among LLMs of the same architecture but varying parameter scales. These samples enable STEM to effectively estimate the capability position of an unknown model. Qwen3 model family is applied to construct the STS pool on six diverse and representative benchmarks. To assess generalizability. Experimental results indicate that STEM reliably captures performance trends, aligns with ground-truth rankings of model capability. These findings highlight STEM as a practical and scalable method for fine-grained, architecture-agnostic evaluation of LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.12096v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haiquan Hu, Jiazhi Jiang, Shiyou Xu, Ruhan Zeng, Tian Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CRED-SQL: Enhancing Real-world Large Scale Database Text-to-SQL Parsing through Cluster Retrieval and Execution Description</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.12769</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.12769v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advances in large language models (LLMs) have significantly improved the accuracy of Text-to-SQL systems. However, a critical challenge remains: the semantic mismatch between natural language questions (NLQs) and their corresponding SQL queries. This issue is exacerbated in large-scale databases, where semantically similar attributes hinder schema linking and semantic drift during SQL generation, ultimately reducing model accuracy. To address these challenges, we introduce CRED-SQL, a framework designed for large-scale databases that integrates Cluster Retrieval and Execution Description. CRED-SQL first performs cluster-based large-scale schema retrieval to pinpoint the tables and columns most relevant to a given NLQ, alleviating schema mismatch. It then introduces an intermediate natural language representation-Execution Description Language (EDL)-to bridge the gap between NLQs and SQL. This reformulation decomposes the task into two stages: Text-to-EDL and EDL-to-SQL, leveraging LLMs' strong general reasoning capabilities while reducing semantic deviation. Extensive experiments on two large-scale, cross-domain benchmarks-SpiderUnion and BirdUnion-demonstrate that CRED-SQL achieves new state-of-the-art (SOTA) performance, validating its effectiveness and scalability. Our code is available at https://github.com/smduan/CRED-SQL.git</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.12769v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shaoming Duan, Zirui Wang, Chuanyi Liu, Zhibin Zhu, Yuhao Zhang, Peiyi Han, Liang Yan, Zewu Peng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Pass@1: Self-Play with Variational Problem Synthesis Sustains RLVR</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.14029</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.14029v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Reinforcement Learning with Verifiable Rewards (RLVR) has recently emerged as a key paradigm for post-training Large Language Models (LLMs), particularly for complex reasoning tasks. However, vanilla RLVR training has been shown to improve Pass@1 performance at the expense of policy entropy, leading to reduced generation diversity and limiting the Pass@k performance, which typically represents the upper bound of LLM reasoning capability. In this paper, we systematically analyze the policy's generation diversity from the perspective of training problems and find that augmenting and updating training problems helps mitigate entropy collapse during training. Based on these observations, we propose an online Self-play with Variational problem Synthesis (SvS) strategy for RLVR training, which uses the policy's correct solutions to synthesize variational problems while ensuring their reference answers remain identical to the originals. This self-improving strategy effectively maintains policy entropy during training and substantially improves Pass@k compared with standard RLVR, sustaining prolonged improvements and achieving absolute gains of 18.3% and 22.8% in Pass@32 performance on the competition-level AIME24 and AIME25 benchmarks. Experiments on 12 reasoning benchmarks across varying model sizes from 3B to 32B consistently demonstrate the generalizability and robustness of SvS.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.14029v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiao Liang, Zhongzhi Li, Yeyun Gong, Yelong Shen, Ying Nian Wu, Zhijiang Guo, Weizhu Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Depression-Diagnosis-Oriented Chat with Psychological State Tracking</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.09717</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.09717v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Depression-diagnosis-oriented chat aims to guide patients in self-expression to collect key symptoms for depression detection. Recent work focuses on combining task-oriented dialogue and chitchat to simulate the interview-based depression diagnosis. Whereas, these methods can not well capture the changing information, feelings, or symptoms of the patient during dialogues. Moreover, no explicit framework has been explored to guide the dialogue, which results in some useless communications that affect the experience. In this paper, we propose to integrate Psychological State Tracking (POST) within the large language model (LLM) to explicitly guide depression-diagnosis-oriented chat. Specifically, the state is adapted from a psychological theoretical model, which consists of four components, namely Stage, Information, Summary and Next. We fine-tune an LLM model to generate the dynamic psychological state, which is further used to assist response generation at each turn to simulate the psychiatrist. Experimental results on the existing benchmark show that our proposed method boosts the performance of all subtasks in depression-diagnosis-oriented chat.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.09717v2</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yiyang Gu, Yougen Zhou, Qin Chen, Ningning Zhou, Jie Zhou, Aimin Zhou, Liang He</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LoRA-XS: Low-Rank Adaptation with Extremely Small Number of Parameters</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.17604</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.17604v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The growth of large language models underscores the need for parameter-efficient fine-tuning. Despite its popularity, LoRA encounters storage and computational challenges when deploying multiple task- or user-specific modules. To address this, we introduce LoRA-XS, a novel fine-tuning method backed by a theoretical derivation. LoRA-XS drastically reduces trainable parameters by incorporating a small, trainable weight matrix between frozen low-rank matrices derived from the Singular Value Decomposition of pre-trained weights. This design enables LoRA-XS to reduce storage requirements by over 100x in 7B models compared to LoRA. Additionally, unlike other methods, LoRA-XS imposes no lower bound on trainable parameters - it can scale from a single parameter per module to arbitrarily large values, adapting to any storage or computational constraint. Evaluations on GLUE, GSM8K, MATH, and commonsense reasoning benchmarks across different model scales reveal that LoRA-XS consistently outperforms or matches LoRA and VeRA in accuracy, offering unmatched parameter efficiency. Our ablation studies highlight the significance of singular vectors in transformer weights, establishing LoRA-XS as a powerful, storage-efficient solution for scaling and personalizing large language models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.17604v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Klaudia Ba{\l}azy, Mohammadreza Banaei, Karl Aberer, Jacek Tabor</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LGR2: Language Guided Reward Relabeling for Accelerating Hierarchical Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.05881</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.05881v5 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have shown remarkable abilities in logical reasoning, in-context learning, and code generation. However, translating natural language instructions into effective robotic control policies remains a significant challenge, especially for tasks requiring long-horizon planning and operating under sparse reward conditions. Hierarchical Reinforcement Learning (HRL) provides a natural framework to address this challenge in robotics; however, it typically suffers from non-stationarity caused by the changing behavior of the lower-level policy during training, destabilizing higher-level policy learning. We introduce LGR2, a novel HRL framework that leverages LLMs to generate language-guided reward functions for the higher-level policy. By decoupling high-level reward generation from low-level policy changes, LGR2 fundamentally mitigates the non-stationarity problem in off-policy HRL, enabling stable and efficient learning. To further enhance sample efficiency in sparse environments, we integrate goal-conditioned hindsight experience relabeling. Extensive experiments across simulated and real-world robotic navigation and manipulation tasks demonstrate LGR2 outperforms both hierarchical and non-hierarchical baselines, achieving over 55% success rates on challenging tasks and robust transfer to real robots, without additional fine-tuning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.05881v5</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Utsav Singh, Pramit Bhattacharyya, Vinay P. Namboodiri</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coupling without Communication and Drafter-Invariant Speculative Decoding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07978</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07978v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Suppose Alice has a distribution $P$ and Bob has a distribution $Q$. Alice wants to draw a sample $a\sim P$ and Bob a sample $b \sim Q$ such that $a = b$ with as high of probability as possible. It is well-known that, by sampling from an optimal coupling between the distributions, Alice and Bob can achieve $\Pr[a = b] = 1 - D_{TV}(P,Q)$, where $D_{TV}(P,Q)$ is the total variation distance between $P$ and $Q$. What if Alice and Bob must solve this same problem \emph{without communicating at all?} Perhaps surprisingly, with access to public randomness, they can still achieve $\Pr[a = b] \geq \frac{1 - D_{TV}(P,Q)}{1 + D_{TV}(P,Q)} \geq 1-2D_{TV}(P,Q)$ using a simple protocol based on the Weighted MinHash algorithm. This bound was shown to be optimal in the worst-case by [Bavarian et al., 2020]. In this work, we revisit the communication-free coupling problem. We provide a simpler proof of the optimality result from [Bavarian et al., 2020]. We show that, while the worst-case success probability of Weighted MinHash cannot be improved, an equally simple protocol based on Gumbel sampling offers a Pareto improvement: for every pair of distributions $P, Q$, Gumbel sampling achieves an equal or higher value of $\Pr[a = b]$ than Weighted MinHash. Importantly, this improvement translates to practice. We demonstrate an application of communication-free coupling to \emph{speculative decoding}, a recent method for accelerating autoregressive large language models [Leviathan, Kalman, Matias, ICML 2023]. We show that communication-free protocols can be used to contruct \emph{\CSD{}} schemes, which have the desirable property that their output is fixed given a fixed random seed, regardless of what drafter is used for speculation. In experiments on a language generation task, Gumbel sampling outperforms Weighted MinHash. Code is available at https://github.com/majid-daliri/DISD.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07978v4</guid>
      <category>cs.DS</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Majid Daliri, Christopher Musco, Ananda Theertha Suresh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ReSpark: Leveraging Previous Data Reports as References to Generate New Reports with LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.02329</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.02329v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Creating data reports is a labor-intensive task involving iterative data exploration, insight extraction, and narrative construction. A key challenge lies in composing the analysis logic-from defining objectives and transforming data to identifying and communicating insights. Manually crafting this logic can be cognitively demanding. While experienced analysts often reuse scripts from past projects, finding a perfect match for a new dataset is rare. Even when similar analyses are available online, they usually share only results or visualizations, not the underlying code, making reuse difficult. To address this, we present ReSpark, a system that leverages large language models (LLMs) to reverse-engineer analysis logic from existing reports and adapt it to new datasets. By generating draft analysis steps, ReSpark provides a warm start for users. It also supports interactive refinement, allowing users to inspect intermediate outputs, insert objectives, and revise content. We evaluate ReSpark through comparative and user studies, demonstrating its effectiveness in lowering the barrier to generating data reports without relying on existing analysis code.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.02329v2</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuan Tian, Chuhan Zhang, Xiaotong Wang, Sitong Pan, Weiwei Cui, Haidong Zhang, Dazhen Deng, Yingcai Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FMSD-TTS: Few-shot Multi-Speaker Multi-Dialect Text-to-Speech Synthesis for \"U-Tsang, Amdo and Kham Speech Dataset Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.14351</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.14351v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Tibetan is a low-resource language with minimal parallel speech corpora spanning its three major dialects-\"U-Tsang, Amdo, and Kham-limiting progress in speech modeling. To address this issue, we propose FMSD-TTS, a few-shot, multi-speaker, multi-dialect text-to-speech framework that synthesizes parallel dialectal speech from limited reference audio and explicit dialect labels. Our method features a novel speaker-dialect fusion module and a Dialect-Specialized Dynamic Routing Network (DSDR-Net) to capture fine-grained acoustic and linguistic variations across dialects while preserving speaker identity. Extensive objective and subjective evaluations demonstrate that FMSD-TTS significantly outperforms baselines in both dialectal expressiveness and speaker similarity. We further validate the quality and utility of the synthesized speech through a challenging speech-to-speech dialect conversion task. Our contributions include: (1) a novel few-shot TTS system tailored for Tibetan multi-dialect speech synthesis, (2) the public release of a large-scale synthetic Tibetan speech corpus generated by FMSD-TTS, and (3) an open-source evaluation toolkit for standardized assessment of speaker similarity, dialect consistency, and audio quality.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.14351v3</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yutong Liu, Ziyue Zhang, Ban Ma-bao, Yuqing Cai, Yongbin Yu, Renzeng Duojie, Xiangxiang Wang, Fan Gao, Cheng Huang, Nyima Tashi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Autonomy to Agency: Agentic Vehicles for Human-Centered Mobility Systems</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.04996</link>
      <description>arXiv:2507.04996v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Autonomy, from the Greek autos (self) and nomos (law), refers to the capacity to operate according to internal rules without external control. Accordingly, autonomous vehicles (AuVs) are viewed as vehicular systems capable of perceiving their environment and executing pre-programmed tasks independently of external input. However, both research and real-world deployments increasingly showcase vehicles that demonstrate behaviors beyond this definition (including the SAE levels 0 to 5); Examples of this outpace include the interaction with humans with natural language, goal adaptation, contextual reasoning, external tool use, and unseen ethical dilemma handling, largely empowered by multi-modal large language models (LLMs). These developments reveal a conceptual gap between technical autonomy and the broader cognitive and social capabilities needed for future human-centered mobility systems. To address this gap, this paper introduces the concept of agentic vehicles (AgVs), referring to vehicles that integrate agentic AI systems to reason, adapt, and interact within complex environments. This paper proposes the term AgVs and their distinguishing characteristics from conventional AuVs. It synthesizes relevant advances in integrating LLMs and AuVs and highlights how AgVs might transform future mobility systems and ensure the systems are human-centered. The paper concludes by identifying key challenges in the development and governance of AgVs, and how they can play a significant role in future agentic transportation systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2507.04996v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.CE</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiangbo Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DeepRetro: Retrosynthetic Pathway Discovery using Iterative LLM Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.07060</link>
      <description>arXiv:2507.07060v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The synthesis of complex natural products remains one of the grand challenges of organic chemistry. We present DeepRetro, a major advancement in computational retrosynthesis that enables the discovery of viable synthetic routes for complex molecules typically considered beyond the reach of existing retrosynthetic methods. DeepRetro is a novel, open-source framework that tightly integrates large language models (LLMs), traditional retrosynthetic engines, and expert human feedback in an iterative design loop. Prior approaches rely solely on template-based methods or unconstrained LLM outputs. In contrast, DeepRetro combines the precision of template-based methods with the generative flexibility of LLMs, controlled by rigorous chemical validity checks and enhanced by recursive refinement. This hybrid system dynamically explores and revises synthetic pathways, guided by both algorithmic checks and expert chemist feedback through an interactive user interface. While DeepRetro achieves strong performance on standard retrosynthesis benchmarks, its true strength lies in its ability to propose novel, viable pathways to highly complex natural products-targets that have historically eluded automated planning. Through detailed case studies, we illustrate how this approach enables new routes for total synthesis and facilitates human-machine collaboration in organic chemistry. Beyond retrosynthesis, DeepRetro represents a working model for how to leverage LLMs in scientific discovery. We provide a transparent account of the system's design, algorithms, and human-feedback loop, enabling broad adaptation across scientific domains. By releasing DeepRetro as an open-source tool, we aim to empower chemists to tackle increasingly ambitious synthetic targets, accelerating progress in drug discovery, materials design, and beyond.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2507.07060v2</guid>
      <category>q-bio.QM</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>q-bio.BM</category>
      <category>q-bio.MN</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shreyas Vinaya Sathyanarayana, Sharanabasava D. Hiremath, Rahil Shah, Rishikesh Panda, Rahul Jana, Riya Singh, Rida Irfan, Ashwin Murali, Bharath Ramsundar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CRINN: Contrastive Reinforcement Learning for Approximate Nearest Neighbor Search</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.02091</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.02091v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Approximate nearest-neighbor search (ANNS) algorithms have become increasingly critical for recent AI applications, particularly in retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) and agent-based LLM applications. In this paper, we present CRINN, a new paradigm for ANNS algorithms. CRINN treats ANNS optimization as a reinforcement learning problem where execution speed serves as the reward signal. This approach enables the automatic generation of progressively faster ANNS implementations while maintaining accuracy constraints. Our experimental evaluation demonstrates CRINN's effectiveness across six widely-used NNS benchmark datasets. When compared against state-of-the-art open-source ANNS algorithms, CRINN achieves best performance on three of them (GIST-960-Euclidean, MNIST-784-Euclidean, and GloVe-25-angular), and tied for first place on two of them (SIFT-128-Euclidean and GloVe-25-angular). The implications of CRINN's success reach well beyond ANNS optimization: It validates that LLMs augmented with reinforcement learning can function as an effective tool for automating sophisticated algorithmic optimizations that demand specialized knowledge and labor-intensive manual refinement. Code can be found at https://github.com/deepreinforce-ai/CRINN</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.02091v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.DB</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoya Li, Xiaofei Sun, Albert Wang, Chris Shum, Jiwei Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ExpVG: Investigating the Design Space of Visual Grounding in Multimodal Large Language Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.08066</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.08066v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Fine-grained multimodal capability in Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) has emerged as a critical research direction, particularly for tackling the visual grounding (VG) problem. Despite the strong performance achieved by existing approaches, they often employ disparate design choices when fine-tuning MLLMs for VG, lacking systematic verification to support these designs. To bridge this gap, this paper presents a comprehensive study of various design choices that impact the VG performance of MLLMs. We conduct our analysis using LLaVA-1.5, which has been widely adopted in prior empirical studies of MLLMs. While more recent models exist, we follow this convention to ensure our findings remain broadly applicable and extendable to other architectures. We cover two key aspects: (1) exploring different visual grounding paradigms in MLLMs, identifying the most effective design, and providing our insights; and (2) conducting ablation studies on the design of grounding data to optimize MLLMs' fine-tuning for the VG task. Finally, our findings contribute to a stronger MLLM for VG, achieving improvements of +5.6% / +6.9% / +7.0% on RefCOCO/+/g over the LLaVA-1.5.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.08066v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weitai Kang, Weiming Zhuang, Zhizhong Li, Yan Yan, Lingjuan Lyu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BeyondWeb: Lessons from Scaling Synthetic Data for Trillion-scale Pretraining</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.10975</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.10975v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Recent advances in large language model (LLM) pretraining have shown that simply scaling data quantity eventually leads to diminishing returns, hitting a data wall. In response, the use of synthetic data for pretraining has emerged as a promising paradigm for pushing the frontier of performance. Despite this, the factors affecting synthetic data quality remain poorly understood. In this work, we introduce BeyondWeb, a synthetic data generation framework that produces high-quality synthetic data for pretraining. BeyondWeb significantly extends the capabilities of traditional web-scale datasets, outperforming state-of-the-art synthetic pretraining datasets such as Cosmopedia and Nemotron-CC's high-quality synthetic subset (Nemotron-Synth) by up to 5.1 percentage points (pp) and 2.6pp, respectively, when averaged across a suite of 14 benchmark evaluations. It delivers up to 7.7x faster training than open web data and 2.7x faster than Nemotron-Synth. Remarkably, a 3B model trained for 180B tokens on BeyondWeb outperforms an 8B model trained for the same token budget on Cosmopedia. We also present several insights from BeyondWeb on synthetic data for pretraining: what drives its benefits, which data to rephrase and how, and the impact of model size and family on data quality. Overall, our work shows that there's no silver bullet for generating high-quality synthetic pretraining data. The best outcomes require jointly optimizing many factors, a challenging task that requires rigorous science and practical expertise. Naive approaches can yield modest improvements, potentially at great cost, while well-executed methods can yield transformative improvements, as exemplified by BeyondWeb.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.10975v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator> DatologyAI,  :, Pratyush Maini, Vineeth Dorna, Parth Doshi, Aldo Carranza, Fan Pan, Jack Urbanek, Paul Burstein, Alex Fang, Alvin Deng, Amro Abbas, Brett Larsen, Cody Blakeney, Charvi Bannur, Christina Baek, Darren Teh, David Schwab, Haakon Mongstad, Haoli Yin, Josh Wills, Kaleigh Mentzer, Luke Merrick, Ricardo Monti, Rishabh Adiga, Siddharth Joshi, Spandan Das, Zhengping Wang, Bogdan Gaza, Ari Morcos, Matthew Leavitt</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TASER: Table Agents for Schema-guided Extraction and Recommendation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.13404</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.13404v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Real-world financial documents report essential information about an entity's financial holdings that can span millions of different financial instrument types. Yet, these details are often buried in messy, multi-page, fragmented tables - for example, 99.4% of the tables in our dataset have no bounding boxes with the maximum number of rows amounting to 426 per table across 44 pages. To tackle these unique challenges from real-world tables, we present a continuously learning, agentic table extraction system, TASER (Table Agents for Schema-guided Extraction and Recommendation) that extracts highly unstructured, multi-page, heterogeneous tables into normalized, schema-conforming outputs. Our table agents execute on table detection, classification, extraction, and recommendations by leveraging an initial schema. Then, our Recommender Agent reviews the outputs, recommends schema revisions, and decides on the final recommendations, enabling TASER to outperform existing table detection models such as Table Transformer by 10.1%. Within this continuous learning process, we highlight that larger batch sizes result in a 104.3% increase in schema recommendations that are actionable and utilized, resulting in a 9.8% increase in extracted holdings - highlighting the importance of a continuous learning process. To train TASER, we have manually labeled 22,584 pages (28,150,449 tokens), 3,213 tables for $731,685,511,687 of holdings culminating in one of the first real financial table datasets. We release our dataset TASERTab to enable the research community to access real-world financial tables and outputs. Our results highlight the promise of agentic, schema-guided extraction systems for robust understanding of real-world financial tables.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.13404v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nicole Cho, Kirsty Fielding, William Watson, Sumitra Ganesh, Manuela Veloso</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Input Time Scaling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.13654</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.13654v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Current Large Language Models (LLMs) are usually post-trained on large-scale carefully curated datasets (data &amp; training scaling) and doing reasoning in test time (inference time scaling). In this work, we present a new scaling paradigm, Input Time Scaling, to complement previous scaling methods by putting resources on queries (input time). During training and testing, we combine meta-knowledge from LLMs to refine inputs with different strategies. We also find a new phenomenon, training-testing co-design there. We need to apply query strategies during both training and testing. Only applying strategies on training or testing would seriously degrade the performance. We are also surprised to find that seemingly low data quality datasets can gain high performance. Adding irrelevant information to the queries, randomly selecting examples from a minimally filtered dataset, can even perform the best. These findings contradict the widely held inductive bias, "garbage in, garbage out". Curating datasets with seemingly high-quality data can even potentially limit the performance ceiling. In addition, models trained on more data with similar quality (15k VS 1k) perform worse, simple dataset size scaling should also be carefully inspected. The good news is that our findings are compatible with the Less is More phenomenon. A small set of examples is enough to evoke high-level reasoning ability. With experiments on models trained on Qwen2.5-32B-Instruct, we are able to reach SOTA performance among 32B models on AIME24(76.7%) and AIME25(76.7%) pass@1. We can further achieve AIME24(76.7%) and AIME25(80%) with a majority vote of three models. Starting from DeepSeek-R1-Distill-Qwen-32B, the best result would be 86.7% on AIME24 and 76.7% on AIME25. To facilitate reproducibility and further research, we are working on open-source our datasets, data pipelines, evaluation results, and checkpoints.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.13654v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rapheal Huang (Yuming), Weilong Guo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RotBench: Evaluating Multimodal Large Language Models on Identifying Image Rotation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.13968</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.13968v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We investigate to what extent Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) can accurately identify the orientation of input images rotated 0{\deg}, 90{\deg}, 180{\deg}, and 270{\deg}. This task demands robust visual reasoning capabilities to detect rotational cues and contextualize spatial relationships within images, regardless of their orientation. To evaluate MLLMs on these abilities, we introduce RotBench -- a 350-image manually-filtered benchmark comprising lifestyle, portrait, and landscape images. Despite the relatively simple nature of this task, we show that several state-of-the-art open and proprietary MLLMs, including GPT-5, o3, and Gemini-2.5-Pro, do not reliably identify rotation in input images. Providing models with auxiliary information -- including captions, depth maps, and more -- or using chain-of-thought prompting offers only small and inconsistent improvements. Our results indicate that most models are able to reliably identify right-side-up (0{\deg}) images, while certain models are able to identify upside-down (180{\deg}) images. None can reliably distinguish between 90{\deg} and 270{\deg}. Simultaneously showing the image rotated in different orientations leads to moderate performance gains for reasoning models, while a modified setup using voting improves the performance of weaker models. We further show that fine-tuning does not improve models' ability to distinguish 90{\deg} and 270{\deg} rotations, despite substantially improving the identification of 180{\deg} images. Together, these results reveal a significant gap between MLLMs' spatial reasoning capabilities and human perception in identifying rotation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.13968v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tianyi Niu, Jaemin Cho, Elias Stengel-Eskin, Mohit Bansal</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
