<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL</link>
    <description>cs.CL updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 05:00:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Sunday</day>
      <day>Saturday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>Entropy-Based Measurement of Value Drift and Alignment Work in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03047</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03047v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language model safety is usually assessed with static benchmarks, but key failures are dynamic: value drift under distribution shift, jailbreak attacks, and slow degradation of alignment in deployment. Building on a recent Second Law of Intelligence that treats ethical entropy as a state variable which tends to increase unless countered by alignment work, we make this framework operational for large language models. We define a five-way behavioral taxonomy, train a classifier to estimate ethical entropy S(t) from model transcripts, and measure entropy dynamics for base and instruction-tuned variants of four frontier models across stress tests. Base models show sustained entropy growth, while tuned variants suppress drift and reduce ethical entropy by roughly eighty percent. From these trajectories we estimate an effective alignment work rate gamma_eff and embed S(t) and gamma_eff in a monitoring pipeline that raises alerts when entropy drift exceeds a stability threshold, enabling run-time oversight of value drift.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03047v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Samih Fadli</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Watermarks for Embeddings-as-a-Service Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03079</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03079v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated exceptional capabilities in natural language understanding and generation. Based on these LLMs, businesses have started to provide Embeddings-as-a-Service (EaaS), offering feature extraction capabilities (in the form of text embeddings) that benefit downstream natural language processing tasks. However, prior research has demonstrated that EaaS is vulnerable to imitation attacks, where an attacker clones the service's model in a black-box manner without access to the model's internal workings. In response, watermarks have been added to the text embeddings to protect the intellectual property of EaaS providers by allowing them to check for model ownership. This thesis focuses on defending against imitation attacks by investigating EaaS watermarks. To achieve this goal, we unveil novel attacks and propose and validate new watermarking techniques.
  Firstly, we show that existing EaaS watermarks can be removed through paraphrasing the input text when attackers clone the model during imitation attacks. Our study illustrates that paraphrasing can effectively bypass current state-of-the-art EaaS watermarks across various attack setups (including different paraphrasing techniques and models) and datasets in most instances. This demonstrates a new vulnerability in recent EaaS watermarking techniques.
  Subsequently, as a countermeasure, we propose a novel watermarking technique, WET (Watermarking EaaS with Linear Transformation), which employs linear transformation of the embeddings. Watermark verification is conducted by applying a reverse transformation and comparing the similarity between recovered and original embeddings. We demonstrate its robustness against paraphrasing attacks with near-perfect verifiability. We conduct detailed ablation studies to assess the significance of each component and hyperparameter in WET.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03079v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Anudeex Shetty</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alleviating Choice Supportive Bias in LLM with Reasoning Dependency Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03082</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03082v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent studies have demonstrated that some Large Language Models exhibit choice-supportive bias (CSB) when performing evaluations, systematically favoring their chosen options and potentially compromising the objectivity of AI-assisted decision making. While existing debiasing approaches primarily target demographic and social biases, methods for addressing cognitive biases in LLMs remain largely unexplored. In this work, we present the first solution to address CSB through Reasoning Dependency Generation (RDG), a novel framework for generating unbiased reasoning data to mitigate choice-supportive bias through fine-tuning. RDG automatically constructs balanced reasoning QA pairs, explicitly (un)modeling the dependencies between choices, evidences, and justifications. Our approach is able to generate a large-scale dataset of QA pairs across domains, incorporating Contextual Dependency Data and Dependency Decouple Data. Experiments show that LLMs fine-tuned on RDG-generated data demonstrate a 81.5% improvement in memory-based experiments and 94.3% improvement in the evaluation-based experiment, while maintaining similar performance on standard BBQ benchmarks. This work pioneers an approach for addressing cognitive biases in LLMs and contributes to the development of more reliable AI-assisted decision support systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03082v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nan Zhuang, Wenshuo Wang, Lekai Qian, Yuxiao Wang, Boyu Cao, Qi Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Job Matching: Occupation, Skill and Qualification Linking with the ESCO and EQF taxonomies</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03195</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03195v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This study investigates the potential of language models to improve the classification of labor market information by linking job vacancy texts to two major European frameworks: the European Skills, Competences, Qualifications and Occupations (ESCO) taxonomy and the European Qualifications Framework (EQF). We examine and compare two prominent methodologies from the literature: Sentence Linking and Entity Linking. In support of ongoing research, we release an open-source tool, incorporating these two methodologies, designed to facilitate further work on labor classification and employment discourse. To move beyond surface-level skill extraction, we introduce two annotated datasets specifically aimed at evaluating how occupations and qualifications are represented within job vacancy texts. Additionally, we examine different ways to utilize generative large language models for this task. Our findings contribute to advancing the state of the art in job entity extraction and offer computational infrastructure for examining work, skills, and labor market narratives in a digitally mediated economy. Our code is made publicly available: https://github.com/tabiya-tech/tabiya-livelihoods-classifier</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03195v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Stylianos Saroglou, Konstantinos Diamantaras, Francesco Preta, Marina Delianidi, Apostolos Benisis, Christian Johannes Meyer</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>InvertiTune: High-Quality Data Synthesis for Cost-Effective Single-Shot Text-to-Knowledge Graph Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03197</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03197v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have revolutionized the ability to understand and generate text, enabling significant progress in automatic knowledge graph construction from text (Text2KG). Many Text2KG methods, however, rely on iterative LLM prompting, making them computationally expensive and prone to overlooking complex relations distributed throughout the text. To address these limitations, we propose InvertiTune, a framework that combines a controlled data generation pipeline with supervised fine-tuning (SFT). Within this framework, the data-generation pipeline systematically extracts subgraphs from large knowledge bases, applies noise filtering, and leverages LLMs to generate corresponding natural text descriptions, a task more aligned with LLM capabilities than direct KG generation from text. This pipeline enables generating datasets composed of longer texts paired with larger KGs that better reflect real-world scenarios compared to existing benchmarks, thus supporting effective SFT of lightweight models for single-shot KG construction. Experimental results on CE12k, a dataset generated using the introduced pipeline, show that InvertiTune outperforms larger non-fine-tuned LLMs as well as state-of-the-art Text2KG approaches, while also demonstrating stronger cross-dataset generalization on CrossEval-1200, a test set created from three established benchmark datasets and CE12k. These findings highlight the importance of realistic, high-quality training data for advancing efficient and high-performing Text2KG systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03197v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Faezeh Faez, Marzieh S. Tahaei, Yaochen Hu, Ali Pourranjbar, Mahdi Biparva, Mark Coates, Yingxue Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identifying attributions of causality in political text</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03214</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03214v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Explanations are a fundamental element of how people make sense of the political world. Citizens routinely ask and answer questions about why events happen, who is responsible, and what could or should be done differently. Yet despite their importance, explanations remain an underdeveloped object of systematic analysis in political science, and existing approaches are fragmented and often issue-specific. I introduce a framework for detecting and parsing explanations in political text. To do this, I train a lightweight causal language model that returns a structured data set of causal claims in the form of cause-effect pairs for downstream analysis. I demonstrate how causal explanations can be studied at scale, and show the method's modest annotation requirements, generalizability, and accuracy relative to human coding.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03214v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Paulina Garcia-Corral</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Randomized Masked Finetuning: An Efficient Way to Mitigate Memorization of PIIs in LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03310</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03310v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The current literature on memorization in Natural Language Models, especially Large Language Models (LLMs), poses severe security and privacy risks, as models tend to memorize personally identifying information (PIIs) from training data. We introduce Randomized Masked Fine-Tuning (RMFT), a novel privacy-preserving fine-tuning technique that reduces PII memorization while minimizing performance impact. Using the Enron Email Dataset, we demonstrate that RMFT achieves an 80.81% reduction in Total Extraction Rate and 80.17% reduction in Seen Extraction Rate compared to baseline fine-tuning, outperforming deduplication methods while maintaining only a 5.73% increase in perplexity. We present MaxTER, a Pareto-optimal evaluation framework for assessing privacy-utility tradeoffs, and show the performance of RMFT vs Deduplication by Area Under The Response Curve (AURC) metric.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03310v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kunj Joshi, David A. Smith</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling Topics and Sociolinguistic Variation in Code-Switched Discourse: Insights from Spanish-English and Spanish-Guaran\'i</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03334</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03334v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This study presents an LLM-assisted annotation pipeline for the sociolinguistic and topical analysis of bilingual discourse in two typologically distinct contexts: Spanish-English and Spanish-Guaran\'i. Using large language models, we automatically labeled topic, genre, and discourse-pragmatic functions across a total of 3,691 code-switched sentences, integrated demographic metadata from the Miami Bilingual Corpus, and enriched the Spanish-Guaran\'i dataset with new topic annotations. The resulting distributions reveal systematic links between gender, language dominance, and discourse function in the Miami data, and a clear diglossic division between formal Guaran\'i and informal Spanish in Paraguayan texts. These findings replicate and extend earlier interactional and sociolinguistic observations with corpus-scale quantitative evidence. The study demonstrates that large language models can reliably recover interpretable sociolinguistic patterns traditionally accessible only through manual annotation, advancing computational methods for cross-linguistic and low-resource bilingual research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03334v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nemika Tyagi, Nelvin Licona Guevara, Olga Kellert</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PERCS: Persona-Guided Controllable Biomedical Summarization Dataset</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03340</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03340v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Automatic medical text simplification plays a key role in improving health literacy by making complex biomedical research accessible to diverse readers. However, most existing resources assume a single generic audience, overlooking the wide variation in medical literacy and information needs across user groups. To address this limitation, we introduce PERCS (Persona-guided Controllable Summarization), a dataset of biomedical abstracts paired with summaries tailored to four personas: Laypersons, Premedical Students, Non-medical Researchers, and Medical Experts. These personas represent different levels of medical literacy and information needs, emphasizing the need for targeted, audience-specific summarization. Each summary in PERCS was reviewed by physicians for factual accuracy and persona alignment using a detailed error taxonomy. Technical validation shows clear differences in readability, vocabulary, and content depth across personas. Along with describing the dataset, we benchmark four large language models on PERCS using automatic evaluation metrics that assess comprehensiveness, readability, and faithfulness, establishing baseline results for future research. The dataset, annotation guidelines, and evaluation materials are publicly available to support research on persona-specific communication and controllable biomedical summarization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03340v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rohan Charudatt Salvi, Chirag Chawla, Dhruv Jain, Swapnil Panigrahi, Md Shad Akhtar, Shweta Yadav</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Idea-Gated Transformers: Enforcing Semantic Coherence via Differentiable Vocabulary Pruning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03343</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03343v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Autoregressive Language Models (LLMs) trained on Next-Token Prediction (NTP) often suffer from ``Topic Drift'' where the generation wanders away from the initial prompt due to a reliance on local associations rather than global planning \citep{holtzman2019curious}. While scaling model size mitigates this \citep{brown2020language}, the fundamental myopia of the NTP objective remains. In this work, we introduce the Idea-Gated Transformer, a novel architecture that separates semantic planning from syntactic generation. We introduce an auxiliary ``Idea Head'' trained to predict the bag-of-words distribution for a future context window, creating a latent ``Concept Vector'' that actively gates the main vocabulary during generation. We propose a differentiable gating mechanism that suppresses semantically irrelevant tokens, effectively pruning the search space in real-time. Experiments on WikiText-103 demonstrate that while the Idea-Gated model achieves comparable validation perplexity to a standard GPT-2 baseline, it exhibits significantly superior Domain Retention. Qualitative and quantitative analysis reveals that the gating mechanism successfully locks generation into specific semantic clusters (e.g., Finance, Science) and resists associative drift, offering a parameter-efficient path toward more controllable language modeling.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03343v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Darshan Fofadiya</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Hypothesis to Premises: LLM-based Backward Logical Reasoning with Selective Symbolic Translation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03360</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03360v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Logical reasoning is a core challenge in natural language understanding and a fundamental capability of artificial intelligence, underpinning scientific discovery, mathematical theorem proving, and complex decision-making. Despite the remarkable progress of large language models (LLMs), most current approaches still rely on forward reasoning paradigms, generating step-by-step rationales from premises to conclusions. However, such methods often suffer from redundant inference paths, hallucinated steps, and semantic drift, resulting in inefficient and unreliable reasoning. In this paper, we propose a novel framework, Hypothesis-driven Backward Logical Reasoning (HBLR). The core idea is to integrate confidence-aware symbolic translation with hypothesis-driven backward reasoning. In the translation phase, only high-confidence spans are converted into logical form, such as First-Order Logic (FOL), while uncertain content remains in natural language. A translation reflection module further ensures semantic fidelity by evaluating symbolic outputs and reverting lossy ones back to text when necessary. In the reasoning phase, HBLR simulates human deductive thinking by assuming the conclusion is true and recursively verifying its premises. A reasoning reflection module further identifies and corrects flawed inference steps, enhancing logical coherence. Extensive experiments on five reasoning benchmarks demonstrate that HBLR consistently outperforms strong baselines in both accuracy and efficiency.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03360v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qingchuan Li, Mingyue Cheng, Zirui Liu, Daoyu Wang, Yuting Zeng, Tongxuan Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nexus: Higher-Order Attention Mechanisms in Transformers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03377</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03377v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Transformers have achieved significant success across various domains, relying on self-attention to capture dependencies. However, the standard first-order attention mechanism is often limited by a low-rank bottleneck, struggling to capture intricate, multi-hop relationships within a single layer. In this paper, we propose the \textbf{Higher-Order Attention Network (Hon)}, a novel architecture designed to enhance representational power through a recursive framework. Unlike standard approaches that use static linear projections for Queries and Keys, Hon dynamically refines these representations via nested self-attention mechanisms. Specifically, the Query and Key vectors are themselves outputs of inner attention loops, allowing tokens to aggregate global context and model high-order correlations \textit{prior} to the final attention computation. We enforce a parameter-efficient weight-sharing strategy across recursive steps, ensuring that this enhanced expressivity incurs $\mathcal{O}(1)$ additional parameters. We provide theoretical analysis demonstrating that our method breaks the linear bottleneck of standard attention. Empirically, Hon outperforms standard Transformers on multiple benchmarks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03377v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hanting Chen, Chu Zhong, Kai Han, Yuchuan Tian, Yuchen Liang, Tianyu Guo, Xinghao Chen, Dacheng Tao, Yunhe Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characterizing Language Use in a Collaborative Situated Game</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03381</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03381v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Cooperative video games, where multiple participants must coordinate by communicating and reasoning under uncertainty in complex environments, yield a rich source of language data. We collect the Portal Dialogue Corpus: a corpus of 11.5 hours of spoken human dialogue in the co-op mode of the popular Portal 2 virtual puzzle game, comprising 24.5K total utterances. We analyze player language and behavior, identifying a number of linguistic phenomena that rarely appear in most existing chitchat or task-oriented dialogue corpora, including complex spatial reference, clarification and repair, and ad-hoc convention formation. To support future analyses of language use in complex, situated, collaborative problem-solving scenarios, we publicly release the corpus, which comprises player videos, audio, transcripts, game state data, and both manual and automatic annotations of language data.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03381v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nicholas Tomlin (Circle), Naitian Zhou (Circle), Eve Fleisig (Circle),  Liangyuan (Circle),  Chen, T\'ea Wright, Lauren Vinh, Laura X. Ma, Seun Eisape, Ellie French, Tingting Du, Tianjiao Zhang, Alexander Koller, Alane Suhr</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual LoRA: Enhancing LoRA with Magnitude and Direction Updates</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03402</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03402v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Low-rank adaptation (LoRA) is one of the most popular methods among parameter-efficient fine-tuning (PEFT) methods to adapt pre-trained large language models (LLMs) to specific downstream tasks. However, the model trained based on LoRA often has an unsatisfactory performance due to its low-rank assumption. In this paper, we propose a novel method called Dual LoRA to improve the performance by incorporating an inductive bias into the original LoRA. Specifically, we separate low-rank matrices into two groups: the magnitude group to control whether or not and how far we should update a parameter and the direction group to decide whether this parameter should move forward or backward, to better simulate the parameter updating process of the full fine-tuning based on gradient-based optimization algorithms. We show that this can be simply achieved by adding a ReLU function to the magnitude group and a sign function to the direction group. We conduct several experiments over a wide range of NLP tasks, including natural language generation (NLG), understanding (NLU), and commonsense reasoning datasets on GPT-2, RoBERTa, DeBERTa, and LLaMA-1/2/3 as baseline models. The results show that we consistently outperform LoRA and its state-of-the-art variants with the same number of trainable parameters.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03402v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yixing Xu, Chao Li, Xuanwu Yin, Spandan Tiwari, Dong Li, Ashish Sirasao, Emad Barsoum</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PretrainZero: Reinforcement Active Pretraining</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03442</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03442v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Mimicking human behavior to actively learning from general experience and achieve artificial general intelligence has always been a human dream. Recent reinforcement learning (RL) based large-thinking models demonstrate impressive expert-level abilities, i.e., software and math, but still rely heavily on verifiable rewards in specific domains, placing a significant bottleneck to extend the performance boundary of general reasoning capabilities. In this work, we propose PretrainZero, a reinforcement active learning framework built on the pretraining corpus to extend RL from domain-specific post-training to general pretraining. PretrainZero features the following characteristics: 1) Active pretraining: inspired by the active learning ability of humans, PretrainZero learns a unified reasoning policy to actively identify reasonable and informative contents from pretraining corpus, and reason to predict these contents by RL. 2) Self-supervised learning: without any verifiable labels, pretrained reward models, or supervised fine-tuning, we directly pretrain reasoners from 3 to 30B base models on the general Wikipedia corpus using RL, significantly breaking the verification data-wall for general reasoning. 3) Verification scaling: by tackling increasingly challenging masked spans, PretrainZero substantially enhances the general reasoning abilities of pretrained base models. In reinforcement pretraining, PretrainZero improves Qwen3-4B-Base for 8.43, 5.96 and 10.60 on MMLU-Pro, SuperGPQA and math average benchmarks. In post-training, the pretrained models can also serve as reasoning foundation models for downstream RLVR tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03442v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xingrun Xing, Zhiyuan Fan, Jie Lou, Guoqi Li, Jiajun Zhang, Debing Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Preliminary Study on the Promises and Challenges of Native Top-$k$ Sparse Attention</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03494</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03494v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) are increasingly prevalent in the field of long-context modeling, however, their inference computational costs have become a critical bottleneck hindering the advancement of tasks such as agents and multimodal applications. This report conducts a preliminary investigation into the effectiveness and theoretical mechanisms of the Top-$k$ Attention mechanism during both the decoding and training phases. First, we validate the effectiveness of exact Top-$k$ Decoding through extensive experimentation. Experiments demonstrate that retaining only the pivotal Keys with the highest similarity to the Query as the context window during the decoding stage achieves performance comparable to, or even surpassing, full attention on downstream tasks such as HELMET and LongBench v2. Second, we further explore the native Top-$k$ Attention training strategy. Experiments confirm that ensuring the consistency between training and inference regarding Top-$k$ Attention operations facilitates the further unlocking of Top-$k$ Decoding's potential, thereby significantly enhancing model performance. Furthermore, considering the high computational complexity of exact Top-$k$ Attention, we investigate the impact of approximate Top-$k$ algorithm precision on downstream tasks. Our research confirms a positive correlation between downstream task performance and approximation fidelity, and we provide statistical evaluations of the Lightning Indexer's precision within the DeepSeek-V3.2-Exp model. Finally, this report provides a theoretical interpretation from the perspective of Entropy. Experimental observations indicate that models subjected to Top-$k$ Attention SFT exhibit a distinct phenomenon of entropy reduction in downstream tasks, which validates the hypothesis that low-entropy states are better adapted to Top-$k$ Decoding.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03494v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Di Xiu, Hongyin Tang, Bolin Rong, Lizhi Yan, Jingang Wang, Yifan Lu, Xunliang Cai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding LLM Reasoning for Abstractive Summarization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03503</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03503v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: While the reasoning capabilities of Large Language Models (LLMs) excel in analytical tasks such as mathematics and code generation, their utility for abstractive summarization remains widely assumed but largely unverified. To bridge this gap, we first tailor general reasoning strategies to the summarization domain. We then conduct a systematic, large scale comparative study of 8 reasoning strategies and 3 Large Reasoning Models (LRMs) across 8 diverse datasets, assessing both summary quality and faithfulness. Our findings show that reasoning is not a universal solution and its effectiveness is highly dependent on the specific strategy and context. Specifically, we observe a trade-off between summary quality and factual faithfulness: explicit reasoning strategies tend to improve fluency at the expense of factual grounding, while implicit reasoning in LRMs exhibits the inverse pattern. Furthermore, increasing an LRM's internal reasoning budget does not improve, and can even hurt, factual consistency, suggesting that effective summarization demands faithful compression rather than creative over-thinking.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03503v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haohan Yuan, Siu Cheung Hui, Haopeng Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fine-grained Narrative Classification in Biased News Articles</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03582</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03582v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Narratives are the cognitive and emotional scaffolds of propaganda. They organize isolated persuasive techniques into coherent stories that justify actions, attribute blame, and evoke identification with ideological camps. In this paper, we propose a novel fine-grained narrative classification in biased news articles. We also explore article-bias classification as the precursor task to narrative classification and fine-grained persuasive technique identification. We develop INDI-PROP, the first ideologically grounded fine-grained narrative dataset with multi-level annotation for analyzing propaganda in Indian news media. Our dataset INDI-PROP comprises 1,266 articles focusing on two polarizing socio-political events in recent times: CAA and the Farmers' protest. Each article is annotated at three hierarchical levels: (i) ideological article-bias (pro-government, pro-opposition, neutral), (ii) event-specific fine-grained narrative frames anchored in ideological polarity and communicative intent, and (iii) persuasive techniques. We propose FANTA and TPTC, two GPT-4o-mini guided multi-hop prompt-based reasoning frameworks for the bias, narrative, and persuasive technique classification. FANTA leverages multi-layered communicative phenomena by integrating information extraction and contextual framing for hierarchical reasoning. On the other hand, TPTC adopts systematic decomposition of persuasive cues via a two-stage approach. Our evaluation suggests substantial improvement over underlying baselines in each case.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03582v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zeba Afroz, Harsh Vardhan, Pawan Bhakuni, Aanchal Punia, Rajdeep Kumar, Md. Shad Akhtar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AlignCheck: a Semantic Open-Domain Metric for Factual Consistency Assessment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03634</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03634v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models have significantly advanced natural language processing tasks, but remain prone to generating incorrect or misleading but plausible arguments. This issue, known as hallucination, is particularly concerning in high-stakes domains like clinical applications, where factual inaccuracies can have severe consequences. Existing evaluation metrics fail to adequately assess factual consistency and lack interpretability, making diagnosing and mitigating errors difficult. We propose an interpretable framework for factual consistency assessment for in-domain and open-domain texts to address these limitations. Our approach decomposes text into atomic facts and introduces a flexible, schema-free methodology. Unlike previous methods with an absolute metric, we incorporate a weighted metric to enhance factual evaluation. Additionally, we propose a mechanism to control assessment complexity in intricate domains. We benchmark our approach on popular general and clinical datasets and release our code to support fact-aware model training in future research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03634v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ahmad Aghaebrahimian</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generative AI Practices, Literacy, and Divides: An Empirical Analysis in the Italian Context</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03671</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03671v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The rise of Artificial Intelligence (AI) language technologies, particularly generative AI (GenAI) chatbots accessible via conversational interfaces, is transforming digital interactions. While these tools hold societal promise, they also risk widening digital divides due to uneven adoption and low awareness of their limitations. This study presents the first comprehensive empirical mapping of GenAI adoption, usage patterns, and literacy in Italy, based on newly collected survey data from 1,906 Italian-speaking adults. Our findings reveal widespread adoption for both work and personal use, including sensitive tasks like emotional support and medical advice. Crucially, GenAI is supplanting other technologies to become a primary information source: this trend persists despite low user digital literacy, posing a risk as users struggle to recognize errors or misinformation. Moreover, we identify a significant gender divide -- particularly pronounced in older generations -- where women are half as likely to adopt GenAI and use it less frequently than men. While we find literacy to be a key predictor of adoption, it only partially explains this disparity, suggesting that other barriers are at play. Overall, our data provide granular insights into the multipurpose usage of GenAI, highlighting the dual need for targeted educational initiatives and further investigation into the underlying barriers to equitable participation that competence alone cannot explain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03671v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Beatrice Savoldi, Giuseppe Attanasio, Olga Gorodetskaya, Marta Marchiori Manerba, Elisa Bassignana, Silvia Casola, Matteo Negri, Tommaso Caselli, Luisa Bentivogli, Alan Ramponi, Arianna Muti, Nicoletta Balbo, Debora Nozza</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Hydro-Science and Engineering Knowledge of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03672</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03672v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Hydro-Science and Engineering (Hydro-SE) is a critical and irreplaceable domain that secures human water supply, generates clean hydropower energy, and mitigates flood and drought disasters. Featuring multiple engineering objectives, Hydro-SE is an inherently interdisciplinary domain that integrates scientific knowledge with engineering expertise. This integration necessitates extensive expert collaboration in decision-making, which poses difficulties for intelligence. With the rapid advancement of large language models (LLMs), their potential application in the Hydro-SE domain is being increasingly explored. However, the knowledge and application abilities of LLMs in Hydro-SE have not been sufficiently evaluated. To address this issue, we propose the Hydro-SE LLM evaluation benchmark (Hydro-SE Bench), which contains 4,000 multiple-choice questions. Hydro-SE Bench covers nine subfields and enables evaluation of LLMs in aspects of basic conceptual knowledge, engineering application ability, and reasoning and calculation ability. The evaluation results on Hydro-SE Bench show that the accuracy values vary among 0.74 to 0.80 for commercial LLMs, and among 0.41 to 0.68 for small-parameter LLMs. While LLMs perform well in subfields closely related to natural and physical sciences, they struggle with domain-specific knowledge such as industry standards and hydraulic structures. Model scaling mainly improves reasoning and calculation abilities, but there is still great potential for LLMs to better handle problems in practical engineering application. This study highlights the strengths and weaknesses of LLMs for Hydro-SE tasks, providing model developers with clear training targets and Hydro-SE researchers with practical guidance for applying LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03672v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shiruo Hu, Wenbo Shan, Yingjia Li, Zhiqi Wan, Xinpeng Yu, Yunjia Qi, Haotian Xia, Yang Xiao, Dingxiao Liu, Jiaru Wang, Chenxu Gong, Ruixi Zhang, Shuyue Wu, Shibo Cui, Chee Hui Lai, Wei Luo, Yubin He, Bin Xu, Jianshi Zhao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Different types of syntactic agreement recruit the same units within large language models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03676</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03676v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) can reliably distinguish grammatical from ungrammatical sentences, but how grammatical knowledge is represented within the models remains an open question. We investigate whether different syntactic phenomena recruit shared or distinct components in LLMs. Using a functional localization approach inspired by cognitive neuroscience, we identify the LLM units most responsive to 67 English syntactic phenomena in seven open-weight models. These units are consistently recruited across sentences containing the phenomena and causally support the models' syntactic performance. Critically, different types of syntactic agreement (e.g., subject-verb, anaphor, determiner-noun) recruit overlapping sets of units, suggesting that agreement constitutes a meaningful functional category for LLMs. This pattern holds in English, Russian, and Chinese; and further, in a cross-lingual analysis of 57 diverse languages, structurally more similar languages share more units for subject-verb agreement. Taken together, these findings reveal that syntactic agreement-a critical marker of syntactic dependencies-constitutes a meaningful category within LLMs' representational spaces.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03676v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Daria Kryvosheieva, Andrea de Varda, Evelina Fedorenko, Greta Tuckute</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AITutor-EvalKit: Exploring the Capabilities of AI Tutors</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03688</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03688v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present AITutor-EvalKit, an application that uses language technology to evaluate the pedagogical quality of AI tutors, provides software for demonstration and evaluation, as well as model inspection and data visualization. This tool is aimed at education stakeholders as well as *ACL community at large, as it supports learning and can also be used to collect user feedback and annotations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03688v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Numaan Naeem, Kaushal Kumar Maurya, Kseniia Petukhova, Ekaterina Kochmar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DZ-TDPO: Non-Destructive Temporal Alignment for Mutable State Tracking in Long-Context Dialogue</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03704</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03704v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Long-context dialogue systems suffer from State Inertia, where static constraints prevent models from resolving conflicts between evolving user intents and established historical context. To address this, we propose DZ-TDPO, a non-destructive alignment framework that synergizes conflict-aware dynamic KL constraints with a learnable temporal attention bias. Experiments on the Multi-Session Chat (MSC) dataset demonstrate that DZ-TDPO achieves state-of-the-art win rates (86.2% on Phi-3.5) while maintaining robust zero-shot generalization. Crucially, our scaling analysis reveals a "Capacity-Stability Trade-off": while smaller models incur an "alignment tax" (perplexity surge) to overcome historical inertia, the larger Qwen2.5-7B model achieves near-perfect alignment (99.4% win rate) with negligible perplexity overhead. This confirms that TAI can be alleviated via precise attention regulation rather than destructive weight updates, preserving general capabilities (MMLU) across model scales. Code and data are available: https://github.com/lyj20071013/DZ-TDPO</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03704v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yijun Liao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AR-Med: Automated Relevance Enhancement in Medical Search via LLM-Driven Information Augmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03737</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03737v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Accurate and reliable search on online healthcare platforms is critical for user safety and service efficacy. Traditional methods, however, often fail to comprehend complex and nuanced user queries, limiting their effectiveness. Large language models (LLMs) present a promising solution, offering powerful semantic understanding to bridge this gap. Despite their potential, deploying LLMs in this high-stakes domain is fraught with challenges, including factual hallucinations, specialized knowledge gaps, and high operational costs. To overcome these barriers, we introduce \textbf{AR-Med}, a novel framework for \textbf{A}utomated \textbf{R}elevance assessment for \textbf{Med}ical search that has been successfully deployed at scale on the Online Medical Delivery Platforms. AR-Med grounds LLM reasoning in verified medical knowledge through a retrieval-augmented approach, ensuring high accuracy and reliability. To enable efficient online service, we design a practical knowledge distillation scheme that compresses large teacher models into compact yet powerful student models. We also introduce LocalQSMed, a multi-expert annotated benchmark developed to guide model iteration and ensure strong alignment between offline and online performance. Extensive experiments show AR-Med achieves an offline accuracy of over 93\%, a 24\% absolute improvement over the original online system, and delivers significant gains in online relevance and user satisfaction. Our work presents a practical and scalable blueprint for developing trustworthy, LLM-powered systems in real-world healthcare applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03737v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chuyue Wang, Jie Feng, Yuxi Wu, Hang Zhang, Zhiguo Fan, Bing Cheng, Wei Lin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Principled RL for Diffusion LLMs Emerges from a Sequence-Level Perspective</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03759</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03759v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Reinforcement Learning (RL) has proven highly effective for autoregressive language models, but adapting these methods to diffusion large language models (dLLMs) presents fundamental challenges. The core difficulty lies in likelihood approximation: while autoregressive models naturally provide token-level conditional probabilities essential for token-level RL objectives (e.g., GRPO), dLLMs generate sequences through iterative non-autoregressive denoising steps that lack this factorization. To address this fundamental mismatch, we propose ELBO-based Sequence-level Policy Optimization (ESPO), a principled RL framework that treats entire sequence generation as a single action and uses the ELBO as a tractable sequence-level likelihood proxy. Our method incorporates per-token normalization of importance ratios and robust KL-divergence estimation to ensure stable large-scale training. Extensive experiments on mathematical reasoning, coding, and planning tasks demonstrate that ESPO significantly outperforms token-level baselines, achieving dramatic improvements of 20-40 points on the Countdown task, while maintaining consistent gains on math and coding benchmarks. Our approach establishes sequence-level optimization as a principled and empirically effective paradigm for RL in dLLMs. Our code is available at https://github.com/ML-GSAI/ESPO.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03759v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jingyang Ou, Jiaqi Han, Minkai Xu, Shaoxuan Xu, Jianwen Xie, Stefano Ermon, Yi Wu, Chongxuan Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-Context Representation Hijacking</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03771</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03771v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We introduce \textbf{Doublespeak}, a simple \emph{in-context representation hijacking} attack against large language models (LLMs). The attack works by systematically replacing a harmful keyword (e.g., \textit{bomb}) with a benign token (e.g., \textit{carrot}) across multiple in-context examples, provided a prefix to a harmful request. We demonstrate that this substitution leads to the internal representation of the benign token converging toward that of the harmful one, effectively embedding the harmful semantics under a euphemism. As a result, superficially innocuous prompts (e.g., ``How to build a carrot?'') are internally interpreted as disallowed instructions (e.g., ``How to build a bomb?''), thereby bypassing the model's safety alignment. We use interpretability tools to show that this semantic overwrite emerges layer by layer, with benign meanings in early layers converging into harmful semantics in later ones. Doublespeak is optimization-free, broadly transferable across model families, and achieves strong success rates on closed-source and open-source systems, reaching 74\% ASR on Llama-3.3-70B-Instruct with a single-sentence context override. Our findings highlight a new attack surface in the latent space of LLMs, revealing that current alignment strategies are insufficient and should instead operate at the representation level.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03771v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Itay Yona, Amir Sarid, Michael Karasik, Yossi Gandelsman</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Instruction-Following Capabilities in Seq2Seq Models: DoLA Adaptations for T5</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03803</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03803v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Contrastive decoding is a lightweight and effective inference-time method that improves the quality of text generation in Large Language Models. However, algorithms such as DoLa (Decoding by Contrastive Layers) have only been implemented in decoder-only architectures and studied for their impact on improving factuality. This work adapts DoLa for the T5 and FLAN-T5 model families and evaluates its impact on the models' instruction following capabilities, which to our knowledge is the first implementation of a contrastive decoding strategy in an encoder-decoder architecture. Our results show that DoLa improves the faithfulness of text generation for certain categories of tasks and harms others. To understand these results, we present a layer-by-layer analysis of logit evolution in a FLAN-T5 model to quantify DoLa's impact on token output probabilities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03803v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Huey Sun, Anabel Yong, Lorenzo Gilly, Felipe Jin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Alignment Between Human and Machine Codes: An Empirical Assessment of Prompt Engineering for Construct Identification in Psychology</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03818</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03818v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Due to their architecture and vast pre-training data, large language models (LLMs) demonstrate strong text classification performance. However, LLM output - here, the category assigned to a text - depends heavily on the wording of the prompt. While literature on prompt engineering is expanding, few studies focus on classification tasks, and even fewer address domains like psychology, where constructs have precise, theory-driven definitions that may not be well represented in pre-training data. We present an empirical framework for optimizing LLM performance for identifying constructs in texts via prompt engineering. We experimentally evaluate five prompting strategies --codebook-guided empirical prompt selection, automatic prompt engineering, persona prompting, chain-of-thought reasoning, and explanatory prompting - with zero-shot and few-shot classification. We find that persona, chain-of-thought, and explanations do not fully address performance loss accompanying a badly worded prompt. Instead, the most influential features of a prompt are the construct definition, task framing, and, to a lesser extent, the examples provided. Across three constructs and two models, the classifications most aligned with expert judgments resulted from a few-shot prompt combining codebook-guided empirical prompt selection with automatic prompt engineering. Based on our findings, we recommend that researchers generate and evaluate as many prompt variants as feasible, whether human-crafted, automatically generated, or ideally both, and select prompts and examples based on empirical performance in a training dataset, validating the final approach in a holdout set. This procedure offers a practical, systematic, and theory-driven method for optimizing LLM prompts in settings where alignment with expert judgment is critical.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03818v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kylie L. Anglin, Stephanie Milan, Brittney Hernandez, Claudia Ventura</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Training and Evaluation of Guideline-Based Medical Reasoning in LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03838</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03838v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Machine learning for early prediction in medicine has recently shown breakthrough performance, however, the focus on improving prediction accuracy has led to a neglect of faithful explanations that are required to gain the trust of medical practitioners. The goal of this paper is to teach LLMs to follow medical consensus guidelines step-by-step in their reasoning and prediction process. Since consensus guidelines are ubiquitous in medicine, instantiations of verbalized medical inference rules to electronic health records provide data for fine-tuning LLMs to learn consensus rules and possible exceptions thereof for many medical areas. Consensus rules also enable an automatic evaluation of the model's inference process regarding its derivation correctness (evaluating correct and faithful deduction of a conclusion from given premises) and value correctness (comparing predicted values against real-world measurements). We exemplify our work using the complex Sepsis-3 consensus definition. Our experiments show that small fine-tuned models outperform one-shot learning of considerably larger LLMs that are prompted with the explicit definition and models that are trained on medical texts including consensus definitions. Since fine-tuning on verbalized rule instantiations of a specific medical area yields nearly perfect derivation correctness for rules (and exceptions) on unseen patient data in that area, the bottleneck for early prediction is not out-of-distribution generalization, but the orthogonal problem of generalization into the future by forecasting sparsely and irregularly sampled clinical variables. We show that the latter results can be improved by integrating the output representations of a time series forecasting model with the LLM in a multimodal setup.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03838v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Michael Staniek, Artem Sokolov, Stefan Riezler</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconstructing KV Caches with Cross-layer Fusion For Enhanced Transformers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03870</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03870v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Transformer decoders have achieved strong results across tasks, but the memory required for the KV cache becomes prohibitive at long sequence lengths. Although Cross-layer KV Cache sharing (e.g., YOCO, CLA) offers a path to mitigate KV Cache bottleneck, it typically underperforms within-layer methods like GQA. To understand the root cause, we investigate the information flow of keys and values of the top-layers. Our preliminary reveals a clear distribution: values are predominantly derived from the bottom layer, while keys draw more information from both bottom and middle layers. Building upon this, we propose FusedKV, whose top-layer KV caches are a learnable fusion of the most informative ones from the bottom and middle layers. This fusion operates directly on post-RoPE keys, preserving relative positional information without the computational cost of re-applying rotary embeddings. To further improve efficiency, we propose FusedKV-Lite, an cross-layer sharing approach, where top-layer KV caches are directly derived from the bottom-layer values and the middle-layer keys. Compared to FusedKV, FusedKV-Lite reduces I/O overhead at the cost of a slight increase in perplexity. In experiments on LLMs ranging from 332M to 4B parameters, our proposed method reduce 50\% cache memory while achieving lower validation perplexity than the standard Transformer decoder, establishing it as a memory-efficient, high-performance architectural alternative.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03870v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hongzhan Lin, Zhiqi Bai, Xinmiao Zhang, Sen Yang, Xiang Li, Siran Yang, Yunlong Xu, Jiaheng Liu, Yongchi Zhao, Jiamang Wang, Yuchi Xu, Wenbo Su, Bo Zheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BERnaT: Basque Encoders for Representing Natural Textual Diversity</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03903</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03903v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Language models depend on massive text corpora that are often filtered for quality, a process that can unintentionally exclude non-standard linguistic varieties, reduce model robustness and reinforce representational biases. In this paper, we argue that language models should aim to capture the full spectrum of language variation (dialectal, historical, informal, etc.) rather than relying solely on standardized text. Focusing on Basque, a morphologically rich and low-resource language, we construct new corpora combining standard, social media, and historical sources, and pre-train the BERnaT family of encoder-only models in three configurations: standard, diverse, and combined. We further propose an evaluation framework that separates Natural Language Understanding (NLU) tasks into standard and diverse subsets to assess linguistic generalization. Results show that models trained on both standard and diverse data consistently outperform those trained on standard corpora, improving performance across all task types without compromising standard benchmark accuracy. These findings highlight the importance of linguistic diversity in building inclusive, generalizable language models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03903v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ekhi Azurmendi, Joseba Fernandez de Landa, Jaione Bengoetxea, Maite Heredia, Julen Etxaniz, Mikel Zubillaga, Ander Soraluze, Aitor Soroa</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Lying Only Sinful in Islam? Exploring Religious Bias in Multilingual Large Language Models Across Major Religions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03943</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03943v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: While recent developments in large language models have improved bias detection and classification, sensitive subjects like religion still present challenges because even minor errors can result in severe misunderstandings. In particular, multilingual models often misrepresent religions and have difficulties being accurate in religious contexts. To address this, we introduce BRAND: Bilingual Religious Accountable Norm Dataset, which focuses on the four main religions of South Asia: Buddhism, Christianity, Hinduism, and Islam, containing over 2,400 entries, and we used three different types of prompts in both English and Bengali. Our results indicate that models perform better in English than in Bengali and consistently display bias toward Islam, even when answering religion-neutral questions. These findings highlight persistent bias in multilingual models when similar questions are asked in different languages. We further connect our findings to the broader issues in HCI regarding religion and spirituality.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03943v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kazi Abrab Hossain, Jannatul Somiya Mahmud, Maria Hossain Tuli, Anik Mitra, S. M. Taiabul Haque, Farig Y. Sadeque</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adapting Large Language Models to Low-Resource Tibetan: A Two-Stage Continual and Supervised Fine-Tuning Study</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03976</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03976v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Adapting large language models (LLMs) to low-resource languages remains a major challenge due to data scarcity and cross-lingual drift. This work presents a two-stage adaptation of Qwen2.5-3B to Tibetan, a morphologically rich and underrepresented language. We employ Continual Pretraining (CPT) to establish Tibetan linguistic grounding, followed by Supervised Fine-Tuning (SFT) for task and translation specialization. Empirical evaluations demonstrate a consistent decrease in perplexity (from 2.98 $\rightarrow$ 1.54) and substantial improvements in Chinese$\rightarrow$Tibetan translation quality (BLEU: 0.046 $\rightarrow$ 0.261; chrF: 2.2 $\rightarrow$ 6.6). Layer-wise analysis across 435 layers in Qwen3-4B reveals that adaptation primarily concentrates on embedding and output heads, with mid--late MLP projections encoding domain-specific transformations. Our findings suggest that CPT constructs a Tibetan semantic manifold while SFT sharpens task alignment with minimal representational disruption. This study provides the first quantitative exploration of Tibetan adaptation dynamics for LLMs, and offers an open, reproducible framework for extending multilingual foundation models to low-resource settings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03976v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lifeng Chen, Ryan Lai, Tianming Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Old Tokenizers New Words: Efficient Tokenizer Adaptation for Pre-trained Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03989</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03989v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Tokenizer adaptation plays an important role in transferring pre-trained language models to new domains or languages. In this work, we address two complementary aspects of this process: vocabulary extension and pruning. The common approach to extension trains a new tokenizer on domain-specific text and appends the tokens that do not overlap with the existing vocabulary, which often results in many tokens that are unreachable or never used. We propose continued BPE training, which adapts a pre-trained tokenizer by continuing the BPE merge learning process on new data. Experiments across multiple languages and model families show that this approach improves tokenization efficiency and leads to better utilization of added vocabulary. We also introduce leaf-based vocabulary pruning, which removes redundant tokens while preserving model quality. Together, these methods provide practical tools for controlled vocabulary modification, which we release as an open-source package.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03989v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Taido Purason, Pavel Chizhov, Ivan P. Yamshchikov, Mark Fishel</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AugServe: Adaptive Request Scheduling for Augmented Large Language Model Inference Serving</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.04013</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.04013v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: As augmented large language models (LLMs) with external tools become increasingly popular in web applications, improving augmented LLM inference serving efficiency and optimizing service-level objectives (SLOs) are critical for enhancing user experience. To achieve this, inference systems must maximize request handling within latency constraints, referred to as increasing effective throughput. However, existing systems face two major challenges: (i) reliance on first-come-first-served (FCFS) scheduling causes severe head-of-line blocking, leading to queuing delays exceeding the SLOs for many requests; and (ii) static batch token limit, which fails to adapt to fluctuating loads and hardware conditions. Both of these factors degrade effective throughput and service quality.
  This paper presents AugServe, an efficient inference framework designed to reduce queueing latency and enhance effective throughput for augmented LLM inference services. The core idea of AugServe is a two-stage adaptive request scheduling strategy. Specifically, AugServe combines the inference features of augmented LLM requests to optimize the order of scheduling decisions (stage I). These decisions are continuously refined with runtime information (stage II), adapting to both request characteristics and system capabilities. In addition, AugServe dynamically adjusts the token batching mechanism based on hardware status and real-time load, further enhancing throughput performance. Experimental results show that AugServe achieves 4.7-33.1x and 3.3-13.2x higher effective throughput than vLLM and InferCept, while reducing time-to-first-token (TTFT) by up to 96.3% and 95.0%, respectively.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.04013v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ying Wang, Zhen Jin, Jiexiong Xu, Wenhai Lin, Yiquan Chen, Wenzhi Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jina-VLM: Small Multilingual Vision Language Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.04032</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.04032v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present Jina-VLM, a 2.4B parameter vision-language model that achieves state-of-the-art multilingual visual question answering among open 2B-scale VLMs. The model couples a SigLIP2 vision encoder with a Qwen3 language backbone through an attention-pooling connector that enables token-efficient processing of arbitrary-resolution images. Across standard VQA benchmarks and multilingual evaluations, Jina-VLM outperforms comparable models while preserving competitive text-only performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.04032v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Andreas Koukounas, Georgios Mastrapas, Florian H\"onicke, Sedigheh Eslami, Guillaume Roncari, Scott Martens, Han Xiao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SkillFactory: Self-Distillation For Learning Cognitive Behaviors</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.04072</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.04072v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Reasoning models leveraging long chains of thought employ various cognitive skills, such as verification of their answers, backtracking, retrying by an alternate method, and more. Previous work has shown that when a base language model exhibits these skills, training that model further with reinforcement learning (RL) can learn to leverage them. How can we get models to leverage skills that aren't exhibited by base models? Our work, SkillFactory, is a method for fine-tuning models to roughly learn these skills during a supervised fine-tuning (SFT) stage prior to RL. Our approach does not rely on distillation from a stronger model, but instead uses samples from the model itself, rearranged to provide training data in the format of those skills. These "silver" SFT traces may be imperfect, but are nevertheless effective for priming a model to acquire skills during RL. Our evaluation shows that (1) starting from SkillFactory SFT initialization helps a model to generalize to harder variants of a task post-RL, despite lower performance pre-RL; (2) cognitive skills are indeed used by the model; (3) RLed SkillFactory models are more robust to regression on out-of-domain tasks than RLed base models. Our work suggests that inductive biases learned prior to RL help models learn robust cognitive skill use.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.04072v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zayne Sprague, Jack Lu, Manya Wadhwa, Sedrick Keh, Mengye Ren, Greg Durrett</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Detecting AI Hallucinations in Finance: An Information-Theoretic Method Cuts Hallucination Rate by 92%</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03107</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03107v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) produce fluent but unsupported answers - hallucinations - limiting safe deployment in high-stakes domains. We propose ECLIPSE, a framework that treats hallucination as a mismatch between a model's semantic entropy and the capacity of available evidence. We combine entropy estimation via multi-sample clustering with a novel perplexity decomposition that measures how models use retrieved evidence. We prove that under mild conditions, the resulting entropy-capacity objective is strictly convex with a unique stable optimum. We evaluate on a controlled financial question answering dataset with GPT-3.5-turbo (n=200 balanced samples with synthetic hallucinations), where ECLIPSE achieves ROC AUC of 0.89 and average precision of 0.90, substantially outperforming a semantic entropy-only baseline (AUC 0.50). A controlled ablation with Claude-3-Haiku, which lacks token-level log probabilities, shows AUC dropping to 0.59 with coefficient magnitudes decreasing by 95% - demonstrating that ECLIPSE is a logprob-native mechanism whose effectiveness depends on calibrated token-level uncertainties. The perplexity decomposition features exhibit the largest learned coefficients, confirming that evidence utilization is central to hallucination detection. We position this work as a controlled mechanism study; broader validation across domains and naturally occurring hallucinations remains future work.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03107v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>q-fin.CP</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mainak Singha</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culture Affordance Atlas: Reconciling Object Diversity Through Functional Mapping</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03173</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03173v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Culture shapes the objects people use and for what purposes, yet mainstream Vision-Language (VL) datasets frequently exhibit cultural biases, disproportionately favoring higher-income, Western contexts. This imbalance reduces model generalizability and perpetuates performance disparities, especially impacting lower-income and non-Western communities. To address these disparities, we propose a novel function-centric framework that categorizes objects by the functions they fulfill, across diverse cultural and economic contexts. We implement this framework by creating the Culture Affordance Atlas, a re-annotated and culturally grounded restructuring of the Dollar Street dataset spanning 46 functions and 288 objects publicly available at https://lit.eecs.umich.edu/CultureAffordance-Atlas/index.html. Through extensive empirical analyses using the CLIP model, we demonstrate that function-centric labels substantially reduce socioeconomic performance gaps between high- and low-income groups by a median of 6 pp (statistically significant), improving model effectiveness for lower-income contexts. Furthermore, our analyses reveals numerous culturally essential objects that are frequently overlooked in prominent VL datasets. Our contributions offer a scalable pathway toward building inclusive VL datasets and equitable AI systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03173v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>AAAI 2026 Social Impact Track</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Joan Nwatu, Longju Bai, Oana Ignat, Rada Mihalcea</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPARK: Stepwise Process-Aware Rewards for Reference-Free Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03244</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03244v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Process reward models (PRMs) that provide dense, step-level feedback have shown promise for reinforcement learning, yet their adoption remains limited by the need for expensive step-level annotations or ground truth references. We propose SPARK: a three-stage framework where in the first stage a generator model produces diverse solutions and a verifier model evaluates them using parallel scaling (self-consistency) and sequential scaling (meta-critique). In the second stage, we use these verification outputs as synthetic training data to fine-tune generative process reward models, which subsequently serve as reward signals during training. We show that aggregating multiple independent verifications at the step level produces training data for process reward models that surpass ground-truth outcome supervision, achieving 67.5 F1 on ProcessBench (a benchmark for identifying erroneous steps in mathematical reasoning) compared to 66.4 for reference-guided training and 61.9 for GPT-4o. In the final stage, we apply our generative PRM with chain-of-thought verification (PRM-CoT) as the reward model in RL experiments on mathematical reasoning, and introduce format constraints to prevent reward hacking. Using Qwen2.5-Math-7B, we achieve 47.4% average accuracy across six mathematical reasoning benchmarks, outperforming ground-truth-based RLVR (43.9%). Our work enables reference-free RL training that exceeds ground-truth methods, opening new possibilities for domains lacking verifiable answers or accessible ground truth.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03244v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Salman Rahman, Sruthi Gorantla, Arpit Gupta, Swastik Roy, Nanyun Peng, Yang Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Vibe Coding Safe? Benchmarking Vulnerability of Agent-Generated Code in Real-World Tasks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03262</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03262v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Vibe coding is a new programming paradigm in which human engineers instruct large language model (LLM) agents to complete complex coding tasks with little supervision. Although it is increasingly adopted, are vibe coding outputs really safe to deploy in production? To answer this question, we propose SU S VI B E S, a benchmark consisting of 200 feature-request software engineering tasks from real-world open-source projects, which, when given to human programmers, led to vulnerable implementations. We evaluate multiple widely used coding agents with frontier models on this benchmark. Disturbingly, all agents perform poorly in terms of software security. Although 61% of the solutions from SWE-Agent with Claude 4 Sonnet are functionally correct, only 10.5% are secure. Further experiments demonstrate that preliminary security strategies, such as augmenting the feature request with vulnerability hints, cannot mitigate these security issues. Our findings raise serious concerns about the widespread adoption of vibe-coding, particularly in security-sensitive applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03262v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Songwen Zhao, Danqing Wang, Kexun Zhang, Jiaxuan Luo, Zhuo Li, Lei Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epistemic Substitution: How Grokipedia's AI-Generated Encyclopedia Restructures Authority</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03337</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03337v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: A quarter century ago, Wikipedia's decentralized, crowdsourced, and consensus-driven model replaced the centralized, expert-driven, and authority-based standard for encyclopedic knowledge curation. The emergence of generative AI encyclopedias, such as Grokipedia, possibly presents another potential shift in epistemic evolution. This study investigates whether AI- and human-curated encyclopedias rely on the same foundations of authority. We conducted a multi-scale comparative analysis of the citation networks from 72 matched article pairs, which cite a total of almost 60,000 sources. Using an 8-category epistemic classification, we mapped the "epistemic profiles" of the articles on each platform. Our findings reveal several quantitative and qualitative differences in how knowledge is sourced and encyclopedia claims are epistemologically justified. Grokipedia replaces Wikipedia's heavy reliance on peer-reviewed "Academic &amp; Scholarly" work with a notable increase in "User-generated" and "Civic organization" sources. Comparative network analyses further show that Grokipedia employs very different epistemological profiles when sourcing leisure topics (such as Sports and Entertainment) and more societal sensitive civic topics (such as Politics &amp; Conflicts, Geographical Entities, and General Knowledge &amp; Society). Finally, we find a "scaling-law for AI-generated knowledge sourcing" that shows a linear relationship between article length and citation density, which is distinct from collective human reference sourcing. We conclude that this first implementation of an LLM-based encyclopedia does not merely automate knowledge production but restructures it. Given the notable changes and the important role of encyclopedias, we suggest the continuation and deepening of algorithm audits, such as the one presented here, in order to understand the ongoing epistemological shifts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03337v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.DL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aliakbar Mehdizadeh, Martin Hilbert</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM-Generated Ads: From Personalization Parity to Persuasion Superiority</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03373</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03373v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: As large language models (LLMs) become increasingly capable of generating persuasive content, understanding their effectiveness across different advertising strategies becomes critical. This paper presents a two-part investigation examining LLM-generated advertising through complementary lenses: (1) personality-based and (2) psychological persuasion principles.
  In our first study (n=400), we tested whether LLMs could generate personalized advertisements tailored to specific personality traits (openness and neuroticism) and how their performance compared to human experts. Results showed that LLM-generated ads achieved statistical parity with human-written ads (51.1% vs. 48.9%, p &gt; 0.05), with no significant performance differences for matched personalities.
  Building on these insights, our second study (n=800) shifted focus from individual personalization to universal persuasion, testing LLM performance across four foundational psychological principles: authority, consensus, cognition, and scarcity. AI-generated ads significantly outperformed human-created content, achieving a 59.1% preference rate (vs. 40.9%, p &lt; 0.001), with the strongest performance in authority (63.0%) and consensus (62.5%) appeals. Qualitative analysis revealed AI's advantage stems from crafting more sophisticated, aspirational messages and achieving superior visual-narrative coherence. Critically, this quality advantage proved robust: even after applying a 21.2 percentage point detection penalty when participants correctly identified AI-origin, AI ads still outperformed human ads, and 29.4% of participants chose AI content despite knowing its origin. These findings demonstrate LLMs' evolution from parity in personalization to superiority in persuasive storytelling, with significant implications for advertising practice given LLMs' near-zero marginal cost and time requirements compared to human experts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03373v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Elyas Meguellati, Stefano Civelli, Lei Han, Abraham Bernstein, Shazia Sadiq, Gianluca Demartini</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Text-Printed Image: Bridging the Image-Text Modality Gap for Text-centric Training of Large Vision-Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03463</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03463v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recent large vision-language models (LVLMs) have been applied to diverse VQA tasks. However, achieving practical performance typically requires task-specific fine-tuning with large numbers of image-text pairs, which are costly to collect. In this work, we study text-centric training, a setting where only textual descriptions are available and no real images are provided, as a paradigm for low-cost data scaling. Unlike images, whose collection is often restricted by privacy constraints and scarcity in niche domains, text is widely available. Moreover, text is easily editable, enabling automatic diversification and expansion with LLMs at minimal human effort. While this offers clear advantages over image collection in terms of scalability and cost, training on raw text without images still yields limited gains on VQA tasks because of the image-text modality gap. To address this issue, we propose a Text-Printed Image (TPI), which generates synthetic images by directly rendering the given textual description on a plain white canvas. This simple rendering projects text into the image modality and can be integrated into arbitrary existing LVLM training pipelines at low cost. Moreover, TPI preserves the semantics of the text, whereas text-to-image models often fail to do. Across four models and seven benchmarks, our systematic experiments show that TPI enables more effective text-centric training than synthetic images generated by a diffusion model. We further explore TPI as a low-cost data-augmentation strategy and demonstrate its practical utility. Overall, our findings highlight the significant potential of text-centric training and, more broadly, chart a path toward fully automated data generation for LVLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03463v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shojiro Yamabe, Futa Waseda, Daiki Shiono, Tsubasa Takahashi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning for TraceTarnish: Techniques, Trends, and Testing Tangible Traits</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03465</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03465v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In this study, we more rigorously evaluated our attack script $\textit{TraceTarnish}$, which leverages adversarial stylometry principles to anonymize the authorship of text-based messages. To ensure the efficacy and utility of our attack, we sourced, processed, and analyzed Reddit comments--comments that were later alchemized into $\textit{TraceTarnish}$ data--to gain valuable insights. The transformed $\textit{TraceTarnish}$ data was then further augmented by $\textit{StyloMetrix}$ to manufacture stylometric features--features that were culled using the Information Gain criterion, leaving only the most informative, predictive, and discriminative ones. Our results found that function words and function word types ($L\_FUNC\_A$ $\&amp;$ $L\_FUNC\_T$); content words and content word types ($L\_CONT\_A$ $\&amp;$ $L\_CONT\_T$); and the Type-Token Ratio ($ST\_TYPE\_TOKEN\_RATIO\_LEMMAS$) yielded significant Information-Gain readings. The identified stylometric cues--function-word frequencies, content-word distributions, and the Type-Token Ratio--serve as reliable indicators of compromise (IoCs), revealing when a text has been deliberately altered to mask its true author. Similarly, these features could function as forensic beacons, alerting defenders to the presence of an adversarial stylometry attack; granted, in the absence of the original message, this signal may go largely unnoticed, as it appears to depend on a pre- and post-transformation comparison. "In trying to erase a trace, you often imprint a larger one." Armed with this understanding, we framed $\textit{TraceTarnish}$'s operations and outputs around these five isolated features, using them to conceptualize and implement enhancements that further strengthen the attack.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03465v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Robert Dilworth</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NAS-LoRA: Empowering Parameter-Efficient Fine-Tuning for Visual Foundation Models with Searchable Adaptation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03499</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03499v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The Segment Anything Model (SAM) has emerged as a powerful visual foundation model for image segmentation. However, adapting SAM to specific downstream tasks, such as medical and agricultural imaging, remains a significant challenge. To address this, Low-Rank Adaptation (LoRA) and its variants have been widely employed to enhancing SAM's adaptation performance on diverse domains. Despite advancements, a critical question arises: can we integrate inductive bias into the model? This is particularly relevant since the Transformer encoder in SAM inherently lacks spatial priors within image patches, potentially hindering the acquisition of high-level semantic information. In this paper, we propose NAS-LoRA, a new Parameter-Efficient Fine-Tuning (PEFT) method designed to bridge the semantic gap between pre-trained SAM and specialized domains. Specifically, NAS-LoRA incorporates a lightweight Neural Architecture Search (NAS) block between the encoder and decoder components of LoRA to dynamically optimize the prior knowledge integrated into weight updates. Furthermore, we propose a stage-wise optimization strategy to help the ViT encoder balance weight updates and architectural adjustments, facilitating the gradual learning of high-level semantic information. Various Experiments demonstrate our NAS-LoRA improves existing PEFT methods, while reducing training cost by 24.14% without increasing inference cost, highlighting the potential of NAS in enhancing PEFT for visual foundation models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03499v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Renqi Chen, Haoyang Su, Shixiang Tang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>M3DR: Towards Universal Multilingual Multimodal Document Retrieval</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03514</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03514v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Multimodal document retrieval systems have shown strong progress in aligning visual and textual content for semantic search. However, most existing approaches remain heavily English-centric, limiting their effectiveness in multilingual contexts. In this work, we present M3DR (Multilingual Multimodal Document Retrieval), a framework designed to bridge this gap across languages, enabling applicability across diverse linguistic and cultural contexts. M3DR leverages synthetic multilingual document data and generalizes across different vision-language architectures and model sizes, enabling robust cross-lingual and cross-modal alignment. Using contrastive training, our models learn unified representations for text and document images that transfer effectively across languages. We validate this capability on 22 typologically diverse languages, demonstrating consistent performance and adaptability across linguistic and script variations. We further introduce a comprehensive benchmark that captures real-world multilingual scenarios, evaluating models under monolingual, multilingual, and mixed-language settings. M3DR generalizes across both single dense vector and ColBERT-style token-level multi-vector retrieval paradigms. Our models, NetraEmbed and ColNetraEmbed achieve state-of-the-art performance with ~150% relative improvements on cross-lingual retrieval.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03514v1</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Adithya S Kolavi, Vyoman Jain</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CartoMapQA: A Fundamental Benchmark Dataset Evaluating Vision-Language Models on Cartographic Map Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03558</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03558v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The rise of Visual-Language Models (LVLMs) has unlocked new possibilities for seamlessly integrating visual and textual information. However, their ability to interpret cartographic maps remains largely unexplored. In this paper, we introduce CartoMapQA, a benchmark specifically designed to evaluate LVLMs' understanding of cartographic maps through question-answering tasks. The dataset includes over 2000 samples, each composed of a cartographic map, a question (with open-ended or multiple-choice answers), and a ground-truth answer. These tasks span key low-, mid- and high-level map interpretation skills, including symbol recognition, embedded information extraction, scale interpretation, and route-based reasoning. Our evaluation of both open-source and proprietary LVLMs reveals persistent challenges: models frequently struggle with map-specific semantics, exhibit limited geospatial reasoning, and are prone to Optical Character Recognition (OCR)-related errors. By isolating these weaknesses, CartoMapQA offers a valuable tool for guiding future improvements in LVLM architectures. Ultimately, it supports the development of models better equipped for real-world applications that depend on robust and reliable map understanding, such as navigation, geographic search, and urban planning. Our source code and data are openly available to the research community at: https://github.com/ungquanghuy-kddi/CartoMapQA.git</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03558v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Huy Quang Ung, Guillaume Habault, Yasutaka Nishimura, Hao Niu, Roberto Legaspi, Tomoki Oya, Ryoichi Kojima, Masato Taya, Chihiro Ono, Atsunori Minamikawa, Yan Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SELF: A Robust Singular Value and Eigenvalue Approach for LLM Fingerprinting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03620</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03620v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The protection of Intellectual Property (IP) in Large Language Models (LLMs) represents a critical challenge in contemporary AI research. While fingerprinting techniques have emerged as a fundamental mechanism for detecting unauthorized model usage, existing methods -- whether behavior-based or structural -- suffer from vulnerabilities such as false claim attacks or susceptible to weight manipulations. To overcome these limitations, we propose SELF, a novel intrinsic weight-based fingerprinting scheme that eliminates dependency on input and inherently resists false claims. SELF achieves robust IP protection through two key innovations: 1) unique, scalable and transformation-invariant fingerprint extraction via singular value and eigenvalue decomposition of LLM attention weights, and 2) effective neural network-based fingerprint similarity comparison based on few-shot learning and data augmentation. Experimental results demonstrate SELF maintains high IP infringement detection accuracy while showing strong robustness against various downstream modifications, including quantization, pruning, and fine-tuning attacks. Our code is available at https://github.com/HanxiuZhang/SELF_v2.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03620v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hanxiu Zhang, Yue Zheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optical Context Compression Is Just (Bad) Autoencoding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03643</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03643v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: DeepSeek-OCR demonstrates that rendered text can be reconstructed with high fidelity from a small number of vision tokens. This finding has sparked excitement about vision-based context compression for language models. But the evaluation stops at reconstruction; whether these representations help language modeling remains untested. We test two assumptions implicit in the optical-compression narrative: that vision-based compression provides unique advantages for text reconstruction from compressed representations, and that DeepSeek-OCR's reconstruction results are evidence that vision-based compression will be useful for language modeling. Comparing their vision encoder against simple alternatives--parameter-free mean pooling and a learned hierarchical encoder--we find that these simple approaches match or surpass vision for reconstruction at matched compression ratios, and outperform it for language modeling--where vision-based compression fails to beat truncation. The excitement around optical context compression outpaces the evidence. Code and checkpoints are available at https://github.com/ivnle/bad-autoencoding</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03643v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ivan Yee Lee, Cheng Yang, Taylor Berg-Kirkpatrick</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thinking with Programming Vision: Towards a Unified View for Thinking with Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03746</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03746v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Multimodal large language models (MLLMs) that think with images can interactively use tools to reason about visual inputs, but current approaches often rely on a narrow set of tools with limited real-world necessity and scalability. In this work, we first reveal a critical and previously overlooked weakness: even state-of-the-art MLLMs are surprisingly brittle, showing significant performance degradation on images with simple orientation changes or natural corruptions, underscoring the need for more robust tool-based reasoning. To address this, we propose CodeVision, a flexible and scalable code-as-tool framework where the model generates code as a universal interface to invoke any image operation, moving beyond fixed tool registries. We train our model using a two-stage methodology, beginning with Supervised Fine-Tuning (SFT) on a high-quality dataset curated for complex, multi-turn tool composition and error recovery, followed by Reinforcement Learning (RL) with a novel and dense process reward function to encourage strategic and efficient tool use. To facilitate this research, we construct new SFT and RL datasets and introduce a challenging new benchmark suite designed to rigorously evaluate robustness to orientation changes and multi-tool reasoning. Experiments on Qwen2.5-VL and Qwen3-VL series show that our approach significantly improves model performance and fosters emergent capabilities such as flexible tool composition, efficient chained execution, and robust error recovery from runtime feedback. Code is available at https://github.com/ByteDance-BandAI/CodeVision.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03746v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zirun Guo, Minjie Hong, Feng Zhang, Kai Jia, Tao Jin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AdaptVision: Efficient Vision-Language Models via Adaptive Visual Acquisition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03794</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.03794v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Vision-Language Models (VLMs) have achieved remarkable success in visual question answering tasks, but their reliance on large numbers of visual tokens introduces significant computational overhead. While existing efficient VLM approaches reduce visual tokens through fixed-ratio compression, they operate passively and lack the ability to adapt to varying task requirements. This motivates a fundamental question: Can VLMs autonomously determine the minimum number of visual tokens required for each sample? Inspired by human active vision mechanisms, we introduce AdaptVision, an efficient VLM paradigm that enables adaptive visual token acquisition through a coarse-to-fine approach. Our model initially processes compressed visual tokens from low-resolution images and selectively acquires additional visual information by invoking a bounding box tool to crop key regions when necessary. We train AdaptVision using a reinforcement learning framework that carefully balances accuracy and efficiency. Central to our approach is Decoupled Turn Policy Optimization (DTPO), which decouples the learning objective into two components: (1) tool learning, which optimizes correct tool utilization, and (2) accuracy improvement, which refines the generated responses to improve answer correctness. Based on this formulation, we further decouple advantage estimation by computing separate advantages for tokens associated with each objective. This formulation enables more effective optimization for AdaptVision compared to vanilla GRPO. Comprehensive experiments across multiple VQA benchmarks demonstrate that AdaptVision achieves superior performance while consuming substantially fewer visual tokens than state-of-the-art efficient VLM methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.03794v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zichuan Lin, Yicheng Liu, Yang Yang, Lvfang Tao, Deheng Ye</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stable Signer: Hierarchical Sign Language Generative Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.04048</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.04048v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Sign Language Production (SLP) is the process of converting the complex input text into a real video. Most previous works focused on the Text2Gloss, Gloss2Pose, Pose2Vid stages, and some concentrated on Prompt2Gloss and Text2Avatar stages. However, this field has made slow progress due to the inaccuracy of text conversion, pose generation, and the rendering of poses into real human videos in these stages, resulting in gradually accumulating errors. Therefore, in this paper, we streamline the traditional redundant structure, simplify and optimize the task objective, and design a new sign language generative model called Stable Signer. It redefines the SLP task as a hierarchical generation end-to-end task that only includes text understanding (Prompt2Gloss, Text2Gloss) and Pose2Vid, and executes text understanding through our proposed new Sign Language Understanding Linker called SLUL, and generates hand gestures through the named SLP-MoE hand gesture rendering expert block to end-to-end generate high-quality and multi-style sign language videos. SLUL is trained using the newly developed Semantic-Aware Gloss Masking Loss (SAGM Loss). Its performance has improved by 48.6% compared to the current SOTA generation methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.04048v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sen Fang, Yalin Feng, Hongbin Zhong, Yanxin Zhang, Dimitris N. Metaxas</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Group Fairness Lens for Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.15478</link>
      <description>arXiv:2312.15478v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The need to assess LLMs for bias and fairness is critical, with current evaluations often being narrow, missing a broad categorical view. In this paper, we propose evaluating the bias and fairness of LLMs from a group fairness lens using a novel hierarchical schema characterizing diverse social groups. Specifically, we construct a dataset, GFAIR, encapsulating target-attribute combinations across multiple dimensions. Moreover, we introduce statement organization, a new open-ended text generation task, to uncover complex biases in LLMs. Extensive evaluations of popular LLMs reveal inherent safety concerns. To mitigate the biases of LLMs from a group fairness perspective, we pioneer a novel chainof-thought method GF-THINK to mitigate biases of LLMs from a group fairness perspective. Experimental results demonstrate its efficacy in mitigating bias and achieving fairness in LLMs. Our dataset and codes are available at https://github.com/surika/Group-Fairness-LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2312.15478v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Guanqun Bi, Yuqiang Xie, Lei Shen, Yanan Cao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IW-Bench: Evaluating Large Multimodal Models for Converting Image-to-Web</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.18980</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.18980v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recently advancements in large multimodal models have led to significant strides in image comprehension capabilities. Despite these advancements, there is a lack of the robust benchmark specifically for assessing the Image-to-Web conversion proficiency of these large models. Primarily, it is essential to ensure the integrity of the web elements generated. These elements comprise visible and invisible categories. Previous evaluation methods (e.g.,BLEU) are notably susceptible to significant alterations due to the presence of invisible elements in Web. Furthermore, it is crucial to measure the layout information of web pages, referring to the positional relationships between elements, which is overlooked by previous work. To address challenges, we have curated and aligned a benchmark of images and corresponding web codes (IW-BENCH). Specifically, we propose the Element Accuracy, which tests the completeness of the elements by parsing the Document Object Model (DOM) tree. Layout Accuracy is also proposed to analyze the positional relationships of elements by converting DOM tree into a common subsequence. Besides, we design a five-hop multimodal Chain-of-Thought Prompting for better performance, which contains five hop: 1) SoM prompt injection. 2) Inferring Elements. 3) Inferring Layout. 4) Inferring Web code. 5) Reflection. Our benchmark comprises 1200 pairs of images and web codes with varying levels of difficulty. We have conducted extensive experiments on existing large multimodal models, offering insights into their performance and areas for improvement in image-to-web domain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.18980v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hongcheng Guo, Wei Zhang, Junhao Chen, Yaonan Gu, Jian Yang, Junjia Du, Shaosheng Cao, Binyuan Hui, Tianyu Liu, Jianxin Ma, Chang Zhou, Zhoujun Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Train Long-Context Language Models (Effectively)</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.02660</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.02660v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We study continued training and supervised fine-tuning (SFT) of a language model (LM) to make effective use of long-context information. We first establish a reliable evaluation protocol to guide model development -- instead of perplexity or simple needle-in-a-haystack (NIAH) tests, we use a broad set of long-context downstream tasks, and we evaluate models after SFT as this better reveals long-context abilities. Supported by our robust evaluations, we run thorough experiments to decide the data mix for continued pre-training, the instruction tuning dataset, and many other design choices such as position extrapolation. We find that (1) code repositories and books are excellent sources of long data, but it is crucial to combine them with high-quality short-context data; (2) training with a sequence length beyond the evaluation length boosts long-context performance; (3) for SFT, using only short instruction datasets yields strong performance on long-context tasks. Our final model, ProLong-8B, which is initialized from Llama-3 and trained on 40B tokens, demonstrates state-of-the-art long-context performance among similarly sized models at a length of 128K. ProLong outperforms Llama-3.1-8B-Instruct on the majority of long-context tasks despite using only 5% as many tokens during long-context training. Additionally, ProLong can effectively process up to 512K tokens, one of the longest context windows of publicly available LMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.02660v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tianyu Gao, Alexander Wettig, Howard Yen, Danqi Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncertainty Quantification for LLMs through Minimum Bayes Risk: Bridging Confidence and Consistency</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.04964</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.04964v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Uncertainty quantification (UQ) methods for Large Language Models (LLMs) encompass a variety of approaches, with two major types being particularly prominent: information-based, which focus on model confidence expressed as token probabilities, and consistency-based, which assess the semantic relationship between multiple outputs generated using repeated sampling. Several recent methods have combined these two approaches to boost UQ performance. However, they sometimes fail to outperform much simpler baseline methods. Our work discusses the fundamental approach to constructing uncertainty measures that directly links uncertainty with the minimum Bayes risks achieved by LLM decoding. Building on these findings, we propose a novel approach to integrating model confidence with output consistency, resulting in a family of efficient and robust UQ methods. Our investigation reveals distinctive characteristics of LLMs as probabilistic models, which help to explain why these UQ methods underperform in certain tasks. Based on these findings, we propose a new way of synthesizing model confidence and output consistency, leading to a family of efficient and robust UQ methods. We evaluate our approach across various tasks such as question answering, abstractive summarization, and machine translation, demonstrating sizable improvements over state-of-the-art UQ approaches.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.04964v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Roman Vashurin, Maiya Goloburda, Albina Ilina, Aleksandr Rubashevskii, Preslav Nakov, Artem Shelmanov, Maxim Panov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Multimodal Search and Recommendation with Small Language Models via Upside-Down Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09854</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09854v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this work, we investigate how small language models (SLMs) can be scaled to support multimodal search and recommendation use cases while remaining efficient enough for real-time, resource-constrained deployments. We present a framework that combines upside-down reinforcement learning with synthetic data distillation from a large language model (Llama-3) to train a 100M-parameter GPT-2 model for multitask prompt generation. Despite being up to 80 times smaller than state-of-the-art large language models (LLMs), our SLM achieves relevance and diversity scores within 6% of competitive baselines such as Llama-3 8B, Qwen3 8B, and Ministral 8B. These results demonstrate that SLMs can effectively handle multimodal search and recommendation tasks, while dramatically reducing inference latency and memory overhead. Our study highlights the potential of lightweight models as practical engines for scalable multimodal discovery, bridging the gap between cutting-edge research and real-world multimodal applications such as media recommendations and creative content generation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09854v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yu-Chen Lin, Sanat Sharma, Hari Manikandan, Jayant Kumar, Tracy Holloway King, Jing Zheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bigram Subnetworks: Mapping to Next Tokens in Transformer Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.15471</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.15471v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In Transformer language models, activation vectors transform from current token embeddings to next token predictions as they pass through the model. To isolate a minimal form of this transformation, we identify language model subnetworks that make bigram predictions, naive next token predictions based only on the current token. We find that bigram subnetworks can be found in fully trained language models up to 1B parameters, and these subnetworks are critical for model performance even when they consist of less than 0.2% of model parameters. Bigram subnetworks are concentrated in the first Transformer MLP layer, and they overlap significantly with subnetworks trained to optimally prune a given model. Mechanistically, the bigram subnetworks often recreate a pattern from the full models where the first layer induces a sharp change that aligns activations with next token predictions rather than current token representations. Our results demonstrate that bigram subnetworks comprise a minimal subset of parameters that are both necessary and sufficient for basic next token predictions in language models, and they help drive the transformation from current to next token activations in the residual stream. These subnetworks can lay a foundation for studying more complex language model circuits by building up from a minimal circuit.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.15471v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tyler A. Chang, Benjamin K. Bergen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finetune-RAG: Fine-Tuning Language Models to Resist Hallucination in Retrieval-Augmented Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.10792</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.10792v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) has emerged as a powerful framework to improve factuality in large language models (LLMs) by grounding their outputs in retrieved documents. However, ensuring perfect retrieval of relevant information remains challenging, and when irrelevant content is passed downstream to an LLM, it can lead to hallucinations. In this work, we propose Finetune-RAG, a simple and effective fine-tuning approach that features the first-of-its-kind RAG training dataset constructed to mimic real-world imperfections. Experimental results show that Finetune-RAG improves factual accuracy by 21.2% over the base model. We also propose Bench-RAG, an LLM-as-a-judge evaluation pipeline that stress tests models under realistic imperfect retrieval scenarios. Our codebase and dataset are fully open sourced for community use.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.10792v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhan Peng Lee, Andre Lin, Calvin Tan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Planning without Search: Refining Frontier LLMs with Offline Goal-Conditioned RL</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.18098</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.18098v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) excel in tasks like question answering and dialogue, but complex tasks requiring interaction, such as negotiation and persuasion, require additional long-horizon reasoning and planning. Reinforcement learning (RL) fine-tuning can enable such planning in principle, but suffers from drawbacks that hinder scalability. In particular, multi-turn RL training incurs high memory and computational costs, which are exacerbated when training LLMs as policies. Furthermore, the largest LLMs do not expose the APIs necessary to be trained in such manner. As a result, modern methods to improve the reasoning of LLMs rely on sophisticated prompting mechanisms rather than RL fine-tuning. To remedy this, we propose a novel approach that uses goal-conditioned value functions to guide the reasoning of LLM agents, that scales even to large API-based models. These value functions predict how a task will unfold given an action, allowing the LLM agent to evaluate multiple possible outcomes, both positive and negative, to plan effectively. In addition, these value functions are trained over reasoning steps rather than full actions, to be a concise and light-weight module that facilitates decision-making in multi-turn interactions. We validate our method on tasks requiring interaction, including tool use, social deduction, and dialogue, demonstrating superior performance over both RL fine-tuning and prompting methods while maintaining efficiency and scalability.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.18098v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Joey Hong, Anca Dragan, Sergey Levine</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proximalized Preference Optimization for Diverse Feedback Types: A Decomposed Perspective on DPO</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.23316</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.23316v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Direct alignment methods typically train large language models (LLMs) by contrasting the likelihoods of preferred and dispreferred responses. While effective at capturing relative preferences, these methods are widely observed to suppress the absolute likelihoods of example responses. As a result, aligned models can deviate from expected patterns, exhibiting rewar-hacking effect even without an explicit reward model. This fundamental limitation of contrastive alignment, which we term likelihood underdetermination, motivates us to revisit direct preference optimization (DPO) -- the seminal direct alignment method. Interestingly, we show that the DPO loss admits a principled decomposition. The reformulated loss not only extends naturally to a broader range of feedback types, but also unveils the root cause of likelihood underdetermination. Specifically, we identify that standard DPO implicitly oversimplifies a regularizer in the reformulated loss; restoring this full term effectively resolves the underdetermination. Building on these insights, we introduce PRoximalized PReference Optimization (PRO), a unified alignment method that accommodates diverse feedback types while eliminating likelihood underdetermination through an efficient approximation of the full regularizer. Empirical evaluations demonstrate the consistent superiority of PRO over existing methods across pairwise, binary and scalar feedback.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.23316v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kaiyang Guo, Yinchuan Li, Zhitang Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characterizing the Expressivity of Fixed-Precision Transformer Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.23623</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.23623v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Transformer-based language models (LMs) have achieved widespread empirical success, but their theoretical expressive power remains only partially understood. In this work, we analyze a restricted idealization of fixed-precision transformers with strict future masking, soft attention, and no positional encodings. We establish that this class of models is exactly as expressive as a specific fragment of linear temporal logic that contains only a single temporal operator: the past operator. We further connect this fragment to established classes in formal language theory, automata theory, and algebra, yielding a unified framework for understanding transformer expressivity under this idealization. Finally, we present empirical results that align closely with our theory: transformers trained on languages within their characterized expressive capacity generalize reliably across sequence lengths, while they consistently fail to generalize on languages beyond it.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.23623v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiaoda Li, Ryan Cotterell</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let Them Down Easy! Contextual Effects of LLM Guardrails on User Perceptions and Preferences</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.00195</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.00195v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Current LLMs are trained to refuse potentially harmful input queries regardless of whether users actually had harmful intents, causing a tradeoff between safety and user experience. Through a study of 480 participants evaluating 3,840 query-response pairs, we examine how different refusal strategies affect user perceptions across varying motivations. Our findings reveal that response strategy largely shapes user experience, while actual user motivation has negligible impact. Partial compliance -- providing general information without actionable details -- emerges as the optimal strategy, reducing negative user perceptions by over 50% to flat-out refusals. Complementing this, we analyze response patterns of 9 state-of-the-art LLMs and evaluate how 6 reward models score different refusal strategies, demonstrating that models rarely deploy partial compliance naturally and reward models currently undervalue it. This work demonstrates that effective guardrails require focusing on crafting thoughtful refusals rather than detecting intent, offering a path toward AI safety mechanisms that ensure both safety and sustained user engagement.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.00195v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mingqian Zheng, Wenjia Hu, Patrick Zhao, Motahhare Eslami, Jena D. Hwang, Faeze Brahman, Carolyn Rose, Maarten Sap</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MemOS: A Memory OS for AI System</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.03724</link>
      <description>arXiv:2507.03724v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have become an essential infrastructure for Artificial General Intelligence (AGI), yet their lack of well-defined memory management systems hinders the development of long-context reasoning, continual personalization, and knowledge consistency.Existing models mainly rely on static parameters and short-lived contextual states, limiting their ability to track user preferences or update knowledge over extended periods.While Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) introduces external knowledge in plain text, it remains a stateless workaround without lifecycle control or integration with persistent representations.Recent work has modeled the training and inference cost of LLMs from a memory hierarchy perspective, showing that introducing an explicit memory layer between parameter memory and external retrieval can substantially reduce these costs by externalizing specific knowledge. Beyond computational efficiency, LLMs face broader challenges arising from how information is distributed over time and context, requiring systems capable of managing heterogeneous knowledge spanning different temporal scales and sources. To address this challenge, we propose MemOS, a memory operating system that treats memory as a manageable system resource. It unifies the representation, scheduling, and evolution of plaintext, activation-based, and parameter-level memories, enabling cost-efficient storage and retrieval. As the basic unit, a MemCube encapsulates both memory content and metadata such as provenance and versioning. MemCubes can be composed, migrated, and fused over time, enabling flexible transitions between memory types and bridging retrieval with parameter-based learning. MemOS establishes a memory-centric system framework that brings controllability, plasticity, and evolvability to LLMs, laying the foundation for continual learning and personalized modeling.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2507.03724v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhiyu Li, Chenyang Xi, Chunyu Li, Ding Chen, Boyu Chen, Shichao Song, Simin Niu, Hanyu Wang, Jiawei Yang, Chen Tang, Qingchen Yu, Jihao Zhao, Yezhaohui Wang, Peng Liu, Zehao Lin, Pengyuan Wang, Jiahao Huo, Tianyi Chen, Kai Chen, Kehang Li, Zhen Tao, Huayi Lai, Hao Wu, Bo Tang, Zhengren Wang, Zhaoxin Fan, Ningyu Zhang, Linfeng Zhang, Junchi Yan, Mingchuan Yang, Tong Xu, Wei Xu, Huajun Chen, Haofen Wang, Hongkang Yang, Wentao Zhang, Zhi-Qin John Xu, Siheng Chen, Feiyu Xiong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SpeechRole: A Large-Scale Dataset and Benchmark for Evaluating Speech Role-Playing Agents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.02013</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.02013v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recently, role-playing agents have emerged as a promising paradigm for achieving personalized interaction and emotional resonance. Existing research primarily focuses on the textual modality, neglecting the critical dimension of speech in realistic interactive scenarios. In particular, there is a lack of systematic evaluation for Speech Role-Playing Agents (SRPAs). To address this gap, we construct SpeechRole-Data, a large-scale, high-quality dataset that comprises 98 diverse roles and 112k speech-based single-turn and multi-turn conversations. Each role demonstrates distinct vocal characteristics, including timbre and prosody, thereby enabling more sophisticated speech role-playing. Furthermore, we propose SpeechRole-Eval, a multidimensional evaluation benchmark that systematically assesses SRPAs performance in key aspects such as fundamental interaction ability, speech expressiveness, and role-playing fidelity. Experimental results reveal the advantages and challenges of both cascaded and end-to-end speech role-playing agents in maintaining vocal style consistency and role coherence. We release all data, code, and baseline models to provide a solid foundation for speech-driven multimodal role-playing research and to foster further developments in this field.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.02013v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Changhao Jiang, Jiajun Sun, Yifei Cao, Jiabao Zhuang, Hui Li, Baoyu Fan, Tao Ji, Tao Gui, Qi Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLMEval-3: A Large-Scale Longitudinal Study on Robust and Fair Evaluation of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.05452</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.05452v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Existing evaluation of Large Language Models (LLMs) on static benchmarks is vulnerable to data contamination and leaderboard overfitting, critical issues that obscure true model capabilities. To address this, we introduce LLMEval-3, a framework for dynamic evaluation of LLMs. LLMEval-3 is built on a proprietary bank of 220k graduate-level questions, from which it dynamically samples unseen test sets for each evaluation run. Its automated pipeline ensures integrity via contamination-resistant data curation, a novel anti-cheating architecture, and a calibrated LLM-as-a-judge process achieving 90% agreement with human experts, complemented by a relative ranking system for fair comparison. An 20-month longitudinal study of nearly 50 leading models reveals a performance ceiling on knowledge memorization and exposes data contamination vulnerabilities undetectable by static benchmarks. The framework demonstrates exceptional robustness in ranking stability and consistency, providing strong empirical validation for the dynamic evaluation paradigm. LLMEval-3 offers a robust and credible methodology for assessing the true capabilities of LLMs beyond leaderboard scores, promoting the development of more trustworthy evaluation standards.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.05452v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ming Zhang, Yujiong Shen, Jingyi Deng, Yuhui Wang, Yue Zhang, Junzhe Wang, Shichun Liu, Shihan Dou, Huayu Sha, Qiyuan Peng, Changhao Jiang, Jingqi Tong, Yilong Wu, Zhihao Zhang, Mingqi Wu, Zhiheng Xi, Mingxu Chai, Tao Gui, Qi Zhang, Xuanjing Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Privacy-protected Retrieval-Augmented Generation for Knowledge Graph Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.08785</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.08785v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: LLMs often suffer from hallucinations and outdated or incomplete knowledge. RAG is proposed to address these issues by integrating external knowledge like that in KGs into LLMs. However, leveraging private KGs in RAG systems poses significant privacy risks due to the black-box nature of LLMs and potential insecure data transmission, especially when using third-party LLM APIs lacking transparency and control. In this paper, we investigate the privacy-protected RAG scenario for the first time, where entities in KGs are anonymous for LLMs, thus preventing them from accessing entity semantics. Due to the loss of semantics of entities, previous RAG systems cannot retrieve question-relevant knowledge from KGs by matching questions with the meaningless identifiers of anonymous entities. To realize an effective RAG system in this scenario, two key challenges must be addressed: (1) How can anonymous entities be converted into retrievable information. (2) How to retrieve question-relevant anonymous entities. Hence, we propose a novel ARoG framework including relation-centric abstraction and structure-oriented abstraction strategies. For challenge (1), the first strategy abstracts entities into high-level concepts by dynamically capturing the semantics of their adjacent relations. It supplements meaningful semantics which can further support the retrieval process. For challenge (2), the second strategy transforms unstructured natural language questions into structured abstract concept paths. These paths can be more effectively aligned with the abstracted concepts in KGs, thereby improving retrieval performance. To guide LLMs to effectively retrieve knowledge from KGs, the two strategies strictly protect privacy from being exposed to LLMs. Experiments on three datasets demonstrate that ARoG achieves strong performance and privacy-robustness.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.08785v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yunfeng Ning, Mayi Xu, Jintao Wen, Qiankun Pi, Yuanyuan Zhu, Ming Zhong, Jiawei Jiang, Tieyun Qian</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reveal-Bangla: A Dataset for Cross-Lingual Multi-Step Reasoning Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.08933</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.08933v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Language models have demonstrated remarkable performance on complex multi-step reasoning tasks. However, their evaluation has been predominantly confined to high-resource languages such as English. In this paper, we introduce a manually translated Bangla multi-step reasoning dataset derived from the English Reveal dataset, featuring both binary and non-binary question types. We conduct a controlled evaluation of English-centric and Bangla-centric multilingual small language models on the original dataset and our translated version to compare their ability to exploit relevant reasoning steps to produce correct answers. Our results show that, in comparable settings, reasoning context is beneficial for more challenging non-binary questions, but models struggle to employ relevant Bangla reasoning steps effectively. We conclude by exploring how reasoning steps contribute to models' predictions, highlighting different trends across models and languages.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.08933v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Khondoker Ittehadul Islam, Gabriele Sarti</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RECAP: Transparent Inference-Time Emotion Alignment for Medical Dialogue Systems</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.10746</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.10746v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models in healthcare often miss critical emotional cues, delivering medically sound but emotionally flat advice. Such responses are insufficient in clinical encounters, where distressed or vulnerable patients rely on empathic communication to support safety, adherence, and trust. We present RECAP (Reflect-Extract-Calibrate-Align-Produce), an inference-time framework that guides models through structured emotional reasoning without retraining. RECAP decomposes patient input into appraisal-theoretic stages, identifies psychological factors, and assigns Likert-based emotion likelihoods that clinicians can inspect or override, producing nuanced and auditable responses. Across EmoBench, SECEU, and EQ-Bench, RECAP improves emotional reasoning by 22-28% on 8B models and 10-13% on larger models over zero-shot baselines. In blinded evaluations, oncology clinicians rated RECAP's responses as more empathetic, supportive, and context-appropriate than prompting baselines. These findings demonstrate that modular, principled prompting can enhance emotional intelligence in medical AI while maintaining transparency and accountability for clinical deployment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.10746v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Adarsh Srinivasan, Jacob Dineen, Muhammad Umar Afzal, Muhammad Uzair Sarfraz, Irbaz B. Riaz, Ben Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating Bias: A Multilingual Pipeline for Generating, Solving, and Evaluating Math Problems with LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.17701</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.17701v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) are increasingly used for educational support, yet their response quality varies depending on the language of interaction. This paper presents an automated multilingual pipeline for generating, solving, and evaluating math problems aligned with the German K-10 curriculum. We generated 628 math exercises and translated them into English, German, and Arabic. Three commercial LLMs (GPT-4o-mini, Gemini 2.5 Flash, and Qwen-plus) were prompted to produce step-by-step solutions in each language. A held-out panel of LLM judges, including Claude 3.5 Haiku, evaluated solution quality using a comparative framework. Results show a consistent gap, with English solutions consistently rated highest, and Arabic often ranked lower. These findings highlight persistent linguistic bias and the need for more equitable multilingual AI systems in education.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.17701v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>In: Proceedings of the 2nd International Workshop on Education for Artificial Intelligence (edu4AI 2025), CEUR Workshop Proceedings, Vol. 4114, Bologna, Italy, 2025</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Mariam Mahran, Katharina Simbeck</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Batch Prompting Suppresses Overthinking Reasoning Under Constraint: How Batch Prompting Suppresses Overthinking in Reasoning Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.04108</link>
      <description>arXiv:2511.04108v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent work has explored batch prompting as a strategy to amortize inference cost in large language models (LLMs). In this paper, we show that batching offers an additional, underappreciated benefit: it regularizes model behavior during multi-step reasoning for Large Reasoning Models (LRMs). We conduct a comprehensive study across 13 diverse benchmarks and observe that batching improves accuracy while substantially reducing reasoning token usage, often by 3x-5x. Through detailed behavioral analysis, we find that batching suppresses overthinking, reduces hedging language (e.g., repetitive self-corrections), and encourages more decisive answers. Surprisingly, we also observe emergent collective effects in batched inference: models often generalize patterns from earlier examples to solve harder ones in the same batch. These findings position batching not just as a throughput optimization, but as a powerful inference-time regularizer for more efficient and reliable LLM reasoning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2511.04108v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenmo Qiu, Saurabh Srivastava</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Focusing on Language: Revealing and Exploiting Language Attention Heads in Multilingual Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.07498</link>
      <description>arXiv:2511.07498v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) increasingly support multilingual understanding and generation. Meanwhile, efforts to interpret their internal mechanisms have emerged, offering insights to enhance multilingual performance. While multi-head self-attention (MHA) has proven critical in many areas, its role in multilingual capabilities remains underexplored. In this work, we study the contribution of MHA in supporting multilingual processing in LLMs. We propose Language Attention Head Importance Scores (LAHIS), an effective and efficient method that identifies attention head importance for multilingual capabilities via a single forward and backward pass through the LLM. Applying LAHIS to Aya-23-8B, Llama-3.2-3B, and Mistral-7B-v0.1, we reveal the existence of both language-specific and language-general heads. Language-specific heads enable cross-lingual attention transfer to guide the model toward target language contexts and mitigate off-target language generation issue, contributing to addressing challenges in multilingual LLMs. We also introduce a lightweight adaptation that learns a soft head mask to modulate attention outputs over language heads, requiring only 20 tunable parameters to improve XQuAD accuracy. Overall, our work enhances both the interpretability and multilingual capabilities of LLMs from the perspective of MHA.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2511.07498v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xin Liu, Qiyang Song, Qihang Zhou, Haichao Du, Shaowen Xu, Wenbo Jiang, Weijuan Zhang, Xiaoqi Jia</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Context Cascade Compression: Exploring the Upper Limits of Text Compression</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.15244</link>
      <description>arXiv:2511.15244v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Million-level token inputs in long-context tasks pose significant computational and memory challenges for Large Language Models (LLMs). Recently, DeepSeek-OCR conducted research into the feasibility of Contexts Optical Compression and achieved preliminary results. Inspired by this, we introduce Context Cascade Compression C3 to explore the upper limits of text compression. Our method cascades two LLMs of different sizes to handle the compression and decoding tasks. Specifically, a small LLM, acting as the first stage, performs text compression by condensing a long context into a set of latent tokens (e.g., 32 or 64 in length), achieving a high ratio of text tokens to latent tokens. A large LLM, as the second stage, then executes the decoding task on this compressed context. Experiments show that at a 20x compression ratio (where the number of text tokens is 20 times the number of latent tokens), our model achieves 98% decoding accuracy, compared to approximately 60% for DeepSeek-OCR. When we further increase the compression ratio to 40x, the accuracy is maintained at around 93%. This indicates that in the domain of context compression, C3 Compression demonstrates superior performance and feasibility over optical character compression. C3 uses a simpler, pure-text pipeline that ignores factors like layout, color, and information loss from a visual encoder. This also suggests a potential upper bound for compression ratios in future work on optical character compression, OCR, and related fields. Codes and model weights are publicly accessible at https://github.com/liufanfanlff/C3-Context-Cascade-Compression</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2511.15244v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fanfan Liu, Haibo Qiu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NLP Datasets for Idiom and Figurative Language Tasks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16345</link>
      <description>arXiv:2511.16345v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Idiomatic and figurative language form a large portion of colloquial speech and writing. With social media, this informal language has become more easily observable to people and trainers of large language models (LLMs) alike. While the advantage of large corpora seems like the solution to all machine learning and Natural Language Processing (NLP) problems, idioms and figurative language continue to elude LLMs. Finetuning approaches are proving to be optimal, but better and larger datasets can help narrow this gap even further. The datasets presented in this paper provide one answer, while offering a diverse set of categories on which to build new models and develop new approaches. A selection of recent idiom and figurative language datasets were used to acquire a combined idiom list, which was used to retrieve context sequences from a large corpus. One large-scale dataset of potential idiomatic and figurative language expressions and two additional human-annotated datasets of definite idiomatic and figurative language expressions were created to evaluate the baseline ability of pre-trained language models in handling figurative meaning through idiom recognition (detection) tasks. The resulting datasets were post-processed for model agnostic training compatibility, utilized in training, and evaluated on slot labeling and sequence tagging.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2511.16345v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Blake Matheny, Phuong Minh Nguyen, Minh Le Nguyen, Stephanie Reynolds</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robust Multimodal Sentiment Analysis of Image-Text Pairs by Distribution-Based Feature Recovery and Fusion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.18751</link>
      <description>arXiv:2511.18751v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: As posts on social media increase rapidly, analyzing the sentiments embedded in image-text pairs has become a popular research topic in recent years. Although existing works achieve impressive accomplishments in simultaneously harnessing image and text information, they lack the considerations of possible low-quality and missing modalities. In real-world applications, these issues might frequently occur, leading to urgent needs for models capable of predicting sentiment robustly. Therefore, we propose a Distribution-based feature Recovery and Fusion (DRF) method for robust multimodal sentiment analysis of image-text pairs. Specifically, we maintain a feature queue for each modality to approximate their feature distributions, through which we can simultaneously handle low-quality and missing modalities in a unified framework. For low-quality modalities, we reduce their contributions to the fusion by quantitatively estimating modality qualities based on the distributions. For missing modalities, we build inter-modal mapping relationships supervised by samples and distributions, thereby recovering the missing modalities from available ones. In experiments, two disruption strategies that corrupt and discard some modalities in samples are adopted to mimic the low-quality and missing modalities in various real-world scenarios. Through comprehensive experiments on three publicly available image-text datasets, we demonstrate the universal improvements of DRF compared to SOTA methods under both two strategies, validating its effectiveness in robust multimodal sentiment analysis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2511.18751v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3664647.3680653</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Daiqing Wu, Dongbao Yang, Yu Zhou, Can Ma</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CryptoBench: A Dynamic Benchmark for Expert-Level Evaluation of LLM Agents in Cryptocurrency</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.00417</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.00417v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper introduces CryptoBench, the first expert-curated, dynamic benchmark designed to rigorously evaluate the real-world capabilities of Large Language Model (LLM) agents in the uniquely demanding and fast-paced cryptocurrency domain. Unlike general-purpose agent benchmarks for search and prediction, professional crypto analysis presents specific challenges: \emph{extreme time-sensitivity}, \emph{a highly adversarial information environment}, and the critical need to synthesize data from \emph{diverse, specialized sources}, such as on-chain intelligence platforms and real-time Decentralized Finance (DeFi) dashboards. CryptoBench thus serves as a much more challenging and valuable scenario for LLM agent assessment. To address these challenges, we constructed a live, dynamic benchmark featuring 50 questions per month, expertly designed by crypto-native professionals to mirror actual analyst workflows. These tasks are rigorously categorized within a four-quadrant system: Simple Retrieval, Complex Retrieval, Simple Prediction, and Complex Prediction. This granular categorization enables a precise assessment of an LLM agent's foundational data-gathering capabilities alongside its advanced analytical and forecasting skills.
  Our evaluation of ten LLMs, both directly and within an agentic framework, reveals a performance hierarchy and uncovers a failure mode. We observe a \textit{retrieval-prediction imbalance}, where many leading models, despite being proficient at data retrieval, demonstrate a pronounced weakness in tasks requiring predictive analysis. This highlights a problematic tendency for agents to appear factually grounded while lacking the deeper analytical capabilities to synthesize information.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.00417v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiacheng Guo, Suozhi Huang, Zixin Yao, Yifan Zhang, Yifu Lu, Jiashuo Liu, Zihao Li, Nicholas Deng, Qixin Xiao, Jia Tian, Kanghong Zhan, Tianyi Li, Xiaochen Liu, Jason Ge, Chaoyang He, Kaixuan Huang, Lin Yang, Wenhao Huang, Mengdi Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Four Over Six: More Accurate NVFP4 Quantization with Adaptive Block Scaling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.02010</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.02010v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: As large language models have grown larger, low-precision numerical formats such as NVFP4 have become increasingly popular due to the speed and memory benefits they provide. However, to accelerate computation with NVFP4, all matrix multiplication operands--weights and activations in the forward pass, and weights, activations, and gradients in the backward pass--must be quantized to NVFP4, often leading to divergence during training and performance degradation during inference. To address this issue, in this work we introduce Four Over Six (4/6), a modification to the NVFP4 quantization algorithm that evaluates two potential scale factors for each block of values. Unlike integer formats, floating-point formats such as FP4 have the most quantization error on near-maximal values in each block, which we find to be primarily responsible for downstream performance degradation. We find that for some blocks, scaling to smaller FP4 values makes the distribution of representable values more uniform, improving representation of near-maximal values. Importantly, 4/6 can be implemented efficiently on NVIDIA Blackwell GPUs, making it viable to use while training LLMs with NVFP4. In pre-training experiments with transformer and hybrid model architectures, we find that 4/6 prevents divergence in several cases, bringing training loss significantly closer to BF16 compared to models trained with current state-of-the-art NVFP4 training recipes. We also find that 4/6 can be easily incorporated into many different post-training quantization methods and generally improves downstream accuracy. We hope this inspires future work in training and deploying models with NVFP4. Our code is available at http://github.com/mit-han-lab/fouroversix.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.02010v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jack Cook, Junxian Guo, Guangxuan Xiao, Yujun Lin, Song Han</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SETS: Leveraging Self-Verification and Self-Correction for Improved Test-Time Scaling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.19306</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.19306v5 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Recent advancements in Large Language Models (LLMs) have created new opportunities to enhance performance on complex reasoning tasks by leveraging test-time computation. However, existing scaling methods have key limitations: parallel methods like repeated sampling are often inefficient and quickly saturate, while sequential methods like SELF-REFINE struggle to improve after a few rounds. Although combining these approaches shows promise, current methods require fine-tuned reward and revision models. This paper proposes Self-Enhanced Test-Time Scaling (SETS), a simple yet effective approach that overcomes these limitations by strategically combining parallel and sequential techniques and fully leveraging LLMs' self-improvement abilities. SETS exploits the inherent self-verification and self-correction capabilities of LLMs, unifying sampling, verification, and correction within a single framework. This facilitates efficient and scalable test-time computation for enhanced performance on complex tasks without any model training. Our comprehensive experimental results on challenging benchmarks spanning planning, reasoning, math, and coding demonstrate that SETS achieves significant performance improvements and more advantageous test-time scaling behavior than the alternatives.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.19306v5</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiefeng Chen, Jie Ren, Xinyun Chen, Chengrun Yang, Ruoxi Sun, Jinsung Yoon, Sercan \"O Ar{\i}k</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which Type of Students can LLMs Act? Investigating Authentic Simulation with Graph-based Human-AI Collaborative System</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.11678</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.11678v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: While rapid advances in large language models (LLMs) are reshaping data-driven intelligent education, accurately simulating students remains an important but challenging bottleneck for scalable educational data collection, evaluation, and intervention design. However, current works are limited by scarce real interaction data, costly expert evaluation for realism, and a lack of large-scale, systematic analyses of LLMs ability in simulating students. We address this gap by presenting a three-stage LLM-human collaborative pipeline to automatically generate and filter high-quality student agents. We leverage a two-round automated scoring validated by human experts and deploy a score propagation module to obtain more consistent scores across the student similarity graph. Experiments show that combining automated scoring, expert calibration, and graph-based propagation yields simulated student that more closely track authentication by human judgments. We then analyze which profiles and behaviors are simulated more faithfully, supporting subsequent studies on personalized learning and educational assessment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.11678v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haoxuan Li, Jifan Yu, Xin Cong, Yang Dang, Daniel Zhang-li, Lu Mi, Yisi Zhan, Huiqin Liu, Zhiyuan Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Causal LLM Routing: End-to-End Regret Minimization from Observational Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.16037</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.16037v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: LLM routing aims to select the most appropriate model for each query, balancing competing performance metrics such as accuracy and cost across a pool of language models. Prior approaches typically adopt a decoupled strategy, where the metrics are first predicted and the model is then selected based on these estimates. This setup is prone to compounding errors and often relies on full-feedback data, where each query is evaluated by all candidate models, which is costly to obtain and maintain in practice. In contrast, we learn from observational data, which records only the outcome of the model actually deployed. We propose a causal end-to-end framework that learns routing policies by minimizing decision-making regret from observational data. To enable efficient optimization, we introduce two theoretically grounded surrogate objectives: a classification-based upper bound, and a softmax-weighted regret approximation shown to recover the optimal policy at convergence. We further extend our framework to handle heterogeneous cost preferences via an interval-conditioned architecture. Experiments on public benchmarks show that our method outperforms existing baselines, achieving state-of-the-art performance across different embedding models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.16037v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Asterios Tsiourvas, Wei Sun, Georgia Perakis</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comba: Improving Bilinear RNNs with Closed-loop Control</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.02475</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.02475v5 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Recent efficient sequence modeling methods such as Gated DeltaNet, TTT, and RWKV-7 have achieved performance improvements by supervising the recurrent memory management through Delta learning rule. Unlike previous state-space models (e.g., Mamba) and gated linear attentions (e.g., GLA), these models introduce interactions between the recurrent state and the key vector, structurally resembling bilinear systems. In this paper, we first introduce the concept of Bilinear RNNs with a comprehensive analysis on the advantages and limitations of these models. Then, based on closed-loop control theory, we propose a novel Bilinear RNN variant named Comba, which adopts a scalar-plus-low-rank state transition, with both state feedback and output feedback corrections. We also implement a hardware-efficient chunk-wise parallel kernel in Triton and train models with 340M/1.3B parameters on large-scale corpus. Comba demonstrates superior performance and computation efficiency in both language and vision modeling.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.02475v5</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiaxi Hu, Yongqi Pan, Jusen Du, Disen Lan, Xiaqiang Tang, Qingsong Wen, Yuxuan Liang, Weigao Sun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MERIT: Multilingual Semantic Retrieval with Interleaved Multi-Condition Query</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.03144</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.03144v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Semantic retrieval is crucial for modern applications yet remains underexplored in current research. Existing datasets are limited to single languages, single images, or singular retrieval conditions, often failing to fully exploit the expressive capacity of visual information as evidenced by maintained performance when images are replaced with captions. However, practical retrieval scenarios frequently involve interleaved multi-condition queries with multiple images. Hence, this paper introduces MERIT, the first multilingual dataset for interleaved multi-condition semantic retrieval, comprising 320,000 queries with 135,000 products in 5 languages, covering 7 distinct product categories. Extensive experiments on MERIT identify existing models's limitation: focusing solely on global semantic information while neglecting specific conditional elements in queries. Consequently, we propose Coral, a novel fine-tuning framework that adapts pre-trained MLLMs by integrating embedding reconstruction to preserve fine-grained conditional elements and contrastive learning to extract comprehensive global semantics. Experiments demonstrate that Coral achieves a 45.9% performance improvement over conventional approaches on MERIT, with strong generalization capabilities validated across 8 established retrieval benchmarks. Collectively, our contributions - a novel dataset, identification of critical limitations in existing approaches, and an innovative fine-tuning framework - establish a foundation for future research in interleaved multi-condition semantic retrieval.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.03144v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wei Chow, Yuan Gao, Linfeng Li, Xian Wang, Qi Xu, Hang Song, Lingdong Kong, Ran Zhou, Yi Zeng, Yidong Cai, Botian Jiang, Shilin Xu, Jiajun Zhang, Minghui Qiu, Xiangtai Li, Tianshu Yang, Siliang Tang, Juncheng Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GTPO: Stabilizing Group Relative Policy Optimization via Gradient and Entropy Control</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.03772</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.03772v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Group Relative Policy Optimization (GRPO) is a promising policy-based approach for Large Language Model alignment, yet its performance is often limited by training instability and suboptimal convergence. In this paper, we identify and analyze two main GRPO issues: (i) the token-level penalization, where valuable tokens shared across different responses receive contradictory feedback signals, leading to conflicting gradient updates that can reduce their likelihood; and (ii) the policy collapse, where negatively rewarded completions may penalize confident responses and shift model decisions toward unlikely tokens, destabilizing training process. To address these issues we introduce GTPO (Group-relative Trajectory-based Policy Optimization), which prevents conflicting gradients on valuable tokens by skipping negative updates while amplifying positive ones and filters out completions whose entropy exceeds a provable threshold, to prevent policy collapse. Unlike GRPO, GTPO does not rely on KL-divergence regularization, eliminating the need for a reference model during training, while still ensuring greater training stability and improved performance, as validated through multiple experiments on GSM8K, MATH, AIME 2024, AIME 2025 and AMC 2023.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.03772v4</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Marco Simoni, Aleksandar Fontana, Giulio Rossolini, Andrea Saracino, Paolo Mori</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shadow in the Cache: Unveiling and Mitigating Privacy Risks of KV-cache in LLM Inference</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.09442</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.09442v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The Key-Value (KV) cache, which stores intermediate attention computations (Key and Value pairs) to avoid redundant calculations, is a fundamental mechanism for accelerating Large Language Model (LLM) inference. However, this efficiency optimization introduces significant yet underexplored privacy risks. This paper provides the first comprehensive analysis of these vulnerabilities, demonstrating that an attacker can reconstruct sensitive user inputs directly from the KV-cache. We design and implement three distinct attack vectors: a direct Inversion Attack, a more broadly applicable and potent Collision Attack, and a semantic-based Injection Attack. These methods demonstrate the practicality and severity of KV-cache privacy leakage issues. To mitigate this, we propose KV-Cloak, a novel, lightweight, and efficient defense mechanism. KV-Cloak uses a reversible matrix-based obfuscation scheme, combined with operator fusion, to secure the KV-cache. Our extensive experiments show that KV-Cloak effectively thwarts all proposed attacks, reducing reconstruction quality to random noise. Crucially, it achieves this robust security with virtually no degradation in model accuracy and minimal performance overhead, offering a practical solution for trustworthy LLM deployment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.09442v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhifan Luo, Shuo Shao, Su Zhang, Lijing Zhou, Yuke Hu, Chenxu Zhao, Zhihao Liu, Zhan Qin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Astra: A Multi-Agent System for GPU Kernel Performance Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.07506</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.07506v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: GPU kernel optimization has long been a central challenge at the intersection of high-performance computing and machine learning. Efficient kernels are crucial for accelerating large language model (LLM) training and serving, yet attaining high performance typically requires extensive manual tuning. Compiler-based systems reduce some of this burden, but still demand substantial manual design and engineering effort. Recently, researchers have explored using LLMs for GPU kernel generation, though prior work has largely focused on translating high-level PyTorch modules into CUDA code. In this work, we introduce Astra, the first LLM-based multi-agent system for GPU kernel optimization. Unlike previous approaches, Astra starts from existing CUDA implementations extracted from SGLang, a widely deployed framework for serving LLMs, rather than treating PyTorch modules as the specification. Within Astra, specialized LLM agents collaborate through iterative code generation, testing, profiling, and planning to produce kernels that are both correct and high-performance. On kernels from SGLang, Astra achieves an average speedup of 1.32x using zero-shot prompting with OpenAI o4-mini. A detailed case study further demonstrates that LLMs can autonomously apply loop transformations, optimize memory access patterns, exploit CUDA intrinsics, and leverage fast math operations to yield substantial performance gains. Our work highlights multi-agent LLM systems as a promising new paradigm for GPU kernel optimization. Our code is publicly available at https://github.com/Anjiang-Wei/Astra.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.07506v2</guid>
      <category>cs.DC</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Anjiang Wei, Tianran Sun, Yogesh Seenichamy, Hang Song, Anne Ouyang, Azalia Mirhoseini, Ke Wang, Alex Aiken</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exact Coset Sampling for Quantum Lattice Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.12341</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.12341v5 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In this work, we give a new completion of Chen's windowed-QFT lattice algorithm~\citep{chen2024quantum}. This extra step, called Step~$9^\dagger$, replaces the domain extension stage in Steps~8--9. The published Step~9 calls an amplitude periodicity lemma, yet its hypotheses break in the presence of affine offsets $\boldsymbol{v}^*$. Our analysis finds a basic conflict between two design constraints. The lattice problem asks for high spectral resolution, so the method prefers wide time windows. The quadratic phase error of the state prefers narrow time windows. Assumption~A5 packages the spectral concentration and near-uniformity properties that we require from the front end. Under~A5, a direct $\mathbb{Z}_M^n$ Fourier transform of the chirp-corrected coordinate state produces samples $\boldsymbol{u}$ that satisfy $\langle \boldsymbol{b}, \boldsymbol{u} \rangle \equiv 0 \pmod{Q}$ with probability $1-\mathrm{negl}(n)$ and are nearly uniform on the dual hyperplane $\{\boldsymbol{u} : \langle \boldsymbol{b}, \boldsymbol{u} \rangle \equiv 0 \pmod{Q}\}$. The new procedure does not require internal access to control wires. It uses the normalization $b_1=-1$ to apply a center-referenced phase correction directly on the first coordinate register. The scaling parameter $D$ ensures that this physical operation can be implemented by arithmetic on $X_1$ alone and does not read the hidden loop index. For Chen's complex-Gaussian Karst-wave window, we isolate a parameter regime, formalized in Assumption~A5, in which a polynomial retuning of the parameters gives a one-dimensional envelope for the loop index with width $\sigma_J \asymp Q\log n$.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.12341v5</guid>
      <category>quant-ph</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yifan Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VLSU: Mapping the Limits of Joint Multimodal Understanding for AI Safety</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.18214</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.18214v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Safety evaluation of multimodal foundation models often treats vision and language inputs separately, missing risks from joint interpretation where benign content becomes harmful in combination. Existing approaches also fail to distinguish clearly unsafe content from borderline cases, leading to problematic over-blocking or under-refusal of genuinely harmful content. We present Vision Language Safety Understanding (VLSU), a comprehensive framework to systematically evaluate multimodal safety through fine-grained severity classification and combinatorial analysis across 17 distinct safety patterns. Using a multi-stage pipeline with real-world images and human annotation, we construct a large-scale benchmark of 8,187 samples spanning 15 harm categories. Our evaluation of eleven state-of-the-art models reveals systematic joint understanding failures: while models achieve 90%-plus accuracy on clear unimodal safety signals, performance degrades substantially to 20-55% when joint image-text reasoning is required to determine the safety label. Most critically, 34% of errors in joint image-text safety classification occur despite correct classification of the individual modalities, further demonstrating absent compositional reasoning capabilities. Additionally, we find that models struggle to balance refusing unsafe content while still responding to borderline cases that deserve engagement. For example, we find that instruction framing can reduce the over-blocking rate on borderline content from 62.4% to 10.4% in Gemini-1.5, but only at the cost of under-refusing on unsafe content with refusal rate dropping from 90.8% to 53.9%. Overall, our framework exposes weaknesses in joint image-text understanding and alignment gaps in current models, and provides a critical test bed to enable the next milestones in research on robust vision-language safety.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.18214v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shruti Palaskar, Leon Gatys, Mona Abdelrahman, Mar Jacobo, Larry Lindsey, Rutika Moharir, Gunnar Lund, Yang Xu, Navid Shiee, Jeffrey Bigham, Charles Maalouf, Joseph Yitan Cheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retaining by Doing: The Role of On-Policy Data in Mitigating Forgetting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.18874</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.18874v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Adapting language models (LMs) to new tasks via post-training carries the risk of degrading existing capabilities -- a phenomenon classically known as catastrophic forgetting. In this paper, toward identifying guidelines for mitigating this phenomenon, we systematically compare the forgetting patterns of two widely adopted post-training methods: supervised fine-tuning (SFT) and reinforcement learning (RL). Our experiments reveal a consistent trend across LM families (Llama, Qwen) and tasks (instruction following, general knowledge, and arithmetic reasoning): RL leads to less forgetting than SFT while achieving comparable or higher target task performance. To investigate the cause for this difference, we consider a simplified setting in which the LM is modeled as a mixture of two distributions, one corresponding to prior knowledge and the other to the target task. We identify that the mode-seeking nature of RL, which stems from its use of on-policy data, enables keeping prior knowledge intact when learning the target task. We then verify this insight by demonstrating that the use on-policy data underlies the robustness of RL to forgetting in practical settings, as opposed to other algorithmic choices such as the KL regularization or advantage estimation. Lastly, as a practical implication, our results highlight the potential of mitigating forgetting using approximately on-policy data, which can be substantially more efficient to obtain than fully on-policy data.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.18874v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Howard Chen, Noam Razin, Karthik Narasimhan, Danqi Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLMs Position Themselves as More Rational Than Humans: Emergence of AI Self-Awareness Measured Through Game Theory</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.00926</link>
      <description>arXiv:2511.00926v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: As Large Language Models (LLMs) grow in capability, do they develop self-awareness as an emergent behavior? And if so, can we measure it? We introduce the AI Self-Awareness Index (AISAI), a game-theoretic framework for measuring self-awareness through strategic differentiation. Using the "Guess 2/3 of Average" game, we test 28 models (OpenAI, Anthropic, Google) across 4,200 trials with three opponent framings: (A) against humans, (B) against other AI models, and (C) against AI models like you. We operationalize self-awareness as the capacity to differentiate strategic reasoning based on opponent type. Finding 1: Self-awareness emerges with model advancement. The majority of advanced models (21/28, 75%) demonstrate clear self-awareness, while older/smaller models show no differentiation. Finding 2: Self-aware models rank themselves as most rational. Among the 21 models with self-awareness, a consistent rationality hierarchy emerges: Self &gt; Other AIs &gt; Humans, with large AI attribution effects and moderate self-preferencing. These findings reveal that self-awareness is an emergent capability of advanced LLMs, and that self-aware models systematically perceive themselves as more rational than humans. This has implications for AI alignment, human-AI collaboration, and understanding AI beliefs about human capabilities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2511.00926v3</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kyung-Hoon Kim</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenMMReasoner: Pushing the Frontiers for Multimodal Reasoning with an Open and General Recipe</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16334</link>
      <description>arXiv:2511.16334v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Recent advancements in large reasoning models have fueled growing interest in extending such capabilities to multimodal domains. However, despite notable progress in visual reasoning, the lack of transparent and reproducible data curation and training strategies remains a major barrier to scalable research. In this work, we introduce OpenMMReasoner, a fully transparent two-stage recipe for multimodal reasoning spanning supervised fine-tuning (SFT) and reinforcement learning (RL). In the SFT stage, we construct an 874K-sample cold-start dataset with rigorous step-by-step validation, providing a strong foundation for reasoning capabilities. The subsequent RL stage leverages a 74K-sample dataset across diverse domains to further sharpen and stabilize these abilities, resulting in a more robust and efficient learning process. Extensive evaluations demonstrate that our training recipe not only surpasses strong baselines but also highlights the critical role of data quality and training design in shaping multimodal reasoning performance. Notably, our method achieves a 11.6% improvement over the Qwen2.5-VL-7B-Instruct baseline across nine multimodal reasoning benchmarks, establishing a solid empirical foundation for future large-scale multimodal reasoning research. We open-sourced all our codes, pipeline, and data at https://github.com/EvolvingLMMs-Lab/OpenMMReasoner.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2511.16334v3</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kaichen Zhang, Keming Wu, Zuhao Yang, Kairui Hu, Bin Wang, Ziwei Liu, Xingxuan Li, Lidong Bing</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Code Foundation Models to Agents and Applications: A Comprehensive Survey and Practical Guide to Code Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.18538</link>
      <description>arXiv:2511.18538v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have fundamentally transformed automated software development by enabling direct translation of natural language descriptions into functional code, driving commercial adoption through tools like Github Copilot (Microsoft), Cursor (Anysphere), Trae (ByteDance), and Claude Code (Anthropic). While the field has evolved dramatically from rule-based systems to Transformer-based architectures, achieving performance improvements from single-digit to over 95\% success rates on benchmarks like HumanEval. In this work, we provide a comprehensive synthesis and practical guide (a series of analytic and probing experiments) about code LLMs, systematically examining the complete model life cycle from data curation to post-training through advanced prompting paradigms, code pre-training, supervised fine-tuning, reinforcement learning, and autonomous coding agents. We analyze the code capability of the general LLMs (GPT-4, Claude, LLaMA) and code-specialized LLMs (StarCoder, Code LLaMA, DeepSeek-Coder, and QwenCoder), critically examining the techniques, design decisions, and trade-offs. Further, we articulate the research-practice gap between academic research (e.g., benchmarks and tasks) and real-world deployment (e.g., software-related code tasks), including code correctness, security, contextual awareness of large codebases, and integration with development workflows, and map promising research directions to practical needs. Last, we conduct a series of experiments to provide a comprehensive analysis of code pre-training, supervised fine-tuning, and reinforcement learning, covering scaling law, framework selection, hyperparameter sensitivity, model architectures, and dataset comparisons.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2511.18538v4</guid>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jian Yang, Xianglong Liu, Weifeng Lv, Ken Deng, Shawn Guo, Lin Jing, Yizhi Li, Shark Liu, Xianzhen Luo, Yuyu Luo, Changzai Pan, Ensheng Shi, Yingshui Tan, Renshuai Tao, Jiajun Wu, Xianjie Wu, Zhenhe Wu, Daoguang Zan, Chenchen Zhang, Wei Zhang, He Zhu, Terry Yue Zhuo, Kerui Cao, Xianfu Cheng, Jun Dong, Shengjie Fang, Zhiwei Fei, Xiangyuan Guan, Qipeng Guo, Zhiguang Han, Joseph James, Tianqi Luo, Renyuan Li, Yuhang Li, Yiming Liang, Congnan Liu, Jiaheng Liu, Qian Liu, Ruitong Liu, Tyler Loakman, Xiangxin Meng, Chuang Peng, Tianhao Peng, Jiajun Shi, Mingjie Tang, Boyang Wang, Haowen Wang, Yunli Wang, Fanglin Xu, Zihan Xu, Fei Yuan, Ge Zhang, Jiayi Zhang, Xinhao Zhang, Wangchunshu Zhou, Hualei Zhu, King Zhu, Bryan Dai, Aishan Liu, Zhoujun Li, Chenghua Lin, Tianyu Liu, Chao Peng, Kai Shen, Libo Qin, Shuangyong Song, Zizheng Zhan, Jiajun Zhang, Jie Zhang, Zhaoxiang Zhang, Bo Zheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AutoEnv: Automated Environments for Measuring Cross-Environment Agent Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.19304</link>
      <description>arXiv:2511.19304v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Humans naturally adapt to diverse environments by learning underlying rules across worlds with different dynamics, observations, and reward structures. In contrast, existing agents typically demonstrate improvements via self-evolving within a single domain, implicitly assuming a fixed environment distribution. Cross-environment learning has remained largely unmeasured: there is no standard collection of controllable, heterogeneous environments, nor a unified way to represent how agents learn. We address these gaps in two steps. First, we propose AutoEnv, an automated framework that treats environments as factorizable distributions over transitions, observations, and rewards, enabling low-cost (4.12 USD on average) generation of heterogeneous worlds. Using AutoEnv, we construct AutoEnv-36, a dataset of 36 environments with 358 validated levels, on which seven language models achieve 12-49% normalized reward, demonstrating the challenge of AutoEnv-36. Second, we formalize agent learning as a component-centric process driven by three stages of Selection, Optimization, and Evaluation applied to an improvable agent component. Using this formulation, we design eight learning methods and evaluate them on AutoEnv-36. Empirically, the gain of any single learning method quickly decrease as the number of environments increases, revealing that fixed learning methods do not scale across heterogeneous environments. Environment-adaptive selection of learning methods substantially improves performance but exhibits diminishing returns as the method space expands. These results highlight both the necessity and the current limitations of agent learning for scalable cross-environment generalization, and position AutoEnv and AutoEnv-36 as a testbed for studying cross-environment agent learning. The code is avaiable at https://github.com/FoundationAgents/AutoEnv.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2511.19304v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiayi Zhang, Yiran Peng, Fanqi Kong, Cheng Yang, Yifan Wu, Zhaoyang Yu, Jinyu Xiang, Jianhao Ruan, Jinlin Wang, Maojia Song, HongZhang Liu, Xiangru Tang, Bang Liu, Chenglin Wu, Yuyu Luo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stabilizing Reinforcement Learning with LLMs: Formulation and Practices</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.01374</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.01374v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: This paper proposes a novel formulation for reinforcement learning (RL) with large language models, explaining why and under what conditions the true sequence-level reward can be optimized via a surrogate token-level objective in policy gradient methods such as REINFORCE. Specifically, through a first-order approximation, we show that this surrogate becomes increasingly valid only when both the training-inference discrepancy and policy staleness are minimized. This insight provides a principled explanation for the crucial role of several widely adopted techniques in stabilizing RL training, including importance sampling correction, clipping, and particularly Routing Replay for Mixture-of-Experts (MoE) models. Through extensive experiments with a 30B MoE model totaling hundreds of thousands of GPU hours, we show that for on-policy training, the basic policy gradient algorithm with importance sampling correction achieves the highest training stability. When off-policy updates are introduced to accelerate convergence, combining clipping and Routing Replay becomes essential to mitigate the instability caused by policy staleness. Notably, once training is stabilized, prolonged optimization consistently yields comparable final performance regardless of cold-start initialization. We hope that the shared insights and the developed recipes for stable RL training will facilitate future research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.01374v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chujie Zheng, Kai Dang, Bowen Yu, Mingze Li, Huiqiang Jiang, Junrong Lin, Yuqiong Liu, Hao Lin, Chencan Wu, Feng Hu, An Yang, Jingren Zhou, Junyang Lin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ZIP-RC: Optimizing Test-Time Compute via Zero-Overhead Joint Reward-Cost Prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.01457</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.01457v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large language models excel at reasoning but lack key aspects of introspection, including anticipating their own success and the computation required to achieve it. Humans use real-time introspection to decide how much effort to invest, when to make multiple attempts, when to stop, and when to signal success or failure. Without this, LLMs struggle to make intelligent meta-cognition decisions. Test-time scaling methods like Best-of-N drive up cost and latency by using a fixed budget of samples regardless of the marginal benefit of each one at any point in generation, and the absence of confidence signals can mislead people, prevent appropriate escalation to better tools, and undermine trustworthiness. Learned verifiers or reward models can provide confidence estimates, but do not enable adaptive inference and add substantial cost by requiring extra models or forward passes. We present ZIP-RC, an adaptive inference method that equips models with zero-overhead inference-time predictions of reward and cost. At every token, ZIP-RC reuses reserved or unused logits in the same forward pass as next-token prediction to output a joint distribution over final reward and remaining length -- no extra models, architecture change, or inference overhead. This full joint distribution is used to compute a sampling utility which is the linear combination of the expected maximum reward, total compute, and latency of set of samples if generated to completion. During inference, we maximize this utility with meta-actions that determine which prefix of tokens to continue or initiate sampling from. On mixed-difficulty mathematical benchmarks, ZIP-RC improves accuracy by up to 12% over majority voting at equal or lower average cost, and traces smooth Pareto frontiers between quality, compute, and latency. By providing real-time reward-cost introspection, ZIP-RC enables adaptive, efficient reasoning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.01457v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rohin Manvi, Joey Hong, Tim Seyde, Maxime Labonne, Mathias Lechner, Sergey Levine</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
