<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL</link>
    <description>cs.CL updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 05:00:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Saturday</day>
      <day>Sunday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding and Enhancing Mamba-Transformer Hybrids for Memory Recall and Language Modeling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.26912</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.26912v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Hybrid models that combine state space models (SSMs) with attention mechanisms have shown strong performance by leveraging the efficiency of SSMs and the high recall ability of attention. However, the architectural design choices behind these hybrid models remain insufficiently understood. In this work, we analyze hybrid architectures through the lens of memory utilization and overall performance, and propose a complementary method to further enhance their effectiveness. We first examine the distinction between sequential and parallel integration of SSM and attention layers. Our analysis reveals several interesting findings, including that sequential hybrids perform better on shorter contexts, whereas parallel hybrids are more effective for longer contexts. We also introduce a data-centric approach of continually training on datasets augmented with paraphrases, which further enhances recall while preserving other capabilities. It generalizes well across different base models and outperforms architectural modifications aimed at enhancing recall. Our findings provide a deeper understanding of hybrid SSM-attention models and offer practical guidance for designing architectures tailored to various use cases. Our findings provide a deeper understanding of hybrid SSM-attention models and offer practical guidance for designing architectures tailored to various use cases.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.26912v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hyunji Lee, Wenhao Yu, Hongming Zhang, Kaixin Ma, Jiyeon Kim, Dong Yu, Minjoon Seo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frame Semantic Patterns for Identifying Underreporting of Notifiable Events in Healthcare: The Case of Gender-Based Violence</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.26969</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.26969v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We introduce a methodology for the identification of notifiable events in the domain of healthcare. The methodology harnesses semantic frames to define fine-grained patterns and search them in unstructured data, namely, open-text fields in e-medical records. We apply the methodology to the problem of underreporting of gender-based violence (GBV) in e-medical records produced during patients' visits to primary care units. A total of eight patterns are defined and searched on a corpus of 21 million sentences in Brazilian Portuguese extracted from e-SUS APS. The results are manually evaluated by linguists and the precision of each pattern measured. Our findings reveal that the methodology effectively identifies reports of violence with a precision of 0.726, confirming its robustness. Designed as a transparent, efficient, low-carbon, and language-agnostic pipeline, the approach can be easily adapted to other health surveillance contexts, contributing to the broader, ethical, and explainable use of NLP in public health systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.26969v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>L\'ivia Dutra, Arthur Lorenzi, La\'is Berno, Franciany Campos, Karoline Biscardi, Kenneth Brown, Marcelo Viridiano, Frederico Belcavello, Ely Matos, Ol\'ivia Guaranha, Erik Santos, Sofia Reinach, Tiago Timponi Torrent</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overview of the MEDIQA-OE 2025 Shared Task on Medical Order Extraction from Doctor-Patient Consultations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.26974</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.26974v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Clinical documentation increasingly uses automatic speech recognition and summarization, yet converting conversations into actionable medical orders for Electronic Health Records remains unexplored. A solution to this problem can significantly reduce the documentation burden of clinicians and directly impact downstream patient care. We introduce the MEDIQA-OE 2025 shared task, the first challenge on extracting medical orders from doctor-patient conversations. Six teams participated in the shared task and experimented with a broad range of approaches, and both closed- and open-weight large language models (LLMs). In this paper, we describe the MEDIQA-OE task, dataset, final leaderboard ranking, and participants' solutions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.26974v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jean-Philippe Corbeil, Asma Ben Abacha, Jerome Tremblay, Phillip Swazinna, Akila Jeeson Daniel, Miguel Del-Agua, Francois Beaulieu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semantically-Aware LLM Agent to Enhance Privacy in Conversational AI Services</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27016</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27016v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: With the increasing use of conversational AI systems, there is growing concern over privacy leaks, especially when users share sensitive personal data in interactions with Large Language Models (LLMs). Conversations shared with these models may contain Personally Identifiable Information (PII), which, if exposed, could lead to security breaches or identity theft. To address this challenge, we present the Local Optimizations for Pseudonymization with Semantic Integrity Directed Entity Detection (LOPSIDED) framework, a semantically-aware privacy agent designed to safeguard sensitive PII data when using remote LLMs. Unlike prior work that often degrade response quality, our approach dynamically replaces sensitive PII entities in user prompts with semantically consistent pseudonyms, preserving the contextual integrity of conversations. Once the model generates its response, the pseudonyms are automatically depseudonymized, ensuring the user receives an accurate, privacy-preserving output. We evaluate our approach using real-world conversations sourced from ShareGPT, which we further augment and annotate to assess whether named entities are contextually relevant to the model's response. Our results show that LOPSIDED reduces semantic utility errors by a factor of 5 compared to baseline techniques, all while enhancing privacy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27016v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jayden Serenari, Stephen Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kad: A Framework for Proxy-based Test-time Alignment with Knapsack Approximation Deferral</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27017</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27017v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Several previous works concluded that the largest part of generation capabilities of large language models (LLM) are learned (early) during pre-training. However, LLMs still require further alignment to adhere to downstream task requirements and stylistic preferences, among other desired properties. As LLMs continue to scale in terms of size, the computational cost of alignment procedures increase prohibitively. In this work, we propose a novel approach to circumvent these costs via proxy-based test-time alignment, i.e. using guidance from a small aligned model. Our approach can be described as token-specific cascading method, where the token-specific deferral rule is reduced to 0-1 knapsack problem. In this setting, we derive primal and dual approximations of the optimal deferral decision. We experimentally show the benefits of our method both in task performance and speculative decoding speed.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27017v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ayoub Hammal, Pierre Zweigenbaum, Caio Corro</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elastic Architecture Search for Efficient Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27037</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27037v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: As large pre-trained language models become increasingly critical to natural language understanding (NLU) tasks, their substantial computational and memory requirements have raised significant economic and environmental concerns. Addressing these challenges, this paper introduces the Elastic Language Model (ELM), a novel neural architecture search (NAS) method optimized for compact language models. ELM extends existing NAS approaches by introducing a flexible search space with efficient transformer blocks and dynamic modules for dimension and head number adjustment. These innovations enhance the efficiency and flexibility of the search process, which facilitates more thorough and effective exploration of model architectures. We also introduce novel knowledge distillation losses that preserve the unique characteristics of each block, in order to improve the discrimination between architectural choices during the search process. Experiments on masked language modeling and causal language modeling tasks demonstrate that models discovered by ELM significantly outperform existing methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27037v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.NE</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1109/ICME59968.2025.11210235</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Shang Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dataset Creation and Baseline Models for Sexism Detection in Hausa</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27038</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27038v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Sexism reinforces gender inequality and social exclusion by perpetuating stereotypes, bias, and discriminatory norms. Noting how online platforms enable various forms of sexism to thrive, there is a growing need for effective sexism detection and mitigation strategies. While computational approaches to sexism detection are widespread in high-resource languages, progress remains limited in low-resource languages where limited linguistic resources and cultural differences affect how sexism is expressed and perceived. This study introduces the first Hausa sexism detection dataset, developed through community engagement, qualitative coding, and data augmentation. For cultural nuances and linguistic representation, we conducted a two-stage user study (n=66) involving native speakers to explore how sexism is defined and articulated in everyday discourse. We further experiment with both traditional machine learning classifiers and pre-trained multilingual language models and evaluating the effectiveness few-shot learning in detecting sexism in Hausa. Our findings highlight challenges in capturing cultural nuance, particularly with clarification-seeking and idiomatic expressions, and reveal a tendency for many false positives in such cases.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27038v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fatima Adam Muhammad, Shamsuddeen Muhammad Hassan, Isa Inuwa-Dutse</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative Intertextuality from the Digital Humanities Perspective: A Survey</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27045</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27045v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The connection between texts is referred to as intertextuality in literary theory, which served as an important theoretical basis in many digital humanities studies. Over the past decade, advancements in natural language processing have ushered intertextuality studies into the quantitative age. Large-scale intertextuality research based on cutting-edge methods has continuously emerged. This paper provides a roadmap for quantitative intertextuality studies, summarizing their data, methods, and applications. Drawing on data from multiple languages and topics, this survey reviews methods from statistics to deep learning. It also summarizes their applications in humanities and social sciences research and the associated platform tools. Driven by advances in computer technology, more precise, diverse, and large-scale intertext studies can be anticipated. Intertextuality holds promise for broader application in interdisciplinary research bridging AI and the humanities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27045v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Siyu Duan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recursive numeral systems are highly regular and easy to process</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27049</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27049v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Previous work has argued that recursive numeral systems optimise the trade-off between lexicon size and average morphosyntatic complexity (Deni\'c and Szymanik, 2024). However, showing that only natural-language-like systems optimise this tradeoff has proven elusive, and the existing solution has relied on ad-hoc constraints to rule out unnatural systems (Yang and Regier, 2025). Here, we argue that this issue arises because the proposed trade-off has neglected regularity, a crucial aspect of complexity central to human grammars in general. Drawing on the Minimum Description Length (MDL) approach, we propose that recursive numeral systems are better viewed as efficient with regard to their regularity and processing complexity. We show that our MDL-based measures of regularity and processing complexity better capture the key differences between attested, natural systems and unattested but possible ones, including "optimal" recursive numeral systems from previous work, and that the ad-hoc constraints from previous literature naturally follow from regularity. Our approach highlights the need to incorporate regularity across sets of forms in studies that attempt to measure and explain optimality in language.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27049v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.FL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ponrawee Prasertsom, Andrea Silvi, Jennifer Culbertson, Moa Johansson, Devdatt Dubhashi, Kenny Smith</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VISTA Score: Verification In Sequential Turn-based Assessment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27052</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27052v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Hallucination--defined here as generating statements unsupported or contradicted by available evidence or conversational context--remains a major obstacle to deploying conversational AI systems in settings that demand factual reliability. Existing metrics either evaluate isolated responses or treat unverifiable content as errors, limiting their use for multi-turn dialogue. We introduce VISTA (Verification In Sequential Turn-based Assessment), a framework for evaluating conversational factuality through claim-level verification and sequential consistency tracking. VISTA decomposes each assistant turn into atomic factual claims, verifies them against trusted sources and dialogue history, and categorizes unverifiable statements (subjective, contradicted, lacking evidence, or abstaining). Across eight large language models and four dialogue factuality benchmarks (AIS, BEGIN, FAITHDIAL, and FADE), VISTA substantially improves hallucination detection over FACTSCORE and LLM-as-Judge baselines. Human evaluation confirms that VISTA's decomposition improves annotator agreement and reveals inconsistencies in existing benchmarks. By modeling factuality as a dynamic property of conversation, VISTA offers a more transparent, human-aligned measure of truthfulness in dialogue systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27052v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ashley Lewis, Andrew Perrault, Eric Fosler-Lussier, Michael White</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM-Centric RAG with Multi-Granular Indexing and Confidence Constraints</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27054</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27054v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper addresses the issues of insufficient coverage, unstable results, and limited reliability in retrieval-augmented generation under complex knowledge environments, and proposes a confidence control method that integrates multi-granularity memory indexing with uncertainty estimation. The method builds a hierarchical memory structure that divides knowledge representations into different levels of granularity, enabling dynamic indexing and retrieval from local details to global context, and thus establishing closer semantic connections between retrieval and generation. On this basis, an uncertainty estimation mechanism is introduced to explicitly constrain and filter low-confidence paths during the generation process, allowing the model to maintain information coverage while effectively suppressing noise and false content. The overall optimization objective consists of generation loss, entropy constraints, and variance regularization, forming a unified confidence control framework. In the experiments, comprehensive sensitivity tests and comparative analyses were designed, covering hyperparameters, environmental conditions, and data structures, to verify the stability and robustness of the proposed method across different scenarios. The results show that the method achieves superior performance over existing models in QA accuracy, retrieval recall, ranking quality, and factual consistency, demonstrating the effectiveness of combining multi-granularity indexing with confidence control. This study not only provides a new technical pathway for retrieval-augmented generation but also offers practical evidence for improving the reliability and controllability of large models in complex contexts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27054v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaofan Guo, Yaxuan Luan, Yue Kang, Xiangchen Song, Jinxu Guo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Detecting Data Contamination in LLMs via In-Context Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27055</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27055v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present Contamination Detection via Context (CoDeC), a practical and accurate method to detect and quantify training data contamination in large language models. CoDeC distinguishes between data memorized during training and data outside the training distribution by measuring how in-context learning affects model performance. We find that in-context examples typically boost confidence for unseen datasets but may reduce it when the dataset was part of training, due to disrupted memorization patterns. Experiments show that CoDeC produces interpretable contamination scores that clearly separate seen and unseen datasets, and reveals strong evidence of memorization in open-weight models with undisclosed training corpora. The method is simple, automated, and both model- and dataset-agnostic, making it easy to integrate with benchmark evaluations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27055v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Micha{\l} Zawalski, Meriem Boubdir, Klaudia Ba{\l}azy, Besmira Nushi, Pablo Ribalta</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contrastive Knowledge Transfer and Robust Optimization for Secure Alignment of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27077</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27077v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper addresses the limitations of large-scale language models in safety alignment and robustness by proposing a fine-tuning method that combines contrastive distillation with noise-robust training. The method freezes the backbone model and transfers the knowledge boundaries of the teacher model to the student model through distillation, thereby improving semantic consistency and alignment accuracy. At the same time, noise perturbations and robust optimization constraints are introduced during training to ensure that the model maintains stable predictive outputs under noisy and uncertain inputs. The overall framework consists of distillation loss, robustness loss, and a regularization term, forming a unified optimization objective that balances alignment ability with resistance to interference. To systematically validate its effectiveness, the study designs experiments from multiple perspectives, including distillation weight sensitivity, stability analysis under computation budgets and mixed-precision environments, and the impact of data noise and distribution shifts on model performance. Results show that the method significantly outperforms existing baselines in knowledge transfer, robustness, and overall safety, achieving the best performance across several key metrics. This work not only enriches the theoretical system of parameter-efficient fine-tuning but also provides a new solution for building safer and more trustworthy alignment mechanisms.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27077v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiasen Zheng, Huajun Zhang, Xu Yan, Ran Hao, Chong Peng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characterizing Selective Refusal Bias in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27087</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27087v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Safety guardrails in large language models(LLMs) are developed to prevent malicious users from generating toxic content at a large scale. However, these measures can inadvertently introduce or reflect new biases, as LLMs may refuse to generate harmful content targeting some demographic groups and not others. We explore this selective refusal bias in LLM guardrails through the lens of refusal rates of targeted individual and intersectional demographic groups, types of LLM responses, and length of generated refusals. Our results show evidence of selective refusal bias across gender, sexual orientation, nationality, and religion attributes. This leads us to investigate additional safety implications via an indirect attack, where we target previously refused groups. Our findings emphasize the need for more equitable and robust performance in safety guardrails across demographic groups.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27087v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Adel Khorramrouz, Sharon Levy</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rating Roulette: Self-Inconsistency in LLM-As-A-Judge Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27106</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27106v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: As Natural Language Generation (NLG) continues to be widely adopted, properly assessing it has become quite difficult. Lately, using large language models (LLMs) for evaluating these generations has gained traction, as they tend to align more closely with human preferences than conventional n-gram or embedding-based metrics. In our experiments, we show that LLM judges have low intra-rater reliability in their assigned scores across different runs. This variance makes their ratings inconsistent, almost arbitrary in the worst case, making it difficult to measure how good their judgments actually are. We quantify this inconsistency across different NLG tasks and benchmarks and see if judicious use of LLM judges can still be useful following proper guidelines.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27106v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rajarshi Haldar, Julia Hockenmaier</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Probability Distributions Computed by Hard-Attention Transformers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27118</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27118v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Most expressivity results for transformers treat them as language recognizers (which accept or reject strings), and not as they are used in practice, as language models (which generate strings autoregressively and probabilistically). Here, we characterize the probability distributions that transformer language models can express. We show that making transformer language recognizers autoregressive can sometimes increase their expressivity, and that making them probabilistic can break equivalences that hold in the non-probabilistic case. Our overall contribution is to tease apart what functions transformers are capable of expressing, in their most common use-case as language models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27118v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Andy Yang, Anej Svete, Jiaoda Li, Anthony Widjaja Lin, Jonathan Rawski, Ryan Cotterell, David Chiang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simple Additions, Substantial Gains: Expanding Scripts, Languages, and Lineage Coverage in URIEL+</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27183</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27183v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The URIEL+ linguistic knowledge base supports multilingual research by encoding languages through geographic, genetic, and typological vectors. However, data sparsity remains prevalent, in the form of missing feature types, incomplete language entries, and limited genealogical coverage. This limits the usefulness of URIEL+ in cross-lingual transfer, particularly for supporting low-resource languages. To address this sparsity, this paper extends URIEL+ with three contributions: introducing script vectors to represent writing system properties for 7,488 languages, integrating Glottolog to add 18,710 additional languages, and expanding lineage imputation for 26,449 languages by propagating typological and script features across genealogies. These additions reduce feature sparsity by 14% for script vectors, increase language coverage by up to 19,015 languages (1,007%), and improve imputation quality metrics by up to 33%. Our benchmark on cross-lingual transfer tasks (oriented around low-resource languages) shows occasionally divergent performance compared to URIEL+, with performance gains up to 6% in certain setups. Our advances make URIEL+ more complete and inclusive for multilingual research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27183v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mason Shipton, York Hay Ng, Aditya Khan, Phuong Hanh Hoang, Xiang Lu, A. Seza Do\u{g}ru\"oz, En-Shiun Annie Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MemeArena: Automating Context-Aware Unbiased Evaluation of Harmfulness Understanding for Multimodal Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27196</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27196v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The proliferation of memes on social media necessitates the capabilities of multimodal Large Language Models (mLLMs) to effectively understand multimodal harmfulness. Existing evaluation approaches predominantly focus on mLLMs' detection accuracy for binary classification tasks, which often fail to reflect the in-depth interpretive nuance of harmfulness across diverse contexts. In this paper, we propose MemeArena, an agent-based arena-style evaluation framework that provides a context-aware and unbiased assessment for mLLMs' understanding of multimodal harmfulness. Specifically, MemeArena simulates diverse interpretive contexts to formulate evaluation tasks that elicit perspective-specific analyses from mLLMs. By integrating varied viewpoints and reaching consensus among evaluators, it enables fair and unbiased comparisons of mLLMs' abilities to interpret multimodal harmfulness. Extensive experiments demonstrate that our framework effectively reduces the evaluation biases of judge agents, with judgment results closely aligning with human preferences, offering valuable insights into reliable and comprehensive mLLM evaluations in multimodal harmfulness understanding. Our code and data are publicly available at https://github.com/Lbotirx/MemeArena.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27196v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zixin Chen, Hongzhan Lin, Kaixin Li, Ziyang Luo, Yayue Deng, Jing Ma</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identifying the Periodicity of Information in Natural Language</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27241</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27241v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent theoretical advancement of information density in natural language has brought the following question on desk: To what degree does natural language exhibit periodicity pattern in its encoded information? We address this question by introducing a new method called AutoPeriod of Surprisal (APS). APS adopts a canonical periodicity detection algorithm and is able to identify any significant periods that exist in the surprisal sequence of a single document. By applying the algorithm to a set of corpora, we have obtained the following interesting results: Firstly, a considerable proportion of human language demonstrates a strong pattern of periodicity in information; Secondly, new periods that are outside the distributions of typical structural units in text (e.g., sentence boundaries, elementary discourse units, etc.) are found and further confirmed via harmonic regression modeling. We conclude that the periodicity of information in language is a joint outcome from both structured factors and other driving factors that take effect at longer distances. The advantages of our periodicity detection method and its potentials in LLM-generation detection are further discussed.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27241v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yulin Ou, Yu Wang, Yang Xu, Hendrik Buschmeier</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond a Million Tokens: Benchmarking and Enhancing Long-Term Memory in LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27246</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27246v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Evaluating the abilities of large language models (LLMs) for tasks that require long-term memory and thus long-context reasoning, for example in conversational settings, is hampered by the existing benchmarks, which often lack narrative coherence, cover narrow domains, and only test simple recall-oriented tasks. This paper introduces a comprehensive solution to these challenges. First, we present a novel framework for automatically generating long (up to 10M tokens), coherent, and topically diverse conversations, accompanied by probing questions targeting a wide range of memory abilities. From this, we construct BEAM, a new benchmark comprising 100 conversations and 2,000 validated questions. Second, to enhance model performance, we propose LIGHT-a framework inspired by human cognition that equips LLMs with three complementary memory systems: a long-term episodic memory, a short-term working memory, and a scratchpad for accumulating salient facts. Our experiments on BEAM reveal that even LLMs with 1M token context windows (with and without retrieval-augmentation) struggle as dialogues lengthen. In contrast, LIGHT consistently improves performance across various models, achieving an average improvement of 3.5%-12.69% over the strongest baselines, depending on the backbone LLM. An ablation study further confirms the contribution of each memory component.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27246v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mohammad Tavakoli, Alireza Salemi, Carrie Ye, Mohamed Abdalla, Hamed Zamani, J Ross Mitchell</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Languages are Modalities: Cross-Lingual Alignment via Encoder Injection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27254</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27254v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Instruction-tuned Large Language Models (LLMs) underperform on low resource, non-Latin scripts due to tokenizer fragmentation and weak cross-lingual coupling. We present LLINK (Latent Language Injection for Non-English Knowledge), a compute efficient language-as-modality method that conditions an instruction-tuned decoder without changing the tokenizer or retraining the decoder. First, we align sentence embeddings from a frozen multilingual encoder to the decoder's latent embedding space at a reserved position via a lightweight contrastive projector. Second, the vector is expanded into K soft slots and trained with minimal adapters so the frozen decoder consumes the signal. LLINK substantially improves bilingual retrieval and achieves 81.3% preference over the base model and 63.6% over direct fine-tuning in LLM-judged Q&amp;A evaluations. We further find that improvements can be attributed to reduced tokenization inflation and a stronger cross lingual alignment, despite the model having residual weaknesses in numeric fidelity. Treating low resource languages as a modality offers a practical path to stronger cross-lingual alignment in lightweight LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27254v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rajan Agarwal, Aarush Gupta</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MedCalc-Eval and MedCalc-Env: Advancing Medical Calculation Capabilities of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27267</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27267v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: As large language models (LLMs) enter the medical domain, most benchmarks evaluate them on question answering or descriptive reasoning, overlooking quantitative reasoning critical to clinical decision-making. Existing datasets like MedCalc-Bench cover few calculation tasks and fail to reflect real-world computational scenarios.
  We introduce MedCalc-Eval, the largest benchmark for assessing LLMs' medical calculation abilities, comprising 700+ tasks across two types: equation-based (e.g., Cockcroft-Gault, BMI, BSA) and rule-based scoring systems (e.g., Apgar, Glasgow Coma Scale). These tasks span diverse specialties including internal medicine, surgery, pediatrics, and cardiology, offering a broader and more challenging evaluation setting.
  To improve performance, we further develop MedCalc-Env, a reinforcement learning environment built on the InternBootcamp framework, enabling multi-step clinical reasoning and planning. Fine-tuning a Qwen2.5-32B model within this environment achieves state-of-the-art results on MedCalc-Eval, with notable gains in numerical sensitivity, formula selection, and reasoning robustness. Remaining challenges include unit conversion, multi-condition logic, and contextual understanding.
  Code and datasets are available at https://github.com/maokangkun/MedCalc-Eval.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27267v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kangkun Mao, Jinru Ding, Jiayuan Chen, Mouxiao Bian, Ruiyao Chen, Xinwei Peng, Sijie Ren, Linyang Li, Jie Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Do Multilingual Reasoning Gaps Emerge in Reasoning Language Models?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27269</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27269v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Reasoning language models (RLMs) achieve strong performance on complex reasoning tasks, yet they still suffer from a multilingual reasoning gap, performing better in high-resource languages than in low-resource ones. While recent efforts have reduced this gap, its underlying causes remain largely unexplored. In this paper, we address this by showing that the multilingual reasoning gap largely stems from failures in language understanding-the model's inability to represent the multilingual input meaning into the dominant language (i.e., English) within its reasoning trace. This motivates us to examine whether understanding failures can be detected, as this ability could help mitigate the multilingual reasoning gap. To this end, we evaluate a range of detection methods and find that understanding failures can indeed be identified, with supervised approaches performing best. Building on this, we propose Selective Translation, a simple yet effective strategy that translates the multilingual input into English only when an understanding failure is detected. Experimental results show that Selective Translation bridges the multilingual reasoning gap, achieving near full-translation performance while using translation for only about 20% of inputs. Together, our work demonstrates that understanding failures are the primary cause of the multilingual reasoning gap and can be detected and selectively mitigated, providing key insight into its origin and a promising path toward more equitable multilingual reasoning. Our code and data are publicly available at https://github.com/deokhk/RLM_analysis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27269v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Deokhyung Kang, Seonjeong Hwang, Daehui Kim, Hyounghun Kim, Gary Geunbae Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Unified Representation Underlying the Judgment of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27328</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27328v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: A central architectural question for both biological and artificial intelligence is whether judgment relies on specialized modules or a unified, domain-general resource. While the discovery of decodable neural representations for distinct concepts in Large Language Models (LLMs) has suggested a modular architecture, whether these representations are truly independent systems remains an open question. Here we provide evidence for a convergent architecture. Across a range of LLMs, we find that diverse evaluative judgments are computed along a dominant dimension, which we term the Valence-Assent Axis (VAA). This axis jointly encodes subjective valence ("what is good") and the model's assent to factual claims ("what is true"). Through direct interventions, we show this unified representation creates a critical dependency: the VAA functions as a control signal that steers the generative process to construct a rationale consistent with its evaluative state, even at the cost of factual accuracy. This mechanism, which we term the subordination of reasoning, shifts the process of reasoning from impartial inference toward goal-directed justification. Our discovery offers a mechanistic account for systemic bias and hallucination, revealing how an architecture that promotes coherent judgment can systematically undermine faithful reasoning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27328v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yi-Long Lu, Jiajun Song, Wei Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TransAlign: Machine Translation Encoders are Strong Word Aligners, Too</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27337</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27337v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In the absence of sizable training data for most world languages and NLP tasks, translation-based strategies such as translate-test -- evaluating on noisy source language data translated from the target language -- and translate-train -- training on noisy target language data translated from the source language -- have been established as competitive approaches for cross-lingual transfer (XLT). For token classification tasks, these strategies require label projection: mapping the labels from each token in the original sentence to its counterpart(s) in the translation. To this end, it is common to leverage multilingual word aligners (WAs) derived from encoder language models such as mBERT or LaBSE. Despite obvious associations between machine translation (MT) and WA, research on extracting alignments with MT models is largely limited to exploiting cross-attention in encoder-decoder architectures, yielding poor WA results. In this work, in contrast, we propose TransAlign, a novel word aligner that utilizes the encoder of a massively multilingual MT model. We show that TransAlign not only achieves strong WA performance but substantially outperforms popular WA and state-of-the-art non-WA-based label projection methods in MT-based XLT for token classification.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27337v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Benedikt Ebing, Christian Goldschmied, Goran Glava\v{s}</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ThoughtProbe: Classifier-Guided LLM Thought Space Exploration via Probing Representations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27355</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27355v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper introduces ThoughtProbe, a novel inference time framework that leverages the hidden reasoning features of Large Language Models (LLMs) to improve their reasoning performance. Unlike previous works that manipulate the hidden representations to steer LLM generation, we harness them as discriminative signals to guide the tree structured response space exploration. In each node expansion, a classifier serves as a scoring and ranking mechanism that efficiently allocates computational resources by prioritizing higher score candidates for continuation. After completing the tree expansion, we collect answers from all branches to form a candidate answer pool. We then propose a branch aggregation method that marginalizes over all supporting branches by aggregating their CoT scores, thereby identifying the optimal answer from the pool. Experimental results show that our framework's comprehensive exploration not only covers valid reasoning chains but also effectively identifies them, achieving significant improvements across multiple arithmetic reasoning benchmarks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27355v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zijian Wang, Chang Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From the Rock Floor to the Cloud: A Systematic Survey of State-of-the-Art NLP in Battery Life Cycle</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27369</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27369v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present a comprehensive systematic survey of the application of natural language processing (NLP) along the entire battery life cycle, instead of one stage or method, and introduce a novel technical language processing (TLP) framework for the EU's proposed digital battery passport (DBP) and other general battery predictions. We follow the Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses (PRISMA) method and employ three reputable databases or search engines, including Google Scholar, Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Xplore (IEEE Xplore), and Scopus. Consequently, we assessed 274 scientific papers before the critical review of the final 66 relevant papers. We publicly provide artifacts of the review for validation and reproducibility. The findings show that new NLP tasks are emerging in the battery domain, which facilitate materials discovery and other stages of the life cycle. Notwithstanding, challenges remain, such as the lack of standard benchmarks. Our proposed TLP framework, which incorporates agentic AI and optimized prompts, will be apt for tackling some of the challenges.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27369v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tosin Adewumi, Martin Karlsson, Marcus Liwicki, Mikael Sj\"odahl, Lama Alkhaled, Rihab Gargouri, Nudrat Habib, Franz Hennie</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Balancing Knowledge Updates: Toward Unified Modular Editing in LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27400</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27400v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Knowledge editing has emerged as an efficient approach for updating factual knowledge in large language models (LLMs). It typically locates knowledge storage modules and then modifies their parameters. However, most existing methods focus on the weights of multilayer perceptron (MLP) modules, which are often identified as the main repositories of factual information. Other components, such as attention (Attn) modules, are often ignored during editing. This imbalance can leave residual outdated knowledge and limit editing effectiveness. We perform comprehensive knowledge localization experiments on advanced LLMs and find that Attn modules play a substantial role in factual knowledge storage and retrieval, especially in earlier layers. Based on these insights, we propose IntAttn-Edit, a method that extends the associative memory paradigm to jointly update both MLP and Attn modules. Our approach uses a knowledge balancing strategy that allocates update magnitudes in proportion to each module's measured contribution to knowledge storage. Experiments on standard benchmarks show that IntAttn-Edit achieves higher edit success, better generalization, and stronger knowledge preservation than prior methods. Further analysis shows that the balancing strategy keeps editing performance within an optimal range across diverse settings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27400v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiahao Liu, Zijian Wang, Kuo Zhao, Dong Hu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Awal -- Community-Powered Language Technology for Tamazight</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27407</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27407v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper presents Awal, a community-powered initiative for developing language technology resources for Tamazight. We provide a comprehensive review of the NLP landscape for Tamazight, examining recent progress in computational resources, and the emergence of community-driven approaches to address persistent data scarcity. Launched in 2024, awaldigital.org platform addresses the underrepresentation of Tamazight in digital spaces through a collaborative platform enabling speakers to contribute translation and voice data. We analyze 18 months of community engagement, revealing significant barriers to participation including limited confidence in written Tamazight and ongoing standardization challenges. Despite widespread positive reception, actual data contribution remained concentrated among linguists and activists. The modest scale of community contributions -- 6,421 translation pairs and 3 hours of speech data -- highlights the limitations of applying standard crowdsourcing approaches to languages with complex sociolinguistic contexts. We are working on improved open-source MT models using the collected data.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27407v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alp \"Oktem, Farida Boudichat</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Affective Memory Management for Personalized LLM Agents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27418</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27418v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Advances in large language models are making personalized AI agents a new research focus. While current agent systems primarily rely on personalized external memory databases to deliver customized experiences, they face challenges such as memory redundancy, memory staleness, and poor memory-context integration, largely due to the lack of effective memory updates during interaction. To tackle these issues, we propose a new memory management system designed for affective scenarios. Our approach employs a Bayesian-inspired memory update algorithm with the concept of memory entropy, enabling the agent to autonomously maintain a dynamically updated memory vector database by minimizing global entropy to provide more personalized services. To better evaluate the system's effectiveness in this context, we propose DABench, a benchmark focusing on emotional expression and emotional change toward objects. Experimental results demonstrate that, our system achieves superior performance in personalization, logical coherence, and accuracy. Ablation studies further validate the effectiveness of the Bayesian-inspired update mechanism in alleviating memory bloat. Our work offers new insights into the design of long-term memory systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27418v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junfeng Lu, Yueyan Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VCORE: Variance-Controlled Optimization-based Reweighting for Chain-of-Thought Supervision</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27462</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27462v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Supervised fine-tuning (SFT) on long chain-of-thought (CoT) trajectories has emerged as a crucial technique for enhancing the reasoning abilities of large language models (LLMs). However, the standard cross-entropy loss treats all tokens equally, ignoring their heterogeneous contributions across a reasoning trajectory. This uniform treatment leads to misallocated supervision and weak generalization, especially in complex, long-form reasoning tasks. To address this, we introduce \textbf{V}ariance-\textbf{C}ontrolled \textbf{O}ptimization-based \textbf{RE}weighting (VCORE), a principled framework that reformulates CoT supervision as a constrained optimization problem. By adopting an optimization-theoretic perspective, VCORE enables a principled and adaptive allocation of supervision across tokens, thereby aligning the training objective more closely with the goal of robust reasoning generalization. Empirical evaluations demonstrate that VCORE consistently outperforms existing token reweighting methods. Across both in-domain and out-of-domain settings, VCORE achieves substantial performance gains on mathematical and coding benchmarks, using models from the Qwen3 series (4B, 8B, 32B) and LLaMA-3.1-8B-Instruct. Moreover, we show that VCORE serves as a more effective initialization for subsequent reinforcement learning, establishing a stronger foundation for advancing the reasoning capabilities of LLMs. The Code will be released at https://github.com/coder-gx/VCORE.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27462v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xuan Gong, Senmiao Wang, Hanbo Huang, Ruoyu Sun, Shiyu Liang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diffuse Thinking: Exploring Diffusion Language Models as Efficient Thought Proposers for Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27469</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27469v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In recent years, large language models (LLMs) have witnessed remarkable advancements, with the test-time scaling law consistently enhancing the reasoning capabilities. Through systematic evaluation and exploration of a diverse spectrum of intermediate thoughts, LLMs demonstrate the potential to generate deliberate reasoning steps, thereby substantially enhancing reasoning accuracy. However, LLMs' autoregressive generation paradigm results in reasoning performance scaling sub-optimally with test-time computation, often requiring excessive computational overhead to propose thoughts while yielding only marginal performance gains. In contrast, diffusion language models (DLMs) can efficiently produce diverse samples through parallel denoising in a single forward pass, inspiring us to leverage them for proposing intermediate thoughts, thereby alleviating the computational burden associated with autoregressive generation while maintaining quality. In this work, we propose an efficient collaborative reasoning framework, leveraging DLMs to generate candidate thoughts and LLMs to evaluate their quality. Experiments across diverse benchmarks demonstrate that our framework achieves strong performance in complex reasoning tasks, offering a promising direction for future research. Our code is open-source at https://anonymous.4open.science/r/Diffuse-Thinking-EC60.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27469v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chenyang Shao, Sijian Ren, Fengli Xu, Yong Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The aftermath of compounds: Investigating Compounds and their Semantic Representations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27477</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27477v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This study investigates how well computational embeddings align with human semantic judgments in the processing of English compound words. We compare static word vectors (GloVe) and contextualized embeddings (BERT) against human ratings of lexeme meaning dominance (LMD) and semantic transparency (ST) drawn from a psycholinguistic dataset. Using measures of association strength (Edinburgh Associative Thesaurus), frequency (BNC), and predictability (LaDEC), we compute embedding-derived LMD and ST metrics and assess their relationships with human judgments via Spearmans correlation and regression analyses. Our results show that BERT embeddings better capture compositional semantics than GloVe, and that predictability ratings are strong predictors of semantic transparency in both human and model data. These findings advance computational psycholinguistics by clarifying the factors that drive compound word processing and offering insights into embedding-based semantic modeling.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27477v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Swarang Joshi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Domain Generalization Techniques in Low Resource Systems</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27512</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27512v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Machine learning models typically assume that training and test data follow the same distribution, an assumption that often fails in real-world scenarios due to distribution shifts. This issue is especially pronounced in low-resource settings, where data scarcity and limited domain diversity hinder robust generalization. Domain generalization (DG) approaches address this challenge by learning features that remain invariant across domains, often using causal mechanisms to improve model robustness. In this study, we examine two distinct causal DG techniques in low-resource natural language tasks. First, we investigate a causal data augmentation (CDA) approach that automatically generates counterfactual examples to improve robustness to spurious correlations. We apply this method to sentiment classification on the NaijaSenti Twitter corpus, expanding the training data with semantically equivalent paraphrases to simulate controlled distribution shifts. Second, we explore an invariant causal representation learning (ICRL) approach using the DINER framework, originally proposed for debiasing aspect-based sentiment analysis. We adapt DINER to a multilingual setting. Our findings demonstrate that both approaches enhance robustness to unseen domains: counterfactual data augmentation yields consistent cross-domain accuracy gains in sentiment classification, while causal representation learning with DINER improves out-of-distribution performance in multilingual sentiment analysis, albeit with varying gains across languages.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27512v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mahi Aminu, Chisom Chibuike, Fatimo Adebanjo, Omokolade Awosanya, Samuel Oyeneye</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BiSparse-AAS: Bilinear Sparse Attention and Adaptive Spans Framework for Scalable and Efficient Text Summarization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27516</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27516v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Transformer-based architectures have advanced text summarization, yet their quadratic complexity limits scalability on long documents. This paper introduces BiSparse-AAS (Bilinear Sparse Attention with Adaptive Spans), a novel framework that combines sparse attention, adaptive spans, and bilinear attention to address these limitations. Sparse attention reduces computational costs by focusing on the most relevant parts of the input, while adaptive spans dynamically adjust the attention ranges. Bilinear attention complements both by modeling complex token interactions within this refined context. BiSparse-AAS consistently outperforms state-of-the-art baselines in both extractive and abstractive summarization tasks, achieving average ROUGE improvements of about 68.1% on CNN/DailyMail and 52.6% on XSum, while maintaining strong performance on OpenWebText and Gigaword datasets. By addressing efficiency, scalability, and long-sequence modeling, BiSparse-AAS provides a unified, practical solution for real-world text summarization applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27516v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Desta Haileselassie Hagos, Legand L. Burge, Anietie Andy, Anis Yazidi, Vladimir Vlassov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQLSpace: A Representation Space for Text-to-SQL to Discover and Mitigate Robustness Gaps</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27532</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27532v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We introduce SQLSpace, a human-interpretable, generalizable, compact representation for text-to-SQL examples derived with minimal human intervention. We demonstrate the utility of these representations in evaluation with three use cases: (i) closely comparing and contrasting the composition of popular text-to-SQL benchmarks to identify unique dimensions of examples they evaluate, (ii) understanding model performance at a granular level beyond overall accuracy scores, and (iii) improving model performance through targeted query rewriting based on learned correctness estimation. We show that SQLSpace enables analysis that would be difficult with raw examples alone: it reveals compositional differences between benchmarks, exposes performance patterns obscured by accuracy alone, and supports modeling of query success.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27532v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Neha Srikanth, Victor Bursztyn, Puneet Mathur, Ani Nenkova</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patient-Centered Summarization Framework for AI Clinical Summarization: A Mixed-Methods Design</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27535</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27535v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) are increasingly demonstrating the potential to reach human-level performance in generating clinical summaries from patient-clinician conversations. However, these summaries often focus on patients' biology rather than their preferences, values, wishes, and concerns. To achieve patient-centered care, we propose a new standard for Artificial Intelligence (AI) clinical summarization tasks: Patient-Centered Summaries (PCS). Our objective was to develop a framework to generate PCS that capture patient values and ensure clinical utility and to assess whether current open-source LLMs can achieve human-level performance in this task. We used a mixed-methods process. Two Patient and Public Involvement groups (10 patients and 8 clinicians) in the United Kingdom participated in semi-structured interviews exploring what personal and contextual information should be included in clinical summaries and how it should be structured for clinical use. Findings informed annotation guidelines used by eight clinicians to create gold-standard PCS from 88 atrial fibrillation consultations. Sixteen consultations were used to refine a prompt aligned with the guidelines. Five open-source LLMs (Llama-3.2-3B, Llama-3.1-8B, Mistral-8B, Gemma-3-4B, and Qwen3-8B) generated summaries for 72 consultations using zero-shot and few-shot prompting, evaluated with ROUGE-L, BERTScore, and qualitative metrics. Patients emphasized lifestyle routines, social support, recent stressors, and care values. Clinicians sought concise functional, psychosocial, and emotional context. The best zero-shot performance was achieved by Mistral-8B (ROUGE-L 0.189) and Llama-3.1-8B (BERTScore 0.673); the best few-shot by Llama-3.1-8B (ROUGE-L 0.206, BERTScore 0.683). Completeness and fluency were similar between experts and models, while correctness and patient-centeredness favored human PCS.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27535v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Maria Lizarazo Jimenez, Ana Gabriela Claros, Kieran Green, David Toro-Tobon, Felipe Larios, Sheena Asthana, Camila Wenczenovicz, Kerly Guevara Maldonado, Luis Vilatuna-Andrango, Cristina Proano-Velez, Satya Sai Sri Bandi, Shubhangi Bagewadi, Megan E. Branda, Misk Al Zahidy, Saturnino Luz, Mirella Lapata, Juan P. Brito, Oscar J. Ponce-Ponte</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DialectalArabicMMLU: Benchmarking Dialectal Capabilities in Arabic and Multilingual Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27543</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27543v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present DialectalArabicMMLU, a new benchmark for evaluating the performance of large language models (LLMs) across Arabic dialects. While recently developed Arabic and multilingual benchmarks have advanced LLM evaluation for Modern Standard Arabic (MSA), dialectal varieties remain underrepresented despite their prevalence in everyday communication. DialectalArabicMMLU extends the MMLU-Redux framework through manual translation and adaptation of 3K multiple-choice question-answer pairs into five major dialects (Syrian, Egyptian, Emirati, Saudi, and Moroccan), yielding a total of 15K QA pairs across 32 academic and professional domains (22K QA pairs when also including English and MSA). The benchmark enables systematic assessment of LLM reasoning and comprehension beyond MSA, supporting both task-based and linguistic analysis. We evaluate 19 open-weight Arabic and multilingual LLMs (1B-13B parameters) and report substantial performance variation across dialects, revealing persistent gaps in dialectal generalization. DialectalArabicMMLU provides the first unified, human-curated resource for measuring dialectal understanding in Arabic, thus promoting more inclusive evaluation and future model development.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27543v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Malik H. Altakrori, Nizar Habash, Abdelhakim Freihat, Younes Samih, Kirill Chirkunov, Muhammed AbuOdeh, Radu Florian, Teresa Lynn, Preslav Nakov, Alham Fikri Aji</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multilingual BERT language model for medical tasks: Evaluation on domain-specific adaptation and cross-linguality</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27552</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27552v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In multilingual healthcare applications, the availability of domain-specific natural language processing(NLP) tools is limited, especially for low-resource languages. Although multilingual bidirectional encoder representations from transformers (BERT) offers a promising motivation to mitigate the language gap, the medical NLP tasks in low-resource languages are still underexplored. Therefore, this study investigates how further pre-training on domain-specific corpora affects model performance on medical tasks, focusing on three languages: Dutch, Romanian and Spanish. In terms of further pre-training, we conducted four experiments to create medical domain models. Then, these models were fine-tuned on three downstream tasks: Automated patient screening in Dutch clinical notes, named entity recognition in Romanian and Spanish clinical notes. Results show that domain adaptation significantly enhanced task performance. Furthermore, further differentiation of domains, e.g. clinical and general biomedical domains, resulted in diverse performances. The clinical domain-adapted model outperformed the more general biomedical domain-adapted model. Moreover, we observed evidence of cross-lingual transferability. Moreover, we also conducted further investigations to explore potential reasons contributing to these performance differences. These findings highlight the feasibility of domain adaptation and cross-lingual ability in medical NLP. Within the low-resource language settings, these findings can provide meaningful guidance for developing multilingual medical NLP systems to mitigate the lack of training data and thereby improve the model performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27552v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yinghao Luo (Department of Pathology &amp; Clinical Bioinformatics, Erasmus University Medical Center Rotterdam, Department of Computer Science, Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam), Lang Zhou (Department of Pathology &amp; Clinical Bioinformatics, Erasmus University Medical Center Rotterdam, Department of Computer Science, Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam), Amrish Jhingoer (Department of Pathology &amp; Clinical Bioinformatics, Erasmus University Medical Center Rotterdam, Department of Computer Science, Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam), Klaske Vliegenthart Jongbloed (Department of Internal Medicine, Erasmus University Medical Center Rotterdam, Department of Medical Microbiology and Infectious Diseases, Erasmus University Medical Center Rotterdam), Carlijn Jordans (Department of Medical Microbiology and Infectious Diseases, Erasmus University Medical Center Rotterdam), Ben Werkhoven (Department of Data and Analytics, Erasmus University Medical Center Rotterdam), Tom Seinen (Department of Medical Informatics, Erasmus University Medical Center Rotterdam), Erik van Mulligen (Department of Medical Informatics, Erasmus University Medical Center Rotterdam), Casper Rokx (Department of Internal Medicine, Erasmus University Medical Center Rotterdam, Department of Medical Microbiology and Infectious Diseases, Erasmus University Medical Center Rotterdam), Yunlei Li (Department of Pathology &amp; Clinical Bioinformatics, Erasmus University Medical Center Rotterdam)</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data-Efficient Domain Adaptation for LLM-based MT using Contrastive Preference Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27556</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27556v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: LLMs often require adaptation to domain-specific requirements, a process that can be expensive when relying solely on SFT. We present an empirical study on applying CPO to simulate a post-editing workflow for data-efficient domain adaptation. Our approach synthesizes preference pairs by treating the base model's own raw output as the 'rejected' translation and the human-approved TM entry as the 'chosen' one. This method provides direct feedback on the model's current knowledge, guiding it to align with domain-specific standards. Experiments in English-Brazilian Portuguese and English-Korean show that, by using just 14.7k preference pairs, the model achieves performance close to that of a model trained on 160k+ samples with SFT, demonstrating significant data efficiency. Although we showcase its effectiveness in MT, this application of CPO naturally generalizes to other generative tasks where a model's initial drafts can serve as a contrastive signal against a golden reference.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27556v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Inacio Vieira, Antonio Castaldo, James O'Doherty, Sheila Castilho</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MARAG-R1: Beyond Single Retriever via Reinforcement-Learned Multi-Tool Agentic Retrieval</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27569</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27569v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) excel at reasoning and generation but are inherently limited by static pretraining data, resulting in factual inaccuracies and weak adaptability to new information. Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) addresses this issue by grounding LLMs in external knowledge; However, the effectiveness of RAG critically depends on whether the model can adequately access relevant information. Existing RAG systems rely on a single retriever with fixed top-k selection, restricting access to a narrow and static subset of the corpus. As a result, this single-retriever paradigm has become the primary bottleneck for comprehensive external information acquisition, especially in tasks requiring corpus-level reasoning. To overcome this limitation, we propose MARAG-R1, a reinforcement-learned multi-tool RAG framework that enables LLMs to dynamically coordinate multiple retrieval mechanisms for broader and more precise information access. MARAG-R1 equips the model with four retrieval tools -- semantic search, keyword search, filtering, and aggregation -- and learns both how and when to use them through a two-stage training process: supervised fine-tuning followed by reinforcement learning. This design allows the model to interleave reasoning and retrieval, progressively gathering sufficient evidence for corpus-level synthesis. Experiments on GlobalQA, HotpotQA, and 2WikiMultiHopQA demonstrate that MARAG-R1 substantially outperforms strong baselines and achieves new state-of-the-art results in corpus-level reasoning tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27569v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qi Luo, Xiaonan Li, Yuxin Wang, Tingshuo Fan, Yuan Li, Xinchi Chen, Xipeng Qiu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SpecAttn: Speculating Sparse Attention</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27641</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27641v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) face significant computational bottlenecks during inference due to the quadratic complexity of self-attention mechanisms, particularly as context lengths increase. We introduce SpecAttn, a novel training-free approach that seamlessly integrates with existing speculative decoding techniques to enable efficient sparse attention in pre-trained transformers. Our key insight is to exploit the attention weights already computed by the draft model during speculative decoding to identify important tokens for the target model, eliminating redundant computation while maintaining output quality. SpecAttn employs three core techniques: KL divergence-based layer alignment between draft and target models, a GPU-optimized sorting-free algorithm for top-p token selection from draft attention patterns, and dynamic key-value cache pruning guided by these predictions. By leveraging the computational work already performed in standard speculative decoding pipelines, SpecAttn achieves over 75% reduction in key-value cache accesses with a mere 15.29% increase in perplexity on the PG-19 dataset, significantly outperforming existing sparse attention methods. Our approach demonstrates that speculative execution can be enhanced to provide approximate verification without significant performance degradation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27641v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.SY</category>
      <category>eess.SY</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Harsh Shah</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culture Cartography: Mapping the Landscape of Cultural Knowledge</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27672</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27672v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: To serve global users safely and productively, LLMs need culture-specific knowledge that might not be learned during pre-training. How do we find such knowledge that is (1) salient to in-group users, but (2) unknown to LLMs? The most common solutions are single-initiative: either researchers define challenging questions that users passively answer (traditional annotation), or users actively produce data that researchers structure as benchmarks (knowledge extraction). The process would benefit from mixed-initiative collaboration, where users guide the process to meaningfully reflect their cultures, and LLMs steer the process towards more challenging questions that meet the researcher's goals. We propose a mixed-initiative methodology called CultureCartography. Here, an LLM initializes annotation with questions for which it has low-confidence answers, making explicit both its prior knowledge and the gaps therein. This allows a human respondent to fill these gaps and steer the model towards salient topics through direct edits. We implement this methodology as a tool called CultureExplorer. Compared to a baseline where humans answer LLM-proposed questions, we find that CultureExplorer more effectively produces knowledge that leading models like DeepSeek R1 and GPT-4o are missing, even with web search. Fine-tuning on this data boosts the accuracy of Llama-3.1-8B by up to 19.2% on related culture benchmarks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27672v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Caleb Ziems, William Held, Jane Yu, Amir Goldberg, David Grusky, Diyi Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Autoregressive Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27688</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27688v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The efficiency of large language models (LLMs) is fundamentally limited by their sequential, token-by-token generation process. We argue that overcoming this bottleneck requires a new design axis for LLM scaling: increasing the semantic bandwidth of each generative step. To this end, we introduce Continuous Autoregressive Language Models (CALM), a paradigm shift from discrete next-token prediction to continuous next-vector prediction. CALM uses a high-fidelity autoencoder to compress a chunk of K tokens into a single continuous vector, from which the original tokens can be reconstructed with over 99.9\% accuracy. This allows us to model language as a sequence of continuous vectors instead of discrete tokens, which reduces the number of generative steps by a factor of K. The paradigm shift necessitates a new modeling toolkit; therefore, we develop a comprehensive likelihood-free framework that enables robust training, evaluation, and controllable sampling in the continuous domain. Experiments show that CALM significantly improves the performance-compute trade-off, achieving the performance of strong discrete baselines at a significantly lower computational cost. More importantly, these findings establish next-vector prediction as a powerful and scalable pathway towards ultra-efficient language models. Code: https://github.com/shaochenze/calm. Project: https://shaochenze.github.io/blog/2025/CALM.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27688v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chenze Shao, Darren Li, Fandong Meng, Jie Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Broken-Token: Filtering Obfuscated Prompts by Counting Characters-Per-Token</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.26847</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.26847v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) are susceptible to jailbreak attacks where malicious prompts are disguised using ciphers and character-level encodings to bypass safety guardrails. While these guardrails often fail to interpret the encoded content, the underlying models can still process the harmful instructions. We introduce CPT-Filtering, a novel, model-agnostic with negligible-costs and near-perfect accuracy guardrail technique that aims to mitigate these attacks by leveraging the intrinsic behavior of Byte-Pair Encoding (BPE) tokenizers. Our method is based on the principle that tokenizers, trained on natural language, represent out-of-distribution text, such as ciphers, using a significantly higher number of shorter tokens. Our technique uses a simple yet powerful artifact of using language models: the average number of Characters Per Token (CPT) in the text. This approach is motivated by the high compute cost of modern methods - relying on added modules such as dedicated LLMs or perplexity models. We validate our approach across a large dataset of over 100,000 prompts, testing numerous encoding schemes with several popular tokenizers. Our experiments demonstrate that a simple CPT threshold robustly identifies encoded text with high accuracy, even for very short inputs. CPT-Filtering provides a practical defense layer that can be immediately deployed for real-time text filtering and offline data curation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.26847v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IT</category>
      <category>math.IT</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shaked Zychlinski, Yuval Kainan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CATArena: Evaluation of LLM Agents through Iterative Tournament Competitions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.26852</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.26852v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large Language Model (LLM) agents have evolved from basic text generation to autonomously completing complex tasks through interaction with external tools. However, current benchmarks mainly assess end-to-end performance in fixed scenarios, restricting evaluation to specific skills and suffering from score saturation and growing dependence on expert annotation as agent capabilities improve. In this work, we emphasize the importance of learning ability, including both self-improvement and peer-learning, as a core driver for agent evolution toward human-level intelligence. We propose an iterative, competitive peer-learning framework, which allows agents to refine and optimize their strategies through repeated interactions and feedback, thereby systematically evaluating their learning capabilities. To address the score saturation issue in current benchmarks, we introduce CATArena, a tournament-style evaluation platform featuring four diverse board and card games with open-ended scoring. By providing tasks without explicit upper score limits, CATArena enables continuous and dynamic evaluation of rapidly advancing agent capabilities. Experimental results and analyses involving both minimal and commercial code agents demonstrate that CATArena provides reliable, stable, and scalable benchmarking for core agent abilities, particularly learning ability and strategy coding.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.26852v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lingyue Fu, Xin Ding, Yaoming Zhu, Shao Zhang, Lin Qiu, Weiwen Liu, Weinan Zhang, Xuezhi Cao, Xunliang Cai, Jiaxin Ding, Yong Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Perspectival Biases in Cross-Modal Retrieval</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.26861</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.26861v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Multimodal retrieval systems are expected to operate in a semantic space, agnostic to the language or cultural origin of the query. In practice, however, retrieval outcomes systematically reflect perspectival biases: deviations shaped by linguistic prevalence and cultural associations. We study two such biases. First, prevalence bias refers to the tendency to favor entries from prevalent languages over semantically faithful entries in image-to-text retrieval. Second, association bias refers to the tendency to favor images culturally associated with the query over semantically correct ones in text-to-image retrieval. Results show that explicit alignment is a more effective strategy for mitigating prevalence bias. However, association bias remains a distinct and more challenging problem. These findings suggest that achieving truly equitable multimodal systems requires targeted strategies beyond simple data scaling and that bias arising from cultural association may be treated as a more challenging problem than one arising from linguistic prevalence.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.26861v1</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Teerapol Saengsukhiran, Peerawat Chomphooyod, Narabodee Rodjananant, Chompakorn Chaksangchaichot, Patawee Prakrankamanant, Witthawin Sripheanpol, Pak Lovichit, SarChaksaana Nutanong, Ekapol Chuangsuwanich</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Denario project: Deep knowledge AI agents for scientific discovery</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.26887</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.26887v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We present Denario, an AI multi-agent system designed to serve as a scientific research assistant. Denario can perform many different tasks, such as generating ideas, checking the literature, developing research plans, writing and executing code, making plots, and drafting and reviewing a scientific paper. The system has a modular architecture, allowing it to handle specific tasks, such as generating an idea, or carrying out end-to-end scientific analysis using Cmbagent as a deep-research backend. In this work, we describe in detail Denario and its modules, and illustrate its capabilities by presenting multiple AI-generated papers generated by it in many different scientific disciplines such as astrophysics, biology, biophysics, biomedical informatics, chemistry, material science, mathematical physics, medicine, neuroscience and planetary science. Denario also excels at combining ideas from different disciplines, and we illustrate this by showing a paper that applies methods from quantum physics and machine learning to astrophysical data. We report the evaluations performed on these papers by domain experts, who provided both numerical scores and review-like feedback. We then highlight the strengths, weaknesses, and limitations of the current system. Finally, we discuss the ethical implications of AI-driven research and reflect on how such technology relates to the philosophy of science. We publicly release the code at https://github.com/AstroPilot-AI/Denario. A Denario demo can also be run directly on the web at https://huggingface.co/spaces/astropilot-ai/Denario, and the full app will be deployed on the cloud.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.26887v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Francisco Villaescusa-Navarro, Boris Bolliet, Pablo Villanueva-Domingo, Adrian E. Bayer, Aidan Acquah, Chetana Amancharla, Almog Barzilay-Siegal, Pablo Bermejo, Camille Bilodeau, Pablo C\'ardenas Ram\'irez, Miles Cranmer, Urbano L. Fran\c{c}a, ChangHoon Hahn, Yan-Fei Jiang, Raul Jimenez, Jun-Young Lee, Antonio Lerario, Osman Mamun, Thomas Meier, Anupam A. Ojha, Pavlos Protopapas, Shimanto Roy, David N. Spergel, Pedro Taranc\'on-\'Alvarez, Ujjwal Tiwari, Matteo Viel, Digvijay Wadekar, Chi Wang, Bonny Y. Wang, Licong Xu, Yossi Yovel, Shuwen Yue, Wen-Han Zhou, Qiyao Zhu, Jiajun Zou, \'I\~nigo Zubeldia</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RepV: Safety-Separable Latent Spaces for Scalable Neurosymbolic Plan Verification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.26935</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.26935v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: As AI systems migrate to safety-critical domains, verifying that their actions comply with well-defined rules remains a challenge. Formal methods provide provable guarantees but demand hand-crafted temporal-logic specifications, offering limited expressiveness and accessibility. Deep learning approaches enable evaluation of plans against natural-language constraints, yet their opaque decision process invites misclassifications with potentially severe consequences. We introduce RepV, a neurosymbolic verifier that unifies both views by learning a latent space where safe and unsafe plans are linearly separable. Starting from a modest seed set of plans labeled by an off-the-shelf model checker, RepV trains a lightweight projector that embeds each plan, together with a language model-generated rationale, into a low-dimensional space; a frozen linear boundary then verifies compliance for unseen natural-language rules in a single forward pass.
  Beyond binary classification, RepV provides a probabilistic guarantee on the likelihood of correct verification based on its position in the latent space. This guarantee enables a guarantee-driven refinement of the planner, improving rule compliance without human annotations. Empirical evaluations show that RepV improves compliance prediction accuracy by up to 15% compared to baseline methods while adding fewer than 0.2M parameters. Furthermore, our refinement framework outperforms ordinary fine-tuning baselines across various planning domains. These results show that safety-separable latent spaces offer a scalable, plug-and-play primitive for reliable neurosymbolic plan verification. Code and data are available at: https://repv-project.github.io/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.26935v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.FL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yunhao Yang, Neel P. Bhatt, Pranay Samineni, Rohan Siva, Zhanyang Wang, Ufuk Topcu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Frame Aggregation-based Transformer for Live Video Comment Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.26978</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.26978v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Live commenting on video streams has surged in popularity on platforms like Twitch, enhancing viewer engagement through dynamic interactions. However, automatically generating contextually appropriate comments remains a challenging and exciting task. Video streams can contain a vast amount of data and extraneous content. Existing approaches tend to overlook an important aspect of prioritizing video frames that are most relevant to ongoing viewer interactions. This prioritization is crucial for producing contextually appropriate comments. To address this gap, we introduce a novel Semantic Frame Aggregation-based Transformer (SFAT) model for live video comment generation. This method not only leverages CLIP's visual-text multimodal knowledge to generate comments but also assigns weights to video frames based on their semantic relevance to ongoing viewer conversation. It employs an efficient weighted sum of frames technique to emphasize informative frames while focusing less on irrelevant ones. Finally, our comment decoder with a cross-attention mechanism that attends to each modality ensures that the generated comment reflects contextual cues from both chats and video. Furthermore, to address the limitations of existing datasets, which predominantly focus on Chinese-language content with limited video categories, we have constructed a large scale, diverse, multimodal English video comments dataset. Extracted from Twitch, this dataset covers 11 video categories, totaling 438 hours and 3.2 million comments. We demonstrate the effectiveness of our SFAT model by comparing it to existing methods for generating comments from live video and ongoing dialogue contexts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.26978v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Anam Fatima, Yi Yu, Janak Kapuriya, Julien Lalanne, Jainendra Shukla</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards a Measure of Algorithm Similarity</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27063</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27063v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Given two algorithms for the same problem, can we determine whether they are meaningfully different? In full generality, the question is uncomputable, and empirically it is muddied by competing notions of similarity. Yet, in many applications (such as clone detection or program synthesis) a pragmatic and consistent similarity metric is necessary. We review existing equivalence and similarity notions and introduce EMOC: An Evaluation-Memory-Operations-Complexity framework that embeds algorithm implementations into a feature space suitable for downstream tasks. We compile PACD, a curated dataset of verified Python implementations across three problems, and show that EMOC features support clustering and classification of algorithm types, detection of near-duplicates, and quantification of diversity in LLM-generated programs. Code, data, and utilities for computing EMOC embeddings are released to facilitate reproducibility and future work on algorithm similarity.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27063v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IT</category>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>math.IT</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shairoz Sohail, Taher Ali</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glia: A Human-Inspired AI for Automated Systems Design and Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27176</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27176v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Can an AI autonomously design mechanisms for computer systems on par with the creativity and reasoning of human experts? We present Glia, an AI architecture for networked systems design that uses large language models (LLMs) in a human-inspired, multi-agent workflow. Each agent specializes in reasoning, experimentation, and analysis, collaborating through an evaluation framework that grounds abstract reasoning in empirical feedback. Unlike prior ML-for-systems methods that optimize black-box policies, Glia generates interpretable designs and exposes its reasoning process. When applied to a distributed GPU cluster for LLM inference, it produces new algorithms for request routing, scheduling, and auto-scaling that perform at human-expert levels in significantly less time, while yielding novel insights into workload behavior. Our results suggest that by combining reasoning LLMs with structured experimentation, an AI can produce creative and understandable designs for complex systems problems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27176v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.DC</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Pouya Hamadanian, Pantea Karimi, Arash Nasr-Esfahany, Kimia Noorbakhsh, Joseph Chandler, Ali ParandehGheibi, Mohammad Alizadeh, Hari Balakrishnan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can MLLMs Read the Room? A Multimodal Benchmark for Verifying Truthfulness in Multi-Party Social Interactions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27195</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27195v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: As AI systems become increasingly integrated into human lives, endowing them with robust social intelligence has emerged as a critical frontier. A key aspect of this intelligence is discerning truth from deception, a ubiquitous element of human interaction that is conveyed through a complex interplay of verbal language and non-verbal visual cues. However, automatic deception detection in dynamic, multi-party conversations remains a significant challenge. The recent rise of powerful Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs), with their impressive abilities in visual and textual understanding, makes them natural candidates for this task. Consequently, their capabilities in this crucial domain are mostly unquantified. To address this gap, we introduce a new task, Multimodal Interactive Veracity Assessment (MIVA), and present a novel multimodal dataset derived from the social deduction game Werewolf. This dataset provides synchronized video, text, with verifiable ground-truth labels for every statement. We establish a comprehensive benchmark evaluating state-of-the-art MLLMs, revealing a significant performance gap: even powerful models like GPT-4o struggle to distinguish truth from falsehood reliably. Our analysis of failure modes indicates that these models fail to ground language in visual social cues effectively and may be overly conservative in their alignment, highlighting the urgent need for novel approaches to building more perceptive and trustworthy AI systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27195v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Caixin Kang, Yifei Huang, Liangyang Ouyang, Mingfang Zhang, Yoichi Sato</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DRAMA: Unifying Data Retrieval and Analysis for Open-Domain Analytic Queries</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27238</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27238v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Manually conducting real-world data analyses is labor-intensive and inefficient. Despite numerous attempts to automate data science workflows, none of the existing paradigms or systems fully demonstrate all three key capabilities required to support them effectively: (1) open-domain data collection, (2) structured data transformation, and (3) analytic reasoning.
  To overcome these limitations, we propose DRAMA, an end-to-end paradigm that answers users' analytic queries in natural language on large-scale open-domain data. DRAMA unifies data collection, transformation, and analysis as a single pipeline. To quantitatively evaluate system performance on tasks representative of DRAMA, we construct a benchmark, DRAMA-Bench, consisting of two categories of tasks: claim verification and question answering, each comprising 100 instances. These tasks are derived from real-world applications that have gained significant public attention and require the retrieval and analysis of open-domain data. We develop DRAMA-Bot, a multi-agent system designed following DRAMA. It comprises a data retriever that collects and transforms data by coordinating the execution of sub-agents, and a data analyzer that performs structured reasoning over the retrieved data. We evaluate DRAMA-Bot on DRAMA-Bench together with five state-of-the-art baseline agents. DRAMA-Bot achieves 86.5% task accuracy at a cost of $0.05, outperforming all baselines with up to 6.9 times the accuracy and less than 1/6 of the cost. DRAMA is publicly available at https://github.com/uiuc-kang-lab/drama.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27238v1</guid>
      <category>cs.DB</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3769781</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Chuxuan Hu, Maxwell Yang, James Weiland, Yeji Lim, Suhas Palawala, Daniel Kang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Higher-order Linear Attention</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27258</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27258v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The quadratic cost of scaled dot-product attention is a central obstacle to scaling autoregressive language models to long contexts. Linear-time attention and State Space Models (SSMs) provide scalable alternatives but are typically restricted to first-order or kernel-based approximations, which can limit expressivity. We introduce Higher-order Linear Attention (HLA), a causal, streaming mechanism that realizes higher interactions via compact prefix sufficient statistics. In the second-order case, HLA maintains a constant-size state and computes per-token outputs in linear time without materializing any $n \times n$ matrices. We give closed-form streaming identities, a strictly causal masked variant using two additional summaries, and a chunk-parallel training scheme based on associative scans that reproduces the activations of a serial recurrence exactly. We further outline extensions to third and higher orders. Collectively, these results position HLA as a principled, scalable building block that combines attention-like, data-dependent mixing with the efficiency of modern recurrent architectures. Project Page: https://github.com/yifanzhang-pro/HLA.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27258v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yifan Zhang, Zhen Qin, Quanquan Gu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Un-Attributability: Computing Novelty From Retrieval &amp; Semantic Similarity</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27313</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27313v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Understanding how language-model outputs relate to the pretraining corpus is central to studying model behavior. Most training data attribution (TDA) methods ask which training examples causally influence a given output, often using leave-one-out tests. We invert the question: which outputs cannot be attributed to any pretraining example? We introduce un-attributability as an operational measure of semantic novelty: an output is novel if the pretraining corpus contains no semantically similar context. We approximate this with a simple two-stage retrieval pipeline: index the corpus with lightweight GIST embeddings, retrieve the top-n candidates, then rerank with ColBERTv2. If the nearest corpus item is less attributable than a human-generated text reference, we consider the output of the model as novel. We evaluate on SmolLM and SmolLM2 and report three findings: (1) models draw on pretraining data across much longer spans than previously reported; (2) some domains systematically promote or suppress novelty; and (3) instruction tuning not only alters style but also increases novelty. Reframing novelty assessment around un-attributability enables efficient analysis at pretraining scale. We release ~20 TB of corpus chunks and index artifacts to support replication and large-scale extension of our analysis at https://huggingface.co/datasets/stai-tuebingen/faiss-smollm</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27313v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Philipp Davydov, Ameya Prabhu, Matthias Bethge, Elisa Nguyen, Seong Joon Oh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measuring Chain-of-Thought Monitorability Through Faithfulness and Verbosity</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27378</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27378v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Chain-of-thought (CoT) outputs let us read a model's step-by-step reasoning. Since any long, serial reasoning process must pass through this textual trace, the quality of the CoT is a direct window into what the model is thinking. This visibility could help us spot unsafe or misaligned behavior (monitorability), but only if the CoT is transparent about its internal reasoning (faithfulness). Fully measuring faithfulness is difficult, so researchers often focus on examining the CoT in cases where the model changes its answer after adding a cue to the input. This proxy finds some instances of unfaithfulness but loses information when the model maintains its answer, and does not investigate aspects of reasoning not tied to the cue. We extend these results to a more holistic sense of monitorability by introducing verbosity: whether the CoT lists every factor needed to solve the task. We combine faithfulness and verbosity into a single monitorability score that shows how well the CoT serves as the model's external `working memory', a property that many safety schemes based on CoT monitoring depend on. We evaluate instruction-tuned and reasoning models on BBH, GPQA, and MMLU. Our results show that models can appear faithful yet remain hard to monitor when they leave out key factors, and that monitorability differs sharply across model families. We release our evaluation code using the Inspect library to support reproducible future work.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27378v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Austin Meek, Eitan Sprejer, Iv\'an Arcuschin, Austin J. Brockmeier, Steven Basart</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atlas-Alignment: Making Interpretability Transferable Across Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27413</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27413v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Interpretability is crucial for building safe, reliable, and controllable language models, yet existing interpretability pipelines remain costly and difficult to scale. Interpreting a new model typically requires costly training of model-specific sparse autoencoders, manual or semi-automated labeling of SAE components, and their subsequent validation. We introduce Atlas-Alignment, a framework for transferring interpretability across language models by aligning unknown latent spaces to a Concept Atlas - a labeled, human-interpretable latent space - using only shared inputs and lightweight representational alignment techniques. Once aligned, this enables two key capabilities in previously opaque models: (1) semantic feature search and retrieval, and (2) steering generation along human-interpretable atlas concepts. Through quantitative and qualitative evaluations, we show that simple representational alignment methods enable robust semantic retrieval and steerable generation without the need for labeled concept data. Atlas-Alignment thus amortizes the cost of explainable AI and mechanistic interpretability: by investing in one high-quality Concept Atlas, we can make many new models transparent and controllable at minimal marginal cost.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27413v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bruno Puri, Jim Berend, Sebastian Lapuschkin, Wojciech Samek</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DeepCompress: A Dual Reward Strategy for Dynamically Exploring and Compressing Reasoning Chains</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27419</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27419v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large Reasoning Models (LRMs) have demonstrated impressive capabilities but suffer from cognitive inefficiencies like ``overthinking'' simple problems and ``underthinking'' complex ones. While existing methods that use supervised fine-tuning~(SFT) or reinforcement learning~(RL) with token-length rewards can improve efficiency, they often do so at the cost of accuracy. This paper introduces \textbf{DeepCompress}, a novel framework that simultaneously enhances both the accuracy and efficiency of LRMs. We challenge the prevailing approach of consistently favoring shorter reasoning paths, showing that longer responses can contain a broader range of correct solutions for difficult problems. DeepCompress employs an adaptive length reward mechanism that dynamically classifies problems as ``Simple'' or ``Hard'' in real-time based on the model's evolving capability. It encourages shorter, more efficient reasoning for ``Simple'' problems while promoting longer, more exploratory thought chains for ``Hard'' problems. This dual-reward strategy enables the model to autonomously adjust its Chain-of-Thought (CoT) length, compressing reasoning for well-mastered problems and extending it for those it finds challenging. Experimental results on challenging mathematical benchmarks show that DeepCompress consistently outperforms baseline methods, achieving superior accuracy while significantly improving token efficiency.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27419v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tian Liang, Wenxiang Jiao, Zhiwei He, Jiahao Xu, Haitao Mi, Dong Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thought Branches: Interpreting LLM Reasoning Requires Resampling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27484</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27484v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Most work interpreting reasoning models studies only a single chain-of-thought (CoT), yet these models define distributions over many possible CoTs. We argue that studying a single sample is inadequate for understanding causal influence and the underlying computation. Though fully specifying this distribution is intractable, it can be understood by sampling. We present case studies using resampling to investigate model decisions. First, when a model states a reason for its action, does that reason actually cause the action? In "agentic misalignment" scenarios, we resample specific sentences to measure their downstream effects. Self-preservation sentences have small causal impact, suggesting they do not meaningfully drive blackmail. Second, are artificial edits to CoT sufficient for steering reasoning? These are common in literature, yet take the model off-policy. Resampling and selecting a completion with the desired property is a principled on-policy alternative. We find off-policy interventions yield small and unstable effects compared to resampling in decision-making tasks. Third, how do we understand the effect of removing a reasoning step when the model may repeat it post-edit? We introduce a resilience metric that repeatedly resamples to prevent similar content from reappearing downstream. Critical planning statements resist removal but have large effects when eliminated. Fourth, since CoT is sometimes "unfaithful", can our methods teach us anything in these settings? Adapting causal mediation analysis, we find that hints that have a causal effect on the output without being explicitly mentioned exert a subtle and cumulative influence on the CoT that persists even if the hint is removed. Overall, studying distributions via resampling enables reliable causal analysis, clearer narratives of model reasoning, and principled CoT interventions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27484v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Uzay Macar, Paul C. Bogdan, Senthooran Rajamanoharan, Neel Nanda</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SIGMA: Search-Augmented On-Demand Knowledge Integration for Agentic Mathematical Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27568</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27568v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Solving mathematical reasoning problems requires not only accurate access to relevant knowledge but also careful, multi-step thinking. However, current retrieval-augmented models often rely on a single perspective, follow inflexible search strategies, and struggle to effectively combine information from multiple sources. We introduce SIGMA (Search-Augmented On-Demand Knowledge Integration for AGentic Mathematical reAsoning), a unified framework that orchestrates specialized agents to independently reason, perform targeted searches, and synthesize findings through a moderator mechanism. Each agent generates hypothetical passages to optimize retrieval for its analytic perspective, ensuring knowledge integration is both context-sensitive and computation-efficient. When evaluated on challenging benchmarks such as MATH500, AIME, and PhD-level science QA GPQA, SIGMA consistently outperforms both open- and closed-source systems, achieving an absolute performance improvement of 7.4%. Our results demonstrate that multi-agent, on-demand knowledge integration significantly enhances both reasoning accuracy and efficiency, offering a scalable approach for complex, knowledge-intensive problem-solving. We will release the code upon publication.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27568v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ali Asgarov, Umid Suleymanov, Aadyant Khatri</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Universal Video Retrieval: Generalizing Video Embedding via Synthesized Multimodal Pyramid Curriculum</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27571</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27571v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The prevailing video retrieval paradigm is structurally misaligned, as narrow benchmarks incentivize correspondingly limited data and single-task training. Therefore, universal capability is suppressed due to the absence of a diagnostic evaluation that defines and demands multi-dimensional generalization. To break this cycle, we introduce a framework built on the co-design of evaluation, data, and modeling. First, we establish the Universal Video Retrieval Benchmark (UVRB), a suite of 16 datasets designed not only to measure performance but also to diagnose critical capability gaps across tasks and domains. Second, guided by UVRB's diagnostics, we introduce a scalable synthesis workflow that generates 1.55 million high-quality pairs to populate the semantic space required for universality. Finally, we devise the Modality Pyramid, a curriculum that trains our General Video Embedder (GVE) by explicitly leveraging the latent interconnections within our diverse data. Extensive experiments show GVE achieves state-of-the-art zero-shot generalization on UVRB. In particular, our analysis reveals that popular benchmarks are poor predictors of general ability and that partially relevant retrieval is a dominant but overlooked scenario. Overall, our co-designed framework provides a practical path to escape the limited scope and advance toward truly universal video retrieval.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27571v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhuoning Guo, Mingxin Li, Yanzhao Zhang, Dingkun Long, Pengjun Xie, Xiaowen Chu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visual Backdoor Attacks on MLLM Embodied Decision Making via Contrastive Trigger Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27623</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27623v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Multimodal large language models (MLLMs) have advanced embodied agents by enabling direct perception, reasoning, and planning task-oriented actions from visual inputs. However, such vision driven embodied agents open a new attack surface: visual backdoor attacks, where the agent behaves normally until a visual trigger appears in the scene, then persistently executes an attacker-specified multi-step policy. We introduce BEAT, the first framework to inject such visual backdoors into MLLM-based embodied agents using objects in the environments as triggers. Unlike textual triggers, object triggers exhibit wide variation across viewpoints and lighting, making them difficult to implant reliably. BEAT addresses this challenge by (1) constructing a training set that spans diverse scenes, tasks, and trigger placements to expose agents to trigger variability, and (2) introducing a two-stage training scheme that first applies supervised fine-tuning (SFT) and then our novel Contrastive Trigger Learning (CTL). CTL formulates trigger discrimination as preference learning between trigger-present and trigger-free inputs, explicitly sharpening the decision boundaries to ensure precise backdoor activation. Across various embodied agent benchmarks and MLLMs, BEAT achieves attack success rates up to 80%, while maintaining strong benign task performance, and generalizes reliably to out-of-distribution trigger placements. Notably, compared to naive SFT, CTL boosts backdoor activation accuracy up to 39% under limited backdoor data. These findings expose a critical yet unexplored security risk in MLLM-based embodied agents, underscoring the need for robust defenses before real-world deployment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27623v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qiusi Zhan, Hyeonjeong Ha, Rui Yang, Sirui Xu, Hanyang Chen, Liang-Yan Gui, Yu-Xiong Wang, Huan Zhang, Heng Ji, Daniel Kang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MindSearch: Mimicking Human Minds Elicits Deep AI Searcher</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.20183</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.20183v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Information seeking and integration is a complex cognitive task that consumes enormous time and effort. Inspired by the remarkable progress of Large Language Models, recent works attempt to solve this task by combining LLMs and search engines. However, these methods still obtain unsatisfying performance due to three challenges: (1) complex requests often cannot be accurately and completely retrieved by the search engine once (2) corresponding information to be integrated is spread over multiple web pages along with massive noise, and (3) a large number of web pages with long contents may quickly exceed the maximum context length of LLMs. Inspired by the cognitive process when humans solve these problems, we introduce MindSearch to mimic the human minds in web information seeking and integration, which can be instantiated by a simple yet effective LLM-based multi-agent framework. The WebPlanner models the human mind of multi-step information seeking as a dynamic graph construction process: it decomposes the user query into atomic sub-questions as nodes in the graph and progressively extends the graph based on the search result from WebSearcher. Tasked with each sub-question, WebSearcher performs hierarchical information retrieval with search engines and collects valuable information for WebPlanner. The multi-agent design of MindSearch enables the whole framework to seek and integrate information parallelly from larger-scale (e.g., more than 300) web pages in 3 minutes, which is worth 3 hours of human effort. MindSearch demonstrates significant improvement in the response quality in terms of depth and breadth, on both close-set and open-set QA problems. Besides, responses from MindSearch based on InternLM2.5-7B are preferable by humans to ChatGPT-Web and Perplexity.ai applications, which implies that MindSearch can already deliver a competitive solution to the proprietary AI search engine.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.20183v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zehui Chen, Kuikun Liu, Qiuchen Wang, Jiangning Liu, Wenwei Zhang, Kai Chen, Feng Zhao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SparsePO: Controlling Preference Alignment of LLMs via Sparse Token Masks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.05102</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.05102v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Direct alignment algorithms have proven an effective step for aligning language models to human-desired behaviors. Current variants of the Direct Preference Optimization objective have focused on a strict setting where all tokens are contributing signals of KL divergence and rewards to the loss function. However, human preference is not affected equally by each word in a sequence but is often dependent on specific words or phrases, e.g. existence of toxic terms leads to non-preferred responses. Based on this observation, we argue that not all tokens should be weighted equally during PO and propose a flexible objective termed SparsePO, that aims to automatically learn to weight the KL divergence and reward corresponding to each token during PO training. We propose two different variants of weight-masks that can either be derived from the reference model itself or learned on the fly. Notably, our method induces sparsity in the learned masks, allowing the model to learn how to best balance reward and KL divergence contributions at the token level, learning an optimal level of mask sparsity. Extensive experiments illustrate the effectiveness of our approach at aligning to preference proxies, including sentiment control, helpfulness and harmlessness, and summary quality. Our method obtains +10% and +3% win rate points in summarization and dialogue scenarios, respectively, without compromising model reasoning or the relevancy and faithfulness of the summary response.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.05102v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fenia Christopoulou, Ronald Cardenas, Gerasimos Lampouras, Haitham Bou-Ammar, Jun Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LIBMoE: A Library for comprehensive benchmarking Mixture of Experts in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.00918</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.00918v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Mixture of experts (MoE) architectures have become a cornerstone for scaling up and are a key component in most large language models such as GPT-OSS, DeepSeek-V3, Llama-4, and Gemini-2.5. However, systematic research on MoE remains severely constrained by the prohibitive computational costs of training and evaluation, restricting large-scale studies accessible to most researchers. We introduce LibMoE, a unified framework for reproducible, efficient, and extensible MoE research that supports both pretraining and sparse-upcycling regimes. Beyond unified implementations, the framework provides transparent analytical tools for probing routing and expert dynamics. Leveraging this foundation, we conduct a comprehensive analysis along three dimensions: (i) routing dynamics, covering expert selection patterns, routing stability and optimality, and how routing entropy reveals task specialization and expert diversity; (ii) the effect of lightweight initialization on load balancing, demonstrating how subtle changes in router initialization shape early expert utilization; and (iii) training regime differences, revealing how sparse upcycling and full pretraining exhibit distinct routing patterns and stability profiles. By lowering the barrier to entry and standardizing evaluation, along with our comprehensive analysis, LibMoE broadens access to MoE research and establishes a reliable benchmark to guide future innovations. Project page: https://fsoft-aic.github.io/fsoft-LibMoE.github.io.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.00918v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nam V. Nguyen, Thong T. Doan, Luong Tran, Van Nguyen, Quang Pham</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multilingual State Space Models for Structured Question Answering in Indic Languages</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.01673</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.01673v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The diversity and complexity of Indic languages present unique challenges for natural language processing (NLP) tasks, particularly in the domain of question answering (QA).To address these challenges, this paper explores the application of State Space Models (SSMs),to build efficient and contextually aware QA systems tailored for Indic languages. SSMs are particularly suited for this task due to their ability to model long-term and short-term dependencies in sequential data, making them well-equipped to handle the rich morphology, complex syntax, and contextual intricacies characteristic of Indian languages. We evaluated multiple SSM architectures across diverse datasets representing various Indic languages and conducted a comparative analysis of their performance. Our results demonstrate that these models effectively capture linguistic subtleties, leading to significant improvements in question interpretation, context alignment, and answer generation. This work represents the first application of SSMs to question answering tasks in Indic languages, establishing a foundational benchmark for future research in this domain. We propose enhancements to existing SSM frameworks, optimizing their applicability to low-resource settings and multilingual scenarios prevalent in Indic languages.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.01673v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Arpita Vats, Rahul Raja, Mrinal Mathur, Vinija Jain, Aman Chadha</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SMOL: Professionally translated parallel data for 115 under-represented languages</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.12301</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.12301v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We open-source SMOL (Set of Maximal Overall Leverage), a suite of training data to unlock machine translation for low-resource languages. SMOL has been translated into 124 (and growing) under-resourced languages (125 language pairs), including many for which there exist no previous public resources, for a total of 6.1M translated tokens. SMOL comprises two sub-datasets, each carefully chosen for maximum impact given its size: SMOLSENT, a set of sentences chosen for broad unique token coverage, and SMOLDOC, a document-level resource focusing on a broad topic coverage. They join the already released GATITOS for a trifecta of paragraph, sentence, and token-level content. We demonstrate that using SMOL to prompt or fine-tune Large Language Models yields robust chrF improvements. In addition to translation, we provide factuality ratings and rationales for all documents in SMOLDOC, yielding the first factuality datasets for most of these languages.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.12301v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Isaac Caswell, Elizabeth Nielsen, Jiaming Luo, Colin Cherry, Geza Kovacs, Hadar Shemtov, Partha Talukdar, Dinesh Tewari, Baba Mamadi Diane, Djibrila Diane, Solo Farabado Ciss\'e, Koulako Moussa Doumbouya, Edoardo Ferrante, Alessandro Guasoni, Christopher Homan, Mamadou K. Keita, Sudhamoy DebBarma, Ali Kuzhuget, David Anugraha, Muhammad Ravi Shulthan Habibi, Genta Indra Winata, Anthony Munthali, Sina Ahmadi, Andrei Chemyshev, Mingfei Lau, Jonathan Eng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Best-of-N Selection for Large Language Models via Self-Certainty</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.18581</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.18581v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Best-of-N selection is a key technique for improving the reasoning performance of Large Language Models (LLMs) through increased test-time computation. Current state-of-the-art methods often employ computationally intensive reward models for response evaluation and selection. Reward-free alternatives, like self-consistency and universal self-consistency, are limited in their ability to handle open-ended generation tasks or scale effectively. To address these limitations, we propose self-certainty, a novel and efficient metric that leverages the inherent probability distribution of LLM outputs to estimate response quality without requiring external reward models. We hypothesize that higher distributional self-certainty, aggregated across multiple samples, correlates with improved response accuracy, as it reflects greater confidence in the generated output. Through extensive experiments on various reasoning tasks, we demonstrate that self-certainty (1) scales effectively with increasing sample size N, akin to reward models but without the computational overhead; (2) complements chain-of-thought, improving reasoning performance beyond greedy decoding; and (3) generalizes to open-ended tasks where traditional self-consistency methods fall short. Our findings establish self-certainty as a practical and efficient way for improving LLM reasoning capabilities. The code is available at https://github.com/backprop07/Self-Certainty</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.18581v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhewei Kang, Xuandong Zhao, Dawn Song</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More of the Same: Persistent Representational Harms Under Increased Representation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.00333</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.00333v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: To recognize and mitigate the harms of generative AI systems, it is crucial to consider whether and how different societal groups are represented by these systems. A critical gap emerges when naively measuring or improving who is represented, as this does not consider how people are represented. In this work, we develop GAS(P), an evaluation methodology for surfacing distribution-level group representational biases in generated text, tackling the setting where groups are unprompted (i.e., groups are not specified in the input to generative systems). We apply this novel methodology to investigate gendered representations in occupations across state-of-the-art large language models. We show that, even though the gender distribution when models are prompted to generate biographies leads to a large representation of women, even representational biases persist in how different genders are represented. Our evaluation methodology reveals that there are statistically significant distribution-level differences in the word choice used to describe biographies and personas of different genders across occupations, and we show that many of these differences are associated with representational harms and stereotypes. Our empirical findings caution that naively increasing (unprompted) representation may inadvertently proliferate representational biases, and our proposed evaluation methodology enables systematic and rigorous measurement of the problem.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.00333v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jennifer Mickel, Maria De-Arteaga, Leqi Liu, Kevin Tian</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(How) Do Language Models Track State?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.02854</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.02854v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Transformer language models (LMs) exhibit behaviors -- from storytelling to code generation -- that seem to require tracking the unobserved state of an evolving world. How do they do this? We study state tracking in LMs trained or fine-tuned to compose permutations (i.e., to compute the order of a set of objects after a sequence of swaps). Despite the simple algebraic structure of this problem, many other tasks (e.g., simulation of finite automata and evaluation of boolean expressions) can be reduced to permutation composition, making it a natural model for state tracking in general. We show that LMs consistently learn one of two state tracking mechanisms for this task. The first closely resembles the "associative scan" construction used in recent theoretical work by Liu et al. (2023) and Merrill et al. (2024). The second uses an easy-to-compute feature (permutation parity) to partially prune the space of outputs, and then refines this with an associative scan. LMs that learn the former algorithm tend to generalize better and converge faster, and we show how to steer LMs toward one or the other with intermediate training tasks that encourage or suppress the heuristics. Our results demonstrate that transformer LMs, whether pre-trained or fine-tuned, can learn to implement efficient and interpretable state-tracking mechanisms, and the emergence of these mechanisms can be predicted and controlled.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.02854v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Belinda Z. Li, Zifan Carl Guo, Jacob Andreas</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Multi-Stage Framework with Taxonomy-Guided Reasoning for Occupation Classification Using Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.12989</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.12989v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Automatically annotating job data with standardized occupations from taxonomies, known as occupation classification, is crucial for labor market analysis. However, this task is often hindered by data scarcity and the challenges of manual annotations. While large language models (LLMs) hold promise due to their extensive world knowledge and in-context learning capabilities, their effectiveness depends on their knowledge of occupational taxonomies, which remains unclear. In this study, we assess the ability of LLMs to generate precise taxonomic entities from taxonomy, highlighting their limitations, especially for smaller models. To address these challenges, we propose a multi-stage framework consisting of inference, retrieval, and reranking stages, which integrates taxonomy-guided reasoning examples to enhance performance by aligning outputs with taxonomic knowledge. Evaluations on a large-scale dataset show that our framework not only enhances occupation and skill classification tasks, but also provides a cost-effective alternative to frontier models like GPT-4o, significantly reducing computational costs while maintaining strong performance. This makes it a practical and scalable solution for occupation classification and related tasks across LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.12989v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Palakorn Achananuparp, Ee-Peng Lim, Yao Lu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FUSE : A Ridge and Random Forest-Based Metric for Evaluating MT in Indigenous Languages</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.00021</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.00021v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper presents the winning submission of the RaaVa team to the AmericasNLP 2025 Shared Task 3 on Automatic Evaluation Metrics for Machine Translation (MT) into Indigenous Languages of America, where our system ranked first overall based on average Pearson correlation with the human annotations. We introduce Feature-Union Scorer (FUSE) for Evaluation, FUSE integrates Ridge regression and Gradient Boosting to model translation quality. In addition to FUSE, we explore five alternative approaches leveraging different combinations of linguistic similarity features and learning paradigms. FUSE Score highlights the effectiveness of combining lexical, phonetic, semantic, and fuzzy token similarity with learning-based modeling to improve MT evaluation for morphologically rich and low-resource languages. MT into Indigenous languages poses unique challenges due to polysynthesis, complex morphology, and non-standardized orthography. Conventional automatic metrics such as BLEU, TER, and ChrF often fail to capture deeper aspects like semantic adequacy and fluency. Our proposed framework, formerly referred to as FUSE, incorporates multilingual sentence embeddings and phonological encodings to better align with human evaluation. We train supervised models on human-annotated development sets and evaluate held-out test data. Results show that FUSE consistently achieves higher Pearson and Spearman correlations with human judgments, offering a robust and linguistically informed solution for MT evaluation in low-resource settings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.00021v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rahul Raja, Arpita Vats</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HELIOS: Adaptive Model And Early-Exit Selection for Efficient LLM Inference Serving</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.10724</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.10724v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Early-Exit Large Language Models (EE-LLMs) enable high throughput inference by allowing tokens to exit early at intermediate layers. However, their throughput is limited by the computational and memory savings. Existing EE-LLM frameworks rely on a single model and therefore, their token generation latencies are bottlenecked by tokens that do not exit early and traverse additional layers. Moreover, early exits are only known at runtime and depend on the request. Therefore, these frameworks load the weights of all model layers even though large portions remain unused when tokens exit early. The lack of memory savings limit us from scaling the batch sizes.
  We propose $\textit{HELIOS}$, a framework that improves both token generation latency and batch sizes to enable high-throughput in EE-LLMs. HELIOS exploits two insights. $\textit{First}$, early exits are often complimentary across models, tokens that do not exit early on one model often take an early-exit on another. HELIOS employs multiple models and dynamically switches between them to collectively maximize the number of tokens that exit early, and minimize token generation latencies. $\textit{Second}$, even when a predicted token does not exit early due to poor confidence, it often remains unchanged even after additional layer traversal. HELIOS greedily allows such tokens to exit early and only loads the weights of the most likely to be used layers, yielding memory savings which is then re-purposed to increase batch sizes. HELIOS employs real-time profiling to accurately identify the early-exit distributions, and adaptively switches between models by tracking tokens in real-time to minimize the performance degradation caused by greedy model loading and exiting. Our evaluations show that HELIOS achieves $1.48\times$ higher throughput and $15.14\times$ larger batch size compared to existing EE-LLM frameworks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.10724v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Avinash Kumar, Shashank Nag, Jason Clemons, Lizy John, Poulami Das</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cancer-Myth: Evaluating Large Language Models on Patient Questions with False Presuppositions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.11373</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.11373v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Cancer patients are increasingly turning to large language models (LLMs) for medical information, making it critical to assess how well these models handle complex, personalized questions. However, current medical benchmarks focus on medical exams or consumer-searched questions and do not evaluate LLMs on real patient questions with patient details. In this paper, we first have three hematology-oncology physicians evaluate cancer-related questions drawn from real patients. While LLM responses are generally accurate, the models frequently fail to recognize or address false presuppositions in the questions, posing risks to safe medical decision-making. To study this limitation systematically, we introduce Cancer-Myth, an expert-verified adversarial dataset of 585 cancer-related questions with false presuppositions. On this benchmark, no frontier LLM -- including GPT-5, Gemini-2.5-Pro, and Claude-4-Sonnet -- corrects these false presuppositions more than $43\%$ of the time. To study mitigation strategies, we further construct a 150-question Cancer-Myth-NFP set, in which physicians confirm the absence of false presuppositions. We find typical mitigation strategies, such as adding precautionary prompts with GEPA optimization, can raise accuracy on Cancer-Myth to $80\%$, but at the cost of misidentifying presuppositions in $41\%$ of Cancer-Myth-NFP questions and causing a $10\%$ relative performance drop on other medical benchmarks. These findings highlight a critical gap in the reliability of LLMs, show that prompting alone is not a reliable remedy for false presuppositions, and underscore the need for more robust safeguards in medical AI systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.11373v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wang Bill Zhu, Tianqi Chen, Xinyan Velocity Yu, Ching Ying Lin, Jade Law, Mazen Jizzini, Jorge J. Nieva, Ruishan Liu, Robin Jia</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minitron-SSM: Efficient Hybrid Language Model Compression through Group-Aware SSM Pruning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.11409</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.11409v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Hybrid LLM architectures that combine Attention and State Space Models (SSMs) achieve state-of-the-art accuracy and runtime performance. Recent work has demonstrated that applying compression and distillation to Attention-only models yields smaller, more accurate models at a fraction of the training cost. In this work, we explore the effectiveness of compressing Hybrid architectures. We introduce a novel group-aware pruning strategy that preserves the structural integrity of SSM blocks and their sequence modeling capabilities. Furthermore, we demonstrate the necessity of such SSM pruning to achieve improved accuracy and inference speed compared to traditional approaches. Our compression recipe combines SSM, FFN, embedding dimension, and layer pruning, followed by knowledge distillation-based retraining, similar to the MINITRON technique. Using this approach, we compress the Nemotron-H 8B Hybrid model down to 4B parameters with up to 40x fewer training tokens. The resulting model surpasses the accuracy of similarly-sized models while achieving 2x faster inference, significantly advancing the Pareto frontier.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.11409v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ali Taghibakhshi, Sharath Turuvekere Sreenivas, Saurav Muralidharan, Marcin Chochowski, Yashaswi Karnati, Raviraj Joshi, Ameya Sunil Mahabaleshwarkar, Zijia Chen, Yoshi Suhara, Oluwatobi Olabiyi, Daniel Korzekwa, Mostofa Patwary, Mohammad Shoeybi, Jan Kautz, Bryan Catanzaro, Ashwath Aithal, Nima Tajbakhsh, Pavlo Molchanov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Video and Text: A Balanced Approach to Multimodal Summary Generation and Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.06594</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.06594v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Vision-Language Models (VLMs) often struggle to balance visual and textual information when summarizing complex multimodal inputs, such as entire TV show episodes. In this paper, we propose a zero-shot video-to-text summarization approach that builds its own screenplay representation of an episode, effectively integrating key video moments, dialogue, and character information into a unified document. Unlike previous approaches, we simultaneously generate screenplays and name the characters in zero-shot, using only the audio, video, and transcripts as input. Additionally, we highlight that existing summarization metrics can fail to assess the multimodal content in summaries. To address this, we introduce MFactSum, a multimodal metric that evaluates summaries with respect to both vision and text modalities. Using MFactSum, we evaluate our screenplay summaries on the SummScreen3D dataset, demonstrating superiority against state-of-the-art VLMs such as Gemini 1.5 by generating summaries containing 20% more relevant visual information while requiring 75% less of the video as input.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.06594v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Galann Pennec, Zhengyuan Liu, Nicholas Asher, Philippe Muller, Nancy F. Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reinforcing the Diffusion Chain of Lateral Thought with Diffusion Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.10446</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.10446v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We introduce the Diffusion Chain of Lateral Thought (DCoLT), a reasoning framework for diffusion language models. DCoLT treats each intermediate step in the reverse diffusion process as a latent "thinking" action and optimizes the entire reasoning trajectory to maximize the reward on the correctness of the final answer with outcome-based Reinforcement Learning (RL). Unlike traditional Chain-of-Thought (CoT) methods that follow a causal, linear thinking process, DCoLT allows bidirectional, non-linear reasoning with no strict rule on grammatical correctness amid its intermediate steps of thought. We implement DCoLT on two representative Diffusion Language Models (DLMs). First, we choose SEDD as a representative continuous-time discrete diffusion model, where its concrete score derives a probabilistic policy to maximize the RL reward over the entire sequence of intermediate diffusion steps. We further consider the discrete-time masked diffusion language model -- LLaDA, and find that the order to predict and unmask tokens plays an essential role to optimize its RL action resulting from the ranking-based Unmasking Policy Module (UPM) defined by the Plackett-Luce model. Experiments on both math and code generation tasks show that using only public data and 16 H800 GPUs, DCoLT-reinforced DLMs outperform other DLMs trained by SFT or RL or even both. Notably, DCoLT-reinforced LLaDA boosts its reasoning accuracy by +9.8%, +5.7%, +11.4%, +19.5% on GSM8K, MATH, MBPP, and HumanEval.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.10446v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zemin Huang, Zhiyang Chen, Zijun Wang, Tiancheng Li, Guo-Jun Qi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VeriFastScore: Speeding up long-form factuality evaluation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.16973</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.16973v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Metrics like FactScore and VeriScore that evaluate long-form factuality operate by decomposing an input response into atomic claims and then individually verifying each claim. While effective and interpretable, these methods incur numerous LLM calls and can take upwards of 100 seconds to evaluate a single response, limiting their practicality in large-scale evaluation and training scenarios. To address this, we propose VeriFastScore, which leverages synthetic data to fine-tune Llama3.1 8B for simultaneously extracting and verifying all verifiable claims within a given text based on evidence from Google Search. We show that this task cannot be solved via few-shot prompting with closed LLMs due to its complexity: the model receives ~4K tokens of evidence on average and needs to concurrently decompose claims, judge their verifiability, and verify them against noisy evidence. However, our fine-tuned VeriFastScore model demonstrates strong correlation with the original VeriScore pipeline at both the example level (r=0.80) and system level (r=0.94) while achieving an overall speedup of 6.6x (9.9x excluding evidence retrieval) over VeriScore. To facilitate future factuality research, we publicly release our VeriFastScore model and synthetic datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.16973v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rishanth Rajendhran, Amir Zadeh, Matthew Sarte, Chuan Li, Mohit Iyyer</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Token Distillation: Attention-aware Input Embeddings For New Tokens</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.20133</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.20133v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Current language models rely on static vocabularies determined at pretraining time, which can lead to decreased performance and increased computational cost for domains underrepresented in the original vocabulary. New tokens can be added to solve this problem, when coupled with a good initialization for their new embeddings. However, existing embedding initialization methods require expensive further training or pretraining of additional modules. In this paper, we propose Token Distillation and show that by distilling representations obtained using the original tokenization, we can quickly learn high-quality input embeddings for new tokens. Experimental results with a wide range of open-weight models show that Token Distillation outperforms even strong baselines.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.20133v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Konstantin Dobler, Desmond Elliott, Gerard de Melo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AstroVisBench: A Code Benchmark for Scientific Computing and Visualization in Astronomy</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.20538</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.20538v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) are being explored for applications in scientific research, including their capabilities to synthesize literature, answer research questions, generate research ideas, and even conduct computational experiments. Ultimately, our goal is for these to help scientists derive novel scientific insights. In many areas of science, such insights often arise from processing and visualizing data to understand its patterns. However, evaluating whether an LLM-mediated scientific workflow produces outputs conveying the correct scientific insights is challenging to evaluate and has not been addressed in past work. We introduce AstroVisBench, the first benchmark for both scientific computing and visualization in the astronomy domain. AstroVisBench judges a language model's ability to both (1) create astronomy-specific workflows to process and analyze data and (2) visualize the results of these workflows through complex plots. Our evaluation of visualizations uses a novel LLM-as-a-judge workflow, which is validated against annotation by five professional astronomers. Using AstroVisBench we present an evaluation of state-of-the-art language models, showing a significant gap in their ability to engage in astronomy research as useful assistants. This evaluation provides a strong end-to-end evaluation for AI scientists that offers a path forward for the development of visualization-based workflows, which are central to a broad range of domains from physics to biology.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.20538v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>astro-ph.IM</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sebastian Antony Joseph, Syed Murtaza Husain, Stella S. R. Offner, St\'ephanie Juneau, Paul Torrey, Adam S. Bolton, Juan P. Farias, Niall Gaffney, Greg Durrett, Junyi Jessy Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Diffusion LLMs via Adaptive Parallel Decoding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.00413</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.00413v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The generation speed of LLMs are bottlenecked by autoregressive decoding, where tokens are predicted sequentially one by one. Alternatively, diffusion large language models (dLLMs) theoretically allow for parallel token generation, but in practice struggle to achieve the speed of autoregressive models without significantly sacrificing quality. We therefore introduce adaptive parallel decoding (APD), a novel method that dynamically adjusts the number of tokens sampled in parallel. We achieve this by defining a multiplicative mixture between the dLLM marginal probabilities and the joint probability of sequences under a small auxiliary autoregressive model. This inverts the standard setup of speculative decoding, where the goal is to sample from a large autoregressive verifier by drafting from a smaller model. We further optimize APD by enabling KV caching and limiting the size of the masked input. Altogether, our method puts forward three tunable parameters to flexibly tradeoff throughput and quality. We show that APD provides markedly higher throughput with minimal quality degradations on downstream benchmarks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.00413v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.PF</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Daniel Israel, Guy Van den Broeck, Aditya Grover</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mathematics Isn't Culture-Free: Probing Cultural Gaps via Entity and Scenario Perturbations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.00883</link>
      <description>arXiv:2507.00883v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Although mathematics is often considered culturally neutral, the way mathematical problems are presented can carry implicit cultural context. Existing benchmarks like GSM8K are predominantly rooted in Western norms, including names, currencies, and everyday scenarios. In this work, we create culturally adapted variants of the GSM8K test set for five regions Africa, India, China, Korea, and Japan using prompt-based transformations followed by manual verification. We evaluate six large language models (LLMs), ranging from 8B to 72B parameters, across five prompting strategies to assess their robustness to cultural variation in math problem presentation. Our findings reveal a consistent performance gap: models perform best on the original US-centric dataset and comparatively worse on culturally adapted versions. However, models with reasoning capabilities are more resilient to these shifts, suggesting that deeper reasoning helps bridge cultural presentation gaps in mathematical tasks</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2507.00883v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aditya Tomar, Nihar Ranjan Sahoo, Ashish Mittal, Rudra Murthy, Pushpak Bhattacharyya</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FastLongSpeech: Enhancing Large Speech-Language Models for Efficient Long-Speech Processing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.14815</link>
      <description>arXiv:2507.14815v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The rapid advancement of Large Language Models (LLMs) has spurred significant progress in Large Speech-Language Models (LSLMs), enhancing their capabilities in both speech understanding and generation. While existing LSLMs often concentrate on augmenting speech generation or tackling a diverse array of short-speech tasks, the efficient processing of long-form speech remains a critical yet underexplored challenge. This gap is primarily attributed to the scarcity of long-speech training datasets and the high computational costs associated with long sequences. To address these limitations, we introduce FastLongSpeech, a novel framework designed to extend LSLM capabilities for efficient long-speech processing without necessitating dedicated long-speech training data. FastLongSpeech incorporates an iterative fusion strategy that can compress excessively long-speech sequences into manageable lengths. To adapt LSLMs for long-speech inputs, it introduces a dynamic compression training approach, which exposes the model to short-speech sequences at varying compression ratios, thereby transferring the capabilities of LSLMs to long-speech tasks. To assess the long-speech capabilities of LSLMs, we develop a long-speech understanding benchmark called LongSpeech-Eval. Experiments show that our method exhibits strong performance in both long-speech and short-speech tasks, while greatly improving inference efficiency.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2507.14815v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shoutao Guo, Shaolei Zhang, Qingkai Fang, Zhengrui Ma, Min Zhang, Yang Feng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multilingual Political Views of Large Language Models: Identification and Steering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.22623</link>
      <description>arXiv:2507.22623v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are increasingly used in everyday tools and applications, raising concerns about their potential influence on political views. While prior research has shown that LLMs often exhibit measurable political biases--frequently skewing toward liberal or progressive positions--key gaps remain. Most existing studies evaluate only a narrow set of models and languages, leaving open questions about the generalizability of political biases across architectures, scales, and multilingual settings. Moreover, few works examine whether these biases can be actively controlled.
  In this work, we address these gaps through a large-scale study of political orientation in modern open-source instruction-tuned LLMs. We evaluate seven models, including LLaMA-3.1, Qwen-3, and Aya-Expanse, across 14 languages using the Political Compass Test with 11 semantically equivalent paraphrases per statement to ensure robust measurement. Our results reveal that larger models consistently shift toward libertarian-left positions, with significant variations across languages and model families. To test the manipulability of political stances, we utilize a simple center-of-mass activation intervention technique and show that it reliably steers model responses toward alternative ideological positions across multiple languages. Our code is publicly available at https://github.com/d-gurgurov/Political-Ideologies-LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2507.22623v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Daniil Gurgurov, Katharina Trinley, Ivan Vykopal, Josef van Genabith, Simon Ostermann, Roberto Zamparelli</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Curse of Knowledge: When Complex Evaluation Context Benefits yet Biases LLM Judges</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.03419</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.03419v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: As large language models (LLMs) grow more capable, they face increasingly diverse and complex tasks, making reliable evaluation challenging. The paradigm of LLMs as judges has emerged as a scalable solution, yet prior work primarily focuses on simple settings. Their reliability in complex tasks--where multi-faceted rubrics, unstructured reference answers, and nuanced criteria are critical--remains understudied. In this paper, we constructed ComplexEval, a challenge benchmark designed to systematically expose and quantify Auxiliary Information Induced Biases. We systematically investigated and validated 6 previously unexplored biases across 12 basic and 3 advanced scenarios. Key findings reveal: (1) all evaluated models exhibit significant susceptibility to these biases, with bias magnitude scaling with task complexity; (2) notably, Large Reasoning Models (LRMs) show paradoxical vulnerability. Our in-depth analysis offers crucial insights for improving the accuracy and verifiability of evaluation signals, paving the way for more general and robust evaluation models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.03419v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weiyuan Li, Xintao Wang, Siyu Yuan, Rui Xu, Jiangjie Chen, Qingqing Dong, Yanghua Xiao, Deqing Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ready to Translate, Not to Represent? Bias and Performance Gaps in Multilingual LLMs Across Language Families and Domains</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.07877</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.07877v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The rise of Large Language Models (LLMs) has redefined Machine Translation (MT), enabling context-aware and fluent translations across hundreds of languages and textual domains. Despite their remarkable capabilities, LLMs often exhibit uneven performance across language families and specialized domains. Moreover, recent evidence reveals that these models can encode and amplify different biases present in their training data, posing serious concerns for fairness, especially in low-resource languages. To address these gaps, we introduce Translation Tangles, a unified framework and dataset for evaluating the translation quality and fairness of open-source LLMs. Our approach benchmarks 24 bidirectional language pairs across multiple domains using different metrics. We further propose a hybrid bias detection pipeline that integrates rule-based heuristics, semantic similarity filtering, and LLM-based validation. We also introduce a high-quality, bias-annotated dataset based on human evaluations of 1,439 translation-reference pairs. The code and dataset are accessible on GitHub: https://github.com/faiyazabdullah/TranslationTangles</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.07877v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Md. Faiyaz Abdullah Sayeedi, Md. Mahbub Alam, Subhey Sadi Rahman, Md. Adnanul Islam, Jannatul Ferdous Deepti, Tasnim Mohiuddin, Md Mofijul Islam, Swakkhar Shatabda</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prompt-MII: Meta-Learning Instruction Induction for LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.16932</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.16932v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: A popular method to adapt large language models (LLMs) to new tasks is in-context learning (ICL), which is effective but incurs high inference costs as context length grows. In this paper we propose a method to perform instruction induction, where we take training examples and reduce them to a compact but descriptive prompt that can achieve performance comparable to ICL over the full training set. Specifically, we propose PROMPT-MII, a reinforcement learning (RL) based framework to meta-learn an instruction induction model that can generate compact instructions on the fly for an arbitrary new dataset. We train on over 3,000 diverse classification datasets from the HuggingFace hub, and evaluate on 90 unseen tasks. PROMPT-MII improves downstream model quality by 4-9 F1 points (10-20% relative), matching ICL performance while requiring 3-13x fewer tokens.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.16932v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Emily Xiao, Yixiao Zeng, Ada Chen, Chin-Jou Li, Amanda Bertsch, Graham Neubig</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Navigating the Alignment-Calibration Trade-off: A Pareto-Superior Frontier via Model Merging</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.17426</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.17426v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The "alignment tax" of post-training is typically framed as a drop in task accuracy. We show it also involves a severe loss of calibration, making models overconfident, less reliable, and model outputs less diverse. We show that this trade-off can be navigated effectively via a simple post-hoc intervention: interpolating between a model's weights before and after alignment. Crucially, this is not a strict trade-off. We find that the process consistently reveals Pareto-optimal interpolations - models that improve accuracy beyond both parents while substantially recovering the calibration lost during alignment. Our work demonstrates that simple model merging provides a computationally efficient method for mitigating the full scope of the alignment tax, yielding models that are more capable and more reliable.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.17426v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tiancheng Hu, Benjamin Minixhofer, Nigel Collier</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KAT-Coder Technical Report</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.18779</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.18779v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advances in large language models (LLMs) have enabled progress in agentic coding, where models autonomously reason, plan, and act within interactive software development workflows. However, bridging the gap between static text-based training and dynamic real-world agentic execution remains a core challenge. In this technical report, we present KAT-Coder, a large-scale agentic code model trained through a multi-stage curriculum encompassing Mid-Term Training, Supervised Fine-Tuning (SFT), Reinforcement Fine-Tuning (RFT), and Reinforcement-to-Deployment Adaptation. The Mid-Term stage enhances reasoning, planning, and reflection capabilities through a corpus of real software engineering data and synthetic agentic interactions. The SFT stage constructs a million-sample dataset balancing twenty programming languages, ten development contexts, and ten task archetypes. The RFT stage introduces a novel multi-ground-truth reward formulation for stable and sample-efficient policy optimization. Finally, the Reinforcement-to-Deployment phase adapts the model to production-grade IDE environments using Error-Masked SFT and Tree-Structured Trajectory Training. In summary, these stages enable KAT-Coder to achieve robust tool-use reliability, instruction alignment, and long-context reasoning, forming a deployable foundation for real-world intelligent coding agents. Our KAT series 32B model, KAT-Dev, has been open-sourced on https://huggingface.co/Kwaipilot/KAT-Dev.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.18779v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zizheng Zhan, Ken Deng, Jinghui Wang, Xiaojiang Zhang, Huaixi Tang, Minglei Zhang, Zhiyi Lai, Haoyang Huang, Wen Xiang, Kun Wu, Wenhao Zhuang, Shaojie Wang, Shangpeng Yan, Kepeng Lei, Zongxian Feng, Huiming Wang, Zheng Lin, Mengtong Li, Mengfei Xie, Yinghan Cui, Xuxing Chen, Chao Wang, Weihao Li, Wenqiang Zhu, Jiarong Zhang, Jingxuan Xu, Songwei Yu, Yifan Yao, Xinping Lei, C. Zhang, Han Li, Junqi Xiong, Zuchen Gao, Dailin Li, Haimo Li, Jiaheng Liu, Yuqun Zhang, Junyi Peng, Haotian Zhang, Bin Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DiffAdapt: Difficulty-Adaptive Reasoning for Token-Efficient LLM Inference</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.19669</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.19669v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent reasoning Large Language Models (LLMs) demonstrate remarkable problem-solving abilities but often generate long thinking traces whose utility is unclear. Our work aims to improve their efficiency, enabling them to reach high performance without overthinking. First, we analyze the entropy of token probabilities in reasoning traces. Across three models, we observe a consistent U-shaped entropy pattern: high entropy on easy problems despite high accuracy, low entropy on problems with medium difficulty, and high entropy on hard problems reflecting uncertainty. Specifically, we notice 22--25\% entropy reduction from easy to medium difficulty regions, suggesting an {overthinking} phenomenon on easy instances. Building on these insights, we introduce \textbf{DiffAdapt}, a lightweight framework that selects Easy/Normal/Hard inference strategies per question based on their difficulty and reasoning trace entropy. Each inference strategy consists of a fixed prompt, temperature and maximum token length. In contrast to existing efficiency optimization methods, our approach does not fine-tune base LLM but a small probe that classifies LLM's final hidden state, allowing inexpensive adaptation. We comprehensively evaluate our method on five models and eight benchmarks. Our method achieves comparable or improved accuracy while reducing token usage by up to 22.4\%, establishing a practical path toward compute-efficient reasoning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.19669v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiang Liu, Xuming Hu, Xiaowen Chu, Eunsol Choi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>E2Rank: Your Text Embedding can Also be an Effective and Efficient Listwise Reranker</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.22733</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.22733v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Text embedding models serve as a fundamental component in real-world search applications. By mapping queries and documents into a shared embedding space, they deliver competitive retrieval performance with high efficiency. However, their ranking fidelity remains limited compared to dedicated rerankers, especially recent LLM-based listwise rerankers, which capture fine-grained query-document and document-document interactions. In this paper, we propose a simple yet effective unified framework E2Rank, means Efficient Embedding-based Ranking (also means Embedding-to-Rank), which extends a single text embedding model to perform both high-quality retrieval and listwise reranking through continued training under a listwise ranking objective, thereby achieving strong effectiveness with remarkable efficiency. By applying cosine similarity between the query and document embeddings as a unified ranking function, the listwise ranking prompt, which is constructed from the original query and its candidate documents, serves as an enhanced query enriched with signals from the top-K documents, akin to pseudo-relevance feedback (PRF) in traditional retrieval models. This design preserves the efficiency and representational quality of the base embedding model while significantly improving its reranking performance. Empirically, E2Rank achieves state-of-the-art results on the BEIR reranking benchmark and demonstrates competitive performance on the reasoning-intensive BRIGHT benchmark, with very low reranking latency. We also show that the ranking training process improves embedding performance on the MTEB benchmark. Our findings indicate that a single embedding model can effectively unify retrieval and reranking, offering both computational efficiency and competitive ranking accuracy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.22733v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qi Liu, Yanzhao Zhang, Mingxin Li, Dingkun Long, Pengjun Xie, Jiaxin Mao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Memorization to Reasoning in the Spectrum of Loss Curvature</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.24256</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.24256v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We characterize how memorization is represented in transformer models and show that it can be disentangled in the weights of both language models (LMs) and vision transformers (ViTs) using a decomposition based on the loss landscape curvature. This insight is based on prior theoretical and empirical work showing that the curvature for memorized training points is much sharper than non memorized, meaning ordering weight components from high to low curvature can reveal a distinction without explicit labels. This motivates a weight editing procedure that suppresses far more recitation of untargeted memorized data more effectively than a recent unlearning method (BalancedSubnet), while maintaining lower perplexity. Since the basis of curvature has a natural interpretation for shared structure in model weights, we analyze the editing procedure extensively on its effect on downstream tasks in LMs, and find that fact retrieval and arithmetic are specifically and consistently negatively affected, even though open book fact retrieval and general logical reasoning is conserved. We posit these tasks rely heavily on specialized directions in weight space rather than general purpose mechanisms, regardless of whether those individual datapoints are memorized. We support this by showing a correspondence between task data's activation strength with low curvature components that we edit out, and the drop in task performance after the edit. Our work enhances the understanding of memorization in neural networks with practical applications towards removing it, and provides evidence for idiosyncratic, narrowly-used structures involved in solving tasks like math and fact retrieval.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.24256v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jack Merullo, Srihita Vatsavaya, Lucius Bushnaq, Owen Lewis</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SynthWorlds: Controlled Parallel Worlds for Disentangling Reasoning and Knowledge in Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.24427</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.24427v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Evaluating the reasoning ability of language models (LMs) is complicated by their extensive parametric world knowledge, where benchmark performance often reflects factual recall rather than genuine reasoning. Existing datasets and approaches (e.g., temporal filtering, paraphrasing, adversarial substitution) cannot cleanly separate the two. We present SynthWorlds, a framework that disentangles task reasoning complexity from factual knowledge. In SynthWorlds, we construct parallel corpora representing two worlds with identical interconnected structure: a real-mapped world, where models may exploit parametric knowledge, and a synthetic-mapped world, where such knowledge is meaningless. On top of these corpora, we design two mirrored tasks as case studies: multi-hop question answering and page navigation, which maintain equal reasoning difficulty across worlds. Experiments in parametric-only (e.g., closed-book QA) and knowledge-augmented (e.g., retrieval-augmented) LM settings reveal a persistent knowledge advantage gap, defined as the performance boost models gain from memorized parametric world knowledge. Knowledge acquisition and integration mechanisms reduce but do not eliminate this gap, highlighting opportunities for system improvements. Fully automatic and scalable, SynthWorlds provides a controlled environment for evaluating LMs in ways that were previously challenging, enabling precise and testable comparisons of reasoning and memorization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.24427v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ken Gu, Advait Bhat, Mike A Merrill, Robert West, Xin Liu, Daniel McDuff, Tim Althoff</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DiagramEval: Evaluating LLM-Generated Diagrams via Graphs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.25761</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.25761v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Diagrams play a central role in research papers for conveying ideas, yet they are often notoriously complex and labor-intensive to create. Although diagrams are presented as images, standard image generative models struggle to produce clear diagrams with well-defined structure. We argue that a promising direction is to generate demonstration diagrams directly in textual form as SVGs, which can leverage recent advances in large language models (LLMs). However, due to the complexity of components and the multimodal nature of diagrams, sufficiently discriminative and explainable metrics for evaluating the quality of LLM-generated diagrams remain lacking. In this paper, we propose DiagramEval, a novel evaluation metric designed to assess demonstration diagrams generated by LLMs. Specifically, DiagramEval conceptualizes diagrams as graphs, treating text elements as nodes and their connections as directed edges, and evaluates diagram quality using two new groups of metrics: node alignment and path alignment. For the first time, we effectively evaluate diagrams produced by state-of-the-art LLMs on recent research literature, quantitatively demonstrating the validity of our metrics. Furthermore, we show how the enhanced explainability of our proposed metrics offers valuable insights into the characteristics of LLM-generated diagrams. Code: https://github.com/ulab-uiuc/diagram-eval.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.25761v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chumeng Liang, Jiaxuan You</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NeuronMM: High-Performance Matrix Multiplication for LLM Inference on AWS Trainium</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.25977</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.25977v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: AI accelerators, customized to AI workloads, provide cost-effective and high-performance solutions for training and inference. Trainium, an AI accelerator recently developed by Amazon Web Services (AWS), provides an attractive option for LLM training and inference through its heterogeneous architecture. However, leveraging Trainium architecture for high performance can be challenging because of its systolic array architecture and special requirement on data layout. In this paper, we design high-performance matrix multiplication (matmul), a critical compute kernel, for LLM inference on Trainium. We introduce a series of techniques customized to Trainium based on kernel fusion and novel caching strategies to reduce data movement across the software-managed memory hierarchy, maximize SRAM bandwidth, and avoid expensive matrix transpose. Evaluating with nine datasets and four recent LLMs, we show that our system largely outperforms the state-of-the-art matmul implemented by AWS on Trainium: at the level of matmul kernel, it achieves an average 1.35x speedup (up to 2.22x), which translates to an average 1.66x speedup (up to 2.49x) for end-to-end LLM inference.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.25977v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dinghong Song, Jierui Xu, Weichu Yang, Pengfei Su, Dong Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The End of Manual Decoding: Towards Truly End-to-End Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.26697</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.26697v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The "end-to-end" label for LLMs is a misnomer. In practice, they depend on a non-differentiable decoding process that requires laborious, hand-tuning of hyperparameters like temperature and top-p. This paper introduces AutoDeco, a novel architecture that enables truly "end-to-end" generation by learning to control its own decoding strategy. We augment the standard transformer with lightweight heads that, at each step, dynamically predict context-specific temperature and top-p values alongside the next-token logits. This approach transforms decoding into a parametric, token-level process, allowing the model to self-regulate its sampling strategy within a single forward pass.
  Through extensive experiments on eight benchmarks, we demonstrate that AutoDeco not only significantly outperforms default decoding strategies but also achieves performance comparable to an oracle-tuned baseline derived from "hacking the test set"-a practical upper bound for any static method. Crucially, we uncover an emergent capability for instruction-based decoding control: the model learns to interpret natural language commands (e.g., "generate with low randomness") and adjusts its predicted temperature and top-p on a token-by-token basis, opening a new paradigm for steerable and interactive LLM decoding.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.26697v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhichao Wang, Dongyang Ma, Xinting Huang, Deng Cai, Tian Lan, Jiahao Xu, Haitao Mi, Xiaoying Tang, Yan Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Representative Social Choice: From Learning Theory to AI Alignment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.23953</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.23953v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Social choice theory is the study of preference aggregation across a population, used both in mechanism design for human agents and in the democratic alignment of language models. In this study, we propose the representative social choice framework for the modeling of democratic representation in collective decisions, where the number of issues and individuals are too large for mechanisms to consider all preferences directly. These scenarios are widespread in real-world decision-making processes, such as jury trials, legislation, corporate governance, and, more recently, language model alignment. In representative social choice, the population is represented by a finite sample of individual-issue pairs based on which social choice decisions are made. We show that many of the deepest questions in representative social choice can be formulated as statistical learning problems, and prove the generalization properties of social choice mechanisms using the theory of machine learning. We further formulate axioms for representative social choice, and prove Arrow-like impossibility theorems with new combinatorial tools of analysis. Our framework introduces the representative approach to social choice, opening up research directions at the intersection of social choice, learning theory, and AI alignment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.23953v4</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.GT</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tianyi Qiu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Training a Generally Curious Agent</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.17543</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.17543v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Efficient exploration is essential for intelligent systems interacting with their environment, but existing language models often fall short in scenarios that require strategic information gathering. In this paper, we present Paprika, a fine-tuning approach that enables language models to develop general decision-making capabilities that are not confined to particular environments. By training on synthetic interaction data from different tasks that require diverse strategies, Paprika teaches models to explore and adapt their behavior on a new task based on environment feedback in-context without more gradient updates. Experimental results show that models fine-tuned with Paprika can effectively transfer their learned decision-making capabilities to entirely unseen tasks without additional training. Unlike traditional training, our approach's primary bottleneck lies in sampling useful interaction data instead of model updates. To improve sample efficiency, we propose a curriculum learning strategy that prioritizes sampling trajectories from tasks with high learning potential. These results suggest a promising path towards AI systems that can autonomously solve novel sequential decision-making problems that require interactions with the external world.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.17543v4</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fahim Tajwar, Yiding Jiang, Abitha Thankaraj, Sumaita Sadia Rahman, J Zico Kolter, Jeff Schneider, Ruslan Salakhutdinov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reinforcement Learning vs. Distillation: Understanding Accuracy and Capability in LLM Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.14216</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.14216v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Recent studies have shown that reinforcement learning with verifiable rewards (RLVR) enhances overall accuracy (pass@1) but often fails to improve capability (pass@k) of LLMs in reasoning tasks, while distillation can improve both. In this paper, we investigate the mechanisms behind these phenomena. First, we demonstrate that RLVR struggles to improve capability as it focuses on improving the accuracy of the easier questions to the detriment of the accuracy of the most difficult questions. Second, we show that RLVR does not merely increase the success probability for the easier questions, but in our small model settings, produces quality responses that were absent in its original output distribution. In addition, we show these responses are neither noticeably longer nor feature more reflection-related keywords, underscoring the need for more reliable indicators of response quality. Third, from the experiment distilling teacher responses to in-distribution problems, we find that capability does not always improve with distillation. We conjecture that capability improves only when new knowledge is introduced, whereas distilling reasoning patterns only improves accuracy but not capability, sacrificing performance on the most difficult questions, similar to RLVR. Together, these findings offer a clearer understanding of how RLVR and distillation shape reasoning behavior in LLMs</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.14216v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Minwu Kim, Anubhav Shrestha, Safal Shrestha, Aadim Nepal, Keith Ross</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>R$^2$ec: Towards Large Recommender Models with Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.16994</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.16994v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large recommender models have extended LLMs as powerful recommenders via encoding or item generation, and recent breakthroughs in LLM reasoning synchronously motivate the exploration of reasoning in recommendation. In this work, we propose R$^2$ec, a unified large recommender model with intrinsic reasoning capability. R$^2$ec introduces a dual-head architecture that supports both reasoning chain generation and efficient item prediction in a single model, significantly reducing inference latency. To overcome the lack of annotated reasoning data, we design RecPO, a reinforcement learning framework that optimizes reasoning and recommendation jointly with a novel fused reward mechanism. Extensive experiments on three datasets demonstrate that R$^2$ec outperforms traditional, LLM-based, and reasoning-augmented recommender baselines, while further analyses validate its competitive efficiency among conventional LLM-based recommender baselines and strong adaptability to diverse recommendation scenarios. Code and checkpoints available at https://github.com/YRYangang/RRec.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.16994v3</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Runyang You, Yongqi Li, Xinyu Lin, Xin Zhang, Wenjie Wang, Wenjie Li, Liqiang Nie</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RADAR: Benchmarking Language Models on Imperfect Tabular Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.08249</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.08249v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Language models (LMs) are increasingly being deployed to perform autonomous data analyses. However, their data awareness -- the ability to recognize, reason over, and appropriately handle data artifacts such as missing values, outliers, and logical inconsistencies -- remains underexplored. These artifacts are especially common in real-world tabular data and, if mishandled, can significantly compromise the validity of analytical conclusions. To address this gap, we present RADAR, a benchmark for systematically evaluating data-aware reasoning on tabular data. We develop a framework to simulate data artifacts via programmatic perturbations to enable targeted evaluation of model behavior. RADAR comprises 2980 table query pairs, grounded in real-world data spanning 9 domains and 5 data artifact types. In addition to evaluating artifact handling, RADAR systematically varies table size to study how reasoning performance holds when increasing table size. Our evaluation reveals that, despite decent performance on tables without data artifacts, frontier models degrade significantly when data artifacts are introduced, exposing critical gaps in their capacity for robust, data-aware analysis. Designed to be flexible and extensible, RADAR supports diverse perturbation types and controllable table sizes, offering a valuable resource for advancing tabular reasoning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.08249v2</guid>
      <category>cs.DB</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ken Gu, Zhihan Zhang, Kate Lin, Yuwei Zhang, Akshay Paruchuri, Hong Yu, Mehran Kazemi, Kumar Ayush, A. Ali Heydari, Maxwell A. Xu, Girish Narayanswamy, Yun Liu, Ming-Zher Poh, Yuzhe Yang, Mark Malhotra, Shwetak Patel, Hamid Palangi, Xuhai Xu, Daniel McDuff, Tim Althoff, Xin Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NaviAgent: Bilevel Planning on Tool Navigation Graph for Large-Scale Orchestration</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.19500</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.19500v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have recently demonstrated the ability to act as function call agents by invoking external tools, enabling them to solve tasks beyond their static knowledge. However, existing agents typically call tools step by step at a time without a global view of task structure. As tools depend on each other, this leads to error accumulation and limited scalability, particularly when scaling to thousands of tools. To address these limitations, we propose NaviAgent, a novel bilevel architecture that decouples task planning from tool execution through graph-based modeling of the tool ecosystem. At the task-planning level, the LLM-based agent decides whether to respond directly, clarify user intent, invoke a toolchain, or execute tool outputs, ensuring broad coverage of interaction scenarios independent of inter-tool complexity. At the execution level, a continuously evolving Tool World Navigation Model (TWNM) encodes structural and behavioral relations among tools, guiding the agent to generate scalable and robust invocation sequences. By incorporating feedback from real tool interactions, NaviAgent supports closed-loop optimization of planning and execution, moving beyond tool calling toward adaptive navigation of large-scale tool ecosystems. Experiments show that NaviAgent achieves the best task success rates across models and tasks, and integrating TWMN further boosts performance by up to 17 points on complex tasks, underscoring its key role in toolchain orchestration.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.19500v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yan Jiang, Hao Zhou, LiZhong GU, Ai Han, TianLong Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HiRA: A Hierarchical Reasoning Framework for Decoupled Planning and Execution in Deep Search</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.02652</link>
      <description>arXiv:2507.02652v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Complex information needs in real-world search scenarios demand deep reasoning and knowledge synthesis across diverse sources, which traditional retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) pipelines struggle to address effectively. Current reasoning-based approaches suffer from a fundamental limitation: they use a single model to handle both high-level planning and detailed execution, leading to inefficient reasoning and limited scalability. In this paper, we introduce HiRA, a hierarchical framework that separates strategic planning from specialized execution. Our approach decomposes complex search tasks into focused subtasks, assigns each subtask to domain-specific agents equipped with external tools and reasoning capabilities, and coordinates the results through a structured integration mechanism. This separation prevents execution details from disrupting high-level reasoning while enabling the system to leverage specialized expertise for different types of information processing. Experiments on four complex, cross-modal deep search benchmarks demonstrate that HiRA significantly outperforms state-of-the-art RAG and agent-based systems. Our results show improvements in both answer quality and system efficiency, highlighting the effectiveness of decoupled planning and execution for multi-step information seeking tasks. Our code is available at https://github.com/ignorejjj/HiRA.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2507.02652v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiajie Jin, Xiaoxi Li, Guanting Dong, Yuyao Zhang, Yutao Zhu, Yang Zhao, Hongjin Qian, Zhicheng Dou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning-based Prediction of Clinical Trial Enrollment with Uncertainty Estimates</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.23607</link>
      <description>arXiv:2507.23607v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Clinical trials are a systematic endeavor to assess the safety and efficacy of new drugs or treatments. Conducting such trials typically demands significant financial investment and meticulous planning, highlighting the need for accurate predictions of trial outcomes. Accurately predicting patient enrollment, a key factor in trial success, is one of the primary challenges during the planning phase. In this work, we propose a novel deep learning-based method to address this critical challenge. Our method, implemented as a neural network model, leverages pre-trained language models (PLMs) to capture the complexities and nuances of clinical documents, transforming them into expressive representations. These representations are then combined with encoded tabular features via an attention mechanism. To account for uncertainties in enrollment prediction, we enhance the model with a probabilistic layer based on the Gamma distribution, which enables range estimation. We apply the proposed model to predict clinical trial duration, assuming site-level enrollment follows a Poisson-Gamma process. We carry out extensive experiments on real-world clinical trial data, and show that the proposed method can effectively predict the number of patients enrolled at a number of sites for a given clinical trial, outperforming established baseline models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2507.23607v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tien Huu Do, Antoine Masquelier, Nae Eoun Lee, Jonathan Crowther</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Pixels: Exploring DOM Downsampling for LLM-Based Web Agents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.04412</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.04412v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Frontier LLMs only recently enabled serviceable, autonomous web agents. At that, a model poses as an instantaneous domain model backend. Ought to suggest interaction, it is consulted with a web-based task and respective application state. The key problem lies in application state serialisation - referred to as snapshot. State-of-the-art web agents are premised on grounded GUI snapshots, i.e., screenshots enhanced with visual cues. Not least to resemble human perception, but for images representing relatively cheap means of model input. LLM vision still lag behind code interpretation capabilities. DOM snapshots, which structurally resemble HTML, impose a desired alternative. Vast model input token size, however, disables reliable implementation with web agents to date. We propose D2Snap, a first-of-its-kind DOM downsampling algorithm. Based on a GPT-4o backend, we evaluate D2Snap on tasks sampled from the Online-Mind2Web dataset. The success rate of D2Snap-downsampled DOM snapshots (67%) matches a grounded GUI snapshot baseline (65%) - within the same input token order of magnitude (1e3). Our best evaluated configurations - one token order above, but within the model's context window - outperform this baseline by 8%. Our evaluation, moreover, yields that DOM-inherent hierarchy embodies a strong UI feature for LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.04412v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Thassilo M. Schiepanski, Nicholas Pi\"el</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mano Technical Report</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.17336</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.17336v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Graphical user interfaces (GUIs) are the primary medium for human-computer interaction, yet automating GUI interactions remains challenging due to the complexity of visual elements, dynamic environments, and the need for multi-step reasoning. Existing methods based on vision-language models (VLMs) often suffer from limited resolution, domain mismatch, and insufficient sequential decisionmaking capability. To address these issues, we propose Mano, a robust GUI agent built upon a multi-modal foundation model pre-trained on extensive web and computer system data. Our approach integrates a novel simulated environment for high-fidelity data generation, a three-stage training pipeline (supervised fine-tuning, offline reinforcement learning, and online reinforcement learning), and a verification module for error recovery. Mano demonstrates state-of-the-art performance on multiple GUI benchmarks, including Mind2Web and OSWorld, achieving significant improvements in success rate and operational accuracy. Our work provides new insights into the effective integration of reinforcement learning with VLMs for practical GUI agent deployment, highlighting the importance of domain-specific data, iterative training, and holistic reward design.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.17336v3</guid>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tianyu Fu, Anyang Su, Chenxu Zhao, Hanning Wang, Minghui Wu, Zhe Yu, Fei Hu, Mingjia Shi, Wei Dong, Jiayao Wang, Yuyang Chen, Ruiyang Yu, Siran Peng, Menglin Li, Nan Huang, Haitian Wei, Jiawei Yu, Yi Xin, Xilin Zhao, Kai Gu, Ping Jiang, Sifan Zhou, Shuo Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking Reasoning Capabilities in LLMs via Reinforcement Learning Exploration</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.03865</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.03865v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Reinforcement learning with verifiable rewards (RLVR) has recently enhanced the reasoning capabilities of large language models (LLMs), particularly for mathematical problem solving. However, a fundamental limitation remains: as the sampling budget increases, the advantage of RLVR-trained models over their pretrained bases often diminishes or even vanishes, revealing a strong dependence on the base model's restricted search space. We attribute this phenomenon to the widespread use of the reverse Kullback-Leibler (KL) divergence regularizer, whose mode-seeking behavior keeps the policy trapped inside the base model's support region and hampers wider exploration. To address this issue, we propose RAPO (Rewards-Aware Policy Optimization), an algorithm to promote broader yet focused exploration. Our method (i) utilizes the forward KL penalty to replace the reverse KL penalty for out-of-distribution exploration, and (ii) reweights the reference policy to facilitate adaptive in-distribution exploration. We train Qwen2.5-3B and 7B models with RAPO on the 8K SimpleRL-Zero dataset, without supervised fine-tuning, and evaluate them on AIME2024 and AIME2025. Results show that RAPO consistently improves problem-solving performance. Notably, RAPO enables models to surpass the base model's performance ceiling and solves previously intractable problems, advancing the frontier of RLVR for challenging reasoning tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.03865v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenhao Deng, Long Wei, Chenglei Yu, Tailin Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Normative Reasoning in Large Language Models: A Comparative Benchmark from Logical and Modal Perspectives</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.26606</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.26606v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Normative reasoning is a type of reasoning that involves normative or deontic modality, such as obligation and permission. While large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated remarkable performance across various reasoning tasks, their ability to handle normative reasoning remains underexplored. In this paper, we systematically evaluate LLMs' reasoning capabilities in the normative domain from both logical and modal perspectives. Specifically, to assess how well LLMs reason with normative modals, we make a comparison between their reasoning with normative modals and their reasoning with epistemic modals, which share a common formal structure. To this end, we introduce a new dataset covering a wide range of formal patterns of reasoning in both normative and epistemic domains, while also incorporating non-formal cognitive factors that influence human reasoning. Our results indicate that, although LLMs generally adhere to valid reasoning patterns, they exhibit notable inconsistencies in specific types of normative reasoning and display cognitive biases similar to those observed in psychological studies of human reasoning. These findings highlight challenges in achieving logical consistency in LLMs' normative reasoning and provide insights for enhancing their reliability. All data and code are released publicly at https://github.com/kmineshima/NeuBAROCO.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.26606v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kentaro Ozeki, Risako Ando, Takanobu Morishita, Hirohiko Abe, Koji Mineshima, Mitsuhiro Okada</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
