<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CV updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CV</link>
    <description>cs.CV updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CV" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 05:00:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Sunday</day>
      <day>Saturday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>PHANTOM: PHysical ANamorphic Threats Obstructing Connected Vehicle Mobility</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.19711</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.19711v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Connected autonomous vehicles (CAVs) rely on vision-based deep neural networks (DNNs) and low-latency (Vehicle-to-Everything) V2X communication to navigate safely and efficiently. Despite their advances, these systems remain vulnerable to physical adversarial attacks. In this paper, we introduce PHANTOM (PHysical ANamorphic Threats Obstructing connected vehicle Mobility), a novel framework for crafting and deploying perspective-dependent adversarial examples using \textit{anamorphic art}. PHANTOM exploits geometric distortions that appear natural to humans but are misclassified with high confidence by state-of-the-art object detectors. Unlike conventional attacks, PHANTOM operates in black-box settings without model access and demonstrates strong transferability across four diverse detector architectures (YOLOv5, SSD, Faster R-CNN, and RetinaNet). Comprehensive evaluation in CARLA across varying speeds, weather conditions, and lighting scenarios shows that PHANTOM achieves over 90\% attack success rate under optimal conditions and maintains 60-80\% effectiveness even in degraded environments. The attack activates within 6-10 meters of the target, providing insufficient time for safe maneuvering. Beyond individual vehicle deception, PHANTOM triggers network-wide disruption in CAV systems: SUMO-OMNeT++ co-simulation demonstrates that false emergency messages propagate through V2X links, increasing Peak Age of Information by 68-89\% and degrading safety-critical communication. These findings expose critical vulnerabilities in both perception and communication layers of CAV ecosystems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.19711v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Md Nahid Hasan Shuvo, Moinul Hossain</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generating the Past, Present and Future from a Motion-Blurred Image</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.19817</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.19817v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We seek to answer the question: what can a motion-blurred image reveal about a scene's past, present, and future? Although motion blur obscures image details and degrades visual quality, it also encodes information about scene and camera motion during an exposure. Previous techniques leverage this information to estimate a sharp image from an input blurry one, or to predict a sequence of video frames showing what might have occurred at the moment of image capture. However, they rely on handcrafted priors or network architectures to resolve ambiguities in this inverse problem, and do not incorporate image and video priors on large-scale datasets. As such, existing methods struggle to reproduce complex scene dynamics and do not attempt to recover what occurred before or after an image was taken. Here, we introduce a new technique that repurposes a pre-trained video diffusion model trained on internet-scale datasets to recover videos revealing complex scene dynamics during the moment of capture and what might have occurred immediately into the past or future. Our approach is robust and versatile; it outperforms previous methods for this task, generalizes to challenging in-the-wild images, and supports downstream tasks such as recovering camera trajectories, object motion, and dynamic 3D scene structure. Code and data are available at https://blur2vid.github.io</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.19817v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3763306</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>ACM Trans. Graph. (SIGGRAPH Asia 2025), vol. 44, no. 6, pp. 1-15, Dec. 2025</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>SaiKiran Tedla, Kelly Zhu, Trevor Canham, Felix Taubner, Michael S. Brown, Kiriakos N. Kutulakos, David B. Lindell</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning to Refocus with Video Diffusion Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.19823</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.19823v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Focus is a cornerstone of photography, yet autofocus systems often fail to capture the intended subject, and users frequently wish to adjust focus after capture. We introduce a novel method for realistic post-capture refocusing using video diffusion models. From a single defocused image, our approach generates a perceptually accurate focal stack, represented as a video sequence, enabling interactive refocusing and unlocking a range of downstream applications. We release a large-scale focal stack dataset acquired under diverse real-world smartphone conditions to support this work and future research. Our method consistently outperforms existing approaches in both perceptual quality and robustness across challenging scenarios, paving the way for more advanced focus-editing capabilities in everyday photography. Code and data are available at www.learn2refocus.github.io</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.19823v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3757377.3763873</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>SaiKiran Tedla, Zhoutong Zhang, Xuaner Zhang, Shumian Xin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RANSAC Scoring Functions: Analysis and Reality Check</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.19850</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.19850v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We revisit the problem of assigning a score (a quality of fit) to candidate geometric models -- one of the key components of RANSAC for robust geometric fitting. In a non-robust setting, the ``gold standard'' scoring function, known as the geometric error, follows from a probabilistic model with Gaussian noises. We extend it to spherical noises. In a robust setting, we consider a mixture with uniformly distributed outliers and show that a threshold-based parameterization leads to a unified view of likelihood-based and robust M-estimators and associated local optimization schemes.
  Next we analyze MAGSAC++ which stands out for two reasons. First, it achieves the best results according to existing benchmarks. Second, it makes quite different modeling assumptions and derivation steps. We discovered, however that the derivation does not correspond to sound principles and the resulting score function is in fact numerically equivalent to a simple Gaussian-uniform likelihood, a basic model within the proposed framework.
  Finally, we propose an experimental methodology for evaluating scoring functions: assuming either a large validation set, or a small random validation set in expectation. We find that all scoring functions, including using a learned inlier distribution, perform identically. In particular, MAGSAC++ score is found to be neither better performing than simple contenders nor less sensitive to the choice of the threshold hyperparameter.
  Our theoretical and experimental analysis thus comprehensively revisit the state-of-the-art, which is critical for any future research seeking to improve the methods or apply them to other robust fitting problems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.19850v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>stat.AP</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>A. Shekhovtsov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HyGE-Occ: Hybrid View-Transformation with 3D Gaussian and Edge Priors for 3D Panoptic Occupancy Prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.19871</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.19871v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: 3D Panoptic Occupancy Prediction aims to reconstruct a dense volumetric scene map by predicting the semantic class and instance identity of every occupied region in 3D space. Achieving such fine-grained 3D understanding requires precise geometric reasoning and spatially consistent scene representation across complex environments. However, existing approaches often struggle to maintain precise geometry and capture the precise spatial range of 3D instances critical for robust panoptic separation. To overcome these limitations, we introduce HyGE-Occ, a novel framework that leverages a hybrid view-transformation branch with 3D Gaussian and edge priors to enhance both geometric consistency and boundary awareness in 3D panoptic occupancy prediction. HyGE-Occ employs a hybrid view-transformation branch that fuses a continuous Gaussian-based depth representation with a discretized depth-bin formulation, producing BEV features with improved geometric consistency and structural coherence. In parallel, we extract edge maps from BEV features and use them as auxiliary information to learn edge cues. In our extensive experiments on the Occ3D-nuScenes dataset, HyGE-Occ outperforms existing work, demonstrating superior 3D geometric reasoning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.19871v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jong Wook Kim, Wonseok Roh, Ha Dam Baek, Pilhyeon Lee, Jonghyun Choi, Sangpil Kim</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Widget2Code: From Visual Widgets to UI Code via Multimodal LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.19918</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.19918v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: User interface to code (UI2Code) aims to generate executable code that can faithfully reconstruct a given input UI. Prior work focuses largely on web pages and mobile screens, leaving app widgets underexplored. Unlike web or mobile UIs with rich hierarchical context, widgets are compact, context-free micro-interfaces that summarize key information through dense layouts and iconography under strict spatial constraints. Moreover, while (image, code) pairs are widely available for web or mobile UIs, widget designs are proprietary and lack accessible markup. We formalize this setting as the Widget-to-Code (Widget2Code) and introduce an image-only widget benchmark with fine-grained, multi-dimensional evaluation metrics. Benchmarking shows that although generalized multimodal large language models (MLLMs) outperform specialized UI2Code methods, they still produce unreliable and visually inconsistent code. To address these limitations, we develop a baseline that jointly advances perceptual understanding and structured code generation. At the perceptual level, we follow widget design principles to assemble atomic components into complete layouts, equipped with icon retrieval and reusable visualization modules. At the system level, we design an end-to-end infrastructure, WidgetFactory, which includes a framework-agnostic widget-tailored domain-specific language (WidgetDSL) and a compiler that translates it into multiple front-end implementations (e.g., React, HTML/CSS). An adaptive rendering module further refines spatial dimensions to satisfy compactness constraints. Together, these contributions substantially enhance visual fidelity, establishing a strong baseline and unified infrastructure for future Widget2Code research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.19918v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Houston H. Zhang, Tao Zhang, Baoze Lin, Yuanqi Xue, Yincheng Zhu, Huan Liu, Li Gu, Linfeng Ye, Ziqiang Wang, Xinxin Zuo, Yang Wang, Yuanhao Yu, Zhixiang Chi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unified Brain Surface and Volume Registration</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.19928</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.19928v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Accurate registration of brain MRI scans is fundamental for cross-subject analysis in neuroscientific studies. This involves aligning both the cortical surface of the brain and the interior volume. Traditional methods treat volumetric and surface-based registration separately, which often leads to inconsistencies that limit downstream analyses. We propose a deep learning framework, NeurAlign, that registers $3$D brain MRI images by jointly aligning both cortical and subcortical regions through a unified volume-and-surface-based representation. Our approach leverages an intermediate spherical coordinate space to bridge anatomical surface topology with volumetric anatomy, enabling consistent and anatomically accurate alignment. By integrating spherical registration into the learning, our method ensures geometric coherence between volume and surface domains. In a series of experiments on both in-domain and out-of-domain datasets, our method consistently outperforms both classical and machine learning-based registration methods -- improving the Dice score by up to 7 points while maintaining regular deformation fields. Additionally, it is orders of magnitude faster than the standard method for this task, and is simpler to use because it requires no additional inputs beyond an MRI scan. With its superior accuracy, fast inference, and ease of use, NeurAlign sets a new standard for joint cortical and subcortical registration.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.19928v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>S. Mazdak Abulnaga, Andrew Hoopes, Malte Hoffmann, Robin Magnet, Maks Ovsjanikov, Lilla Z\"ollei, John Guttag, Bruce Fischl, Adrian Dalca</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vehicle-centric Perception via Multimodal Structured Pre-training</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.19934</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.19934v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Vehicle-centric perception plays a crucial role in many intelligent systems, including large-scale surveillance systems, intelligent transportation, and autonomous driving. Existing approaches lack effective learning of vehicle-related knowledge during pre-training, resulting in poor capability for modeling general vehicle perception representations. To handle this problem, we propose VehicleMAE-V2, a novel vehicle-centric pre-trained large model. By exploring and exploiting vehicle-related multimodal structured priors to guide the masked token reconstruction process, our approach can significantly enhance the model's capability to learn generalizable representations for vehicle-centric perception. Specifically, we design the Symmetry-guided Mask Module (SMM), Contour-guided Representation Module (CRM) and Semantics-guided Representation Module (SRM) to incorporate three kinds of structured priors into token reconstruction including symmetry, contour and semantics of vehicles respectively. SMM utilizes the vehicle symmetry constraints to avoid retaining symmetric patches and can thus select high-quality masked image patches and reduce information redundancy. CRM minimizes the probability distribution divergence between contour features and reconstructed features and can thus preserve holistic vehicle structure information during pixel-level reconstruction. SRM aligns image-text features through contrastive learning and cross-modal distillation to address the feature confusion caused by insufficient semantic understanding during masked reconstruction. To support the pre-training of VehicleMAE-V2, we construct Autobot4M, a large-scale dataset comprising approximately 4 million vehicle images and 12,693 text descriptions. Extensive experiments on five downstream tasks demonstrate the superior performance of VehicleMAE-V2.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.19934v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wentao Wu, Xiao Wang, Chenglong Li, Jin Tang, Bin Luo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Block-Recurrent Dynamics in Vision Transformers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.19941</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.19941v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: As Vision Transformers (ViTs) become standard vision backbones, a mechanistic account of their computational phenomenology is essential. Despite architectural cues that hint at dynamical structure, there is no settled framework that interprets Transformer depth as a well-characterized flow. In this work, we introduce the Block-Recurrent Hypothesis (BRH), arguing that trained ViTs admit a block-recurrent depth structure such that the computation of the original $L$ blocks can be accurately rewritten using only $k \ll L$ distinct blocks applied recurrently. Across diverse ViTs, between-layer representational similarity matrices suggest few contiguous phases. To determine whether these phases reflect genuinely reusable computation, we train block-recurrent surrogates of pretrained ViTs: Recurrent Approximations to Phase-structured TransfORmers (Raptor). In small-scale, we demonstrate that stochastic depth and training promote recurrent structure and subsequently correlate with our ability to accurately fit Raptor. We then provide an empirical existence proof for BRH by training a Raptor model to recover $96\%$ of DINOv2 ImageNet-1k linear probe accuracy in only 2 blocks at equivalent computational cost. Finally, we leverage our hypothesis to develop a program of Dynamical Interpretability. We find i) directional convergence into class-dependent angular basins with self-correcting trajectories under small perturbations, ii) token-specific dynamics, where cls executes sharp late reorientations while patch tokens exhibit strong late-stage coherence toward their mean direction, and iii) a collapse to low rank updates in late depth, consistent with convergence to low-dimensional attractors. Altogether, we find a compact recurrent program emerges along ViT depth, pointing to a low-complexity normative solution that enables these models to be studied through principled dynamical systems analysis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.19941v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mozes Jacobs, Thomas Fel, Richard Hakim, Alessandra Brondetta, Demba Ba, T. Andy Keller</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SE360: Semantic Edit in 360$^\circ$ Panoramas via Hierarchical Data Construction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.19943</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.19943v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: While instruction-based image editing is emerging, extending it to 360$^\circ$ panoramas introduces additional challenges. Existing methods often produce implausible results in both equirectangular projections (ERP) and perspective views. To address these limitations, we propose SE360, a novel framework for multi-condition guided object editing in 360$^\circ$ panoramas. At its core is a novel coarse-to-fine autonomous data generation pipeline without manual intervention. This pipeline leverages a Vision-Language Model (VLM) and adaptive projection adjustment for hierarchical analysis, ensuring the holistic segmentation of objects and their physical context. The resulting data pairs are both semantically meaningful and geometrically consistent, even when sourced from unlabeled panoramas. Furthermore, we introduce a cost-effective, two-stage data refinement strategy to improve data realism and mitigate model overfitting to erase artifacts. Based on the constructed dataset, we train a Transformer-based diffusion model to allow flexible object editing guided by text, mask, or reference image in 360$^\circ$ panoramas. Our experiments demonstrate that our method outperforms existing methods in both visual quality and semantic accuracy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.19943v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haoyi Zhong, Fang-Lue Zhang, Andrew Chalmers, Taehyun Rhee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Much 3D Do Video Foundation Models Encode?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.19949</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.19949v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Videos are continuous 2D projections of 3D worlds. After training on large video data, will global 3D understanding naturally emerge? We study this by quantifying the 3D understanding of existing Video Foundation Models (VidFMs) pretrained on vast video data. We propose the first model-agnostic framework that measures the 3D awareness of various VidFMs by estimating multiple 3D properties from their features via shallow read-outs. Our study presents meaningful findings regarding the 3D awareness of VidFMs on multiple axes. In particular, we show that state-of-the-art video generation models exhibit a strong understanding of 3D objects and scenes, despite not being trained on any 3D data. Such understanding can even surpass that of large expert models specifically trained for 3D tasks. Our findings, together with the 3D benchmarking of major VidFMs, provide valuable observations for building scalable 3D models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.19949v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zixuan Huang, Xiang Li, Zhaoyang Lv, James M. Rehg</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HistoWAS: A Pathomics Framework for Large-Scale Feature-Wide Association Studies of Tissue Topology and Patient Outcomes</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.19954</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.19954v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: High-throughput "pathomic" analysis of Whole Slide Images (WSIs) offers new opportunities to study tissue characteristics and for biomarker discovery. However, the clinical relevance of the tissue characteristics at the micro- and macro-environment level is limited by the lack of tools that facilitate the measurement of the spatial interaction of individual structure characteristics and their association with clinical parameters. To address these challenges, we introduce HistoWAS (Histology-Wide Association Study), a computational framework designed to link tissue spatial organization to clinical outcomes. Specifically, HistoWAS implements (1) a feature space that augments conventional metrics with 30 topological and spatial features, adapted from Geographic Information Systems (GIS) point pattern analysis, to quantify tissue micro-architecture; and (2) an association study engine, inspired by Phenome-Wide Association Studies (PheWAS), that performs mass univariate regression for each feature with statistical correction. As a proof of concept, we applied HistoWAS to analyze a total of 102 features (72 conventional object-level features and our 30 spatial features) using 385 PAS-stained WSIs from 206 participants in the Kidney Precision Medicine Project (KPMP). The code and data have been released to https://github.com/hrlblab/histoWAS.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.19954v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuechen Yang, Junlin Guo, Yanfan Zhu, Jialin Yue, Junchao Zhu, Yu Wang, Shilin Zhao, Haichun Yang, Xingyi Guo, Jovan Tanevski, Laura Barisoni, Avi Z. Rosenberg, Yuankai Huo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WSD-MIL: Window Scale Decay Multiple Instance Learning for Whole Slide Image Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.19982</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.19982v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In recent years, the integration of pre-trained foundational models with multiple instance learning (MIL) has improved diagnostic accuracy in computational pathology. However, existing MIL methods focus on optimizing feature extractors and aggregation strategies while overlooking the complex semantic relationships among instances within whole slide image (WSI). Although Transformer-based MIL approaches aiming to model instance dependencies, the quadratic computational complexity limits their scalability to large-scale WSIs. Moreover, due to the pronounced variations in tumor region scales across different WSIs, existing Transformer-based methods employing fixed-scale attention mechanisms face significant challenges in precisely capturing local instance correlations and fail to account for the distance-based decay effect of patch relevance. To address these challenges, we propose window scale decay MIL (WSD-MIL), designed to enhance the capacity to model tumor regions of varying scales while improving computational efficiency. WSD-MIL comprises: 1) a window scale decay based attention module, which employs a cluster-based sampling strategy to reduce computational costs while progressively decaying attention window-scale to capture local instance relationships at varying scales; and 2) a squeeze-and-excitation based region gate module, which dynamically adjusts window weights to enhance global information modeling. Experimental results demonstrate that WSD-MIL achieves state-of-the-art performance on the CAMELYON16 and TCGA-BRCA datasets while reducing 62% of the computational memory. The code will be publicly available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.19982v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Le Feng, Li Xiao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Novel CNN Gradient Boosting Ensemble for Guava Disease Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.19989</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.19989v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: As a significant agricultural country, Bangladesh utilizes its fertile land for guava cultivation and dedicated labor to boost its economic development. In a nation like Bangladesh, enhancing guava production and agricultural practices plays a crucial role in its economy. Anthracnose and fruit fly infection can lower the quality and productivity of guava, a crucial tropical fruit. Expert systems that detect diseases early can reduce losses and safeguard the harvest. Images of guava fruits classified into the Healthy, Fruit Flies, and Anthracnose classes are included in the Guava Fruit Disease Dataset 2024 (GFDD24), which comes from plantations in Rajshahi and Pabna, Bangladesh. This study aims to create models using CNN alongside traditional machine learning techniques that can effectively identify guava diseases in locally cultivated varieties in Bangladesh. In order to achieve the highest classification accuracy of approximately 99.99% for the guava dataset, we propose utilizing ensemble models that combine CNNML with Gradient Boosting Machine. In general, the CNN-ML cascade framework exhibits strong, high-accuracy guava disease detection that is appropriate for real-time agricultural monitoring systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.19989v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tamim Ahasan Rijon, Yeasin Arafath</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Dual-Branch Local-Global Framework for Cross-Resolution Land Cover Mapping</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.19990</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.19990v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Cross-resolution land cover mapping aims to produce high-resolution semantic predictions from coarse or low-resolution supervision, yet the severe resolution mismatch makes effective learning highly challenging. Existing weakly supervised approaches often struggle to align fine-grained spatial structures with coarse labels, leading to noisy supervision and degraded mapping accuracy. To tackle this problem, we propose DDTM, a dual-branch weakly supervised framework that explicitly decouples local semantic refinement from global contextual reasoning. Specifically, DDTM introduces a diffusion-based branch to progressively refine fine-scale local semantics under coarse supervision, while a transformer-based branch enforces long-range contextual consistency across large spatial extents. In addition, we design a pseudo-label confidence evaluation module to mitigate noise induced by cross-resolution inconsistencies and to selectively exploit reliable supervisory signals. Extensive experiments demonstrate that DDTM establishes a new state-of-the-art on the Chesapeake Bay benchmark, achieving 66.52\% mIoU and substantially outperforming prior weakly supervised methods. The code is available at https://github.com/gpgpgp123/DDTM.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.19990v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Peng Gao, Ke Li, Di Wang, Yongshan Zhu, Yiming Zhang, Xuemei Luo, Yifeng Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Few-Shot-Based Modular Image-to-Video Adapter for Diffusion Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20000</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20000v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Diffusion models (DMs) have recently achieved impressive photorealism in image and video generation. However, their application to image animation remains limited, even when trained on large-scale datasets. Two primary challenges contribute to this: the high dimensionality of video signals leads to a scarcity of training data, causing DMs to favor memorization over prompt compliance when generating motion; moreover, DMs struggle to generalize to novel motion patterns not present in the training set, and fine-tuning them to learn such patterns, especially using limited training data, is still under-explored. To address these limitations, we propose Modular Image-to-Video Adapter (MIVA), a lightweight sub-network attachable to a pre-trained DM, each designed to capture a single motion pattern and scalable via parallelization. MIVAs can be efficiently trained on approximately ten samples using a single consumer-grade GPU. At inference time, users can specify motion by selecting one or multiple MIVAs, eliminating the need for prompt engineering. Extensive experiments demonstrate that MIVA enables more precise motion control while maintaining, or even surpassing, the generation quality of models trained on significantly larger datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20000v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhenhao Li, Shaohan Yi, Zheng Liu, Leonartinus Gao, Minh Ngoc Le, Ambrose Ling, Zhuoran Wang, Md Amirul Islam, Zhixiang Chi, Yuanhao Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PaveSync: A Unified and Comprehensive Dataset for Pavement Distress Analysis and Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20011</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20011v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Automated pavement defect detection often struggles to generalize across diverse real-world conditions due to the lack of standardized datasets. Existing datasets differ in annotation styles, distress type definitions, and formats, limiting their integration for unified training. To address this gap, we introduce a comprehensive benchmark dataset that consolidates multiple publicly available sources into a standardized collection of 52747 images from seven countries, with 135277 bounding box annotations covering 13 distinct distress types. The dataset captures broad real-world variation in image quality, resolution, viewing angles, and weather conditions, offering a unique resource for consistent training and evaluation. Its effectiveness was demonstrated through benchmarking with state-of-the-art object detection models including YOLOv8-YOLOv12, Faster R-CNN, and DETR, which achieved competitive performance across diverse scenarios. By standardizing class definitions and annotation formats, this dataset provides the first globally representative benchmark for pavement defect detection and enables fair comparison of models, including zero-shot transfer to new environments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20011v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Blessing Agyei Kyem, Joshua Kofi Asamoah, Anthony Dontoh, Andrews Danyo, Eugene Denteh, Armstrong Aboah</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SegEarth-R2: Towards Comprehensive Language-guided Segmentation for Remote Sensing Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20013</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20013v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Effectively grounding complex language to pixels in remote sensing (RS) images is a critical challenge for applications like disaster response and environmental monitoring. Current models can parse simple, single-target commands but fail when presented with complex geospatial scenarios, e.g., segmenting objects at various granularities, executing multi-target instructions, and interpreting implicit user intent. To drive progress against these failures, we present LaSeRS, the first large-scale dataset built for comprehensive training and evaluation across four critical dimensions of language-guided segmentation: hierarchical granularity, target multiplicity, reasoning requirements, and linguistic variability. By capturing these dimensions, LaSeRS moves beyond simple commands, providing a benchmark for complex geospatial reasoning. This addresses a critical gap: existing datasets oversimplify, leading to sensitivity-prone real-world models. We also propose SegEarth-R2, an MLLM architecture designed for comprehensive language-guided segmentation in RS, which directly confronts these challenges. The model's effectiveness stems from two key improvements: (1) a spatial attention supervision mechanism specifically handles the localization of small objects and their components, and (2) a flexible and efficient segmentation query mechanism that handles both single-target and multi-target scenarios. Experimental results demonstrate that our SegEarth-R2 achieves outstanding performance on LaSeRS and other benchmarks, establishing a powerful baseline for the next generation of geospatial segmentation. All data and code will be released at https://github.com/earth-insights/SegEarth-R2.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20013v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zepeng Xin, Kaiyu Li, Luodi Chen, Wanchen Li, Yuchen Xiao, Hui Qiao, Weizhan Zhang, Deyu Meng, Xiangyong Cao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Contextual Analysis of Driver-Facing and Dual-View Video Inputs for Distraction Detection in Naturalistic Driving Environments</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20025</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20025v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Despite increasing interest in computer vision-based distracted driving detection, most existing models rely exclusively on driver-facing views and overlook crucial environmental context that influences driving behavior. This study investigates whether incorporating road-facing views alongside driver-facing footage improves distraction detection accuracy in naturalistic driving conditions. Using synchronized dual-camera recordings from real-world driving, we benchmark three leading spatiotemporal action recognition architectures: SlowFast-R50, X3D-M, and SlowOnly-R50. Each model is evaluated under two input configurations: driver-only and stacked dual-view. Results show that while contextual inputs can improve detection in certain models, performance gains depend strongly on the underlying architecture. The single-pathway SlowOnly model achieved a 9.8 percent improvement with dual-view inputs, while the dual-pathway SlowFast model experienced a 7.2 percent drop in accuracy due to representational conflicts. These findings suggest that simply adding visual context is not sufficient and may lead to interference unless the architecture is specifically designed to support multi-view integration. This study presents one of the first systematic comparisons of single- and dual-view distraction detection models using naturalistic driving data and underscores the importance of fusion-aware design for future multimodal driver monitoring systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20025v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Anthony Dontoh, Stephanie Ivey, Armstrong Aboah</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MAPI-GNN: Multi-Activation Plane Interaction Graph Neural Network for Multimodal Medical Diagnosis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20026</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20026v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Graph neural networks are increasingly applied to multimodal medical diagnosis for their inherent relational modeling capabilities. However, their efficacy is often compromised by the prevailing reliance on a single, static graph built from indiscriminate features, hindering the ability to model patient-specific pathological relationships. To this end, the proposed Multi-Activation Plane Interaction Graph Neural Network (MAPI-GNN) reconstructs this single-graph paradigm by learning a multifaceted graph profile from semantically disentangled feature subspaces. The framework first uncovers latent graph-aware patterns via a multi-dimensional discriminator; these patterns then guide the dynamic construction of a stack of activation graphs; and this multifaceted profile is finally aggregated and contextualized by a relational fusion engine for a robust diagnosis. Extensive experiments on two diverse tasks, comprising over 1300 patient samples, demonstrate that MAPI-GNN significantly outperforms state-of-the-art methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20026v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ziwei Qin, Xuhui Song, Deqing Huang, Na Qin, Jun Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>$\text{H}^2$em: Learning Hierarchical Hyperbolic Embeddings for Compositional Zero-Shot Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20029</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20029v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Compositional zero-shot learning (CZSL) aims to recognize unseen state-object compositions by generalizing from a training set of their primitives (state and object). Current methods often overlook the rich hierarchical structures, such as the semantic hierarchy of primitives (e.g., apple fruit) and the conceptual hierarchy between primitives and compositions (e.g, sliced apple apple). A few recent efforts have shown effectiveness in modeling these hierarchies through loss regularization within Euclidean space. In this paper, we argue that they fail to scale to the large-scale taxonomies required for real-world CZSL: the space's polynomial volume growth in flat geometry cannot match the exponential structure, impairing generalization capacity. To this end, we propose H2em, a new framework that learns Hierarchical Hyperbolic EMbeddings for CZSL. H2em leverages the unique properties of hyperbolic geometry, a space naturally suited for embedding tree-like structures with low distortion. However, a naive hyperbolic mapping may suffer from hierarchical collapse and poor fine-grained discrimination. We further design two learning objectives to structure this space: a Dual-Hierarchical Entailment Loss that uses hyperbolic entailment cones to enforce the predefined hierarchies, and a Discriminative Alignment Loss with hard negative mining to establish a large geodesic distance between semantically similar compositions. Furthermore, we devise Hyperbolic Cross-Modal Attention to realize instance-aware cross-modal infusion within hyperbolic geometry. Extensive ablations on three benchmarks demonstrate that H2em establishes a new state-of-the-art in both closed-world and open-world scenarios. Our codes will be released.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20029v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lin Li, Jiahui Li, Jiaming Lei, Jun Xiao, Feifei Shao, Long Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VALLR-Pin: Dual-Decoding Visual Speech Recognition for Mandarin with Pinyin-Guided LLM Refinement</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20032</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20032v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Visual Speech Recognition aims to transcribe spoken words from silent lip-motion videos. This task is particularly challenging for Mandarin, as visemes are highly ambiguous and homophones are prevalent. We propose VALLR-Pin, a novel two-stage framework that extends the recent VALLR architecture from English to Mandarin. First, a shared video encoder feeds into dual decoders, which jointly predict both Chinese character sequences and their standard Pinyin romanization. The multi-task learning of character and phonetic outputs fosters robust visual-semantic representations. During inference, the text decoder generates multiple candidate transcripts. We construct a prompt by concatenating the Pinyin output with these candidate Chinese sequences and feed it to a large language model to resolve ambiguities and refine the transcription. This provides the LLM with explicit phonetic context to correct homophone-induced errors. Finally, we fine-tune the LLM on synthetic noisy examples: we generate imperfect Pinyin-text pairs from intermediate VALLR-Pin checkpoints using the training data, creating instruction-response pairs for error correction. This endows the LLM with awareness of our model's specific error patterns. In summary, VALLR-Pin synergizes visual features with phonetic and linguistic context to improve Mandarin lip-reading performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20032v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chang Sun, Dongliang Xie, Bo Qin, Hong Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FlashLips: 100-FPS Mask-Free Latent Lip-Sync using Reconstruction Instead of Diffusion or GANs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20033</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20033v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present FlashLips, a two-stage, mask-free lip-sync system that decouples lips control from rendering and achieves real-time performance running at over 100 FPS on a single GPU, while matching the visual quality of larger state-of-the-art models. Stage 1 is a compact, one-step latent-space editor that reconstructs an image using a reference identity, a masked target frame, and a low-dimensional lips-pose vector, trained purely with reconstruction losses - no GANs or diffusion. To remove explicit masks at inference, we use self-supervision: we generate mouth-altered variants of the target image, that serve as pseudo ground truth for fine-tuning, teaching the network to localize edits to the lips while preserving the rest. Stage 2 is an audio-to-pose transformer trained with a flow-matching objective to predict lips-poses vectors from speech. Together, these stages form a simple and stable pipeline that combines deterministic reconstruction with robust audio control, delivering high perceptual quality and faster-than-real-time speed.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20033v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Andreas Zinonos, Micha{\l} Stypu{\l}kowski, Antoni Bigata, Stavros Petridis, Maja Pantic, Nikita Drobyshev</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Vision: Contextually Enriched Image Captioning with Multi-Modal Retrieva</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20042</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20042v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Real-world image captions often lack contextual depth, omitting crucial details such as event background, temporal cues, outcomes, and named entities that are not visually discernible. This gap limits the effectiveness of image understanding in domains like journalism, education, and digital archives, where richer, more informative descriptions are essential. To address this, we propose a multimodal pipeline that augments visual input with external textual knowledge. Our system retrieves semantically similar images using BEIT-3 (Flickr30k-384 and COCO-384) and SigLIP So-384, reranks them using ORB and SIFT for geometric alignment, and extracts contextual information from related articles via semantic search. A fine-tuned Qwen3 model with QLoRA then integrates this context with base captions generated by Instruct BLIP (Vicuna-7B) to produce event-enriched, context-aware descriptions. Evaluated on the OpenEvents v1 dataset, our approach generates significantly more informative captions compared to traditional methods, showing strong potential for real-world applications requiring deeper visual-textual understanding</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20042v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nguyen Lam Phu Quy, Pham Phu Hoa, Tran Chi Nguyen, Dao Sy Duy Minh, Nguyen Hoang Minh Ngoc, Huynh Trung Kiet</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progressive Learned Image Compression for Machine Perception</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20070</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20070v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent advances in learned image codecs have been extended from human perception toward machine perception. However, progressive image compression with fine granular scalability (FGS)-which enables decoding a single bitstream at multiple quality levels-remains unexplored for machine-oriented codecs. In this work, we propose a novel progressive learned image compression codec for machine perception, PICM-Net, based on trit-plane coding. By analyzing the difference between human- and machine-oriented rate-distortion priorities, we systematically examine the latent prioritization strategies in terms of machine-oriented codecs. To further enhance real-world adaptability, we design an adaptive decoding controller, which dynamically determines the necessary decoding level during inference time to maintain the desired confidence of downstream machine prediction. Extensive experiments demonstrate that our approach enables efficient and adaptive progressive transmission while maintaining high performance in the downstream classification task, establishing a new paradigm for machine-aware progressive image compression.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20070v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jungwoo Kim, Jun-Hyuk Kim, Jong-Seok Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Item Region-based Style Classification Network (IRSN): A Fashion Style Classifier Based on Domain Knowledge of Fashion Experts</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20088</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20088v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Fashion style classification is a challenging task because of the large visual variation within the same style and the existence of visually similar styles.
  Styles are expressed not only by the global appearance, but also by the attributes of individual items and their combinations.
  In this study, we propose an item region-based fashion style classification network (IRSN) to effectively classify fashion styles by analyzing item-specific features and their combinations in addition to global features.
  IRSN extracts features of each item region using item region pooling (IRP), analyzes them separately, and combines them using gated feature fusion (GFF).
  In addition, we improve the feature extractor by applying a dual-backbone architecture that combines a domain-specific feature extractor and a general feature extractor pre-trained with a large-scale image-text dataset.
  In experiments, applying IRSN to six widely-used backbones, including EfficientNet, ConvNeXt, and Swin Transformer, improved style classification accuracy by an average of 6.9% and a maximum of 14.5% on the FashionStyle14 dataset and by an average of 7.6% and a maximum of 15.1% on the ShowniqV3 dataset. Visualization analysis also supports that the IRSN models are better than the baseline models at capturing differences between similar style classes.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20088v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1007/s10489-024-05683-9</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Applied Intelligence, Vol. 54, pp. 6197-6209 (2024)</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Jinyoung Choi, Youngchae Kwon, Injung Kim</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Activation Function and Model Optimizer on the Performance of Human Activity Recognition System Using Various Deep Learning Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20104</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20104v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Human Activity Recognition (HAR) plays a vital role in healthcare, surveillance, and innovative environments, where reliable action recognition supports timely decision-making and automation. Although deep learning-based HAR systems are widely adopted, the impact of Activation Functions (AFs) and Model Optimizers (MOs) on performance has not been sufficiently analyzed, particularly regarding how their combinations influence model behavior in practical scenarios. Most existing studies focus on architecture design, while the interaction between AF and MO choices remains relatively unexplored. In this work, we investigate the effect of three commonly used activation functions (ReLU, Sigmoid, and Tanh) combined with four optimization algorithms (SGD, Adam, RMSprop, and Adagrad) using two recurrent deep learning architectures, namely BiLSTM and ConvLSTM. Experiments are conducted on six medically relevant activity classes selected from the HMDB51 and UCF101 datasets, considering their suitability for healthcare-oriented HAR applications. Our experimental results show that ConvLSTM consistently outperforms BiLSTM across both datasets. ConvLSTM, combined with Adam or RMSprop, achieves an accuracy of up to 99.00%, demonstrating strong spatio-temporal learning capabilities and stable performance. While BiLSTM performs reasonably well on UCF101, with accuracy approaching 98.00%, its performance drops to approximately 60.00% on HMDB51, indicating limited robustness across datasets and weaker sensitivity to AF and MO variations. This study provides practical insights for optimizing HAR systems, particularly for real-world healthcare environments where fast and precise activity detection is critical.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20104v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Subrata Kumer Paula, Dewan Nafiul Islam Noora, Rakhi Rani Paula, Md. Ekramul Hamidb, Fahmid Al Faridc, Hezerul Abdul Karimd, Md. Maruf Al Hossain Princee, Abu Saleh Musa Miahb</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LiDARDraft: Generating LiDAR Point Cloud from Versatile Inputs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20105</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20105v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Generating realistic and diverse LiDAR point clouds is crucial for autonomous driving simulation. Although previous methods achieve LiDAR point cloud generation from user inputs, they struggle to attain high-quality results while enabling versatile controllability, due to the imbalance between the complex distribution of LiDAR point clouds and the simple control signals. To address the limitation, we propose LiDARDraft, which utilizes the 3D layout to build a bridge between versatile conditional signals and LiDAR point clouds. The 3D layout can be trivially generated from various user inputs such as textual descriptions and images. Specifically, we represent text, images, and point clouds as unified 3D layouts, which are further transformed into semantic and depth control signals. Then, we employ a rangemap-based ControlNet to guide LiDAR point cloud generation. This pixel-level alignment approach demonstrates excellent performance in controllable LiDAR point clouds generation, enabling "simulation from scratch", allowing self-driving environments to be created from arbitrary textual descriptions, images and sketches.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20105v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haiyun Wei, Fan Lu, Yunwei Zhu, Zehan Zheng, Weiyi Xue, Lin Shao, Xudong Zhang, Ya Wu, Rong Fu, Guang Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UMAMI: Unifying Masked Autoregressive Models and Deterministic Rendering for View Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20107</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20107v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Novel view synthesis (NVS) seeks to render photorealistic, 3D-consistent images of a scene from unseen camera poses given only a sparse set of posed views. Existing deterministic networks render observed regions quickly but blur unobserved areas, whereas stochastic diffusion-based methods hallucinate plausible content yet incur heavy training- and inference-time costs. In this paper, we propose a hybrid framework that unifies the strengths of both paradigms. A bidirectional transformer encodes multi-view image tokens and Plucker-ray embeddings, producing a shared latent representation. Two lightweight heads then act on this representation: (i) a feed-forward regression head that renders pixels where geometry is well constrained, and (ii) a masked autoregressive diffusion head that completes occluded or unseen regions. The entire model is trained end-to-end with joint photometric and diffusion losses, without handcrafted 3D inductive biases, enabling scalability across diverse scenes. Experiments demonstrate that our method attains state-of-the-art image quality while reducing rendering time by an order of magnitude compared with fully generative baselines.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20107v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Thanh-Tung Le, Tuan Pham, Tung Nguyen, Deying Kong, Xiaohui Xie, Stephan Mandt</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi Modal Attention Networks with Uncertainty Quantification for Automated Concrete Bridge Deck Delamination Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20113</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20113v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Deteriorating civil infrastructure requires automated inspection techniques overcoming limitations of visual assessment. While Ground Penetrating Radar and Infrared Thermography enable subsurface defect detection, single modal approaches face complementary constraints radar struggles with moisture and shallow defects, while thermography exhibits weather dependency and limited depth. This paper presents a multi modal attention network fusing radar temporal patterns with thermal spatial signatures for bridge deck delamination detection. Our architecture introduces temporal attention for radar processing, spatial attention for thermal features, and cross modal fusion with learnable embeddings discovering complementary defect patterns invisible to individual sensors. We incorporate uncertainty quantification through Monte Carlo dropout and learned variance estimation, decomposing uncertainty into epistemic and aleatoric components for safety critical decisions. Experiments on five bridge datasets reveal that on balanced to moderately imbalanced data, our approach substantially outperforms baselines in accuracy and AUC representing meaningful improvements over single modal and concatenation based fusion. Ablation studies demonstrate cross modal attention provides critical gains beyond within modality attention, while multi head mechanisms achieve improved calibration. Uncertainty quantification reduces calibration error, enabling selective prediction by rejecting uncertain cases. However, under extreme class imbalance, attention mechanisms show vulnerability to majority class collapse. These findings provide actionable guidance: attention based architecture performs well across typical scenarios, while extreme imbalance requires specialized techniques. Our system maintains deployment efficiency, enabling real time inspection with characterized capabilities and limitations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20113v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alireza Moayedikia, Sattar Dorafshan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DDAVS: Disentangled Audio Semantics and Delayed Bidirectional Alignment for Audio-Visual Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20117</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20117v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Audio-Visual Segmentation (AVS) aims to localize sound-producing objects at the pixel level by jointly leveraging auditory and visual information. However, existing methods often suffer from multi-source entanglement and audio-visual misalignment, which lead to biases toward louder or larger objects while overlooking weaker, smaller, or co-occurring sources. To address these challenges, we propose DDAVS, a Disentangled Audio Semantics and Delayed Bidirectional Alignment framework. To mitigate multi-source entanglement, DDAVS employs learnable queries to extract audio semantics and anchor them within a structured semantic space derived from an audio prototype memory bank. This is further optimized through contrastive learning to enhance discriminability and robustness. To alleviate audio-visual misalignment, DDAVS introduces dual cross-attention with delayed modality interaction, improving the robustness of multimodal alignment. Extensive experiments on the AVS-Objects and VPO benchmarks demonstrate that DDAVS consistently outperforms existing approaches, exhibiting strong performance across single-source, multi-source, and multi-instance scenarios. These results validate the effectiveness and generalization ability of our framework under challenging real-world audio-visual segmentation conditions. Project page: https://trilarflagz.github.io/DDAVS-page/</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20117v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jingqi Tian, Yiheng Du, Haoji Zhang, Yuji Wang, Isaac Ning Lee, Xulong Bai, Tianrui Zhu, Jingxuan Niu, Yansong Tang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HEART-VIT: Hessian-Guided Efficient Dynamic Attention and Token Pruning in Vision Transformer</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20120</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20120v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Vision Transformers (ViTs) deliver state-of-the-art accuracy but their quadratic attention cost and redundant computations severely hinder deployment on latency and resource-constrained platforms. Existing pruning approaches treat either tokens or heads in isolation, relying on heuristics or first-order signals, which often sacrifice accuracy or fail to generalize across inputs. We introduce HEART-ViT, a Hessian-guided efficient dynamic attention and token pruning framework for vision transformers, which to the best of our knowledge is the first unified, second-order, input-adaptive framework for ViT optimization. HEART-ViT estimates curvature-weighted sensitivities of both tokens and attention heads using efficient Hessian-vector products, enabling principled pruning decisions under explicit loss budgets.This dual-view sensitivity reveals an important structural insight: token pruning dominates computational savings, while head pruning provides fine-grained redundancy removal, and their combination achieves a superior trade-off. On ImageNet-100 and ImageNet-1K with ViT-B/16 and DeiT-B/16, HEART-ViT achieves up to 49.4 percent FLOPs reduction, 36 percent lower latency, and 46 percent higher throughput, while consistently matching or even surpassing baseline accuracy after fine-tuning, for example 4.7 percent recovery at 40 percent token pruning. Beyond theoretical benchmarks, we deploy HEART-ViT on different edge devices such as AGX Orin, demonstrating that our reductions in FLOPs and latency translate directly into real-world gains in inference speed and energy efficiency. HEART-ViT bridges the gap between theory and practice, delivering the first unified, curvature-driven pruning framework that is both accuracy-preserving and edge-efficient.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20120v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mohammad Helal Uddin, Liam Seymour, Sabur Baidya</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>milliMamba: Specular-Aware Human Pose Estimation via Dual mmWave Radar with Multi-Frame Mamba Fusion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20128</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20128v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Millimeter-wave radar offers a privacy-preserving and lighting-invariant alternative to RGB sensors for Human Pose Estimation (HPE) task. However, the radar signals are often sparse due to specular reflection, making the extraction of robust features from radar signals highly challenging. To address this, we present milliMamba, a radar-based 2D human pose estimation framework that jointly models spatio-temporal dependencies across both the feature extraction and decoding stages. Specifically, given the high dimensionality of radar inputs, we adopt a Cross-View Fusion Mamba encoder to efficiently extract spatio-temporal features from longer sequences with linear complexity. A Spatio-Temporal-Cross Attention decoder then predicts joint coordinates across multiple frames. Together, this spatio-temporal modeling pipeline enables the model to leverage contextual cues from neighboring frames and joints to infer missing joints caused by specular reflections. To reinforce motion smoothness, we incorporate a velocity loss alongside the standard keypoint loss during training. Experiments on the TransHuPR and HuPR datasets demonstrate that our method achieves significant performance improvements, exceeding the baselines by 11.0 AP and 14.6 AP, respectively, while maintaining reasonable complexity. Code: https://github.com/NYCU-MAPL/milliMamba</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20128v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Niraj Prakash Kini, Shiau-Rung Tsai, Guan-Hsun Lin, Wen-Hsiao Peng, Ching-Wen Ma, Jenq-Neng Hwang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing annotations for 5D apple pose estimation through 3D Gaussian Splatting (3DGS)</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20148</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20148v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Automating tasks in orchards is challenging because of the large amount of variation in the environment and occlusions. One of the challenges is apple pose estimation, where key points, such as the calyx, are often occluded. Recently developed pose estimation methods no longer rely on these key points, but still require them for annotations, making annotating challenging and time-consuming. Due to the abovementioned occlusions, there can be conflicting and missing annotations of the same fruit between different images. Novel 3D reconstruction methods can be used to simplify annotating and enlarge datasets. We propose a novel pipeline consisting of 3D Gaussian Splatting to reconstruct an orchard scene, simplified annotations, automated projection of the annotations to images, and the training and evaluation of a pose estimation method. Using our pipeline, 105 manual annotations were required to obtain 28,191 training labels, a reduction of 99.6%. Experimental results indicated that training with labels of fruits that are $\leq95\%$ occluded resulted in the best performance, with a neutral F1 score of 0.927 on the original images and 0.970 on the rendered images. Adjusting the size of the training dataset had small effects on the model performance in terms of F1 score and pose estimation accuracy. It was found that the least occluded fruits had the best position estimation, which worsened as the fruits became more occluded. It was also found that the tested pose estimation method was unable to correctly learn the orientation estimation of apples.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20148v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Robert van de Ven, Trim Bresilla, Bram Nelissen, Ard Nieuwenhuizen, Eldert J. van Henten, Gert Kootstra</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoDi -- an exemplar-conditioned diffusion model for low-shot counting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20153</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20153v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Low-shot object counting addresses estimating the number of previously unobserved objects in an image using only few or no annotated test-time exemplars. A considerable challenge for modern low-shot counters are dense regions with small objects. While total counts in such situations are typically well addressed by density-based counters, their usefulness is limited by poor localization capabilities. This is better addressed by point-detection-based counters, which are based on query-based detectors. However, due to limited number of pre-trained queries, they underperform on images with very large numbers of objects, and resort to ad-hoc techniques like upsampling and tiling. We propose CoDi, the first latent diffusion-based low-shot counter that produces high-quality density maps on which object locations can be determined by non-maxima suppression. Our core contribution is the new exemplar-based conditioning module that extracts and adjusts the object prototypes to the intermediate layers of the denoising network, leading to accurate object location estimation. On FSC benchmark, CoDi outperforms state-of-the-art by 15% MAE, 13% MAE and 10% MAE in the few-shot, one-shot, and reference-less scenarios, respectively, and sets a new state-of-the-art on MCAC benchmark by outperforming the top method by 44% MAE. The code is available at https://github.com/gsustar/CoDi.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20153v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Grega \v{S}u\v{s}tar, Jer Pelhan, Alan Luke\v{z}i\v{c}, Matej Kristan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMoE: Agglomerative Mixture-of-Experts Vision Foundation Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20157</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20157v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Vision foundation models trained via multi-teacher distillation offer a promising path toward unified visual representations, yet the learning dynamics and data efficiency of such approaches remain underexplored. In this paper, we systematically study multi-teacher distillation for vision foundation models and identify key factors that enable training at lower computational cost. We introduce Agglomerative Mixture-of-Experts Vision Foundation Models (AMoE), which distill knowledge from SigLIP2 and DINOv3 simultaneously into a Mixture-of-Experts student. We show that (1) our Asymmetric Relation-Knowledge Distillation loss preserves the geometric properties of each teacher while enabling effective knowledge transfer, (2) token-balanced batching that packs varying-resolution images into sequences with uniform token budgets stabilizes representation learning across resolutions without sacrificing performance, and (3) hierarchical clustering and sampling of training data--typically reserved for self-supervised learning--substantially improves sample efficiency over random sampling for multi-teacher distillation. By combining these findings, we curate OpenLVD200M, a 200M-image corpus that demonstrates superior efficiency for multi-teacher distillation. Instantiated in a Mixture-of-Experts. We release OpenLVD200M and distilled models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20157v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sofian Chaybouti, Sanath Narayan, Yasser Dahou, Ph\'uc H. L\^e Khac, Ankit Singh, Ngoc Dung Huynh, Wamiq Reyaz Para, Hilde Kuehne, Hakim Hacid</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Natural Language-Based Document Image Retrieval: New Dataset and Benchmark</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20174</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20174v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Document image retrieval (DIR) aims to retrieve document images from a gallery according to a given query. Existing DIR methods are primarily based on image queries that retrieve documents within the same coarse semantic category, e.g., newspapers or receipts. However, these methods struggle to effectively retrieve document images in real-world scenarios where textual queries with fine-grained semantics are usually provided. To bridge this gap, we introduce a new Natural Language-based Document Image Retrieval (NL-DIR) benchmark with corresponding evaluation metrics. In this work, natural language descriptions serve as semantically rich queries for the DIR task. The NL-DIR dataset contains 41K authentic document images, each paired with five high-quality, fine-grained semantic queries generated and evaluated through large language models in conjunction with manual verification. We perform zero-shot and fine-tuning evaluations of existing mainstream contrastive vision-language models and OCR-free visual document understanding (VDU) models. A two-stage retrieval method is further investigated for performance improvement while achieving both time and space efficiency. We hope the proposed NL-DIR benchmark can bring new opportunities and facilitate research for the VDU community. Datasets and codes will be publicly available at huggingface.co/datasets/nianbing/NL-DIR.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20174v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hao Guo, Xugong Qin, Jun Jie Ou Yang, Peng Zhang, Gangyan Zeng, Yubo Li, Hailun Lin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generative Latent Coding for Ultra-Low Bitrate Image Compression</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20194</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20194v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Most existing image compression approaches perform transform coding in the pixel space to reduce its spatial redundancy. However, they encounter difficulties in achieving both high-realism and high-fidelity at low bitrate, as the pixel-space distortion may not align with human perception. To address this issue, we introduce a Generative Latent Coding (GLC) architecture, which performs transform coding in the latent space of a generative vector-quantized variational auto-encoder (VQ-VAE), instead of in the pixel space. The generative latent space is characterized by greater sparsity, richer semantic and better alignment with human perception, rendering it advantageous for achieving high-realism and high-fidelity compression. Additionally, we introduce a categorical hyper module to reduce the bit cost of hyper-information, and a code-prediction-based supervision to enhance the semantic consistency. Experiments demonstrate that our GLC maintains high visual quality with less than 0.04 bpp on natural images and less than 0.01 bpp on facial images. On the CLIC2020 test set, we achieve the same FID as MS-ILLM with 45% fewer bits. Furthermore, the powerful generative latent space enables various applications built on our GLC pipeline, such as image restoration and style transfer. The code is available at https://github.com/jzyustc/GLC.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20194v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhaoyang Jia, Jiahao Li, Bin Li, Houqiang Li, Yan Lu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JDPNet: A Network Based on Joint Degradation Processing for Underwater Image Enhancement</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20213</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20213v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Given the complexity of underwater environments and the variability of water as a medium, underwater images are inevitably subject to various types of degradation. The degradations present nonlinear coupling rather than simple superposition, which renders the effective processing of such coupled degradations particularly challenging. Most existing methods focus on designing specific branches, modules, or strategies for specific degradations, with little attention paid to the potential information embedded in their coupling. Consequently, they struggle to effectively capture and process the nonlinear interactions of multiple degradations from a bottom-up perspective. To address this issue, we propose JDPNet, a joint degradation processing network, that mines and unifies the potential information inherent in coupled degradations within a unified framework. Specifically, we introduce a joint feature-mining module, along with a probabilistic bootstrap distribution strategy, to facilitate effective mining and unified adjustment of coupled degradation features. Furthermore, to balance color, clarity, and contrast, we design a novel AquaBalanceLoss to guide the network in learning from multiple coupled degradation losses. Experiments on six publicly available underwater datasets, as well as two new datasets constructed in this study, show that JDPNet exhibits state-of-the-art performance while offering a better tradeoff between performance, parameter size, and computational cost.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20213v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tao Ye, Hongbin Ren, Chongbing Zhang, Haoran Chen, Xiaosong Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LiteFusion: Taming 3D Object Detectors from Vision-Based to Multi-Modal with Minimal Adaptation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20217</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20217v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: 3D object detection is fundamental for safe and robust intelligent transportation systems. Current multi-modal 3D object detectors often rely on complex architectures and training strategies to achieve higher detection accuracy. However, these methods heavily rely on the LiDAR sensor so that they suffer from large performance drops when LiDAR is absent, which compromises the robustness and safety of autonomous systems in practical scenarios. Moreover, existing multi-modal detectors face difficulties in deployment on diverse hardware platforms, such as NPUs and FPGAs, due to their reliance on 3D sparse convolution operators, which are primarily optimized for NVIDIA GPUs. To address these challenges, we reconsider the role of LiDAR in the camera-LiDAR fusion paradigm and introduce a novel multi-modal 3D detector, LiteFusion. Instead of treating LiDAR point clouds as an independent modality with a separate feature extraction backbone, LiteFusion utilizes LiDAR data as a complementary source of geometric information to enhance camera-based detection. This straightforward approach completely eliminates the reliance on a 3D backbone, making the method highly deployment-friendly. Specifically, LiteFusion integrates complementary features from LiDAR points into image features within a quaternion space, where the orthogonal constraints are well-preserved during network training. This helps model domain-specific relations across modalities, yielding a compact cross-modal embedding. Experiments on the nuScenes dataset show that LiteFusion improves the baseline vision-based detector by +20.4% mAP and +19.7% NDS with a minimal increase in parameters (1.1%) without using dedicated LiDAR encoders. Notably, even in the absence of LiDAR input, LiteFusion maintains strong results , highlighting its favorable robustness and effectiveness across diverse fusion paradigms and deployment scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20217v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiangxuan Ren, Zhongdao Wang, Pin Tang, Guoqing Wang, Jilai Zheng, Chao Ma</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IndicDLP: A Foundational Dataset for Multi-Lingual and Multi-Domain Document Layout Parsing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20236</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20236v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Document layout analysis is essential for downstream tasks such as information retrieval, extraction, OCR, and digitization. However, existing large-scale datasets like PubLayNet and DocBank lack fine-grained region labels and multilingual diversity, making them insufficient for representing complex document layouts. In contrast, human-annotated datasets such as M6Doc and D4LA offer richer labels and greater domain diversity, but are too small to train robust models and lack adequate multilingual coverage. This gap is especially pronounced for Indic documents, which encompass diverse scripts yet remain underrepresented in current datasets, further limiting progress in this space. To address these shortcomings, we introduce IndicDLP, a large-scale foundational document layout dataset spanning 11 representative Indic languages alongside English and 12 common document domains. Additionally, we curate UED-mini, a dataset derived from DocLayNet and M6Doc, to enhance pretraining and provide a solid foundation for Indic layout models. Our experiments demonstrate that fine-tuning existing English models on IndicDLP significantly boosts performance, validating its effectiveness. Moreover, models trained on IndicDLP generalize well beyond Indic layouts, making it a valuable resource for document digitization. This work bridges gaps in scale, diversity, and annotation granularity, driving inclusive and efficient document understanding.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20236v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1007/978-3-032-04614-7_2</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Oikantik Nath, Sahithi Kukkala, Mitesh Khapra, Ravi Kiran Sarvadevabhatla</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Degradation-Aware Metric Prompting for Hyperspectral Image Restoration</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20251</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20251v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Unified hyperspectral image (HSI) restoration aims to recover various degraded HSIs using a single model, offering great practical value. However, existing methods often depend on explicit degradation priors (e.g., degradation labels) as prompts to guide restoration, which are difficult to obtain due to complex and mixed degradations in real-world scenarios. To address this challenge, we propose a Degradation-Aware Metric Prompting (DAMP) framework. Instead of relying on predefined degradation priors, we design spatial-spectral degradation metrics to continuously quantify multi-dimensional degradations, serving as Degradation Prompts (DP). These DP enable the model to capture cross-task similarities in degradation distributions and enhance shared feature learning. Furthermore, we introduce a Spatial-Spectral Adaptive Module (SSAM) that dynamically modulates spatial and spectral feature extraction through learnable parameters. By integrating SSAM as experts within a Mixture-of-Experts architecture, and using DP as the gating router, the framework enables adaptive, efficient, and robust restoration under diverse, mixed, or unseen degradations. Extensive experiments on natural and remote sensing HSI datasets show that DAMP achieves state-of-the-art performance and demonstrates exceptional generalization capability. Code is publicly available at https://github.com/MiliLab/DAMP.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20251v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Binfeng Wang, Di Wang, Haonan Guo, Ying Fu, Jing Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BiCoR-Seg: Bidirectional Co-Refinement Framework for High-Resolution Remote Sensing Image Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20255</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20255v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: High-resolution remote sensing image semantic segmentation (HRSS) is a fundamental yet critical task in the field of Earth observation. However, it has long faced the challenges of high inter-class similarity and large intra-class variability. Existing approaches often struggle to effectively inject abstract yet strongly discriminative semantic knowledge into pixel-level feature learning, leading to blurred boundaries and class confusion in complex scenes. To address these challenges, we propose Bidirectional Co-Refinement Framework for HRSS (BiCoR-Seg). Specifically, we design a Heatmap-driven Bidirectional Information Synergy Module (HBIS), which establishes a bidirectional information flow between feature maps and class embeddings by generating class-level heatmaps. Based on HBIS, we further introduce a hierarchical supervision strategy, where the interpretable heatmaps generated by each HBIS module are directly utilized as low-resolution segmentation predictions for supervision, thereby enhancing the discriminative capacity of shallow features. In addition, to further improve the discriminability of the embedding representations, we propose a cross-layer class embedding Fisher Discriminative Loss to enforce intra-class compactness and enlarge inter-class separability. Extensive experiments on the LoveDA, Vaihingen, and Potsdam datasets demonstrate that BiCoR-Seg achieves outstanding segmentation performance while offering stronger interpretability. The released code is available at https://github.com/ShiJinghao566/BiCoR-Seg.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20255v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jinghao Shi, Jianing Song</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LADLE-MM: Limited Annotation based Detector with Learned Ensembles for Multimodal Misinformation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20257</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20257v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: With the rise of easily accessible tools for generating and manipulating multimedia content, realistic synthetic alterations to digital media have become a widespread threat, often involving manipulations across multiple modalities simultaneously. Recently, such techniques have been increasingly employed to distort narratives of important events and to spread misinformation on social media, prompting the development of misinformation detectors. In the context of misinformation conveyed through image-text pairs, several detection methods have been proposed. However, these approaches typically rely on computationally intensive architectures or require large amounts of annotated data. In this work we introduce LADLE-MM: Limited Annotation based Detector with Learned Ensembles for Multimodal Misinformation, a model-soup initialized multimodal misinformation detector designed to operate under a limited annotation setup and constrained training resources. LADLE-MM is composed of two unimodal branches and a third multimodal one that enhances image and text representations with additional multimodal embeddings extracted from BLIP, serving as fixed reference space. Despite using 60.3% fewer trainable parameters than previous state-of-the-art models, LADLE-MM achieves competitive performance on both binary and multi-label classification tasks on the DGM4 benchmark, outperforming existing methods when trained without grounding annotations. Moreover, when evaluated on the VERITE dataset, LADLE-MM outperforms current state-of-the-art approaches that utilize more complex architectures involving Large Vision-Language-Models, demonstrating the effective generalization ability in an open-set setting and strong robustness to unimodal bias.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20257v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Daniele Cardullo, Simone Teglia, Irene Amerini</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>${D}^{3}${ETOR}: ${D}$ebate-Enhanced Pseudo Labeling and Frequency-Aware Progressive ${D}$ebiasing for Weakly-Supervised Camouflaged Object ${D}$etection with Scribble Annotations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20260</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20260v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Weakly-Supervised Camouflaged Object Detection (WSCOD) aims to locate and segment objects that are visually concealed within their surrounding scenes, relying solely on sparse supervision such as scribble annotations. Despite recent progress, existing WSCOD methods still lag far behind fully supervised ones due to two major limitations: (1) the pseudo masks generated by general-purpose segmentation models (e.g., SAM) and filtered via rules are often unreliable, as these models lack the task-specific semantic understanding required for effective pseudo labeling in COD; and (2) the neglect of inherent annotation bias in scribbles, which hinders the model from capturing the global structure of camouflaged objects. To overcome these challenges, we propose ${D}^{3}$ETOR, a two-stage WSCOD framework consisting of Debate-Enhanced Pseudo Labeling and Frequency-Aware Progressive Debiasing. In the first stage, we introduce an adaptive entropy-driven point sampling method and a multi-agent debate mechanism to enhance the capability of SAM for COD, improving the interpretability and precision of pseudo masks. In the second stage, we design FADeNet, which progressively fuses multi-level frequency-aware features to balance global semantic understanding with local detail modeling, while dynamically reweighting supervision strength across regions to alleviate scribble bias. By jointly exploiting the supervision signals from both the pseudo masks and scribble semantics, ${D}^{3}$ETOR significantly narrows the gap between weakly and fully supervised COD, achieving state-of-the-art performance on multiple benchmarks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20260v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiawei Ge, Jiuxin Cao, Xinyi Li, Xuelin Zhu, Chang Liu, Bo Liu, Chen Feng, Ioannis Patras</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UbiQVision: Quantifying Uncertainty in XAI for Image Recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20288</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20288v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent advances in deep learning have led to its widespread adoption across diverse domains, including medical imaging. This progress is driven by increasingly sophisticated model architectures, such as ResNets, Vision Transformers, and Hybrid Convolutional Neural Networks, that offer enhanced performance at the cost of greater complexity. This complexity often compromises model explainability and interpretability. SHAP has emerged as a prominent method for providing interpretable visualizations that aid domain experts in understanding model predictions. However, SHAP explanations can be unstable and unreliable in the presence of epistemic and aleatoric uncertainty. In this study, we address this challenge by using Dirichlet posterior sampling and Dempster-Shafer theory to quantify the uncertainty that arises from these unstable explanations in medical imaging applications. The framework uses a belief, plausible, and fusion map approach alongside statistical quantitative analysis to produce quantification of uncertainty in SHAP. Furthermore, we evaluated our framework on three medical imaging datasets with varying class distributions, image qualities, and modality types which introduces noise due to varying image resolutions and modality-specific aspect covering the examples from pathology, ophthalmology, and radiology, introducing significant epistemic uncertainty.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20288v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Akshat Dubey, Aleksandar An\v{z}el, Bahar \.Ilgen, Georges Hattab</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TAVID: Text-Driven Audio-Visual Interactive Dialogue Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20296</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20296v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The objective of this paper is to jointly synthesize interactive videos and conversational speech from text and reference images. With the ultimate goal of building human-like conversational systems, recent studies have explored talking or listening head generation as well as conversational speech generation. However, these works are typically studied in isolation, overlooking the multimodal nature of human conversation, which involves tightly coupled audio-visual interactions. In this paper, we introduce TAVID, a unified framework that generates both interactive faces and conversational speech in a synchronized manner. TAVID integrates face and speech generation pipelines through two cross-modal mappers (i.e., a motion mapper and a speaker mapper), which enable bidirectional exchange of complementary information between the audio and visual modalities. We evaluate our system across four dimensions: talking face realism, listening head responsiveness, dyadic interaction fluency, and speech quality. Extensive experiments demonstrate the effectiveness of our approach across all these aspects.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20296v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ji-Hoon Kim, Junseok Ahn, Doyeop Kwak, Joon Son Chung, Shinji Watanabe</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The devil is in the details: Enhancing Video Virtual Try-On via Keyframe-Driven Details Injection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20340</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20340v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Although diffusion transformer (DiT)-based video virtual try-on (VVT) has made significant progress in synthesizing realistic videos, existing methods still struggle to capture fine-grained garment dynamics and preserve background integrity across video frames. They also incur high computational costs due to additional interaction modules introduced into DiTs, while the limited scale and quality of existing public datasets also restrict model generalization and effective training. To address these challenges, we propose a novel framework, KeyTailor, along with a large-scale, high-definition dataset, ViT-HD. The core idea of KeyTailor is a keyframe-driven details injection strategy, motivated by the fact that keyframes inherently contain both foreground dynamics and background consistency. Specifically, KeyTailor adopts an instruction-guided keyframe sampling strategy to filter informative frames from the input video. Subsequently,two tailored keyframe-driven modules, the garment details enhancement module and the collaborative background optimization module, are employed to distill garment dynamics into garment-related latents and to optimize the integrity of background latents, both guided by keyframes.These enriched details are then injected into standard DiT blocks together with pose, mask, and noise latents, enabling efficient and realistic try-on video synthesis. This design ensures consistency without explicitly modifying the DiT architecture, while simultaneously avoiding additional complexity. In addition, our dataset ViT-HD comprises 15, 070 high-quality video samples at a resolution of 810*1080, covering diverse garments. Extensive experiments demonstrate that KeyTailor outperforms state-of-the-art baselines in terms of garment fidelity and background integrity across both dynamic and static scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20340v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qingdong He, Xueqin Chen, Yanjie Pan, Peng Tang, Pengcheng Xu, Zhenye Gan, Chengjie Wang, Xiaobin Hu, Jiangning Zhang, Yabiao Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CRAFT: Continuous Reasoning and Agentic Feedback Tuning for Multimodal Text-to-Image Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20362</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20362v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent work has shown that inference-time reasoning and reflection can improve text-to-image generation without retraining. However, existing approaches often rely on implicit, holistic critiques or unconstrained prompt rewrites, making their behavior difficult to interpret, control, or stop reliably. In contrast, large language models have benefited from explicit, structured forms of **thinking** based on verification, targeted correction, and early stopping.
  We introduce CRAFT (Continuous Reasoning and Agentic Feedback Tuning), a training-free, model-agnostic framework that brings this structured reasoning paradigm to multimodal image generation. CRAFT decomposes a prompt into dependency-structured visual questions, veries generated images using a vision-language model, and applies targeted prompt edits through an LLM agent only where constraints fail. The process iterates with an explicit stopping criterion once all constraints are satised, yielding an interpretable and controllable inference-time renement loop.
  Across multiple model families and challenging benchmarks, CRAFT consistently improves compositional accuracy, text rendering, and preference-based evaluations, with particularly strong gains for lightweight generators. Importantly, these improvements incur only a negligible inference-time overhead, allowing smaller or cheaper models to approach the quality of substantially more expensive systems. Our results suggest that explicitly structured, constraint-driven inference-time reasoning is a key ingredient for improving the reliability of multimodal generative models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20362v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>V. Kovalev, A. Kuvshinov, A. Buzovkin, D. Pokidov, D. Timonin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linking Faces and Voices Across Languages: Insights from the FAME 2026 Challenge</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20376</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20376v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Over half of the world's population is bilingual and people often communicate under multilingual scenarios. The Face-Voice Association in Multilingual Environments (FAME) 2026 Challenge, held at ICASSP 2026, focuses on developing methods for face-voice association that are effective when the language at test-time is different than the training one. This report provides a brief summary of the challenge.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20376v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Marta Moscati, Ahmed Abdullah, Muhammad Saad Saeed, Shah Nawaz, Rohan Kumar Das, Muhammad Zaigham Zaheer, Junaid Mir, Muhammad Haroon Yousaf, Khalid Mahmood Malik, Markus Schedl</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SmartSplat: Feature-Smart Gaussians for Scalable Compression of Ultra-High-Resolution Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20377</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20377v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent advances in generative AI have accelerated the production of ultra-high-resolution visual content, posing significant challenges for efficient compression and real-time decoding on end-user devices. Inspired by 3D Gaussian Splatting, recent 2D Gaussian image models improve representation efficiency, yet existing methods struggle to balance compression ratio and reconstruction fidelity in ultra-high-resolution scenarios. To address this issue, we propose SmartSplat, a highly adaptive and feature-aware GS-based image compression framework that supports arbitrary image resolutions and compression ratios. SmartSplat leverages image-aware features such as gradients and color variances, introducing a Gradient-Color Guided Variational Sampling strategy together with an Exclusion-based Uniform Sampling scheme to improve the non-overlapping coverage of Gaussian primitives in pixel space. In addition, we propose a Scale-Adaptive Gaussian Color Sampling method to enhance color initialization across scales. Through joint optimization of spatial layout, scale, and color initialization, SmartSplat efficiently captures both local structures and global textures using a limited number of Gaussians, achieving high reconstruction quality under strong compression. Extensive experiments on DIV8K and a newly constructed 16K dataset demonstrate that SmartSplat consistently outperforms state-of-the-art methods at comparable compression ratios and exceeds their compression limits, showing strong scalability and practical applicability. The code is publicly available at https://github.com/lif314/SmartSplat.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20377v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Linfei Li, Lin Zhang, Zhong Wang, Ying Shen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DETACH : Decomposed Spatio-Temporal Alignment for Exocentric Video and Ambient Sensors with Staged Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20409</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20409v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Aligning egocentric video with wearable sensors have shown promise for human action recognition, but face practical limitations in user discomfort, privacy concerns, and scalability. We explore exocentric video with ambient sensors as a non-intrusive, scalable alternative. While prior egocentric-wearable works predominantly adopt Global Alignment by encoding entire sequences into unified representations, this approach fails in exocentric-ambient settings due to two problems: (P1) inability to capture local details such as subtle motions, and (P2) over-reliance on modality-invariant temporal patterns, causing misalignment between actions sharing similar temporal patterns with different spatio-semantic contexts. To resolve these problems, we propose DETACH, a decomposed spatio-temporal framework. This explicit decomposition preserves local details, while our novel sensor-spatial features discovered via online clustering provide semantic grounding for context-aware alignment. To align the decomposed features, our two-stage approach establishes spatial correspondence through mutual supervision, then performs temporal alignment via a spatial-temporal weighted contrastive loss that adaptively handles easy negatives, hard negatives, and false negatives. Comprehensive experiments with downstream tasks on Opportunity++ and HWU-USP datasets demonstrate substantial improvements over adapted egocentric-wearable baselines.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20409v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junho Yoon, Jaemo Jung, Hyunju Kim, Dongman Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chain-of-Anomaly Thoughts with Large Vision-Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20417</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20417v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Automated video surveillance with Large Vision-Language Models is limited by their inherent bias towards normality, often failing to detect crimes. While Chain-of-Thought reasoning strategies show significant potential for improving performance in language tasks, the lack of inductive anomaly biases in their reasoning further steers the models towards normal interpretations. To address this, we propose Chain-of-Anomaly-Thoughts (CoAT), a multi-agent reasoning framework that introduces inductive criminal bias in the reasoning process through a final, anomaly-focused classification layer. Our method significantly improves Anomaly Detection, boosting F1-score by 11.8 p.p. on challenging low-resolution footage and Anomaly Classification by 3.78 p.p. in high-resolution videos.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20417v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Pedro Domingos, Jo\~ao Pereira, Vasco Lopes, Jo\~ao Neves, David Semedo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Skin Lesion Classification Using a Soft Voting Ensemble of Convolutional Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20431</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20431v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Skin cancer can be identified by dermoscopic examination and ocular inspection, but early detection significantly increases survival chances. Artificial intelligence (AI), using annotated skin images and Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs), improves diagnostic accuracy. This paper presents an early skin cancer classification method using a soft voting ensemble of CNNs. In this investigation, three benchmark datasets, namely HAM10000, ISIC 2016, and ISIC 2019, were used. The process involved rebalancing, image augmentation, and filtering techniques, followed by a hybrid dual encoder for segmentation via transfer learning. Accurate segmentation focused classification models on clinically significant features, reducing background artifacts and improving accuracy. Classification was performed through an ensemble of MobileNetV2, VGG19, and InceptionV3, balancing accuracy and speed for real-world deployment. The method achieved lesion recognition accuracies of 96.32\%, 90.86\%, and 93.92\% for the three datasets. The system performance was evaluated using established skin lesion detection metrics, yielding impressive results.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20431v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1109/ECCE64574.2025.11013422</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Abdullah Al Shafi, Abdul Muntakim, Pintu Chandra Shill, Rowzatul Zannat, Abdullah Al-Amin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Dimensional Data Decomposition for Anomaly Detection of Textured Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20432</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20432v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In the realm of diverse high-dimensional data, images play a significant role across various processes of manufacturing systems where efficient image anomaly detection has emerged as a core technology of utmost importance. However, when applied to textured defect images, conventional anomaly detection methods have limitations including non-negligible misidentification, low robustness, and excessive reliance on large-scale and structured datasets. This paper proposes a texture basis integrated smooth decomposition (TBSD) approach, which is targeted at efficient anomaly detection in textured images with smooth backgrounds and sparse anomalies. Mathematical formulation of quasi-periodicity and its theoretical properties are investigated for image texture estimation. TBSD method consists of two principal processes: the first process learns the texture basis functions to effectively extract quasi-periodic texture patterns; the subsequent anomaly detection process utilizes that texture basis as prior knowledge to prevent texture misidentification and capture potential anomalies with high accuracy.The proposed method surpasses benchmarks with less misidentification, smaller training dataset requirement, and superior anomaly detection performance on both simulation and real-world datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20432v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1080/24725854.2025.2606372</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Ji Song, Xing Wang, Jianguo Wu, Xiaowei Yue</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Motion Pattern: An Empirical Study of Physical Forces for Human Motion Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20451</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20451v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Human motion understanding has advanced rapidly through vision-based progress in recognition, tracking, and captioning. However, most existing methods overlook physical cues such as joint actuation forces that are fundamental in biomechanics. This gap motivates our study: if and when do physically inferred forces enhance motion understanding? By incorporating forces into established motion understanding pipelines, we systematically evaluate their impact across baseline models on 3 major tasks: gait recognition, action recognition, and fine-grained video captioning. Across 8 benchmarks, incorporating forces yields consistent performance gains; for example, on CASIA-B, Rank-1 gait recognition accuracy improved from 89.52% to 90.39% (+0.87), with larger gain observed under challenging conditions: +2.7% when wearing a coat and +3.0% at the side view. On Gait3D, performance also increases from 46.0% to 47.3% (+1.3). In action recognition, CTR-GCN achieved +2.00% on Penn Action, while high-exertion classes like punching/slapping improved by +6.96%. Even in video captioning, Qwen2.5-VL's ROUGE-L score rose from 0.310 to 0.339 (+0.029), indicating that physics-inferred forces enhance temporal grounding and semantic richness. These results demonstrate that force cues can substantially complement visual and kinematic features under dynamic, occluded, or appearance-varying conditions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20451v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Anh Dao, Manh Tran, Yufei Zhang, Xiaoming Liu, Zijun Cui</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UTDesign: A Unified Framework for Stylized Text Editing and Generation in Graphic Design Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20479</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20479v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: AI-assisted graphic design has emerged as a powerful tool for automating the creation and editing of design elements such as posters, banners, and advertisements. While diffusion-based text-to-image models have demonstrated strong capabilities in visual content generation, their text rendering performance, particularly for small-scale typography and non-Latin scripts, remains limited. In this paper, we propose UTDesign, a unified framework for high-precision stylized text editing and conditional text generation in design images, supporting both English and Chinese scripts. Our framework introduces a novel DiT-based text style transfer model trained from scratch on a synthetic dataset, capable of generating transparent RGBA text foregrounds that preserve the style of reference glyphs. We further extend this model into a conditional text generation framework by training a multi-modal condition encoder on a curated dataset with detailed text annotations, enabling accurate, style-consistent text synthesis conditioned on background images, prompts, and layout specifications. Finally, we integrate our approach into a fully automated text-to-design (T2D) pipeline by incorporating pre-trained text-to-image (T2I) models and an MLLM-based layout planner. Extensive experiments demonstrate that UTDesign achieves state-of-the-art performance among open-source methods in terms of stylistic consistency and text accuracy, and also exhibits unique advantages compared to proprietary commercial approaches. Code and data for this paper are available at https://github.com/ZYM-PKU/UTDesign.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20479v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3757377.3763923</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Yiming Zhao, Yuanpeng Gao, Yuxuan Luo, Jiwei Duan, Shisong Lin, Longfei Xiong, Zhouhui Lian</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-temporal Adaptive Red-Green-Blue and Long-Wave Infrared Fusion for You Only Look Once-Based Landmine Detection from Unmanned Aerial Systems</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20487</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20487v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Landmines remain a persistent humanitarian threat, with 110 million actively deployed mines across 60 countries, claiming 26,000 casualties annually. This research evaluates adaptive Red-Green-Blue (RGB) and Long-Wave Infrared (LWIR) fusion for Unmanned Aerial Systems (UAS)-based detection of surface-laid landmines, leveraging the thermal contrast between the ordnance and the surrounding soil to enhance feature extraction. Using You Only Look Once (YOLO) architectures (v8, v10, v11) across 114 test images, generating 35,640 model-condition evaluations, YOLOv11 achieved optimal performance (86.8% mAP), with 10 to 30% thermal fusion at 5 to 10m altitude identified as the optimal detection parameters. A complementary architectural comparison revealed that while RF-DETR achieved the highest accuracy (69.2% mAP), followed by Faster R-CNN (67.6%), YOLOv11 (64.2%), and RetinaNet (50.2%), YOLOv11 trained 17.7 times faster than the transformer-based RF-DETR (41 minutes versus 12 hours), presenting a critical accuracy-efficiency tradeoff for operational deployment. Aggregated multi-temporal training datasets outperformed season-specific approaches by 1.8 to 9.6%, suggesting that models benefit from exposure to diverse thermal conditions. Anti-Tank (AT) mines achieved 61.9% detection accuracy, compared with 19.2% for Anti-Personnel (AP) mines, reflecting both the size differential and thermal-mass differences between these ordnance classes. As this research examined surface-laid mines where thermal contrast is maximized, future research should quantify thermal contrast effects for mines buried at varying depths across heterogeneous soil types.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20487v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>James E. Gallagher, Edward J. Oughton, Jana Kosecka</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging Modalities and Transferring Knowledge: Enhanced Multimodal Understanding and Recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20501</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20501v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This manuscript explores multimodal alignment, translation, fusion, and transference to enhance machine understanding of complex inputs. We organize the work into five chapters, each addressing unique challenges in multimodal machine learning.
  Chapter 3 introduces Spatial-Reasoning Bert for translating text-based spatial relations into 2D arrangements between clip-arts. This enables effective decoding of spatial language into visual representations, paving the way for automated scene generation aligned with human spatial understanding.
  Chapter 4 presents a method for translating medical texts into specific 3D locations within an anatomical atlas. We introduce a loss function leveraging spatial co-occurrences of medical terms to create interpretable mappings, significantly enhancing medical text navigability.
  Chapter 5 tackles translating structured text into canonical facts within knowledge graphs. We develop a benchmark for linking natural language to entities and predicates, addressing ambiguities in text extraction to provide clearer, actionable insights.
  Chapter 6 explores multimodal fusion methods for compositional action recognition. We propose a method fusing video frames and object detection representations, improving recognition robustness and accuracy.
  Chapter 7 investigates multimodal knowledge transference for egocentric action recognition. We demonstrate how multimodal knowledge distillation enables RGB-only models to mimic multimodal fusion-based capabilities, reducing computational requirements while maintaining performance.
  These contributions advance methodologies for spatial language understanding, medical text interpretation, knowledge graph enrichment, and action recognition, enhancing computational systems' ability to process complex, multimodal inputs across diverse applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20501v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gorjan Radevski</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SirenPose: Dynamic Scene Reconstruction via Geometric Supervision</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20531</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20531v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We introduce SirenPose, a geometry-aware loss formulation that integrates the periodic activation properties of sinusoidal representation networks with keypoint-based geometric supervision, enabling accurate and temporally consistent reconstruction of dynamic 3D scenes from monocular videos. Existing approaches often struggle with motion fidelity and spatiotemporal coherence in challenging settings involving fast motion, multi-object interaction, occlusion, and rapid scene changes. SirenPose incorporates physics inspired constraints to enforce coherent keypoint predictions across both spatial and temporal dimensions, while leveraging high frequency signal modeling to capture fine grained geometric details. We further expand the UniKPT dataset to 600,000 annotated instances and integrate graph neural networks to model keypoint relationships and structural correlations. Extensive experiments on benchmarks including Sintel, Bonn, and DAVIS demonstrate that SirenPose consistently outperforms state-of-the-art methods. On DAVIS, SirenPose achieves a 17.8 percent reduction in FVD, a 28.7 percent reduction in FID, and a 6.0 percent improvement in LPIPS compared to MoSCA. It also improves temporal consistency, geometric accuracy, user score, and motion smoothness. In pose estimation, SirenPose outperforms Monst3R with lower absolute trajectory error as well as reduced translational and rotational relative pose error, highlighting its effectiveness in handling rapid motion, complex dynamics, and physically plausible reconstruction.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20531v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kaitong Cai, Jensen Zhang, Jing Yang, Keze Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AlignPose: Generalizable 6D Pose Estimation via Multi-view Feature-metric Alignment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20538</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20538v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Single-view RGB model-based object pose estimation methods achieve strong generalization but are fundamentally limited by depth ambiguity, clutter, and occlusions. Multi-view pose estimation methods have the potential to solve these issues, but existing works rely on precise single-view pose estimates or lack generalization to unseen objects. We address these challenges via the following three contributions. First, we introduce AlignPose, a 6D object pose estimation method that aggregates information from multiple extrinsically calibrated RGB views and does not require any object-specific training or symmetry annotation. Second, the key component of this approach is a new multi-view feature-metric refinement specifically designed for object pose. It optimizes a single, consistent world-frame object pose minimizing the feature discrepancy between on-the-fly rendered object features and observed image features across all views simultaneously. Third, we report extensive experiments on four datasets (YCB-V, T-LESS, ITODD-MV, HouseCat6D) using the BOP benchmark evaluation and show that AlignPose outperforms other published methods, especially on challenging industrial datasets where multiple views are readily available in practice.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20538v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Anna \v{S}\'arov\'a Mike\v{s}t\'ikov\'a, M\'ed\'eric Fourmy, Martin C\'ifka, Josef Sivic, Vladimir Petrik</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Grained Text-Guided Image Fusion for Multi-Exposure and Multi-Focus Scenarios</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20556</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20556v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Image fusion aims to synthesize a single high-quality image from a pair of inputs captured under challenging conditions, such as differing exposure levels or focal depths. A core challenge lies in effectively handling disparities in dynamic range and focus depth between the inputs. With the advent of vision-language models, recent methods incorporate textual descriptions as auxiliary guidance to enhance fusion quality. However, simply incorporating coarse-grained descriptions hampers the understanding of fine-grained details and poses challenges for precise cross-modal alignment. To address these limitations, we propose Multi-grained Text-guided Image Fusion (MTIF), a novel fusion paradigm with three key designs. First, it introduces multi-grained textual descriptions that separately capture fine details, structural cues, and semantic content, guiding image fusion through a hierarchical cross-modal modulation module. Second, it involves supervision signals at each granularity to facilitate alignment between visual and textual features and enhance the utility of auxiliary text. Third, it adopts a saliency-driven enrichment module to augment training data with dense semantic content, further strengthening the cross-modal modulation and alignment. Extensive experiments show that MTIF consistently outperforms previous methods on both multi-exposure and multi-focus image fusion tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20556v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mingwei Tang, Jiahao Nie, Guang Yang, Ziqing Cui, Jie Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning to Reason in 4D: Dynamic Spatial Understanding for Vision Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20557</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20557v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Vision-language models (VLM) excel at general understanding yet remain weak at dynamic spatial reasoning (DSR), i.e., reasoning about the evolvement of object geometry and relationship in 3D space over time, largely due to the scarcity of scalable 4D-aware training resources. To bridge this gap across aspects of dataset, benchmark and model, we introduce DSR Suite. First, we propose an automated pipeline that generates multiple-choice question-answer pairs from in-the-wild videos for DSR. By leveraging modern vision foundation models, the pipeline extracts rich geometric and motion information, including camera poses, local point clouds, object masks, orientations, and 3D trajectories. These geometric cues enable the construction of DSR-Train for learning and further human-refined DSR-Bench for evaluation. Compared with previous works, our data emphasize (i) in-the-wild video sources, (ii) object- and scene-level 3D requirements, (iii) viewpoint transformations, (iv) multi-object interactions, and (v) fine-grained, procedural answers. Beyond data, we propose a lightweight Geometry Selection Module (GSM) to seamlessly integrate geometric priors into VLMs, which condenses question semantics and extracts question-relevant knowledge from pretrained 4D reconstruction priors into a compact set of geometry tokens. This targeted extraction avoids overwhelming the model with irrelevant knowledge. Experiments show that integrating DSR-Train and GSM into Qwen2.5-VL-7B significantly enhances its dynamic spatial reasoning capability, while maintaining accuracy on general video understanding benchmarks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20557v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shengchao Zhou, Yuxin Chen, Yuying Ge, Wei Huang, Jiehong Lin, Ying Shan, Xiaojuan Qi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FlashVLM: Text-Guided Visual Token Selection for Large Multimodal Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20561</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20561v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large vision-language models (VLMs) typically process hundreds or thousands of visual tokens per image or video frame, incurring quadratic attention cost and substantial redundancy. Existing token reduction methods often ignore the textual query or rely on deep attention maps, whose instability under aggressive pruning leads to degraded semantic alignment.
  We propose FlashVLM, a text guided visual token selection framework that dynamically adapts visual inputs to the query. Instead of relying on noisy attention weights, FlashVLM computes an explicit cross modal similarity between projected image tokens and normalized text embeddings in the language model space. This extrinsic relevance is fused with intrinsic visual saliency using log domain weighting and temperature controlled sharpening. In addition, a diversity preserving partition retains a minimal yet representative set of background tokens to maintain global context.
  Under identical token budgets and evaluation protocols, FlashVLM achieves beyond lossless compression, slightly surpassing the unpruned baseline while pruning up to 77.8 percent of visual tokens on LLaVA 1.5, and maintaining 92.8 percent accuracy even under 94.4 percent compression. Extensive experiments on 14 image and video benchmarks demonstrate that FlashVLM delivers state of the art efficiency performance trade offs while maintaining strong robustness and generalization across mainstream VLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20561v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kaitong Cai, Jusheng Zhang, Jing Yang, Yijia Fan, Pengtao Xie, Jian Wang, Keze Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LEAD: Minimizing Learner-Expert Asymmetry in End-to-End Driving</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20563</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20563v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Simulators can generate virtually unlimited driving data, yet imitation learning policies in simulation still struggle to achieve robust closed-loop performance. Motivated by this gap, we empirically study how misalignment between privileged expert demonstrations and sensor-based student observations can limit the effectiveness of imitation learning. More precisely, experts have significantly higher visibility (e.g., ignoring occlusions) and far lower uncertainty (e.g., knowing other vehicles' actions), making them difficult to imitate reliably. Furthermore, navigational intent (i.e., the route to follow) is under-specified in student models at test time via only a single target point. We demonstrate that these asymmetries can measurably limit driving performance in CARLA and offer practical interventions to address them. After careful modifications to narrow the gaps between expert and student, our TransFuser v6 (TFv6) student policy achieves a new state of the art on all major publicly available CARLA closed-loop benchmarks, reaching 95 DS on Bench2Drive and more than doubling prior performances on Longest6~v2 and Town13. Additionally, by integrating perception supervision from our dataset into a shared sim-to-real pipeline, we show consistent gains on the NAVSIM and Waymo Vision-Based End-to-End driving benchmarks. Our code, data, and models are publicly available at https://github.com/autonomousvision/lead.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20563v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Long Nguyen, Micha Fauth, Bernhard Jaeger, Daniel Dauner, Maximilian Igl, Andreas Geiger, Kashyap Chitta</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Repurposing Video Diffusion Transformers for Robust Point Tracking</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20606</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20606v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Point tracking aims to localize corresponding points across video frames, serving as a fundamental task for 4D reconstruction, robotics, and video editing. Existing methods commonly rely on shallow convolutional backbones such as ResNet that process frames independently, lacking temporal coherence and producing unreliable matching costs under challenging conditions. Through systematic analysis, we find that video Diffusion Transformers (DiTs), pre-trained on large-scale real-world videos with spatio-temporal attention, inherently exhibit strong point tracking capability and robustly handle dynamic motions and frequent occlusions. We propose DiTracker, which adapts video DiTs through: (1) query-key attention matching, (2) lightweight LoRA tuning, and (3) cost fusion with a ResNet backbone. Despite training with 8 times smaller batch size, DiTracker achieves state-of-the-art performance on challenging ITTO benchmark and matches or outperforms state-of-the-art models on TAP-Vid benchmarks. Our work validates video DiT features as an effective and efficient foundation for point tracking.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20606v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Soowon Son, Honggyu An, Chaehyun Kim, Hyunah Ko, Jisu Nam, Dahyun Chung, Siyoon Jin, Jung Yi, Jaewon Min, Junhwa Hur, Seungryong Kim</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FedPOD: the deployable units of training for federated learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20610</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20610v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper proposes FedPOD (Proportionally Orchestrated Derivative) for optimizing learning efficiency and communication cost in federated learning among multiple clients. Inspired by FedPIDAvg, we define a round-wise task for FedPOD to enhance training efficiency. FedPIDAvg achieved performance improvement by incorporating the training loss reduction for prediction entropy as weights using differential terms. Furthermore, by modeling data distribution with a Poisson distribution and using a PID controller, it reduced communication costs even in skewed data distribution. However, excluding participants classified as outliers based on the Poisson distribution can limit data utilization. Additionally, PID controller requires the same participants to be maintained throughout the federated learning process as it uses previous rounds' learning information in the current round. In our approach, FedPOD addresses these issues by including participants excluded as outliers, eliminating dependency on previous rounds' learning information, and applying a method for calculating validation loss at each round. In this challenge, FedPOD presents comparable performance to FedPIDAvg in metrics of Dice score, 0.78, 0.71 and 0.72 for WT, ET and TC in average, and projected convergence score, 0.74 in average. Furthermore, the concept of FedPOD draws inspiration from Kubernetes' smallest computing unit, POD, designed to be compatible with Kubernetes auto-scaling. Extending round-wise tasks of FedPOD to POD units allows flexible design by applying scale-out similar to Kubernetes' auto-scaling. This work demonstrated the potentials of FedPOD to enhance federated learning by improving efficiency, flexibility, and performance in metrics.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20610v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Daewoon Kim, Si Young Yie, Jae Sung Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active Intelligence in Video Avatars via Closed-loop World Modeling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20615</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20615v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Current video avatar generation methods excel at identity preservation and motion alignment but lack genuine agency, they cannot autonomously pursue long-term goals through adaptive environmental interaction. We address this by introducing L-IVA (Long-horizon Interactive Visual Avatar), a task and benchmark for evaluating goal-directed planning in stochastic generative environments, and ORCA (Online Reasoning and Cognitive Architecture), the first framework enabling active intelligence in video avatars. ORCA embodies Internal World Model (IWM) capabilities through two key innovations: (1) a closed-loop OTAR cycle (Observe-Think-Act-Reflect) that maintains robust state tracking under generative uncertainty by continuously verifying predicted outcomes against actual generations, and (2) a hierarchical dual-system architecture where System 2 performs strategic reasoning with state prediction while System 1 translates abstract plans into precise, model-specific action captions. By formulating avatar control as a POMDP and implementing continuous belief updating with outcome verification, ORCA enables autonomous multi-step task completion in open-domain scenarios. Extensive experiments demonstrate that ORCA significantly outperforms open-loop and non-reflective baselines in task success rate and behavioral coherence, validating our IWM-inspired design for advancing video avatar intelligence from passive animation to active, goal-oriented behavior.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20615v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xuanhua He, Tianyu Yang, Ke Cao, Ruiqi Wu, Cheng Meng, Yong Zhang, Zhuoliang Kang, Xiaoming Wei, Qifeng Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SpatialTree: How Spatial Abilities Branch Out in MLLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20617</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20617v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Cognitive science suggests that spatial ability develops progressively-from perception to reasoning and interaction. Yet in multimodal LLMs (MLLMs), this hierarchy remains poorly understood, as most studies focus on a narrow set of tasks. We introduce SpatialTree, a cognitive-science-inspired hierarchy that organizes spatial abilities into four levels: low-level perception (L1), mental mapping (L2), simulation (L3), and agentic competence (L4). Based on this taxonomy, we construct the first capability-centric hierarchical benchmark, thoroughly evaluating mainstream MLLMs across 27 sub-abilities. The evaluation results reveal a clear structure: L1 skills are largely orthogonal, whereas higher-level skills are strongly correlated, indicating increasing interdependency. Through targeted supervised fine-tuning, we uncover a surprising transfer dynamic-negative transfer within L1, but strong cross-level transfer from low- to high-level abilities with notable synergy. Finally, we explore how to improve the entire hierarchy. We find that naive RL that encourages extensive "thinking" is unreliable: it helps complex reasoning but hurts intuitive perception. We propose a simple auto-think strategy that suppresses unnecessary deliberation, enabling RL to consistently improve performance across all levels. By building SpatialTree, we provide a proof-of-concept framework for understanding and systematically scaling spatial abilities in MLLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20617v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuxi Xiao, Longfei Li, Shen Yan, Xinhang Liu, Sida Peng, Yunchao Wei, Xiaowei Zhou, Bingyi Kang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SemanticGen: Video Generation in Semantic Space</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20619</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20619v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: State-of-the-art video generative models typically learn the distribution of video latents in the VAE space and map them to pixels using a VAE decoder. While this approach can generate high-quality videos, it suffers from slow convergence and is computationally expensive when generating long videos. In this paper, we introduce SemanticGen, a novel solution to address these limitations by generating videos in the semantic space. Our main insight is that, due to the inherent redundancy in videos, the generation process should begin in a compact, high-level semantic space for global planning, followed by the addition of high-frequency details, rather than directly modeling a vast set of low-level video tokens using bi-directional attention. SemanticGen adopts a two-stage generation process. In the first stage, a diffusion model generates compact semantic video features, which define the global layout of the video. In the second stage, another diffusion model generates VAE latents conditioned on these semantic features to produce the final output. We observe that generation in the semantic space leads to faster convergence compared to the VAE latent space. Our method is also effective and computationally efficient when extended to long video generation. Extensive experiments demonstrate that SemanticGen produces high-quality videos and outperforms state-of-the-art approaches and strong baselines.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20619v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jianhong Bai, Xiaoshi Wu, Xintao Wang, Fu Xiao, Yuanxing Zhang, Qinghe Wang, Xiaoyu Shi, Menghan Xia, Zuozhu Liu, Haoji Hu, Pengfei Wan, Kun Gai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAM Audio: Segment Anything in Audio</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.18099</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.18099v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: General audio source separation is a key capability for multimodal AI systems that can perceive and reason about sound. Despite substantial progress in recent years, existing separation models are either domain-specific, designed for fixed categories such as speech or music, or limited in controllability, supporting only a single prompting modality such as text. In this work, we present SAM Audio, a foundation model for general audio separation that unifies text, visual, and temporal span prompting within a single framework. Built on a diffusion transformer architecture, SAM Audio is trained with flow matching on large-scale audio data spanning speech, music, and general sounds, and can flexibly separate target sources described by language, visual masks, or temporal spans. The model achieves state-of-the-art performance across a diverse suite of benchmarks, including general sound, speech, music, and musical instrument separation in both in-the-wild and professionally produced audios, substantially outperforming prior general-purpose and specialized systems. Furthermore, we introduce a new real-world separation benchmark with human-labeled multimodal prompts and a reference-free evaluation model that correlates strongly with human judgment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.18099v1</guid>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bowen Shi, Andros Tjandra, John Hoffman, Helin Wang, Yi-Chiao Wu, Luya Gao, Julius Richter, Matt Le, Apoorv Vyas, Sanyuan Chen, Christoph Feichtenhofer, Piotr Doll\'ar, Wei-Ning Hsu, Ann Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Deep-to-Shallow Transformable Neural Networks for Intelligent Embedded Systems</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.19731</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.19731v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Thanks to the evolving network depth, convolutional neural networks (CNNs) have achieved remarkable success across various embedded scenarios, paving the way for ubiquitous embedded intelligence. Despite its promise, the evolving network depth comes at the cost of degraded hardware efficiency. In contrast to deep networks, shallow networks can deliver superior hardware efficiency but often suffer from inferior accuracy. To address this dilemma, we propose Double-Win NAS, a novel deep-to-shallow transformable neural architecture search (NAS) paradigm tailored for resource-constrained intelligent embedded systems. Specifically, Double-Win NAS strives to automatically explore deep networks to first win strong accuracy, which are then equivalently transformed into their shallow counterparts to further win strong hardware efficiency. In addition to search, we also propose two enhanced training techniques, including hybrid transformable training towards better training accuracy and arbitrary-resolution elastic training towards enabling natural network elasticity across arbitrary input resolutions. Extensive experimental results on two popular intelligent embedded systems (i.e., NVIDIA Jetson AGX Xavier and NVIDIA Jetson Nano) and two representative large-scale datasets (i.e., ImageNet and ImageNet-100) clearly demonstrate the superiority of Double-Win NAS over previous state-of-the-art NAS approaches.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.19731v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiangzhong Luo, Weichen Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Generative Location Awareness for Disaster Response: A Probabilistic Cross-view Geolocalization Approach</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20056</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20056v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: As Earth's climate changes, it is impacting disasters and extreme weather events across the planet. Record-breaking heat waves, drenching rainfalls, extreme wildfires, and widespread flooding during hurricanes are all becoming more frequent and more intense. Rapid and efficient response to disaster events is essential for climate resilience and sustainability. A key challenge in disaster response is to accurately and quickly identify disaster locations to support decision-making and resources allocation. In this paper, we propose a Probabilistic Cross-view Geolocalization approach, called ProbGLC, exploring new pathways towards generative location awareness for rapid disaster response. Herein, we combine probabilistic and deterministic geolocalization models into a unified framework to simultaneously enhance model explainability (via uncertainty quantification) and achieve state-of-the-art geolocalization performance. Designed for rapid diaster response, the ProbGLC is able to address cross-view geolocalization across multiple disaster events as well as to offer unique features of probabilistic distribution and localizability score. To evaluate the ProbGLC, we conduct extensive experiments on two cross-view disaster datasets (i.e., MultiIAN and SAGAINDisaster), consisting diverse cross-view imagery pairs of multiple disaster types (e.g., hurricanes, wildfires, floods, to tornadoes). Preliminary results confirms the superior geolocalization accuracy (i.e., 0.86 in Acc@1km and 0.97 in Acc@25km) and model explainability (i.e., via probabilistic distributions and localizability scores) of the proposed ProbGLC approach, highlighting the great potential of leveraging generative cross-view approach to facilitate location awareness for better and faster disaster response. The data and code is publicly available at https://github.com/bobleegogogo/ProbGLC</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20056v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hao Li, Fabian Deuser, Wenping Yin, Steffen Knoblauch, Wufan Zhao, Filip Biljecki, Yong Xue, Wei Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dreamcrafter: Immersive Editing of 3D Radiance Fields Through Flexible, Generative Inputs and Outputs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20129</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20129v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Authoring 3D scenes is a central task for spatial computing applications. Competing visions for lowering existing barriers are (1) focus on immersive, direct manipulation of 3D content or (2) leverage AI techniques that capture real scenes (3D Radiance Fields such as, NeRFs, 3D Gaussian Splatting) and modify them at a higher level of abstraction, at the cost of high latency. We unify the complementary strengths of these approaches and investigate how to integrate generative AI advances into real-time, immersive 3D Radiance Field editing. We introduce Dreamcrafter, a VR-based 3D scene editing system that: (1) provides a modular architecture to integrate generative AI algorithms; (2) combines different levels of control for creating objects, including natural language and direct manipulation; and (3) introduces proxy representations that support interaction during high-latency operations. We contribute empirical findings on control preferences and discuss how generative AI interfaces beyond text input enhance creativity in scene editing and world building.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20129v1</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Cyrus Vachha, Yixiao Kang, Zach Dive, Ashwat Chidambaram, Anik Gupta, Eunice Jun, Bjoern Hartmann</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retrieval-augmented Prompt Learning for Pre-trained Foundation Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20145</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20145v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The pre-trained foundation models (PFMs) have become essential for facilitating large-scale multimodal learning. Researchers have effectively employed the ``pre-train, prompt, and predict'' paradigm through prompt learning to induce improved few-shot performance. However, prompt learning approaches for PFMs still follow a parametric learning paradigm. As such, the stability of generalization in memorization and rote learning can be compromised. More specifically, conventional prompt learning might face difficulties in fully utilizing atypical instances and avoiding overfitting to shallow patterns with limited data during the process of fully-supervised training. To overcome these constraints, we present our approach, named RetroPrompt, which aims to achieve a balance between memorization and generalization by decoupling knowledge from mere memorization. Unlike traditional prompting methods, RetroPrompt leverages a publicly accessible knowledge base generated from the training data and incorporates a retrieval mechanism throughout the input, training, and inference stages. This enables the model to actively retrieve relevant contextual information from the corpus, thereby enhancing the available cues. We conduct comprehensive experiments on a variety of datasets across natural language processing and computer vision tasks to demonstrate the superior performance of our proposed approach, RetroPrompt, in both zero-shot and few-shot scenarios. Through detailed analysis of memorization patterns, we observe that RetroPrompt effectively reduces the reliance on rote memorization, leading to enhanced generalization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20145v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1109/TASLPRO.2025.3608936</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Xiang Chen, Yixin Ou, Quan Feng, Lei Li, Piji Li, Haibo Ye, Sheng-Jun Huang, Shuofei Qiao, Shumin Deng, Huajun Chen, Ningyu Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Met Your Bias: Investigating Bias Amplification in Diffusion Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20233</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20233v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Diffusion-based generative models demonstrate state-of-the-art performance across various image synthesis tasks, yet their tendency to replicate and amplify dataset biases remains poorly understood. Although previous research has viewed bias amplification as an inherent characteristic of diffusion models, this work provides the first analysis of how sampling algorithms and their hyperparameters influence bias amplification. We empirically demonstrate that samplers for diffusion models -- commonly optimized for sample quality and speed -- have a significant and measurable effect on bias amplification. Through controlled studies with models trained on Biased MNIST, Multi-Color MNIST and BFFHQ, and with Stable Diffusion, we show that sampling hyperparameters can induce both bias reduction and amplification, even when the trained model is fixed. Source code is available at https://github.com/How-I-met-your-bias/how_i_met_your_bias.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20233v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nathan Roos, Ekaterina Iakovleva, Ani Gjergji, Vito Paolo Pastore, Enzo Tartaglione</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unified Multimodal Brain Decoding via Cross-Subject Soft-ROI Fusion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20249</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20249v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Multimodal brain decoding aims to reconstruct semantic information that is consistent with visual stimuli from brain activity signals such as fMRI, and then generate readable natural language descriptions. However, multimodal brain decoding still faces key challenges in cross-subject generalization and interpretability. We propose a BrainROI model and achieve leading-level results in brain-captioning evaluation on the NSD dataset. Under the cross-subject setting, compared with recent state-of-the-art methods and representative baselines, metrics such as BLEU-4 and CIDEr show clear improvements. Firstly, to address the heterogeneity of functional brain topology across subjects, we design a new fMRI encoder. We use multi-atlas soft functional parcellations (soft-ROI) as a shared space. We extend the discrete ROI Concatenation strategy in MINDLLM to a voxel-wise gated fusion mechanism (Voxel-gate). We also ensure consistent ROI mapping through global label alignment, which enhances cross-subject transferability. Secondly, to overcome the limitations of manual and black-box prompting methods in stability and transparency, we introduce an interpretable prompt optimization process. In a small-sample closed loop, we use a locally deployed Qwen model to iteratively generate and select human-readable prompts. This process improves the stability of prompt design and preserves an auditable optimization trajectory. Finally, we impose parameterized decoding constraints during inference to further improve the stability and quality of the generated descriptions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20249v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xuanyu Hu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KnowVal: A Knowledge-Augmented and Value-Guided Autonomous Driving System</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20299</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20299v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Visual-language reasoning, driving knowledge, and value alignment are essential for advanced autonomous driving systems. However, existing approaches largely rely on data-driven learning, making it difficult to capture the complex logic underlying decision-making through imitation or limited reinforcement rewards. To address this, we propose KnowVal, a new autonomous driving system that enables visual-language reasoning through the synergistic integration of open-world perception and knowledge retrieval. Specifically, we construct a comprehensive driving knowledge graph that encodes traffic laws, defensive driving principles, and ethical norms, complemented by an efficient LLM-based retrieval mechanism tailored for driving scenarios. Furthermore, we develop a human-preference dataset and train a Value Model to guide interpretable, value-aligned trajectory assessment. Experimental results show that our method substantially improves planning performance while remaining compatible with existing architectures. Notably, KnowVal achieves the lowest collision rate on nuScenes and state-of-the-art results on Bench2Drive.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20299v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhongyu Xia, Wenhao Chen, Yongtao Wang, Ming-Hsuan Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Field-Space Attention for Structure-Preserving Earth System Transformers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20350</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20350v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Accurate and physically consistent modeling of Earth system dynamics requires machine-learning architectures that operate directly on continuous geophysical fields and preserve their underlying geometric structure. Here we introduce Field-Space attention, a mechanism for Earth system Transformers that computes attention in the physical domain rather than in a learned latent space. By maintaining all intermediate representations as continuous fields on the sphere, the architecture enables interpretable internal states and facilitates the enforcement of scientific constraints. The model employs a fixed, non-learned multiscale decomposition and learns structure-preserving deformations of the input field, allowing coherent integration of coarse and fine-scale information while avoiding the optimization instabilities characteristic of standard single-scale Vision Transformers. Applied to global temperature super-resolution on a HEALPix grid, Field-Space Transformers converge more rapidly and stably than conventional Vision Transformers and U-Net baselines, while requiring substantially fewer parameters. The explicit preservation of field structure throughout the network allows physical and statistical priors to be embedded directly into the architecture, yielding improved fidelity and reliability in data-driven Earth system modeling. These results position Field-Space Attention as a compact, interpretable, and physically grounded building block for next-generation Earth system prediction and generative modeling frameworks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20350v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>math-ph</category>
      <category>math.MP</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Maximilian Witte, Johannes Meuer, \'Etienne Pl\'esiat, Christopher Kadow</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CLIP Based Region-Aware Feature Fusion for Automated BBPS Scoring in Colonoscopy Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20374</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20374v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Accurate assessment of bowel cleanliness is essential for effective colonoscopy procedures. The Boston Bowel Preparation Scale (BBPS) offers a standardized scoring system but suffers from subjectivity and inter-observer variability when performed manually. In this paper, to support robust training and evaluation, we construct a high-quality colonoscopy dataset comprising 2,240 images from 517 subjects, annotated with expert-agreed BBPS scores. We propose a novel automated BBPS scoring framework that leverages the CLIP model with adapter-based transfer learning and a dedicated fecal-feature extraction branch. Our method fuses global visual features with stool-related textual priors to improve the accuracy of bowel cleanliness evaluation without requiring explicit segmentation. Extensive experiments on both our dataset and the public NERTHU dataset demonstrate the superiority of our approach over existing baselines, highlighting its potential for clinical deployment in computer-aided colonoscopy analysis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20374v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yujia Fu, Zhiyu Dong, Tianwen Qian, Chenye Zheng, Danian Ji, Linhai Zhuo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generative Digital Twins: Vision-Language Simulation Models for Executable Industrial Systems</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20387</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20387v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We propose a Vision-Language Simulation Model (VLSM) that unifies visual and textual understanding to synthesize executable FlexScript from layout sketches and natural-language prompts, enabling cross-modal reasoning for industrial simulation systems. To support this new paradigm, the study constructs the first large-scale dataset for generative digital twins, comprising over 120,000 prompt-sketch-code triplets that enable multimodal learning between textual descriptions, spatial structures, and simulation logic. In parallel, three novel evaluation metrics, Structural Validity Rate (SVR), Parameter Match Rate (PMR), and Execution Success Rate (ESR), are proposed specifically for this task to comprehensively evaluate structural integrity, parameter fidelity, and simulator executability. Through systematic ablation across vision encoders, connectors, and code-pretrained language backbones, the proposed models achieve near-perfect structural accuracy and high execution robustness. This work establishes a foundation for generative digital twins that integrate visual reasoning and language understanding into executable industrial simulation systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20387v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>YuChe Hsu, AnJui Wang, TsaiChing Ni, YuanFu Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simplifying Multi-Task Architectures Through Task-Specific Normalization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20420</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20420v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Multi-task learning (MTL) aims to leverage shared knowledge across tasks to improve generalization and parameter efficiency, yet balancing resources and mitigating interference remain open challenges. Architectural solutions often introduce elaborate task-specific modules or routing schemes, increasing complexity and overhead. In this work, we show that normalization layers alone are sufficient to address many of these challenges. Simply replacing shared normalization with task-specific variants already yields competitive performance, questioning the need for complex designs. Building on this insight, we propose Task-Specific Sigmoid Batch Normalization (TS$\sigma$BN), a lightweight mechanism that enables tasks to softly allocate network capacity while fully sharing feature extractors. TS$\sigma$BN improves stability across CNNs and Transformers, matching or exceeding performance on NYUv2, Cityscapes, CelebA, and PascalContext, while remaining highly parameter-efficient. Moreover, its learned gates provide a natural framework for analyzing MTL dynamics, offering interpretable insights into capacity allocation, filter specialization, and task relationships. Our findings suggest that complex MTL architectures may be unnecessary and that task-specific normalization offers a simple, interpretable, and efficient alternative.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20420v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mihai Suteu, Ovidiu Serban</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual-Encoder Transformer-Based Multimodal Learning for Ischemic Stroke Lesion Segmentation Using Diffusion MRI</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20436</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20436v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Accurate segmentation of ischemic stroke lesions from diffusion magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) is essential for clinical decision-making and outcome assessment. Diffusion-Weighted Imaging (DWI) and Apparent Diffusion Coefficient (ADC) scans provide complementary information on acute and sub-acute ischemic changes; however, automated lesion delineation remains challenging due to variability in lesion appearance.
  In this work, we study ischemic stroke lesion segmentation using multimodal diffusion MRI from the ISLES 2022 dataset. Several state-of-the-art convolutional and transformer-based architectures, including U-Net variants, Swin-UNet, and TransUNet, are benchmarked. Based on performance, a dual-encoder TransUNet architecture is proposed to learn modality-specific representations from DWI and ADC inputs. To incorporate spatial context, adjacent slice information is integrated using a three-slice input configuration.
  All models are trained under a unified framework and evaluated using the Dice Similarity Coefficient (DSC). Results show that transformer-based models outperform convolutional baselines, and the proposed dual-encoder TransUNet achieves the best performance, reaching a Dice score of 85.4% on the test set. The proposed framework offers a robust solution for automated ischemic stroke lesion segmentation from diffusion MRI.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20436v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Muhammad Usman, Azka Rehman, Muhammad Mutti Ur Rehman, Abd Ur Rehman, Muhammad Umar Farooq</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Snapshot 3D image projection using a diffractive decoder</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20464</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20464v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: 3D image display is essential for next-generation volumetric imaging; however, dense depth multiplexing for 3D image projection remains challenging because diffraction-induced cross-talk rapidly increases as the axial image planes get closer. Here, we introduce a 3D display system comprising a digital encoder and a diffractive optical decoder, which simultaneously projects different images onto multiple target axial planes with high axial resolution. By leveraging multi-layer diffractive wavefront decoding and deep learning-based end-to-end optimization, the system achieves high-fidelity depth-resolved 3D image projection in a snapshot, enabling axial plane separations on the order of a wavelength. The digital encoder leverages a Fourier encoder network to capture multi-scale spatial and frequency-domain features from input images, integrates axial position encoding, and generates a unified phase representation that simultaneously encodes all images to be axially projected in a single snapshot through a jointly-optimized diffractive decoder. We characterized the impact of diffractive decoder depth, output diffraction efficiency, spatial light modulator resolution, and axial encoding density, revealing trade-offs that govern axial separation and 3D image projection quality. We further demonstrated the capability to display volumetric images containing 28 axial slices, as well as the ability to dynamically reconfigure the axial locations of the image planes, performed on demand. Finally, we experimentally validated the presented approach, demonstrating close agreement between the measured results and the target images. These results establish the diffractive 3D display system as a compact and scalable framework for depth-resolved snapshot 3D image projection, with potential applications in holographic displays, AR/VR interfaces, and volumetric optical computing.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20464v1</guid>
      <category>physics.optics</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.NE</category>
      <category>physics.app-ph</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Cagatay Isil, Alexander Chen, Yuhang Li, F. Onuralp Ardic, Shiqi Chen, Che-Yung Shen, Aydogan Ozcan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cube Bench: A Benchmark for Spatial Visual Reasoning in MLLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20595</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20595v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We introduce Cube Bench, a Rubik's-cube benchmark for evaluating spatial and sequential reasoning in multimodal large language models (MLLMs). The benchmark decomposes performance into five skills: (i) reconstructing cube faces from images and text, (ii) choosing the optimal next move, (iii) predicting the outcome of a candidate move without applying it, (iv) executing multi-step plans while recovering from mistakes, and (v) detecting and revising one's own errors. Using a shared set of scrambled cube states, identical prompts and parsers, and a single distance-to-solved metric, we compare recent MLLMs side by side as a function of scramble depth. Across seven MLLMs, accuracy drops sharply with depth; once a trajectory stalls or diverges, models rarely recover, and high face-reconstruction accuracy does not guarantee competent action selection or multi-step execution. A pronounced closed- vs open-source gap emerges: the strongest closed model leads on both single-step perception tasks and multi-step control tasks, while open-weight models cluster near chance on the hardest settings; yet even the best MLLM degrades at higher cube complexity. A simple self-correction via reflective thinking yields modest gains but can also introduce overthinking. Cube Bench offers a compact, reproducible probe of sequential spatial reasoning in MLLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20595v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dhruv Anand, Ehsan Shareghi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LongVideoAgent: Multi-Agent Reasoning with Long Videos</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20618</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20618v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recent advances in multimodal LLMs and systems that use tools for long-video QA point to the promise of reasoning over hour-long episodes. However, many methods still compress content into lossy summaries or rely on limited toolsets, weakening temporal grounding and missing fine-grained cues. We propose a multi-agent framework in which a master LLM coordinates a grounding agent to localize question-relevant segments and a vision agent to extract targeted textual observations. The master agent plans with a step limit, and is trained with reinforcement learning to encourage concise, correct, and efficient multi-agent cooperation. This design helps the master agent focus on relevant clips via grounding, complements subtitles with visual detail, and yields interpretable trajectories. On our proposed LongTVQA and LongTVQA+ which are episode-level datasets aggregated from TVQA/TVQA+, our multi-agent system significantly outperforms strong non-agent baselines. Experiments also show reinforcement learning further strengthens reasoning and planning for the trained agent. Code and data will be shared at https://longvideoagent.github.io/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20618v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Runtao Liu, Ziyi Liu, Jiaqi Tang, Yue Ma, Renjie Pi, Jipeng Zhang, Qifeng Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TropNNC: Structured Neural Network Compression Using Tropical Geometry</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.03945</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.03945v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We present TropNNC, a framework for compressing neural networks with linear and convolutional layers and ReLU activations using tropical geometry. By representing a network's output as a tropical rational function, TropNNC enables structured compression via reduction of the corresponding tropical polynomials. Our method refines the geometric approximation of previous work by adaptively selecting the weights of retained neurons. Key contributions include the first application of tropical geometry to convolutional layers and the tightest known theoretical compression bound. TropNNC requires only access to network weights - no training data - and achieves competitive performance on MNIST, CIFAR, and ImageNet, matching strong baselines such as ThiNet and CUP.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.03945v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Konstantinos Fotopoulos, Petros Maragos, Panagiotis Misiakos</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Image Matching Filtering and Refinement by Planes and Beyond</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09484</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09484v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper introduces a modular, non-deep learning method for filtering and refining sparse correspondences in image matching. Assuming that motion flow within the scene can be approximated by local homography transformations, matches are aggregated into overlapping clusters corresponding to virtual planes using an iterative RANSAC-based approach discarding incompatible correspondences. Moreover, the underlying planar structural design provides an explicit map between local patches associated with the matches, by which optionally refine the keypoint positions through cross-correlation template matching after the patch reprojection. Finally, to enhance robustness and fault-tolerance against violations of the piece-wise planar approximation assumption, a further strategy is designed in order to minimize the relative patch distortion in the plane reprojection by introducing an intermediate homography that projects both patches into a common plane. The proposed method is extensively evaluated on standard datasets and image matching pipelines, and compared with state-of-the-art approaches. Unlike other current comparisons, the proposed benchmark also takes into account the more general, real, and practical cases where camera intrinsics are unavailable. Experimental results demonstrate that our proposed non-deep learning, geometry-based filter is effective in presence of outliers and the optional cross-correlation refinement step is valid in the case of corner-like keypoints. Finally, this study suggests that there is still significant development potential in practical image matching solutions in the considered research direction, which could be in the future incorporated in novel deep image matching architectures.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09484v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fabio Bellavia, Zhenjun Zhao, Luca Morelli, Fabio Remondino</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compression for Better: A General and Stable Lossless Compression Framework</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.06868</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.06868v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This work focus on how to stabilize and lossless model compression, aiming to reduce model complexity and enhance efficiency without sacrificing performance due to compression errors. A key challenge is effectively leveraging compression errors and defining the boundaries for lossless compression to minimize model loss. i.e., compression for better. Currently, there is no systematic approach to determining this error boundary or understanding its specific impact on model performance. We propose a general \textbf{L}oss\textbf{L}ess \textbf{C}ompression theoretical framework (\textbf{LLC}), which further delineates the compression neighborhood and higher-order analysis boundaries through the total differential, thereby specifying the error range within which a model can be compressed without loss. To verify the effectiveness of LLC, we apply various compression techniques, including quantization and decomposition. Specifically, for quantization, we reformulate the classic quantization search problem as a grouped knapsack problem within the lossless neighborhood, achieving lossless quantization while improving computational efficiency. For decomposition, LLC addresses the approximation problem under low-rank constraints, automatically determining the rank for each layer and producing lossless low-rank models. We conduct extensive experiments on multiple neural network architectures on different datasets. The results show that without fancy tricks, LLC can effectively achieve lossless model compression. Our code will be made publicly.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.06868v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Boyang Zhang, Daning Cheng, Yunquan Zhang, Fangming Liu, Wenguang Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GenVidBench: A 6-Million Benchmark for AI-Generated Video Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.11340</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.11340v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The rapid advancement of video generation models has made it increasingly challenging to distinguish AI-generated videos from real ones. This issue underscores the urgent need for effective AI-generated video detectors to prevent the dissemination of false information via such videos. However, the development of high-performance AI-generated video detectors is currently impeded by the lack of large-scale, high-quality datasets specifically designed for generative video detection. To this end, we introduce GenVidBench, a challenging AI-generated video detection dataset with several key advantages: 1) Large-scale video collection: The dataset contains 6.78 million videos and is currently the largest dataset for AI-generated video detection. 2) Cross-Source and Cross-Generator: The cross-source generation reduces the interference of video content on the detection. The cross-generator ensures diversity in video attributes between the training and test sets, preventing them from being overly similar. 3) State-of-the-Art Video Generators: The dataset includes videos from 11 state-of-the-art AI video generators, ensuring that it covers the latest advancements in the field of video generation. These generators ensure that the datasets are not only large in scale but also diverse, aiding in the development of generalized and effective detection models. Additionally, we present extensive experimental results with advanced video classification models. With GenVidBench, researchers can efficiently develop and evaluate AI-generated video detection models.. Datasets and code are available at https://genvidbench.github.io.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.11340v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhenliang Ni, Qiangyu Yan, Mouxiao Huang, Tianning Yuan, Yehui Tang, Hailin Hu, Xinghao Chen, Yunhe Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regressor-Guided Generative Image Editing Balances User Emotions to Reduce Time Spent Online</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.12289</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.12289v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Internet overuse is a widespread phenomenon in today's digital society. Existing interventions, such as time limits or grayscaling, often rely on restrictive controls that provoke psychological reactance and are frequently circumvented. Building on prior work showing that emotional responses mediate the relationship between content consumption and online engagement, we investigate whether regulating the emotional impact of images can reduce online use in a non-coercive manner. We introduce and systematically analyze three regressor-guided image-editing approaches: (i) global optimization of emotion-related image attributes, (ii) optimization in a style latent space, and (iii) a diffusion-based method using classifier and classifier-free guidance. While the first two approaches modify low-level visual features (e.g., contrast, color), the diffusion-based method enables higher-level changes (e.g., adjusting clothing, facial features). Results from a controlled image-rating study and a social media experiment show that diffusion-based edits balance emotional responses and are associated with lower usage duration while preserving visual quality.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.12289v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Christoph Gebhardt, Robin Willardt, Seyedmorteza Sadat, Chih-Wei Ning, Andreas Brombach, Jie Song, Otmar Hilliges, Christian Holz</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPECIAL: Zero-shot Hyperspectral Image Classification With CLIP</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.16222</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.16222v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Hyperspectral image (HSI) classification aims to categorize each pixel in an HSI into a specific land cover class, which is crucial for applications such as remote sensing, environmental monitoring, and agriculture. Although deep learning-based HSI classification methods have achieved significant advancements, existing methods still rely on manually labeled data for training, which is both time-consuming and labor-intensive. To address this limitation, we introduce a novel zero-shot hyperspectral image classification framework based on CLIP (SPECIAL), aiming to eliminate the need for manual annotations. The SPECIAL framework consists of two main stages: (1) CLIP-based pseudo-label generation, and (2) noisy label learning. In the first stage, HSI is spectrally interpolated to produce RGB bands. These bands are subsequently classified using CLIP, resulting in noisy pseudo-labels that are accompanied by confidence scores. To improve the quality of these labels, we propose a scaling strategy that fuses predictions from multiple spatial scales. In the second stage, spectral information and a label refinement technique are incorporated to mitigate label noise and further enhance classification accuracy. Experimental results on three benchmark datasets demonstrate that our SPECIAL outperforms existing methods in zero-shot HSI classification, showing its potential for more practical applications. The code is available at https://github.com/LiPang/SPECIAL.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.16222v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Li Pang, Jing Yao, Kaiyu Li, Jun Zhou, Deyu Meng, Xiangyong Cao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BUFFER-X: Towards Zero-Shot Point Cloud Registration in Diverse Scenes</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.07940</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.07940v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advances in deep learning-based point cloud registration have improved generalization, yet most methods still require retraining or manual parameter tuning for each new environment. In this paper, we identify three key factors limiting generalization: (a) reliance on environment-specific voxel size and search radius, (b) poor out-of-domain robustness of learning-based keypoint detectors, and (c) raw coordinate usage, which exacerbates scale discrepancies. To address these issues, we present a zero-shot registration pipeline called BUFFER-X by (a) adaptively determining voxel size/search radii, (b) using farthest point sampling to bypass learned detectors, and (c) leveraging patch-wise scale normalization for consistent coordinate bounds. In particular, we present a multi-scale patch-based descriptor generation and a hierarchical inlier search across scales to improve robustness in diverse scenes. We also propose a novel generalizability benchmark using 11 datasets that cover various indoor/outdoor scenarios and sensor modalities, demonstrating that BUFFER-X achieves substantial generalization without prior information or manual parameter tuning for the test datasets. Our code is available at https://github.com/MIT-SPARK/BUFFER-X.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.07940v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Minkyun Seo, Hyungtae Lim, Kanghee Lee, Luca Carlone, Jaesik Park</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fine-Grained Instruction-Guided Graph Reasoning for Vision-and-Language Navigation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.11006</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.11006v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Vision-and-Language Navigation (VLN) requires an embodied agent to traverse complex environments by following natural language instructions, demanding accurate alignment between visual observations and linguistic guidance. Despite recent progress, existing methods typically encode visual and directional cues in a coupled manner, and process instructions without explicitly extracting navigation-critical semantics, which often leads to imprecise spatial reasoning and suboptimal cross-modal alignment. To address these challenges, we propose a fine-grained instruction-guided graph reasoning framework (OIKG) that enhances both spatial representation and instruction understanding during navigation. Specifically, an observation-graph interaction mechanism is introduced to disentangle angular and visual cues while strengthening directed edge representations through geometric embedding, enabling more reliable spatial reasoning within the navigation graph. In addition, a fine-grained instruction guidance module is designed to explicitly extract and leverage location-specific and object-centric information from language instructions, facilitating more precise cross-modal alignment between linguistic semantics and navigable trajectories. By jointly integrating structured graph reasoning with instruction-critical semantic cues, the proposed approach significantly improves the agent's ability to follow complex navigation instructions. Extensive experiments on the R2R and RxR benchmarks demonstrate that our method consistently achieves state-of-the-art performance across multiple evaluation metrics, validating the effectiveness of fine-grained instruction-guided graph reasoning for vision-and-language navigation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.11006v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yaohua Liu, Xinyuan Song, Yunfu Deng, Yifan Xie, Binkai Ou, Yan Zhong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Want It That Way! Specifying Nuanced Camera Motions in Video Editing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.09472</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.09472v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Specifying nuanced and compelling camera motion remains a major hurdle for non-expert creators using generative tools, creating an ``expressive gap" where generic text prompts fail to capture cinematic vision. To address this, we present a novel zero-shot diffusion-based system that enables personalized camera motion transfer from a single reference video onto a user-provided static image. Our technical contribution introduces an intuitive interaction paradigm that bypasses the need for 3D data, predefined trajectories, or complex graphical interfaces. The core pipeline leverages a text-to-video diffusion model, employing a two-phase strategy: 1) a multi-concept learning method using LoRA layers and an orthogonality loss to distinctly capture spatial-temporal characteristics and scene features, and 2) a homography-based refinement strategy to enhance temporal and spatial alignment of the generated video. Extensive evaluation demonstrates the efficacy of our method. In a comparative study with 72 participants, our system was significantly preferred over prior work for both motion accuracy (90.45\%) and scene preservation (70.31\%). A second study confirmed our interface significantly improves usability and creative control for video direction. Our work contributes a robust technical solution and a novel human-centered design, significantly expanding cinematic video editing for diverse users.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.09472v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Pooja Guhan, Divya Kothandaraman, Geonsun Lee, Tsung-Wei Huang, Guan-Ming Su, Dinesh Manocha</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VibrantLeaves: A principled parametric image generator for training deep restoration models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.10201</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.10201v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Even though Deep Neural Networks are extremely powerful for image restoration tasks, they have several limitations. They are poorly understood and suffer from strong biases inherited from the training sets. One way to address these shortcomings is to have a better control over the training sets, in particular by using synthetic sets. In this paper, we propose a synthetic image generator relying on a few simple principles. In particular, we focus on geometric modeling, textures, and a simple modeling of image acquisition. These properties, integrated in a classical Dead Leaves model, enable the creation of efficient training sets. Standard image denoising and super-resolution networks can be trained on such datasets, reaching performance almost on par with training on natural image datasets. As a first step towards explainability, we provide a careful analysis of the considered principles, identifying which image properties are necessary to obtain good performances. Besides, such training also yields better robustness to various geometric and radiometric perturbations of the test sets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.10201v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Raphael Achddou, Yann Gousseau, Sa\"id Ladjal, Sabine S\"usstrunk</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FiGO: Fine-Grained Object Counting without Annotations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.11705</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.11705v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Class-agnostic counting (CAC) methods reduce annotation costs by letting users define what to count at test-time through text or visual exemplars. However, current open-vocabulary approaches work well for broad categories but fail when fine-grained category distinctions are needed, such as telling apart waterfowl species or pepper cultivars. We present FiGO, a new annotation-free method that adapts existing counting models to fine-grained categories using only the category name. Our approach uses a text-to-image diffusion model to create synthetic examples and a joint positive/hard-negative loss to learn a compact concept embedding that conditions a specialization module to convert outputs from any frozen counter into accurate, fine-grained estimates. To evaluate fine-grained counting, we introduce LOOKALIKES, a dataset of 37 subcategories across 14 parent categories with many visually similar objects per image. Our method substantially outperforms strong open-vocabulary baselines, moving counting systems from "count all the peppers" to "count only the habaneros."</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.11705v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Adriano D'Alessandro, Ali Mahdavi-Amiri, Ghassan Hamarneh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COMPACT: COMPositional Atomic-to-Complex Visual Capability Tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.21850</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.21850v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Visual instruction tuning (VIT) datasets are constructed from randomly sampled image-question pairs, without regard to the informativeness of each pair. Recent dataset selection methods have shown that a small fraction of such datasets enriched with informative samples can lead to efficient finetuning of Multimodal Large Language Models. In this work, we explore the impact of sample complexity on informative data curation and introduce COMPACT (COMPositional Atomic-to-complex Visual Capability Tuning), a VIT data recipe that scales training sample complexity by combining multiple atomic visual capabilities in a single training example. Concretely, we synthesize rich and informative text questions for each image, allowing us to significantly reduce the number of training examples required for effective visual instruction tuning. COMPACT demonstrates superior data efficiency compared to existing data reduction methods. When applied to the LLAVA-665K VIT dataset, COMPACT reduces the data budget by 90% while still achieving 100.2% of the full VIT performance (compared to only 97.5% by the state-of-the-art method) across eight multimodal benchmarks. Further, training on the COMPACT data outperforms training on the full-scale data on particularly complex benchmarks such as MM-Vet (+8.6%) and MMStar (+2.9%). COMPACT offers a scalable and efficient synthetic data generation recipe to improve on visual language tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.21850v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xindi Wu, Hee Seung Hwang, Polina Kirichenko, Esin Tureci, Olga Russakovsky</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Dataset Copyright Evasion Attack against Personalized Text-to-Image Diffusion Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.02824</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.02824v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Text-to-image (T2I) diffusion models enable high-quality image generation conditioned on textual prompts. However, fine-tuning these pre-trained models for personalization raises concerns about unauthorized dataset usage. To address this issue, dataset ownership verification (DOV) has recently been proposed, which embeds watermarks into fine-tuning datasets via backdoor techniques. These watermarks remain dormant on benign samples but produce owner-specified outputs when triggered. Despite its promise, the robustness of DOV against copyright evasion attacks (CEA) remains unexplored. In this paper, we investigate how adversaries can circumvent these mechanisms, enabling models trained on watermarked datasets to bypass ownership verification. We begin by analyzing the limitations of potential attacks achieved by backdoor removal, including TPD and T2IShield. In practice, TPD suffers from inconsistent effectiveness due to randomness, while T2IShield fails when watermarks are embedded as local image patches. To this end, we introduce CEAT2I, the first CEA specifically targeting DOV in T2I diffusion models. CEAT2I consists of three stages: (1) motivated by the observation that T2I models converge faster on watermarked samples with respect to intermediate features rather than training loss, we reliably detect watermarked samples; (2) we iteratively ablate tokens from the prompts of detected samples and monitor feature shifts to identify trigger tokens; and (3) we apply a closed-form concept erasure method to remove the injected watermarks. Extensive experiments demonstrate that CEAT2I effectively evades state-of-the-art DOV mechanisms while preserving model performance. The code is available at https://github.com/csyufei/CEAT2I.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.02824v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kuofeng Gao, Yufei Zhu, Yiming Li, Jiawang Bai, Yong Yang, Zhifeng Li, Shu-Tao Xia</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Informative Attention Weights for Person Re-Identification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.08961</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.08961v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Attention mechanisms have been widely used in deep learning, and recent efforts have been devoted to incorporating attention modules into deep neural networks (DNNs) for person Re-Identification (Re-ID) to enhance their discriminative feature learning capabilities. Existing attention modules, including self-attention and channel attention, learn attention weights that quantify the importance of feature tokens or feature channels. However, existing attention methods do not explicitly ensure that the attention weights are informative for predicting the identity of the person in the input image, and may consequently introduce noisy information from the input image. To address this issue, we propose a novel method termed Reduction of Information Bottleneck loss (RIB), motivated by the principle of the Information Bottleneck (IB). A novel distribution-free and efficient variational upper bound for the IB loss (IBB), which can be optimized by standard SGD, is derived and incorporated into the training loss of the RIB models. RIB is applied to DNNs with self-attention modules through a novel Differentiable Channel Selection Attention module, or DCS-Attention, that selects the most informative channels for computing attention weights, leading to competitive models termed RIB-DCS. RIB is also incorporated into DNNs with existing channel attention modules to promote the learning of informative channel attention weights, leading to models termed RIB-CA. Both RIB-DCS and RIB-CA are applied to fixed neural network backbones and learnable backbones with Differentiable Neural Architecture Search (DNAS). Extensive experiments on multiple person Re-ID benchmarks show that RIB significantly enhances the prediction accuracy of DNNs for person Re-ID, even for the occluded person Re-ID.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.08961v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yancheng Wang, Nebojsa Jojic, Yingzhen Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Binarization-Aware Adjuster for Discrete Decision Learning with an Application to Edge Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.12460</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.12460v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Discrete decision tasks in machine learning exhibit a fundamental misalignment between training and inference: models are optimized with continuous-valued outputs but evaluated using discrete predictions. This misalignment arises from the discontinuity of discretization operations, which prevents decision behavior from being directly incorporated into gradient-based optimization. To address this issue, we propose a theoretically grounded framework termed the Binarization-Aware Adjuster (BAA), which embeds binarization characteristics into continuous optimization. The framework is built upon the Distance Weight Function (DWF), which modulates loss contributions according to prediction correctness and proximity to the decision threshold, thereby aligning optimization emphasis with decision-critical regions while remaining compatible with standard learning pipelines. We apply the proposed BAA framework to the edge detection (ED) task, a representative binary decision problem. Experimental results on representative models and datasets show that incorporating BAA into optimization leads to consistent performance improvements, supporting its effectiveness. Overall, this work establishes a principled approach for aligning continuous optimization with discrete decision behavior, with its effectiveness demonstrated in a concrete application setting.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.12460v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hao Shu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portable Biomechanics Laboratory: Clinically Accessible Movement Analysis from a Handheld Smartphone</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.08268</link>
      <description>arXiv:2507.08268v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Movement directly reflects neurological and musculoskeletal health, yet objective biomechanical assessment is rarely available in routine care. We introduce Portable Biomechanics Laboratory (PBL), a secure platform for fitting biomechanical models to video collected with a handheld, moving, smartphone. We validate this approach on over 15 hours of data synchronized to ground truth motion capture, finding mean joint-angle errors &lt; 3$\deg$ and pelvis-translation errors of a few centimeters across patients with neurological-injury, lower-limb prosthesis users, pediatric in-patients, and controls. In &gt; 5 hours of prospective deployments to neurosurgery and sports-medicine clinics, PBL was easy to setup, yielded highly reliable gait metrics (ICC &gt; 0.9), and detected clinically relevant differences. For cervical-myelopathy patients, its measurement of gait quality correlated with modified Japanese Orthopedic Association (mJOA) scores and were responsive to clinical intervention. Handheld smartphone video can therefore deliver accurate, scalable, and low-burden biomechanical measurement, enabling greatly increased monitoring of movement impairments. We release the first clinically-validated method for measuring whole-body kinematics from handheld smartphone video at https://IntelligentSensingAndRehabilitation.github.io/MonocularBiomechanics/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2507.08268v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>J. D. Peiffer, Kunal Shah, Irina Djuraskovic, Shawana Anarwala, Kayan Abdou, Rujvee Patel, Prakash Jayabalan, Brenton Pennicooke, R. James Cotton</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Binary to Semantic: Utilizing Large-Scale Binary Occupancy Data for 3D Semantic Occupancy Prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.13387</link>
      <description>arXiv:2507.13387v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Accurate perception of the surrounding environment is essential for safe autonomous driving. 3D occupancy prediction, which estimates detailed 3D structures of roads, buildings, and other objects, is particularly important for vision-centric autonomous driving systems that do not rely on LiDAR sensors. However, in 3D semantic occupancy prediction -- where each voxel is assigned a semantic label -- annotated LiDAR point clouds are required, making data acquisition costly. In contrast, large-scale binary occupancy data, which only indicate occupied or free space without semantic labels, can be collected at a lower cost. Despite their availability, the potential of leveraging such data remains unexplored. In this study, we investigate the utilization of large-scale binary occupancy data from two perspectives: (1) pre-training and (2) learning-based auto-labeling. We propose a novel binary occupancy-based framework that decomposes the prediction process into binary and semantic occupancy modules, enabling effective use of binary occupancy data. Our experimental results demonstrate that the proposed framework outperforms existing methods in both pre-training and auto-labeling tasks, highlighting its effectiveness in enhancing 3D semantic occupancy prediction. The code will be available at https://github.com/ToyotaInfoTech/b2s-occupancy</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2507.13387v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chihiro Noguchi, Takaki Yamamoto</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RemoteReasoner: Towards Unifying Geospatial Reasoning Workflow</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.19280</link>
      <description>arXiv:2507.19280v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Remote sensing imagery presents vast, inherently unstructured spatial data, necessitating sophisticated reasoning to interpret complex user intents and contextual relationships beyond simple recognition tasks. In this paper, we aim to construct an Earth observation workflow to handle complex queries by reasoning about spatial context and user intent. As a reasoning workflow, it should autonomously explore and construct its own inference paths, rather than being confined to predefined ground-truth sequences. Ideally, its architecture ought to be unified yet generalized, possessing capabilities to perform diverse reasoning tasks through one model without requiring additional fine-tuning. Existing remote sensing approaches rely on supervised fine-tuning paradigms and task-specific heads, limiting both autonomous reasoning and unified generalization. To this end, we propose RemoteReasoner, a unified workflow for geospatial reasoning. The design of RemoteReasoner integrates a multi-modal large language model (MLLM) for interpreting user instructions and localizing targets, together with task transformation strategies that enable multi-granularity tasks, including object-, region-, and pixel-level. In contrast to existing methods, our framework is trained with reinforcement learning (RL) to endow the MLLM sufficient reasoning autonomy. At the inference stage, our transformation strategies enable diverse task output formats without requiring task-specific decoders or further fine-tuning. Experiments demonstrated that RemoteReasoner achieves state-of-the-art (SOTA) performance across multi-granularity reasoning tasks. Furthermore, it retains the MLLM's inherent generalization capability, demonstrating robust performance on unseen tasks and out-of-distribution categories.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2507.19280v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Liang Yao, Fan Liu, Hongbo Lu, Chuanyi Zhang, Rui Min, Shengxiang Xu, Shimin Di, Pai Peng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LAMIC: Layout-Aware Multi-Image Composition via Scalability of Multimodal Diffusion Transformer</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.00477</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.00477v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In controllable image synthesis, generating coherent and consistent images from multiple references with spatial layout awareness remains an open challenge. We present LAMIC, a Layout-Aware Multi-Image Composition framework that, for the first time, extends single-reference diffusion models to multi-reference scenarios in a training-free manner. Built upon the MMDiT model, LAMIC introduces two plug-and-play attention mechanisms: 1) Group Isolation Attention (GIA) to enhance entity disentanglement; and 2) Region-Modulated Attention (RMA) to enable layout-aware generation. To comprehensively evaluate model capabilities, we further introduce three metrics: 1) Inclusion Ratio (IN-R) and Fill Ratio (FI-R) for assessing layout control; and 2) Background Similarity (BG-S) for measuring background consistency. Extensive experiments show that LAMIC achieves state-of-the-art performance across most major metrics: it consistently outperforms existing multi-reference baselines in ID-S, BG-S, IN-R and AVG scores across all settings, and achieves the best DPG in complex composition tasks. These results demonstrate LAMIC's superior abilities in identity keeping, background preservation, layout control, and prompt-following, all achieved without any training or fine-tuning, showcasing strong zero-shot generalization ability. By inheriting the strengths of advanced single-reference models and enabling seamless extension to multi-image scenarios, LAMIC establishes a new training-free paradigm for controllable multi-image composition. As foundation models continue to evolve, LAMIC's performance is expected to scale accordingly. Our implementation is available at: https://github.com/Suchenl/LAMIC.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.00477v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuzhuo Chen, Zehua Ma, Jianhua Wang, Kai Kang, Shunyu Yao, Weiming Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simulated Ensemble Attack: Transferring Jailbreaks Across Fine-tuned Vision-Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.01741</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.01741v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Fine-tuning open-source Vision-Language Models (VLMs) creates a critical yet underexplored attack surface: vulnerabilities in the base VLM could be retained in fine-tuned variants, rendering them susceptible to transferable jailbreak attacks. To demonstrate this risk, we introduce the Simulated Ensemble Attack (SEA), a novel grey-box jailbreak method in which the adversary has full access to the base VLM but no knowledge of the fine-tuned target's weights or training configuration. To improve jailbreak transferability across fine-tuned VLMs, SEA combines two key techniques: Fine-tuning Trajectory Simulation (FTS) and Targeted Prompt Guidance (TPG). FTS generates transferable adversarial images by simulating the vision encoder's parameter shifts, while TPG is a textual strategy that steers the language decoder toward adversarially optimized outputs. Experiments on the Qwen2-VL family (2B and 7B) demonstrate that SEA achieves high transfer attack success rates exceeding 86.5% and toxicity rates near 49.5% across diverse fine-tuned variants, even those specifically fine-tuned to improve safety behaviors. Notably, while direct PGD-based image jailbreaks rarely transfer across fine-tuned VLMs, SEA reliably exploits inherited vulnerabilities from the base model, significantly enhancing transferability. These findings highlight an urgent need to safeguard fine-tuned proprietary VLMs against transferable vulnerabilities inherited from open-source foundations, motivating the development of holistic defenses across the entire model lifecycle.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.01741v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ruofan Wang, Xin Wang, Yang Yao, Xuan Tong, Xingjun Ma</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reinforcement Learning for Large Model: A Survey</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.08189</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.08189v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advances at the intersection of reinforcement learning (RL) and visual intelligence have enabled agents that not only perceive complex visual scenes but also reason, generate, and act within them. This survey offers a critical and up-to-date synthesis of the field. We first formalize visual RL problems and trace the evolution of policy-optimization strategies from RLHF to verifiable reward paradigms, and from Proximal Policy Optimization to Group Relative Policy Optimization. We then organize more than 200 representative works into four thematic pillars: multi-modal large language models, visual generation, unified model frameworks, and vision-language-action models. For each pillar we examine algorithmic design, reward engineering, benchmark progress, and we distill trends such as curriculum-driven training, preference-aligned diffusion, and unified reward modeling. Finally, we review evaluation protocols spanning set-level fidelity, sample-level preference, and state-level stability, and we identify open challenges that include sample efficiency, generalization, and safe deployment. Our goal is to provide researchers and practitioners with a coherent map of the rapidly expanding landscape of visual RL and to highlight promising directions for future inquiry. Resources are available at: https://github.com/weijiawu/Awesome-Visual-Reinforcement-Learning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.08189v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weijia Wu, Chen Gao, Joya Chen, Kevin Qinghong Lin, Qingwei Meng, Yiming Zhang, Yuke Qiu, Hong Zhou, Mike Zheng Shou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drifting Away from Truth: GenAI-Driven News Diversity Challenges LVLM-Based Misinformation Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.12711</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.12711v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The proliferation of multimodal misinformation poses growing threats to public discourse and societal trust. While Large Vision-Language Models (LVLMs) have enabled recent progress in multimodal misinformation detection (MMD), the rise of generative AI (GenAI) tools introduces a new challenge: GenAI-driven news diversity, characterized by highly varied and complex content. We show that this diversity induces multi-level drift, comprising (1) model-level misperception drift, where stylistic variations disrupt a model's internal reasoning, and (2) evidence-level drift, where expression diversity degrades the quality or relevance of retrieved external evidence. These drifts significantly degrade the robustness of current LVLM-based MMD systems. To systematically study this problem, we introduce DriftBench, a large-scale benchmark comprising 16,000 news instances across six categories of diversification. We design three evaluation tasks: (1) robustness of truth verification under multi-level drift; (2) susceptibility to adversarial evidence contamination generated by GenAI; and (3) analysis of reasoning consistency across diverse inputs. Experiments with six state-of-the-art LVLM-based detectors show substantial performance drops (average F1 -14.8%) and increasingly unstable reasoning traces, with even more severe failures under adversarial evidence injection. Our findings uncover fundamental vulnerabilities in existing MMD systems and suggest an urgent need for more resilient approaches in the GenAI era.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.12711v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fanxiao Li, Jiaying Wu, Tingchao Fu, Yunyun Dong, Bingbing Song, Wei Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EmoCAST: Emotional Talking Portrait via Emotive Text Description</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.20615</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.20615v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Emotional talking head synthesis aims to generate talking portrait videos with vivid expressions. Existing methods still exhibit limitations in control flexibility, motion naturalness, and expression quality. Moreover, currently available datasets are mainly collected in lab settings, further exacerbating these shortcomings and hindering real-world deployment. To address these challenges, we propose EmoCAST, a diffusion-based talking head framework for precise, text-driven emotional synthesis. Its contributions are threefold: (1) architectural modules that enable effective text control; (2) an emotional talking-head dataset that expands the framework's ability; and (3) training strategies that further improve performance. Specifically, for appearance modeling, emotional prompts are integrated through a text-guided emotive attention module, enhancing spatial knowledge to improve emotion understanding. To strengthen audio-emotion alignment, we introduce an emotive audio attention module to capture the interplay between controlled emotion and driving audio, generating emotion-aware features to guide precise facial motion synthesis. Additionally, we construct a large-scale, in-the-wild emotional talking head dataset with emotive text descriptions to optimize the framework's performance. Based on this dataset, we propose an emotion-aware sampling strategy and a progressive functional training strategy that improve the model's ability to capture nuanced expressive features and achieve accurate lip-sync. Overall, EmoCAST achieves state-of-the-art performance in generating realistic, emotionally expressive, and audio-synchronized talking-head videos. Project Page: https://github.com/GVCLab/EmoCAST</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.20615v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yiguo Jiang, Xiaodong Cun, Yong Zhang, Yudian Zheng, Fan Tang, Chi-Man Pun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WaveletGaussian: Wavelet-domain Diffusion for Sparse-view 3D Gaussian Object Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.19073</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.19073v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: 3D Gaussian Splatting (3DGS) has become a powerful representation for image-based object reconstruction, yet its performance drops sharply in sparse-view settings. Prior works address this limitation by employing diffusion models to repair corrupted renders, subsequently using them as pseudo ground truths for later optimization. While effective, such approaches incur heavy computation from the diffusion fine-tuning and repair steps. We present WaveletGaussian, a framework for more efficient sparse-view 3D Gaussian object reconstruction. Our key idea is to shift diffusion into the wavelet domain: diffusion is applied only to the low-resolution LL subband, while high-frequency subbands are refined with a lightweight network. We further propose an efficient online random masking strategy to curate training pairs for diffusion fine-tuning, replacing the commonly used, but inefficient, leave-one-out strategy. Experiments across two benchmark datasets, Mip-NeRF 360 and OmniObject3D, show WaveletGaussian achieves competitive rendering quality while substantially reducing training time.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.19073v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>eess.SP</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hung Nguyen, Runfa Li, An Le, Truong Nguyen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resolution scaling governs DINOv3 transfer performance in chest radiograph classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.07191</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.07191v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Self-supervised learning (SSL) has advanced visual representation learning, but its value in chest radiography, a high-volume imaging modality with fine-grained findings, remains unclear. Meta's DINOv3 extends earlier SSL models through Gram-anchored self-distillation. Whether these design choices improve transfer learning for chest radiography has not been systematically tested. We benchmarked DINOv3 against DINOv2 and ImageNet initialization across seven datasets (n&gt;814,000). Two representative backbones were evaluated: ViT-B/16 and ConvNeXt-B. Images were analyzed at 224x224, 512x512, and 1024x1024 pixels. We additionally assessed frozen features from a 7B model. The primary outcome was mean AUROC across labels. At 224x224, DINOv3 and DINOv2 achieved comparable performance on adult datasets. Increasing resolution to 512x512 yielded consistent improvements for DINOv3 over both DINOv2 and ImageNet. In contrast, results in pediatric cohort showed no differences across initializations. Across all settings, ConvNeXt-B outperformed ViT-B/16. Models using frozen DINOv3-7B features underperformed relative to fully finetuned 86-89M-parameter backbones, highlighting the importance of domain adaptation. Scaling to 1024x1024 did not further improve accuracy. Resolution-related gains were most evident for boundary-dependent and small focal abnormalities. In chest radiography, higher input resolution is critical for leveraging the benefits of modern self-supervised models. 512x512 pixels represent a practical upper limit where DINOv3-initialized ConvNeXt-B networks provide the strongest performance, while larger inputs offer minimal return on cost. Clinically, these findings support use of finetuned, mid-sized backbones at 512x512 for chest radiograph interpretation, with the greatest gains expected in detecting subtle or boundary-centered lesions relevant to emergency and critical care settings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.07191v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Soroosh Tayebi Arasteh, Mina Shaigan, Christiane Kuhl, Jakob Nikolas Kather, Sven Nebelung, Daniel Truhn</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weakly Supervised Ephemeral Gully Detection In Remote Sensing Images Using Vision Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.13891</link>
      <description>arXiv:2511.13891v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Among soil erosion problems, Ephemeral Gullies are one of the most concerning phenomena occurring in agricultural fields. Their short temporal cycles increase the difficulty in automatically detecting them using classical computer vision approaches and remote sensing. Also, due to scarcity of and the difficulty in producing accurate labeled data, automatic detection of ephemeral gullies using Machine Learning is limited to zero-shot approaches which are hard to implement. To overcome these challenges, we present the first weakly supervised pipeline for detection of ephemeral gullies. Our method relies on remote sensing and uses Vision Language Models (VLMs) to drastically reduce the labor-intensive task of manual labeling. In order to achieve that, the method exploits: 1) the knowledge embedded in the VLM's pretraining; 2) a teacher-student model where the teacher learns from noisy labels coming from the VLMs, and the student learns by weak supervision using teacher-generate labels and a noise-aware loss function. We also make available the first-of-its-kind dataset for semi-supervised detection of ephemeral gully from remote-sensed images. The dataset consists of a number of locations labeled by a group of soil and plant scientists, as well as a large number of unlabeled locations. The dataset represent more than 18,000 high-resolution remote-sensing images obtained over the course of 13 years. Our experimental results demonstrate the validity of our approach by showing superior performances compared to VLMs and the label model itself when using weak supervision to train an student model. The code and dataset for this work are made publicly available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2511.13891v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Seyed Mohamad Ali Tousi, Ramy Farag, John A. Lory, G. N. DeSouza</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vision Language Models are Confused Tourists</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17004</link>
      <description>arXiv:2511.17004v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Although the cultural dimension has been one of the key aspects in evaluating Vision-Language Models (VLMs), their ability to remain stable across diverse cultural inputs remains largely untested, despite being crucial to support diversity and multicultural societies. Existing evaluations often rely on benchmarks featuring only a singular cultural concept per image, overlooking scenarios where multiple, potentially unrelated cultural cues coexist. To address this gap, we introduce ConfusedTourist, a novel cultural adversarial robustness suite designed to assess VLMs' stability against perturbed geographical cues. Our experiments reveal a critical vulnerability, where accuracy drops heavily under simple image-stacking perturbations and even worsens with its image-generation-based variant. Interpretability analyses further show that these failures stem from systematic attention shifts toward distracting cues, diverting the model from its intended focus. These findings highlight a critical challenge: visual cultural concept mixing can substantially impair even state-of-the-art VLMs, underscoring the urgent need for more culturally robust multimodal understanding.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2511.17004v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Patrick Amadeus Irawan, Ikhlasul Akmal Hanif, Muhammad Dehan Al Kautsar, Genta Indra Winata, Fajri Koto, Alham Fikri Aji</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video Generation Models Are Good Latent Reward Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.21541</link>
      <description>arXiv:2511.21541v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Reward feedback learning (ReFL) has proven effective for aligning image generation with human preferences. However, its extension to video generation faces significant challenges. Existing video reward models rely on vision-language models designed for pixel-space inputs, confining ReFL optimization to near-complete denoising steps after computationally expensive VAE decoding. This pixel-space approach incurs substantial memory overhead and increased training time, and its late-stage optimization lacks early-stage supervision, refining only visual quality rather than fundamental motion dynamics and structural coherence. In this work, we show that pre-trained video generation models are naturally suited for reward modeling in the noisy latent space, as they are explicitly designed to process noisy latent representations at arbitrary timesteps and inherently preserve temporal information through their sequential modeling capabilities. Accordingly, we propose Process Reward Feedback Learning~(PRFL), a framework that conducts preference optimization entirely in latent space, enabling efficient gradient backpropagation throughout the full denoising chain without VAE decoding. Extensive experiments demonstrate that PRFL significantly improves alignment with human preferences, while achieving substantial reductions in memory consumption and training time compared to RGB ReFL.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2511.21541v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoyue Mi, Wenqing Yu, Jiesong Lian, Shibo Jie, Ruizhe Zhong, Zijun Liu, Guozhen Zhang, Zixiang Zhou, Zhiyong Xu, Yuan Zhou, Qinglin Lu, Fan Tang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TriDF: Evaluating Perception, Detection, and Hallucination for Interpretable DeepFake Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.10652</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.10652v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Advances in generative modeling have made it increasingly easy to fabricate realistic portrayals of individuals, creating serious risks for security, communication, and public trust. Detecting such person-driven manipulations requires systems that not only distinguish altered content from authentic media but also provide clear and reliable reasoning. In this paper, we introduce TriDF, a comprehensive benchmark for interpretable DeepFake detection. TriDF contains high-quality forgeries from advanced synthesis models, covering 16 DeepFake types across image, video, and audio modalities. The benchmark evaluates three key aspects: Perception, which measures the ability of a model to identify fine-grained manipulation artifacts using human-annotated evidence; Detection, which assesses classification performance across diverse forgery families and generators; and Hallucination, which quantifies the reliability of model-generated explanations. Experiments on state-of-the-art multimodal large language models show that accurate perception is essential for reliable detection, but hallucination can severely disrupt decision-making, revealing the interdependence of these three aspects. TriDF provides a unified framework for understanding the interaction between detection accuracy, evidence identification, and explanation reliability, offering a foundation for building trustworthy systems that address real-world synthetic media threats.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.10652v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jian-Yu Jiang-Lin, Kang-Yang Huang, Ling Zou, Ling Lo, Sheng-Ping Yang, Yu-Wen Tseng, Kun-Hsiang Lin, Chia-Ling Chen, Yu-Ting Ta, Yan-Tsung Wang, Po-Ching Chen, Hongxia Xie, Hong-Han Shuai, Wen-Huang Cheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seedance 1.5 pro: A Native Audio-Visual Joint Generation Foundation Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.13507</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.13507v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent strides in video generation have paved the way for unified audio-visual generation. In this work, we present Seedance 1.5 pro, a foundational model engineered specifically for native, joint audio-video generation. Leveraging a dual-branch Diffusion Transformer architecture, the model integrates a cross-modal joint module with a specialized multi-stage data pipeline, achieving exceptional audio-visual synchronization and superior generation quality. To ensure practical utility, we implement meticulous post-training optimizations, including Supervised Fine-Tuning (SFT) on high-quality datasets and Reinforcement Learning from Human Feedback (RLHF) with multi-dimensional reward models. Furthermore, we introduce an acceleration framework that boosts inference speed by over 10X. Seedance 1.5 pro distinguishes itself through precise multilingual and dialect lip-syncing, dynamic cinematic camera control, and enhanced narrative coherence, positioning it as a robust engine for professional-grade content creation. Seedance 1.5 pro is now accessible on Volcano Engine at https://console.volcengine.com/ark/region:ark+cn-beijing/experience/vision?type=GenVideo.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.13507v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Team Seedance, Heyi Chen, Siyan Chen, Xin Chen, Yanfei Chen, Ying Chen, Zhuo Chen, Feng Cheng, Tianheng Cheng, Xinqi Cheng, Xuyan Chi, Jian Cong, Jing Cui, Qinpeng Cui, Qide Dong, Junliang Fan, Jing Fang, Zetao Fang, Chengjian Feng, Han Feng, Mingyuan Gao, Yu Gao, Dong Guo, Qiushan Guo, Boyang Hao, Qingkai Hao, Bibo He, Qian He, Tuyen Hoang, Ruoqing Hu, Xi Hu, Weilin Huang, Zhaoyang Huang, Zhongyi Huang, Donglei Ji, Siqi Jiang, Wei Jiang, Yunpu Jiang, Zhuo Jiang, Ashley Kim, Jianan Kong, Zhichao Lai, Shanshan Lao, Yichong Leng, Ai Li, Feiya Li, Gen Li, Huixia Li, JiaShi Li, Liang Li, Ming Li, Shanshan Li, Tao Li, Xian Li, Xiaojie Li, Xiaoyang Li, Xingxing Li, Yameng Li, Yifu Li, Yiying Li, Chao Liang, Han Liang, Jianzhong Liang, Ying Liang, Zhiqiang Liang, Wang Liao, Yalin Liao, Heng Lin, Kengyu Lin, Shanchuan Lin, Xi Lin, Zhijie Lin, Feng Ling, Fangfang Liu, Gaohong Liu, Jiawei Liu, Jie Liu, Jihao Liu, Shouda Liu, Shu Liu, Sichao Liu, Songwei Liu, Xin Liu, Xue Liu, Yibo Liu, Zikun Liu, Zuxi Liu, Junlin Lyu, Lecheng Lyu, Qian Lyu, Han Mu, Xiaonan Nie, Jingzhe Ning, Xitong Pan, Yanghua Peng, Lianke Qin, Xueqiong Qu, Yuxi Ren, Kai Shen, Guang Shi, Lei Shi, Yan Song, Yinglong Song, Fan Sun, Li Sun, Renfei Sun, Yan Sun, Zeyu Sun, Wenjing Tang, Yaxue Tang, Zirui Tao, Feng Wang, Furui Wang, Jinran Wang, Junkai Wang, Ke Wang, Kexin Wang, Qingyi Wang, Rui Wang, Sen Wang, Shuai Wang, Tingru Wang, Weichen Wang, Xin Wang, Yanhui Wang, Yue Wang, Yuping Wang, Yuxuan Wang, Ziyu Wang, Guoqiang Wei, Wanru Wei, Di Wu, Guohong Wu, Hanjie Wu, Jian Wu, Jie Wu, Ruolan Wu, Xinglong Wu, Yonghui Wu, Ruiqi Xia, Liang Xiang, Fei Xiao, XueFeng Xiao, Pan Xie, Shuangyi Xie, Shuang Xu, Jinlan Xue, Shen Yan, Bangbang Yang, Ceyuan Yang, Jiaqi Yang, Runkai Yang, Tao Yang, Yang Yang, Yihang Yang, ZhiXian Yang, Ziyan Yang, Songting Yao, Yifan Yao, Zilyu Ye, Bowen Yu, Jian Yu, Chujie Yuan, Linxiao Yuan, Sichun Zeng, Weihong Zeng, Xuejiao Zeng, Yan Zeng, Chuntao Zhang, Heng Zhang, Jingjie Zhang, Kuo Zhang, Liang Zhang, Liying Zhang, Manlin Zhang, Ting Zhang, Weida Zhang, Xiaohe Zhang, Xinyan Zhang, Yan Zhang, Yuan Zhang, Zixiang Zhang, Fengxuan Zhao, Huating Zhao, Yang Zhao, Hao Zheng, Jianbin Zheng, Xiaozheng Zheng, Yangyang Zheng, Yijie Zheng, Jiexin Zhou, Jiahui Zhu, Kuan Zhu, Shenhan Zhu, Wenjia Zhu, Benhui Zou, Feilong Zuo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VTCBench: Can Vision-Language Models Understand Long Context with Vision-Text Compression?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.15649</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.15649v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The computational and memory overheads associated with expanding the context window of LLMs severely limit their scalability. A noteworthy solution is vision-text compression (VTC), exemplified by frameworks like DeepSeek-OCR and Glyph, which convert long texts into dense 2D visual representations, thereby achieving token compression ratios of 3x-20x. However, the impact of this high information density on the core long-context capabilities of vision-language models (VLMs) remains under-investigated. To address this gap, we introduce the first benchmark for VTC and systematically assess the performance of VLMs across three long-context understanding settings: VTC-Retrieval, which evaluates the model's ability to retrieve and aggregate information; VTC-Reasoning, which requires models to infer latent associations to locate facts with minimal lexical overlap; and VTC-Memory, which measures comprehensive question answering within long-term dialogue memory. Furthermore, we establish the VTCBench-Wild to simulate diverse input scenarios.We comprehensively evaluate leading open-source and proprietary models on our benchmarks. The results indicate that, despite being able to decode textual information (e.g., OCR) well, most VLMs exhibit a surprisingly poor long-context understanding ability with VTC-processed information, failing to capture long associations or dependencies in the context.This study provides a deep understanding of VTC and serves as a foundation for designing more efficient and scalable VLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.15649v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hongbo Zhao, Meng Wang, Fei Zhu, Wenzhuo Liu, Bolin Ni, Fanhu Zeng, Gaofeng Meng, Zhaoxiang Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Next-Embedding Prediction Makes Strong Vision Learners</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.16922</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.16922v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Inspired by the success of generative pretraining in natural language, we ask whether the same principles can yield strong self-supervised visual learners. Instead of training models to output features for downstream use, we train them to generate embeddings to perform predictive tasks directly. This work explores such a shift from learning representations to learning models. Specifically, models learn to predict future patch embeddings conditioned on past ones, using causal masking and stop gradient, which we refer to as Next-Embedding Predictive Autoregression (NEPA). We demonstrate that a simple Transformer pretrained on ImageNet-1k with next embedding prediction as its sole learning objective is effective - no pixel reconstruction, discrete tokens, contrastive loss, or task-specific heads. This formulation retains architectural simplicity and scalability, without requiring additional design complexity. NEPA achieves strong results across tasks, attaining 83.8% and 85.3% top-1 accuracy on ImageNet-1K with ViT-B and ViT-L backbones after fine-tuning, and transferring effectively to semantic segmentation on ADE20K. We believe generative pretraining from embeddings provides a simple, scalable, and potentially modality-agnostic alternative to visual self-supervised learning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.16922v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sihan Xu, Ziqiao Ma, Wenhao Chai, Xuweiyi Chen, Weiyang Jin, Joyce Chai, Saining Xie, Stella X. Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HeadHunt-VAD: Hunting Robust Anomaly-Sensitive Heads in MLLM for Tuning-Free Video Anomaly Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.17601</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.17601v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Video Anomaly Detection (VAD) aims to locate events that deviate from normal patterns in videos. Traditional approaches often rely on extensive labeled data and incur high computational costs. Recent tuning-free methods based on Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) offer a promising alternative by leveraging their rich world knowledge. However, these methods typically rely on textual outputs, which introduces information loss, exhibits normalcy bias, and suffers from prompt sensitivity, making them insufficient for capturing subtle anomalous cues. To address these constraints, we propose HeadHunt-VAD, a novel tuning-free VAD paradigm that bypasses textual generation by directly hunting robust anomaly-sensitive internal attention heads within the frozen MLLM. Central to our method is a Robust Head Identification module that systematically evaluates all attention heads using a multi-criteria analysis of saliency and stability, identifying a sparse subset of heads that are consistently discriminative across diverse prompts. Features from these expert heads are then fed into a lightweight anomaly scorer and a temporal locator, enabling efficient and accurate anomaly detection with interpretable outputs. Extensive experiments show that HeadHunt-VAD achieves state-of-the-art performance among tuning-free methods on two major VAD benchmarks while maintaining high efficiency, validating head-level probing in MLLMs as a powerful and practical solution for real-world anomaly detection.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.17601v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhaolin Cai, Fan Li, Ziwei Zheng, Haixia Bi, Lijun He</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LiteGE: Lightweight Geodesic Embedding for Efficient Geodesics Computation and Non-Isometric Shape Correspondence</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.17781</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.17781v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Computing geodesic distances on 3D surfaces is fundamental to many tasks in 3D vision and geometry processing, with deep connections to tasks such as shape correspondence. Recent learning-based methods achieve strong performance but rely on large 3D backbones, leading to high memory usage and latency, which limit their use in interactive or resource-constrained settings. We introduce LiteGE, a lightweight approach that constructs compact, category-aware shape descriptors by applying Principal Component Analysis (PCA) to unsigned distance field (UDFs) samples at informative voxels. This descriptor is efficient to compute and removes the need for high-capacity networks. LiteGE remains robust on sparse point clouds, supporting inputs with as few as 300 points, where prior methods fail. Extensive experiments show that LiteGE reduces memory usage and inference time by up to 300$\times$ compared to existing neural approaches. In addition, by exploiting the intrinsic relationship between geodesic distance and shape correspondence, LiteGE enables fast and accurate shape matching. Our method achieves up to 1000$\times$ speedup over state-of-the-art mesh-based approaches while maintaining comparable accuracy on non-isometric shape pairs, including evaluations on point-cloud inputs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.17781v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yohanes Yudhi Adikusuma, Qixing Huang, Ying He</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UniMPR: A Unified Framework for Multimodal Place Recognition with Heterogeneous Sensor Configurations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.18279</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.18279v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Place recognition is a critical component of autonomous vehicles and robotics, enabling global localization in GPS-denied environments. Recent advances have spurred significant interest in multimodal place recognition (MPR), which leverages complementary strengths of multiple modalities. Despite its potential, most existing MPR methods still face three key challenges: (1) dynamically adapting to various modality inputs within a unified framework, (2) maintaining robustness with missing or degraded modalities, and (3) generalizing across diverse sensor configurations and setups. In this paper, we propose UniMPR, a unified framework for multimodal place recognition. Using only one trained model, it can seamlessly adapt to any combination of common perceptual modalities (e.g., camera, LiDAR, radar). To tackle the data heterogeneity, we unify all inputs within a polar BEV feature space. Subsequently, the polar BEVs are fed into a multi-branch network to exploit discriminative intra-model and inter-modal features from any modality combinations. To fully exploit the network's generalization capability and robustness, we construct a large-scale training set from multiple datasets and introduce an adaptive label assignment strategy for extensive pre-training. Experiments on seven datasets demonstrate that UniMPR achieves state-of-the-art performance under varying sensor configurations, modality combinations, and environmental conditions. Our code will be released at https://github.com/QiZS-BIT/UniMPR.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.18279v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhangshuo Qi, Jingyi Xu, Luqi Cheng, Shichen Wen, Yiming Ma, Guangming Xiong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memorize-and-Generate: Towards Long-Term Consistency in Real-Time Video Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.18741</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.18741v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Frame-level autoregressive (frame-AR) models have achieved significant progress, enabling real-time video generation comparable to bidirectional diffusion models and serving as a foundation for interactive world models and game engines. However, current approaches in long video generation typically rely on window attention, which naively discards historical context outside the window, leading to catastrophic forgetting and scene inconsistency; conversely, retaining full history incurs prohibitive memory costs. To address this trade-off, we propose Memorize-and-Generate (MAG), a framework that decouples memory compression and frame generation into distinct tasks. Specifically, we train a memory model to compress historical information into a compact KV cache, and a separate generator model to synthesize subsequent frames utilizing this compressed representation. Furthermore, we introduce MAG-Bench to strictly evaluate historical memory retention. Extensive experiments demonstrate that MAG achieves superior historical scene consistency while maintaining competitive performance on standard video generation benchmarks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.18741v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tianrui Zhu, Shiyi Zhang, Zhirui Sun, Jingqi Tian, Yansong Tang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neural Implicit Heart Coordinates: 3D cardiac shape reconstruction from sparse segmentations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.19316</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.19316v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Accurate reconstruction of cardiac anatomy from sparse clinical images remains a major challenge in patient-specific modeling. While neural implicit functions have previously been applied to this task, their application to mapping anatomical consistency across subjects has been limited. In this work, we introduce Neural Implicit Heart Coordinates (NIHCs), a standardized implicit coordinate system, based on universal ventricular coordinates, that provides a common anatomical reference frame for the human heart. Our method predicts NIHCs directly from a limited number of 2D segmentations (sparse acquisition) and subsequently decodes them into dense 3D segmentations and high-resolution meshes at arbitrary output resolution. Trained on a large dataset of 5,000 cardiac meshes, the model achieves high reconstruction accuracy on clinical contours, with mean Euclidean surface errors of 2.51$\pm$0.33 mm in a diseased cohort (n=4549) and 2.3$\pm$0.36 mm in a healthy cohort (n=5576). The NIHC representation enables anatomically coherent reconstruction even under severe slice sparsity and segmentation noise, faithfully recovering complex structures such as the valve planes. Compared with traditional pipelines, inference time is reduced from over 60 s to 5-15 s. These results demonstrate that NIHCs constitute a robust and efficient anatomical representation for patient-specific 3D cardiac reconstruction from minimal input data.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.19316v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Marica Muffoletto, Uxio Hermida, Charl\`ene Mauger, Avan Suinesiaputra, Yiyang Xu, Richard Burns, Lisa Pankewitz, Andrew D McCulloch, Steffen E Petersen, Daniel Rueckert, Alistair A Young</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reinforcement Learning for Unsupervised Video Summarization with Reward Generator Training</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.04258</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.04258v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: This paper presents a novel approach for unsupervised video summarization using reinforcement learning (RL), addressing limitations like unstable adversarial training and reliance on heuristic-based reward functions. The method operates on the principle that reconstruction fidelity serves as a proxy for informativeness, correlating summary quality with reconstruction ability. The summarizer model assigns importance scores to frames to generate the final summary. For training, RL is coupled with a unique reward generation pipeline that incentivizes improved reconstructions. This pipeline uses a generator model to reconstruct the full video from the selected summary frames; the similarity between the original and reconstructed video provides the reward signal. The generator itself is pre-trained self-supervisedly to reconstruct randomly masked frames. This two-stage training process enhances stability compared to adversarial architectures. Experimental results show strong alignment with human judgments and promising F-scores, validating the reconstruction objective.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.04258v2</guid>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1109/TCSVT.2025.3623074</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Mehryar Abbasi, Hadi Hadizadeh, Parvaneh Saeedi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiscale Corrections by Continuous Super-Resolution</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.07576</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.07576v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Finite element methods typically require a high resolution to satisfactorily approximate micro and even macro patterns of an underlying physical model. This issue can be circumvented by appropriate multiscale strategies that are able to obtain reasonable approximations on under-resolved scales. In this paper, we study the implicit neural representation and propose a continuous super-resolution network as a correction strategy for multiscale effects. It can take coarse finite element data to learn both in-distribution and out-of-distribution high-resolution finite element predictions. Our highlight is the design of a local implicit transformer, which is able to learn multiscale features. We also propose Gabor wavelet-based coordinate encodings, which can overcome the bias of neural networks learning low-frequency features. Finally, perception is often preferred over distortion, so scientists can recognize the visual pattern for further investigation. However, implicit neural representation is known for its lack of local pattern supervision. We propose to use stochastic cosine similarities to compare the local feature differences between prediction and ground truth. It shows better performance on structural alignments. Our experiments show that our proposed strategy achieves superior performance as an in-distribution and out-of-distribution super-resolution strategy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.07576v2</guid>
      <category>math.NA</category>
      <category>cs.CE</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.NA</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhi-Song Liu, Roland Maier, Andreas Rupp</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning for Spatio-Temporal Fusion in Land Surface Temperature Estimation: A Comprehensive Survey, Experimental Analysis, and Future Trends</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.16631</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.16631v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Land Surface Temperature (LST) plays a key role in climate monitoring, urban heat assessment, and land-atmosphere interactions. However, current thermal infrared satellite sensors cannot simultaneously achieve high spatial and temporal resolution. Spatio-temporal fusion (STF) techniques address this limitation by combining complementary satellite data, one with high spatial but low temporal resolution, and another with high temporal but low spatial resolution. Existing STF techniques, from classical models to modern deep learning (DL) architectures, were primarily developed for surface reflectance (SR). Their application to thermal data remains limited and often overlooks LST-specific spatial and temporal variability. This study provides a focused review of DL-based STF methods for LST. We present a formal mathematical definition of the thermal fusion task, propose a refined taxonomy of relevant DL methods, and analyze the modifications required when adapting SR-oriented models to LST. To support reproducibility and benchmarking, we introduce a new dataset comprising 51 Terra MODIS-Landsat LST pairs from 2013 to 2024, and evaluate representative models to explore their behavior on thermal data. The analysis highlights performance gaps, architecture sensitivities, and open research challenges. The dataset and accompanying resources are publicly available at https://github.com/Sofianebouaziz1/STF-LST.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.16631v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sofiane Bouaziz, Adel Hafiane, Raphael Canals, Rachid Nedjai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GradMix: Gradient-based Selective Mixup for Robust Data Augmentation in Class-Incremental Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.08528</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.08528v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In the context of continual learning, acquiring new knowledge while maintaining previous knowledge presents a significant challenge. Existing methods often use experience replay techniques that store a small portion of previous task data for training. In experience replay approaches, data augmentation has emerged as a promising strategy to further improve the model performance by mixing limited previous task data with sufficient current task data. However, we theoretically and empirically analyze that training with mixed samples from random sample pairs may harm the knowledge of previous tasks and cause greater catastrophic forgetting. We then propose GradMix, a robust data augmentation method specifically designed for mitigating catastrophic forgetting in class-incremental learning. GradMix performs gradient-based selective mixup using a class-based criterion that mixes only samples from helpful class pairs and not from detrimental class pairs for reducing catastrophic forgetting. Our experiments on various real datasets show that GradMix outperforms data augmentation baselines in accuracy by minimizing the forgetting of previous knowledge.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.08528v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Minsu Kim, Seong-Hyeon Hwang, Steven Euijong Whang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spectral Bottleneck in Sinusoidal Representation Networks: Noise is All You Need</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.09719</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.09719v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: This work identifies and attempts to address a fundamental limitation of implicit neural representations with sinusoidal activation. The fitting error of SIRENs is highly sensitive to the target frequency content and to the choice of initialization. In extreme cases, this sensitivity leads to a spectral bottleneck that can result in a zero-valued output. This phenomenon is characterized by analyzing the evolution of activation spectra and the empirical neural tangent kernel (NTK) during the training process. An unfavorable distribution of energy across frequency modes was noted to give rise to this failure mode. Furthermore, the effect of Gaussian perturbations applied to the baseline uniformly initialized weights is examined, showing how these perturbations influence activation spectra and the NTK eigenbasis of SIREN. Overall, initialization emerges as a central factor governing the evolution of SIRENs, indicating the need for adaptive, target-aware strategies as the target length increases and fine-scale detail becomes essential. The proposed weight initialization scheme (WINNER) represents a simple ad hoc step in this direction and demonstrates that fitting accuracy can be significantly improved by modifying the spectral profile of network activations through a target-aware initialization. The approach achieves state-of-the-art performance on audio fitting tasks and yields notable improvements in image fitting tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.09719v2</guid>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hemanth Chandravamsi, Dhanush V. Shenoy, Itay Zinn, Ziv Chen, Shimon Pisnoy, Steven H. Frankel</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Structured State-Space Duality</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.04944</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.04944v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Structured State-Space Duality (SSD) [Dao &amp; Gu, ICML 2024] is an equivalence between a simple Structured State-Space Model (SSM) and a masked attention mechanism. In particular, a state-space model with a scalar-times-identity state matrix is equivalent to a masked self-attention with a $1$-semiseparable causal mask. Consequently, the same sequence transformation (model) has two algorithmic realizations: as a linear-time $O(T)$ recurrence or as a quadratic-time $O(T^2)$ attention. In this note, we formalize and generalize this duality: (i) we extend SSD from the scalar-identity case to general diagonal SSMs (diagonal state matrices); (ii) we show that these diagonal SSMs match the scalar case's training complexity lower bounds while supporting richer dynamics; (iii) we establish a necessary and sufficient condition under which an SSM is equivalent to $1$-semiseparable masked attention; and (iv) we show that such duality fails to extend to standard softmax attention due to rank explosion. Together, these results tighten bridge between recurrent SSMs and Transformers, and widen the design space for expressive yet efficient sequence models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.04944v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jerry Yao-Chieh Hu, Xiwen Zhang, Ali ElSheikh, Weimin Wu, Han Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Vision-Language-Action Co-Learning with Semantic-Physical Alignment for Behavioral Cloning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.14396</link>
      <description>arXiv:2511.14396v5 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Language-conditioned manipulation facilitates human-robot interaction via behavioral cloning (BC), which learns control policies from human demonstrations and serves as a cornerstone of embodied AI. Overcoming compounding errors in sequential action decisions remains a central challenge to improving BC performance. Existing approaches mitigate compounding errors through data augmentation, expressive representation, or temporal abstraction. However, they suffer from physical discontinuities and semantic-physical misalignment, leading to inaccurate action cloning and intermittent execution. In this paper, we present Continuous vision-language-action Co-Learning with Semantic-Physical Alignment (CCoL), a novel BC framework that ensures temporally consistent execution and fine-grained semantic grounding. It generates robust and smooth action execution trajectories through continuous co-learning across vision, language, and proprioceptive inputs (e.g., robot internal states). Meanwhile, we anchor language semantics to visuomotor representations by a bidirectional cross-attention to learn contextual information for action generation, successfully overcoming the problem of semantic-physical misalignment. Extensive experiments show that CCoL achieves an average 8.0% relative improvement across three simulation suites, with up to 19.2% relative gain in human-demonstrated bimanual insertion tasks. Real-world tests on a 7-DoF robot further confirm CCoL's generalization under unseen and noisy object states.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2511.14396v5</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiuxiu Qi, Yu Yang, Jiannong Cao, Luyao Bai, Chongshan Fan, Chengtai Cao, Hongpeng Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Categorical Equivariant Deep Learning: Category-Equivariant Neural Networks and Universal Approximation Theorems</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.18417</link>
      <description>arXiv:2511.18417v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We develop a theory of category-equivariant neural networks (CENNs) that unifies group/groupoid-equivariant networks, poset/lattice-equivariant networks, graph and sheaf neural networks. Equivariance is formulated as naturality in a topological category with Radon measures. Formulating linear and nonlinear layers in the categorical setup, we prove the equivariant universal approximation theorem in the general setting: the class of finite-depth CENNs is dense in the space of continuous equivariant transformations. We instantiate the framework for groups/groupoids, posets/lattices, graphs and cellular sheaves, deriving universal approximation theorems for them in a systematic manner. Categorical equivariant deep learning thus allows us to expand the horizons of equivariant deep learning beyond group actions, encompassing not only geometric symmetries but also contextual and compositional symmetries.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2511.18417v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yoshihiro Maruyama</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SLIM: Semantic-based Low-bitrate Image compression for Machines by leveraging diffusion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.18200</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.18200v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In recent years, the demand of image compression models for machine vision has increased dramatically. However, the training frameworks of image compression still focus on the vision of human, maintaining the excessive perceptual details, thus have limitations in optimally reducing the bits per pixel in the case of performing machine vision tasks. In this paper, we propose Semantic-based Low-bitrate Image compression for Machines by leveraging diffusion, termed SLIM. This is a new effective training framework of image compression for machine vision, using a pretrained latent diffusion model.The compressor model of our method focuses only on the Region-of-Interest (RoI) areas for machine vision in the image latent, to compress it compactly. Then the pretrained Unet model enhances the decompressed latent, utilizing a RoI-focused text caption which containing semantic information of the image. Therefore, SLIM is able to focus on RoI areas of the image without any guide mask at the inference stage, achieving low bitrate when compressing. And SLIM is also able to enhance a decompressed latent by denoising steps, so the final reconstructed image from the enhanced latent can be optimized for the machine vision task while still containing perceptual details for human vision. Experimental results show that SLIM achieves a higher classification accuracy in the same bits per pixel condition, compared to conventional image compression models for machines.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.18200v2</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hyeonjin Lee, Jun-Hyuk Kim, Jong-Seok Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Unlearning in the Era of Quantum Machine Learning: An Empirical Study</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.19253</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.19253v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We present the first comprehensive empirical study of machine unlearning (MU) in hybrid quantum-classical neural networks. While MU has been extensively explored in classical deep learning, its behavior within variational quantum circuits (VQCs) and quantum-augmented architectures remains largely unexplored. First, we adapt a broad suite of unlearning methods to quantum settings, including gradient-based, distillation-based, regularization-based and certified techniques. Second, we introduce two new unlearning strategies tailored to hybrid models. Experiments across Iris, MNIST, and Fashion-MNIST, under both subset removal and full-class deletion, reveal that quantum models can support effective unlearning, but outcomes depend strongly on circuit depth, entanglement structure, and task complexity. Shallow VQCs display high intrinsic stability with minimal memorization, whereas deeper hybrid models exhibit stronger trade-offs between utility, forgetting strength, and alignment with retrain oracle. We find that certain methods, e.g. EU-k, LCA, and Certified Unlearning, consistently provide the best balance across metrics. These findings establish baseline empirical insights into quantum machine unlearning and highlight the need for quantum-aware algorithms and theoretical guarantees, as quantum machine learning systems continue to expand in scale and capability. We publicly release our code at: https://github.com/CrivoiCarla/HQML.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.19253v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Carla Crivoi, Radu Tudor Ionescu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LoGoPlanner: Localization Grounded Navigation Policy with Metric-aware Visual Geometry</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.19629</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.19629v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Trajectory planning in unstructured environments is a fundamental and challenging capability for mobile robots. Traditional modular pipelines suffer from latency and cascading errors across perception, localization, mapping, and planning modules. Recent end-to-end learning methods map raw visual observations directly to control signals or trajectories, promising greater performance and efficiency in open-world settings. However, most prior end-to-end approaches still rely on separate localization modules that depend on accurate sensor extrinsic calibration for self-state estimation, thereby limiting generalization across embodiments and environments. We introduce LoGoPlanner, a localization-grounded, end-to-end navigation framework that addresses these limitations by: (1) finetuning a long-horizon visual-geometry backbone to ground predictions with absolute metric scale, thereby providing implicit state estimation for accurate localization; (2) reconstructing surrounding scene geometry from historical observations to supply dense, fine-grained environmental awareness for reliable obstacle avoidance; and (3) conditioning the policy on implicit geometry bootstrapped by the aforementioned auxiliary tasks, thereby reducing error propagation. We evaluate LoGoPlanner in both simulation and real-world settings, where its fully end-to-end design reduces cumulative error while metric-aware geometry memory enhances planning consistency and obstacle avoidance, leading to more than a 27.3\% improvement over oracle-localization baselines and strong generalization across embodiments and environments. The code and models have been made publicly available on the https://steinate.github.io/logoplanner.github.io.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.19629v2</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiaqi Peng, Wenzhe Cai, Yuqiang Yang, Tai Wang, Yuan Shen, Jiangmiao Pang</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
