<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL</link>
    <description>cs.CL updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 05:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Saturday</day>
      <day>Sunday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>A Survey on Large Language Models with some Insights on their Capabilities and Limitations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04040</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04040v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The rapid advancement of artificial intelligence, particularly with the development of Large Language Models (LLMs) built on the transformer architecture, has redefined the capabilities of natural language processing. These models now exhibit remarkable performance across various language-related tasks, such as text generation, question answering, translation, and summarization, often rivaling human-like comprehension. More intriguingly, LLMs have demonstrated emergent abilities extending beyond their core functions, showing proficiency in tasks like commonsense reasoning, code generation, and arithmetic. This survey paper explores the foundational components, scaling mechanisms, and architectural strategies that drive these capabilities. Emphasizing models like GPT and LLaMA, we analyze the impact of exponential data and computational growth on LLM performance, while also addressing the trade-offs associated with scaling. We also examine LLM applications across sectors, such as healthcare, finance, education, and law, highlighting their adaptability and potential to solve domain-specific challenges. Central to this work are the questions of how LLMs generalize across diverse tasks, exhibit planning, and reasoning abilities, and whether these emergent abilities can be systematically elicited or enhanced. In particular, we provide some insights into the CoT (Chain of Thought) and PoT (Plan of Thought) abilities within LLMs, focusing on how pre-training data influences their emergence. Additionally, we investigate LLM-modulo frameworks that integrate external systems, allowing LLMs to handle complex, dynamic tasks. By analyzing these factors, this paper aims to foster the ongoing discussion on the capabilities and limits of LLMs, promoting their responsible development and application in novel and increasingly complex environments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04040v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.NE</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Andrea Matarazzo, Riccardo Torlone</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"Yeah Right!" -- Do LLMs Exhibit Multimodal Feature Transfer?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04138</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04138v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Human communication is a multifaceted and multimodal skill. Communication requires an understanding of both the surface-level textual content and the connotative intent of a piece of communication. In humans, learning to go beyond the surface level starts by learning communicative intent in speech. Once humans acquire these skills in spoken communication, they transfer those skills to written communication. In this paper, we assess the ability of speech+text models and text models trained with special emphasis on human-to-human conversations to make this multimodal transfer of skill. We specifically test these models on their ability to detect covert deceptive communication. We find that with no special prompting speech+text LLMs have an advantage over unimodal LLMs in performing this task. Likewise, we find that human-to-human conversation-trained LLMs are also advantaged in this skill.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04138v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Benjamin Reichman, Kartik Talamadupula</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multilingual Open QA on the MIA Shared Task</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04153</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04153v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Cross-lingual information retrieval (CLIR) ~\cite{shi2021cross, asai2021one, jiang2020cross} for example, can find relevant text in any language such as English(high resource) or Telugu (low resource) even when the query is posed in a different, possibly low-resource, language. In this work, we aim to develop useful CLIR models for this constrained, yet important, setting where we do not require any kind of additional supervision or labelled data for retrieval task and hence can work effectively for low-resource languages.
  \par We propose a simple and effective re-ranking method for improving passage retrieval in open question answering. The re-ranker re-scores retrieved passages with a zero-shot multilingual question generation model, which is a pre-trained language model, to compute the probability of the input question in the target language conditioned on a retrieved passage, which can be possibly in a different language. We evaluate our method in a completely zero shot setting and doesn't require any training. Thus the main advantage of our method is that our approach can be used to re-rank results obtained by any sparse retrieval methods like BM-25. This eliminates the need for obtaining expensive labelled corpus required for the retrieval tasks and hence can be used for low resource languages.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04153v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Navya Yarrabelly, Saloni Mittal, Ketan Todi, Kimihiro Hasegawa</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reasoning-Enhanced Self-Training for Long-Form Personalized Text Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04167</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04167v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Personalized text generation requires a unique ability of large language models (LLMs) to learn from context that they often do not encounter during their standard training. One way to encourage LLMs to better use personalized context for generating outputs that better align with the user's expectations is to instruct them to reason over the user's past preferences, background knowledge, or writing style. To achieve this, we propose Reasoning-Enhanced Self-Training for Personalized Text Generation (REST-PG), a framework that trains LLMs to reason over personal data during response generation. REST-PG first generates reasoning paths to train the LLM's reasoning abilities and then employs Expectation-Maximization Reinforced Self-Training to iteratively train the LLM based on its own high-reward outputs. We evaluate REST-PG on the LongLaMP benchmark, consisting of four diverse personalized long-form text generation tasks. Our experiments demonstrate that REST-PG achieves significant improvements over state-of-the-art baselines, with an average relative performance gain of 14.5% on the benchmark.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04167v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alireza Salemi, Cheng Li, Mingyang Zhang, Qiaozhu Mei, Weize Kong, Tao Chen, Zhuowan Li, Michael Bendersky, Hamed Zamani</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multimodal Multihop Source Retrieval for Web Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04173</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04173v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This work deals with the challenge of learning and reasoning over multi-modal multi-hop question answering (QA). We propose a graph reasoning network based on the semantic structure of the sentences to learn multi-source reasoning paths and find the supporting facts across both image and text modalities for answering the question. In this paper, we investigate the importance of graph structure for multi-modal multi-hop question answering. Our analysis is centered on WebQA. We construct a strong baseline model, that finds relevant sources using a pairwise classification task. We establish that, with the proper use of feature representations from pre-trained models, graph structure helps in improving multi-modal multi-hop question answering. We point out that both graph structure and adjacency matrix are task-related prior knowledge, and graph structure can be leveraged to improve the retrieval performance for the task. Experiments and visualized analysis demonstrate that message propagation over graph networks or the entire graph structure can replace massive multimodal transformers with token-wise cross-attention. We demonstrated the applicability of our method and show a performance gain of \textbf{4.6$\%$} retrieval F1score over the transformer baselines, despite being a very light model. We further demonstrated the applicability of our model to a large scale retrieval setting.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04173v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Navya Yarrabelly, Saloni Mittal</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IOLBENCH: Benchmarking LLMs on Linguistic Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04249</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04249v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Despite the remarkable advancements and widespread applications of deep neural networks, their ability to perform reasoning tasks remains limited, particularly in domains requiring structured, abstract thought. In this paper, we investigate the linguistic reasoning capabilities of state-of-the-art large language models (LLMs) by introducing IOLBENCH, a novel benchmark derived from International Linguistics Olympiad (IOL) problems. This dataset encompasses diverse problems testing syntax, morphology, phonology, and semantics, all carefully designed to be self-contained and independent of external knowledge. These tasks challenge models to engage in metacognitive linguistic reasoning, requiring the deduction of linguistic rules and patterns from minimal examples. Through extensive benchmarking of leading LLMs, we find that even the most advanced models struggle to handle the intricacies of linguistic complexity, particularly in areas demanding compositional generalization and rule abstraction. Our analysis highlights both the strengths and persistent limitations of current models in linguistic problem-solving, offering valuable insights into their reasoning capabilities. By introducing IOLBENCH, we aim to foster further research into developing models capable of human-like reasoning, with broader implications for the fields of computational linguistics and artificial intelligence.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04249v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Satyam Goyal, Soham Dan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multimodal Graph Constrastive Learning and Prompt for ChartQA</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04303</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04303v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: ChartQA presents significant challenges due to the complex distribution of chart elements and the implicit patterns embedded within the underlying data. In this chapter, we have developed a joint multimodal scene graph for charts, explicitly representing the relationships between chart elements and their associated patterns.
  Our proposed multimodal scene graph consists of two components: a visual graph and a textual graph, each designed to capture the structural and semantic information within the chart. To unify representations across these different modalities, we introduce a multimodal graph contrastive learning approach that learns unified representations by maximizing similarity between nodes representing the same object across multimodal graphs. The learned graph representations can be seamlessly incorporated into a transformer decoder as a soft prompt.
  Additionally, given the growing need for Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) in zero-shot scenarios, we have designed Chain-of-Thought (CoT) prompts for MLLMs to reduce hallucinations. We tested both methods on public benchmarks such as ChartQA, OpenCQA, and ChartX, demonstrating improved performance and validating the effectiveness of our proposed methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04303v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yue Dai, Soyeon Caren Han, Wei Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM4SR: A Survey on Large Language Models for Scientific Research</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04306</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04306v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In recent years, the rapid advancement of Large Language Models (LLMs) has transformed the landscape of scientific research, offering unprecedented support across various stages of the research cycle. This paper presents the first systematic survey dedicated to exploring how LLMs are revolutionizing the scientific research process. We analyze the unique roles LLMs play across four critical stages of research: hypothesis discovery, experiment planning and implementation, scientific writing, and peer reviewing. Our review comprehensively showcases the task-specific methodologies and evaluation benchmarks. By identifying current challenges and proposing future research directions, this survey not only highlights the transformative potential of LLMs, but also aims to inspire and guide researchers and practitioners in leveraging LLMs to advance scientific inquiry. Resources are available at the following repository: https://github.com/du-nlp-lab/LLM4SR</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04306v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.DL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ziming Luo, Zonglin Yang, Zexin Xu, Wei Yang, Xinya Du</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who Does the Giant Number Pile Like Best: Analyzing Fairness in Hiring Contexts</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04316</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04316v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are increasingly being deployed in high-stakes applications like hiring, yet their potential for unfair decision-making and outcomes remains understudied, particularly in generative settings. In this work, we examine the fairness of LLM-based hiring systems through two real-world tasks: resume summarization and retrieval. By constructing a synthetic resume dataset and curating job postings, we investigate whether model behavior differs across demographic groups and is sensitive to demographic perturbations. Our findings reveal that race-based differences appear in approximately 10% of generated summaries, while gender-based differences occur in only 1%. In the retrieval setting, all evaluated models display non-uniform selection patterns across demographic groups and exhibit high sensitivity to both gender and race-based perturbations. Surprisingly, retrieval models demonstrate comparable sensitivity to non-demographic changes, suggesting that fairness issues may stem, in part, from general brittleness issues. Overall, our results indicate that LLM-based hiring systems, especially at the retrieval stage, can exhibit notable biases that lead to discriminatory outcomes in real-world contexts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04316v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Preethi Seshadri, Seraphina Goldfarb-Tarrant</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Before Reasoning: Enhancing Chain-of-Thought with Iterative Summarization Pre-Prompting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04341</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04341v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Chain-of-Thought (CoT) Prompting is a dominant paradigm in Large Language Models (LLMs) to enhance complex reasoning. It guides LLMs to present multi-step reasoning, rather than generating the final answer directly. However, CoT encounters difficulties when key information required for reasoning is implicit or missing. This occurs because CoT emphasizes the sequence of reasoning steps while overlooking the early extraction of essential information. We propose a pre-prompting method called Iterative Summarization Pre-Prompting (ISP^2) to refine LLM reasoning when key information is not explicitly provided. First, entities and their corresponding descriptions are extracted to form potential key information pairs. Next, we use a reliability rating to assess these pairs, then merge the two lowest-ranked pairs into a new entity description. This process is repeated until a unique key information pair is obtained. Finally, that pair, along with the original question, is fed into LLMs to produce the answer. Extensive experiments demonstrate a 7.1% improvement compared to existing methods. Unlike traditional prompting, ISP^2 adopts an inductive approach with pre-prompting, offering flexible integration into diverse reasoning frameworks. The code is available at https://github.com/zdhgreat/ISP-2.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04341v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dong-Hai Zhu, Yu-Jie Xiong, Jia-Chen Zhang, Xi-Jiong Xie, Chun-Ming Xia</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SEO: Stochastic Experience Optimization for Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04393</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04393v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) can benefit from useful experiences to improve their performance on specific tasks. However, finding helpful experiences for different LLMs is not obvious, since it is unclear what experiences suit specific LLMs. Previous studies intended to automatically find useful experiences using LLMs, while it is difficult to ensure the effectiveness of the obtained experience. In this paper, we propose Stochastic Experience Optimization (SEO), an iterative approach that finds optimized model-specific experience without modifying model parameters through experience update in natural language. In SEO, we propose a stochastic validation method to ensure the update direction of experience, avoiding unavailing updates. Experimental results on three tasks for three LLMs demonstrate that experiences optimized by SEO can achieve consistently improved performance. Further analysis indicates that SEO-optimized experience can generalize to out-of-distribution data, boosting the performance of LLMs on similar tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04393v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jitao Xu, Hongyun Zhou, Lei Shen, Conghui Zhu, Jin Huang, Yitao Duan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>End-to-End Bangla AI for Solving Math Olympiad Problem Benchmark: Leveraging Large Language Model Using Integrated Approach</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04425</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04425v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This work introduces systematic approach for enhancing large language models (LLMs) to address Bangla AI mathematical challenges. Through the assessment of diverse LLM configurations, fine-tuning with specific datasets, and the implementation of Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG), we enhanced the model's reasoning precision in a multilingual setting. Crucial discoveries indicate that customized prompting, dataset augmentation, and iterative reasoning improve the model's efficiency regarding Olympiad-level mathematical challenges.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04425v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.5121/ijnlc.2024.13604</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>IJNLC,vol:13, Issue:5/6, page 49-59,2024</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>H. M. Shadman Tabib, Jaber Ahmed Deedar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hidden Entity Detection from GitHub Leveraging Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04455</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04455v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Named entity recognition is an important task when constructing knowledge bases from unstructured data sources. Whereas entity detection methods mostly rely on extensive training data, Large Language Models (LLMs) have paved the way towards approaches that rely on zero-shot learning (ZSL) or few-shot learning (FSL) by taking advantage of the capabilities LLMs acquired during pretraining. Specifically, in very specialized scenarios where large-scale training data is not available, ZSL / FSL opens new opportunities. This paper follows this recent trend and investigates the potential of leveraging Large Language Models (LLMs) in such scenarios to automatically detect datasets and software within textual content from GitHub repositories. While existing methods focused solely on named entities, this study aims to broaden the scope by incorporating resources such as repositories and online hubs where entities are also represented by URLs. The study explores different FSL prompt learning approaches to enhance the LLMs' ability to identify dataset and software mentions within repository texts. Through analyses of LLM effectiveness and learning strategies, this paper offers insights into the potential of advanced language models for automated entity detection.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04455v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.DL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lu Gan, Martin Blum, Danilo Dessi, Brigitte Mathiak, Ralf Schenkel, Stefan Dietze</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When LLMs Struggle: Reference-less Translation Evaluation for Low-resource Languages</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04473</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04473v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper investigates the reference-less evaluation of machine translation for low-resource language pairs, known as quality estimation (QE). Segment-level QE is a challenging cross-lingual language understanding task that provides a quality score (0-100) to the translated output. We comprehensively evaluate large language models (LLMs) in zero/few-shot scenarios and perform instruction fine-tuning using a novel prompt based on annotation guidelines. Our results indicate that prompt-based approaches are outperformed by the encoder-based fine-tuned QE models. Our error analysis reveals tokenization issues, along with errors due to transliteration and named entities, and argues for refinement in LLM pre-training for cross-lingual tasks. We release the data, and models trained publicly for further research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04473v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Archchana Sindhujan, Diptesh Kanojia, Constantin Orasan, Shenbin Qian</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PolInterviews -- A Dataset of German Politician Public Broadcast Interviews</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04484</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04484v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper presents a novel dataset of public broadcast interviews featuring high-ranking German politicians. The interviews were sourced from YouTube, transcribed, processed for speaker identification, and stored in a tidy and open format. The dataset comprises 99 interviews with 33 different German politicians across five major interview formats, containing a total of 28,146 sentences. As the first of its kind, this dataset offers valuable opportunities for research on various aspects of political communication in the (German) political contexts, such as agenda-setting, interviewer dynamics, or politicians' self-presentation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04484v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lukas Birkenmaier, Laureen Sieber, Felix Bergstein</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rStar-Math: Small LLMs Can Master Math Reasoning with Self-Evolved Deep Thinking</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04519</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04519v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present rStar-Math to demonstrate that small language models (SLMs) can rival or even surpass the math reasoning capability of OpenAI o1, without distillation from superior models. rStar-Math achieves this by exercising "deep thinking" through Monte Carlo Tree Search (MCTS), where a math policy SLM performs test-time search guided by an SLM-based process reward model. rStar-Math introduces three innovations to tackle the challenges in training the two SLMs: (1) a novel code-augmented CoT data sythesis method, which performs extensive MCTS rollouts to generate step-by-step verified reasoning trajectories used to train the policy SLM; (2) a novel process reward model training method that avoids na\"ive step-level score annotation, yielding a more effective process preference model (PPM); (3) a self-evolution recipe in which the policy SLM and PPM are built from scratch and iteratively evolved to improve reasoning capabilities. Through 4 rounds of self-evolution with millions of synthesized solutions for 747k math problems, rStar-Math boosts SLMs' math reasoning to state-of-the-art levels. On the MATH benchmark, it improves Qwen2.5-Math-7B from 58.8% to 90.0% and Phi3-mini-3.8B from 41.4% to 86.4%, surpassing o1-preview by +4.5% and +0.9%. On the USA Math Olympiad (AIME), rStar-Math solves an average of 53.3% (8/15) of problems, ranking among the top 20% the brightest high school math students. Code and data will be available at https://github.com/microsoft/rStar.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04519v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xinyu Guan, Li Lyna Zhang, Yifei Liu, Ning Shang, Youran Sun, Yi Zhu, Fan Yang, Mao Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenOmni: Large Language Models Pivot Zero-shot Omnimodal Alignment across Language with Real-time Self-Aware Emotional Speech Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04561</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04561v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent advancements in omnimodal learning have been achieved in understanding and generation across images, text, and speech, though mainly within proprietary models. Limited omnimodal datasets and the inherent challenges associated with real-time emotional speech generation have hindered open-source progress. To address these issues, we propose openomni, a two-stage training method combining omnimodal alignment and speech generation to develop a state-of-the-art omnimodal large language model. In the alignment phase, a pre-trained speech model is further trained on text-image tasks to generalize from vision to speech in a (near) zero-shot manner, outperforming models trained on tri-modal datasets. In the speech generation phase, a lightweight decoder facilitates real-time emotional speech through training on speech tasks and preference learning. Experiments demonstrate that openomni consistently improves across omnimodal, vision-language, and speech-language evaluations, enabling natural, emotion-rich dialogues and real-time emotional speech generation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04561v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Run Luo, Ting-En Lin, Haonan Zhang, Yuchuan Wu, Xiong Liu, Min Yang, Yongbin Li, Longze Chen, Jiaming Li, Lei Zhang, Yangyi Chen, Hamid Alinejad-Rokny, Fei Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantum-inspired Embeddings Projection and Similarity Metrics for Representation Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04591</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04591v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Over the last decade, representation learning, which embeds complex information extracted from large amounts of data into dense vector spaces, has emerged as a key technique in machine learning. Among other applications, it has been a key building block for large language models and advanced computer vision systems based on contrastive learning. A core component of representation learning systems is the projection head, which maps the original embeddings into different, often compressed spaces, while preserving the similarity relationship between vectors.
  In this paper, we propose a quantum-inspired projection head that includes a corresponding quantum-inspired similarity metric. Specifically, we map classical embeddings onto quantum states in Hilbert space and introduce a quantum circuit-based projection head to reduce embedding dimensionality. To evaluate the effectiveness of this approach, we extended the BERT language model by integrating our projection head for embedding compression. We compared the performance of embeddings, which were compressed using our quantum-inspired projection head, with those compressed using a classical projection head on information retrieval tasks using the TREC 2019 and TREC 2020 Deep Learning benchmarks. The results demonstrate that our quantum-inspired method achieves competitive performance relative to the classical method while utilizing 32 times fewer parameters. Furthermore, when trained from scratch, it notably excels, particularly on smaller datasets. This work not only highlights the effectiveness of the quantum-inspired approach but also emphasizes the utility of efficient, ad hoc low-entanglement circuit simulations within neural networks as a powerful quantum-inspired technique.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04591v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cond-mat.dis-nn</category>
      <category>quant-ph</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ivan Kankeu, Stefan Gerd Fritsch, Gunnar Sch\"onhoff, Elie Mounzer, Paul Lukowicz, Maximilian Kiefer-Emmanouilidis</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-task retriever fine-tuning for domain-specific and efficient RAG</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04652</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04652v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) has become ubiquitous when deploying Large Language Models (LLMs), as it can address typical limitations such as generating hallucinated or outdated information. However, when building real-world RAG applications, practical issues arise. First, the retrieved information is generally domain-specific. Since it is computationally expensive to fine-tune LLMs, it is more feasible to fine-tune the retriever to improve the quality of the data included in the LLM input. Second, as more applications are deployed in the same real-world system, one cannot afford to deploy separate retrievers. Moreover, these RAG applications normally retrieve different kinds of data. Our solution is to instruction fine-tune a small retriever encoder on a variety of domain-specific tasks to allow us to deploy one encoder that can serve many use cases, thereby achieving low-cost, scalability, and speed. We show how this encoder generalizes to out-of-domain settings as well as to an unseen retrieval task on real-world enterprise use cases.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04652v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Patrice B\'echard, Orlando Marquez Ayala</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing Language Comprehension in Large Language Models Using Construction Grammar</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04661</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04661v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models, despite their significant capabilities, are known to fail in surprising and unpredictable ways. Evaluating their true `understanding' of language is particularly challenging due to the extensive web-scale data they are trained on. Therefore, we construct an evaluation to systematically assess natural language understanding (NLU) in LLMs by leveraging Construction Grammar (CxG), which provides insights into the meaning captured by linguistic elements known as constructions (Cxns). CxG is well-suited for this purpose because provides a theoretical basis to construct targeted evaluation sets. These datasets are carefully constructed to include examples which are unlikely to appear in pre-training data, yet intuitive and easy for humans to understand, enabling a more targeted and reliable assessment. Our experiments focus on downstream natural language inference and reasoning tasks by comparing LLMs' understanding of the underlying meanings communicated through 8 unique Cxns with that of humans. The results show that while LLMs demonstrate some knowledge of constructional information, even the latest models including GPT-o1 struggle with abstract meanings conveyed by these Cxns, as demonstrated in cases where test sentences are dissimilar to their pre-training data. We argue that such cases provide a more accurate test of true language understanding, highlighting key limitations in LLMs' semantic capabilities. We make our novel dataset and associated experimental data including prompts and model responses publicly available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04661v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wesley Scivetti, Melissa Torgbi, Austin Blodgett, Mollie Shichman, Taylor Hudson, Claire Bonial, Harish Tayyar Madabushi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On The Origin of Cultural Biases in Language Models: From Pre-training Data to Linguistic Phenomena</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04662</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04662v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Language Models (LMs) have been shown to exhibit a strong preference towards entities associated with Western culture when operating in non-Western languages. In this paper, we aim to uncover the origins of entity-related cultural biases in LMs by analyzing several contributing factors, including the representation of entities in pre-training data and the impact of variations in linguistic phenomena across languages. We introduce CAMeL-2, a parallel Arabic-English benchmark of 58,086 entities associated with Arab and Western cultures and 367 masked natural contexts for entities. Our evaluations using CAMeL-2 reveal reduced performance gaps between cultures by LMs when tested in English compared to Arabic. We find that LMs struggle in Arabic with entities that appear at high frequencies in pre-training, where entities can hold multiple word senses. This also extends to entities that exhibit high lexical overlap with languages that are not Arabic but use the Arabic script. Further, we show how frequency-based tokenization leads to this issue in LMs, which gets worse with larger Arabic vocabularies. We will make CAMeL-2 available at: https://github.com/tareknaous/camel2</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04662v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tarek Naous, Wei Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Financial VQA in Vision Language Models using Intermediate Structured Representations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04675</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04675v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Chart interpretation is crucial for visual data analysis, but accurately extracting information from charts poses significant challenges for automated models. This study investigates the fine-tuning of DEPLOT, a modality conversion module that translates the image of a plot or chart to a linearized table, on a custom dataset of 50,000 bar charts. The dataset comprises simple, stacked, and grouped bar charts, targeting the unique structural features of these visualizations. The finetuned DEPLOT model is evaluated against its base version using a test set of 1,000 images and two metrics: Relative Mapping Similarity (RMS), which measures categorical mapping accuracy, and Relative Number Set Similarity (RNSS), which evaluates numerical interpretation accuracy. To further explore the reasoning capabilities of large language models (LLMs), we curate an additional set of 100 bar chart images paired with question answer sets. Our findings demonstrate that providing a structured intermediate table alongside the image significantly enhances LLM reasoning performance compared to direct image queries.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04675v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Archita Srivastava, Abhas Kumar, Rajesh Kumar, Prabhakar Srinivasan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>URSA: Understanding and Verifying Chain-of-thought Reasoning in Multimodal Mathematics</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04686</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04686v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Chain-of-thought (CoT) reasoning has been widely applied in the mathematical reasoning of Large Language Models (LLMs). Recently, the introduction of derivative process supervision on CoT trajectories has sparked discussions on enhancing scaling capabilities during test time, thereby boosting the potential of these models. However, in multimodal mathematical reasoning, the scarcity of high-quality CoT training data has hindered existing models from achieving high-precision CoT reasoning and has limited the realization of reasoning potential during test time. In this work, we propose a three-module synthesis strategy that integrates CoT distillation, trajectory-format rewriting, and format unification. It results in a high-quality CoT reasoning instruction fine-tuning dataset in multimodal mathematics, MMathCoT-1M. We comprehensively validate the state-of-the-art (SOTA) performance of the trained URSA-7B model on multiple multimodal mathematical benchmarks. For test-time scaling, we introduce a data synthesis strategy that automatically generates process annotation datasets, known as DualMath-1.1M, focusing on both interpretation and logic. By further training URSA-7B on DualMath-1.1M, we transition from CoT reasoning capabilities to robust supervision abilities. The trained URSA-RM-7B acts as a verifier, effectively enhancing the performance of URSA-7B at test time. URSA-RM-7B also demonstrates excellent out-of-distribution (OOD) verifying capabilities, showcasing its generalization. Model weights, training data and code will be open-sourced.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04686v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ruilin Luo, Zhuofan Zheng, Yifan Wang, Yiyao Yu, Xinzhe Ni, Zicheng Lin, Jin Zeng, Yujiu Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EpiCoder: Encompassing Diversity and Complexity in Code Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04694</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04694v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Effective instruction tuning is indispensable for optimizing code LLMs, aligning model behavior with user expectations and enhancing model performance in real-world applications. However, most existing methods focus on code snippets, which are limited to specific functionalities and rigid structures, restricting the complexity and diversity of the synthesized data. To address these limitations, we introduce a novel feature tree-based synthesis framework inspired by Abstract Syntax Trees (AST). Unlike AST, which captures syntactic structure of code, our framework models semantic relationships between code elements, enabling the generation of more nuanced and diverse data. The feature tree is constructed from raw data and refined iteratively to increase the quantity and diversity of the extracted features. This process enables the identification of more complex patterns and relationships within the code. By sampling subtrees with controlled depth and breadth, our framework allows precise adjustments to the complexity of the generated code, supporting a wide range of tasks from simple function-level operations to intricate multi-file scenarios. We fine-tuned widely-used base models to create the EpiCoder series, achieving state-of-the-art performance at both the function and file levels across multiple benchmarks. Notably, empirical evidence indicates that our approach shows significant potential in synthesizing highly complex repository-level code data. Further analysis elucidates the merits of this approach by rigorously assessing data complexity and diversity through software engineering principles and LLM-as-a-judge method.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04694v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yaoxiang Wang, Haoling Li, Xin Zhang, Jie Wu, Xiao Liu, Wenxiang Hu, Zhongxin Guo, Yangyu Huang, Ying Xin, Yujiu Yang, Jinsong Su, Qi Chen, Scarlett Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Negative Zero: Datatype Customization for Quantized Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04052</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04052v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated remarkable performance across various machine learning tasks, quickly becoming one of the most prevalent AI workloads. Yet the substantial memory requirement of LLMs significantly hinders their deployment for end users. Post-training quantization (PTQ) serves as one of the most hardware-efficient methods to mitigate the memory and computational demands of LLMs. Although the traditional integer (INT) datatype has received widespread adoption in PTQ methods, floating-point (FP) quantization has emerged as a viable alternative thanks to its effectiveness in fitting LLM numerical distributions. However, the FP datatype in sign-magnitude binary representation contains both positive and negative zero, which constrains its representation capability, particularly under low precision (3 and 4 bits). In this paper, we extend the basic FP datatype to perform Redundant Zero Remapping (RaZeR), which remaps the negative zero FP encoding to a set of pre-defined special values to maximally utilize FP quantization encodings and to better fit LLM numerical distributions. Through careful selection of special values, RaZeR outperforms conventional asymmetric INT quantization while achieving high computational efficiency. We demonstrate that RaZeR can be seamlessly integrated with quantization algorithms for both weights and KV-cache, including advanced methods with clipping and transformations, and consistently achieve better model accuracy. Additionally, we implement a fast GEMV kernel with fused dequantization that efficiently converts the 4-bit RaZeR value to FP16 through novel bit-level manipulation. On modern GPUs, our evaluation shows that RaZeR improves the GEMV speed by up to 7.56$\times$ compared to the FP16 implementation, while achieving up to 2.72$\times$ speedup in the LLM decoding throughput.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04052v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuzong Chen, Xilai Dai, Chi-chih Chang, Yash Akhauri, Mohamed S. Abdelfattah</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More is not always better? Enhancing Many-Shot In-Context Learning with Differentiated and Reweighting Objectives</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04070</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04070v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) excel at few-shot in-context learning (ICL) without requiring parameter updates. However, as the number of ICL demonstrations increases from a few to many, performance tends to plateau and eventually decline. We identify two primary causes for this trend: the suboptimal negative log-likelihood (NLL) optimization objective and the incremental data noise. To address these issues, we introduce DR-ICL, a novel optimization method that enhances model performance through Differentiated Learning and advantage-based Reweighting objectives. Globally, DR-ICL utilizes differentiated learning to optimize the NLL objective, ensuring that many-shot performance surpasses zero-shot levels. Locally, it dynamically adjusts the weighting of many-shot demonstrations by leveraging cumulative advantages inspired by reinforcement learning, thereby improving generalization. This approach allows the model to handle varying numbers of shots effectively, mitigating the impact of noisy data. Recognizing the lack of multi-task datasets with diverse many-shot distributions, we develop the Many-Shot ICL Benchmark (MICLB)-a large-scale benchmark covering shot numbers from 1 to 350 within sequences of up to 8,000 tokens-for fine-tuning purposes. MICLB facilitates the evaluation of many-shot ICL strategies across seven prominent NLP tasks and 50 distinct datasets. Experimental results demonstrate that LLMs enhanced with DR-ICL achieve significant improvements in many-shot setups across various tasks, including both in-domain and out-of-domain scenarios. We release the code and benchmark dataset hoping to facilitate further research in many-shot ICL.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04070v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoqing Zhang, Ang Lv, Yuhan Liu, Flood Sung, Wei Liu, Shuo Shang, Xiuying Chen, Rui Yan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MM-GEN: Enhancing Task Performance Through Targeted Multimodal Data Curation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04155</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04155v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Vision-language models (VLMs) are highly effective but often underperform on specialized tasks; for example, Llava-1.5 struggles with chart and diagram understanding due to scarce task-specific training data. Existing training data, sourced from general-purpose datasets, fails to capture the nuanced details needed for these tasks. We introduce MM-Gen, a scalable method that generates task-specific, high-quality synthetic text for candidate images by leveraging stronger models. MM-Gen employs a three-stage targeted process: partitioning data into subgroups, generating targeted text based on task descriptions, and filtering out redundant and outlier data. Fine-tuning VLMs with data generated by MM-Gen leads to significant performance gains, including 29% on spatial reasoning and 15% on diagram understanding for Llava-1.5 (7B). Compared to human-curated caption data, MM-Gen achieves up to 1.6x better improvements for the original models, proving its effectiveness in enhancing task-specific VLM performance and bridging the gap between general-purpose datasets and specialized requirements. Code available at https://github.com/sjoshi804/MM-Gen.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04155v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Siddharth Joshi, Besmira Nushi, Vidhisha Balachandran, Varun Chandrasekaran, Vibhav Vineet, Neel Joshi, Baharan Mirzasoleiman</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agent Laboratory: Using LLM Agents as Research Assistants</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04227</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04227v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Historically, scientific discovery has been a lengthy and costly process, demanding substantial time and resources from initial conception to final results. To accelerate scientific discovery, reduce research costs, and improve research quality, we introduce Agent Laboratory, an autonomous LLM-based framework capable of completing the entire research process. This framework accepts a human-provided research idea and progresses through three stages--literature review, experimentation, and report writing to produce comprehensive research outputs, including a code repository and a research report, while enabling users to provide feedback and guidance at each stage. We deploy Agent Laboratory with various state-of-the-art LLMs and invite multiple researchers to assess its quality by participating in a survey, providing human feedback to guide the research process, and then evaluate the final paper. We found that: (1) Agent Laboratory driven by o1-preview generates the best research outcomes; (2) The generated machine learning code is able to achieve state-of-the-art performance compared to existing methods; (3) Human involvement, providing feedback at each stage, significantly improves the overall quality of research; (4) Agent Laboratory significantly reduces research expenses, achieving an 84% decrease compared to previous autonomous research methods. We hope Agent Laboratory enables researchers to allocate more effort toward creative ideation rather than low-level coding and writing, ultimately accelerating scientific discovery.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04227v1</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Samuel Schmidgall, Yusheng Su, Ze Wang, Ximeng Sun, Jialian Wu, Xiaodong Yu, Jiang Liu, Zicheng Liu, Emad Barsoum</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Circuit Complexity Bounds for Visual Autoregressive Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04299</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04299v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Understanding the expressive ability of a specific model is essential for grasping its capacity limitations. Recently, several studies have established circuit complexity bounds for Transformer architecture. Besides, the Visual AutoRegressive (VAR) model has risen to be a prominent method in the field of image generation, outperforming previous techniques, such as Diffusion Transformers, in generating high-quality images. We investigate the circuit complexity of the VAR model and establish a bound in this study. Our primary result demonstrates that the VAR model is equivalent to a simulation by a uniform $\mathsf{TC}^0$ threshold circuit with hidden dimension $d \leq O(n)$ and $\mathrm{poly}(n)$ precision. This is the first study to rigorously highlight the limitations in the expressive power of VAR models despite their impressive performance. We believe our findings will offer valuable insights into the inherent constraints of these models and guide the development of more efficient and expressive architectures in the future.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04299v1</guid>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CC</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yekun Ke, Xiaoyu Li, Yingyu Liang, Zhenmei Shi, Zhao Song</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TimelineKGQA: A Comprehensive Question-Answer Pair Generator for Temporal Knowledge Graphs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04343</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04343v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Question answering over temporal knowledge graphs (TKGs) is crucial for understanding evolving facts and relationships, yet its development is hindered by limited datasets and difficulties in generating custom QA pairs. We propose a novel categorization framework based on timeline-context relationships, along with \textbf{TimelineKGQA}, a universal temporal QA generator applicable to any TKGs. The code is available at: \url{https://github.com/PascalSun/TimelineKGQA} as an open source Python package.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04343v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LO</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qiang Sun, Sirui Li, Du Huynh, Mark Reynolds, Wei Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoding EEG Speech Perception with Transformers and VAE-based Data Augmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04359</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04359v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Decoding speech from non-invasive brain signals, such as electroencephalography (EEG), has the potential to advance brain-computer interfaces (BCIs), with applications in silent communication and assistive technologies for individuals with speech impairments. However, EEG-based speech decoding faces major challenges, such as noisy data, limited datasets, and poor performance on complex tasks like speech perception. This study attempts to address these challenges by employing variational autoencoders (VAEs) for EEG data augmentation to improve data quality and applying a state-of-the-art (SOTA) sequence-to-sequence deep learning architecture, originally successful in electromyography (EMG) tasks, to EEG-based speech decoding. Additionally, we adapt this architecture for word classification tasks. Using the Brennan dataset, which contains EEG recordings of subjects listening to narrated speech, we preprocess the data and evaluate both classification and sequence-to-sequence models for EEG-to-words/sentences tasks. Our experiments show that VAEs have the potential to reconstruct artificial EEG data for augmentation. Meanwhile, our sequence-to-sequence model achieves more promising performance in generating sentences compared to our classification model, though both remain challenging tasks. These findings lay the groundwork for future research on EEG speech perception decoding, with possible extensions to speech production tasks such as silent or imagined speech.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04359v1</guid>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Terrance Yu-Hao Chen, Yulin Chen, Pontus Soederhaell, Sadrishya Agrawal, Kateryna Shapovalenko</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NSA: Neuro-symbolic ARC Challenge</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04424</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04424v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The Abstraction and Reasoning Corpus (ARC) evaluates general reasoning capabilities that are difficult for both machine learning models and combinatorial search methods. We propose a neuro-symbolic approach that combines a transformer for proposal generation with combinatorial search using a domain-specific language. The transformer narrows the search space by proposing promising search directions, which allows the combinatorial search to find the actual solution in short time. We pre-train the trainsformer with synthetically generated data. During test-time we generate additional task-specific training tasks and fine-tune our model. Our results surpass comparable state of the art on the ARC evaluation set by 27% and compare favourably on the ARC train set. We make our code and dataset publicly available at https://github.com/Batorskq/NSA.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04424v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Pawe{\l} Batorski, Jannik Brinkmann, Paul Swoboda</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing a Modular Compiler for a Subset of a C-like Language</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04503</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04503v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The paper introduces the development of a modular compiler for a subset of a C-like language, which addresses the challenges in constructing a compiler for high-level languages. This modular approach will allow developers to modify a language by adding or removing subsets as required, resulting in a minimal and memory-efficient compiler. The development process is divided into small, incremental steps, where each step yields a fully functioning compiler for an expanding subset of the language. The paper outlines the iterative developmental phase of the compiler, emphasizing progressive enhancements in capabilities and functionality. Adherence to industry best practices of modular design, code reusability, and documentation has enabled the resulting compiler's functional efficiency, maintainability, and extensibility. The compiler proved to be effective not only in managing the language structure but also in developing optimized code, which demonstrates its practical usability. This was also further assessed using the compiler on a tiny memory-deficient single-board computer, again showing the compiler's efficiency and suitability for resource-constrained devices.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04503v1</guid>
      <category>cs.PL</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.PF</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Debasish Dutta, Neeharika Sonowal, Irani Hazarika</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Image Captioning by Mimicking Human Reformulation Feedback at Inference-time</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04513</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04513v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Incorporating automatically predicted human feedback into the process of training generative models has attracted substantial recent interest, while feedback at inference time has received less attention. The typical feedback at training time, i.e., preferences of choice given two samples, does not naturally transfer to the inference phase. We introduce a novel type of feedback -- caption reformulations -- and train models to mimic reformulation feedback based on human annotations. Our method does not require training the image captioning model itself, thereby demanding substantially less computational effort. We experiment with two types of reformulation feedback: first, we collect a dataset of human reformulations that correct errors in the generated captions. We find that incorporating reformulation models trained on this data into the inference phase of existing image captioning models results in improved captions, especially when the original captions are of low quality. We apply our method to non-English image captioning, a domain where robust models are less prevalent, and gain substantial improvement. Second, we apply reformulations to style transfer. Quantitative evaluations reveal state-of-the-art performance on German image captioning and English style transfer, while human validation with a detailed comparative framework exposes the specific axes of improvement.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04513v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Uri Berger, Omri Abend, Lea Frermann, Gabriel Stanovsky</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supervision-free Vision-Language Alignment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04568</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04568v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Vision-language models (VLMs) have demonstrated remarkable potential in integrating visual and linguistic information, but their performance is often constrained by the need for extensive, high-quality image-text training data. Curation of these image-text pairs is both time-consuming and computationally expensive. To address this challenge, we introduce SVP (Supervision-free Visual Projection), a novel framework that enhances vision-language alignment without relying on curated data or preference annotation. SVP leverages self-captioning and a pre-trained grounding model as a feedback mechanism to elicit latent information in VLMs. We evaluate our approach across six key areas: captioning, referring, visual question answering, multitasking, hallucination control, and object recall. Results demonstrate significant improvements, including a 14% average improvement in captioning tasks, up to 12% increase in object recall, and substantial reduction in hallucination rates. Notably, a small VLM using SVP achieves hallucination reductions comparable to a model five times larger, while a VLM with initially poor referring capabilities more than doubles its performance, approaching parity with a model twice its size.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04568v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Giorgio Giannone, Ruoteng Li, Qianli Feng, Evgeny Perevodchikov, Rui Chen, Aleix Martinez</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>InfiGUIAgent: A Multimodal Generalist GUI Agent with Native Reasoning and Reflection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04575</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04575v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Graphical User Interface (GUI) Agents, powered by multimodal large language models (MLLMs), have shown great potential for task automation on computing devices such as computers and mobile phones. However, existing agents face challenges in multi-step reasoning and reliance on textual annotations, limiting their effectiveness. We introduce \textit{InfiGUIAgent}, an MLLM-based GUI Agent trained with a two-stage supervised fine-tuning pipeline. Stage 1 enhances fundamental skills such as GUI understanding and grounding, while Stage 2 integrates hierarchical reasoning and expectation-reflection reasoning skills using synthesized data to enable native reasoning abilities of the agents. \textit{InfiGUIAgent} achieves competitive performance on several GUI benchmarks, highlighting the impact of native reasoning skills in enhancing GUI interaction for automation tasks. Resources are available at \url{https://github.com/Reallm-Labs/InfiGUIAgent}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04575v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuhang Liu, Pengxiang Li, Zishu Wei, Congkai Xie, Xueyu Hu, Xinchen Xu, Shengyu Zhang, Xiaotian Han, Hongxia Yang, Fei Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FlairGPT: Repurposing LLMs for Interior Designs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04648</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04648v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Interior design involves the careful selection and arrangement of objects to create an aesthetically pleasing, functional, and harmonized space that aligns with the client's design brief. This task is particularly challenging, as a successful design must not only incorporate all the necessary objects in a cohesive style, but also ensure they are arranged in a way that maximizes accessibility, while adhering to a variety of affordability and usage considerations. Data-driven solutions have been proposed, but these are typically room- or domain-specific and lack explainability in their design design considerations used in producing the final layout. In this paper, we investigate if large language models (LLMs) can be directly utilized for interior design. While we find that LLMs are not yet capable of generating complete layouts, they can be effectively leveraged in a structured manner, inspired by the workflow of interior designers. By systematically probing LLMs, we can reliably generate a list of objects along with relevant constraints that guide their placement. We translate this information into a design layout graph, which is then solved using an off-the-shelf constrained optimization setup to generate the final layouts. We benchmark our algorithm in various design configurations against existing LLM-based methods and human designs, and evaluate the results using a variety of quantitative and qualitative metrics along with user studies. In summary, we demonstrate that LLMs, when used in a structured manner, can effectively generate diverse high-quality layouts, making them a viable solution for creating large-scale virtual scenes. Project webpage at https://flairgpt.github.io/</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04648v1</guid>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gabrielle Littlefair, Niladri Shekhar Dutt, Niloy J. Mitra</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards System 2 Reasoning in LLMs: Learning How to Think With Meta Chain-of-Though</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.04682</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.04682v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We propose a novel framework, Meta Chain-of-Thought (Meta-CoT), which extends traditional Chain-of-Thought (CoT) by explicitly modeling the underlying reasoning required to arrive at a particular CoT. We present empirical evidence from state-of-the-art models exhibiting behaviors consistent with in-context search, and explore methods for producing Meta-CoT via process supervision, synthetic data generation, and search algorithms. Finally, we outline a concrete pipeline for training a model to produce Meta-CoTs, incorporating instruction tuning with linearized search traces and reinforcement learning post-training. Finally, we discuss open research questions, including scaling laws, verifier roles, and the potential for discovering novel reasoning algorithms. This work provides a theoretical and practical roadmap to enable Meta-CoT in LLMs, paving the way for more powerful and human-like reasoning in artificial intelligence.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.04682v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Violet Xiang, Charlie Snell, Kanishk Gandhi, Alon Albalak, Anikait Singh, Chase Blagden, Duy Phung, Rafael Rafailov, Nathan Lile, Dakota Mahan, Louis Castricato, Jan-Philipp Franken, Nick Haber, Chelsea Finn</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preference-grounded Token-level Guidance for Language Model Fine-tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2306.00398</link>
      <description>arXiv:2306.00398v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Aligning language models (LMs) with preferences is an important problem in natural language generation. A key challenge is that preferences are typically provided at the sequence level while LM training and generation both occur at the token level. There is, therefore, a granularity mismatch between the preference and the LM training losses, which may complicate the learning problem. In this paper, we address this issue by developing an alternate training process, where we iterate between grounding the sequence-level preference into token-level training guidance, and improving the LM with the learned guidance. For guidance learning, we design a framework that extends the pairwise-preference learning in imitation learning to both variable-length LM generation and the utilization of the preference among multiple generations. For LM training, based on the amount of supervised data, we present two minimalist learning objectives that utilize the learned guidance. In experiments, our method performs competitively on two distinct representative LM tasks -- discrete-prompt generation and text summarization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2306.00398v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shentao Yang, Shujian Zhang, Congying Xia, Yihao Feng, Caiming Xiong, Mingyuan Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Bridge the Gap between Modalities: Survey on Multimodal Large Language Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.07594</link>
      <description>arXiv:2311.07594v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We explore Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs), which integrate LLMs like GPT-4 to handle multimodal data, including text, images, audio, and more. MLLMs demonstrate capabilities such as generating image captions and answering image-based questions, bridging the gap towards real-world human-computer interactions and hinting at a potential pathway to artificial general intelligence. However, MLLMs still face challenges in addressing the semantic gap in multimodal data, which may lead to erroneous outputs, posing potential risks to society. Selecting the appropriate modality alignment method is crucial, as improper methods might require more parameters without significant performance improvements. This paper aims to explore modality alignment methods for LLMs and their current capabilities. Implementing effective modality alignment can help LLMs address environmental issues and enhance accessibility. The study surveys existing modality alignment methods for MLLMs, categorizing them into four groups: (1) Multimodal Converter, which transforms data into a format that LLMs can understand; (2) Multimodal Perceiver, which improves how LLMs percieve different types of data; (3) Tool Learning, which leverages external tools to convert data into a common format, usually text; and (4) Data-Driven Method, which teaches LLMs to understand specific data types within datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2311.07594v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shezheng Song, Xiaopeng Li, Shasha Li, Shan Zhao, Jie Yu, Jun Ma, Xiaoguang Mao, Weimin Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Tool Use with Chain-of-Abstraction Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17464</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.17464v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: To achieve faithful reasoning that aligns with human expectations, large language models (LLMs) need to ground their reasoning to real-world knowledge (e.g., web facts, math and physical rules). Tools help LLMs access this external knowledge, but there remains challenges for fine-tuning LLM agents (e.g., Toolformer) to invoke tools in multi-step reasoning problems, where inter-connected tool calls require holistic and efficient tool usage planning.
  In this work, we propose a new method for LLMs to better leverage tools in multi-step reasoning. Our method, Chain-of-Abstraction (CoA), trains LLMs to first decode reasoning chains with abstract placeholders, and then call domain tools to reify each reasoning chain by filling in specific knowledge. This planning with abstract chains enables LLMs to learn more general reasoning strategies, which are robust to shifts of domain knowledge (e.g., math results) relevant to different reasoning questions. It also allows LLMs to perform decoding and calling of external tools in parallel, which avoids the inference delay caused by waiting for tool responses. In mathematical reasoning and Wiki QA domains, we show that our method consistently outperforms previous chain-of-thought and tool-augmented baselines on both in-distribution and out-of-distribution test sets, with an average ~6% absolute QA accuracy improvement. LLM agents trained with our method also show more efficient tool use, with inference speed being on average ~1.4x faster than baseline tool-augmented LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.17464v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Silin Gao, Jane Dwivedi-Yu, Ping Yu, Xiaoqing Ellen Tan, Ramakanth Pasunuru, Olga Golovneva, Koustuv Sinha, Asli Celikyilmaz, Antoine Bosselut, Tianlu Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aligning with Human Judgement: The Role of Pairwise Large Language Model Evaluators in Preference Aggregation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.16950</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.16950v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated promising capabilities as automatic evaluators in assessing the quality of generated natural language. However, LLMs still exhibit biases in evaluation and often struggle to generate coherent evaluations that align with human assessments. In this work, we first conduct a systematic study of the misalignment between LLM evaluators and human judgement, revealing that existing calibration methods aimed at mitigating biases are insufficient for effectively aligning LLM evaluators. Inspired by the use of preference data in RLHF, we formulate the evaluation as a ranking problem and introduce Pairwise-preference Search (PairS), an uncertainty-guided search method that employs LLMs to conduct pairwise comparisons and efficiently ranks candidate texts. PairS achieves state-of-the-art performance on representative evaluation tasks and demonstrates significant improvements over direct scoring. Furthermore, we provide insights into the role of pairwise preference in quantifying the transitivity of LLMs and demonstrate how PairS benefits from calibration.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.16950v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yinhong Liu, Han Zhou, Zhijiang Guo, Ehsan Shareghi, Ivan Vuli\'c, Anna Korhonen, Nigel Collier</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Bad Apples to Good Oranges: Aligning Large Language Models via Joint Preference Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.00530</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.00530v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: A common technique for aligning large language models (LLMs) relies on acquiring human preferences by comparing multiple generations conditioned on a fixed context. This method, however, relies solely on pairwise comparisons, where the generations are evaluated within an identical context. While effective to such conditional preferences often fail to encompass the nuanced and multidimensional nature of human preferences. In this work, we revisit the traditional paradigm of preference acquisition and propose a new axis based on eliciting preferences jointly over the instruction-response pairs. Unlike prior preference optimizations, which are designed for conditional ranking protocols (e.g., DPO), we propose Joint Preference Optimization (JPO), a new preference optimization objective that upweights the joint probability of the chosen instruction-response pair over the rejected instruction-response pair. Interestingly, LLMs trained with joint instruction-response preference data using JPO outperform LLM trained with DPO by $5.2\%$ and $3.3\%$ win-rate for summarization and open-ended dialogue datasets, respectively. Our findings reveal that joint preferences over instruction and response pairs can significantly enhance the alignment of LLMs by tapping into a broader spectrum of human preference elicitation. The data and code is available at https://github.com/Hritikbansal/dove.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.00530v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hritik Bansal, Ashima Suvarna, Gantavya Bhatt, Nanyun Peng, Kai-Wei Chang, Aditya Grover</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rho-1: Not All Tokens Are What You Need</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.07965</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.07965v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Previous language model pre-training methods have uniformly applied a next-token prediction loss to all training tokens. Challenging this norm, we posit that "9l training". Our initial analysis examines token-level training dynamics of language model, revealing distinct loss patterns for different tokens. Leveraging these insights, we introduce a new language model called Rho-1. Unlike traditional LMs that learn to predict every next token in a corpus, Rho-1 employs Selective Language Modeling (SLM), which selectively trains on useful tokens that aligned with the desired distribution. This approach involves scoring pretraining tokens using a reference model, and then training the language model with a focused loss on tokens with higher scores. When continual pretraining on 15B OpenWebMath corpus, Rho-1 yields an absolute improvement in few-shot accuracy of up to 30% in 9 math tasks. After fine-tuning, Rho-1-1B and 7B achieved state-of-the-art results of 40.6% and 51.8% on MATH dataset, respectively - matching DeepSeekMath with only 3% of the pretraining tokens. Furthermore, when continual pretraining on 80B general tokens, Rho-1 achieves 6.8% average enhancement across 15 diverse tasks, increasing both efficiency and performance of the language model pre-training.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.07965v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhenghao Lin, Zhibin Gou, Yeyun Gong, Xiao Liu, Yelong Shen, Ruochen Xu, Chen Lin, Yujiu Yang, Jian Jiao, Nan Duan, Weizhu Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Watch Out for Your Guidance on Generation! Exploring Conditional Backdoor Attacks against Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.14795</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.14795v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Mainstream backdoor attacks on large language models (LLMs) typically set a fixed trigger in the input instance and specific responses for triggered queries. However, the fixed trigger setting (e.g., unusual words) may be easily detected by human detection, limiting the effectiveness and practicality in real-world scenarios. To enhance the stealthiness of backdoor activation, we present a new poisoning paradigm against LLMs triggered by specifying generation conditions, which are commonly adopted strategies by users during model inference. The poisoned model performs normally for output under normal/other generation conditions, while becomes harmful for output under target generation conditions. To achieve this objective, we introduce BrieFool, an efficient attack framework. It leverages the characteristics of generation conditions by efficient instruction sampling and poisoning data generation, thereby influencing the behavior of LLMs under target conditions. Our attack can be generally divided into two types with different targets: Safety unalignment attack and Ability degradation attack. Our extensive experiments demonstrate that BrieFool is effective across safety domains and ability domains, achieving higher success rates than baseline methods, with 94.3 % on GPT-3.5-turbo</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.14795v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiaming He, Wenbo Jiang, Guanyu Hou, Wenshu Fan, Rui Zhang, Hongwei Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RDRec: Rationale Distillation for LLM-based Recommendation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.10587</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.10587v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language model (LLM)-based recommender models that bridge users and items through textual prompts for effective semantic reasoning have gained considerable attention. However, few methods consider the underlying rationales behind interactions, such as user preferences and item attributes, limiting the reasoning capability of LLMs for recommendations. This paper proposes a rationale distillation recommender (RDRec), a compact model designed to learn rationales generated by a larger language model (LM). By leveraging rationales from reviews related to users and items, RDRec remarkably specifies their profiles for recommendations. Experiments show that RDRec achieves state-of-the-art (SOTA) performance in both top-N and sequential recommendations. Our source code is released at https://github.com/WangXFng/RDRec.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.10587v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xinfeng Wang, Jin Cui, Yoshimi Suzuki, Fumiyo Fukumoto</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Zero-Shot Chinese-English Code-Switching ASR with kNN-CTC and Gated Monolingual Datastores</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.03814</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.03814v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The kNN-CTC model has proven to be effective for monolingual automatic speech recognition (ASR). However, its direct application to multilingual scenarios like code-switching, presents challenges. Although there is potential for performance improvement, a kNN-CTC model utilizing a single bilingual datastore can inadvertently introduce undesirable noise from the alternative language. To address this, we propose a novel kNN-CTC-based code-switching ASR (CS-ASR) framework that employs dual monolingual datastores and a gated datastore selection mechanism to reduce noise interference. Our method selects the appropriate datastore for decoding each frame, ensuring the injection of language-specific information into the ASR process. We apply this framework to cutting-edge CTC-based models, developing an advanced CS-ASR system. Extensive experiments demonstrate the remarkable effectiveness of our gated datastore mechanism in enhancing the performance of zero-shot Chinese-English CS-ASR.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.03814v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiaming Zhou, Shiwan Zhao, Hui Wang, Tian-Hao Zhang, Haoqin Sun, Xuechen Wang, Yong Qin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CaT-BENCH: Benchmarking Language Model Understanding of Causal and Temporal Dependencies in Plans</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.15823</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.15823v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Understanding the abilities of LLMs to reason about natural language plans, such as instructional text and recipes, is critical to reliably using them in decision-making systems. A fundamental aspect of plans is the temporal order in which their steps needs to be executed, which reflects the underlying causal dependencies between them. We introduce CaT-Bench, a benchmark of Step Order Prediction questions, which test whether a step must necessarily occur before or after another in cooking recipe plans. We use this to evaluate how well frontier LLMs understand causal and temporal dependencies. We find that SOTA LLMs are underwhelming (best zero-shot is only 0.59 in F1), and are biased towards predicting dependence more often, perhaps relying on temporal order of steps as a heuristic. While prompting for explanations and using few-shot examples improve performance, the best F1 result is only 0.73. Further, human evaluation of explanations along with answer correctness show that, on average, humans do not agree with model reasoning. Surprisingly, we also find that explaining after answering leads to better performance than normal chain-of-thought prompting, and LLM answers are not consistent across questions about the same step pairs. Overall, results show that LLMs' ability to detect dependence between steps has significant room for improvement.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.15823v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yash Kumar Lal, Vanya Cohen, Nathanael Chambers, Niranjan Balasubramanian, Raymond Mooney</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HAF-RM: A Hybrid Alignment Framework for Reward Model Training</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.04185</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.04185v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The reward model has become increasingly important in alignment, assessment, and data construction for large language models (LLMs). Most existing researchers focus on enhancing reward models through data improvements, following the conventional training framework for reward models that directly optimizes the predicted rewards. In this paper, we propose a hybrid alignment framework HaF-RM for reward model training by introducing an additional constraint on token-level policy probabilities in addition to the reward score. It can simultaneously supervise the internal preference model at the token level and optimize the mapping layer of the reward model at the sequence level. Experiment results on five datasets sufficiently show the validity and effectiveness of our proposed hybrid framework for training a high-quality reward model. By decoupling the reward modeling procedure and incorporating hybrid supervision, our HaF-RM framework offers a principled and effective approach to enhancing the performance and alignment of reward models, a critical component in the responsible development of powerful language models. We release our code at https://haf-rm.github.io.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.04185v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shujun Liu, Xiaoyu Shen, Yuhang Lai, Siyuan Wang, Shengbin Yue, Zengfeng Huang, Xuanjing Huang, Zhongyu Wei</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting the Graph Reasoning Ability of Large Language Models: Case Studies in Translation, Connectivity and Shortest Path</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09529</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.09529v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have achieved great success in various reasoning tasks. In this work, we focus on the graph reasoning ability of LLMs. Although theoretical studies proved that LLMs are capable of handling graph reasoning tasks, empirical evaluations reveal numerous failures. To deepen our understanding on this discrepancy, we revisit the ability of LLMs on three fundamental graph tasks: graph description translation, graph connectivity, and the shortest-path problem. Our findings suggest that LLMs can fail to understand graph structures through text descriptions and exhibit varying performance for all these three fundamental tasks. Meanwhile, we perform a real-world investigation on knowledge graphs and make consistent observations with our findings. The codes and datasets are available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.09529v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xinnan Dai, Qihao Wen, Yifei Shen, Hongzhi Wen, Dongsheng Li, Jiliang Tang, Caihua Shan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Balancing Diversity and Risk in LLM Sampling: How to Select Your Method and Parameter for Open-Ended Text Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13586</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.13586v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Sampling-based decoding strategies have been widely adopted for Large Language Models (LLMs) in numerous applications, targeting a balance between diversity and quality via temperature tuning and tail truncation. Considering the strong dependency of the candidate next tokens on different prefixes, recent studies propose to adaptively truncate the tail of LLMs' predicted distribution. Although improved results have been reported with these methods on open-ended text generation tasks, the results are highly dependent on the curated parameters and the limited exemplar text. In this paper, we propose a systematic way to estimate the capacity of a truncation sampling method by considering the trade-off between diversity and risk at each decoding step, based on our collected prefix tree which preserves the context of a full sentence. Our work offers a comprehensive comparison of existing truncation sampling methods and serves as a practical user guideline for their parameter selection.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.13586v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuxuan Zhou, Margret Keuper, Mario Fritz</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MEDSAGE: Enhancing Robustness of Medical Dialogue Summarization to ASR Errors with LLM-generated Synthetic Dialogues</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14418</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14418v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Automatic Speech Recognition (ASR) systems are pivotal in transcribing speech into text, yet the errors they introduce can significantly degrade the performance of downstream tasks like summarization. This issue is particularly pronounced in clinical dialogue summarization, a low-resource domain where supervised data for fine-tuning is scarce, necessitating the use of ASR models as black-box solutions. Employing conventional data augmentation for enhancing the noise robustness of summarization models is not feasible either due to the unavailability of sufficient medical dialogue audio recordings and corresponding ASR transcripts. To address this challenge, we propose MEDSAGE, an approach for generating synthetic samples for data augmentation using Large Language Models (LLMs). Specifically, we leverage the in-context learning capabilities of LLMs and instruct them to generate ASR-like errors based on a few available medical dialogue examples with audio recordings. Experimental results show that LLMs can effectively model ASR noise, and incorporating this noisy data into the training process significantly improves the robustness and accuracy of medical dialogue summarization systems. This approach addresses the challenges of noisy ASR outputs in critical applications, offering a robust solution to enhance the reliability of clinical dialogue summarization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14418v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kuluhan Binici, Abhinav Ramesh Kashyap, Viktor Schlegel, Andy T. Liu, Vijay Prakash Dwivedi, Thanh-Tung Nguyen, Xiaoxue Gao, Nancy F. Chen, Stefan Winkler</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Zero-Shot Open-Vocabulary Pipeline for Dialogue Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.15861</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.15861v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Dialogue State Tracking (DST) is crucial for understanding user needs and executing appropriate system actions in task-oriented dialogues. Majority of existing DST methods are designed to work within predefined ontologies and assume the availability of gold domain labels, struggling with adapting to new slots values. While Large Language Models (LLMs)-based systems show promising zero-shot DST performance, they either require extensive computational resources or they underperform existing fully-trained systems, limiting their practicality. To address these limitations, we propose a zero-shot, open-vocabulary system that integrates domain classification and DST in a single pipeline. Our approach includes reformulating DST as a question-answering task for less capable models and employing self-refining prompts for more adaptable ones. Our system does not rely on fixed slot values defined in the ontology allowing the system to adapt dynamically. We compare our approach with existing SOTA, and show that it provides up to 20% better Joint Goal Accuracy (JGA) over previous methods on datasets like Multi-WOZ 2.1, with up to 90% fewer requests to the LLM API.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.15861v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Abdulfattah Safa, G\"ozde G\"ul \c{S}ahin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FactBench: A Dynamic Benchmark for In-the-Wild Language Model Factuality Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.22257</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.22257v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The rapid adoption of language models (LMs) across diverse applications has raised concerns about their factuality, i.e., their consistency with real-world facts. We first present VERIFY (Verification and Evidence RetrIeval for FactualitY evaluation), a pipeline to evaluate LMs' factuality in real-world user interactions. VERIFY considers the verifiability of LM-generated content and categorizes content units as supported, unsupported, or undecidable based on Web-retrieved evidence. Importantly, factuality judgment by VERIFY correlates better with human evaluations than existing methods. Using VERIFY, we identify "hallucination prompts" across diverse topics, i.e., those eliciting the highest rates of incorrect (unsupported) and inconclusive (undecidable) LM responses. These prompts form FACTBENCH, a dataset of 1K prompts across 150 fine-grained topics. Our dataset captures emerging factuality challenges in real-world LM interactions and can be regularly updated with new prompts. We benchmark widely-used LMs from GPT, Gemini, and Llama families on FACTBENCH, yielding the following key findings: (i) Proprietary models exhibit better factuality, with decreased performance from Easy to Hard hallucination prompts. (ii) Llama3.1-405B-Instruct shows comparable or lower factual precision than Llama3.1-70B-Instruct across all evaluation methods due to its higher subjectivity that leads to more content labeled as undecidable. (iii) Gemini1.5-Pro shows a significantly higher refusal rate, with over-refusal in 25% of cases.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.22257v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Farima Fatahi Bayat, Lechen Zhang, Sheza Munir, Lu Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mixture of Knowledge Minigraph Agents for Literature Review Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.06159</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.06159v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Literature reviews play a crucial role in scientific research for understanding the current state of research, identifying gaps, and guiding future studies on specific topics. However, the process of conducting a comprehensive literature review is yet time-consuming. This paper proposes a novel framework, collaborative knowledge minigraph agents (CKMAs), to automate scholarly literature reviews. A novel prompt-based algorithm, the knowledge minigraph construction agent (KMCA), is designed to identify relations between concepts from academic literature and automatically constructs knowledge minigraphs. By leveraging the capabilities of large language models on constructed knowledge minigraphs, the multiple path summarization agent (MPSA) efficiently organizes concepts and relations from different viewpoints to generate literature review paragraphs. We evaluate CKMAs on three benchmark datasets. Experimental results show the effectiveness of the proposed method, further revealing promising applications of LLMs in scientific research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.06159v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CE</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhi Zhang, Yan Liu, Sheng-hua Zhong, Gong Chen, Yu Yang, Jiannong Cao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LoRA-LiteE: A Computationally Efficient Framework for Chatbot Preference-Tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09947</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09947v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Effective preference tuning is pivotal in aligning chatbot responses with human expectations, enhancing user satisfaction and engagement. Traditional approaches, notably Reinforcement Learning from Human Feedback (RLHF) as employed in advanced models like GPT-4, have demonstrated considerable success in this domain. However, RLHF methods are often computationally intensive and resource-demanding, limiting their scalability and accessibility for broader applications. To address these challenges, this study introduces LoRA-Lite Ensemble (LoRA-LiteE), an innovative framework that combines Supervised Fine-tuning (SFT) with Low-Rank Adaptation (LoRA) and Ensemble Learning techniques to effectively aggregate predictions of lightweight models, which aim to achieve a balance between the performance and computational cost. Utilizing the Chatbot Arena benchmark dataset, we conduct a comprehensive comparative analysis among our LoRA-LiteE model, corresponding base models at different scales, and GPT-4 trained with RLHF. Our empirical results demonstrate that the proposed LoRA-LiteE model achieves comparable performance to un-finetuned GPT-4 and outperforms the single larger-scale models under limited resource constraints. These findings highlight that our LoRA-LiteE provides a feasible and efficient methodology for human preference prediction in chatbot systems, enhancing scalability and accessibility, and thereby broadening the applicability of preference-tuned chatbots in resource-constrained environments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09947v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yahe Yang, Chunliang Tao, Xiaojing Fan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extending LLMs to New Languages: A Case Study of Llama and Persian Adaptation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.13375</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.13375v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have made great progress in classification and text generation tasks. However, they are mainly trained on English data and often struggle with low-resource languages. In this study, we explore adding a new language, i.e., Persian, to Llama (a model with a limited understanding of Persian) using parameter-efficient fine-tuning. We employ a multi-stage approach involving pretraining on monolingual Persian data, aligning representations through bilingual pretraining and instruction datasets, and instruction-tuning with task-specific datasets. We evaluate the model's performance at each stage on generation and classification tasks. Our findings suggest that incorporating the Persian language, through bilingual data alignment, can enhance classification accuracy for Persian tasks, with no adverse impact and sometimes even improvements on English tasks. Additionally, the results highlight the model's initial strength as a critical factor when working with limited training data, with cross-lingual alignment offering minimal benefits for the low-resource language. Knowledge transfer from English to Persian has a marginal effect, primarily benefiting simple classification tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.13375v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Samin Mahdizadeh Sani, Pouya Sadeghi, Thuy-Trang Vu, Yadollah Yaghoobzadeh, Gholamreza Haffari</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Federated Learning and RAG Integration: A Scalable Approach for Medical Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.13720</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.13720v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This study analyzes the performance of domain-specific Large Language Models (LLMs) for the medical field by integrating Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) systems within a federated learning framework. Leveraging the inherent advantages of federated learning, such as preserving data privacy and enabling distributed computation, this research explores the integration of RAG systems with models trained under varying client configurations to optimize performance. Experimental results demonstrate that the federated learning-based models integrated with RAG systems consistently outperform their non-integrated counterparts across all evaluation metrics. This study highlights the potential of combining federated learning and RAG systems for developing domain-specific LLMs in the medical field, providing a scalable and privacy-preserving solution for enhancing text generation capabilities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.13720v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jincheol Jung, Hongju Jeong, Eui-Nam Huh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Global AI Inclusivity: A Large-Scale Multilingual Terminology Dataset</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18367</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18367v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The field of machine translation has achieved significant advancements, yet domain-specific terminology translation, particularly in AI, remains challenging. We introduced GIST, a large-scale multilingual AI terminology dataset containing 5K terms extracted from top AI conference papers spanning 2000 to 2023. The terms were translated into Arabic, Chinese, French, Japanese, and Russian using a hybrid framework that combines LLMs for extraction with human expertise for translation. The dataset's quality was benchmarked against existing resources, demonstrating superior translation accuracy through crowdsourced evaluation. GIST was integrated into translation workflows using post-translation refinement methods that required no retraining, where LLM prompting consistently improved BLEU and COMET scores. A web demonstration on the ACL Anthology platform highlights its practical application, showcasing improved accessibility for non-English speakers. This work aims to address critical gaps in AI terminology resources and fosters global inclusivity and collaboration in AI research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18367v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiarui Liu, Iman Ouzzani, Wenkai Li, Lechen Zhang, Tianyue Ou, Houda Bouamor, Zhijing Jin, Mona Diab</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AGGA: A Dataset of Academic Guidelines for Generative AI and Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.02063</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.02063v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This study introduces AGGA, a dataset comprising 80 academic guidelines for the use of Generative AIs (GAIs) and Large Language Models (LLMs) in academic settings, meticulously collected from official university websites. The dataset contains 188,674 words and serves as a valuable resource for natural language processing tasks commonly applied in requirements engineering, such as model synthesis, abstraction identification, and document structure assessment. Additionally, AGGA can be further annotated to function as a benchmark for various tasks, including ambiguity detection, requirements categorization, and the identification of equivalent requirements. Our methodologically rigorous approach ensured a thorough examination, with a selection of universities that represent a diverse range of global institutions, including top-ranked universities across six continents. The dataset captures perspectives from a variety of academic fields, including humanities, technology, and both public and private institutions, offering a broad spectrum of insights into the integration of GAIs and LLMs in academia.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.02063v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junfeng Jiao, Saleh Afroogh, Kevin Chen, David Atkinson, Amit Dhurandhar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instruction-Following Pruning for Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.02086</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.02086v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: With the rapid scaling of large language models (LLMs), structured pruning has become a widely used technique to learn efficient, smaller models from larger ones, delivering superior performance compared to training similarly sized models from scratch. In this paper, we move beyond the traditional static pruning approach of determining a fixed pruning mask for a model, and propose a dynamic approach to structured pruning. In our method, the pruning mask is input-dependent and adapts dynamically based on the information described in a user instruction. Our approach, termed "instruction-following pruning", introduces a sparse mask predictor that takes the user instruction as input and dynamically selects the most relevant model parameters for the given task. To identify and activate effective parameters, we jointly optimize the sparse mask predictor and the LLM, leveraging both instruction-following data and the pre-training corpus. Experimental results demonstrate the effectiveness of our approach on a wide range of evaluation benchmarks. For example, our 3B activated model improves over the 3B dense model by 5-8 points of absolute margin on domains such as math and coding, and rivals the performance of a 9B model.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.02086v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bairu Hou, Qibin Chen, Jianyu Wang, Guoli Yin, Chong Wang, Nan Du, Ruoming Pang, Shiyu Chang, Tao Lei</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tougher Text, Smarter Models: Raising the Bar for Adversarial Defence Benchmarks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.02654</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.02654v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advancements in natural language processing have highlighted the vulnerability of deep learning models to adversarial attacks. While various defence mechanisms have been proposed, there is a lack of comprehensive benchmarks that evaluate these defences across diverse datasets, models, and tasks. In this work, we address this gap by presenting an extensive benchmark for textual adversarial defence that significantly expands upon previous work. Our benchmark incorporates a wide range of datasets, evaluates state-of-the-art defence mechanisms, and extends the assessment to include critical tasks such as single-sentence classification, similarity and paraphrase identification, natural language inference, and commonsense reasoning. This work not only serves as a valuable resource for researchers and practitioners in the field of adversarial robustness but also identifies key areas for future research in textual adversarial defence. By establishing a new standard for benchmarking in this domain, we aim to accelerate progress towards more robust and reliable natural language processing systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.02654v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yang Wang, Chenghua Lin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Superficial Patterns to Semantic Understanding: Fine-Tuning Language Models on Contrast Sets</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.02683</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.02683v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large-scale pre-trained language models have demonstrated high performance on standard datasets for natural language inference (NLI) tasks. Unfortunately, these evaluations can be misleading, as although the models can perform well on in-distribution data, they perform poorly on out-of-distribution test sets, such as contrast sets. Contrast sets consist of perturbed instances of data that have very minor, but meaningful, changes to the input that alter the gold label, revealing how models can learn superficial patterns in the training data rather than learning more sophisticated language nuances. As an example, the ELECTRA-small language model achieves nearly 90% accuracy on an SNLI dataset but drops to 75% when tested on an out-of-distribution contrast set. The research carried out in this study explores how the robustness of a language model can be improved by exposing it to small amounts of more complex contrast sets during training to help it better learn language patterns. With this approach, the model recovers performance and achieves nearly 90% accuracy on contrast sets, highlighting the importance of diverse and challenging training data.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.02683v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Daniel Petrov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samba-ASR: State-Of-The-Art Speech Recognition Leveraging Structured State-Space Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.02832</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.02832v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We propose Samba ASR,the first state of the art Automatic Speech Recognition(ASR)model leveraging the novel Mamba architecture as both encoder and decoder,built on the foundation of state space models(SSMs).Unlike transformerbased ASR models,which rely on self-attention mechanisms to capture dependencies,Samba ASR effectively models both local and global temporal dependencies using efficient statespace dynamics,achieving remarkable performance gains.By addressing the limitations of transformers,such as quadratic scaling with input length and difficulty in handling longrange dependencies,Samba ASR achieves superior accuracy and efficiency.Experimental results demonstrate that Samba ASR surpasses existing opensource transformerbased ASR models across various standard benchmarks,establishing it as the new state of theart in ASR.Extensive evaluations on the benchmark dataset show significant improvements in Word Error Rate(WER),with competitive performance even in lowresource scenarios.Furthermore,the inherent computational efficiency and parameter optimization of the Mamba architecture make Samba ASR a scalable and robust solution for diverse ASR tasks.Our contributions include the development of a new Samba ASR architecture for automatic speech recognition(ASR),demonstrating the superiority of structured statespace models(SSMs)over transformer based models for speech sequence processing.We provide a comprehensive evaluation on public benchmarks,showcasing stateoftheart(SOTA)performance,and present an indepth analysis of computational efficiency,robustness to noise,and sequence generalization.This work highlights the viability of Mamba SSMs as a transformerfree alternative for efficient and accurate ASR.By leveraging the advancements of statespace modeling,Samba ASR redefines ASR performance standards and sets a new benchmark for future research in this field.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.02832v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Syed Abdul Gaffar Shakhadri, Kruthika KR, Kartik Basavaraj Angadi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interesting Scientific Idea Generation using Knowledge Graphs and LLMs: Evaluations with 100 Research Group Leaders</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.17044</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.17044v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The rapid growth of scientific literature makes it challenging for researchers to identify novel and impactful ideas, especially across disciplines. Modern artificial intelligence (AI) systems offer new approaches, potentially inspiring ideas not conceived by humans alone. But how compelling are these AI-generated ideas, and how can we improve their quality? Here, we introduce SciMuse, which uses 58 million research papers and a large-language model to generate research ideas. We conduct a large-scale evaluation in which over 100 research group leaders -- from natural sciences to humanities -- ranked more than 4,400 personalized ideas based on their interest. This data allows us to predict research interest using (1) supervised neural networks trained on human evaluations, and (2) unsupervised zero-shot ranking with large-language models. Our results demonstrate how future systems can help generating compelling research ideas and foster unforeseen interdisciplinary collaborations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.17044v3</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.DL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xuemei Gu, Mario Krenn</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Channel-Aware Domain-Adaptive Generative Adversarial Network for Robust Speech Recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.12386</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.12386v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: While pre-trained automatic speech recognition (ASR) systems demonstrate impressive performance on matched domains, their performance often degrades when confronted with channel mismatch stemming from unseen recording environments and conditions. To mitigate this issue, we propose a novel channel-aware data simulation method for robust ASR training. Our method harnesses the synergistic power of channel-extractive techniques and generative adversarial networks (GANs). We first train a channel encoder capable of extracting embeddings from arbitrary audio. On top of this, channel embeddings are extracted using a minimal amount of target-domain data and used to guide a GAN-based speech synthesizer. This synthesizer generates speech that faithfully preserves the phonetic content of the input while mimicking the channel characteristics of the target domain. We evaluate our method on the challenging Hakka Across Taiwan (HAT) and Taiwanese Across Taiwan (TAT) corpora, achieving relative character error rate (CER) reductions of 20.02% and 9.64%, respectively, compared to the baselines. These results highlight the efficacy of our channel-aware data simulation method for bridging the gap between source- and target-domain acoustics.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.12386v2</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chien-Chun Wang, Li-Wei Chen, Cheng-Kang Chou, Hung-Shin Lee, Berlin Chen, Hsin-Min Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BudgetMLAgent: A Cost-Effective LLM Multi-Agent system for Automating Machine Learning Tasks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.07464</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.07464v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) excel in diverse applications including generation of code snippets, but often struggle with generating code for complex Machine Learning (ML) tasks. Although existing LLM single-agent based systems give varying performance depending on the task complexity, they purely rely on larger and expensive models such as GPT-4. Our investigation reveals that no-cost and low-cost models such as Gemini-Pro, Mixtral and CodeLlama perform far worse than GPT-4 in a single-agent setting. With the motivation of developing a cost-efficient LLM based solution for solving ML tasks, we propose an LLM Multi-Agent based system which leverages combination of experts using profiling, efficient retrieval of past observations, LLM cascades, and ask-the-expert calls. Through empirical analysis on ML engineering tasks in the MLAgentBench benchmark, we demonstrate the effectiveness of our system, using no-cost models, namely Gemini as the base LLM, paired with GPT-4 in cascade and expert to serve occasional ask-the-expert calls for planning. With 94.2\% reduction in the cost (from \$0.931 per run cost averaged over all tasks for GPT-4 single agent system to \$0.054), our system is able to yield better average success rate of 32.95\% as compared to GPT-4 single-agent system yielding 22.72\% success rate averaged over all the tasks of MLAgentBench.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.07464v2</guid>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shubham Gandhi, Manasi Patwardhan, Lovekesh Vig, Gautam Shroff</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SWEPO: Simultaneous Weighted Preference Optimization for Group Contrastive Alignment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.04628</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.04628v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We introduce Simultaneous Weighted Preference Optimization (SWEPO), a novel extension of Direct Preference Optimization (DPO) designed to accommodate multiple dynamically chosen positive and negative responses for each query. SWEPO employs a weighted group contrastive loss, assigning weights to responses based on their deviation from the mean reward score. This approach effectively prioritizes responses that are significantly better or worse than the average, enhancing optimization. Our theoretical analysis demonstrates that simultaneously considering multiple preferences reduces alignment bias, resulting in more robust alignment. Additionally, we provide insights into the training dynamics of our loss function and a related function, InfoNCA. Empirical validation on the UltraFeedback dataset establishes SWEPO as state-of-the-art, with superior performance in downstream evaluations using the AlpacaEval dataset.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.04628v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Taneesh Gupta, Rahul Madhavan, Xuchao Zhang, Chetan Bansal, Saravan Rajmohan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Large Language Models for Active Merchant Non-player Characters</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.11189</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.11189v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We highlight two significant issues leading to the passivity of current merchant non-player characters (NPCs): pricing and communication. While immersive interactions have been a focus, negotiations between merchant NPCs and players on item prices have not received sufficient attention. First, we define passive pricing as the limited ability of merchants to modify predefined item prices. Second, passive communication means that merchants can only interact with players in a scripted manner. To tackle these issues and create an active merchant NPC, we propose a merchant framework based on large language models (LLMs), called MART, which consists of an appraiser module and a negotiator module. We conducted two experiments to guide game developers in selecting appropriate implementations by comparing different training methods and LLM sizes. Our findings indicate that finetuning methods, such as supervised finetuning (SFT) and knowledge distillation (KD), are effective in using smaller LLMs to implement active merchant NPCs. Additionally, we found three irregular cases arising from the responses of LLMs. We expect our findings to guide developers in using LLMs for developing active merchant NPCs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.11189v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Byungjun Kim, Minju Kim, Dayeon Seo, Bugeun Kim</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toxicity Detection towards Adaptability to Changing Perturbations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.15267</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.15267v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Toxicity detection is crucial for maintaining the peace of the society. While existing methods perform well on normal toxic contents or those generated by specific perturbation methods, they are vulnerable to evolving perturbation patterns. However, in real-world scenarios, malicious users tend to create new perturbation patterns for fooling the detectors. For example, some users may circumvent the detector of large language models (LLMs) by adding `I am a scientist' at the beginning of the prompt. In this paper, we introduce a novel problem, i.e., continual learning jailbreak perturbation patterns, into the toxicity detection field. To tackle this problem, we first construct a new dataset generated by 9 types of perturbation patterns, 7 of them are summarized from prior work and 2 of them are developed by us. We then systematically validate the vulnerability of current methods on this new perturbation pattern-aware dataset via both the zero-shot and fine tuned cross-pattern detection. Upon this, we present the domain incremental learning paradigm and the corresponding benchmark to ensure the detector's robustness to dynamically emerging types of perturbed toxic text. Our code and dataset are provided in the appendix and will be publicly available at GitHub, by which we wish to offer new research opportunities for the security-relevant communities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.15267v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hankun Kang, Jianhao Chen, Yongqi Li, Xin Miao, Mayi Xu, Ming Zhong, Yuanyuan Zhu, Tieyun Qian</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retrieval-Augmented Generation with Graphs (GraphRAG)</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.00309</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.00309v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) is a powerful technique that enhances downstream task execution by retrieving additional information, such as knowledge, skills, and tools from external sources. Graph, by its intrinsic "nodes connected by edges" nature, encodes massive heterogeneous and relational information, making it a golden resource for RAG in tremendous real-world applications. As a result, we have recently witnessed increasing attention on equipping RAG with Graph, i.e., GraphRAG. However, unlike conventional RAG, where the retriever, generator, and external data sources can be uniformly designed in the neural-embedding space, the uniqueness of graph-structured data, such as diverse-formatted and domain-specific relational knowledge, poses unique and significant challenges when designing GraphRAG for different domains. Given the broad applicability, the associated design challenges, and the recent surge in GraphRAG, a systematic and up-to-date survey of its key concepts and techniques is urgently desired. Following this motivation, we present a comprehensive and up-to-date survey on GraphRAG. Our survey first proposes a holistic GraphRAG framework by defining its key components, including query processor, retriever, organizer, generator, and data source. Furthermore, recognizing that graphs in different domains exhibit distinct relational patterns and require dedicated designs, we review GraphRAG techniques uniquely tailored to each domain. Finally, we discuss research challenges and brainstorm directions to inspire cross-disciplinary opportunities. Our survey repository is publicly maintained at https://github.com/Graph-RAG/GraphRAG/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.00309v2</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haoyu Han, Yu Wang, Harry Shomer, Kai Guo, Jiayuan Ding, Yongjia Lei, Mahantesh Halappanavar, Ryan A. Rossi, Subhabrata Mukherjee, Xianfeng Tang, Qi He, Zhigang Hua, Bo Long, Tong Zhao, Neil Shah, Amin Javari, Yinglong Xia, Jiliang Tang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graph-Aware Isomorphic Attention for Adaptive Dynamics in Transformers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.02393</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.02393v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We present an approach to modifying Transformer architectures by integrating graph-aware relational reasoning into the attention mechanism, merging concepts from graph neural networks and language modeling. Building on the inherent connection between attention and graph theory, we reformulate the Transformer's attention mechanism as a graph operation and propose Graph-Aware Isomorphic Attention. This method leverages advanced graph modeling strategies, including Graph Isomorphism Networks (GIN) and Principal Neighborhood Aggregation (PNA), to enrich the representation of relational structures. Our approach captures complex dependencies and generalizes across tasks, as evidenced by a reduced generalization gap and improved learning performance. Additionally, we expand the concept of graph-aware attention to introduce Sparse GIN-Attention, a fine-tuning approach that employs sparse GINs. By interpreting attention matrices as sparse adjacency graphs, this technique enhances the adaptability of pre-trained foundational models with minimal computational overhead, endowing them with graph-aware capabilities. Sparse GIN-Attention fine-tuning achieves improved training dynamics and better generalization compared to alternative methods like low-rank adaption (LoRA). We discuss latent graph-like structures within traditional attention mechanisms, offering a new lens through which Transformers can be understood. By evolving Transformers as hierarchical GIN models for relational reasoning. This perspective suggests profound implications for foundational model development, enabling the design of architectures that dynamically adapt to both local and global dependencies. Applications in bioinformatics, materials science, language modeling, and beyond could benefit from this synthesis of relational and sequential data modeling, setting the stage for interpretable and generalizable modeling strategies.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.02393v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cond-mat.mes-hall</category>
      <category>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Markus J. Buehler</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DPO Kernels: A Semantically-Aware, Kernel-Enhanced, and Divergence-Rich Paradigm for Direct Preference Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.03271</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.03271v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The rapid rise of large language models (LLMs) has unlocked many applications but also underscores the challenge of aligning them with diverse values and preferences. Direct Preference Optimization (DPO) is central to alignment but constrained by fixed divergences and limited feature transformations. We propose DPO-Kernels, which integrates kernel methods to address these issues through four key contributions: (i) Kernelized Representations with polynomial, RBF, Mahalanobis, and spectral kernels for richer transformations, plus a hybrid loss combining embedding-based and probability-based objectives; (ii) Divergence Alternatives (Jensen-Shannon, Hellinger, Renyi, Bhattacharyya, Wasserstein, and f-divergences) for greater stability; (iii) Data-Driven Selection metrics that automatically choose the best kernel-divergence pair; and (iv) a Hierarchical Mixture of Kernels for both local precision and global modeling. Evaluations on 12 datasets demonstrate state-of-the-art performance in factuality, safety, reasoning, and instruction following. Grounded in Heavy-Tailed Self-Regularization, DPO-Kernels maintains robust generalization for LLMs, offering a comprehensive resource for further alignment research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.03271v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Amitava Das, Suranjana Trivedy, Danush Khanna, Rajarshi Roy, Gurpreet Singh, Basab Ghosh, Yaswanth Narsupalli, Vinija Jain, Vasu Sharma, Aishwarya Naresh Reganti, Aman Chadha</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
