<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL</link>
    <description>cs.CL updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 04:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Saturday</day>
      <day>Sunday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>It's the same but not the same: Do LLMs distinguish Spanish varieties?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20049</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20049v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In recent years, large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated a high capacity for understanding and generating text in Spanish. However, with five hundred million native speakers, Spanish is not a homogeneous language but rather one rich in diatopic variations spanning both sides of the Atlantic. For this reason, in this study, we evaluate the ability of nine language models to identify and distinguish the morphosyntactic and lexical peculiarities of seven varieties of Spanish (Andean, Antillean, Continental Caribbean, Chilean, Peninsular, Mexican and Central American and Rioplatense) through a multiple-choice test. The results indicate that the Peninsular Spanish variety is the best identified by all models and that, among them, GPT-4o is the only model capable of recognizing the variability of the Spanish language.
  --
  En los \'ultimos a\~nos, los grandes modelos de lenguaje (LLMs, por sus siglas en ingl\'es) han demostrado una alta capacidad para comprender y generar texto en espa\~nol. Sin embargo, con quinientos millones de hablantes nativos, la espa\~nola no es una lengua homog\'enea, sino rica en variedades diat\'opicas que se extienden a ambos lados del Atl\'antico. Por todo ello, evaluamos en este trabajo la capacidad de nueve modelos de lenguaje de identificar y discernir las peculiaridades morfosint\'acticas y l\'exicas de siete variedades de espa\~nol (andino, antillano, caribe\~no continental, chileno, espa\~nol peninsular, mexicano y centroamericano y rioplatense) mediante un test de respuesta m\'ultiple. Los resultados obtenidos indican que la variedad de espa\~nol peninsular es la mejor identificada por todos los modelos y que, de entre todos, GPT-4o es el \'unico modelo capaz de identificar la variabilidad de la lengua espa\~nola.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20049v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Marina Mayor-Rocher, Cristina Pozo, Nina Melero, Gonzalo Mart\'inez, Mar\'ia Grandury, Pedro Reviriego</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Large Language Models on Multiword Expressions in Multilingual and Code-Switched Contexts</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20051</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20051v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Multiword expressions, characterised by non-compositional meanings and syntactic irregularities, are an example of nuanced language. These expressions can be used literally or idiomatically, leading to significant changes in meaning. While large language models have demonstrated strong performance across many tasks, their ability to handle such linguistic subtleties remains uncertain. Therefore, this study evaluates how state-of-the-art language models process the ambiguity of potentially idiomatic multiword expressions, particularly in contexts that are less frequent, where models are less likely to rely on memorisation. By evaluating models across in Portuguese and Galician, in addition to English, and using a novel code-switched dataset and a novel task, we find that large language models, despite their strengths, struggle with nuanced language. In particular, we find that the latest models, including GPT-4, fail to outperform the xlm-roBERTa-base baselines in both detection and semantic tasks, with especially poor performance on the novel tasks we introduce, despite its similarity to existing tasks. Overall, our results demonstrate that multiword expressions, especially those which are ambiguous, continue to be a challenge to models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20051v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Frances Laureano De Leon, Harish Tayyar Madabushi, Mark G. Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding and Mitigating Risks of Generative AI in Financial Services</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20086</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20086v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: To responsibly develop Generative AI (GenAI) products, it is critical to define the scope of acceptable inputs and outputs. What constitutes a "safe" response is an actively debated question. Academic work puts an outsized focus on evaluating models by themselves for general purpose aspects such as toxicity, bias, and fairness, especially in conversational applications being used by a broad audience. In contrast, less focus is put on considering sociotechnical systems in specialized domains. Yet, those specialized systems can be subject to extensive and well-understood legal and regulatory scrutiny. These product-specific considerations need to be set in industry-specific laws, regulations, and corporate governance requirements. In this paper, we aim to highlight AI content safety considerations specific to the financial services domain and outline an associated AI content risk taxonomy. We compare this taxonomy to existing work in this space and discuss implications of risk category violations on various stakeholders. We evaluate how existing open-source technical guardrail solutions cover this taxonomy by assessing them on data collected via red-teaming activities. Our results demonstrate that these guardrails fail to detect most of the content risks we discuss.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20086v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3715275.3732168</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Sebastian Gehrmann, Claire Huang, Xian Teng, Sergei Yurovski, Iyanuoluwa Shode, Chirag S. Patel, Arjun Bhorkar, Naveen Thomas, John Doucette, David Rosenberg, Mark Dredze, David Rabinowitz</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward Evaluative Thinking: Meta Policy Optimization with Evolving Reward Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20157</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20157v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Reward-based alignment methods for large language models (LLMs) face two key limitations: vulnerability to reward hacking, where models exploit flaws in the reward signal; and reliance on brittle, labor-intensive prompt engineering when LLMs are used as reward models. We introduce Meta Policy Optimization (MPO), a framework that addresses these challenges by integrating a meta-reward model that dynamically refines the reward model's prompt throughout training. In MPO, the meta-reward model monitors the evolving training context and continuously adjusts the reward model's prompt to maintain high alignment, providing an adaptive reward signal that resists exploitation by the policy. This meta-learning approach promotes a more stable policy optimization, and greatly reduces the need for manual reward prompt design. It yields performance on par with or better than models guided by extensively hand-crafted reward prompts. Furthermore, we show that MPO maintains its effectiveness across diverse tasks, such as question answering and mathematical reasoning, without requiring specialized reward designs. Beyond standard RLAIF, MPO's meta-learning formulation is readily extensible to higher-level alignment frameworks. Overall, this method addresses theoretical and practical challenges in reward-based RL alignment for LLMs, paving the way for more robust and adaptable alignment strategies. The code and models will be publicly shared.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20157v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zae Myung Kim, Chanwoo Park, Vipul Raheja, Dongyeop Kang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MICE for CATs: Model-Internal Confidence Estimation for Calibrating Agents with Tools</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20168</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20168v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Tool-using agents that act in the world need to be both useful and safe. Well-calibrated model confidences can be used to weigh the risk versus reward of potential actions, but prior work shows that many models are poorly calibrated. Inspired by interpretability literature exploring the internals of models, we propose a novel class of model-internal confidence estimators (MICE) to better assess confidence when calling tools. MICE first decodes from each intermediate layer of the language model using logitLens and then computes similarity scores between each layer's generation and the final output. These features are fed into a learned probabilistic classifier to assess confidence in the decoded output. On the simulated trial and error (STE) tool-calling dataset using Llama3 models, we find that MICE beats or matches the baselines on smoothed expected calibration error. Using MICE confidences to determine whether to call a tool significantly improves over strong baselines on a new metric, expected tool-calling utility. Further experiments show that MICE is sample-efficient, can generalize zero-shot to unseen APIs, and results in higher tool-calling utility in scenarios with varying risk levels. Our code is open source, available at https://github.com/microsoft/mice_for_cats.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20168v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nishant Subramani, Jason Eisner, Justin Svegliato, Benjamin Van Durme, Yu Su, Sam Thomson</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Multimodal Pipeline for Clinical Data Extraction: Applying Vision-Language Models to Scans of Transfusion Reaction Reports</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20220</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20220v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Despite the growing adoption of electronic health records, many processes still rely on paper documents, reflecting the heterogeneous real-world conditions in which healthcare is delivered. The manual transcription process is time-consuming and prone to errors when transferring paper-based data to digital formats. To streamline this workflow, this study presents an open-source pipeline that extracts and categorizes checkbox data from scanned documents. Demonstrated on transfusion reaction reports, the design supports adaptation to other checkbox-rich document types. The proposed method integrates checkbox detection, multilingual optical character recognition (OCR) and multilingual vision-language models (VLMs). The pipeline achieves high precision and recall compared against annually compiled gold-standards from 2017 to 2024. The result is a reduction in administrative workload and accurate regulatory reporting. The open-source availability of this pipeline encourages self-hosted parsing of checkbox forms.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20220v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Henning Sch\"afer, Cynthia S. Schmidt, Johannes Wutzkowsky, Kamil Lorek, Lea Reinartz, Johannes R\"uckert, Christian Temme, Britta B\"ockmann, Peter A. Horn, Christoph M. Friedrich</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Platform for Generating Educational Activities to Teach English as a Second Language</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20251</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20251v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present a platform for the generation of educational activities oriented to teaching English as a foreign language. The different activities --games and language practice exercises-- are strongly based on Natural Language Processing techniques. The platform offers the possibility of playing out-of-the-box games, generated from resources created semi-automatically and then manually curated. It can also generate games or exercises of greater complexity from texts entered by teachers, providing a stage of review and edition of the generated content before use. As a way of expanding the variety of activities in the platform, we are currently experimenting with image and text generation. In order to integrate them and improve the performance of other neural tools already integrated, we are working on migrating the platform to a more powerful server. In this paper we describe the development of our platform and its deployment for end users, discussing the challenges faced and how we overcame them, and also detail our future work plans.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20251v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aiala Ros\'a, Santiago G\'ongora, Juan Pablo Filevich, Ignacio Sastre, Laura Musto, Brian Carpenter, Luis Chiruzzo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Systematic Reviews with Large Language Models: Using GPT-4 and Kimi</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20276</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20276v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This research delved into GPT-4 and Kimi, two Large Language Models (LLMs), for systematic reviews. We evaluated their performance by comparing LLM-generated codes with human-generated codes from a peer-reviewed systematic review on assessment. Our findings suggested that the performance of LLMs fluctuates by data volume and question complexity for systematic reviews.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20276v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>stat.AP</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dandan Chen Kaptur, Yue Huang, Xuejun Ryan Ji, Yanhui Guo, Bradley Kaptur</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UD-English-CHILDES: A Collected Resource of Gold and Silver Universal Dependencies Trees for Child Language Interactions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20304</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20304v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: CHILDES is a widely used resource of transcribed child and child-directed speech. This paper introduces UD-English-CHILDES, the first officially released Universal Dependencies (UD) treebank derived from previously dependency-annotated CHILDES data with consistent and unified annotation guidelines. Our corpus harmonizes annotations from 11 children and their caregivers, totaling over 48k sentences. We validate existing gold-standard annotations under the UD v2 framework and provide an additional 1M silver-standard sentences, offering a consistent resource for computational and linguistic research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20304v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiulin Yang, Zhuoxuan Ju, Lanni Bu, Zoey Liu, Nathan Schneider</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Labeling Case Similarity based on Co-Citation of Legal Articles in Judgment Documents with Empirical Dispute-Based Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20323</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20323v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This report addresses the challenge of limited labeled datasets for developing legal recommender systems, particularly in specialized domains like labor disputes. We propose a new approach leveraging the co-citation of legal articles within cases to establish similarity and enable algorithmic annotation. This method draws a parallel to the concept of case co-citation, utilizing cited precedents as indicators of shared legal issues. To evaluate the labeled results, we employ a system that recommends similar cases based on plaintiffs' accusations, defendants' rebuttals, and points of disputes. The evaluation demonstrates that the recommender, with finetuned text embedding models and a reasonable BiLSTM module can recommend labor cases whose similarity was measured by the co-citation of the legal articles. This research contributes to the development of automated annotation techniques for legal documents, particularly in areas with limited access to comprehensive legal databases.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20323v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.DL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence (volumn number to be added), 2025</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Chao-Lin Liu, Po-Hsien Wu, Yi-Ting Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local Prompt Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20355</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20355v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In recent years, the use of prompts to guide the output of Large Language Models have increased dramatically. However, even the best of experts struggle to choose the correct words to stitch up a prompt for the desired task. To solve this, LLM driven prompt optimization emerged as an important problem. Existing prompt optimization methods optimize a prompt globally, where in all the prompt tokens have to be optimized over a large vocabulary while solving a complex task. The large optimization space (tokens) leads to insufficient guidance for a better prompt. In this work, we introduce Local Prompt Optimization (LPO) that integrates with any general automatic prompt engineering method. We identify the optimization tokens in a prompt and nudge the LLM to focus only on those tokens in its optimization step. We observe remarkable performance improvements on Math Reasoning (GSM8k and MultiArith) and BIG-bench Hard benchmarks across various automatic prompt engineering methods. Further, we show that LPO converges to the optimal prompt faster than global methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20355v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yash Jain, Vishal Chowdhary</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Causes Knowledge Loss in Multilingual Language Models?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20356</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20356v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Cross-lingual transfer in natural language processing (NLP) models enhances multilingual performance by leveraging shared linguistic knowledge. However, traditional methods that process all data simultaneously often fail to mimic real-world scenarios, leading to challenges like catastrophic forgetting, where fine-tuning on new tasks degrades performance on previously learned ones. Our study explores this issue in multilingual contexts, focusing on linguistic differences affecting representational learning rather than just model parameters. We experiment with 52 languages using LoRA adapters of varying ranks to evaluate non-shared, partially shared, and fully shared parameters. Our aim is to see if parameter sharing through adapters can mitigate forgetting while preserving prior knowledge. We find that languages using non-Latin scripts are more susceptible to catastrophic forgetting, whereas those written in Latin script facilitate more effective cross-lingual transfer.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20356v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Maria Khelli, Samuel Cahyawijaya, Ayu Purwarianti, Genta Indra Winata</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DMDTEval: An Evaluation and Analysis of LLMs on Disambiguation in Multi-domain Translation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20371</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20371v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Currently, Large Language Models (LLMs) have achieved remarkable results in machine translation. However, their performance in multi-domain translation (MDT) is less satisfactory; the meanings of words can vary across different domains, highlighting the significant ambiguity inherent in MDT. Therefore, evaluating the disambiguation ability of LLMs in MDT remains an open problem. To this end, we present an evaluation and analysis of LLMs on disambiguation in multi-domain translation (DMDTEval), our systematic evaluation framework consisting of three critical aspects: (1) we construct a translation test set with multi-domain ambiguous word annotation, (2) we curate a diverse set of disambiguation prompting templates, and (3) we design precise disambiguation metrics, and study the efficacy of various prompting strategies on multiple state-of-the-art LLMs. Our extensive experiments reveal a number of crucial findings that we believe will pave the way and also facilitate further research in the critical area of improving the disambiguation of LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20371v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhibo Man, Yuanmeng Chen, Yujie Zhang, Yufeng Chen, Jinan Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Psychology of AI -- Does Primacy Effect Affect ChatGPT and Other LLMs?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20444</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20444v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We study the primacy effect in three commercial LLMs: ChatGPT, Gemini and Claude. We do this by repurposing the famous experiment Asch (1946) conducted using human subjects. The experiment is simple, given two candidates with equal descriptions which one is preferred if one description has positive adjectives first before negative ones and another description has negative adjectives followed by positive ones. We test this in two experiments. In one experiment, LLMs are given both candidates simultaneously in the same prompt, and in another experiment, LLMs are given both candidates separately. We test all the models with 200 candidate pairs. We found that, in the first experiment, ChatGPT preferred the candidate with positive adjectives listed first, while Gemini preferred both equally often. Claude refused to make a choice. In the second experiment, ChatGPT and Claude were most likely to rank both candidates equally. In the case where they did not give an equal rating, both showed a clear preference to a candidate that had negative adjectives listed first. Gemini was most likely to prefer a candidate with negative adjectives listed first.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20444v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mika H\"am\"al\"ainen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Team ACK at SemEval-2025 Task 2: Beyond Word-for-Word Machine Translation for English-Korean Pairs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20451</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20451v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Translating knowledge-intensive and entity-rich text between English and Korean requires transcreation to preserve language-specific and cultural nuances beyond literal, phonetic or word-for-word conversion. We evaluate 13 models (LLMs and MT models) using automatic metrics and human assessment by bilingual annotators. Our findings show LLMs outperform traditional MT systems but struggle with entity translation requiring cultural adaptation. By constructing an error taxonomy, we identify incorrect responses and entity name errors as key issues, with performance varying by entity type and popularity level. This work exposes gaps in automatic evaluation metrics and hope to enable future work in completing culturally-nuanced machine translation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20451v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Daniel Lee, Harsh Sharma, Jieun Han, Sunny Jeong, Alice Oh, Vered Shwartz</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fane at SemEval-2025 Task 10: Zero-Shot Entity Framing with Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20469</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20469v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Understanding how news narratives frame entities is crucial for studying media's impact on societal perceptions of events. In this paper, we evaluate the zero-shot capabilities of large language models (LLMs) in classifying framing roles. Through systematic experimentation, we assess the effects of input context, prompting strategies, and task decomposition. Our findings show that a hierarchical approach of first identifying broad roles and then fine-grained roles, outperforms single-step classification. We also demonstrate that optimal input contexts and prompts vary across task levels, highlighting the need for subtask-specific strategies. We achieve a Main Role Accuracy of 89.4% and an Exact Match Ratio of 34.5%, demonstrating the effectiveness of our approach. Our findings emphasize the importance of tailored prompt design and input context optimization for improving LLM performance in entity framing.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20469v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Enfa Fane, Mihai Surdeanu, Eduardo Blanco, Steven R. Corman</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing LLM Language Adaption through Cross-lingual In-Context Pre-training</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20484</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20484v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) exhibit remarkable multilingual capabilities despite English-dominated pre-training, attributed to cross-lingual mechanisms during pre-training. Existing methods for enhancing cross-lingual transfer remain constrained by parallel resources, suffering from limited linguistic and domain coverage. We propose Cross-lingual In-context Pre-training (CrossIC-PT), a simple and scalable approach that enhances cross-lingual transfer by leveraging semantically related bilingual texts via simple next-word prediction. We construct CrossIC-PT samples by interleaving semantic-related bilingual Wikipedia documents into a single context window. To access window size constraints, we implement a systematic segmentation policy to split long bilingual document pairs into chunks while adjusting the sliding window mechanism to preserve contextual coherence. We further extend data availability through a semantic retrieval framework to construct CrossIC-PT samples from web-crawled corpus. Experimental results demonstrate that CrossIC-PT improves multilingual performance on three models (Llama-3.1-8B, Qwen2.5-7B, and Qwen2.5-1.5B) across six target languages, yielding performance gains of 3.79%, 3.99%, and 1.95%, respectively, with additional improvements after data augmentation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20484v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Linjuan Wu, Haoran Wei, Huan Lin, Tianhao Li, Baosong Yang, Weiming Lu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UniDetox: Universal Detoxification of Large Language Models via Dataset Distillation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20500</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20500v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present UniDetox, a universally applicable method designed to mitigate toxicity across various large language models (LLMs). Previous detoxification methods are typically model-specific, addressing only individual models or model families, and require careful hyperparameter tuning due to the trade-off between detoxification efficacy and language modeling performance. In contrast, UniDetox provides a detoxification technique that can be universally applied to a wide range of LLMs without the need for separate model-specific tuning. Specifically, we propose a novel and efficient dataset distillation technique for detoxification using contrastive decoding. This approach distills detoxifying representations in the form of synthetic text data, enabling universal detoxification of any LLM through fine-tuning with the distilled text. Our experiments demonstrate that the detoxifying text distilled from GPT-2 can effectively detoxify larger models, including OPT, Falcon, and LLaMA-2. Furthermore, UniDetox eliminates the need for separate hyperparameter tuning for each model, as a single hyperparameter configuration can be seamlessly applied across different models. Additionally, analysis of the detoxifying text reveals a reduction in politically biased content, providing insights into the attributes necessary for effective detoxification of LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20500v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Huimin Lu, Masaru Isonuma, Junichiro Mori, Ichiro Sakata</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting the MIMIC-IV Benchmark: Experiments Using Language Models for Electronic Health Records</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20547</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20547v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The lack of standardized evaluation benchmarks in the medical domain for text inputs can be a barrier to widely adopting and leveraging the potential of natural language models for health-related downstream tasks. This paper revisited an openly available MIMIC-IV benchmark for electronic health records (EHRs) to address this issue. First, we integrate the MIMIC-IV data within the Hugging Face datasets library to allow an easy share and use of this collection. Second, we investigate the application of templates to convert EHR tabular data to text. Experiments using fine-tuned and zero-shot LLMs on the mortality of patients task show that fine-tuned text-based models are competitive against robust tabular classifiers. In contrast, zero-shot LLMs struggle to leverage EHR representations. This study underlines the potential of text-based approaches in the medical field and highlights areas for further improvement.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20547v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Proceedings of the First Workshop on Patient-Oriented Language Processing (CL4Health) @ LREC-COLING 2024, May 2024, Torino, Italy</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Jesus Lovon (IRIT-IRIS), Thouria Ben-Haddi (IRIT-IRIS), Jules Di Scala (IRIT-IRIS), Jose G. Moreno (IRIT-IRIS), Lynda Tamine (IRIT-IRIS)</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BrAIcht, a theatrical agent that speaks like Bertolt Brecht's characters</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20552</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20552v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This project introduces BrAIcht, an AI conversational agent that creates dialogues in the distinctive style of the famous German playwright Bertolt Brecht. BrAIcht is fine-tuned using German LeoLM, a large language model with 7 billion parameters and a modified version of the base Llama2 suitable for German language tasks. For fine-tuning, 29 plays of Bertolt Brecht and 907 of other German plays that are stylistically similar to Bertolt Brecht are used to form a more di-erse dataset. Due to the limited memory capacity, a parameterefficient fine-tuning technique called QLoRA is implemented to train the large language model. The results, based on BLEU score and perplexity, show very promising performance of BrAIcht in generating dialogues in the style of Bertolt Brecht.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20552v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Generative Art Conference - GA2024, Generative Art and Design Lab, Argenia Association, Roma, Italy, Dec 2024, Venice, Italy. pp.290-296</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Baz Roland (LIASD), Kristina Malyseva (LIASD), Anna Pappa (LIASD), Tristan Cazenave (APA)</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ClonEval: An Open Voice Cloning Benchmark</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20581</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20581v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present a novel benchmark for voice cloning text-to-speech models. The benchmark consists of an evaluation protocol, an open-source library for assessing the performance of voice cloning models, and an accompanying leaderboard. The paper discusses design considerations and presents a detailed description of the evaluation procedure. The usage of the software library is explained, along with the organization of results on the leaderboard.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20581v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Iwona Christop, Tomasz Kuczy\'nski, Marek Kubis</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TF1-EN-3M: Three Million Synthetic Moral Fables for Training Small, Open Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20605</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20605v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Moral stories are a time-tested vehicle for transmitting values, yet modern NLP lacks a large, structured corpus that couples coherent narratives with explicit ethical lessons. We close this gap with TF1-EN-3M, the first open dataset of three million English-language fables generated exclusively by instruction-tuned models no larger than 8B parameters. Each story follows a six-slot scaffold (character -&gt; trait -&gt; setting -&gt; conflict -&gt; resolution -&gt; moral), produced through a combinatorial prompt engine that guarantees genre fidelity while covering a broad thematic space.
  A hybrid evaluation pipeline blends (i) a GPT-based critic that scores grammar, creativity, moral clarity, and template adherence with (ii) reference-free diversity and readability metrics. Among ten open-weight candidates, an 8B-parameter Llama-3 variant delivers the best quality-speed trade-off, producing high-scoring fables on a single consumer GPU (&lt;24 GB VRAM) at approximately 13.5 cents per 1,000 fables.
  We release the dataset, generation code, evaluation scripts, and full metadata under a permissive license, enabling exact reproducibility and cost benchmarking. TF1-EN-3M opens avenues for research in instruction following, narrative intelligence, value alignment, and child-friendly educational AI, demonstrating that large-scale moral storytelling no longer requires proprietary giant models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20605v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mihai Nadas, Laura Diosan, Andrei Piscoran, Andreea Tomescu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WenyanGPT: A Large Language Model for Classical Chinese Tasks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20609</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20609v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Classical Chinese, as the core carrier of Chinese culture, plays a crucial role in the inheritance and study of ancient literature. However, existing natural language processing models primarily optimize for Modern Chinese, resulting in inadequate performance on Classical Chinese. This paper presents a comprehensive solution for Classical Chinese language processing. By continuing pre-training and instruction fine-tuning on the LLaMA3-8B-Chinese model, we construct a large language model, WenyanGPT, which is specifically designed for Classical Chinese tasks. Additionally, we develop an evaluation benchmark dataset, WenyanBENCH. Experimental results on WenyanBENCH demonstrate that WenyanGPT significantly outperforms current advanced LLMs in various Classical Chinese tasks. We make the model's training data, instruction fine-tuning data\footnote, and evaluation benchmark dataset publicly available to promote further research and development in the field of Classical Chinese processing.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20609v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xinyu Yao, Mengdi Wang, Bo Chen, Xiaobing Zhao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cooking Up Creativity: A Cognitively-Inspired Approach for Enhancing LLM Creativity through Structured Representations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20643</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20643v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) excel at countless tasks, yet struggle with creativity. In this paper, we introduce a novel approach that couples LLMs with structured representations and cognitively inspired manipulations to generate more creative and diverse ideas. Our notion of creativity goes beyond superficial token-level variations; rather, we explicitly recombine structured representations of existing ideas, allowing our algorithm to effectively explore the more abstract landscape of ideas. We demonstrate our approach in the culinary domain with DishCOVER, a model that generates creative recipes. Experiments comparing our model's results to those of GPT-4o show greater diversity. Domain expert evaluations reveal that our outputs, which are mostly coherent and feasible culinary creations, significantly surpass GPT-4o in terms of novelty, thus outperforming it in creative generation. We hope our work inspires further research into structured creativity in AI.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20643v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Moran Mizrahi, Chen Shani, Gabriel Stanovsky, Dan Jurafsky, Dafna Shahaf</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Generative-AI-Driven Claim Retrieval System Capable of Detecting and Retrieving Claims from Social Media Platforms in Multiple Languages</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20668</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20668v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Online disinformation poses a global challenge, placing significant demands on fact-checkers who must verify claims efficiently to prevent the spread of false information. A major issue in this process is the redundant verification of already fact-checked claims, which increases workload and delays responses to newly emerging claims. This research introduces an approach that retrieves previously fact-checked claims, evaluates their relevance to a given input, and provides supplementary information to support fact-checkers. Our method employs large language models (LLMs) to filter irrelevant fact-checks and generate concise summaries and explanations, enabling fact-checkers to faster assess whether a claim has been verified before. In addition, we evaluate our approach through both automatic and human assessments, where humans interact with the developed tool to review its effectiveness. Our results demonstrate that LLMs are able to filter out many irrelevant fact-checks and, therefore, reduce effort and streamline the fact-checking process.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20668v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ivan Vykopal, Martin Hyben, Robert Moro, Michal Gregor, Jakub Simko</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-native Children's Automatic Speech Assessment Challenge (NOCASA)</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20678</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20678v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper presents the "Non-native Children's Automatic Speech Assessment" (NOCASA) - a data competition part of the IEEE MLSP 2025 conference. NOCASA challenges participants to develop new systems that can assess single-word pronunciations of young second language (L2) learners as part of a gamified pronunciation training app. To achieve this, several issues must be addressed, most notably the limited nature of available training data and the highly unbalanced distribution among the pronunciation level categories. To expedite the development, we provide a pseudo-anonymized training data (TeflonNorL2), containing 10,334 recordings from 44 speakers attempting to pronounce 205 distinct Norwegian words, human-rated on a 1 to 5 scale (number of stars that should be given in the game). In addition to the data, two already trained systems are released as official baselines: an SVM classifier trained on the ComParE_16 acoustic feature set and a multi-task wav2vec 2.0 model. The latter achieves the best performance on the challenge test set, with an unweighted average recall (UAR) of 36.37%.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20678v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yaroslav Getman, Tam\'as Gr\'osz, Mikko Kurimo, Giampiero Salvi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Information Retrieval Approaches Good at Harmonising Longitudinal Survey Questions in Social Science?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20679</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20679v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Automated detection of semantically equivalent questions in longitudinal social science surveys is crucial for long-term studies informing empirical research in the social, economic, and health sciences. Retrieving equivalent questions faces dual challenges: inconsistent representation of theoretical constructs (i.e. concept/sub-concept) across studies as well as between question and response options, and the evolution of vocabulary and structure in longitudinal text. To address these challenges, our multi-disciplinary collaboration of computer scientists and survey specialists presents a new information retrieval (IR) task of identifying concept (e.g. Housing, Job, etc.) equivalence across question and response options to harmonise longitudinal population studies. This paper investigates multiple unsupervised approaches on a survey dataset spanning 1946-2020, including probabilistic models, linear probing of language models, and pre-trained neural networks specialised for IR. We show that IR-specialised neural models achieve the highest overall performance with other approaches performing comparably. Additionally, the re-ranking of the probabilistic model's results with neural models only introduces modest improvements of 0.07 at most in F1-score. Qualitative post-hoc evaluation by survey specialists shows that models generally have a low sensitivity to questions with high lexical overlap, particularly in cases where sub-concepts are mismatched. Altogether, our analysis serves to further research on harmonising longitudinal studies in social science.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20679v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wing Yan Li, Zeqiang Wang, Jon Johnson, Suparna De</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can LLMs Detect Intrinsic Hallucinations in Paraphrasing and Machine Translation?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20699</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20699v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: A frequently observed problem with LLMs is their tendency to generate output that is nonsensical, illogical, or factually incorrect, often referred to broadly as hallucination. Building on the recently proposed HalluciGen task for hallucination detection and generation, we evaluate a suite of open-access LLMs on their ability to detect intrinsic hallucinations in two conditional generation tasks: translation and paraphrasing. We study how model performance varies across tasks and language and we investigate the impact of model size, instruction tuning, and prompt choice. We find that performance varies across models but is consistent across prompts. Finally, we find that NLI models perform comparably well, suggesting that LLM-based detectors are not the only viable option for this specific task.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20699v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Evangelia Gogoulou, Shorouq Zahra, Liane Guillou, Luise D\"urlich, Joakim Nivre</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BrightCookies at SemEval-2025 Task 9: Exploring Data Augmentation for Food Hazard Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20703</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20703v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper presents our system developed for the SemEval-2025 Task 9: The Food Hazard Detection Challenge. The shared task's objective is to evaluate explainable classification systems for classifying hazards and products in two levels of granularity from food recall incident reports. In this work, we propose text augmentation techniques as a way to improve poor performance on minority classes and compare their effect for each category on various transformer and machine learning models. We explore three word-level data augmentation techniques, namely synonym replacement, random word swapping, and contextual word insertion. The results show that transformer models tend to have a better overall performance. None of the three augmentation techniques consistently improved overall performance for classifying hazards and products. We observed a statistically significant improvement (P &lt; 0.05) in the fine-grained categories when using the BERT model to compare the baseline with each augmented model. Compared to the baseline, the contextual words insertion augmentation improved the accuracy of predictions for the minority hazard classes by 6%. This suggests that targeted augmentation of minority classes can improve the performance of transformer models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20703v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Foteini Papadopoulou, Osman Mutlu, Neris \"Ozen, Bas H. M. van der Velden, Iris Hendrickx, Ali H\"urriyeto\u{g}lu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the Last Answer: Your Reasoning Trace Uncovers More than You Think</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20708</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20708v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) leverage step-by-step reasoning to solve complex problems. Standard evaluation practice involves generating a complete reasoning trace and assessing the correctness of the final answer presented at its conclusion. In this paper, we challenge the reliance on the final answer by posing the following two questions: Does the final answer reliably represent the model's optimal conclusion? Can alternative reasoning paths yield different results? To answer these questions, we analyze intermediate reasoning steps, termed subthoughts, and propose a method based on our findings. Our approach involves segmenting a reasoning trace into sequential subthoughts based on linguistic cues. We start by prompting the model to generate continuations from the end-point of each intermediate subthought. We extract a potential answer from every completed continuation originating from different subthoughts. We find that aggregating these answers by selecting the most frequent one (the mode) often yields significantly higher accuracy compared to relying solely on the answer derived from the original complete trace. Analyzing the consistency among the answers derived from different subthoughts reveals characteristics that correlate with the model's confidence and correctness, suggesting potential for identifying less reliable answers. Our experiments across various LLMs and challenging mathematical reasoning datasets (AIME2024 and AIME2025) show consistent accuracy improvements, with gains reaching up to 13\% and 10\% respectively. Implementation is available at: https://github.com/hammoudhasan/SubthoughtReasoner.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20708v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hasan Abed Al Kader Hammoud, Hani Itani, Bernard Ghanem</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UniversalRAG: Retrieval-Augmented Generation over Multiple Corpora with Diverse Modalities and Granularities</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20734</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20734v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) has shown substantial promise in improving factual accuracy by grounding model responses with external knowledge relevant to queries. However, most existing RAG approaches are limited to a text-only corpus, and while recent efforts have extended RAG to other modalities such as images and videos, they typically operate over a single modality-specific corpus. In contrast, real-world queries vary widely in the type of knowledge they require, which a single type of knowledge source cannot address. To address this, we introduce UniversalRAG, a novel RAG framework designed to retrieve and integrate knowledge from heterogeneous sources with diverse modalities and granularities. Specifically, motivated by the observation that forcing all modalities into a unified representation space derived from a single combined corpus causes a modality gap, where the retrieval tends to favor items from the same modality as the query, we propose a modality-aware routing mechanism that dynamically identifies the most appropriate modality-specific corpus and performs targeted retrieval within it. Also, beyond modality, we organize each modality into multiple granularity levels, enabling fine-tuned retrieval tailored to the complexity and scope of the query. We validate UniversalRAG on 8 benchmarks spanning multiple modalities, showing its superiority over modality-specific and unified baselines.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20734v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Woongyeong Yeo, Kangsan Kim, Soyeong Jeong, Jinheon Baek, Sung Ju Hwang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grokking in the Wild: Data Augmentation for Real-World Multi-Hop Reasoning with Transformers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20752</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20752v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Transformers have achieved great success in numerous NLP tasks but continue to exhibit notable gaps in multi-step factual reasoning, especially when real-world knowledge is sparse. Recent advances in grokking have demonstrated that neural networks can transition from memorizing to perfectly generalizing once they detect underlying logical patterns - yet these studies have primarily used small, synthetic tasks. In this paper, for the first time, we extend grokking to real-world factual data and address the challenge of dataset sparsity by augmenting existing knowledge graphs with carefully designed synthetic data to raise the ratio $\phi_r$ of inferred facts to atomic facts above the threshold required for grokking. Surprisingly, we find that even factually incorrect synthetic data can strengthen emergent reasoning circuits rather than degrade accuracy, as it forces the model to rely on relational structure rather than memorization. When evaluated on multi-hop reasoning benchmarks, our approach achieves up to 95-100% accuracy on 2WikiMultiHopQA - substantially improving over strong baselines and matching or exceeding current state-of-the-art results. We further provide an in-depth analysis of how increasing $\phi_r$ drives the formation of generalizing circuits inside Transformers. Our findings suggest that grokking-based data augmentation can unlock implicit multi-hop reasoning capabilities, opening the door to more robust and interpretable factual reasoning in large-scale language models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20752v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Roman Abramov, Felix Steinbauer, Gjergji Kasneci</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chain-of-Defensive-Thought: Structured Reasoning Elicits Robustness in Large Language Models against Reference Corruption</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20769</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20769v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Chain-of-thought prompting has demonstrated great success in facilitating the reasoning abilities of large language models. In this work, we explore how these enhanced reasoning abilities can be exploited to improve the robustness of large language models in tasks that are not necessarily reasoning-focused. In particular, we show how a wide range of large language models exhibit significantly improved robustness against reference corruption using a simple method called chain-of-defensive-thought, where only a few exemplars with structured and defensive reasoning are provided as demonstrations. Empirically, the improvements can be astounding, especially given the simplicity and applicability of the method. For example, in the Natural Questions task, the accuracy of GPT-4o degrades from 60% to as low as 3% with standard prompting when 1 out of 10 references provided is corrupted with prompt injection attacks. In contrast, GPT-4o using chain-of-defensive-thought prompting maintains an accuracy of 50%.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20769v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenxiao Wang, Parsa Hosseini, Soheil Feizi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turing Machine Evaluation for Large Language Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20771</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20771v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: With the rapid development and widespread application of Large Language Models (LLMs), rigorous evaluation has become particularly crucial. This research adopts a novel perspective, focusing on evaluating the core computational reasoning ability of LLMs, defined as the capacity of model to accurately understand rules, and execute logically computing operations. This capability assesses the reliability of LLMs as precise executors, and is critical to advanced tasks such as complex code generation and multi-step problem-solving. We propose an evaluation framework based on Universal Turing Machine (UTM) simulation. This framework requires LLMs to strictly follow instructions and track dynamic states, such as tape content and read/write head position, during multi-step computations. To enable standardized evaluation, we developed TMBench, a benchmark for systematically studying the computational reasoning capabilities of LLMs. TMBench provides several key advantages, including knowledge-agnostic evaluation, adjustable difficulty, foundational coverage through Turing machine encoding, and unlimited capacity for instance generation, ensuring scalability as models continue to evolve. We find that model performance on TMBench correlates strongly with performance on other recognized reasoning benchmarks (Pearson correlation coefficient is 0.73), clearly demonstrating that computational reasoning is a significant dimension for measuring the deep capabilities of LLMs. Code and data are available at https://github.com/HaitaoWuTJU/Turing-Machine-Bench.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20771v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haitao Wu, Zongbo Han, Huaxi Huang, Changqing Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Universal language model with the intervention of quantum theory</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20839</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20839v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper examines language modeling based on the theory of quantum mechanics. It focuses on the introduction of quantum mechanics into the symbol-meaning pairs of language in order to build a representation model of natural language. At the same time, it is realized that word embedding, which is widely used as a basic technique for statistical language modeling, can be explained and improved by the mathematical framework of quantum mechanics. On this basis, this paper continues to try to use quantum statistics and other related theories to study the mathematical representation, natural evolution and statistical properties of natural language. It is also assumed that the source of such quantum properties is the physicality of information. The feasibility of using quantum theory to model natural language is pointed out through the construction of a experimental code. The paper discusses, in terms of applications, the possible help of the theory in constructing generative models that are popular nowadays. A preliminary discussion of future applications of the theory to quantum computers is also presented.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20839v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>quant-ph</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>D. -F. Qin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JaccDiv: A Metric and Benchmark for Quantifying Diversity of Generated Marketing Text in the Music Industry</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20849</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20849v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Online platforms are increasingly interested in using Data-to-Text technologies to generate content and help their users. Unfortunately, traditional generative methods often fall into repetitive patterns, resulting in monotonous galleries of texts after only a few iterations. In this paper, we investigate LLM-based data-to-text approaches to automatically generate marketing texts that are of sufficient quality and diverse enough for broad adoption. We leverage Language Models such as T5, GPT-3.5, GPT-4, and LLaMa2 in conjunction with fine-tuning, few-shot, and zero-shot approaches to set a baseline for diverse marketing texts. We also introduce a metric JaccDiv to evaluate the diversity of a set of texts. This research extends its relevance beyond the music industry, proving beneficial in various fields where repetitive automated content generation is prevalent.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20849v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Anum Afzal, Alexandre Mercier, Florian Matthes</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DYNAMAX: Dynamic computing for Transformers and Mamba based architectures</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20922</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20922v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Early exits (EEs) offer a promising approach to reducing computational costs and latency by dynamically terminating inference once a satisfactory prediction confidence on a data sample is achieved. Although many works integrate EEs into encoder-only Transformers, their application to decoder-only architectures and, more importantly, Mamba models, a novel family of state-space architectures in the LLM realm, remains insufficiently explored. This work introduces DYNAMAX, the first framework to exploit the unique properties of Mamba architectures for early exit mechanisms. We not only integrate EEs into Mamba but also repurpose Mamba as an efficient EE classifier for both Mamba-based and transformer-based LLMs, showcasing its versatility. Our experiments employ the Mistral 7B transformer compared to the Codestral 7B Mamba model, using data sets such as TruthfulQA, CoQA, and TriviaQA to evaluate computational savings, accuracy, and consistency. The results highlight the adaptability of Mamba as a powerful EE classifier and its efficiency in balancing computational cost and performance quality across NLP tasks. By leveraging Mamba's inherent design for dynamic processing, we open pathways for scalable and efficient inference in embedded applications and resource-constrained environments. This study underscores the transformative potential of Mamba in redefining dynamic computing paradigms for LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20922v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Miguel Nogales, Matteo Gambella, Manuel Roveri</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trace-of-Thought: Enhanced Arithmetic Problem Solving via Reasoning Distillation From Large to Small Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20946</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20946v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: As Large Language Models (LLMs) continue to be leveraged for daily tasks, prompt engineering remains an active field of contribution within computational linguistics, particularly in domains requiring specialized knowledge such as arithmetic reasoning. While these LLMs are optimized for a variety of tasks, their exhaustive employment may become computationally or financially cumbersome for small teams. Additionally, complete reliance on proprietary, closed-source models often limits customization and adaptability, posing significant challenges in research and application scalability. Instead, by leveraging open-source models at or below 7 billion parameters, we can optimize our resource usage while still observing remarkable gains over standard prompting approaches. To cultivate this notion, we introduce Trace-of-Thought Prompting, a simple, zero-shot prompt engineering method that instructs LLMs to create observable subproblems using critical problem-solving, specifically designed to enhance arithmetic reasoning capabilities. When applied to open-source models in tandem with GPT-4, we observe that Trace-of-Thought not only allows novel insight into the problem-solving process but also introduces performance gains as large as 125% on language models at or below 7 billion parameters. This approach underscores the potential of open-source initiatives in democratizing AI research and improving the accessibility of high-quality computational linguistics applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20946v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tyler McDonald, Ali Emami</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Information Gravity: A Field-Theoretic Model for Token Selection in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20951</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20951v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We propose a theoretical model called "information gravity" to describe the text generation process in large language models (LLMs). The model uses physical apparatus from field theory and spacetime geometry to formalize the interaction between user queries and the probability distribution of generated tokens. A query is viewed as an object with "information mass" that curves the semantic space of the model, creating gravitational potential wells that "attract" tokens during generation. This model offers a mechanism to explain several observed phenomena in LLM behavior, including hallucinations (emerging from low-density semantic voids), sensitivity to query formulation (due to semantic field curvature changes), and the influence of sampling temperature on output diversity.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20951v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.5281/zenodo.15289890</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Maryna Vyshnyvetska</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OSVBench: Benchmarking LLMs on Specification Generation Tasks for Operating System Verification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20964</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20964v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We introduce OSVBench, a new benchmark for evaluating Large Language Models (LLMs) in generating complete specification code pertaining to operating system kernel verification tasks. The benchmark first defines the specification generation problem into a program synthesis problem within a confined scope of syntax and semantics by providing LLMs with the programming model. The LLMs are required to understand the provided verification assumption and the potential syntax and semantics space to search for, then generate the complete specification for the potentially buggy operating system code implementation under the guidance of the high-level functional description of the operating system. This benchmark is built upon a real-world operating system kernel, Hyperkernel, and consists of 245 complex specification generation tasks in total, each is a long context task of about 20k-30k tokens. Our comprehensive evaluation of 12 LLMs exhibits the limited performance of the current LLMs on the specification generation tasks for operating system verification. Significant disparities in their performance on the benchmark highlight differences in their ability to handle long-context code generation tasks. The evaluation toolkit and benchmark are available at https://github.com/lishangyu-hkust/OSVBench.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20964v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.OS</category>
      <category>cs.PL</category>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shangyu Li, Juyong Jiang, Tiancheng Zhao, Jiasi Shen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SetKE: Knowledge Editing for Knowledge Elements Overlap</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20972</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20972v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) excel in tasks such as retrieval and question answering but require updates to incorporate new knowledge and reduce inaccuracies and hallucinations. Traditional updating methods, like fine-tuning and incremental learning, face challenges such as overfitting and high computational costs. Knowledge Editing (KE) provides a promising alternative but often overlooks the Knowledge Element Overlap (KEO) phenomenon, where multiple triplets share common elements, leading to editing conflicts. We identify the prevalence of KEO in existing KE datasets and show its significant impact on current KE methods, causing performance degradation in handling such triplets. To address this, we propose a new formulation, Knowledge Set Editing (KSE), and introduce SetKE, a method that edits sets of triplets simultaneously. Experimental results demonstrate that SetKE outperforms existing methods in KEO scenarios on mainstream LLMs. Additionally, we introduce EditSet, a dataset containing KEO triplets, providing a comprehensive benchmark.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20972v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>IJCAI 2025</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Yifan Wei, Xiaoyan Yu, Ran Song, Hao Peng, Angsheng Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recommending Clinical Trials for Online Patient Cases using Artificial Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20059</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20059v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Clinical trials are crucial for assessing new treatments; however, recruitment challenges - such as limited awareness, complex eligibility criteria, and referral barriers - hinder their success. With the growth of online platforms, patients increasingly turn to social media and health communities for support, research, and advocacy, expanding recruitment pools and established enrollment pathways. Recognizing this potential, we utilized TrialGPT, a framework that leverages a large language model (LLM) as its backbone, to match 50 online patient cases (collected from published case reports and a social media website) to clinical trials and evaluate performance against traditional keyword-based searches. Our results show that TrialGPT outperforms traditional methods by 46% in identifying eligible trials, with each patient, on average, being eligible for around 7 trials. Additionally, our outreach efforts to case authors and trial organizers regarding these patient-trial matches yielded highly positive feedback, which we present from both perspectives.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20059v1</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Joey Chan, Qiao Jin, Nicholas Wan, Charalampos S. Floudas, Elisabetta Xue, Zhiyong Lu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RAGEN: Understanding Self-Evolution in LLM Agents via Multi-Turn Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20073</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20073v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Training large language models (LLMs) as interactive agents presents unique challenges including long-horizon decision making and interacting with stochastic environment feedback. While reinforcement learning (RL) has enabled progress in static tasks, multi-turn agent RL training remains underexplored. We propose StarPO (State-Thinking-Actions-Reward Policy Optimization), a general framework for trajectory-level agent RL, and introduce RAGEN, a modular system for training and evaluating LLM agents. Our study on three stylized environments reveals three core findings. First, our agent RL training shows a recurring mode of Echo Trap where reward variance cliffs and gradient spikes; we address this with StarPO-S, a stabilized variant with trajectory filtering, critic incorporation, and decoupled clipping. Second, we find the shaping of RL rollouts would benefit from diverse initial states, medium interaction granularity and more frequent sampling. Third, we show that without fine-grained, reasoning-aware reward signals, agent reasoning hardly emerge through multi-turn RL and they may show shallow strategies or hallucinated thoughts. Code and environments are available at https://github.com/RAGEN-AI/RAGEN.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20073v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zihan Wang, Kangrui Wang, Qineng Wang, Pingyue Zhang, Linjie Li, Zhengyuan Yang, Kefan Yu, Minh Nhat Nguyen, Licheng Liu, Eli Gottlieb, Monica Lam, Yiping Lu, Kyunghyun Cho, Jiajun Wu, Li Fei-Fei, Lijuan Wang, Yejin Choi, Manling Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Awareness</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20084</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20084v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recent breakthroughs in artificial intelligence (AI) have brought about increasingly capable systems that demonstrate remarkable abilities in reasoning, language understanding, and problem-solving. These advancements have prompted a renewed examination of AI awareness, not as a philosophical question of consciousness, but as a measurable, functional capacity. In this review, we explore the emerging landscape of AI awareness, which includes meta-cognition (the ability to represent and reason about its own state), self-awareness (recognizing its own identity, knowledge, limitations, inter alia), social awareness (modeling the knowledge, intentions, and behaviors of other agents), and situational awareness (assessing and responding to the context in which it operates).
  First, we draw on insights from cognitive science, psychology, and computational theory to trace the theoretical foundations of awareness and examine how the four distinct forms of AI awareness manifest in state-of-the-art AI. Next, we systematically analyze current evaluation methods and empirical findings to better understand these manifestations. Building on this, we explore how AI awareness is closely linked to AI capabilities, demonstrating that more aware AI agents tend to exhibit higher levels of intelligent behaviors. Finally, we discuss the risks associated with AI awareness, including key topics in AI safety, alignment, and broader ethical concerns.
  AI awareness is a double-edged sword: it improves general capabilities, i.e., reasoning, safety, while also raises concerns around misalignment and societal risks, demanding careful oversight as AI capabilities grow. On the whole, our interdisciplinary review provides a roadmap for future research and aims to clarify the role of AI awareness in the ongoing development of intelligent machines.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20084v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaojian Li, Haoyuan Shi, Rongwu Xu, Wei Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MATCHA: Can Multi-Agent Collaboration Build a Trustworthy Conversational Recommender?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20094</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20094v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In this paper, we propose a multi-agent collaboration framework called MATCHA for conversational recommendation system, leveraging large language models (LLMs) to enhance personalization and user engagement. Users can request recommendations via free-form text and receive curated lists aligned with their interests, preferences, and constraints. Our system introduces specialized agents for intent analysis, candidate generation, ranking, re-ranking, explainability, and safeguards. These agents collaboratively improve recommendations accuracy, diversity, and safety. On eight metrics, our model achieves superior or comparable performance to the current state-of-the-art. Through comparisons with six baseline models, our approach addresses key challenges in conversational recommendation systems for game recommendations, including: (1) handling complex, user-specific requests, (2) enhancing personalization through multi-agent collaboration, (3) empirical evaluation and deployment, and (4) ensuring safe and trustworthy interactions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20094v1</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zheng Hui, Xiaokai Wei, Yexi Jiang, Kevin Gao, Chen Wang, Frank Ong, Se-eun Yoon, Rachit Pareek, Michelle Gong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ResearchCodeAgent: An LLM Multi-Agent System for Automated Codification of Research Methodologies</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20117</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20117v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In this paper we introduce ResearchCodeAgent, a novel multi-agent system leveraging large language models (LLMs) agents to automate the codification of research methodologies described in machine learning literature. The system bridges the gap between high-level research concepts and their practical implementation, allowing researchers auto-generating code of existing research papers for benchmarking or building on top-of existing methods specified in the literature with availability of partial or complete starter code. ResearchCodeAgent employs a flexible agent architecture with a comprehensive action suite, enabling context-aware interactions with the research environment. The system incorporates a dynamic planning mechanism, utilizing both short and long-term memory to adapt its approach iteratively. We evaluate ResearchCodeAgent on three distinct machine learning tasks with distinct task complexity and representing different parts of the ML pipeline: data augmentation, optimization, and data batching. Our results demonstrate the system's effectiveness and generalizability, with 46.9% of generated code being high-quality and error-free, and 25% showing performance improvements over baseline implementations. Empirical analysis shows an average reduction of 57.9% in coding time compared to manual implementation. We observe higher gains for more complex tasks. ResearchCodeAgent represents a significant step towards automating the research implementation process, potentially accelerating the pace of machine learning research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20117v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shubham Gandhi, Dhruv Shah, Manasi Patwardhan, Lovekesh Vig, Gautam Shroff</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weaving Context Across Images: Improving Vision-Language Models through Focus-Centric Visual Chains</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20199</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20199v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Vision-language models (VLMs) achieve remarkable success in single-image tasks. However, real-world scenarios often involve intricate multi-image inputs, leading to a notable performance decline as models struggle to disentangle critical information scattered across complex visual features. In this work, we propose Focus-Centric Visual Chain, a novel paradigm that enhances VLMs'perception, comprehension, and reasoning abilities in multi-image scenarios. To facilitate this paradigm, we propose Focus-Centric Data Synthesis, a scalable bottom-up approach for synthesizing high-quality data with elaborate reasoning paths. Through this approach, We construct VISC-150K, a large-scale dataset with reasoning data in the form of Focus-Centric Visual Chain, specifically designed for multi-image tasks. Experimental results on seven multi-image benchmarks demonstrate that our method achieves average performance gains of 3.16% and 2.24% across two distinct model architectures, without compromising the general vision-language capabilities. our study represents a significant step toward more robust and capable vision-language systems that can handle complex visual scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20199v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Juntian Zhang, Chuanqi cheng, Yuhan Liu, Wei Liu, Jian Luan, Rui Yan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>mrCAD: Multimodal Refinement of Computer-aided Designs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20294</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20294v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: A key feature of human collaboration is the ability to iteratively refine the concepts we have communicated. In contrast, while generative AI excels at the \textit{generation} of content, it often struggles to make specific language-guided \textit{modifications} of its prior outputs. To bridge the gap between how humans and machines perform edits, we present mrCAD, a dataset of multimodal instructions in a communication game. In each game, players created computer aided designs (CADs) and refined them over several rounds to match specific target designs. Only one player, the Designer, could see the target, and they must instruct the other player, the Maker, using text, drawing, or a combination of modalities. mrCAD consists of 6,082 communication games, 15,163 instruction-execution rounds, played between 1,092 pairs of human players. We analyze the dataset and find that generation and refinement instructions differ in their composition of drawing and text. Using the mrCAD task as a benchmark, we find that state-of-the-art VLMs are better at following generation instructions than refinement instructions. These results lay a foundation for analyzing and modeling a multimodal language of refinement that is not represented in previous datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20294v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>William P. McCarthy, Saujas Vaduguru, Karl D. D. Willis, Justin Matejka, Judith E. Fan, Daniel Fried, Yewen Pu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reviving Any-Subset Autoregressive Models with Principled Parallel Sampling and Speculative Decoding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20456</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20456v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In arbitrary-order language models, it is an open question how to sample tokens in parallel from the correct joint distribution. With discrete diffusion models, the more tokens they generate in parallel, the less their predicted distributions adhere to the originally learned data distribution, as they rely on a conditional independence assumption that only works with infinitesimally small timesteps. We find that a different class of models, any-subset autoregressive models (AS-ARMs), holds the solution. As implied by the name, AS-ARMs can generate tokens in any order, and in parallel. Moreover, AS-ARMs support parallelized joint probability density estimation, allowing them to correct their own parallel-generated token distributions, via our Any-Subset Speculative Decoding (ASSD) algorithm. ASSD provably enables generation of tokens from the correct joint distribution, with the number of neural network calls upper bounded by the number of tokens predicted. We empirically verify that ASSD speeds up language generation, without sacrificing quality. Furthermore, we provide a mathematically justified scheme for training AS-ARMs for generation, and show that AS-ARMs achieve state-of-the-art performance among sub-200M parameter models on infilling benchmark tasks, and nearly match the performance of models 50X larger on code generation. Our theoretical and empirical results indicate that the once-forgotten AS-ARMs are a promising direction of language modeling.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20456v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gabe Guo, Stefano Ermon</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Search-Based Interaction For Conversation Recommendation via Generative Reward Model Based Simulated User</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20458</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20458v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Conversational recommendation systems (CRSs) use multi-turn interaction to capture user preferences and provide personalized recommendations. A fundamental challenge in CRSs lies in effectively understanding user preferences from conversations. User preferences can be multifaceted and complex, posing significant challenges for accurate recommendations even with access to abundant external knowledge. While interaction with users can clarify their true preferences, frequent user involvement can lead to a degraded user experience.
  To address this problem, we propose a generative reward model based simulated user, named GRSU, for automatic interaction with CRSs. The simulated user provides feedback to the items recommended by CRSs, enabling them to better capture intricate user preferences through multi-turn interaction. Inspired by generative reward models, we design two types of feedback actions for the simulated user: i.e., generative item scoring, which offers coarse-grained feedback, and attribute-based item critique, which provides fine-grained feedback. To ensure seamless integration, these feedback actions are unified into an instruction-based format, allowing the development of a unified simulated user via instruction tuning on synthesized data. With this simulated user, automatic multi-turn interaction with CRSs can be effectively conducted. Furthermore, to strike a balance between effectiveness and efficiency, we draw inspiration from the paradigm of reward-guided search in complex reasoning tasks and employ beam search for the interaction process. On top of this, we propose an efficient candidate ranking method to improve the recommendation results derived from interaction. Extensive experiments on public datasets demonstrate the effectiveness, efficiency, and transferability of our approach.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20458v1</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaolei Wang, Chunxuan Xia, Junyi Li, Fanzhe Meng, Lei Huang, Jinpeng Wang, Wayne Xin Zhao, Ji-Rong Wen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reinforcement Learning for Reasoning in Large Language Models with One Training Example</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20571</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20571v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We show that reinforcement learning with verifiable reward using one training example (1-shot RLVR) is effective in incentivizing the math reasoning capabilities of large language models (LLMs). Applying RLVR to the base model Qwen2.5-Math-1.5B, we identify a single example that elevates model performance on MATH500 from 36.0% to 73.6%, and improves the average performance across six common mathematical reasoning benchmarks from 17.6% to 35.7%. This result matches the performance obtained using the 1.2k DeepScaleR subset (MATH500: 73.6%, average: 35.9%), which includes the aforementioned example. Similar substantial improvements are observed across various models (Qwen2.5-Math-7B, Llama3.2-3B-Instruct, DeepSeek-R1-Distill-Qwen-1.5B), RL algorithms (GRPO and PPO), and different math examples (many of which yield approximately 30% or greater improvement on MATH500 when employed as a single training example). In addition, we identify some interesting phenomena during 1-shot RLVR, including cross-domain generalization, increased frequency of self-reflection, and sustained test performance improvement even after the training accuracy has saturated, a phenomenon we term post-saturation generalization. Moreover, we verify that the effectiveness of 1-shot RLVR primarily arises from the policy gradient loss, distinguishing it from the "grokking" phenomenon. We also show the critical role of promoting exploration (e.g., by adding entropy loss with an appropriate coefficient) in 1-shot RLVR training. As a bonus, we observe that applying entropy loss alone, without any outcome reward, significantly enhances Qwen2.5-Math-1.5B's performance on MATH500 by 27.4%. These findings can inspire future work on RLVR data efficiency and encourage a re-examination of both recent progress and the underlying mechanisms in RLVR. Our code, model, and data are open source at https://github.com/ypwang61/One-Shot-RLVR</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20571v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yiping Wang, Qing Yang, Zhiyuan Zeng, Liliang Ren, Lucas Liu, Baolin Peng, Hao Cheng, Xuehai He, Kuan Wang, Jianfeng Gao, Weizhu Chen, Shuohang Wang, Simon Shaolei Du, Yelong Shen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ReasonIR: Training Retrievers for Reasoning Tasks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20595</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20595v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We present ReasonIR-8B, the first retriever specifically trained for general reasoning tasks. Existing retrievers have shown limited gains on reasoning tasks, in part because existing training datasets focus on short factual queries tied to documents that straightforwardly answer them. We develop a synthetic data generation pipeline that, for each document, our pipeline creates a challenging and relevant query, along with a plausibly related but ultimately unhelpful hard negative. By training on a mixture of our synthetic data and existing public data, ReasonIR-8B achieves a new state-of-the-art of 29.9 nDCG@10 without reranker and 36.9 nDCG@10 with reranker on BRIGHT, a widely-used reasoning-intensive information retrieval (IR) benchmark. When applied to RAG tasks, ReasonIR-8B improves MMLU and GPQA performance by 6.4% and 22.6% respectively, relative to the closed-book baseline, outperforming other retrievers and search engines. In addition, ReasonIR-8B uses test-time compute more effectively: on BRIGHT, its performance consistently increases with longer and more information-rich rewritten queries; it continues to outperform other retrievers when combined with an LLM reranker. Our training recipe is general and can be easily extended to future LLMs; to this end, we open-source our code, data, and model.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20595v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rulin Shao, Rui Qiao, Varsha Kishore, Niklas Muennighoff, Xi Victoria Lin, Daniela Rus, Bryan Kian Hsiang Low, Sewon Min, Wen-tau Yih, Pang Wei Koh, Luke Zettlemoyer</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>X-Cross: Dynamic Integration of Language Models for Cross-Domain Sequential Recommendation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20859</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20859v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: As new products are emerging daily, recommendation systems are required to quickly adapt to possible new domains without needing extensive retraining. This work presents ``X-Cross'' -- a novel cross-domain sequential-recommendation model that recommends products in new domains by integrating several domain-specific language models; each model is fine-tuned with low-rank adapters (LoRA). Given a recommendation prompt, operating layer by layer, X-Cross dynamically refines the representation of each source language model by integrating knowledge from all other models. These refined representations are propagated from one layer to the next, leveraging the activations from each domain adapter to ensure domain-specific nuances are preserved while enabling adaptability across domains. Using Amazon datasets for sequential recommendation, X-Cross achieves performance comparable to a model that is fine-tuned with LoRA, while using only 25% of the additional parameters. In cross-domain tasks, such as adapting from Toys domain to Tools, Electronics or Sports, X-Cross demonstrates robust performance, while requiring about 50%-75% less fine-tuning data than LoRA to make fine-tuning effective. Furthermore, X-Cross achieves significant improvement in accuracy over alternative cross-domain baselines. Overall, X-Cross enables scalable and adaptive cross-domain recommendations, reducing computational overhead and providing an efficient solution for data-constrained environments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20859v1</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3726302.3730117</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Guy Hadad, Haggai Roitman, Yotam Eshel, Bracha Shapira, Lior Rokach</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Leaderboard Illusion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20879</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20879v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Measuring progress is fundamental to the advancement of any scientific field. As benchmarks play an increasingly central role, they also grow more susceptible to distortion. Chatbot Arena has emerged as the go-to leaderboard for ranking the most capable AI systems. Yet, in this work we identify systematic issues that have resulted in a distorted playing field. We find that undisclosed private testing practices benefit a handful of providers who are able to test multiple variants before public release and retract scores if desired. We establish that the ability of these providers to choose the best score leads to biased Arena scores due to selective disclosure of performance results. At an extreme, we identify 27 private LLM variants tested by Meta in the lead-up to the Llama-4 release. We also establish that proprietary closed models are sampled at higher rates (number of battles) and have fewer models removed from the arena than open-weight and open-source alternatives. Both these policies lead to large data access asymmetries over time. Providers like Google and OpenAI have received an estimated 19.2% and 20.4% of all data on the arena, respectively. In contrast, a combined 83 open-weight models have only received an estimated 29.7% of the total data. We show that access to Chatbot Arena data yields substantial benefits; even limited additional data can result in relative performance gains of up to 112% on the arena distribution, based on our conservative estimates. Together, these dynamics result in overfitting to Arena-specific dynamics rather than general model quality. The Arena builds on the substantial efforts of both the organizers and an open community that maintains this valuable evaluation platform. We offer actionable recommendations to reform the Chatbot Arena's evaluation framework and promote fairer, more transparent benchmarking for the field</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20879v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>stat.ME</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shivalika Singh, Yiyang Nan, Alex Wang, Daniel D'Souza, Sayash Kapoor, Ahmet \"Ust\"un, Sanmi Koyejo, Yuntian Deng, Shayne Longpre, Noah Smith, Beyza Ermis, Marzieh Fadaee, Sara Hooker</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChestX-Reasoner: Advancing Radiology Foundation Models with Reasoning through Step-by-Step Verification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20930</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20930v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recent advances in reasoning-enhanced large language models (LLMs) and multimodal LLMs (MLLMs) have significantly improved performance in complex tasks, yet medical AI models often overlook the structured reasoning processes inherent in clinical practice. In this work, we present ChestX-Reasoner, a radiology diagnosis MLLM designed to leverage process supervision mined directly from clinical reports, reflecting the step-by-step reasoning followed by radiologists. We construct a large dataset by extracting and refining reasoning chains from routine radiology reports. Our two-stage training framework combines supervised fine-tuning and reinforcement learning guided by process rewards to better align model reasoning with clinical standards. We introduce RadRBench-CXR, a comprehensive benchmark featuring 59K visual question answering samples with 301K clinically validated reasoning steps, and propose RadRScore, a metric evaluating reasoning factuality, completeness, and effectiveness. ChestX-Reasoner outperforms existing medical and general-domain MLLMs in both diagnostic accuracy and reasoning ability, achieving 16%, 5.9%, and 18% improvements in reasoning ability compared to the best medical MLLM, the best general MLLM, and its base model, respectively, as well as 3.3%, 24%, and 27% improvements in outcome accuracy. All resources are open-sourced to facilitate further research in medical reasoning MLLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20930v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ziqing Fan, Cheng Liang, Chaoyi Wu, Ya Zhang, Yanfeng Wang, Weidi Xie</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Understanding the Nature of Attention with Low-Rank Sparse Decomposition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20938</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20938v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We propose Low-Rank Sparse Attention (Lorsa), a sparse replacement model of Transformer attention layers to disentangle original Multi Head Self Attention (MHSA) into individually comprehensible components. Lorsa is designed to address the challenge of attention superposition to understand attention-mediated interaction between features in different token positions. We show that Lorsa heads find cleaner and finer-grained versions of previously discovered MHSA behaviors like induction heads, successor heads and attention sink behavior (i.e., heavily attending to the first token). Lorsa and Sparse Autoencoder (SAE) are both sparse dictionary learning methods applied to different Transformer components, and lead to consistent findings in many ways. For instance, we discover a comprehensive family of arithmetic-specific Lorsa heads, each corresponding to an atomic operation in Llama-3.1-8B. Automated interpretability analysis indicates that Lorsa achieves parity with SAE in interpretability while Lorsa exhibits superior circuit discovery properties, especially for features computed collectively by multiple MHSA heads. We also conduct extensive experiments on architectural design ablation, Lorsa scaling law and error analysis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20938v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhengfu He, Junxuan Wang, Rui Lin, Xuyang Ge, Wentao Shu, Qiong Tang, Junping Zhang, Xipeng Qiu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Consistency for Assuring Reliability of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2308.09138</link>
      <description>arXiv:2308.09138v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) exhibit remarkable fluency and competence across various natural language tasks. However, recent research has highlighted their sensitivity to variations in input prompts. To deploy LLMs in a safe and reliable manner, it is crucial for their outputs to be consistent when prompted with expressions that carry the same meaning or intent. While some existing work has explored how state-of-the-art LLMs address this issue, their evaluations have been confined to assessing lexical equality of single- or multi-word answers, overlooking the consistency of generative text sequences. For a more comprehensive understanding of the consistency of LLMs in open-ended text generation scenarios, we introduce a general measure of semantic consistency, and formulate multiple versions of this metric to evaluate the performance of various LLMs. Our proposal demonstrates significantly higher consistency and stronger correlation with human evaluations of output consistency than traditional metrics based on lexical consistency. Finally, we propose a novel prompting strategy, called Ask-to-Choose (A2C), to enhance semantic consistency. When evaluated for closed-book question answering based on answer variations from the TruthfulQA benchmark, A2C increases accuracy metrics for pretrained and finetuned LLMs by up to 47%, and semantic consistency metrics for instruction-tuned models by up to 7-fold.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2308.09138v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Harsh Raj, Vipul Gupta, Domenic Rosati, Subhabrata Majumdar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM-Coordination: Evaluating and Analyzing Multi-agent Coordination Abilities in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.03903</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.03903v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated emergent common-sense reasoning and Theory of Mind (ToM) capabilities, making them promising candidates for developing coordination agents. This study introduces the LLM-Coordination Benchmark, a novel benchmark for analyzing LLMs in the context of Pure Coordination Settings, where agents must cooperate to maximize gains. Our benchmark evaluates LLMs through two distinct tasks. The first is Agentic Coordination, where LLMs act as proactive participants in four pure coordination games. The second is Coordination Question Answering (CoordQA), which tests LLMs on 198 multiple-choice questions across these games to evaluate three key abilities: Environment Comprehension, ToM Reasoning, and Joint Planning. Results from Agentic Coordination experiments reveal that LLM-Agents excel in multi-agent coordination settings where decision-making primarily relies on environmental variables but face challenges in scenarios requiring active consideration of partners' beliefs and intentions. The CoordQA experiments further highlight significant room for improvement in LLMs' Theory of Mind reasoning and joint planning capabilities. Zero-Shot Coordination (ZSC) experiments in the Agentic Coordination setting demonstrate that LLM agents, unlike RL methods, exhibit robustness to unseen partners. These findings indicate the potential of LLMs as Agents in pure coordination setups and underscore areas for improvement. Code Available at https://github.com/eric-ai-lab/llm_coordination.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.03903v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Saaket Agashe, Yue Fan, Anthony Reyna, Xin Eric Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the Symbol Binding Ability of Large Language Models for Multiple-Choice Questions in Vietnamese General Education</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.12059</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.12059v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this paper, we evaluate the ability of large language models (LLMs) to perform multiple choice symbol binding (MCSB) for multiple choice question answering (MCQA) tasks in zero-shot, one-shot, and few-shot settings. We focus on Vietnamese, with fewer challenging MCQA datasets than in English. The two existing datasets, ViMMRC 1.0 and ViMMRC 2.0, focus on literature. Recent research in Vietnamese natural language processing (NLP) has focused on the Vietnamese National High School Graduation Examination (VNHSGE) from 2019 to 2023 to evaluate ChatGPT. However, these studies have mainly focused on how ChatGPT solves the VNHSGE step by step. We aim to create a novel and high-quality dataset by providing structured guidelines for typing LaTeX formulas for mathematics, physics, chemistry, and biology. This dataset can be used to evaluate the MCSB ability of LLMs and smaller language models (LMs) because it is typed in a strict LaTeX style. We focus on predicting the character (A, B, C, or D) that is the most likely answer to a question, given the context of the question. Our evaluation of six well-known LLMs, namely BLOOMZ-7.1B-MT, LLaMA-2-7B, LLaMA-2-70B, GPT-3, GPT-3.5, and GPT-4.0, on the ViMMRC 1.0 and ViMMRC 2.0 benchmarks and our proposed dataset shows promising results on the MCSB ability of LLMs for Vietnamese. The dataset is available for research purposes only.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.12059v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Duc-Vu Nguyen, Quoc-Nam Nguyen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agentic AI: The Era of Semantic Decoding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.14562</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.14562v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent work demonstrated great promise in the idea of orchestrating collaborations between LLMs, human input, and various tools to address the inherent limitations of LLMs. We propose a novel perspective called semantic decoding, which frames these collaborative processes as optimization procedures in semantic space. Specifically, we conceptualize LLMs as semantic processors that manipulate meaningful pieces of information that we call semantic tokens (known thoughts). LLMs are among a large pool of other semantic processors, including humans and tools, such as search engines or code executors. Collectively, semantic processors engage in dynamic exchanges of semantic tokens to progressively construct high-utility outputs. We refer to these orchestrated interactions among semantic processors, optimizing and searching in semantic space, as semantic decoding algorithms. This concept draws a direct parallel to the well-studied problem of syntactic decoding, which involves crafting algorithms to best exploit auto-regressive language models for extracting high-utility sequences of syntactic tokens. By focusing on the semantic level and disregarding syntactic details, we gain a fresh perspective on the engineering of AI systems, enabling us to imagine systems with much greater complexity and capabilities. In this position paper, we formalize the transition from syntactic to semantic tokens as well as the analogy between syntactic and semantic decoding. Subsequently, we explore the possibilities of optimizing within the space of semantic tokens via semantic decoding algorithms. We conclude with a list of research opportunities and questions arising from this fresh perspective. The semantic decoding perspective offers a powerful abstraction for search and optimization directly in the space of meaningful concepts, with semantic tokens as the fundamental units of a new type of computation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.14562v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Maxime Peyrard, Martin Josifoski, Robert West</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Practical Analysis of Human Alignment with *PO</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.15229</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.15229v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: At the forefront of state-of-the-art human alignment methods are preference optimization methods (*PO). Prior research has often concentrated on identifying the best-performing method, typically involving a grid search over hyperparameters, which can be impractical for general practitioners. In this paper, we examine the robustness of existing state-of-the-art methods to varying hyperparameters in a realistic out-of-distribution (OOD) scenario that mirrors real-world applications of human alignment. Our goal is to empirically find the method that increases the likelihood of achieving better results through the lens of various metrics, such as KL divergence and response length. We also introduce LN-DPO, a simple length-normalized version of DPO that is more stable across hyperparameters, effectively reduces the average response length, and improves performance. Our analysis of state-of-the-art reference-free (i.e., SimPO) and reference-dependent (i.e., DPO and LN-DPO) methods reveals that they perform similarly at their peak (i.e., best possible scenario). However, we uncover that the pattern of change in performance greatly varies as we move away from the best possible scenario.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.15229v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kian Ahrabian, Xihui Lin, Barun Patra, Vishrav Chaudhary, Alon Benhaim, Jay Pujara, Xia Song</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correcting Negative Bias in Large Language Models through Negative Attention Score Alignment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00137</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.00137v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: A binary decision task, like yes-no questions or answer verification, reflects a significant real-world scenario such as where users look for confirmation about the correctness of their decisions on specific issues. In this work, we observe that language models exhibit a negative bias in the binary decisions of complex reasoning tasks. Based on our observations and the rationale about attention-based model dynamics, we propose a negative attention score (NAS) to systematically and quantitatively formulate negative bias. Based on NAS, we identify attention heads that attend to negative tokens provided in the instructions as answer candidate of binary decisions, regardless of the question in the prompt, and validate their association with the negative bias. Additionally, we propose the negative attention score alignment (NASA) method, which is a parameter-efficient fine-tuning technique to address the extracted negatively biased attention heads. Experimental results from various domains of reasoning tasks and large model search space demonstrate that NASA significantly reduces the gap between precision and recall caused by negative bias while preserving their generalization abilities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.00137v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sangwon Yu, Jongyoon Song, Bongkyu Hwang, Hoyoung Kang, Sooah Cho, Junhwa Choi, Seongho Joe, Taehee Lee, Youngjune L. Gwon, Sungroh Yoon</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AdaCAD: Adaptively Decoding to Balance Conflicts between Contextual and Parametric Knowledge</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.07394</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.07394v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Knowledge conflict arises from discrepancies between information in the context of a large language model (LLM) and the knowledge stored in its parameters. This can hurt performance when using standard decoding techniques, which tend to ignore the context. Existing test-time contrastive methods seek to address this by comparing the LLM's output distribution with and without the context and adjust the model according to the contrast between them. However, we find that these methods frequently misjudge the degree of conflict and struggle to handle instances that vary in their amount of conflict, with static methods over-adjusting when conflict is absent. We propose a fine-grained, instance-level approach called AdaCAD, which dynamically infers the weight of adjustment based on the degree of conflict, as measured by the Jensen-Shannon divergence between distributions representing contextual and parametric knowledge. Across four LLMs, six question-answering (QA) and three summarization datasets, we demonstrate that ADACAD consistently outperforms other decoding baselines with average QA accuracy gains of 14.21% (absolute) over a static contrastive baseline, and improves the factuality of summaries by 6.19 (AlignScore). Lastly, we show that while contrastive baselines hurt performance when conflict is absent, ADACAD mitigates these losses, making it more applicable to real-world datasets in which some examples have conflict and others do not.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.07394v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Han Wang, Archiki Prasad, Elias Stengel-Eskin, Mohit Bansal</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Racing Thoughts: Explaining Contextualization Errors in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.02102</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.02102v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The profound success of transformer-based language models can largely be attributed to their ability to integrate relevant contextual information from an input sequence in order to generate a response or complete a task. However, we know very little about the algorithms that a model employs to implement this capability, nor do we understand their failure modes. For example, given the prompt "John is going fishing, so he walks over to the bank. Can he make an ATM transaction?", a model may incorrectly respond "Yes" if it has not properly contextualized "bank" as a geographical feature, rather than a financial institution. We propose the LLM Race Conditions Hypothesis as an explanation of contextualization errors of this form. This hypothesis identifies dependencies between tokens (e.g., "bank" must be properly contextualized before the final token, "?", integrates information from "bank"), and claims that contextualization errors are a result of violating these dependencies. Using a variety of techniques from mechanistic intepretability, we provide correlational and causal evidence in support of the hypothesis, and suggest inference-time interventions to address it.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.02102v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Michael A. Lepori, Michael C. Mozer, Asma Ghandeharioun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unleashing Multi-Hop Reasoning Potential in Large Language Models through Repetition of Misordered Context</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.07103</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.07103v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Multi-hop reasoning, which requires multi-step reasoning based on the supporting documents within a given context, remains challenging for large language models (LLMs). LLMs often struggle to filter out irrelevant documents within the context, and their performance is sensitive to the absolute position of supporting documents within that context. In this paper, we identify an additional challenge: LLMs' performance is also sensitive to the order, relative position, in which the supporting documents are presented. We refer to this as the misordered context problem. To address this issue, based on the theoretical approach, we propose a simple yet effective method called context repetition (CoRe), which involves prompting the model by repeatedly presenting the context. This ensures that certain contiguous reasoning segments within supporting documents are presented in the optimal order, effectively guiding the model's reasoning in the appropriate direction. Applying CoRe, we improve the F1 score by up to 30%p on multi-hop QA tasks and increase accuracy by up to 70%p on a synthetic task. Additionally, CoRe helps mitigate the well-known "lost-in-the-middle" problem in LLMs and can be effectively combined with retrieval-based approaches utilizing Chain-of-Thought (CoT) reasoning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.07103v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sangwon Yu, Ik-hwan Kim, Jongyoon Song, Saehyung Lee, Junsung Park, Sungroh Yoon</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MDCure: A Scalable Pipeline for Multi-Document Instruction-Following</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.23463</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.23463v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Multi-document (MD) processing is crucial for LLMs to handle real-world tasks such as summarization and question-answering across large sets of documents. While LLMs have improved at processing long inputs, MD contexts still present unique difficulties, including management of inter-document dependencies, redundancy, and incoherent structures. To address this challenge, we introduce MDCure, a scalable and effective instruction data generation framework to enhance the MD capabilities of LLMs without the computational cost of pre-training or reliance on human-annotated data. MDCure generates high-quality synthetic MD instruction data over sets of articles via targeted prompts. We also introduce MDCureRM, a cost-effective, MD-specific reward model to score and filter generated data based on their training utility for MD settings. MDCure is compatible with open- and closed-source models in addition to policy optimization methods such as PPO, enabling even small open-source models to surpass proprietary LLMs as strong generators of high-quality MD instruction data without further data filtering. With MDCure, we fine-tune a wide variety of LLMs up to 70B parameters in size from the FlanT5, Qwen2, and LLAMA3.1 model families. Extensive evaluations on a wide range of MD and long-context benchmarks spanning various tasks and domains show MDCure consistently improves performance over pre-trained baselines and base models by up to 75.1%. Our code, datasets, and models are available at https://github.com/yale-nlp/MDCure.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.23463v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gabrielle Kaili-May Liu, Bowen Shi, Avi Caciularu, Idan Szpektor, Arman Cohan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constraint Back-translation Improves Complex Instruction Following of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.24175</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.24175v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) struggle to follow instructions with complex constraints in format, length, etc. Following the conventional instruction-tuning practice, previous works conduct post-training on complex instruction-response pairs generated by feeding complex instructions to advanced LLMs. However, even advanced LLMs cannot follow complex instructions well, thus limiting the quality of generated data. In this work, we find that existing datasets inherently contain implicit complex constraints and propose a novel data generation technique, constraint back-translation. Specifically, we take the high-quality instruction-response pairs in existing datasets and only adopt advanced LLMs to add complex constraints already met by the responses to the instructions, which naturally reduces costs and data noise. In the experiments, we adopt Llama3-70B-Instruct to back-translate constraints and create a high-quality complex instruction-response dataset, named CRAB. We present that post-training on CRAB improves multiple backbone LLMs' complex instruction-following ability, evaluated on extensive instruction-following benchmarks. We further find that constraint back-translation also serves as a useful auxiliary training objective in post-training. Our code, data, and models will be released to facilitate future research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.24175v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yunjia Qi, Hao Peng, Xiaozhi Wang, Bin Xu, Lei Hou, Juanzi Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking LLMs' Judgments with No Gold Standard</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.07127</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.07127v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We introduce the GEM (Generative Estimator for Mutual Information), an evaluation metric for assessing language generation by Large Language Models (LLMs), particularly in generating informative judgments, without the need for a gold standard reference. GEM broadens the scenarios where we can benchmark LLM generation performance-from traditional ones, like machine translation and summarization, where gold standard references are readily available, to subjective tasks without clear gold standards, such as academic peer review.
  GEM uses a generative model to estimate mutual information between candidate and reference responses, without requiring the reference to be a gold standard. In experiments on a human-annotated dataset, GEM demonstrates competitive correlations with human scores compared to the state-of-the-art GPT-4o Examiner, and outperforms all other baselines. Additionally, GEM is more robust against strategic manipulations, such as rephrasing or elongation, which can artificially inflate scores under a GPT-4o Examiner.
  We also present GRE-bench (Generating Review Evaluation Benchmark) which evaluates LLMs based on how well they can generate high-quality peer reviews for academic research papers. Because GRE-bench is based upon GEM, it inherits its robustness properties. Additionally, GRE-bench circumvents data contamination problems (or data leakage) by using the continuous influx of new open-access research papers and peer reviews each year. We show GRE-bench results of various popular LLMs on their peer review capabilities using the ICLR2023 dataset.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.07127v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shengwei Xu, Yuxuan Lu, Grant Schoenebeck, Yuqing Kong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the Safety Bundle: Auditing the Helpful and Harmless Dataset</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.08243</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.08243v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In an effort to mitigate the harms of large language models (LLMs), learning from human feedback (LHF) has been used to steer LLMs towards outputs that are intended to be both less harmful and more helpful. Despite the widespread adoption of LHF in practice, the quality of this feedback and its effectiveness as a safety mitigation technique remain unclear. This study addresses these issues by auditing the widely-used Helpful and Harmless (HH) dataset by Anthropic. Our work includes: (1) a thorough investigation of the dataset's content through both manual and automated evaluation; (2) experiments demonstrating the dataset's impact on models' safety; and (3) an analysis of the 100 most influential papers citing this dataset. Through our audit, we showcase how conceptualization failures and quality issues identified in the HH dataset can create additional harms by leading to disparate safety behaviors across demographic groups. Our findings highlight the need for more nuanced, context-sensitive approaches to safety mitigation in LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.08243v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Khaoula Chehbouni, Jonathan Cola\c{c}o Carr, Yash More, Jackie CK Cheung, Golnoosh Farnadi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Bayesian Optimization Approach to Machine Translation Reranking</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09694</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09694v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Reranking a list of candidates from a machine translation system with an external scoring model and returning the highest-scoring candidate remains a simple and effective method for improving the overall output quality. Translation scoring models continue to grow in size, with the best models being comparable to generation models. Thus, reranking can add substantial computational cost to the translation pipeline. In this work, we pose reranking as a Bayesian optimization (BayesOpt) problem. By strategically selecting candidates to score based on a balance of exploration and exploitation, we show that it is possible to find top-scoring candidates when scoring only a fraction of the candidate list. For instance, our method achieves the same CometKiwi score using only 70 scoring evaluations compared a baseline system using 180. We present a multi-fidelity setting for BayesOpt, where the candidates are first scored with a cheaper but noisier proxy scoring model, which further improves the cost-performance tradeoff when using smaller but well-trained distilled proxy scorers.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09694v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Julius Cheng, Maike Z\"ufle, Vil\'em Zouhar, Andreas Vlachos</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Massive Values in Self-Attention Modules are the Key to Contextual Knowledge Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.01563</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.01563v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have achieved remarkable success in contextual knowledge understanding. In this paper, we show that these concentrated massive values consistently emerge in specific regions of attention queries (Q) and keys (K) while not having such patterns in values (V) in various modern transformer-based LLMs (Q, K, and V mean the representations output by the query, key, and value layers respectively). Through extensive experiments, we further demonstrate that these massive values play a critical role in interpreting contextual knowledge (knowledge obtained from the current context window) rather than in retrieving parametric knowledge stored within the model's parameters. Our further investigation of quantization strategies reveals that ignoring these massive values leads to a pronounced drop in performance on tasks requiring rich contextual understanding, aligning with our analysis. Finally, we trace the emergence of concentrated massive values and find that such concentration is caused by Rotary Positional Encoding (RoPE), which has appeared since the first layers. These findings shed new light on how Q and K operate in LLMs and offer practical insights for model design and optimization. The Code is Available at https://github.com/MingyuJ666/Rope_with_LLM.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.01563v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mingyu Jin, Kai Mei, Wujiang Xu, Mingjie Sun, Ruixiang Tang, Mengnan Du, Zirui Liu, Yongfeng Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An LLM-Powered Agent for Physiological Data Analysis: A Case Study on PPG-based Heart Rate Estimation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.12836</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.12836v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are revolutionizing healthcare by improving diagnosis, patient care, and decision support through interactive communication. More recently, they have been applied to analyzing physiological time-series like wearable data for health insight extraction. Existing methods embed raw numerical sequences directly into prompts, which exceeds token limits and increases computational costs. Additionally, some studies integrated features extracted from time-series in textual prompts or applied multimodal approaches. However, these methods often produce generic and unreliable outputs due to LLMs' limited analytical rigor and inefficiency in interpreting continuous waveforms. In this paper, we develop an LLM-powered agent for physiological time-series analysis aimed to bridge the gap in integrating LLMs with well-established analytical tools. Built on the OpenCHA, an open-source LLM-powered framework, our agent powered by OpenAI's GPT-3.5-turbo model features an orchestrator that integrates user interaction, data sources, and analytical tools to generate accurate health insights. To evaluate its effectiveness, we implement a case study on heart rate (HR) estimation from Photoplethysmogram (PPG) signals using a dataset of PPG and Electrocardiogram (ECG) recordings in a remote health monitoring study. The agent's performance is benchmarked against OpenAI GPT-4o-mini and GPT-4o, with ECG serving as the gold standard for HR estimation. Results demonstrate that our agent significantly outperforms benchmark models by achieving lower error rates and more reliable HR estimations. The agent implementation is publicly available on GitHub.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.12836v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mohammad Feli, Iman Azimi, Pasi Liljeberg, Amir M. Rahmani</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MEMERAG: A Multilingual End-to-End Meta-Evaluation Benchmark for Retrieval Augmented Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.17163</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.17163v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Automatic evaluation of retrieval augmented generation (RAG) systems relies on fine-grained dimensions like faithfulness and relevance, as judged by expert human annotators. Meta-evaluation benchmarks support the development of automatic evaluators that correlate well with human judgement. However, existing benchmarks predominantly focus on English or use translated data, which fails to capture cultural nuances. A native approach provides a better representation of the end user experience.
  In this work, we develop a Multilingual End-to-end Meta-Evaluation RAG benchmark (MEMERAG). Our benchmark builds on the popular MIRACL dataset, using native-language questions and generating responses with diverse large language models (LLMs), which are then assessed by expert annotators for faithfulness and relevance. We describe our annotation process and show that it achieves high inter-annotator agreement. We then analyse the performance of the answer-generating LLMs across languages as per the human evaluators. Finally we apply the dataset to our main use-case which is to benchmark multilingual automatic evaluators (LLM-as-a-judge). We show that our benchmark can reliably identify improvements offered by advanced prompting techniques and LLMs. Our dataset is available at https://github.com/amazon-science/MEMERAG</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.17163v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mar\'ia Andrea Cruz Bland\'on, Jayasimha Talur, Bruno Charron, Dong Liu, Saab Mansour, Marcello Federico</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SemEval-2025 Task 1: AdMIRe -- Advancing Multimodal Idiomaticity Representation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.15358</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.15358v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Idiomatic expressions present a unique challenge in NLP, as their meanings are often not directly inferable from their constituent words. Despite recent advancements in Large Language Models (LLMs), idiomaticity remains a significant obstacle to robust semantic representation. We present datasets and tasks for SemEval-2025 Task 1: AdMiRe (Advancing Multimodal Idiomaticity Representation), which challenges the community to assess and improve models' ability to interpret idiomatic expressions in multimodal contexts and in multiple languages. Participants competed in two subtasks: ranking images based on their alignment with idiomatic or literal meanings, and predicting the next image in a sequence. The most effective methods achieved human-level performance by leveraging pretrained LLMs and vision-language models in mixture-of-experts settings, with multiple queries used to smooth over the weaknesses in these models' representations of idiomaticity.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.15358v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Thomas Pickard, Aline Villavicencio, Maggie Mi, Wei He, Dylan Phelps, Marco Idiart</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CausalRAG: Integrating Causal Graphs into Retrieval-Augmented Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.19878</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.19878v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have revolutionized natural language processing (NLP), particularly through Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG), which enhances LLM capabilities by integrating external knowledge. However, traditional RAG systems face critical limitations, including disrupted contextual integrity due to text chunking, and over-reliance on semantic similarity for retrieval. To address these issues, we propose CausalRAG, a novel framework that incorporates causal graphs into the retrieval process. By constructing and tracing causal relationships, CausalRAG preserves contextual continuity and improves retrieval precision, leading to more accurate and interpretable responses. We evaluate CausalRAG against regular RAG and graph-based RAG approaches, demonstrating its superiority across several metrics. Our findings suggest that grounding retrieval in causal reasoning provides a promising approach to knowledge-intensive tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.19878v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nengbo Wang, Xiaotian Han, Jagdip Singh, Jing Ma, Vipin Chaudhary</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inaccuracy of an E-Dictionary and Its Influence on Chinese Language Users</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.00799</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.00799v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Electronic dictionaries have largely replaced paper dictionaries and become central tools for L2 learners seeking to expand their vocabulary. Users often assume these resources are reliable and rarely question the validity of the definitions provided. The accuracy of major E-dictionaries is seldom scrutinized, and little attention has been paid to how their corpora are constructed. Research on dictionary use, particularly the limitations of electronic dictionaries, remains scarce. This study adopts a combined method of experimentation, user survey, and dictionary critique to examine Youdao, one of the most widely used E-dictionaries in China. The experiment involved a translation task paired with retrospective reflection. Participants were asked to translate sentences containing words that are insufficiently or inaccurately defined in Youdao. Their consultation behavior was recorded to analyze how faulty definitions influenced comprehension. Results show that incomplete or misleading definitions can cause serious misunderstandings. Additionally, students exhibited problematic consultation habits. The study further explores how such flawed definitions originate, highlighting issues in data processing and the integration of AI and machine learning technologies in dictionary construction. The findings suggest a need for better training in dictionary literacy for users, as well as improvements in the underlying AI models used to build E-dictionaries.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.00799v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xi Wang, Fanfei Meng, Shiyang Zhang, Lan Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM-based Automated Grading with Human-in-the-Loop</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.05239</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.05239v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The rise of artificial intelligence (AI) technologies, particularly large language models (LLMs), has brought significant advancements to the field of education. Among various applications, automatic short answer grading (ASAG), which focuses on evaluating open-ended textual responses, has seen remarkable progress with the introduction of LLMs. These models not only enhance grading performance compared to traditional ASAG approaches but also move beyond simple comparisons with predefined "golden" answers, enabling more sophisticated grading scenarios, such as rubric-based evaluation. However, existing LLM-powered methods still face challenges in achieving human-level grading performance in rubric-based assessments due to their reliance on fully automated approaches. In this work, we explore the potential of LLMs in ASAG tasks by leveraging their interactive capabilities through a human-in-the-loop (HITL) approach. Our proposed framework, GradeHITL, utilizes the generative properties of LLMs to pose questions to human experts, incorporating their insights to refine grading rubrics dynamically. This adaptive process significantly improves grading accuracy, outperforming existing methods and bringing ASAG closer to human-level evaluation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.05239v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hang Li, Yucheng Chu, Kaiqi Yang, Yasemin Copur-Gencturk, Jiliang Tang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kaleidoscope: In-language Exams for Massively Multilingual Vision Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.07072</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.07072v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The evaluation of vision-language models (VLMs) has mainly relied on English-language benchmarks, leaving significant gaps in both multilingual and multicultural coverage. While multilingual benchmarks have expanded, both in size and languages, many rely on translations of English datasets, failing to capture cultural nuances. In this work, we propose Kaleidoscope, as the most comprehensive exam benchmark to date for the multilingual evaluation of vision-language models. Kaleidoscope is a large-scale, in-language multimodal benchmark designed to evaluate VLMs across diverse languages and visual inputs. Kaleidoscope covers 18 languages and 14 different subjects, amounting to a total of 20,911 multiple-choice questions. Built through an open science collaboration with a diverse group of researchers worldwide, Kaleidoscope ensures linguistic and cultural authenticity. We evaluate top-performing multilingual vision-language models and find that they perform poorly on low-resource languages and in complex multimodal scenarios. Our results highlight the need for progress on culturally inclusive multimodal evaluation frameworks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.07072v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Israfel Salazar, Manuel Fern\'andez Burda, Shayekh Bin Islam, Arshia Soltani Moakhar, Shivalika Singh, Fabian Farestam, Angelika Romanou, Danylo Boiko, Dipika Khullar, Mike Zhang, Dominik Krzemi\'nski, Jekaterina Novikova, Lu\'isa Shimabucoro, Joseph Marvin Imperial, Rishabh Maheshwary, Sharad Duwal, Alfonso Amayuelas, Swati Rajwal, Jebish Purbey, Ahmed Ruby, Nicholas Popovi\v{c}, Marek Suppa, Azmine Toushik Wasi, Ram Mohan Rao Kadiyala, Olga Tsymboi, Maksim Kostritsya, Bardia Soltani Moakhar, Gabriel da Costa Merlin, Ot\'avio Ferracioli Coletti, Maral Jabbari Shiviari, MohammadAmin farahani fard, Silvia Fernandez, Mar\'ia Grandury, Dmitry Abulkhanov, Drishti Sharma, Andre Guarnier De Mitri, Leticia Bossatto Marchezi, Setayesh Heydari, Johan Obando-Ceron, Nazar Kohut, Beyza Ermis, Desmond Elliott, Enzo Ferrante, Sara Hooker, Marzieh Fadaee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seed1.5-Thinking: Advancing Superb Reasoning Models with Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13914</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13914v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We introduce Seed1.5-Thinking, capable of reasoning through thinking before responding, resulting in improved performance on a wide range of benchmarks. Seed1.5-Thinking achieves 86.7 on AIME 2024, 55.0 on Codeforces and 77.3 on GPQA, demonstrating excellent reasoning abilities in STEM and coding. Beyond reasoning tasks, the method demonstrates notable generalization across diverse domains. For instance, it surpasses DeepSeek R1 by 8% in win rate on non-reasoning tasks, indicating its broader applicability. Compared to other state-of-the-art reasoning models, Seed1.5-Thinking is a Mixture-of-Experts (MoE) model with a relatively small size, featuring 20B activated and 200B total parameters. As part of our effort to assess generalized reasoning, we develop two internal benchmarks, BeyondAIME and Codeforces, both of which will be publicly released to support future research. Model trial link: https://www.volcengine.com/experience/ark.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13914v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>ByteDance Seed,  :, Jiaze Chen, Tiantian Fan, Xin Liu, Lingjun Liu, Zhiqi Lin, Mingxuan Wang, Chengyi Wang, Xiangpeng Wei, Wenyuan Xu, Yufeng Yuan, Yu Yue, Lin Yan, Qiying Yu, Xiaochen Zuo, Chi Zhang, Ruofei Zhu, Zhecheng An, Zhihao Bai, Yu Bao, Xingyan Bin, Jiangjie Chen, Feng Chen, Hongmin Chen, Riwei Chen, Liangqiang Chen, Zixin Chen, Jinsong Chen, Siyan Chen, Kaiyuan Chen, Zhi Chen, Jin Chen, Jiecao Chen, Jinxin Chi, Weinan Dai, Ning Dai, Jiahui Dai, Shihan Dou, Yantao Du, Zhengyin Du, Jianhui Duan, Chen Dun, Ting-Han Fan, Jiazhan Feng, Junda Feng, Ziyuan Feng, Yuwei Fu, Wenqi Fu, Hanjie Fu, Hao Ge, Hongyi Guo, Mingji Han, Li Han, Wenhao Hao, Xintong Hao, Qianyu He, Jerry He, Feng He, Wen Heng, Zehua Hong, Qi Hou, Liang Hu, Shengding Hu, Nan Hu, Kai Hua, Qi Huang, Ziyue Huang, Hongzhi Huang, Zihao Huang, Ting Huang, Wenhao Huang, Wei Jia, Bin Jia, Xiaoying Jia, Yuhua Jiang, Haobin Jiang, Ziheng Jiang, Kaihua Jiang, Chengquan Jiang, Jianpeng Jiao, Xiaoran Jin, Xing Jin, Xunhao Lai, Zheng Li, Xiang Li, Liyi Li, Hongkai Li, Zheng Li, Shengxian Wan, Ya Wang, Yunshui Li, Chenggang Li, Niuniu Li, Siyu Li, Xi Li, Xiao Li, Aoyan Li, Yuntao Li, Nianning Liang, Xinnian Liang, Haibin Lin, Weijian Lin, Ye Lin, Zhicheng Liu, Guanlin Liu, Guanlin Liu, Chenxiao Liu, Yan Liu, Gaohong Liu, Juncai Liu, Chundian Liu, Deyi Liu, Kaibo Liu, Siyao Liu, Qi Liu, Yongfei Liu, Kang Liu, Gan Liu, Boyi Liu, Rui Long, Weiqiang Lou, Chenwei Lou, Xiang Luo, Yao Luo, Caiping Lv, Heyang Lv, Bole Ma, Qianli Ma, Hongzhi Ma, Yiyuan Ma, Jin Ma, Wenchang Ma, Tingting Ma, Chen Mao, Qiyang Min, Zhe Nan, Guanghan Ning, Jinxiang Ou, Haojie Pan, Renming Pang, Yanghua Peng, Tao Peng, Lihua Qian, Lihua Qian, Mu Qiao, Meng Qu, Cheng Ren, Hongbin Ren, Yong Shan, Wei Shen, Ke Shen, Kai Shen, Guangming Sheng, Jinlong Shi, Wenlei Shi, Guang Shi, Shuai Shuai Cao, Yuxin Song, Zuquan Song, Jing Su, Yifan Sun, Tao Sun, Zewei Sun, Borui Wan, Zihan Wang, Xiaohui Wang, Xi Wang, Shuguang Wang, Jun Wang, Qinlong Wang, Chenyuan Wang, Shuai Wang, Zihan Wang, Changbao Wang, Jiaqiang Wang, Shihang Wang, Xuwu Wang, Zaiyuan Wang, Yuxuan Wang, Wenqi Wang, Taiqing Wang, Chengzhi Wei, Houmin Wei, Ziyun Wei, Shufa Wei, Zheng Wu, Yonghui Wu, Yangjun Wu, Bohong Wu, Shuang Wu, Jingqiao Wu, Ning Wu, Shuangzhi Wu, Jianmin Wu, Chenguang Xi, Fan Xia, Yuqiao Xian, Liang Xiang, Boren Xiang, Bowen Xiao, Zhen Xiao, Xia Xiao, Yongsheng Xiao, Chao Xin, Shulin Xin, Yuwen Xiong, Jingjing Xu, Ziwen Xu, Chenyin Xu, Jiayi Xu, Yifan Xu, Wei Xu, Yufei Xu, Shikun Xu, Shipeng Yan, Shen Yan, Qingping Yang, Xi Yang, Tianhao Yang, Yuehang Yang, Yuan Yang, Ximing Yang, Zeyu Yang, Guang Yang, Yifan Yang, Xuesong Yao, Bairen Yi, Fan Yin, Jianian Yin, Ziqiang Ying, Xiangyu Yu, Hongli Yu, Song Yu, Menghan Yu, Huan Yu, Siyu Yuan, Jun Yuan, Yutao Zeng, Tianyang Zhan, Zheng Zhang, Yun Zhang, Mofan Zhang, Wang Zhang, Ru Zhang, Zhi Zhang, Tianqi Zhang, Xinyi Zhang, Zhexi Zhang, Sijun Zhang, Wenqiang Zhang, Xiangxiang Zhang, Yongtao Zhang, Yuyu Zhang, Ge Zhang, He Zhang, Yue Zhang, Renjie Zheng, Ningxin Zheng, Zhuolin Zheng, Yaowei Zheng, Chen Zheng, Xiaoyun Zhi, Wanjun Zhong, Cheng Zhong, Zheng Zhong, Baoquan Zhong, Xun Zhou, Na Zhou, Huan Zhou, Hang Zhu, Defa Zhu, Wenjia Zhu, Lei Zuo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Typology</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.15642</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.15642v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Typology is a subfield of linguistics that focuses on the study and classification of languages based on their structural features. Unlike genealogical classification, which examines the historical relationships between languages, typology seeks to understand the diversity of human languages by identifying common properties and patterns, known as universals. In recent years, computational methods have played an increasingly important role in typological research, enabling the analysis of large-scale linguistic data and the testing of hypotheses about language structure and evolution. This article provides an illustration of the benefits of computational statistical modeling in typology.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.15642v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>q-bio.PE</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gerhard J\"ager</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SARI: Structured Audio Reasoning via Curriculum-Guided Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.15900</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.15900v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent work shows that reinforcement learning(RL) can markedly sharpen the reasoning ability of large language models (LLMs) by prompting them to "think before answering." Yet whether and how these gains transfer to audio-language reasoning remains largely unexplored. We extend the Group-Relative Policy Optimization (GRPO) framework from DeepSeek-R1 to a Large Audio-Language Model (LALM), and construct a 32k sample multiple-choice corpus. Using a two-stage regimen supervised fine-tuning on structured and unstructured chains-of-thought, followed by curriculum-guided GRPO, we systematically compare implicit vs. explicit, and structured vs. free form reasoning under identical architectures. Our structured audio reasoning model, SARI (Structured Audio Reasoning via Curriculum-Guided Reinforcement Learning), achieves a 16.35% improvement in average accuracy over the base model Qwen2-Audio-7B-Instruct. Furthermore, the variant built upon Qwen2.5-Omni reaches state-of-the-art performance of 67.08% on the MMAU test-mini benchmark. Ablation experiments show that on the base model we use: (i) SFT warm-up is important for stable RL training, (ii) structured chains yield more robust generalization than unstructured ones, and (iii) easy-to-hard curricula accelerate convergence and improve final performance. These findings demonstrate that explicit, structured reasoning and curriculum learning substantially enhances audio-language understanding.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.15900v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Cheng Wen, Tingwei Guo, Shuaijiang Zhao, Wei Zou, Xiangang Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HRScene: How Far Are VLMs from Effective High-Resolution Image Understanding?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.18406</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.18406v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: High-resolution image (HRI) understanding aims to process images with a large number of pixels, such as pathological images and agricultural aerial images, both of which can exceed 1 million pixels. Vision Large Language Models (VLMs) can allegedly handle HRIs, however, there is a lack of a comprehensive benchmark for VLMs to evaluate HRI understanding. To address this gap, we introduce HRScene, a novel unified benchmark for HRI understanding with rich scenes. HRScene incorporates 25 real-world datasets and 2 synthetic diagnostic datasets with resolutions ranging from 1,024 $\times$ 1,024 to 35,503 $\times$ 26,627. HRScene is collected and re-annotated by 10 graduate-level annotators, covering 25 scenarios, ranging from microscopic to radiology images, street views, long-range pictures, and telescope images. It includes HRIs of real-world objects, scanned documents, and composite multi-image. The two diagnostic evaluation datasets are synthesized by combining the target image with the gold answer and distracting images in different orders, assessing how well models utilize regions in HRI. We conduct extensive experiments involving 28 VLMs, including Gemini 2.0 Flash and GPT-4o. Experiments on HRScene show that current VLMs achieve an average accuracy of around 50% on real-world tasks, revealing significant gaps in HRI understanding. Results on synthetic datasets reveal that VLMs struggle to effectively utilize HRI regions, showing significant Regional Divergence and lost-in-middle, shedding light on future research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.18406v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yusen Zhang, Wenliang Zheng, Aashrith Madasu, Peng Shi, Ryo Kamoi, Hao Zhou, Zhuoyang Zou, Shu Zhao, Sarkar Snigdha Sarathi Das, Vipul Gupta, Xiaoxin Lu, Nan Zhang, Ranran Haoran Zhang, Avitej Iyer, Renze Lou, Wenpeng Yin, Rui Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unified Multi-Task Learning &amp; Model Fusion for Efficient Language Model Guardrailing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.19333</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.19333v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The trend towards large language models (LLMs) for guardrailing against undesired behaviors is increasing and has shown promise for censoring user inputs. However, increased latency, memory consumption, hosting expenses and non-structured outputs can make their use prohibitive.
  In this work, we show that task-specific data generation can lead to fine-tuned classifiers that significantly outperform current state of the art (SoTA) while being orders of magnitude smaller. Secondly, we show that using a single model, \texttt{MultiTaskGuard}, that is pretrained on a large synthetically generated dataset with unique task instructions further improves generalization. Thirdly, our most performant models, \texttt{UniGuard}, are found using our proposed search-based model merging approach that finds an optimal set of parameters to combine single-policy models and multi-policy guardrail models. % On 7 public datasets and 4 guardrail benchmarks we created, our efficient guardrail classifiers improve over the best performing SoTA publicly available LLMs and 3$^{\text{rd}}$ party guardrail APIs in detecting unsafe and safe behaviors by an average F1 score improvement of \textbf{29.92} points over Aegis-LlamaGuard and \textbf{21.62} over \texttt{gpt-4o}, respectively. Lastly, our guardrail synthetic data generation process that uses custom task-specific guardrail poli</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.19333v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>James O' Neill, Santhosh Subramanian, Eric Lin, Vaikkunth Mugunthan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Context Selection and Rewriting for Video-based Educational Question Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.19406</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.19406v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Educational question generation (EQG) is a crucial component of intelligent educational systems, significantly aiding self-assessment, active learning, and personalized education. While EQG systems have emerged, existing datasets typically rely on predefined, carefully edited texts, failing to represent real-world classroom content, including lecture speech with a set of complementary slides. To bridge this gap, we collect a dataset of educational questions based on lectures from real-world classrooms. On this realistic dataset, we find that current methods for EQG struggle with accurately generating questions from educational videos, particularly in aligning with specific timestamps and target answers. Common challenges include selecting informative contexts from extensive transcripts and ensuring generated questions meaningfully incorporate the target answer. To address the challenges, we introduce a novel framework utilizing large language models for dynamically selecting and rewriting contexts based on target timestamps and answers. First, our framework selects contexts from both lecture transcripts and video keyframes based on answer relevance and temporal proximity. Then, we integrate the contexts selected from both modalities and rewrite them into answer-containing knowledge statements, to enhance the logical connection between the contexts and the desired answer. This approach significantly improves the quality and relevance of the generated questions. Our dataset and code are released in https://github.com/mengxiayu/COSER.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.19406v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mengxia Yu, Bang Nguyen, Olivia Zino, Meng Jiang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM-Generated Fake News Induces Truth Decay in News Ecosystem: A Case Study on Neural News Recommendation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20013</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20013v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Online fake news moderation now faces a new challenge brought by the malicious use of large language models (LLMs) in fake news production. Though existing works have shown LLM-generated fake news is hard to detect from an individual aspect, it remains underexplored how its large-scale release will impact the news ecosystem. In this study, we develop a simulation pipeline and a dataset with ~56k generated news of diverse types to investigate the effects of LLM-generated fake news within neural news recommendation systems. Our findings expose a truth decay phenomenon, where real news is gradually losing its advantageous position in news ranking against fake news as LLM-generated news is involved in news recommendation. We further provide an explanation about why truth decay occurs from a familiarity perspective and show the positive correlation between perplexity and news ranking. Finally, we discuss the threats of LLM-generated fake news and provide possible countermeasures. We urge stakeholders to address this emerging challenge to preserve the integrity of news ecosystems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20013v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3726302.3730027</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Beizhe Hu, Qiang Sheng, Juan Cao, Yang Li, Danding Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prophet: Prompting Large Language Models with Complementary Answer Heuristics for Knowledge-based Visual Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2303.01903</link>
      <description>arXiv:2303.01903v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Knowledge-based visual question answering (VQA) requires external knowledge beyond the image to answer the question. Early studies retrieve required knowledge from explicit knowledge bases (KBs), which often introduces irrelevant information to the question, hence restricting the performance of their models. Recent works have resorted to using a powerful large language model (LLM) as an implicit knowledge engine to acquire the necessary knowledge for answering. Despite the encouraging results achieved by these methods, we argue that they have not fully activated the capacity of the \emph{blind} LLM as the provided textual input is insufficient to depict the required visual information to answer the question. In this paper, we present Prophet -- a conceptually simple, flexible, and general framework designed to prompt LLM with answer heuristics for knowledge-based VQA. Specifically, we first train a vanilla VQA model on a specific knowledge-based VQA dataset without external knowledge. After that, we extract two types of complementary answer heuristics from the VQA model: answer candidates and answer-aware examples. The two types of answer heuristics are jointly encoded into a formatted prompt to facilitate the LLM's understanding of both the image and question, thus generating a more accurate answer. By incorporating the state-of-the-art LLM GPT-3, Prophet significantly outperforms existing state-of-the-art methods on four challenging knowledge-based VQA datasets. Prophet is general that can be instantiated with the combinations of different VQA models (i.e., both discriminative and generative ones) and different LLMs (i.e., both commercial and open-source ones). Moreover, Prophet can also be integrated with modern large multimodal models in different stages, which is named Prophet++, to further improve the capabilities on knowledge-based VQA tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2303.01903v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1109/TPAMI.2025.3562422</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Zhou Yu, Xuecheng Ouyang, Zhenwei Shao, Meng Wang, Jun Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pose-Based Sign Language Appearance Transfer</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.13675</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.13675v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We introduce a method for transferring the signer's appearance in sign language skeletal poses while preserving the sign content. Using estimated poses, we transfer the appearance of one signer to another, maintaining natural movements and transitions. This approach improves pose-based rendering and sign stitching while obfuscating identity. Our experiments show that while the method reduces signer identification accuracy, it slightly harms sign recognition performance, highlighting a tradeoff between privacy and utility. Our code is available at https://github.com/sign-language-processing/pose-anonymization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.13675v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Amit Moryossef, Gerard Sant, Zifan Jiang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DP-2Stage: Adapting Language Models as Differentially Private Tabular Data Generators</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02467</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02467v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Generating tabular data under differential privacy (DP) protection ensures theoretical privacy guarantees but poses challenges for training machine learning models, primarily due to the need to capture complex structures under noisy supervision signals. Recently, pre-trained Large Language Models (LLMs) -- even those at the scale of GPT-2 -- have demonstrated great potential in synthesizing tabular data. However, their applications under DP constraints remain largely unexplored. In this work, we address this gap by applying DP techniques to the generation of synthetic tabular data. Our findings shows that LLMs face difficulties in generating coherent text when fine-tuned with DP, as privacy budgets are inefficiently allocated to non-private elements like table structures. To overcome this, we propose DP-2Stage, a two-stage fine-tuning framework for differentially private tabular data generation. The first stage involves non-private fine-tuning on a pseudo dataset, followed by DP fine-tuning on a private dataset. Our empirical results show that this approach improves performance across various settings and metrics compared to directly fine-tuned LLMs in DP contexts. We release our code and setup at https://github.com/tejuafonja/DP-2Stage.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02467v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Transactions on Machine Learning Research (03/2025)</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Tejumade Afonja, Hui-Po Wang, Raouf Kerkouche, Mario Fritz</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SLA Management in Reconfigurable Multi-Agent RAG: A Systems Approach to Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.06832</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.06832v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) enables Large Language Models (LLMs) to generalize to new information by decoupling reasoning capabilities from static knowledge bases. Traditional RAG enhancements have explored vertical scaling-assigning subtasks to specialized modules-and horizontal scaling-replicating tasks across multiple agents-to improve performance. However, real-world applications impose diverse Service Level Agreements (SLAs) and Quality of Service (QoS) requirements, involving trade-offs among objectives such as reducing cost, ensuring answer quality, and adhering to specific operational constraints.
  In this work, we present a systems-oriented approach to multi-agent RAG tailored for real-world Question Answering (QA) applications. By integrating task-specific non-functional requirements-such as answer quality, cost, and latency-into the system, we enable dynamic reconfiguration to meet diverse SLAs. Our method maps these Service Level Objectives (SLOs) to system-level parameters, allowing the generation of optimal results within specified resource constraints.
  We conduct a case study in the QA domain, demonstrating how dynamic re-orchestration of a multi-agent RAG system can effectively manage the trade-off between answer quality and cost. By adjusting the system based on query intent and operational conditions, we systematically balance performance and resource utilization. This approach allows the system to meet SLOs for various query types, showcasing its practicality for real-world applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.06832v2</guid>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.DC</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Michael Iannelli, Sneha Kuchipudi, Vera Dvorak</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Owls are wise and foxes are unfaithful: Uncovering animal stereotypes in vision-language models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.12433</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.12433v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Animal stereotypes are deeply embedded in human culture and language. They often shape our perceptions and expectations of various species. Our study investigates how animal stereotypes manifest in vision-language models during the task of image generation. Through targeted prompts, we explore whether DALL-E perpetuates stereotypical representations of animals, such as "owls as wise," "foxes as unfaithful," etc. Our findings reveal significant stereotyped instances where the model consistently generates images aligned with cultural biases. The current work is the first of its kind to examine animal stereotyping in vision-language models systematically and to highlight a critical yet underexplored dimension of bias in AI-generated visual content.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.12433v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tabinda Aman, Mohammad Nadeem, Shahab Saquib Sohail, Mohammad Anas, Erik Cambria</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From tools to thieves: Measuring and understanding public perceptions of AI through crowdsourced metaphors</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.18045</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.18045v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: How has the public responded to the increasing prevalence of artificial intelligence (AI)-based technologies? We investigate public perceptions of AI by collecting over 12,000 responses over 12 months from a nationally representative U.S. sample. Participants provided open-ended metaphors reflecting their mental models of AI, a methodology that overcomes the limitations of traditional self-reported measures by capturing more nuance. Using a mixed-methods approach combining quantitative clustering and qualitative coding, we identify 20 dominant metaphors shaping public understanding of AI. To analyze these metaphors systematically, we present a scalable framework integrating language modeling (LM)-based techniques to measure key dimensions of public perception: anthropomorphism (attribution of human-like qualities), warmth, and competence. We find that Americans generally view AI as warm and competent, and that over the past year, perceptions of AI's human-likeness and warmth have significantly increased ($+34\%, r = 0.80, p &lt; 0.01; +41\%, r = 0.62, p &lt; 0.05$). These implicit perceptions, along with the identified dominant metaphors, strongly predict trust in and willingness to adopt AI ($r^2 = 0.21, 0.18, p &lt; 0.001$). Moreover, we uncover systematic demographic differences in metaphors and implicit perceptions, such as the higher propensity of women, older individuals, and people of color to anthropomorphize AI, which shed light on demographic disparities in trust and adoption. In addition to our dataset and framework for tracking evolving public attitudes, we provide actionable insights on using metaphors for inclusive and responsible AI development.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.18045v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Myra Cheng, Angela Y. Lee, Kristina Rapuano, Kate Niederhoffer, Alex Liebscher, Jeffrey Hancock</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>REALEDIT: Reddit Edits As a Large-scale Empirical Dataset for Image Transformations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.03629</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.03629v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Existing image editing models struggle to meet real-world demands. Despite excelling in academic benchmarks, they have yet to be widely adopted for real user needs. Datasets that power these models use artificial edits, lacking the scale and ecological validity necessary to address the true diversity of user requests. We introduce REALEDIT, a large-scale image editing dataset with authentic user requests and human-made edits sourced from Reddit. REALEDIT includes a test set of 9300 examples to evaluate models on real user requests. Our results show that existing models fall short on these tasks, highlighting the need for realistic training data. To address this, we introduce 48K training examples and train our REALEDIT model, achieving substantial gains - outperforming competitors by up to 165 Elo points in human judgment and 92 percent relative improvement on the automated VIEScore metric. We deploy our model on Reddit, testing it on new requests, and receive positive feedback. Beyond image editing, we explore REALEDIT's potential in detecting edited images by partnering with a deepfake detection non-profit. Finetuning their model on REALEDIT data improves its F1-score by 14 percentage points, underscoring the dataset's value for broad applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.03629v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Peter Sushko, Ayana Bharadwaj, Zhi Yang Lim, Vasily Ilin, Ben Caffee, Dongping Chen, Mohammadreza Salehi, Cheng-Yu Hsieh, Ranjay Krishna</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Best of Both Worlds: Integrating Language Models and Diffusion Models for Video Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.04606</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.04606v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Recent advancements in text-to-video (T2V) generation have been driven by two competing paradigms: autoregressive language models and diffusion models. However, each paradigm has intrinsic limitations: language models struggle with visual quality and error accumulation, while diffusion models lack semantic understanding and causal modeling. In this work, we propose LanDiff, a hybrid framework that synergizes the strengths of both paradigms through coarse-to-fine generation. Our architecture introduces three key innovations: (1) a semantic tokenizer that compresses 3D visual features into compact 1D discrete representations through efficient semantic compression, achieving a $\sim$14,000$\times$ compression ratio; (2) a language model that generates semantic tokens with high-level semantic relationships; (3) a streaming diffusion model that refines coarse semantics into high-fidelity videos. Experiments show that LanDiff, a 5B model, achieves a score of 85.43 on the VBench T2V benchmark, surpassing the state-of-the-art open-source models Hunyuan Video (13B) and other commercial models such as Sora, Kling, and Hailuo. Furthermore, our model also achieves state-of-the-art performance in long video generation, surpassing other open-source models in this field. Our demo can be viewed at https://landiff.github.io/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.04606v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aoxiong Yin, Kai Shen, Yichong Leng, Xu Tan, Xinyu Zhou, Juncheng Li, Siliang Tang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wanda++: Pruning Large Language Models via Regional Gradients</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.04992</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.04992v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) pruning seeks to remove unimportant weights for inference speedup with minimal performance impact. However, existing methods often suffer from performance loss without full-model sparsity-aware fine-tuning. This paper presents Wanda++, a novel pruning framework that outperforms the state-of-the-art methods by utilizing decoder-block-level \textbf{regional} gradients. Specifically, Wanda++ improves the pruning score with regional gradients for the first time and proposes an efficient regional optimization method to minimize pruning-induced output discrepancies between the dense and sparse decoder output. Notably, Wanda++ improves perplexity by up to 32\% over Wanda in the language modeling task and generalizes effectively to downstream tasks. Further experiments indicate our proposed method is orthogonal to sparsity-aware fine-tuning, where Wanda++ can be combined with LoRA fine-tuning to achieve a similar perplexity improvement as the Wanda method. The proposed method is lightweight, pruning a 7B LLaMA model in under 10 minutes on a single NVIDIA H100 GPU.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.04992v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yifan Yang, Kai Zhen, Bhavana Ganesh, Aram Galstyan, Goeric Huybrechts, Markus M\"uller, Jonas M. K\"ubler, Rupak Vignesh Swaminathan, Athanasios Mouchtaris, Sravan Babu Bodapati, Nathan Susanj, Zheng Zhang, Jack FitzGerald, Abhishek Kumar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LocAgent: Graph-Guided LLM Agents for Code Localization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.09089</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.09089v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Code localization--identifying precisely where in a codebase changes need to be made--is a fundamental yet challenging task in software maintenance. Existing approaches struggle to efficiently navigate complex codebases when identifying relevant code sections. The challenge lies in bridging natural language problem descriptions with the appropriate code elements, often requiring reasoning across hierarchical structures and multiple dependencies. We introduce LocAgent, a framework that addresses code localization through graph-based representation. By parsing codebases into directed heterogeneous graphs, LocAgent creates a lightweight representation that captures code structures (files, classes, functions) and their dependencies (imports, invocations, inheritance), enabling LLM agents to effectively search and locate relevant entities through powerful multi-hop reasoning. Experimental results on real-world benchmarks demonstrate that our approach significantly enhances accuracy in code localization. Notably, our method with the fine-tuned Qwen-2.5-Coder-Instruct-32B model achieves comparable results to SOTA proprietary models at greatly reduced cost (approximately 86% reduction), reaching up to 92.7% accuracy on file-level localization while improving downstream GitHub issue resolution success rates by 12% for multiple attempts (Pass@10). Our code is available at https://github.com/gersteinlab/LocAgent.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.09089v2</guid>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhaoling Chen, Xiangru Tang, Gangda Deng, Fang Wu, Jialong Wu, Zhiwei Jiang, Viktor Prasanna, Arman Cohan, Xingyao Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Probing and Inducing Combinational Creativity in Vision-Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.13120</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.13120v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The ability to combine existing concepts into novel ideas stands as a fundamental hallmark of human intelligence. Recent advances in Vision-Language Models (VLMs) like GPT-4V and DALLE-3 have sparked debate about whether their outputs reflect combinational creativity--defined by M. A. Boden (1998) as synthesizing novel ideas through combining existing concepts--or sophisticated pattern matching of training data. Drawing inspiration from cognitive science, we investigate the combinational creativity of VLMs from the lens of concept blending. We propose the Identification-Explanation-Implication (IEI) framework, which decomposes creative processes into three levels: identifying input spaces, extracting shared attributes, and deriving novel semantic implications. To validate this framework, we curate CreativeMashup, a high-quality dataset of 666 artist-generated visual mashups annotated according to the IEI framework. Through extensive experiments, we demonstrate that in comprehension tasks, best VLMs have surpassed average human performance while falling short of expert-level understanding; in generation tasks, incorporating our IEI framework into the generation pipeline significantly enhances the creative quality of VLMs' outputs. Our findings establish both a theoretical foundation for evaluating artificial creativity and practical guidelines for improving creative generation in VLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.13120v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yongqian Peng, Yuxi Ma, Mengmeng Wang, Yuxuan Wang, Yizhou Wang, Chi Zhang, Yixin Zhu, Zilong Zheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TimeSoccer: An End-to-End Multimodal Large Language Model for Soccer Commentary Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.17365</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.17365v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Soccer is a globally popular sporting event, typically characterized by long matches and distinctive highlight moments. Recent advances in Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) offer promising capabilities in temporal grounding and video understanding, soccer commentary generation often requires precise temporal localization and semantically rich descriptions over long-form video. However, existing soccer MLLMs often rely on the temporal a priori for caption generation, so they cannot process the soccer video end-to-end. While some traditional approaches follow a two-step paradigm that is complex and fails to capture the global context to achieve suboptimal performance. To solve the above issues, we present TimeSoccer, the first end-to-end soccer MLLM for Single-anchor Dense Video Captioning (SDVC) in full-match soccer videos. TimeSoccer jointly predicts timestamps and generates captions in a single pass, enabling global context modeling across 45-minute matches. To support long video understanding of soccer matches, we introduce MoFA-Select, a training-free, motion-aware frame compression module that adaptively selects representative frames via a coarse-to-fine strategy, and incorporates complementary training paradigms to strengthen the model's ability to handle long temporal sequences. Extensive experiments demonstrate that our TimeSoccer achieves State-of-The-Art (SoTA) performance on the SDVC task in an end-to-end form, generating high-quality commentary with accurate temporal alignment and strong semantic relevance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.17365v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ling You, Wenxuan Huang, Xinni Xie, Xiangyi Wei, Bangyan Li, Shaohui Lin, Yang Li, Changbo Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Versatile Framework for Song Generation with Prompt-based Control</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.19062</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.19062v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Song generation focuses on producing controllable high-quality songs based on various prompts. However, existing methods struggle to generate vocals and accompaniments with prompt-based control and proper alignment. Additionally, they fall short in supporting various tasks. To address these challenges, we introduce VersBand, a multi-task song generation framework for synthesizing high-quality, aligned songs with prompt-based control. VersBand comprises these primary models: 1) VocalBand, a decoupled model, leverages the flow-matching method for generating singing styles, pitches, and mel-spectrograms, allowing fast, high-quality vocal generation with style control. 2) AccompBand, a flow-based transformer model, incorporates the Band-MOE, selecting suitable experts for enhanced quality, alignment, and control. This model allows for generating controllable, high-quality accompaniments aligned with vocals. 3) Two generation models, LyricBand for lyrics and MelodyBand for melodies, contribute to the comprehensive multi-task song generation system, allowing for extensive control based on multiple prompts. Experimental results demonstrate that VersBand performs better over baseline models across multiple song generation tasks using objective and subjective metrics. Audio samples are available at https://aaronz345.github.io/VersBandDemo.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.19062v2</guid>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yu Zhang, Wenxiang Guo, Changhao Pan, Zhiyuan Zhu, Ruiqi Li, Jingyu Lu, Rongjie Huang, Ruiyuan Zhang, Zhiqing Hong, Ziyue Jiang, Zhou Zhao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mitigating Modality Bias in Multi-modal Entity Alignment from a Causal Perspective</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.19458</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.19458v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Multi-Modal Entity Alignment (MMEA) aims to retrieve equivalent entities from different Multi-Modal Knowledge Graphs (MMKGs), a critical information retrieval task. Existing studies have explored various fusion paradigms and consistency constraints to improve the alignment of equivalent entities, while overlooking that the visual modality may not always contribute positively. Empirically, entities with low-similarity images usually generate unsatisfactory performance, highlighting the limitation of overly relying on visual features. We believe the model can be biased toward the visual modality, leading to a shortcut image-matching task. To address this, we propose a counterfactual debiasing framework for MMEA, termed CDMEA, which investigates visual modality bias from a causal perspective. Our approach aims to leverage both visual and graph modalities to enhance MMEA while suppressing the direct causal effect of the visual modality on model predictions. By estimating the Total Effect (TE) of both modalities and excluding the Natural Direct Effect (NDE) of the visual modality, we ensure that the model predicts based on the Total Indirect Effect (TIE), effectively utilizing both modalities and reducing visual modality bias. Extensive experiments on 9 benchmark datasets show that CDMEA outperforms 14 state-of-the-art methods, especially in low-similarity, high-noise, and low-resource data scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.19458v2</guid>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3726302.3730037</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Taoyu Su, Jiawei Sheng, Duohe Ma, Xiaodong Li, Juwei Yue, Mengxiao Song, Yingkai Tang, Tingwen Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
