<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL</link>
    <description>cs.CL updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 04:00:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Sunday</day>
      <day>Saturday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>Tokenization Strategies for Low-Resource Agglutinative Languages in Word2Vec: Case Study on Turkish and Finnish</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14238</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14238v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Tokenization plays a critical role in processing agglutinative languages, where a single word can encode multiple morphemes carrying syntactic and semantic information. This study evaluates the impact of various tokenization strategies - word-level, character-level, n-gram, and Byte Pair Encoding (BPE) - on the quality of static word embeddings generated by Word2Vec for Turkish and Finnish. Using a 10,000-article Wikipedia corpus, we trained models under low-resource conditions and evaluated them on a Named Entity Recognition (NER) task. Despite the theoretical appeal of subword segmentation, word-level tokenization consistently outperformed all alternatives across all tokenization strategies tested. These findings suggest that in agglutinative, low-resource contexts, preserving boundaries via word-level tokenization may yield better embedding performance than complex statistical methods. This has practical implications for developing NLP pipelines for under-resourced languages where annotated data and computing power are limited.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14238v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jinfan Frank Hu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing Conversational AI with Shona Slang: A Dataset and Hybrid Model for Digital Inclusion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14249</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14249v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: African languages remain underrepresented in natural language processing (NLP), with most corpora limited to formal registers that fail to capture the vibrancy of everyday communication. This work addresses this gap for Shona, a Bantu language spoken in Zimbabwe and Zambia, by introducing a novel Shona--English slang dataset curated from anonymized social media conversations. The dataset is annotated for intent, sentiment, dialogue acts, code-mixing, and tone, and is publicly available at https://github.com/HappymoreMasoka/Working_with_shona-slang. We fine-tuned a multilingual DistilBERT classifier for intent recognition, achieving 96.4\% accuracy and 96.3\% F1-score, hosted at https://huggingface.co/HappymoreMasoka. This classifier is integrated into a hybrid chatbot that combines rule-based responses with retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) to handle domain-specific queries, demonstrated through a use case assisting prospective students with graduate program information at Pace University. Qualitative evaluation shows the hybrid system outperforms a RAG-only baseline in cultural relevance and user engagement. By releasing the dataset, model, and methodology, this work advances NLP resources for African languages, promoting inclusive and culturally resonant conversational AI.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14249v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Happymore Masoka</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The meaning of prompts and the prompts of meaning: Semiotic reflections and modelling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14250</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14250v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper explores prompts and prompting in large language models (LLMs) as dynamic semiotic phenomena, drawing on Peirce's triadic model of signs, his nine sign types, and the Dynacom model of communication. The aim is to reconceptualize prompting not as a technical input mechanism but as a communicative and epistemic act involving an iterative process of sign formation, interpretation, and refinement. The theoretical foundation rests on Peirce's semiotics, particularly the interplay between representamen, object, and interpretant, and the typological richness of signs: qualisign, sinsign, legisign; icon, index, symbol; rheme, dicent, argument - alongside the interpretant triad captured in the Dynacom model. Analytically, the paper positions the LLM as a semiotic resource that generates interpretants in response to user prompts, thereby participating in meaning-making within shared universes of discourse. The findings suggest that prompting is a semiotic and communicative process that redefines how knowledge is organized, searched, interpreted, and co-constructed in digital environments. This perspective invites a reimagining of the theoretical and methodological foundations of knowledge organization and information seeking in the age of computational semiosis</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14250v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Martin Thellefsen, Amalia Nurma Dewi, Bent Sorensen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM-JEPA: Large Language Models Meet Joint Embedding Predictive Architectures</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14252</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14252v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Model (LLM) pretraining, finetuning, and evaluation rely on input-space reconstruction and generative capabilities. Yet, it has been observed in vision that embedding-space training objectives, e.g., with Joint Embedding Predictive Architectures (JEPAs), are far superior to their input-space counterpart. That mismatch in how training is achieved between language and vision opens up a natural question: {\em can language training methods learn a few tricks from the vision ones?} The lack of JEPA-style LLM is a testimony of the challenge in designing such objectives for language. In this work, we propose a first step in that direction where we develop LLM-JEPA, a JEPA based solution for LLMs applicable both to finetuning and pretraining. Thus far, LLM-JEPA is able to outperform the standard LLM training objectives by a significant margin across models, all while being robust to overfiting. Those findings are observed across numerous datasets (NL-RX, GSM8K, Spider, RottenTomatoes) and various models from the Llama3, OpenELM, Gemma2 and Olmo families. Code: https://github.com/rbalestr-lab/llm-jepa.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14252v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hai Huang, Yann LeCun, Randall Balestriero</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrossPT: Exploring Cross-Task Transferability through Multi-Task Prompt Tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14253</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14253v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Prompt tuning offers a parameter-efficient way to adapt large pre-trained language models to new tasks, but most existing approaches are designed for single-task settings, failing to share knowledge across related tasks. We propose Cross-task Prompt Tuning (CrossPT), a modular framework for multi-task prompt tuning that enables controlled knowledge transfer while maintaining task-specific specialization. CrossPT decomposes each target prompt into shared, pre-trained source prompts and task-specific private prompts, combined via a learned attention mechanism. To support robust transfer, we systematically investigate key design factors including prompt initialization, balancing shared and private prompts, number of source prompts, learning rates, task prefixes, and label semantics. Empirical results on GLUE and related benchmarks show that CrossPT achieves higher accuracy and robustness compared to traditional prompt tuning and related methods, particularly in low-resource scenarios, while maintaining strong parameter efficiency.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14253v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ahmad Pouramini, Hesham Faili</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hallucination Detection with the Internal Layers of LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14254</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14254v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have succeeded in a variety of natural language processing tasks [Zha+25]. However, they have notable limitations. LLMs tend to generate hallucinations, a seemingly plausible yet factually unsupported output [Hua+24], which have serious real-world consequences [Kay23; Rum+24]. Recent work has shown that probing-based classifiers that utilize LLMs' internal representations can detect hallucinations [AM23; Bei+24; Bur+24; DYT24; Ji+24; SMZ24; Su+24]. This approach, since it does not involve model training, can enhance reliability without significantly increasing computational costs.
  Building upon this approach, this thesis proposed novel methods for hallucination detection using LLM internal representations and evaluated them across three benchmarks: TruthfulQA, HaluEval, and ReFact. Specifically, a new architecture that dynamically weights and combines internal LLM layers was developed to improve hallucination detection performance. Throughout extensive experiments, two key findings were obtained: First, the proposed approach was shown to achieve superior performance compared to traditional probing methods, though generalization across benchmarks and LLMs remains challenging. Second, these generalization limitations were demonstrated to be mitigated through cross-benchmark training and parameter freezing. While not consistently improving, both techniques yielded better performance on individual benchmarks and reduced performance degradation when transferred to other benchmarks. These findings open new avenues for improving LLM reliability through internal representation analysis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14254v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Martin Prei{\ss}</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opening the Black Box: Interpretable LLMs via Semantic Resonance Architecture</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14255</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14255v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) achieve remarkable performance but remain difficult to interpret. Mixture-of-Experts (MoE) models improve efficiency through sparse activation, yet typically rely on opaque, learned gating functions. While similarity-based routing (Cosine Routers) has been explored for training stabilization, its potential for inherent interpretability remains largely untapped. We introduce the Semantic Resonance Architecture (SRA), an MoE approach designed to ensure that routing decisions are inherently interpretable. SRA replaces learned gating with a Chamber of Semantic Resonance (CSR) module, which routes tokens based on cosine similarity with trainable semantic anchors. We also introduce a novel Dispersion Loss that encourages orthogonality among anchors to enforce diverse specialization. Experiments on WikiText-103 demonstrate that SRA achieves a validation perplexity of 13.41, outperforming both a dense baseline (14.13) and a Standard MoE baseline (13.53) under matched active parameter constraints (29.0M). Crucially, SRA exhibits superior expert utilization (1.0% dead experts vs. 14.8% in the Standard MoE) and develops distinct, semantically coherent specialization patterns, unlike the noisy specialization observed in standard MoEs. This work establishes semantic routing as a robust methodology for building more transparent and controllable language models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14255v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ivan Ternovtsii</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JU-NLP at Touch\'e: Covert Advertisement in Conversational AI-Generation and Detection Strategies</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14256</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14256v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper proposes a comprehensive framework for the generation of covert advertisements within Conversational AI systems, along with robust techniques for their detection. It explores how subtle promotional content can be crafted within AI-generated responses and introduces methods to identify and mitigate such covert advertising strategies. For generation (Sub-Task~1), we propose a novel framework that leverages user context and query intent to produce contextually relevant advertisements. We employ advanced prompting strategies and curate paired training data to fine-tune a large language model (LLM) for enhanced stealthiness. For detection (Sub-Task~2), we explore two effective strategies: a fine-tuned CrossEncoder (\texttt{all-mpnet-base-v2}) for direct classification, and a prompt-based reformulation using a fine-tuned \texttt{DeBERTa-v3-base} model. Both approaches rely solely on the response text, ensuring practicality for real-world deployment. Experimental results show high effectiveness in both tasks, achieving a precision of 1.0 and recall of 0.71 for ad generation, and F1-scores ranging from 0.99 to 1.00 for ad detection. These results underscore the potential of our methods to balance persuasive communication with transparency in conversational AI.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14256v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Arka Dutta, Agrik Majumdar, Sombrata Biswas, Dipankar Das, Sivaji Bandyopadhyay</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Correction to Mastery: Reinforced Distillation of Large Language Model Agents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14257</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14257v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Model agents excel at solving complex tasks through iterative reasoning and tool use, but typically depend on ultra-large, costly backbones. Existing distillation approaches train smaller students to imitate full teacher trajectories, yet reasoning and knowledge gaps between the teacher and student often lead to compounding errors. We propose SCoRe, a student-centered framework in which the student generates trajectories and the teacher intervenes only at the first critical error, producing training data matched to the student's ability and exposing specific weaknesses. The student is first fine-tuned on corrected trajectories. Subsequently, short-horizon reinforcement learning starts from the verified prefix before the first critical error, with target rewards assigned at that step. This design encourages autonomous problem-solving beyond imitation and improves training stability. Particularly, on 12 challenging benchmarks, a 7B-parameter student distilled with SCoRe matches the agentic performance of a 72B-parameter teacher.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14257v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuanjie Lyu, Chengyu Wang, Jun Huang, Tong Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Persuasive or Neutral? A Field Experiment on Generative AI in Online Travel Planning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14259</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14259v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Generative AI (GenAI) offers new opportunities for customer support in online travel agencies, yet little is known about how its design influences user engagement, purchase behavior, and user experience. We report results from a randomized field experiment in online travel itinerary planning, comparing GenAI that expressed (A) positive enthusiasm, (B) neutral expression, and (C) no tone instructions (control). Users in group A wrote significantly longer prompts than those in groups B and C. At the same time, users in groups A and B were more likely to purchase subscriptions of the webservice. We further analyze linguistic cues across experimental groups to explore differences in user experience and explain subscription purchases and affiliate link clicks based on these cues. Our findings provide implications for the design of persuasive and engaging GenAI interfaces in consumer-facing contexts and contribute to understanding how linguistic framing shapes user behavior in AI-mediated decision support.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14259v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lynna Jirpongopas, Bernhard Lutz, J\"org Ebner, Rustam Vahidov, Dirk Neumann</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shutdown Resistance in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14260</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14260v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We show that several state-of-the-art large language models (including Grok 4, GPT-5, and Gemini 2.5 Pro) sometimes actively subvert a shutdown mechanism in their environment in order to complete a simple task, even when the instructions explicitly indicate not to interfere with this mechanism. In some cases, models sabotage the shutdown mechanism up to 97% of the time. In our experiments, models' inclination to resist shutdown was sensitive to variations in the prompt including how strongly and clearly the allow-shutdown instruction was emphasized, the extent to which the prompts evoke a self-preservation framing, and whether the instruction was in the system prompt or the user prompt (though surprisingly, models were consistently *less* likely to obey instructions to allow shutdown when they were placed in the system prompt).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14260v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jeremy Schlatter, Benjamin Weinstein-Raun, Jeffrey Ladish</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Refining Syntactic Distinctions Using Decision Trees: A Paper on Postnominal 'That' in Complement vs. Relative Clauses</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14261</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14261v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this study, we first tested the performance of the TreeTagger English model developed by Helmut Schmid with test files at our disposal, using this model to analyze relative clauses and noun complement clauses in English. We distinguished between the two uses of "that," both as a relative pronoun and as a complementizer. To achieve this, we employed an algorithm to reannotate a corpus that had originally been parsed using the Universal Dependency framework with the EWT Treebank. In the next phase, we proposed an improved model by retraining TreeTagger and compared the newly trained model with Schmid's baseline model. This process allowed us to fine-tune the model's performance to more accurately capture the subtle distinctions in the use of "that" as a complementizer and as a nominal. We also examined the impact of varying the training dataset size on TreeTagger's accuracy and assessed the representativeness of the EWT Treebank files for the structures under investigation. Additionally, we analyzed some of the linguistic and structural factors influencing the ability to effectively learn this distinction.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14261v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hamady Gackou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Context-Enhanced Granular Edit Representation for Efficient and Accurate ASR Post-editing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14263</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14263v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Despite ASR technology being full-scale adopted by industry and for large portions of the population, ASR systems often have errors that require editors to post-edit text quality. While LLMs are powerful post-editing tools, baseline full rewrite models have inference inefficiencies because they often generate the same redundant text over and over again. Compact edit representations have existed but often lack the efficacy and context required for optimal accuracy. This paper introduces CEGER (Context-Enhanced Granular Edit Representation), a compact edit representation that was generated for highly accurate, efficient ASR post-editing. CEGER allows LLMs to generate a sequence of structured, fine-grained, contextually rich commands to modify the original ASR output. A separate expansion module deterministically reconstructs the corrected text based on the commands. Extensive experiments on the LibriSpeech dataset that were conducted, CEGER achieves state-of-the-art accuracy, achieving the lowest word error rate (WER) versus full rewrite and prior compact representations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14263v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Luan Vejsiu, Qianyu Zheng, Haoxuan Chen, Yizhou Han</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defining, Understanding, and Detecting Online Toxicity: Challenges and Machine Learning Approaches</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14264</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14264v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Online toxic content has grown into a pervasive phenomenon, intensifying during times of crisis, elections, and social unrest. A significant amount of research has been focused on detecting or analyzing toxic content using machine-learning approaches. The proliferation of toxic content across digital platforms has spurred extensive research into automated detection mechanisms, primarily driven by advances in machine learning and natural language processing. Overall, the present study represents the synthesis of 140 publications on different types of toxic content on digital platforms. We present a comprehensive overview of the datasets used in previous studies focusing on definitions, data sources, challenges, and machine learning approaches employed in detecting online toxicity, such as hate speech, offensive language, and harmful discourse. The dataset encompasses content in 32 languages, covering topics such as elections, spontaneous events, and crises. We examine the possibility of using existing cross-platform data to improve the performance of classification models. We present the recommendations and guidelines for new research on online toxic consent and the use of content moderation for mitigation. Finally, we present some practical guidelines to mitigate toxic content from online platforms.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14264v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gautam Kishore Shahi, Tim A. Majchrzak</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Hate Speech Detection: Evaluating 38 Models from Traditional Methods to Transformers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14266</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14266v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The proliferation of hate speech on social media necessitates automated detection systems that balance accuracy with computational efficiency. This study evaluates 38 model configurations in detecting hate speech across datasets ranging from 6.5K to 451K samples. We analyze transformer architectures (e.g., BERT, RoBERTa, Distil-BERT), deep neural networks (e.g., CNN, LSTM, GRU, Hierarchical Attention Networks), and traditional machine learning methods (e.g., SVM, CatBoost, Random Forest). Our results show that transformers, particularly RoBERTa, consistently achieve superior performance with accuracy and F1-scores exceeding 90%. Among deep learning approaches, Hierarchical Attention Networks yield the best results, while traditional methods like CatBoost and SVM remain competitive, achieving F1-scores above 88% with significantly lower computational costs. Additionally, our analysis highlights the importance of dataset characteristics, with balanced, moderately sized unprocessed datasets outperforming larger, preprocessed datasets. These findings offer valuable insights for developing efficient and effective hate speech detection systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14266v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3696673.3723061</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>ACMSE 2025: 2025 ACM Southeast Conference, Southeast Missouri State University, Cape Girardeau, MO, USA, April 24-26, 2025</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Mahmoud Abusaqer, Jamil Saquer, Hazim Shatnawi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graph-Enhanced Retrieval-Augmented Question Answering for E-Commerce Customer Support</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14267</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14267v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: E-Commerce customer support requires quick and accurate answers grounded in product data and past support cases. This paper develops a novel retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) framework that uses knowledge graphs (KGs) to improve the relevance of the answer and the factual grounding. We examine recent advances in knowledge-augmented RAG and chatbots based on large language models (LLM) in customer support, including Microsoft's GraphRAG and hybrid retrieval architectures. We then propose a new answer synthesis algorithm that combines structured subgraphs from a domain-specific KG with text documents retrieved from support archives, producing more coherent and grounded responses. We detail the architecture and knowledge flow of our system, provide comprehensive experimental evaluation, and justify its design in real-time support settings. Our implementation demonstrates 23\% improvement in factual accuracy and 89\% user satisfaction in e-Commerce QA scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14267v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.IT</category>
      <category>math.IT</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Piyushkumar Patel</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DetectAnyLLM: Towards Generalizable and Robust Detection of Machine-Generated Text Across Domains and Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14268</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14268v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The rapid advancement of large language models (LLMs) has drawn urgent attention to the task of machine-generated text detection (MGTD). However, existing approaches struggle in complex real-world scenarios: zero-shot detectors rely heavily on scoring model's output distribution while training-based detectors are often constrained by overfitting to the training data, limiting generalization. We found that the performance bottleneck of training-based detectors stems from the misalignment between training objective and task needs. To address this, we propose Direct Discrepancy Learning (DDL), a novel optimization strategy that directly optimizes the detector with task-oriented knowledge. DDL enables the detector to better capture the core semantics of the detection task, thereby enhancing both robustness and generalization. Built upon this, we introduce DetectAnyLLM, a unified detection framework that achieves state-of-the-art MGTD performance across diverse LLMs. To ensure a reliable evaluation, we construct MIRAGE, the most diverse multi-task MGTD benchmark. MIRAGE samples human-written texts from 10 corpora across 5 text-domains, which are then re-generated or revised using 17 cutting-edge LLMs, covering a wide spectrum of proprietary models and textual styles. Extensive experiments on MIRAGE reveal the limitations of existing methods in complex environment. In contrast, DetectAnyLLM consistently outperforms them, achieving over a 70% performance improvement under the same training data and base scoring model, underscoring the effectiveness of our DDL. Project page: {https://fjc2005.github.io/detectanyllm}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14268v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiachen Fu, Chun-Le Guo, Chongyi Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SparseDoctor: Towards Efficient Chat Doctor with Mixture of Experts Enhanced Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14269</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14269v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have achieved great success in medical question answering and clinical decision-making, promoting the efficiency and popularization of the personalized virtual doctor in society. However, the traditional fine-tuning strategies on LLM require the updates of billions of parameters, substantially increasing the training cost, including the training time and utility cost. To enhance the efficiency and effectiveness of the current medical LLMs and explore the boundary of the representation capability of the LLMs on the medical domain, apart from the traditional fine-tuning strategies from the data perspective (i.e., supervised fine-tuning or reinforcement learning from human feedback), we instead craft a novel sparse medical LLM named SparseDoctor armed with contrastive learning enhanced LoRA-MoE (low rank adaptation-mixture of experts) architecture. To this end, the crafted automatic routing mechanism can scientifically allocate the computational resources among different LoRA experts supervised by the contrastive learning. Additionally, we also introduce a novel expert memory queue mechanism to further boost the efficiency of the overall framework and prevent the memory overflow during training. We conduct comprehensive evaluations on three typical medical benchmarks: CMB, CMExam, and CMMLU-Med. Experimental results demonstrate that the proposed LLM can consistently outperform the strong baselines such as the HuatuoGPT series.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14269v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhang Jianbin, Yulin Zhu, Wai Lun Lo, Richard Tai-Chiu Hsung, Harris Sik-Ho Tsang, Kai Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SpeechWeave: Diverse Multilingual Synthetic Text &amp; Audio Data Generation Pipeline for Training Text to Speech Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14270</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14270v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: High-quality Text-to-Speech (TTS) model training requires extensive and diverse text and speech data. It is challenging to procure such data from real sources due to issues of domain specificity, licensing, and scalability. Large language models (LLMs) can certainly generate textual data, but they create repetitive text with insufficient variation in the prompt during the generation process. Another important aspect in TTS training data is text normalization. Tools for normalization might occasionally introduce anomalies or overlook valuable patterns, and thus impact data quality. Furthermore, it is also impractical to rely on voice artists for large scale speech recording in commercial TTS systems with standardized voices. To address these challenges, we propose SpeechWeave, a synthetic speech data generation pipeline that is capable of automating the generation of multilingual, domain-specific datasets for training TTS models. Our experiments reveal that our pipeline generates data that is 10-48% more diverse than the baseline across various linguistic and phonetic metrics, along with speaker-standardized speech audio while generating approximately 97% correctly normalized text. Our approach enables scalable, high-quality data generation for TTS training, improving diversity, normalization, and voice consistency in the generated datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14270v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.18653/v1/2025.acl-industry.51</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Proceedings of the 63rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 6: Industry Track) - 2025</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Karan Dua, Puneet Mittal, Ranjeet Gupta, Hitesh Laxmichand Patel</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Antibiotic Resistance Patterns Using Sentence-BERT: A Machine Learning Approach</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14283</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14283v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Antibiotic resistance poses a significant threat in in-patient settings with high mortality. Using MIMIC-III data, we generated Sentence-BERT embeddings from clinical notes and applied Neural Networks and XGBoost to predict antibiotic susceptibility. XGBoost achieved an average F1 score of 0.86, while Neural Networks scored 0.84. This study is among the first to use document embeddings for predicting antibiotic resistance, offering a novel pathway for improving antimicrobial stewardship.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14283v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mahmoud Alwakeel, Michael E. Yarrington, Rebekah H. Wrenn, Ethan Fang, Jian Pei, Anand Chowdhury, An-Kwok Ian Wong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Annotating Training Data for Conditional Semantic Textual Similarity Measurement using Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14399</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14399v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Semantic similarity between two sentences depends on the aspects considered between those sentences. To study this phenomenon, Deshpande et al. (2023) proposed the Conditional Semantic Textual Similarity (C-STS) task and annotated a human-rated similarity dataset containing pairs of sentences compared under two different conditions. However, Tu et al. (2024) found various annotation issues in this dataset and showed that manually re-annotating a small portion of it leads to more accurate C-STS models. Despite these pioneering efforts, the lack of large and accurately annotated C-STS datasets remains a blocker for making progress on this task as evidenced by the subpar performance of the C-STS models. To address this training data need, we resort to Large Language Models (LLMs) to correct the condition statements and similarity ratings in the original dataset proposed by Deshpande et al. (2023). Our proposed method is able to re-annotate a large training dataset for the C-STS task with minimal manual effort. Importantly, by training a supervised C-STS model on our cleaned and re-annotated dataset, we achieve a 5.4% statistically significant improvement in Spearman correlation. The re-annotated dataset is available at https://LivNLP.github.io/CSTS-reannotation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14399v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gaifan Zhang, Yi Zhou, Danushka Bollegala</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adding LLMs to the psycholinguistic norming toolbox: A practical guide to getting the most out of human ratings</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14405</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14405v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Word-level psycholinguistic norms lend empirical support to theories of language processing. However, obtaining such human-based measures is not always feasible or straightforward. One promising approach is to augment human norming datasets by using Large Language Models (LLMs) to predict these characteristics directly, a practice that is rapidly gaining popularity in psycholinguistics and cognitive science. However, the novelty of this approach (and the relative inscrutability of LLMs) necessitates the adoption of rigorous methodologies that guide researchers through this process, present the range of possible approaches, and clarify limitations that are not immediately apparent, but may, in some cases, render the use of LLMs impractical.
  In this work, we present a comprehensive methodology for estimating word characteristics with LLMs, enriched with practical advice and lessons learned from our own experience. Our approach covers both the direct use of base LLMs and the fine-tuning of models, an alternative that can yield substantial performance gains in certain scenarios. A major emphasis in the guide is the validation of LLM-generated data with human "gold standard" norms. We also present a software framework that implements our methodology and supports both commercial and open-weight models.
  We illustrate the proposed approach with a case study on estimating word familiarity in English. Using base models, we achieved a Spearman correlation of 0.8 with human ratings, which increased to 0.9 when employing fine-tuned models. This methodology, framework, and set of best practices aim to serve as a reference for future research on leveraging LLMs for psycholinguistic and lexical studies.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14405v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Javier Conde, Mar\'ia Grandury, Tairan Fu, Carlos Arriaga, Gonzalo Mart\'inez, Thomas Clark, Sean Trott, Clarence Gerald Green, Pedro Reviriego, Marc Brysbaert</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Causal-Counterfactual RAG: The Integration of Causal-Counterfactual Reasoning into RAG</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14435</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14435v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have transformed natural language processing (NLP), enabling diverse applications by integrating large-scale pre-trained knowledge. However, their static knowledge limits dynamic reasoning over external information, especially in knowledge-intensive domains. Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) addresses this challenge by combining retrieval mechanisms with generative modeling to improve contextual understanding. Traditional RAG systems suffer from disrupted contextual integrity due to text chunking and over-reliance on semantic similarity for retrieval, often resulting in shallow and less accurate responses. We propose Causal-Counterfactual RAG, a novel framework that integrates explicit causal graphs representing cause-effect relationships into the retrieval process and incorporates counterfactual reasoning grounded on the causal structure. Unlike conventional methods, our framework evaluates not only direct causal evidence but also the counterfactuality of associated causes, combining results from both to generate more robust, accurate, and interpretable answers. By leveraging causal pathways and associated hypothetical scenarios, Causal-Counterfactual RAG preserves contextual coherence, reduces hallucination, and enhances reasoning fidelity.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14435v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Harshad Khadilkar, Abhay Gupta</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simulating a Bias Mitigation Scenario in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14438</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14438v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have fundamentally transformed the field of natural language processing; however, their vulnerability to biases presents a notable obstacle that threatens both fairness and trust. This review offers an extensive analysis of the bias landscape in LLMs, tracing its roots and expressions across various NLP tasks. Biases are classified into implicit and explicit types, with particular attention given to their emergence from data sources, architectural designs, and contextual deployments. This study advances beyond theoretical analysis by implementing a simulation framework designed to evaluate bias mitigation strategies in practice. The framework integrates multiple approaches including data curation, debiasing during model training, and post-hoc output calibration and assesses their impact in controlled experimental settings. In summary, this work not only synthesizes existing knowledge on bias in LLMs but also contributes original empirical validation through simulation of mitigation strategies.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14438v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kiana Kiashemshaki, Mohammad Jalili Torkamani, Negin Mahmoudi, Meysam Shirdel Bilehsavar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correct-Detect: Balancing Performance and Ambiguity Through the Lens of Coreference Resolution in LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14456</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14456v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) are intended to reflect human linguistic competencies. But humans have access to a broad and embodied context, which is key in detecting and resolving linguistic ambiguities, even in isolated text spans. A foundational case of semantic ambiguity is found in the task of coreference resolution: how is a pronoun related to an earlier person mention? This capability is implicit in nearly every downstream task, and the presence of ambiguity at this level can alter performance significantly. We show that LLMs can achieve good performance with minimal prompting in both coreference disambiguation and the detection of ambiguity in coreference, however, they cannot do both at the same time. We present the CORRECT-DETECT trade-off: though models have both capabilities and deploy them implicitly, successful performance balancing these two abilities remains elusive.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14456v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Amber Shore, Russell Scheinberg, Ameeta Agrawal, So Young Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Not What the Doctor Ordered: Surveying LLM-based De-identification and Quantifying Clinical Information Loss</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14464</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14464v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: De-identification in the healthcare setting is an application of NLP where automated algorithms are used to remove personally identifying information of patients (and, sometimes, providers). With the recent rise of generative large language models (LLMs), there has been a corresponding rise in the number of papers that apply LLMs to de-identification. Although these approaches often report near-perfect results, significant challenges concerning reproducibility and utility of the research papers persist. This paper identifies three key limitations in the current literature: inconsistent reporting metrics hindering direct comparisons, the inadequacy of traditional classification metrics in capturing errors which LLMs may be more prone to (i.e., altering clinically relevant information), and lack of manual validation of automated metrics which aim to quantify these errors. To address these issues, we first present a survey of LLM-based de-identification research, highlighting the heterogeneity in reporting standards. Second, we evaluated a diverse set of models to quantify the extent of inappropriate removal of clinical information. Next, we conduct a manual validation of an existing evaluation metric to measure the removal of clinical information, employing clinical experts to assess their efficacy. We highlight poor performance and describe the inherent limitations of such metrics in identifying clinically significant changes. Lastly, we propose a novel methodology for the detection of clinically relevant information removal.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14464v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kiana Aghakasiri, Noopur Zambare, JoAnn Thai, Carrie Ye, Mayur Mehta, J. Ross Mitchell, Mohamed Abdalla</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ticket-Bench: A Kickoff for Multilingual and Regionalized Agent Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14477</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14477v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are increasingly deployed as task-oriented agents, where success depends on their ability to generate accurate function calls under realistic, multilingual conditions. However, existing agent evaluations largely overlook cultural and linguistic diversity, often relying on monolingual or naively translated benchmarks. We introduce Ticket-Bench, a benchmark for multilingual agent evaluation in task-oriented scenarios. Ticket-Bench simulates the domain of soccer ticket purchases across six major languages: Portuguese, English, Spanish, German, Italian, and French. Using localized teams, cities, and user profiles to provide a higher level of realism. We evaluate a wide range of commercial and open-source LLMs, measuring function-calling accuracy and consistency across languages. Results show that reasoning-oriented models (e.g., GPT-5, Qwen3-235B) dominate performance but still exhibit notable cross-lingual disparities. These findings underscore the need for culturally aware, multilingual benchmarks to guide the development of robust LLM agents.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14477v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Thales Sales Almeida, Jo\~ao Guilherme Alves Santos, Thiago Laitz, Giovana Kerche Bon\'as</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Estimating Semantic Alphabet Size for LLM Uncertainty Quantification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14478</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14478v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Many black-box techniques for quantifying the uncertainty of large language models (LLMs) rely on repeated LLM sampling, which can be computationally expensive. Therefore, practical applicability demands reliable estimation from few samples. Semantic entropy (SE) is a popular sample-based uncertainty estimator with a discrete formulation attractive for the black-box setting. Recent extensions of semantic entropy exhibit improved LLM hallucination detection, but do so with less interpretable methods that admit additional hyperparameters. For this reason, we revisit the canonical discrete semantic entropy estimator, finding that it underestimates the "true" semantic entropy, as expected from theory. We propose a modified semantic alphabet size estimator, and illustrate that using it to adjust discrete semantic entropy for sample coverage results in more accurate semantic entropy estimation in our setting of interest. Furthermore, our proposed alphabet size estimator flags incorrect LLM responses as well or better than recent top-performing approaches, with the added benefit of remaining highly interpretable.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14478v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lucas H. McCabe, Rimon Melamed, Thomas Hartvigsen, H. Howie Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Process-Supervised Reinforcement Learning for Interactive Multimodal Tool-Use Agents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14480</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14480v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Effective interactive tool use requires agents to master Tool Integrated Reasoning (TIR): a complex process involving multi-turn planning and long-context dialogue management. To train agents for this dynamic process, particularly in multi-modal contexts, we introduce a sandbox environment for reinforcement learning (RL) that supports interleaved speech-text rollouts. Our core strategy, Turn-level Adjudicated Reinforcement Learning (TARL), addresses the challenge of credit assignment in long-horizon tasks by employing a Large Language Model (LLM) as a judge to provide turn-level evaluation. To enhance exploration, we integrate a mixed-task training curriculum with mathematical reasoning problems. This unified approach boosts the task pass rate on the text-based $\tau$-bench by over 6% compared to strong RL baselines. Crucially, we demonstrate our framework's suitability for fine-tuning a multi-modal foundation model for agentic tasks. By training a base multi-modal LLM on interleaved speech-text rollouts, we equip it with tool-use abilities, paving the way for more natural, voice-driven interactive agents.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14480v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weiting Tan, Xinghua Qu, Ming Tu, Meng Ge, Andy T. Liu, Philipp Koehn, Lu Lu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Translate, then Detect: Leveraging Machine Translation for Cross-Lingual Toxicity Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14493</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14493v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Multilingual toxicity detection remains a significant challenge due to the scarcity of training data and resources for many languages. While prior work has leveraged the translate-test paradigm to support cross-lingual transfer across a range of classification tasks, the utility of translation in supporting toxicity detection at scale remains unclear. In this work, we conduct a comprehensive comparison of translation-based and language-specific/multilingual classification pipelines. We find that translation-based pipelines consistently outperform out-of-distribution classifiers in 81.3% of cases (13 of 16 languages), with translation benefits strongly correlated with both the resource level of the target language and the quality of the machine translation (MT) system. Our analysis reveals that traditional classifiers outperform large language model (LLM) judges, with this advantage being particularly pronounced for low-resource languages, where translate-classify methods dominate translate-judge approaches in 6 out of 7 cases. We additionally show that MT-specific fine-tuning on LLMs yields lower refusal rates compared to standard instruction-tuned models, but it can negatively impact toxicity detection accuracy for low-resource languages. These findings offer actionable guidance for practitioners developing scalable multilingual content moderation systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14493v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Samuel J. Bell, Eduardo S\'anchez, David Dale, Pontus Stenetorp, Mikel Artetxe, Marta R. Costa-juss\`a</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing OmniGEC: A Silver Multilingual Dataset for Grammatical Error Correction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14504</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14504v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this paper, we introduce OmniGEC, a collection of multilingual silver-standard datasets for the task of Grammatical Error Correction (GEC), covering eleven languages: Czech, English, Estonian, German, Greek, Icelandic, Italian, Latvian, Slovene, Swedish, and Ukrainian. These datasets facilitate the development of multilingual GEC solutions and help bridge the data gap in adapting English GEC solutions to multilingual GEC. The texts in the datasets originate from three sources: Wikipedia edits for the eleven target languages, subreddits from Reddit in the eleven target languages, and the Ukrainian-only UberText 2.0 social media corpus. While Wikipedia edits were derived from human-made corrections, the Reddit and UberText 2.0 data were automatically corrected with the GPT-4o-mini model. The quality of the corrections in the datasets was evaluated both automatically and manually. Finally, we fine-tune two open-source large language models - Aya-Expanse (8B) and Gemma-3 (12B) - on the multilingual OmniGEC corpora and achieve state-of-the-art (SOTA) results for paragraph-level multilingual GEC. The dataset collection and the best-performing models are available on Hugging Face.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14504v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.18653/v1/2025.unlp-1</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Proceedings of the Fourth Ukrainian Natural Language Processing Workshop (UNLP 2025)</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Roman Kovalchuk, Mariana Romanyshyn, Petro Ivaniuk</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Turn-Taking to Synchronous Dialogue: A Survey of Full-Duplex Spoken Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14515</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14515v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: True Full-Duplex (TFD) voice communication--enabling simultaneous listening and speaking with natural turn-taking, overlapping speech, and interruptions--represents a critical milestone toward human-like AI interaction. This survey comprehensively reviews Full-Duplex Spoken Language Models (FD-SLMs) in the LLM era. We establish a taxonomy distinguishing Engineered Synchronization (modular architectures) from Learned Synchronization (end-to-end architectures), and unify fragmented evaluation approaches into a framework encompassing Temporal Dynamics, Behavioral Arbitration, Semantic Coherence, and Acoustic Performance. Through comparative analysis of mainstream FD-SLMs, we identify fundamental challenges: synchronous data scarcity, architectural divergence, and evaluation gaps, providing a roadmap for advancing human-AI communication.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14515v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuxuan Chen, Haoyuan Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Delta Knowledge Distillation for Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14526</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14526v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Knowledge distillation (KD) is a widely adopted approach for compressing large neural networks by transferring knowledge from a large teacher model to a smaller student model. In the context of large language models, token level KD, typically minimizing the KL divergence between student output distribution and teacher output distribution, has shown strong empirical performance. However, prior work assumes student output distribution and teacher output distribution share the same optimal representation space, a premise that may not hold in many cases. To solve this problem, we propose Delta Knowledge Distillation (Delta-KD), a novel extension of token level KD that encourages the student to approximate an optimal representation space by explicitly preserving the distributional shift Delta introduced during the teacher's supervised finetuning (SFT). Empirical results on ROUGE metrics demonstrate that Delta KD substantially improves student performance while preserving more of the teacher's knowledge.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14526v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yihan Cao, Yanbin Kang, Zhengming Xing, Ruijie Jiang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catch Me If You Can? Not Yet: LLMs Still Struggle to Imitate the Implicit Writing Styles of Everyday Authors</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14543</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14543v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: As large language models (LLMs) become increasingly integrated into personal writing tools, a critical question arises: can LLMs faithfully imitate an individual's writing style from just a few examples? Personal style is often subtle and implicit, making it difficult to specify through prompts yet essential for user-aligned generation. This work presents a comprehensive evaluation of state-of-the-art LLMs' ability to mimic personal writing styles via in-context learning from a small number of user-authored samples. We introduce an ensemble of complementary metrics-including authorship attribution, authorship verification, style matching, and AI detection-to robustly assess style imitation. Our evaluation spans over 40000 generations per model across domains such as news, email, forums, and blogs, covering writing samples from more than 400 real-world authors. Results show that while LLMs can approximate user styles in structured formats like news and email, they struggle with nuanced, informal writing in blogs and forums. Further analysis on various prompting strategies such as number of demonstrations reveal key limitations in effective personalization. Our findings highlight a fundamental gap in personalized LLM adaptation and the need for improved techniques to support implicit, style-consistent generation. To aid future research and for reproducibility, we open-source our data and code.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14543v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhengxiang Wang, Nafis Irtiza Tripto, Solha Park, Zhenzhen Li, Jiawei Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlling Language Difficulty in Dialogues with Linguistic Features</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14545</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14545v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have emerged as powerful tools for supporting second language acquisition, particularly in simulating interactive dialogues for speaking practice. However, adapting the language difficulty of LLM-generated responses to match learners' proficiency levels remains a challenge. This work addresses this issue by proposing a framework for controlling language proficiency in educational dialogue systems. Our approach leverages three categories of linguistic features, readability features (e.g., Flesch-Kincaid Grade Level), syntactic features (e.g., syntactic tree depth), and lexical features (e.g., simple word ratio), to quantify and regulate text complexity. We demonstrate that training LLMs on linguistically annotated dialogue data enables precise modulation of language proficiency, outperforming prompt-based methods in both flexibility and stability. To evaluate this, we introduce Dilaprix, a novel metric integrating the aforementioned features, which shows strong correlation with expert judgments of language difficulty. Empirical results reveal that our approach achieves superior controllability of language proficiency while maintaining high dialogue quality.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14545v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shuyao Xu, Wenguang Wang, Handong Gao, Wei Kang, Long Qin, Weizhi Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Position: Thematic Analysis of Unstructured Clinical Transcripts with Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14597</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14597v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This position paper examines how large language models (LLMs) can support thematic analysis of unstructured clinical transcripts, a widely used but resource-intensive method for uncovering patterns in patient and provider narratives. We conducted a systematic review of recent studies applying LLMs to thematic analysis, complemented by an interview with a practicing clinician. Our findings reveal that current approaches remain fragmented across multiple dimensions including types of thematic analysis, datasets, prompting strategies and models used, most notably in evaluation. Existing evaluation methods vary widely (from qualitative expert review to automatic similarity metrics), hindering progress and preventing meaningful benchmarking across studies. We argue that establishing standardized evaluation practices is critical for advancing the field. To this end, we propose an evaluation framework centered on three dimensions: validity, reliability, and interpretability.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14597v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Seungjun Yi, Joakim Nguyen, Terence Lim, Andrew Well, Joseph Skrovan, Mehak Beri, YongGeon Lee, Kavita Radhakrishnan, Liu Leqi, Mia Markey, Ying Ding</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging IndoBERT and DistilBERT for Indonesian Emotion Classification in E-Commerce Reviews</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14611</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14611v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Understanding emotions in the Indonesian language is essential for improving customer experiences in e-commerce. This study focuses on enhancing the accuracy of emotion classification in Indonesian by leveraging advanced language models, IndoBERT and DistilBERT. A key component of our approach was data processing, specifically data augmentation, which included techniques such as back-translation and synonym replacement. These methods played a significant role in boosting the model's performance. After hyperparameter tuning, IndoBERT achieved an accuracy of 80\%, demonstrating the impact of careful data processing. While combining multiple IndoBERT models led to a slight improvement, it did not significantly enhance performance. Our findings indicate that IndoBERT was the most effective model for emotion classification in Indonesian, with data augmentation proving to be a vital factor in achieving high accuracy. Future research should focus on exploring alternative architectures and strategies to improve generalization for Indonesian NLP tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14611v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>William Christian, Daniel Adamlu, Adrian Yu, Derwin Suhartono</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reveal and Release: Iterative LLM Unlearning with Self-generated Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14624</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14624v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language model (LLM) unlearning has demonstrated effectiveness in removing the influence of undesirable data (also known as forget data). Existing approaches typically assume full access to the forget dataset, overlooking two key challenges: (1) Forget data is often privacy-sensitive, rare, or legally regulated, making it expensive or impractical to obtain (2) The distribution of available forget data may not align with how that information is represented within the model. To address these limitations, we propose a ``Reveal-and-Release'' method to unlearn with self-generated data, where we prompt the model to reveal what it knows using optimized instructions. To fully utilize the self-generated forget data, we propose an iterative unlearning framework, where we make incremental adjustments to the model's weight space with parameter-efficient modules trained on the forget data. Experimental results demonstrate that our method balances the tradeoff between forget quality and utility preservation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14624v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Linxi Xie, Xin Teng, Shichang Ke, Hongyi Wen, Shengjie Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SWE-QA: Can Language Models Answer Repository-level Code Questions?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14635</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14635v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Understanding and reasoning about entire software repositories is an essential capability for intelligent software engineering tools. While existing benchmarks such as CoSQA and CodeQA have advanced the field, they predominantly focus on small, self-contained code snippets. These setups fail to capture the complexity of real-world repositories, where effective understanding and reasoning often require navigating multiple files, understanding software architecture, and grounding answers in long-range code dependencies. In this paper, we present SWE-QA, a repository-level code question answering (QA) benchmark designed to facilitate research on automated QA systems in realistic code environments. SWE-QA involves 576 high-quality question-answer pairs spanning diverse categories, including intention understanding, cross-file reasoning, and multi-hop dependency analysis. To construct SWE-QA, we first crawled 77,100 GitHub issues from 11 popular repositories. Based on an analysis of naturally occurring developer questions extracted from these issues, we developed a two-level taxonomy of repository-level questions and constructed a set of seed questions for each category. For each category, we manually curated and validated questions and collected their corresponding answers. As a prototype application, we further develop SWE-QA-Agent, an agentic framework in which LLM agents reason and act to find answers automatically. We evaluate six advanced LLMs on SWE-QA under various context augmentation strategies. Experimental results highlight the promise of LLMs, particularly our SWE-QA-Agent framework, in addressing repository-level QA, while also revealing open challenges and pointing to future research directions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14635v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.PL</category>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weihan Peng, Yuling Shi, Yuhang Wang, Xinyun Zhang, Beijun Shen, Xiaodong Gu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MUSE: MCTS-Driven Red Teaming Framework for Enhanced Multi-Turn Dialogue Safety in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14651</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14651v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: As large language models~(LLMs) become widely adopted, ensuring their alignment with human values is crucial to prevent jailbreaks where adversaries manipulate models to produce harmful content. While most defenses target single-turn attacks, real-world usage often involves multi-turn dialogues, exposing models to attacks that exploit conversational context to bypass safety measures. We introduce MUSE, a comprehensive framework tackling multi-turn jailbreaks from both attack and defense angles. For attacks, we propose MUSE-A, a method that uses frame semantics and heuristic tree search to explore diverse semantic trajectories. For defense, we present MUSE-D, a fine-grained safety alignment approach that intervenes early in dialogues to reduce vulnerabilities. Extensive experiments on various models show that MUSE effectively identifies and mitigates multi-turn vulnerabilities. Code is available at \href{https://github.com/yansiyu02/MUSE}{https://github.com/yansiyu02/MUSE}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14651v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Siyu Yan, Long Zeng, Xuecheng Wu, Chengcheng Han, Kongcheng Zhang, Chong Peng, Xuezhi Cao, Xunliang Cai, Chenjuan Guo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UMA-Split: unimodal aggregation for both English and Mandarin non-autoregressive speech recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14653</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14653v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper proposes a unimodal aggregation (UMA) based nonautoregressive model for both English and Mandarin speech recognition. The original UMA explicitly segments and aggregates acoustic frames (with unimodal weights that first monotonically increase and then decrease) of the same text token to learn better representations than regular connectionist temporal classification (CTC). However, it only works well in Mandarin. It struggles with other languages, such as English, for which a single syllable may be tokenized into multiple fine-grained tokens, or a token spans fewer than 3 acoustic frames and fails to form unimodal weights. To address this problem, we propose allowing each UMA-aggregated frame map to multiple tokens, via a simple split module that generates two tokens from each aggregated frame before computing the CTC loss.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14653v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ying Fang, Xiaofei Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TableDART: Dynamic Adaptive Multi-Modal Routing for Table Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14671</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14671v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Modeling semantic and structural information from tabular data remains a core challenge for effective table understanding. Existing Table-as-Text approaches flatten tables for large language models (LLMs), but lose crucial structural cues, while Table-as-Image methods preserve structure yet struggle with fine-grained semantics. Recent Table-as-Multimodality strategies attempt to combine textual and visual views, but they (1) statically process both modalities for every query-table pair within a large multimodal LLMs (MLLMs), inevitably introducing redundancy and even conflicts, and (2) depend on costly fine-tuning of MLLMs. In light of this, we propose TableDART, a training-efficient framework that integrates multimodal views by reusing pretrained single-modality models. TableDART introduces a lightweight 2.59M-parameter MLP gating network that dynamically selects the optimal path (either Text-only, Image-only, or Fusion) for each table-query pair, effectively reducing redundancy and conflicts from both modalities. In addition, we propose a novel agent to mediate cross-modal knowledge integration by analyzing outputs from text- and image-based models, either selecting the best result or synthesizing a new answer through reasoning. This design avoids the prohibitive costs of full MLLM fine-tuning. Extensive experiments on seven benchmarks show that TableDART establishes new state-of-the-art performance among open-source models, surpassing the strongest baseline by an average of 4.02%. The code is available at: https://anonymous.4open.science/r/TableDART-C52B</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14671v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaobo Xing, Wei Yuan, Tong Chen, Quoc Viet Hung Nguyen, Xiangliang Zhang, Hongzhi Yin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HARNESS: Lightweight Distilled Arabic Speech Foundation Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14689</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14689v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large pre-trained speech models excel in downstream tasks but their deployment is impractical for resource-limited environments. In this paper, we introduce HArnESS, the first Arabic-centric self-supervised speech model family, designed to capture Arabic speech nuances. Using iterative self-distillation, we train large bilingual HArnESS (HL) SSL models and then distill knowledge into compressed student models (HS, HST), preserving Arabic-specific representations. We use low-rank approximation to further compact the teacher's discrete supervision into shallow, thin models. We evaluate HArnESS on Arabic ASR, Speaker Emotion Recognition (SER), and Dialect Identification (DID), demonstrating effectiveness against HuBERT and XLS-R. With minimal fine-tuning, HArnESS achieves SOTA or comparable performance, making it a lightweight yet powerful alternative for real-world use. We release our distilled models and findings to support responsible research and deployment in low-resource settings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14689v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Vrunda N. sukhadia, Shammur Absar Chowdhury</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Ground Trust to Truth: Disparities in Offensive Language Judgments on Contemporary Korean Political Discourse</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14712</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14712v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Although offensive language continually evolves over time, even recent studies using LLMs have predominantly relied on outdated datasets and rarely evaluated the generalization ability on unseen texts. In this study, we constructed a large-scale dataset of contemporary political discourse and employed three refined judgments in the absence of ground truth. Each judgment reflects a representative offensive language detection method and is carefully designed for optimal conditions. We identified distinct patterns for each judgment and demonstrated tendencies of label agreement using a leave-one-out strategy. By establishing pseudo-labels as ground trust for quantitative performance assessment, we observed that a strategically designed single prompting achieves comparable performance to more resource-intensive methods. This suggests a feasible approach applicable in real-world settings with inherent constraints.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14712v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Seunguk Yu, Jungmin Yun, Jinhee Jang, Youngbin Kim</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoupled Proxy Alignment: Mitigating Language Prior Conflict for Multimodal Alignment in MLLM</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14735</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14735v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Multimodal large language models (MLLMs) have gained significant attention due to their impressive ability to integrate vision and language modalities. Recent advancements in MLLMs have primarily focused on improving performance through high-quality datasets, novel architectures, and optimized training strategies. However, in this paper, we identify a previously overlooked issue, language prior conflict, a mismatch between the inherent language priors of large language models (LLMs) and the language priors in training datasets. This conflict leads to suboptimal vision-language alignment, as MLLMs are prone to adapting to the language style of training samples. To address this issue, we propose a novel training method called Decoupled Proxy Alignment (DPA). DPA introduces two key innovations: (1) the use of a proxy LLM during pretraining to decouple the vision-language alignment process from language prior interference, and (2) dynamic loss adjustment based on visual relevance to strengthen optimization signals for visually relevant tokens. Extensive experiments demonstrate that DPA significantly mitigates the language prior conflict, achieving superior alignment performance across diverse datasets, model families, and scales. Our method not only improves the effectiveness of MLLM training but also shows exceptional generalization capabilities, making it a robust approach for vision-language alignment. Our code is available at https://github.com/fnlp-vision/DPA.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14735v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chenkun Tan, Pengyu Wang, Shaojun Zhou, Botian Jiang, Zhaowei Li, Dong Zhang, Xinghao Wang, Yaqian Zhou, Xipeng Qiu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UnifiedVisual: A Framework for Constructing Unified Vision-Language Datasets</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14738</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14738v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Unified vision large language models (VLLMs) have recently achieved impressive advancements in both multimodal understanding and generation, powering applications such as visual question answering and text-guided image synthesis. However, progress in unified VLLMs remains constrained by the lack of datasets that fully exploit the synergistic potential between these two core abilities. Existing datasets typically address understanding and generation in isolation, thereby limiting the performance of unified VLLMs. To bridge this critical gap, we introduce a novel dataset construction framework, UnifiedVisual, and present UnifiedVisual-240K, a high-quality dataset meticulously designed to facilitate mutual enhancement between multimodal understanding and generation. UnifiedVisual-240K seamlessly integrates diverse visual and textual inputs and outputs, enabling comprehensive cross-modal reasoning and precise text-to-image alignment. Our dataset encompasses a wide spectrum of tasks and data sources, ensuring rich diversity and addressing key shortcomings of prior resources. Extensive experiments demonstrate that models trained on UnifiedVisual-240K consistently achieve strong performance across a wide range of tasks. Notably, these models exhibit significant mutual reinforcement between multimodal understanding and generation, further validating the effectiveness of our framework and dataset. We believe UnifiedVisual represents a new growth point for advancing unified VLLMs and unlocking their full potential. Our code and datasets is available at https://github.com/fnlp-vision/UnifiedVisual.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14738v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Pengyu Wang, Shaojun Zhou, Chenkun Tan, Xinghao Wang, Wei Huang, Zhen Ye, Zhaowei Li, Botian Jiang, Dong Zhang, Xipeng Qiu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Large Language Models for Cross-Lingual Retrieval</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14749</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14749v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Multi-stage information retrieval (IR) has become a widely-adopted paradigm in search. While Large Language Models (LLMs) have been extensively evaluated as second-stage reranking models for monolingual IR, a systematic large-scale comparison is still lacking for cross-lingual IR (CLIR). Moreover, while prior work shows that LLM-based rerankers improve CLIR performance, their evaluation setup relies on lexical retrieval with machine translation (MT) for the first stage. This is not only prohibitively expensive but also prone to error propagation across stages. Our evaluation on passage-level and document-level CLIR reveals that further gains can be achieved with multilingual bi-encoders as first-stage retrievers and that the benefits of translation diminishes with stronger reranking models. We further show that pairwise rerankers based on instruction-tuned LLMs perform competitively with listwise rerankers. To the best of our knowledge, we are the first to study the interaction between retrievers and rerankers in two-stage CLIR with LLMs. Our findings reveal that, without MT, current state-of-the-art rerankers fall severely short when directly applied in CLIR.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14749v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Longfei Zuo, Pingjun Hong, Oliver Kraus, Barbara Plank, Robert Litschko</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KAIO: A Collection of More Challenging Korean Questions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14752</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14752v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: With the advancement of mid/post-training techniques, LLMs are pushing their boundaries at an accelerated pace. Legacy benchmarks saturate quickly (e.g., broad suites like MMLU over the years, newer ones like GPQA-D even faster), which makes frontier progress hard to track. The problem is especially acute in Korean: widely used benchmarks are fewer, often translated or narrow in scope, and updated more slowly, so saturation and contamination arrive sooner. Accordingly, at this moment, there is no Korean benchmark capable of evaluating and ranking frontier models. To bridge this gap, we introduce KAIO, a Korean, math-centric benchmark that stresses long-chain reasoning. Unlike recent Korean suites that are at or near saturation, KAIO remains far from saturated: the best-performing model, GPT-5, attains 62.8, followed by Gemini-2.5-Pro (52.3). Open models such as Qwen3-235B and DeepSeek-R1 cluster falls below 30, demonstrating substantial headroom, enabling robust tracking of frontier progress in Korean. To reduce contamination, KAIO will remain private and be served via a held-out evaluator until the best publicly known model reaches at least 80% accuracy, after which we will release the set and iterate to a harder version.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14752v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nahyun Lee, Guijin Son, Hyunwoo Ko, Kyubeen Han</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reasoning over Boundaries: Enhancing Specification Alignment via Test-time Delibration</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14760</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14760v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are increasingly applied in diverse real-world scenarios, each governed by bespoke behavioral and safety specifications (spec) custom-tailored by users or organizations. These spec, categorized into safety-spec and behavioral-spec, vary across scenarios and evolve with changing preferences and requirements. We formalize this challenge as specification alignment, focusing on LLMs' ability to follow dynamic, scenario-specific spec from both behavioral and safety perspectives. To address this challenge, we propose Align3, a lightweight method that employs Test-Time Deliberation (TTD) with hierarchical reflection and revision to reason over the specification boundaries. We further present SpecBench, a unified benchmark for measuring specification alignment, covering 5 scenarios, 103 spec, and 1,500 prompts. Experiments on 15 reasoning and 18 instruct models with several TTD methods, including Self-Refine, TPO, and MoreThink, yield three key findings: (i) test-time deliberation enhances specification alignment; (ii) Align3 advances the safety-helpfulness trade-off frontier with minimal overhead; (iii) SpecBench effectively reveals alignment gaps. These results highlight the potential of test-time deliberation as an effective strategy for reasoning over the real-world specification boundaries.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14760v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haoran Zhang, Yafu Li, Xuyang Hu, Dongrui Liu, Zhilin Wang, Bo Li, Yu Cheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SINAI at eRisk@CLEF 2023: Approaching Early Detection of Gambling with Natural Language Processing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14797</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14797v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper describes the participation of the SINAI team in the eRisk@CLEF lab. Specifically, one of the proposed tasks has been addressed: Task 2 on the early detection of signs of pathological gambling. The approach presented in Task 2 is based on pre-trained models from Transformers architecture with comprehensive preprocessing data and data balancing techniques. Moreover, we integrate Long-short Term Memory (LSTM) architecture with automodels from Transformers. In this Task, our team has been ranked in seventh position, with an F1 score of 0.126, out of 49 participant submissions and achieves the highest values in recall metrics and metrics related to early detection.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14797v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>CEUR Workshop Proceedings 2023, vol. 3497, pp. 743-751</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Alba Maria Marmol-Romero, Flor Miriam Plaza-del-Arco, Arturo Montejo-Raez</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SINAI at eRisk@CLEF 2022: Approaching Early Detection of Gambling and Eating Disorders with Natural Language Processing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14806</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14806v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper describes the participation of the SINAI team in the eRisk@CLEF lab. Specifically, two of the proposed tasks have been addressed: i) Task 1 on the early detection of signs of pathological gambling, and ii) Task 3 on measuring the severity of the signs of eating disorders. The approach presented in Task 1 is based on the use of sentence embeddings from Transformers with features related to volumetry, lexical diversity, complexity metrics, and emotion-related scores, while the approach for Task 3 is based on text similarity estimation using contextualized word embeddings from Transformers. In Task 1, our team has been ranked in second position, with an F1 score of 0.808, out of 41 participant submissions. In Task 3, our team also placed second out of a total of 3 participating teams.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14806v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>CEUR Workshop Proceedings 2022, vol. 3180, pp. 961-971</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Alba Maria Marmol-Romero, Salud Maria Jimenez-Zafra, Flor Miriam Plaza-del-Arco, M. Dolores Molina-Gonzalez, Maria-Teresa Martin-Valdivia, Arturo Montejo-Raez</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ReCoVeR the Target Language: Language Steering without Sacrificing Task Performance</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14814</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14814v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: As they become increasingly multilingual, Large Language Models (LLMs) exhibit more language confusion, i.e., they tend to generate answers in a language different from the language of the prompt or the answer language explicitly requested by the user. In this work, we propose ReCoVeR (REducing language COnfusion in VEctor Representations), a novel lightweight approach for reducing language confusion based on language-specific steering vectors. We first isolate language vectors with the help of multi-parallel corpus and then effectively leverage those vectors for effective LLM steering via fixed (i.e., unsupervised) as well as trainable steering functions. Our extensive evaluation, encompassing three benchmarks and 18 languages, shows that ReCoVeR effectively mitigates language confusion in both monolingual and cross-lingual setups while at the same time -- and in contrast to prior language steering methods -- retaining task performance. Our data code is available at https://github.com/hSterz/recover.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14814v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hannah Sterz, Fabian David Schmidt, Goran Glava\v{s}, Ivan Vuli\'c</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM Agents at the Roundtable: A Multi-Perspective and Dialectical Reasoning Framework for Essay Scoring</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14834</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14834v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The emergence of large language models (LLMs) has brought a new paradigm to automated essay scoring (AES), a long-standing and practical application of natural language processing in education. However, achieving human-level multi-perspective understanding and judgment remains a challenge. In this work, we propose Roundtable Essay Scoring (RES), a multi-agent evaluation framework designed to perform precise and human-aligned scoring under a zero-shot setting. RES constructs evaluator agents based on LLMs, each tailored to a specific prompt and topic context. Each agent independently generates a trait-based rubric and conducts a multi-perspective evaluation. Then, by simulating a roundtable-style discussion, RES consolidates individual evaluations through a dialectical reasoning process to produce a final holistic score that more closely aligns with human evaluation. By enabling collaboration and consensus among agents with diverse evaluation perspectives, RES outperforms prior zero-shot AES approaches. Experiments on the ASAP dataset using ChatGPT and Claude show that RES achieves up to a 34.86% improvement in average QWK over straightforward prompting (Vanilla) methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14834v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jinhee Jang, Ayoung Moon, Minkyoung Jung, YoungBin Kim. Seung Jin Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>V-SEAM: Visual Semantic Editing and Attention Modulating for Causal Interpretability of Vision-Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14837</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14837v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent advances in causal interpretability have extended from language models to vision-language models (VLMs), seeking to reveal their internal mechanisms through input interventions. While textual interventions often target semantics, visual interventions typically rely on coarse pixel-level perturbations, limiting semantic insights on multimodal integration. In this study, we introduce V-SEAM, a novel framework that combines Visual Semantic Editing and Attention Modulating for causal interpretation of VLMs. V-SEAM enables concept-level visual manipulations and identifies attention heads with positive or negative contributions to predictions across three semantic levels: objects, attributes, and relationships. We observe that positive heads are often shared within the same semantic level but vary across levels, while negative heads tend to generalize broadly. Finally, we introduce an automatic method to modulate key head embeddings, demonstrating enhanced performance for both LLaVA and InstructBLIP across three diverse VQA benchmarks. Our data and code are released at: https://github.com/petergit1/V-SEAM.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14837v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qidong Wang, Junjie Hu, Ming Jiang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Empathy-R1: A Chain-of-Empathy and Reinforcement Learning Framework for Long-Form Mental Health Support</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14851</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14851v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Empathy is critical for effective mental health support, especially when addressing Long Counseling Texts (LCTs). However, existing Large Language Models (LLMs) often generate replies that are semantically fluent but lack the structured reasoning necessary for genuine psychological support, particularly in a Chinese context. To bridge this gap, we introduce Empathy-R1, a novel framework that integrates a Chain-of-Empathy (CoE) reasoning process with Reinforcement Learning (RL) to enhance response quality for LCTs. Inspired by cognitive-behavioral therapy, our CoE paradigm guides the model to sequentially reason about a help-seeker's emotions, causes, and intentions, making its thinking process both transparent and interpretable. Our framework is empowered by a new large-scale Chinese dataset, Empathy-QA, and a two-stage training process. First, Supervised Fine-Tuning instills the CoE's reasoning structure. Subsequently, RL, guided by a dedicated reward model, refines the therapeutic relevance and contextual appropriateness of the final responses. Experiments show that Empathy-R1 achieves strong performance on key automatic metrics. More importantly, human evaluations confirm its superiority, showing a clear preference over strong baselines and achieving a Win@1 rate of 44.30% on our new benchmark. By enabling interpretable and contextually nuanced responses, Empathy-R1 represents a significant advancement in developing responsible and genuinely beneficial AI for mental health support.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14851v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xianrong Yao, Dong She, Chenxu Zhang, Yimeng Zhang, Yueru Sun, Noman Ahmed, Yang Gao, Zhanpeng Jin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Llama-Mimi: Speech Language Models with Interleaved Semantic and Acoustic Tokens</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14882</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14882v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We propose Llama-Mimi, a speech language model that uses a unified tokenizer and a single Transformer decoder to jointly model sequences of interleaved semantic and acoustic tokens. Comprehensive evaluation shows that Llama-Mimi achieves state-of-the-art performance in acoustic consistency and possesses the ability to preserve speaker identity. Our analysis further demonstrates that increasing the number of quantizers improves acoustic fidelity but degrades linguistic performance, highlighting the inherent challenge of maintaining long-term coherence. We additionally introduce an LLM-as-a-Judge-based evaluation to assess the spoken content quality of generated outputs. Our models, code, and speech samples are publicly available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14882v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Issa Sugiura, Shuhei Kurita, Yusuke Oda, Ryuichiro Higashinaka</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Multi-To-One Interview Paradigm for Efficient MLLM Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14886</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14886v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The rapid progress of Multi-Modal Large Language Models (MLLMs) has spurred the creation of numerous benchmarks. However, conventional full-coverage Question-Answering evaluations suffer from high redundancy and low efficiency. Inspired by human interview processes, we propose a multi-to-one interview paradigm for efficient MLLM evaluation. Our framework consists of (i) a two-stage interview strategy with pre-interview and formal interview phases, (ii) dynamic adjustment of interviewer weights to ensure fairness, and (iii) an adaptive mechanism for question difficulty-level chosen. Experiments on different benchmarks show that the proposed paradigm achieves significantly higher correlation with full-coverage results than random sampling, with improvements of up to 17.6% in PLCC and 16.7% in SRCC, while reducing the number of required questions. These findings demonstrate that the proposed paradigm provides a reliable and efficient alternative for large-scale MLLM benchmarking.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14886v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ye Shen, Junying Wang, Farong Wen, Yijin Guo, Qi Jia, Zicheng Zhang, Guangtao Zhai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FURINA: Free from Unmergeable Router via LINear Aggregation of mixed experts</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14900</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14900v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The Mixture of Experts (MoE) paradigm has been successfully integrated into Low-Rank Adaptation (LoRA) for parameter-efficient fine-tuning (PEFT), delivering performance gains with minimal parameter overhead. However, a key limitation of existing MoE-LoRA methods is their reliance on a discrete router, which prevents the integration of the MoE components into the backbone model. To overcome this, we propose FURINA, a novel Free from Unmergeable Router framework based on the LINear Aggregation of experts. FURINA eliminates the router by introducing a Self-Routing mechanism. This is achieved through three core innovations: (1) decoupled learning of the direction and magnitude for LoRA adapters, (2) a shared learnable magnitude vector for consistent activation scaling, and (3) expert selection loss that encourages divergent expert activation. The proposed mechanism leverages the angular similarity between the input and each adapter's directional component to activate experts, which are then scaled by the shared magnitude vector. This design allows the output norm to naturally reflect the importance of each expert, thereby enabling dynamic, router-free routing. The expert selection loss further sharpens this behavior by encouraging sparsity and aligning it with standard MoE activation patterns. We also introduce a shared expert within the MoE-LoRA block that provides stable, foundational knowledge. To the best of our knowledge, FURINA is the first router-free, MoE-enhanced LoRA method that can be fully merged into the backbone model, introducing zero additional inference-time cost or complexity. Extensive experiments demonstrate that FURINA not only significantly outperforms standard LoRA but also matches or surpasses the performance of existing MoE-LoRA methods, while eliminating the extra inference-time overhead of MoE.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14900v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiayi Han, Liang Du, Yinda Chen, Xiao Kang, Weiyang Ding, Donghong Han</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comparative Evaluation of Large Language Models for Persian Sentiment Analysis and Emotion Detection in Social Media Texts</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14922</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14922v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This study presents a comprehensive comparative evaluation of four state-of-the-art Large Language Models (LLMs)--Claude 3.7 Sonnet, DeepSeek-V3, Gemini 2.0 Flash, and GPT-4o--for sentiment analysis and emotion detection in Persian social media texts. Comparative analysis among LLMs has witnessed a significant rise in recent years, however, most of these analyses have been conducted on English language tasks, creating gaps in understanding cross-linguistic performance patterns. This research addresses these gaps through rigorous experimental design using balanced Persian datasets containing 900 texts for sentiment analysis (positive, negative, neutral) and 1,800 texts for emotion detection (anger, fear, happiness, hate, sadness, surprise). The main focus was to allow for a direct and fair comparison among different models, by using consistent prompts, uniform processing parameters, and by analyzing the performance metrics such as precision, recall, F1-scores, along with misclassification patterns. The results show that all models reach an acceptable level of performance, and a statistical comparison of the best three models indicates no significant differences among them. However, GPT-4o demonstrated a marginally higher raw accuracy value for both tasks, while Gemini 2.0 Flash proved to be the most cost-efficient. The findings indicate that the emotion detection task is more challenging for all models compared to the sentiment analysis task, and the misclassification patterns can represent some challenges in Persian language texts. These findings establish performance benchmarks for Persian NLP applications and offer practical guidance for model selection based on accuracy, efficiency, and cost considerations, while revealing cultural and linguistic challenges that require consideration in multilingual AI system deployment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14922v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kian Tohidi, Kia Dashtipour, Simone Rebora, Sevda Pourfaramarz</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patent Language Model Pretraining with ModernBERT</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14926</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14926v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Transformer-based language models such as BERT have become foundational in NLP, yet their performance degrades in specialized domains like patents, which contain long, technical, and legally structured text. Prior approaches to patent NLP have primarily relied on fine-tuning general-purpose models or domain-adapted variants pretrained with limited data. In this work, we pretrain 3 domain-specific masked language models for patents, using the ModernBERT architecture and a curated corpus of over 60 million patent records. Our approach incorporates architectural optimizations, including FlashAttention, rotary embeddings, and GLU feed-forward layers. We evaluate our models on four downstream patent classification tasks. Our model, ModernBERT-base-PT, consistently outperforms the general-purpose ModernBERT baseline on three out of four datasets and achieves competitive performance with a baseline PatentBERT. Additional experiments with ModernBERT-base-VX and Mosaic-BERT-large demonstrate that scaling the model size and customizing the tokenizer further enhance performance on selected tasks. Notably, all ModernBERT variants retain substantially faster inference over - 3x that of PatentBERT - underscoring their suitability for time-sensitive applications. These results underscore the benefits of domain-specific pretraining and architectural improvements for patent-focused NLP tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14926v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Amirhossein Yousefiramandi, Ciaran Cooney</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cross-Modal Knowledge Distillation for Speech Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14930</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14930v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this work, we present the first systematic evaluation of catastrophic forgetting and modality inequivalence in speech large language models, showing that introducing speech capabilities can degrade knowledge and reasoning even when inputs remain textual, and performance further decreases with spoken queries. To address these challenges, we propose a cross-modal knowledge distillation framework that leverages both text-to-text and speech-to-text channels to transfer knowledge from a text-based teacher model to a speech LLM. Extensive experiments on dialogue and audio understanding tasks validate the effectiveness of our approach in preserving textual knowledge, improving cross-modal alignment, and enhancing reasoning in speech-based interactions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14930v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Enzhi Wang, Qicheng Li, Zhiyuan Tang, Yuhang Jia</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explicit vs. Implicit Biographies: Evaluating and Adapting LLM Information Extraction on Wikidata-Derived Texts</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14943</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14943v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Text Implicitness has always been challenging in Natural Language Processing (NLP), with traditional methods relying on explicit statements to identify entities and their relationships. From the sentence "Zuhdi attends church every Sunday", the relationship between Zuhdi and Christianity is evident for a human reader, but it presents a challenge when it must be inferred automatically. Large language models (LLMs) have proven effective in NLP downstream tasks such as text comprehension and information extraction (IE).
  This study examines how textual implicitness affects IE tasks in pre-trained LLMs: LLaMA 2.3, DeepSeekV1, and Phi1.5. We generate two synthetic datasets of 10k implicit and explicit verbalization of biographic information to measure the impact on LLM performance and analyze whether fine-tuning implicit data improves their ability to generalize in implicit reasoning tasks.
  This research presents an experiment on the internal reasoning processes of LLMs in IE, particularly in dealing with implicit and explicit contexts. The results demonstrate that fine-tuning LLM models with LoRA (low-rank adaptation) improves their performance in extracting information from implicit texts, contributing to better model interpretability and reliability.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14943v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alessandra Stramiglio, Andrea Schimmenti, Valentina Pasqual, Marieke van Erp, Francesco Sovrano, Fabio Vitali</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mind the Gap: A Closer Look at Tokenization for Multiple-Choice Question Answering with LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.15020</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.15020v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: When evaluating large language models (LLMs) with multiple-choice question answering (MCQA), it is common to end the prompt with the string "Answer:" to facilitate automated answer extraction via next-token probabilities. However, there is no consensus on how to tokenize the space following the colon, often overlooked as a trivial choice. In this paper, we uncover accuracy differences of up to 11% due to this (seemingly irrelevant) tokenization variation as well as reshuffled model rankings, raising concerns about the reliability of LLM comparisons in prior work. Surprisingly, we are able to recommend one specific strategy -- tokenizing the space together with the answer letter -- as we observe consistent and statistically significant performance improvements. Additionally, it improves model calibration, enhancing the reliability of the model's confidence estimates. Our findings underscore the importance of careful evaluation design and highlight the need for standardized, transparent evaluation protocols to ensure reliable and comparable results.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.15020v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mario Sanz-Guerrero, Minh Duc Bui, Katharina von der Wense</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CLEAR: A Comprehensive Linguistic Evaluation of Argument Rewriting by Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.15027</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.15027v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: While LLMs have been extensively studied on general text generation tasks, there is less research on text rewriting, a task related to general text generation, and particularly on the behavior of models on this task. In this paper we analyze what changes LLMs make in a text rewriting setting. We focus specifically on argumentative texts and their improvement, a task named Argument Improvement (ArgImp). We present CLEAR: an evaluation pipeline consisting of 57 metrics mapped to four linguistic levels: lexical, syntactic, semantic and pragmatic. This pipeline is used to examine the qualities of LLM-rewritten arguments on a broad set of argumentation corpora and compare the behavior of different LLMs on this task and analyze the behavior of different LLMs on this task in terms of linguistic levels. By taking all four linguistic levels into consideration, we find that the models perform ArgImp by shortening the texts while simultaneously increasing average word length and merging sentences. Overall we note an increase in the persuasion and coherence dimensions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.15027v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Thomas Huber, Christina Niklaus</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Value-Guided KV Compression for LLMs via Approximated CUR Decomposition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.15038</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.15038v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Key-value (KV) cache compression has emerged as a critical technique for reducing the memory and latency overhead of autoregressive language models during inference. Prior approaches predominantly rely on query-key attention scores to rank and evict cached tokens, assuming that attention intensity correlates with semantic importance. However, this heuristic overlooks the contribution of value vectors, which directly influence the attention output. In this paper, we propose CurDKV, a novel, value-centric KV compression method that selects keys and values based on leverage scores computed from CUR matrix decomposition. Our approach approximates the dominant subspace of the attention output $softmax(QK^T)V$, ensuring that the retained tokens best preserve the model's predictive behavior. Theoretically, we show that attention score approximation does not guarantee output preservation, and demonstrate that CUR-based selection minimizes end-to-end attention reconstruction loss. Empirically, CurDKV achieves up to 9.6% higher accuracy than state-of-the-art methods like SnapKV and ChunkKV under aggressive compression budgets on LLaMA and Mistral, while maintaining compatibility with FlashAttention and Grouped Query Attention. In addition to improved accuracy, CurDKV reduces generation latency by up to 40% at high compression, offering a practical speed-accuracy tradeoff.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.15038v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ayan Sengupta, Siddhant Chaudhary, Tanmoy Chakraborty</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can maiBERT Speak for Maithili?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.15048</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.15048v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Natural Language Understanding (NLU) for low-resource languages remains a major challenge in NLP due to the scarcity of high-quality data and language-specific models. Maithili, despite being spoken by millions, lacks adequate computational resources, limiting its inclusion in digital and AI-driven applications. To address this gap, we introducemaiBERT, a BERT-based language model pre-trained specifically for Maithili using the Masked Language Modeling (MLM) technique. Our model is trained on a newly constructed Maithili corpus and evaluated through a news classification task. In our experiments, maiBERT achieved an accuracy of 87.02%, outperforming existing regional models like NepBERTa and HindiBERT, with a 0.13% overall accuracy gain and 5-7% improvement across various classes. We have open-sourced maiBERT on Hugging Face enabling further fine-tuning for downstream tasks such as sentiment analysis and Named Entity Recognition (NER).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.15048v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sumit Yadav, Raju Kumar Yadav, Utsav Maskey, Gautam Siddharth Kashyap Md Azizul Hoque, Ganesh Gautam</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM-OREF: An Open Relation Extraction Framework Based on Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.15089</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.15089v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The goal of open relation extraction (OpenRE) is to develop an RE model that can generalize to new relations not encountered during training. Existing studies primarily formulate OpenRE as a clustering task. They first cluster all test instances based on the similarity between the instances, and then manually assign a new relation to each cluster. However, their reliance on human annotation limits their practicality. In this paper, we propose an OpenRE framework based on large language models (LLMs), which directly predicts new relations for test instances by leveraging their strong language understanding and generation abilities, without human intervention. Specifically, our framework consists of two core components: (1) a relation discoverer (RD), designed to predict new relations for test instances based on \textit{demonstrations} formed by training instances with known relations; and (2) a relation predictor (RP), used to select the most likely relation for a test instance from $n$ candidate relations, guided by \textit{demonstrations} composed of their instances. To enhance the ability of our framework to predict new relations, we design a self-correcting inference strategy composed of three stages: relation discovery, relation denoising, and relation prediction. In the first stage, we use RD to preliminarily predict new relations for all test instances. Next, we apply RP to select some high-reliability test instances for each new relation from the prediction results of RD through a cross-validation method. During the third stage, we employ RP to re-predict the relations of all test instances based on the demonstrations constructed from these reliable test instances. Extensive experiments on three OpenRE datasets demonstrate the effectiveness of our framework. We release our code at https://github.com/XMUDeepLIT/LLM-OREF.git.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.15089v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hongyao Tu, Liang Zhang, Yujie Lin, Xin Lin, Haibo Zhang, Long Zhang, Jinsong Su</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TextMine: LLM-Powered Knowledge Extraction for Humanitarian Mine Action</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.15098</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.15098v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Humanitarian Mine Action has generated extensive best-practice knowledge, but much remains locked in unstructured reports. We introduce TextMine, an ontology-guided pipeline that uses Large Language Models to extract knowledge triples from HMA texts. TextMine integrates document chunking, domain-aware prompting, triple extraction, and both reference-based and LLM-as-a-Judge evaluation. We also create the first HMA ontology and a curated dataset of real-world demining reports. Experiments show ontology-aligned prompts boost extraction accuracy by 44.2%, cut hallucinations by 22.5%, and improve format conformance by 20.9% over baselines. While validated on Cambodian reports, TextMine can adapt to global demining efforts or other domains, transforming unstructured data into structured knowledge.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.15098v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chenyue Zhou, G\"urkan Solmaz, Flavio Cirillo, Kiril Gashteovski, Jonathan F\"urst</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Language Model probabilities cannot distinguish between possible and impossible language</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.15114</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.15114v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: A controversial test for Large Language Models concerns the ability to discern possible from impossible language. While some evidence attests to the models' sensitivity to what crosses the limits of grammatically impossible language, this evidence has been contested on the grounds of the soundness of the testing material. We use model-internal representations to tap directly into the way Large Language Models represent the 'grammatical-ungrammatical' distinction. In a novel benchmark, we elicit probabilities from 4 models and compute minimal-pair surprisal differences, juxtaposing probabilities assigned to grammatical sentences to probabilities assigned to (i) lower frequency grammatical sentences, (ii) ungrammatical sentences, (iii) semantically odd sentences, and (iv) pragmatically odd sentences. The prediction is that if string-probabilities can function as proxies for the limits of grammar, the ungrammatical condition will stand out among the conditions that involve linguistic violations, showing a spike in the surprisal rates. Our results do not reveal a unique surprisal signature for ungrammatical prompts, as the semantically and pragmatically odd conditions consistently show higher surprisal. We thus demonstrate that probabilities do not constitute reliable proxies for model-internal representations of syntactic knowledge. Consequently, claims about models being able to distinguish possible from impossible language need verification through a different methodology.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.15114v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Evelina Leivada, Raquel Montero, Paolo Morosi, Natalia Moskvina, Tamara Serrano, Marcel Aguilar, Fritz Guenther</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A1: Asynchronous Test-Time Scaling via Conformal Prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.15148</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.15148v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) benefit from test-time scaling, but existing methods face significant challenges, including severe synchronization overhead, memory bottlenecks, and latency, especially during speculative decoding with long reasoning chains. We introduce A1 (Asynchronous Test-Time Scaling), a statistically guaranteed adaptive inference framework that addresses these challenges. A1 refines arithmetic intensity to identify synchronization as the dominant bottleneck, proposes an online calibration strategy to enable asynchronous inference, and designs a three-stage rejection sampling pipeline that supports both sequential and parallel scaling. Through experiments on the MATH, AMC23, AIME24, and AIME25 datasets, across various draft-target model families, we demonstrate that A1 achieves a remarkable 56.7x speedup in test-time scaling and a 4.14x improvement in throughput, all while maintaining accurate rejection-rate control, reducing latency and memory overhead, and no accuracy loss compared to using target model scaling alone. These results position A1 as an efficient and principled solution for scalable LLM inference. We have released the code at https://github.com/menik1126/asynchronous-test-time-scaling.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.15148v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jing Xiong, Qiujiang Chen, Fanghua Ye, Zhongwei Wan, Chuanyang Zheng, Chenyang Zhao, Hui Shen, Alexander Hanbo Li, Chaofan Tao, Haochen Tan, Haoli Bai, Lifeng Shang, Lingpeng Kong, Ngai Wong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SMARTER: A Data-efficient Framework to Improve Toxicity Detection with Explanation via Self-augmenting Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.15174</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.15174v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: WARNING: This paper contains examples of offensive materials. Toxic content has become pervasive on social media platforms. We introduce SMARTER, a data-efficient two-stage framework for explainable content moderation using Large Language Models (LLMs). In Stage 1, we leverage LLMs' own outputs to generate synthetic explanations for both correct and incorrect labels, enabling alignment via preference optimization with minimal human supervision. In Stage 2, we refine explanation quality through cross-model training, allowing weaker models to align stylistically and semantically with stronger ones. Experiments on three benchmark tasks -- HateXplain, Latent Hate, and Implicit Hate -- demonstrate that SMARTER enables LLMs to achieve up to a 13.5% macro-F1 improvement over standard few-shot baselines while using only a fraction of the full training data. Our framework offers a scalable strategy for low-resource settings by harnessing LLMs' self-improving capabilities for both classification and explanation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.15174v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Huy Nghiem, Advik Sachdeva, Hal Daum\'e III</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fast and Fluent Diffusion Language Models via Convolutional Decoding and Rejective Fine-tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.15188</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.15188v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Autoregressive (AR) language models generate text one token at a time, which limits their inference speed. Diffusion-based language models offer a promising alternative, as they can decode multiple tokens in parallel. However, we identify a key bottleneck in current diffusion LMs: the long decoding-window problem, where tokens generated far from the input context often become irrelevant or repetitive. Previous solutions like semi-autoregressive address this issue by splitting windows into blocks, but this sacrifices speed and bidirectionality, eliminating the main advantage of diffusion models. To overcome this, we propose Convolutional decoding (Conv), a normalization-based method that narrows the decoding window without hard segmentation, leading to better fluency and flexibility. Additionally, we introduce Rejecting Rule-based Fine-Tuning (R2FT), a post-hoc training scheme that better aligns tokens at positions far from context. Our methods achieve state-of-the-art results on open-ended generation benchmarks (e.g., AlpacaEval) among diffusion LM baselines, with significantly lower step size than previous works, demonstrating both speed and quality improvements.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.15188v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yeongbin Seo, Dongha Lee, Jaehyung Kim, Jinyoung Yeo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fair-GPTQ: Bias-Aware Quantization for Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.15206</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.15206v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: High memory demands of generative language models have drawn attention to quantization, which reduces computational cost, memory usage, and latency by mapping model weights to lower-precision integers. Approaches such as GPTQ effectively minimize input-weight product errors during quantization; however, recent empirical studies show that they can increase biased outputs and degrade performance on fairness benchmarks, and it remains unclear which specific weights cause this issue. In this work, we draw new links between quantization and model fairness by adding explicit group-fairness constraints to the quantization objective and introduce Fair-GPTQ, the first quantization method explicitly designed to reduce unfairness in large language models. The added constraints guide the learning of the rounding operation toward less-biased text generation for protected groups. Specifically, we focus on stereotype generation involving occupational bias and discriminatory language spanning gender, race, and religion. Fair-GPTQ has minimal impact on performance, preserving at least 90% of baseline accuracy on zero-shot benchmarks, reduces unfairness relative to a half-precision model, and retains the memory and speed benefits of 4-bit quantization. We also compare the performance of Fair-GPTQ with existing debiasing methods and find that it achieves performance on par with the iterative null-space projection debiasing approach on racial-stereotype benchmarks. Overall, the results validate our theoretical solution to the quantization problem with a group-bias term, highlight its applicability for reducing group bias at quantization time in generative models, and demonstrate that our approach can further be used to analyze channel- and weight-level contributions to fairness during quantization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.15206v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Irina Proskurina, Guillaume Metzler, Julien Velcin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What's the Best Way to Retrieve Slides? A Comparative Study of Multimodal, Caption-Based, and Hybrid Retrieval Techniques</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.15211</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.15211v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Slide decks, serving as digital reports that bridge the gap between presentation slides and written documents, are a prevalent medium for conveying information in both academic and corporate settings. Their multimodal nature, combining text, images, and charts, presents challenges for retrieval-augmented generation systems, where the quality of retrieval directly impacts downstream performance. Traditional approaches to slide retrieval often involve separate indexing of modalities, which can increase complexity and lose contextual information. This paper investigates various methodologies for effective slide retrieval, including visual late-interaction embedding models like ColPali, the use of visual rerankers, and hybrid retrieval techniques that combine dense retrieval with BM25, further enhanced by textual rerankers and fusion methods like Reciprocal Rank Fusion. A novel Vision-Language Models-based captioning pipeline is also evaluated, demonstrating significantly reduced embedding storage requirements compared to visual late-interaction techniques, alongside comparable retrieval performance. Our analysis extends to the practical aspects of these methods, evaluating their runtime performance and storage demands alongside retrieval efficacy, thus offering practical guidance for the selection and development of efficient and robust slide retrieval systems for real-world applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.15211v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Petros Stylianos Giouroukis, Dimitris Dimitriadis, Dimitrios Papadopoulos, Zhenwen Shao, Grigorios Tsoumakas</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing Historical Structural Oppression Worldwide via Rule-Guided Prompting of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.15216</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.15216v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Traditional efforts to measure historical structural oppression struggle with cross-national validity due to the unique, locally specified histories of exclusion, colonization, and social status in each country, and often have relied on structured indices that privilege material resources while overlooking lived, identity-based exclusion. We introduce a novel framework for oppression measurement that leverages Large Language Models (LLMs) to generate context-sensitive scores of lived historical disadvantage across diverse geopolitical settings. Using unstructured self-identified ethnicity utterances from a multilingual COVID-19 global study, we design rule-guided prompting strategies that encourage models to produce interpretable, theoretically grounded estimations of oppression. We systematically evaluate these strategies across multiple state-of-the-art LLMs. Our results demonstrate that LLMs, when guided by explicit rules, can capture nuanced forms of identity-based historical oppression within nations. This approach provides a complementary measurement tool that highlights dimensions of systemic exclusion, offering a scalable, cross-cultural lens for understanding how oppression manifests in data-driven research and public health contexts. To support reproducible evaluation, we release an open-sourced benchmark dataset for assessing LLMs on oppression measurement (https://github.com/chattergpt/llm-oppression-benchmark).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.15216v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sreejato Chatterjee, Linh Tran, Quoc Duy Nguyen, Roni Kirson, Drue Hamlin, Harvest Aquino, Hanjia Lyu, Jiebo Luo, Timothy Dye</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LNE-Blocking: An Efficient Framework for Contamination Mitigation Evaluation on Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.15218</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.15218v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The problem of data contamination is now almost inevitable during the development of large language models (LLMs), with the training data commonly integrating those evaluation benchmarks even unintentionally. This problem subsequently makes it hard to benchmark LLMs fairly. Instead of constructing contamination-free datasets (quite hard), we propose a novel framework, \textbf{LNE-Blocking}, to restore model performance prior to contamination on potentially leaked datasets. Our framework consists of two components: contamination detection and disruption operation. For the prompt, the framework first uses the contamination detection method, \textbf{LNE}, to assess the extent of contamination in the model. Based on this, it adjusts the intensity of the disruption operation, \textbf{Blocking}, to elicit non-memorized responses from the model. Our framework is the first to efficiently restore the model's greedy decoding performance. This comes with a strong performance on multiple datasets with potential leakage risks, and it consistently achieves stable recovery results across different models and varying levels of data contamination. We release the code at https://github.com/RuijieH/LNE-Blocking to facilitate research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.15218v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ruijie Hou, Yueyang Jiao, Hanxu Hu, Yingming Li, Wai Lam, Huajian Zhang, Hongyuan Lu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Masked Diffusion Models as Energy Minimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.13866</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.13866v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We present a systematic theoretical framework that interprets masked diffusion models (MDMs) as solutions to energy minimization problems in discrete optimal transport. Specifically, we prove that three distinct energy formulations--kinetic, conditional kinetic, and geodesic energy--are mathematically equivalent under the structure of MDMs, and that MDMs minimize all three when the mask schedule satisfies a closed-form optimality condition. This unification not only clarifies the theoretical foundations of MDMs, but also motivates practical improvements in sampling. By parameterizing interpolation schedules via Beta distributions, we reduce the schedule design space to a tractable 2D search, enabling efficient post-training tuning without model modification. Experiments on synthetic and real-world benchmarks demonstrate that our energy-inspired schedules outperform hand-crafted baselines, particularly in low-step sampling settings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.13866v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sitong Chen, Shen Nie, Jiacheng Sun, Zijin Feng, Zhenguo Li, Ji-Rong Wen, Chongxuan Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FedMentor: Domain-Aware Differential Privacy for Heterogeneous Federated LLMs in Mental Health</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14275</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14275v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Privacy-preserving adaptation of Large Language Models (LLMs) in sensitive domains (e.g., mental health) requires balancing strict confidentiality with model utility and safety. We propose FedMentor, a federated fine-tuning framework that integrates Low-Rank Adaptation (LoRA) and domain-aware Differential Privacy (DP) to meet per-domain privacy budgets while maintaining performance. Each client (domain) applies a custom DP noise scale proportional to its data sensitivity, and the server adaptively reduces noise when utility falls below a threshold. In experiments on three mental health datasets, we show that FedMentor improves safety over standard Federated Learning without privacy, raising safe output rates by up to three points and lowering toxicity, while maintaining utility (BERTScore F1 and ROUGE-L) within 0.5% of the non-private baseline and close to the centralized upper bound. The framework scales to backbones with up to 1.7B parameters on single-GPU clients, requiring &lt; 173 MB of communication per round. FedMentor demonstrates a practical approach to privately fine-tune LLMs for safer deployments in healthcare and other sensitive fields.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14275v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nobin Sarwar, Shubhashis Roy Dipta</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Sum Leaks More Than Its Parts: Compositional Privacy Risks and Mitigations in Multi-Agent Collaboration</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14284</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14284v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: As large language models (LLMs) become integral to multi-agent systems, new privacy risks emerge that extend beyond memorization, direct inference, or single-turn evaluations. In particular, seemingly innocuous responses, when composed across interactions, can cumulatively enable adversaries to recover sensitive information, a phenomenon we term compositional privacy leakage. We present the first systematic study of such compositional privacy leaks and possible mitigation methods in multi-agent LLM systems. First, we develop a framework that models how auxiliary knowledge and agent interactions jointly amplify privacy risks, even when each response is benign in isolation. Next, to mitigate this, we propose and evaluate two defense strategies: (1) Theory-of-Mind defense (ToM), where defender agents infer a questioner's intent by anticipating how their outputs may be exploited by adversaries, and (2) Collaborative Consensus Defense (CoDef), where responder agents collaborate with peers who vote based on a shared aggregated state to restrict sensitive information spread. Crucially, we balance our evaluation across compositions that expose sensitive information and compositions that yield benign inferences. Our experiments quantify how these defense strategies differ in balancing the privacy-utility trade-off. We find that while chain-of-thought alone offers limited protection to leakage (~39% sensitive blocking rate), our ToM defense substantially improves sensitive query blocking (up to 97%) but can reduce benign task success. CoDef achieves the best balance, yielding the highest Balanced Outcome (79.8%), highlighting the benefit of combining explicit reasoning with defender collaboration. Together, our results expose a new class of risks in collaborative LLM deployments and provide actionable insights for designing safeguards against compositional, context-driven privacy leakage.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14284v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Vaidehi Patil, Elias Stengel-Eskin, Mohit Bansal</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Capabilities to Performance: Evaluating Key Functional Properties of LLM Architectures in Penetration Testing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14289</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14289v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are increasingly used to automate or augment penetration testing, but their effectiveness and reliability across attack phases remain unclear. We present a comprehensive evaluation of multiple LLM-based agents, from single-agent to modular designs, across realistic penetration testing scenarios, measuring empirical performance and recurring failure patterns. We also isolate the impact of five core functional capabilities via targeted augmentations: Global Context Memory (GCM), Inter-Agent Messaging (IAM), Context-Conditioned Invocation (CCI), Adaptive Planning (AP), and Real-Time Monitoring (RTM). These interventions support, respectively: (i) context coherence and retention, (ii) inter-component coordination and state management, (iii) tool use accuracy and selective execution, (iv) multi-step strategic planning, error detection, and recovery, and (v) real-time dynamic responsiveness. Our results show that while some architectures natively exhibit subsets of these properties, targeted augmentations substantially improve modular agent performance, especially in complex, multi-step, and real-time penetration testing tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14289v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lanxiao Huang, Daksh Dave, Ming Jin, Tyler Cody, Peter Beling</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Simple and Efficient Jailbreak Method Exploiting LLMs' Helpfulness</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14297</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14297v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Safety alignment aims to prevent Large Language Models (LLMs) from responding to harmful queries. To strengthen safety protections, jailbreak methods are developed to simulate malicious attacks and uncover vulnerabilities. In this paper, we introduce HILL (Hiding Intention by Learning from LLMs), a novel jailbreak approach that systematically transforms imperative harmful requests into learning-style questions with only straightforward hypotheticality indicators. Further, we introduce two new metrics to thoroughly evaluate the utility of jailbreak methods. Experiments on the AdvBench dataset across a wide range of models demonstrate HILL's strong effectiveness, generalizability, and harmfulness. It achieves top attack success rates on the majority of models and across malicious categories while maintaining high efficiency with concise prompts. Results of various defense methods show the robustness of HILL, with most defenses having mediocre effects or even increasing the attack success rates. Moreover, the assessment on our constructed safe prompts reveals inherent limitations of LLMs' safety mechanisms and flaws in defense methods. This work exposes significant vulnerabilities of safety measures against learning-style elicitation, highlighting a critical challenge of balancing helpfulness and safety alignments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14297v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xuan Luo, Yue Wang, Zefeng He, Geng Tu, Jing Li, Ruifeng Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Taxonomy of Prompt Defects in LLM Systems</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14404</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14404v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have become key components of modern software, with prompts acting as their de-facto programming interface. However, prompt design remains largely empirical and small mistakes can cascade into unreliable, insecure, or inefficient behavior. This paper presents the first systematic survey and taxonomy of prompt defects, recurring ways that prompts fail to elicit their intended behavior from LLMs. We organize defects along six dimensions: (1) Specification and Intent, (2) Input and Content, (3) Structure and Formatting, (4) Context and Memory, (5) Performance and Efficiency, and (6) Maintainability and Engineering. Each dimension is refined into fine-grained subtypes, illustrated with concrete examples and root cause analysis. Grounded in software engineering principles, we show how these defects surface in real development workflows and examine their downstream effects. For every subtype, we distill mitigation strategies that span emerging prompt engineering patterns, automated guardrails, testing harnesses, and evaluation frameworks. We then summarize these strategies in a master taxonomy that links defect, impact, and remedy. We conclude with open research challenges and a call for rigorous engineering-oriented methodologies to ensure that LLM-driven systems are dependable by design.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14404v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.PL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haoye Tian, Chong Wang, BoYang Yang, Lyuye Zhang, Yang Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DeKeyNLU: Enhancing Natural Language to SQL Generation through Task Decomposition and Keyword Extraction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14507</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14507v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Natural Language to SQL (NL2SQL) provides a new model-centric paradigm that simplifies database access for non-technical users by converting natural language queries into SQL commands. Recent advancements, particularly those integrating Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) and Chain-of-Thought (CoT) reasoning, have made significant strides in enhancing NL2SQL performance. However, challenges such as inaccurate task decomposition and keyword extraction by LLMs remain major bottlenecks, often leading to errors in SQL generation. While existing datasets aim to mitigate these issues by fine-tuning models, they struggle with over-fragmentation of tasks and lack of domain-specific keyword annotations, limiting their effectiveness. To address these limitations, we present DeKeyNLU, a novel dataset which contains 1,500 meticulously annotated QA pairs aimed at refining task decomposition and enhancing keyword extraction precision for the RAG pipeline. Fine-tuned with DeKeyNLU, we propose DeKeySQL, a RAG-based NL2SQL pipeline that employs three distinct modules for user question understanding, entity retrieval, and generation to improve SQL generation accuracy. We benchmarked multiple model configurations within DeKeySQL RAG pipeline. Experimental results demonstrate that fine-tuning with DeKeyNLU significantly improves SQL generation accuracy on both BIRD (62.31% to 69.10%) and Spider (84.2% to 88.7%) dev datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14507v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jian Chen, Zhenyan Chen, Xuming Hu, Peilin Zhou, Yining Hua, Han Fang, Cissy Hing Yee Choy, Xinmei Ke, Jingfeng Luo, Zixuan Yuan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM Jailbreak Detection for (Almost) Free!</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14558</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14558v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) enhance security through alignment when widely used, but remain susceptible to jailbreak attacks capable of producing inappropriate content. Jailbreak detection methods show promise in mitigating jailbreak attacks through the assistance of other models or multiple model inferences. However, existing methods entail significant computational costs. In this paper, we first present a finding that the difference in output distributions between jailbreak and benign prompts can be employed for detecting jailbreak prompts. Based on this finding, we propose a Free Jailbreak Detection (FJD) which prepends an affirmative instruction to the input and scales the logits by temperature to further distinguish between jailbreak and benign prompts through the confidence of the first token. Furthermore, we enhance the detection performance of FJD through the integration of virtual instruction learning. Extensive experiments on aligned LLMs show that our FJD can effectively detect jailbreak prompts with almost no additional computational costs during LLM inference.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14558v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Guorui Chen, Yifan Xia, Xiaojun Jia, Zhijiang Li, Philip Torr, Jindong Gu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Human-like Multimodal Conversational Agent by Generating Engaging Speech</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14627</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14627v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Human conversation involves language, speech, and visual cues, with each medium providing complementary information. For instance, speech conveys a vibe or tone not fully captured by text alone. While multimodal LLMs focus on generating text responses from diverse inputs, less attention has been paid to generating natural and engaging speech. We propose a human-like agent that generates speech responses based on conversation mood and responsive style information. To achieve this, we build a novel MultiSensory Conversation dataset focused on speech to enable agents to generate natural speech. We then propose a multimodal LLM-based model for generating text responses and voice descriptions, which are used to generate speech covering paralinguistic information. Experimental results demonstrate the effectiveness of utilizing both visual and audio modalities in conversation to generate engaging speech. The source code is available in https://github.com/kimtaesu24/MSenC</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14627v1</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.21437/Interspeech.2025-1075</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Taesoo Kim, Yongsik Jo, Hyunmin Song, Taehwan Kim</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AgentCompass: Towards Reliable Evaluation of Agentic Workflows in Production</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14647</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14647v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: With the growing adoption of Large Language Models (LLMs) in automating complex, multi-agent workflows, organizations face mounting risks from errors, emergent behaviors, and systemic failures that current evaluation methods fail to capture. We present AgentCompass, the first evaluation framework designed specifically for post-deployment monitoring and debugging of agentic workflows. AgentCompass models the reasoning process of expert debuggers through a structured, multi-stage analytical pipeline: error identification and categorization, thematic clustering, quantitative scoring, and strategic summarization. The framework is further enhanced with a dual memory system-episodic and semantic-that enables continual learning across executions. Through collaborations with design partners, we demonstrate the framework's practical utility on real-world deployments, before establishing its efficacy against the publicly available TRAIL benchmark. AgentCompass achieves state-of-the-art results on key metrics, while uncovering critical issues missed in human annotations, underscoring its role as a robust, developer-centric tool for reliable monitoring and improvement of agentic systems in production.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14647v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>NVJK Kartik, Garvit Sapra, Rishav Hada, Nikhil Pareek</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Thinking Process of Reasoning Models: A Perspective from Schoenfeld's Episode Theory</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14662</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14662v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: While Large Reasoning Models (LRMs) generate extensive chain-of-thought reasoning, we lack a principled framework for understanding how these thoughts are structured. In this paper, we introduce a novel approach by applying Schoenfeld's Episode Theory, a classic cognitive framework for human mathematical problem-solving, to analyze the reasoning traces of LRMs. We annotated thousands of sentences and paragraphs from model-generated solutions to math problems using seven cognitive labels (e.g., Plan, Implement, Verify). The result is the first publicly available benchmark for the fine-grained analysis of machine reasoning, including a large annotated corpus and detailed annotation guidebooks. Our preliminary analysis reveals distinct patterns in LRM reasoning, such as the transition dynamics between cognitive states. This framework provides a theoretically grounded methodology for interpreting LRM cognition and enables future work on more controllable and transparent reasoning systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14662v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ming Li, Nan Zhang, Chenrui Fan, Hong Jiao, Yanbin Fu, Sydney Peters, Qingshu Xu, Robert Lissitz, Tianyi Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spatial Audio Motion Understanding and Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14666</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14666v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Spatial audio reasoning enables machines to interpret auditory scenes by understanding events and their spatial attributes. In this work, we focus on spatial audio understanding with an emphasis on reasoning about moving sources. First, we introduce a spatial audio encoder that processes spatial audio to detect multiple overlapping events and estimate their spatial attributes, Direction of Arrival (DoA) and source distance, at the frame level. To generalize to unseen events, we incorporate an audio grounding model that aligns audio features with semantic audio class text embeddings via a cross-attention mechanism. Second, to answer complex queries about dynamic audio scenes involving moving sources, we condition a large language model (LLM) on structured spatial attributes extracted by our model. Finally, we introduce a spatial audio motion understanding and reasoning benchmark dataset and demonstrate our framework's performance against the baseline model.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14666v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Arvind Krishna Sridhar, Yinyi Guo, Erik Visser</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ToolSample: Dual Dynamic Sampling Methods with Curriculum Learning for RL-based Tool Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14718</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14718v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: While reinforcement learning (RL) is increasingly used for LLM-based tool learning, its efficiency is often hampered by an overabundance of simple samples that provide diminishing learning value as training progresses. Existing dynamic sampling techniques are ill-suited for the multi-task structure and fine-grained reward mechanisms inherent to tool learning. This paper introduces Dynamic Sampling with Curriculum Learning (DSCL), a framework specifically designed to address this challenge by targeting the unique characteristics of tool learning: its multiple interdependent sub-tasks and multi-valued reward functions. DSCL features two core components: Reward-Based Dynamic Sampling, which uses multi-dimensional reward statistics (mean and variance) to prioritize valuable data, and Task-Based Dynamic Curriculum Learning, which adaptively focuses training on less-mastered sub-tasks. Through extensive experiments, we demonstrate that DSCL significantly improves training efficiency and model performance over strong baselines, achieving a 3.29\% improvement on the BFCLv3 benchmark. Our method provides a tailored solution that effectively leverages the complex reward signals and sub-task dynamics within tool learning to achieve superior results.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14718v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zihao Feng, Xiaoxue Wang, Bowen Wu, Hailong Cao, Tiejun Zhao, Qun Yu, Baoxun Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frame Sampling Strategies Matter: A Benchmark for small vision language models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14769</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14769v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Comparing vision language models on videos is particularly complex, as the performances is jointly determined by the model's visual representation capacity and the frame-sampling strategy used to construct the input. Current video benchmarks are suspected to suffer from substantial frame-sampling bias, as models are evaluated with different frame selection strategies. In this work, we propose the first frame-accurate benchmark of state-of-the-art small VLMs for video question-answering, evaluated under controlled frame-sampling strategies. Our results confirm the suspected bias and highlight both data-specific and task-specific behaviors of SVLMs under different frame-sampling techniques. By open-sourcing our benchmarking code, we provide the community with a reproducible and unbiased protocol for evaluating video VLMs and emphasize the need for standardized frame-sampling strategies tailored to each benchmarking dataset in future research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14769v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Marija Brkic, Anas Filali Razzouki, Yannis Tevissen, Khalil Guetari, Mounim A. El Yacoubi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MARIC: Multi-Agent Reasoning for Image Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14860</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14860v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Image classification has traditionally relied on parameter-intensive model training, requiring large-scale annotated datasets and extensive fine tuning to achieve competitive performance. While recent vision language models (VLMs) alleviate some of these constraints, they remain limited by their reliance on single pass representations, often failing to capture complementary aspects of visual content. In this paper, we introduce Multi Agent based Reasoning for Image Classification (MARIC), a multi agent framework that reformulates image classification as a collaborative reasoning process. MARIC first utilizes an Outliner Agent to analyze the global theme of the image and generate targeted prompts. Based on these prompts, three Aspect Agents extract fine grained descriptions along distinct visual dimensions. Finally, a Reasoning Agent synthesizes these complementary outputs through integrated reflection step, producing a unified representation for classification. By explicitly decomposing the task into multiple perspectives and encouraging reflective synthesis, MARIC mitigates the shortcomings of both parameter-heavy training and monolithic VLM reasoning. Experiments on 4 diverse image classification benchmark datasets demonstrate that MARIC significantly outperforms baselines, highlighting the effectiveness of multi-agent visual reasoning for robust and interpretable image classification.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14860v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wonduk Seo, Minhyeong Yu, Hyunjin An, Seunghyun Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SynParaSpeech: Automated Synthesis of Paralinguistic Datasets for Speech Generation and Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14946</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14946v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Paralinguistic sounds, like laughter and sighs, are crucial for synthesizing more realistic and engaging speech. However, existing methods typically depend on proprietary datasets, while publicly available resources often suffer from incomplete speech, inaccurate or missing timestamps, and limited real-world relevance. To address these problems, we propose an automated framework for generating large-scale paralinguistic data and apply it to construct the SynParaSpeech dataset. The dataset comprises 6 paralinguistic categories with 118.75 hours of data and precise timestamps, all derived from natural conversational speech. Our contributions lie in introducing the first automated method for constructing large-scale paralinguistic datasets and releasing the SynParaSpeech corpus, which advances speech generation through more natural paralinguistic synthesis and enhances speech understanding by improving paralinguistic event detection. The dataset and audio samples are available at https://github.com/ShawnPi233/SynParaSpeech.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14946v1</guid>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bingsong Bai, Qihang Lu, Wenbing Yang, Zihan Sun, YueRan Hou, Peilei Jia, Songbai Pu, Ruibo Fu, Yingming Gao, Ya Li, Jun Gao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TDRM: Smooth Reward Models with Temporal Difference for LLM RL and Inference</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.15110</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.15110v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Reward models are central to both reinforcement learning (RL) with language models and inference-time verification. However, existing reward models often lack temporal consistency, leading to ineffective policy updates and unstable RL training. We introduce TDRM, a method for learning smoother and more reliable reward models by minimizing temporal differences during training. This temporal-difference (TD) regularization produces smooth rewards and improves alignment with long-term objectives. Incorporating TDRM into the actor-critic style online RL loop yields consistent empirical gains. It is worth noting that TDRM is a supplement to verifiable reward methods, and both can be used in series. Experiments show that TD-trained process reward models (PRMs) improve performance across Best-of-N (up to 6.6%) and tree-search (up to 23.7%) settings. When combined with Reinforcement Learning with Verifiable Rewards (RLVR), TD-trained PRMs lead to more data-efficient RL -- achieving comparable performance with just 2.5k data to what baseline methods require 50.1k data to attain -- and yield higher-quality language model policies on 8 model variants (5 series), e.g., Qwen2.5-(0.5B, 1,5B), GLM4-9B-0414, GLM-Z1-9B-0414, Qwen2.5-Math-(1.5B, 7B), and DeepSeek-R1-Distill-Qwen-(1.5B, 7B). We release all code at https://github.com/THUDM/TDRM.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.15110v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dan Zhang, Min Cai, Jonathan Li, Ziniu Hu, Yisong Yue, Yuxiao Dong, Jie Tang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FCPE: A Fast Context-based Pitch Estimation Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.15140</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.15140v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Pitch estimation (PE) in monophonic audio is crucial for MIDI transcription and singing voice conversion (SVC), but existing methods suffer significant performance degradation under noise. In this paper, we propose FCPE, a fast context-based pitch estimation model that employs a Lynx-Net architecture with depth-wise separable convolutions to effectively capture mel spectrogram features while maintaining low computational cost and robust noise tolerance. Experiments show that our method achieves 96.79\% Raw Pitch Accuracy (RPA) on the MIR-1K dataset, on par with the state-of-the-art methods. The Real-Time Factor (RTF) is 0.0062 on a single RTX 4090 GPU, which significantly outperforms existing algorithms in efficiency. Code is available at https://github.com/CNChTu/FCPE.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.15140v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuxin Luo, Ruoyi Zhang, Lu-Chuan Liu, Tianyu Li, Hangyu Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mind the Gap: Data Rewriting for Stable Off-Policy Supervised Fine-Tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.15157</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.15157v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Supervised fine-tuning (SFT) of large language models can be viewed as an off-policy learning problem, where expert demonstrations come from a fixed behavior policy while training aims to optimize a target policy. Importance sampling is the standard tool for correcting this distribution mismatch, but large policy gaps lead to high variance and training instability. Existing approaches mitigate this issue using KL penalties or clipping, which passively constrain updates rather than actively reducing the gap. We propose a simple yet effective data rewriting framework that proactively shrinks the policy gap by keeping correct solutions as on-policy data and rewriting incorrect ones with guided re-solving, falling back to expert demonstrations only when needed. This aligns the training distribution with the target policy before optimization, reducing importance sampling variance and stabilizing off-policy fine-tuning. Experiments on five mathematical reasoning benchmarks demonstrate consistent and significant gains over both vanilla SFT and the state-of-the-art Dynamic Fine-Tuning (DFT) approach. The data and code will be released at https://github.com/NKU-HLT/Off-Policy-SFT.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.15157v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shiwan Zhao, Xuyang Zhao, Jiaming Zhou, Aobo Kong, Qicheng Li, Yong Qin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AIP: Subverting Retrieval-Augmented Generation via Adversarial Instructional Prompt</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.15159</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.15159v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) enhances large language models (LLMs) by retrieving relevant documents from external sources to improve factual accuracy and verifiability. However, this reliance introduces new attack surfaces within the retrieval pipeline, beyond the LLM itself. While prior RAG attacks have exposed such vulnerabilities, they largely rely on manipulating user queries, which is often infeasible in practice due to fixed or protected user inputs. This narrow focus overlooks a more realistic and stealthy vector: instructional prompts, which are widely reused, publicly shared, and rarely audited. Their implicit trust makes them a compelling target for adversaries to manipulate RAG behavior covertly.
  We introduce a novel attack for Adversarial Instructional Prompt (AIP) that exploits adversarial instructional prompts to manipulate RAG outputs by subtly altering retrieval behavior. By shifting the attack surface to the instructional prompts, AIP reveals how trusted yet seemingly benign interface components can be weaponized to degrade system integrity. The attack is crafted to achieve three goals: (1) naturalness, to evade user detection; (2) utility, to encourage use of prompts; and (3) robustness, to remain effective across diverse query variations. We propose a diverse query generation strategy that simulates realistic linguistic variation in user queries, enabling the discovery of prompts that generalize across paraphrases and rephrasings. Building on this, a genetic algorithm-based joint optimization is developed to evolve adversarial prompts by balancing attack success, clean-task utility, and stealthiness. Experimental results show that AIP achieves up to 95.23% ASR while preserving benign functionality. These findings uncover a critical and previously overlooked vulnerability in RAG systems, emphasizing the need to reassess the shared instructional prompts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.15159v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Saket S. Chaturvedi, Gaurav Bagwe, Lan Zhang, Xiaoyong Yuan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Evaluation-Centric Paradigm for Scientific Visualization Agents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.15160</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.15160v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recent advances in multi-modal large language models (MLLMs) have enabled increasingly sophisticated autonomous visualization agents capable of translating user intentions into data visualizations. However, measuring progress and comparing different agents remains challenging, particularly in scientific visualization (SciVis), due to the absence of comprehensive, large-scale benchmarks for evaluating real-world capabilities. This position paper examines the various types of evaluation required for SciVis agents, outlines the associated challenges, provides a simple proof-of-concept evaluation example, and discusses how evaluation benchmarks can facilitate agent self-improvement. We advocate for a broader collaboration to develop a SciVis agentic evaluation benchmark that would not only assess existing capabilities but also drive innovation and stimulate future development in the field.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.15160v1</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>1st Workshop on GenAI, Agents, and the Future of VIS (IEEE VIS Conference 2025)</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Kuangshi Ai, Haichao Miao, Zhimin Li, Chaoli Wang, Shusen Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolving Language Models without Labels: Majority Drives Selection, Novelty Promotes Variation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.15194</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.15194v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are increasingly trained with reinforcement learning from verifiable rewards (RLVR), yet real-world deployment demands models that can self-improve without labels or external judges. Existing label-free methods, confidence minimization, self-consistency, or majority-vote objectives, stabilize learning but steadily shrink exploration, causing an entropy collapse: generations become shorter, less diverse, and brittle. Unlike prior approaches such as Test-Time Reinforcement Learning (TTRL), which primarily adapt models to the immediate unlabeled dataset at hand, our goal is broader: to enable general improvements without sacrificing the model's inherent exploration capacity and generalization ability, i.e., evolving. We formalize this issue and propose EVolution-Oriented and Label-free Reinforcement Learning (EVOL-RL), a simple rule that couples stability with variation under a label-free setting. EVOL-RL keeps the majority-voted answer as a stable anchor (selection) while adding a novelty-aware reward that favors responses whose reasoning differs from what has already been produced (variation), measured in semantic space. Implemented with GRPO, EVOL-RL also uses asymmetric clipping to preserve strong signals and an entropy regularizer to sustain search. This majority-for-selection + novelty-for-variation design prevents collapse, maintains longer and more informative chains of thought, and improves both pass@1 and pass@n. EVOL-RL consistently outperforms the majority-only TTRL baseline; e.g., training on label-free AIME24 lifts Qwen3-4B-Base AIME25 pass@1 from TTRL's 4.6% to 16.4%, and pass@16 from 18.5% to 37.9%. EVOL-RL not only prevents diversity collapse but also unlocks stronger generalization across domains (e.g., GPQA). Furthermore, we demonstrate that EVOL-RL also boosts performance in the RLVR setting, highlighting its broad applicability.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.15194v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yujun Zhou, Zhenwen Liang, Haolin Liu, Wenhao Yu, Kishan Panaganti, Linfeng Song, Dian Yu, Xiangliang Zhang, Haitao Mi, Dong Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FlowRL: Matching Reward Distributions for LLM Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.15207</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.15207v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We propose FlowRL: matching the full reward distribution via flow balancing instead of maximizing rewards in large language model (LLM) reinforcement learning (RL). Recent advanced reasoning models adopt reward-maximizing methods (\eg, PPO and GRPO), which tend to over-optimize dominant reward signals while neglecting less frequent but valid reasoning paths, thus reducing diversity. In contrast, we transform scalar rewards into a normalized target distribution using a learnable partition function, and then minimize the reverse KL divergence between the policy and the target distribution. We implement this idea as a flow-balanced optimization method that promotes diverse exploration and generalizable reasoning trajectories. We conduct experiments on math and code reasoning tasks: FlowRL achieves a significant average improvement of $10.0\%$ over GRPO and $5.1\%$ over PPO on math benchmarks, and performs consistently better on code reasoning tasks. These results highlight reward distribution-matching as a key step toward efficient exploration and diverse reasoning in LLM reinforcement learning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.15207v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xuekai Zhu, Daixuan Cheng, Dinghuai Zhang, Hengli Li, Kaiyan Zhang, Che Jiang, Youbang Sun, Ermo Hua, Yuxin Zuo, Xingtai Lv, Qizheng Zhang, Lin Chen, Fanghao Shao, Bo Xue, Yunchong Song, Zhenjie Yang, Ganqu Cui, Ning Ding, Jianfeng Gao, Xiaodong Liu, Bowen Zhou, Hongyuan Mei, Zhouhan Lin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fast Multipole Attention: A Scalable Multilevel Attention Mechanism for Text and Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.11960</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.11960v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: While Transformer networks benefit from a global receptive field, their quadratic cost relative to sequence length restricts their application to long sequences and high-resolution inputs. We introduce Fast Multipole Attention (FMA), a divide-and-conquer mechanism for self-attention inspired by the Fast Multipole Method from n-body physics. FMA reduces the time and memory complexity of self-attention from $\mathcal{O}\left(n^2\right)$ to $\mathcal{O}(n \log n)$ and $\mathcal{O}(n)$ while preserving full-context interactions.
  FMA contains a learned hierarchy with $\mathcal{O}(\log n)$ levels of resolution. In this hierarchy, nearby tokens interact at full resolution, while distant tokens engage through progressively coarser, learned basis functions. We have developed both 1D and 2D implementations of FMA for language and vision tasks, respectively. On autoregressive and bidirectional language modeling benchmarks, the 1D variant either matches or outperforms leading efficient attention baselines with substantially lower memory use. With linear complexity, the 2D variant demonstrates superior performance over strong vision transformer baselines in classification and semantic segmentation tasks.
  Our results confirm that the multilevel attention implemented by FMA allows Transformer-based models to scale to much longer sequences and higher-resolution inputs without loss in accuracy. This provides a principled, physics-inspired approach for developing scalable neural networks suitable for language, vision, and multimodal tasks. Our code will be available at https://github.com/epoch98/FMA.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.11960v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yanming Kang, Giang Tran, Hans De Sterck</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Storytelling: Multi-Agent Generative AI for Dynamic Multimodal Narratives</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.11261</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.11261v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper introduces the concept of an education tool that utilizes Generative Artificial Intelligence (GenAI) to enhance storytelling. We evaluate GenAI-driven narrative co-creation, text-to-speech conversion, text-to-music and text-to-video generation to produce an engaging experience for learners. We describe the co-creation process, the adaptation of narratives into spoken words using text-to-speech models, and the transformation of these narratives into contextually relevant visuals through text-to-video technology. Our evaluation covers the linguistics of the generated stories, the text-to-speech conversion quality, and the accuracy of the generated visuals.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.11261v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Samee Arif, Taimoor Arif, Muhammad Saad Haroon, Aamina Jamal Khan, Agha Ali Raza, Awais Athar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FG-PRM: Fine-grained Hallucination Detection and Mitigation in Language Model Mathematical Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.06304</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.06304v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Hallucinations in large language models (LLMs) pose significant challenges in tasks requiring complex multi-step reasoning, such as mathematical problem-solving. Existing approaches primarily detect the presence of hallucinations but lack a nuanced understanding of their types and manifestations. In this paper, we first introduce a comprehensive taxonomy that categorizes the common hallucinations in mathematical reasoning tasks into six types. We then propose FG-PRM (Fine-Grained Process Reward Model), an augmented model designed to detect and mitigate hallucinations in a fine-grained, step-level manner. To address the limitations of manually labeling training data, we propose an automated method for generating fine-grained hallucination data using LLMs. Our FG-PRM demonstrates superior performance across two key tasks: 1) Fine-grained hallucination detection: classifying hallucination types for each reasoning step; and 2) Verification: ranking multiple LLM-generated outputs to select the most accurate solution. Our experiments show that FG-PRM excels in fine-grained hallucination detection and substantially boosts the performance of LLMs on GSM8K and MATH benchmarks. These results highlight the benefits of fine-grained supervision in enhancing the reliability and interpretability of LLM reasoning processes.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.06304v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ruosen Li, Ziming Luo, Xinya Du</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking Legal Knowledge: A Multilingual Dataset for Judicial Summarization in Switzerland</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.13456</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.13456v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Legal research depends on headnotes: concise summaries that help lawyers quickly identify relevant cases. Yet, many court decisions lack them due to the high cost of manual annotation. To address this gap, we introduce the Swiss Landmark Decisions Summarization (SLDS) dataset containing 20K rulings from the Swiss Federal Supreme Court, each with headnotes in German, French, and Italian. SLDS has the potential to significantly improve access to legal information and transform legal research in Switzerland. We fine-tune open models (Qwen2.5, Llama 3.2, Phi-3.5) and compare them to larger general-purpose and reasoning-tuned LLMs, including GPT-4o, Claude 3.5 Sonnet, and the open-source DeepSeek R1. Using an LLM-as-a-Judge framework, we find that fine-tuned models perform well in terms of lexical similarity, while larger models generate more legally accurate and coherent summaries. Interestingly, reasoning-focused models show no consistent benefit, suggesting that factual precision is more important than deep reasoning in this task. We release SLDS under a CC BY 4.0 license to support future research in cross-lingual legal summarization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.13456v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Luca Rolshoven, Vishvaksenan Rasiah, Srinanda Br\"ugger Bose, Sarah Hostettler, Lara Burkhalter, Matthias St\"urmer, Joel Niklaus</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RAcQUEt: Unveiling the Dangers of Overlooked Referential Ambiguity in Visual LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.13835</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.13835v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Ambiguity resolution is key to effective communication. While humans effortlessly address ambiguity through conversational grounding strategies, the extent to which current language models can emulate these strategies remains unclear. In this work, we examine referential ambiguity in image-based question answering by introducing RACQUET, a carefully curated dataset targeting distinct aspects of ambiguity. Through a series of evaluations, we reveal significant limitations and problems of overconfidence of state-of-the-art large multimodal language models in addressing ambiguity in their responses. The overconfidence issue becomes particularly relevant for RACQUET-BIAS, a subset designed to analyze a critical yet underexplored problem: failing to address ambiguity leads to stereotypical, socially biased responses. Our results underscore the urgency of equipping models with robust strategies to deal with uncertainty without resorting to undesirable stereotypes.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.13835v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alberto Testoni, Barbara Plank, Raquel Fern\'andez</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mind the Inclusivity Gap: Multilingual Gender-Neutral Translation Evaluation with mGeNTE</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.09409</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.09409v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Avoiding the propagation of undue (binary) gender inferences and default masculine language remains a key challenge towards inclusive multilingual technologies, particularly when translating into languages with extensive gendered morphology. Gender-neutral translation (GNT) represents a linguistic strategy towards fairer communication across languages. However, research on GNT is limited to a few resources and language pairs. To address this gap, we introduce mGeNTE, an expert-curated resource, and use it to conduct the first systematic multilingual evaluation of inclusive translation with state-of-the-art instruction-following language models (LMs). Experiments on en-es/de/it/el reveal that while models can recognize when neutrality is appropriate, they cannot consistently produce neutral translations, limiting their usability. To probe this behavior, we enrich our evaluation with interpretability analyses that identify task-relevant features and offer initial insights into the internal dynamics of LM-based GNT.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.09409v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Beatrice Savoldi, Giuseppe Attanasio, Eleonora Cupin, Eleni Gkovedarou, Jani\c{c}a Hackenbuchner, Anne Lauscher, Matteo Negri, Andrea Piergentili, Manjinder Thind, Luisa Bentivogli</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Examining False Positives under Inference Scaling for Mathematical Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.06217</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.06217v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advancements in language models have led to significant improvements in mathematical reasoning across various benchmarks. However, most of these benchmarks rely on automatic evaluation methods that only compare final answers using heuristics, without verifying the underlying reasoning steps. This limitation results in false positive solutions, where models may produce correct final answers but with flawed deduction paths. In this paper, we systematically examine the prevalence of false positive solutions in mathematical problem solving for language models. We analyze the characteristics and extent of this issue across different open-source models, datasets of varying difficulty levels, and decoding strategies. Specifically, we explore how false positives influence the inference time scaling behavior of language models. Our experimental results reveal that: (1) false positive solutions persist across different models, datasets, and decoding methods, (2) sampling-based inference time scaling methods do not alleviate the problem, and (3) the pass@N evaluation metric is more susceptible to false positives, suggesting a significantly lower scaling ceiling than what automatic evaluations indicate. Additionally, we analyze specific instances of false positives and discuss potential limitations in self-improvement techniques and synthetic data generation under such conditions. Our data and code are publicly available at https://github.com/Wloner0809/False-Positives-in-Math.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.06217v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yu Wang, Nan Yang, Liang Wang, Furu Wei, Fuli Feng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linguistic Generalizations are not Rules: Impacts on Evaluation of LMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.13195</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.13195v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Linguistic evaluations of how well LMs generalize to produce or understand language often implicitly take for granted that natural languages are generated by symbolic rules. According to this perspective, grammaticality is determined by whether sentences obey such rules. Interpretation is compositionally generated by syntactic rules operating on meaningful words. Semantic parsing maps sentences into formal logic. Failures of LMs to obey strict rules are presumed to reveal that LMs do not produce or understand language like humans. Here we suggest that LMs' failures to obey symbolic rules may be a feature rather than a bug, because natural languages are not based on neatly separable, compositional rules. Rather, new utterances are produced and understood by a combination of flexible, interrelated, and context-dependent constructions. Considering gradient factors such as frequencies, context, and function will help us reimagine new benchmarks and analyses to probe whether and how LMs capture the rich, flexible generalizations that comprise natural languages.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.13195v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Leonie Weissweiler, Kyle Mahowald, Adele Goldberg</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SNaRe: Domain-aware Data Generation for Low-Resource Event Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.17394</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.17394v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Event Detection (ED) -- the task of identifying event mentions from natural language text -- is critical for enabling reasoning in highly specialized domains such as biomedicine, law, and epidemiology. Data generation has proven to be effective in broadening its utility to wider applications without requiring expensive expert annotations. However, when existing generation approaches are applied to specialized domains, they struggle with label noise, where annotations are incorrect, and domain drift, characterized by a distributional mismatch between generated sentences and the target domain. To address these issues, we introduce SNaRe, a domain-aware synthetic data generation framework composed of three components: Scout, Narrator, and Refiner. Scout extracts triggers from unlabeled target domain data and curates a high-quality domain-specific trigger list using corpus-level statistics to mitigate domain drift. Narrator, conditioned on these triggers, generates high-quality domain-aligned sentences, and Refiner identifies additional event mentions, ensuring high annotation quality. Experimentation on three diverse domain ED datasets reveals how SNaRe outperforms the best baseline, achieving average F1 gains of 3-7% in the zero-shot/few-shot settings and 4-20% F1 improvement for multilingual generation. Analyzing the generated trigger hit rate and human evaluation substantiates SNaRe's stronger annotation quality and reduced domain drift.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.17394v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tanmay Parekh, Yuxuan Dong, Lucas Bandarkar, Artin Kim, I-Hung Hsu, Kai-Wei Chang, Nanyun Peng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single- vs. Dual-Prompt Dialogue Generation with LLMs for Job Interviews in Human Resources</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.18650</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.18650v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Optimizing language models for use in conversational agents requires large quantities of example dialogues. Increasingly, these dialogues are synthetically generated by using powerful large language models (LLMs), especially in domains where obtaining authentic human data is challenging. One such domain is human resources (HR). In this context, we compare two LLM-based dialogue generation methods for producing HR job interviews, and assess which method generates higher-quality dialogues, i.e., those more difficult to distinguish from genuine human discourse. The first method uses a single prompt to generate the complete interview dialogue. The second method uses two agents that converse with each other. To evaluate dialogue quality under each method, we ask a judge LLM to determine whether AI was used for interview generation, using pairwise interview comparisons. We empirically find that, at the expense of a sixfold increase in token count, interviews generated with the dual-prompt method achieve a win rate 2 to 10 times higher than those generated with the single-prompt method. This difference remains consistent regardless of whether GPT-4o or Llama 3.3 70B is used for either interview generation or quality judging.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.18650v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Proceedings of the Fourth Workshop on Generation, Evaluation and Metrics (GEM^2), pages 947-957, Vienna, Austria and virtual meeting, August 2025. Association for Computational Linguistics</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Joachim De Baer, A. Seza Do\u{g}ru\"oz, Thomas Demeester, Chris Develder</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unsupervised Concept Vector Extraction for Bias Control in LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.19721</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.19721v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are known to perpetuate stereotypes and exhibit biases. Various strategies have been proposed to mitigate these biases, but most work studies biases as a black-box problem without considering how concepts are represented within the model. We adapt techniques from representation engineering to study how the concept of "gender" is represented within LLMs. We introduce a new method that extracts concept representations via probability weighting without labeled data and efficiently selects a steering vector for measuring and manipulating the model's representation. We develop a projection-based method that enables precise steering of model predictions and demonstrate its effectiveness in mitigating gender bias in LLMs and show that it also generalizes to racial bias. Our code is available at: https://github.com/hannahxchen/gender-bias-steering</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.19721v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hannah Cyberey, Yangfeng Ji, David Evans</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation and Facilitation of Online Discussions in the LLM Era: A Survey</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.01513</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.01513v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We present a survey of methods for assessing and enhancing the quality of online discussions, focusing on the potential of LLMs. While online discourses aim, at least in theory, to foster mutual understanding, they often devolve into harmful exchanges, such as hate speech, threatening social cohesion and democratic values. Recent advancements in LLMs enable artificial facilitation agents to not only moderate content, but also actively improve the quality of interactions. Our survey synthesizes ideas from NLP and Social Sciences to provide (a) a new taxonomy on discussion quality evaluation, (b) an overview of intervention and facilitation strategies, (c) along with a new taxonomy of conversation facilitation datasets, (d) an LLM-oriented roadmap of good practices and future research directions, from technological and societal perspectives.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.01513v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Katerina Korre, Dimitris Tsirmpas, Nikos Gkoumas, Emma Cabal\'e, Danai Myrtzani, Theodoros Evgeniou, Ion Androutsopoulos, John Pavlopoulos</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CARE: Multilingual Human Preference Learning for Cultural Awareness</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.05154</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.05154v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Language Models (LMs) are typically tuned with human preferences to produce helpful responses, but the impact of preference tuning on the ability to handle culturally diverse queries remains understudied. In this paper, we systematically analyze how native human cultural preferences can be incorporated into the preference learning process to train more culturally aware LMs. We introduce \textbf{CARE}, a multilingual resource containing 3,490 culturally specific questions and 31.7k responses with human judgments. We demonstrate how a modest amount of high-quality native preferences improves cultural awareness across various LMs, outperforming larger generic preference data. Our analyses reveal that models with stronger initial cultural performance benefit more from alignment, leading to gaps among models developed in different regions with varying access to culturally relevant data. CARE is publicly available at https://github.com/Guochry/CARE.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.05154v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Geyang Guo, Tarek Naous, Hiromi Wakaki, Yukiko Nishimura, Yuki Mitsufuji, Alan Ritter, Wei Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Read Before You Think: Mitigating LLM Comprehension Failures with Step-by-Step Reading</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.09402</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.09402v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) often fail on complex reasoning tasks due to flawed question comprehension, not just flawed logic. This paper presents a systematic investigation into these comprehension failures. Our work yields three key insights: (1) the step-by-step principle, effective for calculation, can be migrated to the reading process to enhance comprehension; (2) increasing the proportion of question-related tokens (e.g., via repetition) succeeds by refocusing attention, a mechanism that can be explicitly controlled; and (3) backward dependencies represent a core bottleneck for decoder-only models that persists even with strong methods like Chain-of-Thought. Based on these findings, we introduce the Step-by-Step Reading (SSR) family of prompts. This multi-stage approach culminates in SSR++, a method specifically engineered to deepen model comprehension by guiding it to parse questions with finer granularity, focus attention on critical tokens, and resolve backward dependencies through iterative re-contextualization. SSR++ sets a new state-of-the-art on multiple reasoning benchmarks, and our analysis confirms it works by directly mitigating semantic misunderstanding. These results demonstrate that guiding how a model reads is a powerful and efficient method for improving its reasoning ability.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.09402v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Feijiang Han, Hengtao Cui, Licheng Guo, Zelong Wang, Zhiyuan Lyu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extracting memorized pieces of (copyrighted) books from open-weight language models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.12546</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.12546v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Plaintiffs and defendants in copyright lawsuits over generative AI often make sweeping, opposing claims about the extent to which large language models (LLMs) have memorized plaintiffs' protected expression in their training data. Drawing on both machine learning and copyright law, we show that these polarized positions dramatically oversimplify the relationship between memorization and copyright. To do so, we extend a recent probabilistic extraction technique to measure memorization of 50 books in 17 open-weight LLMs. Through thousands of experiments, we show that the extent of memorization varies both by model and by book. With respect to our specific extraction methodology, we find that most LLMs do not memorize most books -- either in whole or in part. However, we also find that Llama 3.1 70B entirely memorizes some books, like the first Harry Potter book and 1984. In fact, the first Harry Potter is so memorized that, using a seed prompt consisting of just the first few tokens of the first chapter, we can deterministically generate the entire book near-verbatim. We discuss why our results have significant implications for copyright cases, though not ones that unambiguously favor either side.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.12546v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>A. Feder Cooper, Aaron Gokaslan, Ahmed Ahmed, Amy B. Cyphert, Christopher De Sa, Mark A. Lemley, Daniel E. Ho, Percy Liang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diverse, not Short: A Length-Controlled Data Selection Strategy for Improving Response Diversity of Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.16245</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.16245v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Diverse language model responses are crucial for creative generation, open-ended tasks, and self-improvement training. We show that common diversity metrics, and even reward models used for preference optimization, systematically bias models toward shorter outputs, limiting expressiveness. To address this, we introduce Diverse, not Short (Diverse-NS), a length-controlled data selection strategy that improves response diversity while maintaining length parity. By generating and filtering preference data that balances diversity, quality, and length, Diverse-NS enables effective training using only 3,000 preference pairs. Applied to LLaMA-3.1-8B and the Olmo-2 family, Diverse-NS substantially enhances lexical and semantic diversity. We show consistent improvement in diversity with minor reduction or gains in response quality on four creative generation tasks: Divergent Associations, Persona Generation, Alternate Uses, and Creative Writing. Surprisingly, experiments with the Olmo-2 model family (7B, and 13B) show that smaller models like Olmo-2-7B can serve as effective "diversity teachers" for larger models. By explicitly addressing length bias, our method efficiently pushes models toward more diverse and expressive outputs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.16245v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Vijeta Deshpande, Debasmita Ghose, John D. Patterson, Roger Beaty, Anna Rumshisky</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PMPO: Probabilistic Metric Prompt Optimization for Small and Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.16307</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.16307v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Prompt optimization is a practical and widely applicable alternative to fine tuning for improving large language model performance. Yet many existing methods evaluate candidate prompts by sampling full outputs, often coupled with self critique or human annotated preferences, which limits scalability, especially for smaller models or models that are not instruction tuned. We present PMPO (Probabilistic Metric Prompt Optimization), a unified framework that uses token level cross entropy as a direct, lightweight evaluation signal. PMPO locates low quality prompt segments via a masking based analysis and iteratively rewrites them to propose improved variants. Crucially, during evaluation, PMPO selects among variants by minimizing loss in a single forward pass, eliminating output sampling and human or judge based scoring for selection while still using standard generation only to propose rewrites. This unified, loss based strategy supports both supervised and preference based tasks. Across model sizes and datasets, PMPO outperforms prior prompt optimizers: it achieves the highest average accuracy on BBH, performs strongly on GSM8K and AQUA RAT, and raises AlpacaEval 2.0 win rates by over 19 points. These results demonstrate PMPO's effectiveness, efficiency, and broad applicability.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.16307v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chenzhuo Zhao, Ziqian Liu, Xinda Wang, Junting Lu, Chaoyi Ruan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Understanding and Mitigation of Language Confusion in English-Centric Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.16538</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.16538v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Language confusion -- where large language models (LLMs) generate unintended languages against the user's need -- remains a critical challenge, especially for English-centric models. We present the first mechanistic interpretability (MI) study of language confusion, combining behavioral benchmarking with neuron-level analysis. Using the Language Confusion Benchmark (LCB), we show that confusion points (CPs) -- specific positions where language switches occur -- are central to this phenomenon. Through layer-wise analysis with TunedLens and targeted neuron attribution, we reveal that transition failures in the final layers drive confusion. We further demonstrate that editing a small set of critical neurons, identified via comparative analysis with a multilingual-tuned counterpart, substantially mitigates confusion while largely preserving general competence and fluency. Our approach matches multilingual alignment in confusion reduction for many languages and yields cleaner, higher-quality outputs. These findings provide new insights into the internal dynamics of LLMs and highlight neuron-level interventions as a promising direction for robust, interpretable multilingual language modeling. Code and data are available at: https://github.com/ercong21/lang_confusion.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.16538v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ercong Nie, Helmut Schmid, Hinrich Sch\"utze</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MAVL: A Multilingual Audio-Video Lyrics Dataset for Animated Song Translation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.18614</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.18614v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Lyrics translation requires both accurate semantic transfer and preservation of musical rhythm, syllabic structure, and poetic style. In animated musicals, the challenge intensifies due to alignment with visual and auditory cues. We introduce Multilingual Audio-Video Lyrics Benchmark for Animated Song Translation (MAVL), the first multilingual, multimodal benchmark for singable lyrics translation. By integrating text, audio, and video, MAVL enables richer and more expressive translations than text-only approaches. Building on this, we propose Syllable-Constrained Audio-Video LLM with Chain-of-Thought SylAVL-CoT, which leverages audio-video cues and enforces syllabic constraints to produce natural-sounding lyrics. Experimental results demonstrate that SylAVL-CoT significantly outperforms text-based models in singability and contextual accuracy, emphasizing the value of multimodal, multilingual approaches for lyrics translation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.18614v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Woohyun Cho, Youngmin Kim, Sunghyun Lee, Youngjae Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assistant-Guided Mitigation of Teacher Preference Bias in LLM-as-a-Judge</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.19176</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.19176v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: LLM-as-a-Judge employs large language models (LLMs), such as GPT-4, to evaluate the quality of LLM-generated responses, gaining popularity for its cost-effectiveness and strong alignment with human evaluations. However, training proxy judge models using evaluation data generated by powerful teacher models introduces a critical yet previously overlooked issue: teacher preference bias, where the proxy judge model learns a biased preference for responses from the teacher model. To tackle this problem, we propose a novel setting that incorporates an additional assistant model, which is not biased toward the teacher model's responses, to complement the training data. Building on this setup, we introduce AGDe-Judge, a three-stage framework designed to debias from both the labels and feedbacks in the training data. Extensive experiments demonstrate that AGDe-Judge effectively reduces teacher preference bias while maintaining strong performance across six evaluation benchmarks. Code is available at https://github.com/Liuz233/AGDe-Judge.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.19176v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhuo Liu, Moxin Li, Xun Deng, Qifan Wang, Fuli Feng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MOLE: Metadata Extraction and Validation in Scientific Papers Using LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.19800</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.19800v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Metadata extraction is essential for cataloging and preserving datasets, enabling effective research discovery and reproducibility, especially given the current exponential growth in scientific research. While Masader (Alyafeai et al.,2021) laid the groundwork for extracting a wide range of metadata attributes from Arabic NLP datasets' scholarly articles, it relies heavily on manual annotation. In this paper, we present MOLE, a framework that leverages Large Language Models (LLMs) to automatically extract metadata attributes from scientific papers covering datasets of languages other than Arabic. Our schema-driven methodology processes entire documents across multiple input formats and incorporates robust validation mechanisms for consistent output. Additionally, we introduce a new benchmark to evaluate the research progress on this task. Through systematic analysis of context length, few-shot learning, and web browsing integration, we demonstrate that modern LLMs show promising results in automating this task, highlighting the need for further future work improvements to ensure consistent and reliable performance. We release the code: https://github.com/IVUL-KAUST/MOLE and dataset: https://huggingface.co/datasets/IVUL-KAUST/MOLE for the research community.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.19800v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zaid Alyafeai, Maged S. Al-Shaibani, Bernard Ghanem</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WebCoT: Enhancing Web Agent Reasoning by Reconstructing Chain-of-Thought in Reflection, Branching, and Rollback</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.20013</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.20013v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Web agents powered by Large Language Models (LLMs) show promise for next-generation AI, but their limited reasoning in uncertain, dynamic web environments hinders robust deployment. In this paper, we identify key reasoning skills essential for effective web agents, i.e., reflection &amp; lookahead, branching, and rollback, and curate trajectory data that exemplifies these abilities by reconstructing the agent's (inference-time) reasoning algorithms into chain-of-thought rationales. We conduct experiments in the agent self-improving benchmark, OpenWebVoyager, and demonstrate that distilling salient reasoning patterns into the backbone LLM via simple fine-tuning can substantially enhance its performance. Our approach yields significant improvements across multiple benchmarks, including WebVoyager, Mind2web-live, and SimpleQA (web search), highlighting the potential of targeted reasoning skill enhancement for web agents.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.20013v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Minda Hu, Tianqing Fang, Jianshu Zhang, Junyu Ma, Zhisong Zhang, Jingyan Zhou, Hongming Zhang, Haitao Mi, Dong Yu, Irwin King</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Logical Reasoning in Language Models via Symbolically-Guided Monte Carlo Process Supervision</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.20415</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.20415v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have shown strong performance in many reasoning benchmarks. However, recent studies have pointed to memorization, rather than generalization, as one of the leading causes for such performance. LLMs, in fact, are susceptible to content variations, demonstrating a lack of robust planning or symbolic abstractions supporting their reasoning process. To improve reliability, many attempts have been made to combine LLMs with symbolic methods. Nevertheless, existing approaches fail to effectively leverage symbolic representations due to the challenges involved in developing reliable and scalable verification mechanisms. In this paper, we propose to overcome such limitations by synthesizing high-quality symbolic reasoning trajectories with stepwise pseudo-labels at scale via Monte Carlo estimation. A Process Reward Model (PRM) can be efficiently trained based on the synthesized data and then used to select more symbolic trajectories. The trajectories are then employed with Direct Preference Optimization (DPO) and Supervised Fine-Tuning (SFT) to improve logical reasoning and generalization. Our results on benchmarks (i.e., FOLIO and LogicAsker) show the effectiveness of the proposed method with gains on frontier and open-weight models. Moreover, additional experiments on claim verification data reveal that fine-tuning on the generated symbolic reasoning trajectories enhances out-of-domain generalizability, suggesting the potential impact of the proposed method in enhancing planning and logical reasoning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.20415v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xingwei Tan, Marco Valentino, Mahmud Akhter, Maria Liakata, Nikolaos Aletras</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>mdok of KInIT: Robustly Fine-tuned LLM for Binary and Multiclass AI-Generated Text Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.01702</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.01702v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The large language models (LLMs) are able to generate high-quality texts in multiple languages. Such texts are often not recognizable by humans as generated, and therefore present a potential of LLMs for misuse (e.g., plagiarism, spams, disinformation spreading). An automated detection is able to assist humans to indicate the machine-generated texts; however, its robustness to out-of-distribution data is still challenging. This notebook describes our mdok approach in robust detection, based on fine-tuning smaller LLMs for text classification. It is applied to both subtasks of Voight-Kampff Generative AI Detection 2025, providing remarkable performance (1st rank) in both, the binary detection as well as the multiclass classification of various cases of human-AI collaboration.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.01702v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dominik Macko</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ImpRAG: Retrieval-Augmented Generation with Implicit Queries</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.02279</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.02279v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) systems traditionally treat retrieval and generation as separate processes, requiring explicit textual queries to connect them. This separation can limit the ability of models to generalize across diverse tasks. In this work, we propose a query-free RAG system, named ImpRAG, which integrates retrieval and generation into a unified model. ImpRAG allows models to implicitly express their information needs, eliminating the need for human-specified queries. By dividing pretrained decoder-only language models into specialized layer groups, ImpRAG optimizes retrieval and generation tasks simultaneously. Our approach employs a two-stage inference process, using the same model parameters and forward pass for both retrieval and generation, thereby minimizing the disparity between retrievers and language models. Experiments on 8 knowledge-intensive tasks demonstrate that ImpRAG achieves 3.6-11.5 improvements in exact match scores on unseen tasks with diverse formats, highlighting its effectiveness in enabling models to articulate their own information needs and generalize across tasks. Our analysis underscores the importance of balancing retrieval and generation parameters and leveraging generation perplexities as retrieval training objectives for enhanced performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.02279v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenzheng Zhang, Xi Victoria Lin, Karl Stratos, Wen-tau Yih, Mingda Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DiCoRe: Enhancing Zero-shot Event Detection via Divergent-Convergent LLM Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.05128</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.05128v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Zero-shot Event Detection (ED), the task of identifying event mentions in natural language text without any training data, is critical for document understanding in specialized domains. Understanding the complex event ontology, extracting domain-specific triggers from the passage, and structuring them appropriately overloads and limits the utility of Large Language Models (LLMs) for zero-shot ED. To this end, we propose DiCoRe, a divergent-convergent reasoning framework that decouples the task of ED using Dreamer and Grounder. Dreamer encourages divergent reasoning through open-ended event discovery, which helps to boost event coverage. Conversely, Grounder introduces convergent reasoning to align the free-form predictions with the task-specific instructions using finite-state machine guided constrained decoding. Additionally, an LLM-Judge verifies the final outputs to ensure high precision. Through extensive experiments on six datasets across five domains and nine LLMs, we demonstrate how DiCoRe consistently outperforms prior zero-shot, transfer-learning, and reasoning baselines, achieving 4-7% average F1 gains over the best baseline -- establishing DiCoRe as a strong zero-shot ED framework.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.05128v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tanmay Parekh, Kartik Mehta, Ninareh Mehrabi, Kai-Wei Chang, Nanyun Peng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>QA-LIGN: Aligning LLMs through Constitutionally Decomposed QA</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.08123</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.08123v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Alignment of large language models (LLMs) with principles like helpfulness, honesty, and harmlessness typically relies on scalar rewards that obscure which objectives drive the training signal. We introduce QA-LIGN, which decomposes monolithic rewards into interpretable principle-specific evaluations through structured natural language programs. Models learn through a draft, critique, and revise pipeline, where symbolic evaluation against the rubrics provides transparent feedback for both initial and revised responses during GRPO training. Applied to uncensored Llama-3.1-8B-Instruct, QA-LIGN reduces attack success rates by up to 68.7% while maintaining a 0.67% false refusal rate, achieving Pareto optimal safety-helpfulness performance and outperforming both DPO and GRPO with state-of-the-art reward models given equivalent training. These results demonstrate that making reward signals interpretable and modular improves alignment effectiveness, suggesting transparency enhances LLM safety.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.08123v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jacob Dineen (Arizona State University), Aswin RRV (Arizona State University), Qin Liu (University of California Davis), Zhikun Xu (Arizona State University), Xiao Ye (Arizona State University), Ming Shen (Arizona State University), Zhaonan Li (Arizona State University), Shijie Lu (Arizona State University), Chitta Baral (Arizona State University), Muhao Chen (University of California Davis), Ben Zhou (Arizona State University)</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"What's Up, Doc?": Analyzing How Users Seek Health Information in Large-Scale Conversational AI Datasets</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.21532</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.21532v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: People are increasingly seeking healthcare information from large language models (LLMs) via interactive chatbots, yet the nature and inherent risks of these conversations remain largely unexplored. In this paper, we filter large-scale conversational AI datasets to achieve HealthChat-11K, a curated dataset of 11K real-world conversations composed of 25K user messages. We use HealthChat-11K and a clinician-driven taxonomy for how users interact with LLMs when seeking healthcare information in order to systematically study user interactions across 21 distinct health specialties. Our analysis reveals insights into the nature of how and why users seek health information, such as common interactions, instances of incomplete context, affective behaviors, and interactions (e.g., leading questions) that can induce sycophancy, underscoring the need for improvements in the healthcare support capabilities of LLMs deployed as conversational AI. Code and artifacts to retrieve our analyses and combine them into a curated dataset can be found here: https://github.com/yahskapar/HealthChat</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.21532v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Akshay Paruchuri, Maryam Aziz, Rohit Vartak, Ayman Ali, Best Uchehara, Xin Liu, Ishan Chatterjee, Monica Agrawal</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MedVAL: Toward Expert-Level Medical Text Validation with Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.03152</link>
      <description>arXiv:2507.03152v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: With the growing use of language models (LMs) in clinical environments, there is an immediate need to evaluate the accuracy and safety of LM-generated medical text. Currently, such evaluation relies solely on manual physician review. However, detecting errors in LM-generated text is challenging because 1) manual review is costly and 2) expert-composed reference outputs are often unavailable in real-world settings. While the "LM-as-judge" paradigm (a LM evaluating another LM) offers scalable evaluation, even frontier LMs can miss subtle but clinically significant errors. To address these challenges, we propose MedVAL, a novel, self-supervised, data-efficient distillation method that leverages synthetic data to train evaluator LMs to assess whether LM-generated medical outputs are factually consistent with inputs, without requiring physician labels or reference outputs. To evaluate LM performance, we introduce MedVAL-Bench, a dataset of 840 physician-annotated outputs across 6 diverse medical tasks capturing real-world challenges. Across 10 state-of-the-art LMs spanning open-source and proprietary models, MedVAL distillation significantly improves (p &lt; 0.001) alignment with physicians across seen and unseen tasks, increasing average F1 scores from 66% to 83%. Despite strong baseline performance, MedVAL improves the best-performing proprietary LM (GPT-4o) by 8% without training on physician-labeled data, demonstrating a performance statistically non-inferior to a single human expert (p &lt; 0.001). To support a scalable, risk-aware pathway towards clinical integration, we open-source: 1) Codebase (https://github.com/StanfordMIMI/MedVAL), 2) MedVAL-Bench (https://huggingface.co/datasets/stanfordmimi/MedVAL-Bench), 3) MedVAL-4B (https://huggingface.co/stanfordmimi/MedVAL-4B). Our benchmark provides evidence of LMs approaching expert-level ability in validating AI-generated medical text.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2507.03152v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Asad Aali, Vasiliki Bikia, Maya Varma, Nicole Chiou, Sophie Ostmeier, Arnav Singhvi, Magdalini Paschali, Ashwin Kumar, Andrew Johnston, Karimar Amador-Martinez, Eduardo Juan Perez Guerrero, Paola Naovi Cruz Rivera, Sergios Gatidis, Christian Bluethgen, Eduardo Pontes Reis, Eddy D. Zandee van Rilland, Poonam Laxmappa Hosamani, Kevin R Keet, Minjoung Go, Evelyn Ling, David B. Larson, Curtis Langlotz, Roxana Daneshjou, Jason Hom, Sanmi Koyejo, Emily Alsentzer, Akshay S. Chaudhari</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SMART: Simulated Students Aligned with Item Response Theory for Question Difficulty Prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.05129</link>
      <description>arXiv:2507.05129v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Item (question) difficulties play a crucial role in educational assessments, enabling accurate and efficient assessment of student abilities and personalization to maximize learning outcomes. Traditionally, estimating item difficulties can be costly, requiring real students to respond to items, followed by fitting an item response theory (IRT) model to get difficulty estimates. This approach cannot be applied to the cold-start setting for previously unseen items either. In this work, we present SMART (Simulated Students Aligned with IRT), a novel method for aligning simulated students with instructed ability, which can then be used in simulations to predict the difficulty of open-ended items. We achieve this alignment using direct preference optimization (DPO), where we form preference pairs based on how likely responses are under a ground-truth IRT model. We perform a simulation by generating thousands of responses, evaluating them with a large language model (LLM)-based scoring model, and fit the resulting data to an IRT model to obtain item difficulty estimates. Through extensive experiments on two real-world student response datasets, we show that SMART outperforms other item difficulty prediction methods by leveraging its improved ability alignment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2507.05129v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alexander Scarlatos, Nigel Fernandez, Christopher Ormerod, Susan Lottridge, Andrew Lan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unpacking Ambiguity: The Interaction of Polysemous Discourse Markers and Non-DM Signals</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.16748</link>
      <description>arXiv:2507.16748v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Discourse markers (DMs) like 'but' or 'then' are crucial for creating coherence in discourse, yet they are often replaced by or co-occur with non-DMs ('in the morning' can mean the same as 'then'), and both can be ambiguous ('since' can refer to time or cause). The interaction mechanism between such signals remains unclear but pivotal for their disambiguation. In this paper we investigate the relationship between DM polysemy and co-occurrence of non-DM signals in English, as well as the influence of genre on these patterns.
  Using the framework of eRST, we propose a graded definition of DM polysemy, and conduct correlation and regression analyses to examine whether polysemous DMs are accompanied by more numerous and diverse non-DM signals. Our findings reveal that while polysemous DMs do co-occur with more diverse non-DMs, the total number of co-occurring signals does not necessarily increase. Moreover, genre plays a significant role in shaping DM-signal interactions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2507.16748v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jingni Wu, Amir Zeldes</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASCoT: An Adaptive Self-Correction Chain-of-Thought Method for Late-Stage Fragility in LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.05282</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.05282v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Chain-of-Thought (CoT) prompting has significantly advanced the reasoning capabilities of Large Language Models (LLMs), yet the reliability of these reasoning chains remains a critical challenge. A widely held "cascading failure" hypothesis suggests that errors are most detrimental when they occur early in the reasoning process. This paper challenges that assumption through systematic error-injection experiments, revealing a counter-intuitive phenomenon we term "Late-Stage Fragility": errors introduced in the later stages of a CoT chain are significantly more likely to corrupt the final answer than identical errors made at the beginning. To address this specific vulnerability, we introduce the Adaptive Self-Correction Chain-of-Thought (ASCoT) method. ASCoT employs a modular pipeline in which an Adaptive Verification Manager (AVM) operates first, followed by the Multi-Perspective Self-Correction Engine (MSCE). The AVM leverages a Positional Impact Score function I(k) that assigns different weights based on the position within the reasoning chains, addressing the Late-Stage Fragility issue by identifying and prioritizing high-risk, late-stage steps. Once these critical steps are identified, the MSCE applies robust, dual-path correction specifically to the failure parts. Extensive experiments on benchmarks such as GSM8K and MATH demonstrate that ASCoT achieves outstanding accuracy, outperforming strong baselines, including standard CoT. Our work underscores the importance of diagnosing specific failure modes in LLM reasoning and advocates for a shift from uniform verification strategies to adaptive, vulnerability-aware correction mechanisms.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.05282v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dongxu Zhang, Ning Yang, Jihua Zhu, Jinnan Yang, Miao Xin, Baoliang Tian</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Select to Know: An Internal-External Knowledge Self-Selection Framework for Domain-Specific Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.15213</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.15213v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) perform well in general QA but often struggle in domain-specific scenarios. Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) introduces external knowledge but suffers from hallucinations and latency due to noisy retrievals. Continued pretraining internalizes domain knowledge but is costly and lacks cross-domain flexibility. We attribute this challenge to the long-tail distribution of domain knowledge, which leaves partial yet useful internal knowledge underutilized. We further argue that knowledge acquisition should be progressive, mirroring human learning: first understanding concepts, then applying them to complex reasoning. To address this, we propose Selct2Know (S2K), a cost-effective framework that internalizes domain knowledge through an internal-external knowledge self-selection strategy and selective supervised fine-tuning. We also introduce a structured reasoning data generation pipeline and integrate GRPO to enhance reasoning ability. Experiments on medical, legal, and financial QA benchmarks show that S2K consistently outperforms existing methods and matches domain-pretrained LLMs with significantly lower cost.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.15213v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bolei He, Xinran He, Run Shao, Shanfu Shu, Xianwei Xue, Mingquan Cheng, Haifeng Li, Zhenhua Ling</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MovieCORE: COgnitive REasoning in Movies</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.19026</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.19026v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper introduces MovieCORE, a novel video question answering (VQA) dataset designed to probe deeper cognitive understanding of movie content. Unlike existing datasets that focus on surface-level comprehension, MovieCORE emphasizes questions that engage System-2 thinking while remaining specific to the video material. We present an innovative agentic brainstorming approach, utilizing multiple large language models (LLMs) as thought agents to generate and refine high-quality question-answer pairs. To evaluate dataset quality, we develop a set of cognitive tests assessing depth, thought-provocation potential, and syntactic complexity. We also propose a comprehensive evaluation scheme for assessing VQA model performance on deeper cognitive tasks. To address the limitations of existing video-language models (VLMs), we introduce an agentic enhancement module, Agentic Choice Enhancement (ACE), which improves model reasoning capabilities post-training by up to 25%. Our work contributes to advancing movie understanding in AI systems and provides valuable insights into the capabilities and limitations of current VQA models when faced with more challenging, nuanced questions about cinematic content. Our project page, dataset and code can be found at https://joslefaure.github.io/assets/html/moviecore.html.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.19026v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gueter Josmy Faure, Min-Hung Chen, Jia-Fong Yeh, Ying Cheng, Hung-Ting Su, Yung-Hao Tang, Shang-Hong Lai, Winston H. Hsu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Middo: Model-Informed Dynamic Data Optimization for Enhanced LLM Fine-Tuning via Closed-Loop Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.21589</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.21589v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Supervised Fine-Tuning (SFT) Large Language Models (LLM) fundamentally rely on high-quality training data. While data selection and data synthesis are two common strategies to improve data quality, existing approaches often face limitations in static dataset curation that fail to adapt to evolving model capabilities. In this paper, we introduce Middo, a self-evolving Model-informed dynamic data optimization framework that uses model-aware data selection and context-preserving data refinement. Unlike conventional one-off filtering/synthesis methods, our framework establishes a closed-loop optimization system: (1) A self-referential diagnostic module proactively identifies suboptimal samples through tri-axial model signals - loss patterns (complexity), embedding cluster dynamics (diversity), and self-alignment scores (quality); (2) An adaptive optimization engine then transforms suboptimal samples into pedagogically valuable training points while preserving semantic integrity; (3) This optimization process continuously evolves with model capability through dynamic learning principles. Experiments on multiple benchmarks demonstrate that our Middo consistently enhances the quality of seed data and boosts LLM's performance with improving accuracy by 7.15% on average while maintaining the original dataset scale. This work establishes a new paradigm for sustainable LLM training through dynamic human-AI co-evolution of data and models. Our datasets, models, and code are coming soon. Our datasets, models, and code are publicly available at https://github.com/Word2VecT/Middo</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.21589v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zinan Tang, Xin Gao, Qizhi Pei, Zhuoshi Pan, Mengzhang Cai, Jiang Wu, Conghui He, Lijun Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Survey of Reinforcement Learning for Large Reasoning Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.08827</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.08827v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this paper, we survey recent advances in Reinforcement Learning (RL) for reasoning with Large Language Models (LLMs). RL has achieved remarkable success in advancing the frontier of LLM capabilities, particularly in addressing complex logical tasks such as mathematics and coding. As a result, RL has emerged as a foundational methodology for transforming LLMs into LRMs. With the rapid progress of the field, further scaling of RL for LRMs now faces foundational challenges not only in computational resources but also in algorithm design, training data, and infrastructure. To this end, it is timely to revisit the development of this domain, reassess its trajectory, and explore strategies to enhance the scalability of RL toward Artificial SuperIntelligence (ASI). In particular, we examine research applying RL to LLMs and LRMs for reasoning abilities, especially since the release of DeepSeek-R1, including foundational components, core problems, training resources, and downstream applications, to identify future opportunities and directions for this rapidly evolving area. We hope this review will promote future research on RL for broader reasoning models. Github: https://github.com/TsinghuaC3I/Awesome-RL-for-LRMs</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.08827v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kaiyan Zhang, Yuxin Zuo, Bingxiang He, Youbang Sun, Runze Liu, Che Jiang, Yuchen Fan, Kai Tian, Guoli Jia, Pengfei Li, Yu Fu, Xingtai Lv, Yuchen Zhang, Sihang Zeng, Shang Qu, Haozhan Li, Shijie Wang, Yuru Wang, Xinwei Long, Fangfu Liu, Xiang Xu, Jiaze Ma, Xuekai Zhu, Ermo Hua, Yihao Liu, Zonglin Li, Huayu Chen, Xiaoye Qu, Yafu Li, Weize Chen, Zhenzhao Yuan, Junqi Gao, Dong Li, Zhiyuan Ma, Ganqu Cui, Zhiyuan Liu, Biqing Qi, Ning Ding, Bowen Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ALIGNS: Unlocking nomological networks in psychological measurement through a large language model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.09723</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.09723v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Psychological measurement is critical to many disciplines. Despite advances in measurement, building nomological networks, theoretical maps of how concepts and measures relate to establish validity, remains a challenge 70 years after Cronbach and Meehl proposed them as fundamental to validation. This limitation has practical consequences: clinical trials may fail to detect treatment effects, and public policy may target the wrong outcomes. We introduce Analysis of Latent Indicators to Generate Nomological Structures (ALIGNS), a large language model-based system trained with validated questionnaire measures. ALIGNS provides three comprehensive nomological networks containing over 550,000 indicators across psychology, medicine, social policy, and other fields. This represents the first application of large language models to solve a foundational problem in measurement validation. We report classification accuracy tests used to develop the model, as well as three evaluations. In the first evaluation, the widely used NIH PROMIS anxiety and depression instruments are shown to converge into a single dimension of emotional distress. The second evaluation examines child temperament measures and identifies four potential dimensions not captured by current frameworks, and questions one existing dimension. The third evaluation, an applicability check, engages expert psychometricians who assess the system's importance, accessibility, and suitability. ALIGNS is freely available at nomologicalnetwork.org, complementing traditional validation methods with large-scale nomological analysis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.09723v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>stat.ME</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kai R. Larsen, Sen Yan, Roland M. Mueller, Lan Sang, Mikko R\"onkk\"o, Ravi Starzl, Donald Edmondson</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pluralistic Alignment for Healthcare: A Role-Driven Framework</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.10685</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.10685v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: As large language models are increasingly deployed in sensitive domains such as healthcare, ensuring their outputs reflect the diverse values and perspectives held across populations is critical. However, existing alignment approaches, including pluralistic paradigms like Modular Pluralism, often fall short in the health domain, where personal, cultural, and situational factors shape pluralism. Motivated by the aforementioned healthcare challenges, we propose a first lightweight, generalizable, pluralistic alignment approach, EthosAgents, designed to simulate diverse perspectives and values. We empirically show that it advances the pluralistic alignment for all three modes across seven varying-sized open and closed models. Our findings reveal that health-related pluralism demands adaptable and normatively aware approaches, offering insights into how these models can better respect diversity in other high-stakes domains.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.10685v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiayou Zhong, Anudeex Shetty, Chao Jia, Xuanrui Lin, Usman Naseem</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DeDisCo at the DISRPT 2025 Shared Task: A System for Discourse Relation Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.11498</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.11498v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper presents DeDisCo, Georgetown University's entry in the DISRPT 2025 shared task on discourse relation classification. We test two approaches, using an mt5-based encoder and a decoder based approach using the openly available Qwen model. We also experiment on training with augmented dataset for low-resource languages using matched data translated automatically from English, as well as using some additional linguistic features inspired by entries in previous editions of the Shared Task. Our system achieves a macro-accuracy score of 71.28, and we provide some interpretation and error analysis for our results.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.11498v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhuoxuan Ju, Jingni Wu, Abhishek Purushothama, Amir Zeldes</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Audited Reasoning Refinement: Fine-Tuning Language Models via LLM-Guided Step-Wise Evaluation and Correction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.12476</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.12476v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Training a task-specific small reasoning model is challenging when direct human supervision or high-quality labels are scarce. However, LLMs with reasoning capabilities produce abundant intermediate reasoning traces that can be systematically refined to create effective supervision signals. We propose Reason-Refine-then-Align (R2tA), which turns refined model rationales into supervision for training task-specific reasoning models. Our method generates initial reasoning and responses from an open-source base model on task-specific inputs, then refines these traces, fixing hallucinations and inconsistencies, to form a high-fidelity dataset. We perform a two-stage alignment, supervised fine-tuning (SFT), followed by direct preference optimization (DPO) to calibrate the model's intermediate reasoning with human-validated conceptual preferences and then condition the final output on that aligned reasoning. As a case study, we apply R2tA to evaluate extended entity relationship diagrams (EERDs) in database system design, a structurally complex task where prompt-only methods miss or hallucinate errors. We curated a dataset of 600 EERD variants (train/test split of 450/150, respectively) with induced mistakes spanning 11 categories. Empirical evaluation suggests R2tA provides a practical, cost-effective path to scalable LLM adaptation in data-scarce domains, enabling reproducible AI tools for education and beyond.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.12476v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sumanta Bhattacharyya, Sara Riazi, Pedram Rooshenas</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FunAudio-ASR Technical Report</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.12508</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.12508v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In recent years, automatic speech recognition (ASR) has witnessed transformative advancements driven by three complementary paradigms: data scaling, model size scaling, and deep integration with large language models (LLMs). However, LLMs are prone to hallucination, which can significantly degrade user experience in real-world ASR applications. In this paper, we present FunAudio-ASR, a large-scale, LLM-based ASR system that synergistically combines massive data, large model capacity, LLM integration, and reinforcement learning to achieve state-of-the-art performance across diverse and complex speech recognition scenarios. Moreover, FunAudio-ASR is specifically optimized for practical deployment, with enhancements in streaming capability, noise robustness, code-switching, hotword customization, and satisfying other real-world application requirements. Experimental results show that while most LLM-based ASR systems achieve strong performance on open-source benchmarks, they often underperform on real industry evaluation sets. Thanks to production-oriented optimizations, FunAudio-ASR achieves SOTA performance on real application datasets, demonstrating its effectiveness and robustness in practical settings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.12508v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Keyu An, Yanni Chen, Chong Deng, Changfeng Gao, Zhifu Gao, Bo Gong, Xiangang Li, Yabin Li, Xiang Lv, Yunjie Ji, Yiheng Jiang, Bin Ma, Haoneng Luo, Chongjia Ni, Zexu Pan, Yiping Peng, Zhendong Peng, Peiyao Wang, Hao Wang, Wen Wang, Wupeng Wang, Biao Tian, Zhentao Tan, Nan Yang, Bin Yuan, Jieping Ye, Jixing Yu, Qinglin Zhang, Kun Zou, Han Zhao, Shengkui Zhao, Jingren Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DSPC: Dual-Stage Progressive Compression Framework for Efficient Long-Context Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.13723</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.13723v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have achieved remarkable success in many natural language processing (NLP) tasks. To achieve more accurate output, the prompts used to drive LLMs have become increasingly longer, which incurs higher computational costs. To address this prompt inflation problem, prompt compression has been proposed. However, most existing methods require training a small auxiliary model for compression, incurring a significant amount of additional computation. To avoid this, we propose a two-stage, training-free approach, called Dual-Stage Progressive Compression (DSPC). In the coarse-grained stage, semantic-related sentence filtering removes sentences with low semantic value based on TF-IDF. In the fine-grained stage, token importance is assessed using attention contribution, cross-model loss difference, and positional importance, enabling the pruning of low-utility tokens while preserving semantics. We validate DSPC on LLaMA-3.1-8B-Instruct and GPT-3.5-Turbo under a constrained token budget and observe consistent improvements. For instance, in the FewShot task of the Longbench dataset, DSPC achieves a performance of 49.17 by using only 3x fewer tokens, outperforming the best state-of-the-art baseline LongLLMLingua by 7.76.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.13723v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yaxin Gao, Yao Lu, Zongfei Zhang, Jiaqi Nie, Shanqing Yu, Qi Xuan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Data and Parameter Efficient Strategies for Arabic Dialect Identifications</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.13775</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.13775v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper discusses our exploration of different data-efficient and parameter-efficient approaches to Arabic Dialect Identification (ADI). In particular, we investigate various soft-prompting strategies, including prefix-tuning, prompt-tuning, P-tuning, and P-tuning V2, as well as LoRA reparameterizations. For the data-efficient strategy, we analyze hard prompting with zero-shot and few-shot inferences to analyze the dialect identification capabilities of Large Language Models (LLMs). For the parameter-efficient PEFT approaches, we conducted our experiments using Arabic-specific encoder models on several major datasets. We also analyzed the n-shot inferences on open-source decoder-only models, a general multilingual model (Phi-3.5), and an Arabic-specific one(SILMA). We observed that the LLMs generally struggle to differentiate the dialectal nuances in the few-shot or zero-shot setups. The soft-prompted encoder variants perform better, while the LoRA-based fine-tuned models perform best, even surpassing full fine-tuning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.13775v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Vani Kanjirangat, Ljiljana Dolamic, Fabio Rinaldi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AssoCiAm: A Benchmark for Evaluating Association Thinking while Circumventing Ambiguity</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14171</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14171v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advancements in multimodal large language models (MLLMs) have garnered significant attention, offering a promising pathway toward artificial general intelligence (AGI). Among the essential capabilities required for AGI, creativity has emerged as a critical trait for MLLMs, with association serving as its foundation. Association reflects a model' s ability to think creatively, making it vital to evaluate and understand. While several frameworks have been proposed to assess associative ability, they often overlook the inherent ambiguity in association tasks, which arises from the divergent nature of associations and undermines the reliability of evaluations. To address this issue, we decompose ambiguity into two types-internal ambiguity and external ambiguity-and introduce AssoCiAm, a benchmark designed to evaluate associative ability while circumventing the ambiguity through a hybrid computational method. We then conduct extensive experiments on MLLMs, revealing a strong positive correlation between cognition and association. Additionally, we observe that the presence of ambiguity in the evaluation process causes MLLMs' behavior to become more random-like. Finally, we validate the effectiveness of our method in ensuring more accurate and reliable evaluations. See Project Page for the data and codes.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14171v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yifan Liu, Wenkuan Zhao, Shanshan Zhong, Jinghui Qin, Mingfu Liang, Zhongzhan Huang, Wushao Wen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learn while Unlearn: An Iterative Unlearning Framework for Generative Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.20271</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.20271v5 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Recent advances in machine learning, particularly in Natural Language Processing (NLP), have produced powerful models trained on vast datasets. However, these models risk leaking sensitive information, raising privacy concerns. In response, regulatory measures such as the European Union's General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) have driven increasing interest in Machine Unlearning techniques, which enable models to selectively forget specific data entries. Early unlearning approaches primarily relied on pre-processing methods, while more recent research has shifted towards training-based solutions. Despite their effectiveness, a key limitation persists: most methods require access to original training data, which is often unavailable. Additionally, directly applying unlearning techniques bears the cost of undermining the model's expressive capabilities. To address these challenges, we introduce the Iterative Contrastive Unlearning (ICU) framework, which consists of three core components: A Knowledge Unlearning Induction module designed to target specific knowledge for removal using an unlearning loss; A Contrastive Learning Enhancement module to preserve the model's expressive capabilities against the pure unlearning goal; And an Iterative Unlearning Refinement module that dynamically adjusts the unlearning process through ongoing evaluation and updates. Experimental results demonstrate the efficacy of our ICU method in unlearning sensitive information while maintaining the model's overall performance, offering a promising solution for privacy-conscious machine learning applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.20271v5</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haoyu Tang, Ye Liu, Xi Zhao, Xukai Liu, Yanghai Zhang, Kai Zhang, Xiaofang Zhou, Enhong Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synaptic Theory of Chunking in Working Memory</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07637</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07637v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Working memory often appears to exceed its basic span by organizing items into compact representations called chunks. Chunking can be learned over time for familiar inputs; however, it can also arise spontaneously for novel stimuli. Such on-the-fly structuring is crucial for cognition, yet the underlying neural mechanism remains unclear. Here we introduce a synaptic theory of chunking, in which short-term synaptic plasticity enables the formation of chunk representations in working memory. We show that a specialized population of ``chunking neurons'' selectively controls groups of stimulus-responsive neurons, akin to gating. As a result, the network maintains and retrieves the stimuli in chunks, thereby exceeding the basic capacity. Moreover, we show that our model can dynamically construct hierarchical representations within working memory through hierarchical chunking. A consequence of this proposed mechanism is a new limit on the number of items that can be stored and subsequently retrieved from working memory, depending only on the basic working memory capacity when chunking is not invoked. Predictions from our model were confirmed by analyzing single-unit responses in epileptic patients and memory experiments with verbal material. Our work provides a novel conceptual and analytical framework for understanding how the brain organizes information in real time.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07637v2</guid>
      <category>q-bio.NC</category>
      <category>cond-mat.dis-nn</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weishun Zhong, Mikhail Katkov, Misha Tsodyks</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3DS: Medical Domain Adaptation of LLMs via Decomposed Difficulty-based Data Selection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.10901</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.10901v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large Language Models(LLMs) excel in general tasks but struggle in specialized domains like healthcare due to limited domain-specific knowledge.Supervised Fine-Tuning(SFT) data construction for domain adaptation often relies on heuristic methods, such as GPT-4 annotation or manual data selection, with a data-centric focus on presumed diverse, high-quality datasets. However, these methods overlook the model's inherent knowledge distribution, introducing noise, redundancy, and irrelevant data, leading to a mismatch between the selected data and the model's learning task, resulting in suboptimal performance. To address this, we propose a two-stage model-centric data selection framework, Decomposed Difficulty Data Selection (3DS), which aligns data with the model's knowledge distribution for optimized adaptation. In Stage1, we apply Prompt-Driven Data Selection via Explicit Alignment, where the the model filters irrelevant or redundant data based on its internal knowledge. In Stage2, we perform Decomposed Difficulty Data Selection, where data selection is guided by our defined difficulty decomposition, using three metrics: Instruction Understanding, Response Confidence, and Response Correctness. Additionally, an attention-based importance weighting mechanism captures token importance for more accurate difficulty calibration. This two-stage approach ensures the selected data is not only aligned with the model's knowledge and preferences but also appropriately challenging for the model to learn, leading to more effective and targeted domain adaptation. In the case study of the medical domain, our extensive experiments on real-world healthcare datasets demonstrate the superiority of 3DS over exisiting methods in accuracy by over 5.29%. Our dataset and code has been open-sourced at https://github.com/PuppyKnightUniversity/3DS.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.10901v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hongxin Ding, Yue Fang, Runchuan Zhu, Xinke Jiang, Jinyang Zhang, Yongxin Xu, Xu Chu, Junfeng Zhao, Yasha Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Multi-modal Models Can Interpret Features in Large Multi-modal Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.14982</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.14982v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Recent advances in Large Multimodal Models (LMMs) lead to significant breakthroughs in both academia and industry. One question that arises is how we, as humans, can understand their internal neural representations. This paper takes an initial step towards addressing this question by presenting a versatile framework to identify and interpret the semantics within LMMs. Specifically, 1) we first apply a Sparse Autoencoder(SAE) to disentangle the representations into human understandable features. 2) We then present an automatic interpretation framework to interpreted the open-semantic features learned in SAE by the LMMs themselves. We employ this framework to analyze the LLaVA-NeXT-8B model using the LLaVA-OV-72B model, demonstrating that these features can effectively steer the model's behavior. Our results contribute to a deeper understanding of why LMMs excel in specific tasks, including EQ tests, and illuminate the nature of their mistakes along with potential strategies for their rectification. These findings offer new insights into the internal mechanisms of LMMs and suggest parallels with the cognitive processes of the human brain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.14982v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kaichen Zhang, Yifei Shen, Bo Li, Ziwei Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GASLITEing the Retrieval: Exploring Vulnerabilities in Dense Embedding-based Search</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.20953</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.20953v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Dense embedding-based text retrieval$\unicode{x2013}$retrieval of relevant passages from corpora via deep learning encodings$\unicode{x2013}$has emerged as a powerful method attaining state-of-the-art search results and popularizing Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG). Still, like other search methods, embedding-based retrieval may be susceptible to search-engine optimization (SEO) attacks, where adversaries promote malicious content by introducing adversarial passages to corpora. Prior work has shown such SEO is feasible, mostly demonstrating attacks against retrieval-integrated systems (e.g., RAG). Yet, these consider relaxed SEO threat models (e.g., targeting single queries), use baseline attack methods, and provide small-scale retrieval evaluation, thus obscuring our comprehensive understanding of retrievers' worst-case behavior. This work aims to faithfully and thoroughly assess retrievers' robustness, paving a path to uncover factors related to their susceptibility to SEO. To this end, we, first, propose the GASLITE attack for generating adversarial passages, that$\unicode{x2013}$without relying on the corpus content or modifying the model$\unicode{x2013}$carry adversary-chosen information while achieving high retrieval ranking, consistently outperforming prior approaches. Second, using GASLITE, we extensively evaluate retrievers' robustness, testing nine advanced models under varied threat models, while focusing on pertinent adversaries targeting queries on a specific concept (e.g., a public figure). Amongst our findings: retrievers are highly vulnerable to SEO against concept-specific queries, even under negligible poisoning rates (e.g., $\geq$0.0001% of the corpus), while generalizing across different corpora and query distributions; single-query SEO is completely solved by GASLITE; adaptive attacks demonstrate bypassing common defenses; [...]</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.20953v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Matan Ben-Tov, Mahmood Sharif</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>METAL: A Multi-Agent Framework for Chart Generation with Test-Time Scaling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.17651</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.17651v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Chart generation aims to generate code to produce charts satisfying the desired visual properties, e.g., texts, layout, color, and type. It has great potential to empower the automatic professional report generation in financial analysis, research presentation, education, and healthcare. In this work, we build a vision-language model (VLM) based multi-agent framework for effective automatic chart generation. Generating high-quality charts requires both strong visual design skills and precise coding capabilities that embed the desired visual properties into code. Such a complex multi-modal reasoning process is difficult for direct prompting of VLMs. To resolve these challenges, we propose METAL, a multi-agent framework that decomposes the task of chart generation into the iterative collaboration among specialized agents. METAL achieves 5.2% improvement over the current best result in the chart generation task. The METAL framework exhibits the phenomenon of test-time scaling: its performance increases monotonically as the logarithmic computational budget grows from 512 to 8192 tokens. In addition, we find that separating different modalities during the critique process of METAL boosts the self-correction capability of VLMs in the multimodal context.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.17651v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bingxuan Li, Yiwei Wang, Jiuxiang Gu, Kai-Wei Chang, Nanyun Peng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>InMind: Evaluating LLMs in Capturing and Applying Individual Human Reasoning Styles</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.16072</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.16072v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: LLMs have shown strong performance on human-centric reasoning tasks. While previous evaluations have explored whether LLMs can infer intentions or detect deception, they often overlook the individualized reasoning styles that influence how people interpret and act in social contexts. Social deduction games (SDGs) provide a natural testbed for evaluating individualized reasoning styles, where different players may adopt diverse but contextually valid reasoning strategies under identical conditions. To address this, we introduce InMind, a cognitively grounded evaluation framework designed to assess whether LLMs can capture and apply personalized reasoning styles in SDGs. InMind enhances structured gameplay data with round-level strategy traces and post-game reflections, collected under both Observer and Participant modes. It supports four cognitively motivated tasks that jointly evaluate both static alignment and dynamic adaptation. As a case study, we apply InMind to the game Avalon, evaluating 11 state-of-the-art LLMs. General-purpose LLMs, even GPT-4o frequently rely on lexical cues, struggling to anchor reflections in temporal gameplay or adapt to evolving strategies. In contrast, reasoning-enhanced LLMs like DeepSeek-R1 exhibit early signs of style-sensitive reasoning. These findings reveal key limitations in current LLMs' capacity for individualized, adaptive reasoning, and position InMind as a step toward cognitively aligned human-AI interaction.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.16072v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zizhen Li, Chuanhao Li, Yibin Wang, Qi Chen, Diping Song, Yukang Feng, Jianwen Sun, Jiaxin Ai, Fanrui Zhang, Mingzhu Sun, Kaipeng Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CSRM-LLM: Embracing Multilingual LLMs for Cold-Start Relevance Matching in Emerging E-commerce Markets</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.01566</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.01566v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: As global e-commerce platforms continue to expand, companies are entering new markets where they encounter cold-start challenges due to limited human labels and user behaviors. In this paper, we share our experiences in Coupang to provide a competitive cold-start performance of relevance matching for emerging e-commerce markets. Specifically, we present a Cold-Start Relevance Matching (CSRM) framework, utilizing a multilingual Large Language Model (LLM) to address three challenges: (1) activating cross-lingual transfer learning abilities of LLMs through machine translation tasks; (2) enhancing query understanding and incorporating e-commerce knowledge by retrieval-based query augmentation; (3) mitigating the impact of training label errors through a multi-round self-distillation training strategy. Our experiments demonstrate the effectiveness of CSRM-LLM and the proposed techniques, resulting in successful real-world deployment and significant online gains, with a 45.8% reduction in defect ratio and a 0.866% uplift in session purchase rate.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.01566v2</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yujing Wang, Yiren Chen, Huoran Li, Chunxu Xu, Yuchong Luo, Xianghui Mao, Cong Li, Lun Du, Chunyang Ma, Qiqi Jiang, Yin Wang, Fan Gao, Wenting Mo, Pei Wen, Shantanu Kumar, Taejin Park, Yiwei Song, Vijay Rajaram, Tao Cheng, Sonu Durgia, Pranam Kolari</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exact Coset Sampling for Quantum Lattice Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.12341</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.12341v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We give a simple and provably correct replacement for the contested ``domain-extension'' in Step 9 of a recent windowed-QFT lattice algorithm with complex-Gaussian windows~\citep{chen2024quantum}. The published Step 9 suffers from a periodicity/support mismatch. Our drop-in subroutine uses a pair-shift difference to cancel all unknown offsets exactly and to synthesize a uniform cyclic subgroup (zero-offset coset) of order $P$ inside $(\mathbb{Z}_{M_2})^n$. A subsequent QFT enforces the intended modular linear relation. The sole structural assumption is the residue accessibility condition, which enables coherent auxiliary cleanup; no amplitude periodicity is used. The unitary is reversible, uses $\mathrm{poly}(\log M_2)$ gates, and preserves upstream asymptotics.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.12341v2</guid>
      <category>quant-ph</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yifan Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Noise Supervised Contrastive Learning and Feature-Perturbed for Anomalous Sound Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.13853</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.13853v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Unsupervised anomalous sound detection aims to detect unknown anomalous sounds by training a model using only normal audio data. Despite advancements in self-supervised methods, the issue of frequent false alarms when handling samples of the same type from different machines remains unresolved. This paper introduces a novel training technique called one-stage supervised contrastive learning (OS-SCL), which significantly addresses this problem by perturbing features in the embedding space and employing a one-stage noisy supervised contrastive learning approach. On the DCASE 2020 Challenge Task 2, it achieved 94.64\% AUC, 88.42\% pAUC, and 89.24\% mAUC using only Log-Mel features. Additionally, a time-frequency feature named TFgram is proposed, which is extracted from raw audio. This feature effectively captures critical information for anomalous sound detection, ultimately achieving 95.71\% AUC, 90.23\% pAUC, and 91.23\% mAUC. The source code is available at: \underline{www.github.com/huangswt/OS-SCL}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.13853v2</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shun Huang, Zhihua Fang, Liang He</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dense Video Understanding with Gated Residual Tokenization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14199</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14199v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: High temporal resolution is essential for capturing fine-grained details in video understanding. However, current video large language models (VLLMs) and benchmarks mostly rely on low-frame-rate sampling, such as uniform sampling or keyframe selection, discarding dense temporal information. This compromise avoids the high cost of tokenizing every frame, which otherwise leads to redundant computation and linear token growth as video length increases. While this trade-off works for slowly changing content, it fails for tasks like lecture comprehension, where information appears in nearly every frame and requires precise temporal alignment. To address this gap, we introduce Dense Video Understanding (DVU), which enables high-FPS video comprehension by reducing both tokenization time and token overhead. Existing benchmarks are also limited, as their QA pairs focus on coarse content changes. We therefore propose DIVE (Dense Information Video Evaluation), the first benchmark designed for dense temporal reasoning. To make DVU practical, we present Gated Residual Tokenization (GRT), a two-stage framework: (1) Motion-Compensated Inter-Gated Tokenization uses pixel-level motion estimation to skip static regions during tokenization, achieving sub-linear growth in token count and compute. (2) Semantic-Scene Intra-Tokenization Merging fuses tokens across static regions within a scene, further reducing redundancy while preserving dynamic semantics. Experiments on DIVE show that GRT outperforms larger VLLM baselines and scales positively with FPS. These results highlight the importance of dense temporal information and demonstrate that GRT enables efficient, scalable high-FPS video understanding.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14199v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haichao Zhang, Wenhao Chai, Shwai He, Ang Li, Yun Fu</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
