<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL</link>
    <description>cs.CL updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 05:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Sunday</day>
      <day>Saturday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>Teaching People LLM's Errors and Getting it Right</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21422</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21422v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: People use large language models (LLMs) when they should not. This is partly because they see LLMs compose poems and answer intricate questions, so they understandably, but incorrectly, assume LLMs won't stumble on basic tasks like simple arithmetic. Prior work has tried to address this by clustering instance embeddings into regions where an LLM is likely to fail and automatically describing patterns in these regions. The found failure patterns are taught to users to mitigate their overreliance. Yet, this approach has not fully succeeded. In this analysis paper, we aim to understand why.
  We first examine whether the negative result stems from the absence of failure patterns. We group instances in two datasets by their meta-labels and evaluate an LLM's predictions on these groups. We then define criteria to flag groups that are sizable and where the LLM is error-prone, and find meta-label groups that meet these criteria. Their meta-labels are the LLM's failure patterns that could be taught to users, so they do exist. We next test whether prompting and embedding-based approaches can surface these known failures. Without this, users cannot be taught about them to reduce their overreliance. We find mixed results across methods, which could explain the negative result. Finally, we revisit the final metric that measures teaching effectiveness. We propose to assess a user's ability to effectively use the given failure patterns to anticipate when an LLM is error-prone. A user study shows a positive effect from teaching with this metric, unlike the human-AI team accuracy. Our findings show that teaching failure patterns could be a viable approach to mitigating overreliance, but success depends on better automated failure-discovery methods and using metrics like ours.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21422v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nathan Stringham, Fateme Hashemi Chaleshtori, Xinyuan Yan, Zhichao Xu, Bei Wang, Ana Marasovi\'c</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morality is Contextual: Learning Interpretable Moral Contexts from Human Data with Probabilistic Clustering and Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21439</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21439v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Moral actions are judged not only by their outcomes but by the context in which they occur. We present COMETH (Contextual Organization of Moral Evaluation from Textual Human inputs), a framework that integrates a probabilistic context learner with LLM-based semantic abstraction and human moral evaluations to model how context shapes the acceptability of ambiguous actions. We curate an empirically grounded dataset of 300 scenarios across six core actions (violating Do not kill, Do not deceive, and Do not break the law) and collect ternary judgments (Blame/Neutral/Support) from N=101 participants. A preprocessing pipeline standardizes actions via an LLM filter and MiniLM embeddings with K-means, producing robust, reproducible core-action clusters. COMETH then learns action-specific moral contexts by clustering scenarios online from human judgment distributions using principled divergence criteria. To generalize and explain predictions, a Generalization module extracts concise, non-evaluative binary contextual features and learns feature weights in a transparent likelihood-based model. Empirically, COMETH roughly doubles alignment with majority human judgments relative to end-to-end LLM prompting (approx. 60% vs. approx. 30% on average), while revealing which contextual features drive its predictions. The contributions are: (i) an empirically grounded moral-context dataset, (ii) a reproducible pipeline combining human judgments with model-based context learning and LLM semantics, and (iii) an interpretable alternative to end-to-end LLMs for context-sensitive moral prediction and explanation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21439v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Geoffroy Morlat, Marceau Nahon, Augustin Chartouny, Raja Chatila, Ismael T. Freire, Mehdi Khamassi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oogiri-Master: Benchmarking Humor Understanding via Oogiri</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21494</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21494v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Humor is a salient testbed for human-like creative thinking in large language models (LLMs). We study humor using the Japanese creative response game Oogiri, in which participants produce witty responses to a given prompt, and ask the following research question: What makes such responses funny to humans? Previous work has offered only limited reliable means to answer this question. Existing datasets contain few candidate responses per prompt, expose popularity signals during ratings, and lack objective and comparable metrics for funniness. Thus, we introduce Oogiri-Master and Oogiri-Corpus, which are a benchmark and dataset designed to enable rigorous evaluation of humor understanding in LLMs. Each prompt is paired with approximately 100 diverse candidate responses, and funniness is rated independently by approximately 100 human judges without access to others' ratings, reducing popularity bias and enabling robust aggregation. Using Oogiri-Corpus, we conduct a quantitative analysis of the linguistic factors associated with funniness, such as text length, ambiguity, and incongruity resolution, and derive objective metrics for predicting human judgments. Subsequently, we benchmark a range of LLMs and human baselines in Oogiri-Master, demonstrating that state-of-the-art models approach human performance and that insight-augmented prompting improves the model performance. Our results provide a principled basis for evaluating and advancing humor understanding in LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21494v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Soichiro Murakami, Hidetaka Kamigaito, Hiroya Takamura, Manabu Okumura</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Heuristics: A Decision-Theoretic Framework for Agent Memory Management</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21567</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21567v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: External memory is a key component of modern large language model (LLM) systems, enabling long-term interaction and personalization. Despite its importance, memory management is still largely driven by hand-designed heuristics, offering little insight into the long-term and uncertain consequences of memory decisions. In practice, choices about what to read or write shape future retrieval and downstream behavior in ways that are difficult to anticipate. We argue that memory management should be viewed as a sequential decision-making problem under uncertainty, where the utility of memory is delayed and dependent on future interactions. To this end, we propose DAM (Decision-theoretic Agent Memory), a decision-theoretic framework that decomposes memory management into immediate information access and hierarchical storage maintenance. Within this architecture, candidate operations are evaluated via value functions and uncertainty estimators, enabling an aggregate policy to arbitrate decisions based on estimated long-term utility and risk. Our contribution is not a new algorithm, but a principled reframing that clarifies the limitations of heuristic approaches and provides a foundation for future research on uncertainty-aware memory systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21567v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Changzhi Sun, Xiangyu Chen, Jixiang Luo, Dell Zhang, Xuelong Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Unified Definition of Hallucination, Or: It's the World Model, Stupid</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21577</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21577v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Despite numerous attempts to solve the issue of hallucination since the inception of neural language models, it remains a problem in even frontier large language models today. Why is this the case? We walk through definitions of hallucination used in the literature from a historical perspective up to the current day, and fold them into a single definition of hallucination, wherein different prior definitions focus on different aspects of our definition. At its core, we argue that hallucination is simply inaccurate (internal) world modeling, in a form where it is observable to the user (e.g., stating a fact which contradicts a knowledge base, or producing a summary which contradicts a known source). By varying the reference world model as well as the knowledge conflict policy (e.g., knowledge base vs. in-context), we arrive at the different existing definitions of hallucination present in the literature.
  We argue that this unified view is useful because it forces evaluations to make clear their assumed "world" or source of truth, clarifies what should and should not be called hallucination (as opposed to planning or reward/incentive-related errors), and provides a common language to compare benchmarks and mitigation techniques. Building on this definition, we outline plans for a family of benchmarks in which hallucinations are defined as mismatches with synthetic but fully specified world models in different environments, and sketch out how these benchmarks can use such settings to stress-test and improve the world modeling components of language models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21577v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Emmy Liu, Varun Gangal, Chelsea Zou, Xiaoqi Huang, Michael Yu, Alex Chang, Zhuofu Tao, Sachin Kumar, Steven Y. Feng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gamayun's Path to Multilingual Mastery: Cost-Efficient Training of a 1.5B-Parameter LLM</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21580</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21580v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present Gamayun, a 1.5B-parameter multilingual language model trained entirely from scratch on 2.5T tokens. Designed for efficiency and deployment in resource-constrained environments, Gamayun addresses the lack of research on small non-English-centric LLMs by adopting a novel two-stage pre-training strategy: balanced multilingual training for cross-lingual alignment, followed by high-quality English enrichment to transfer performance gains across languages. Our model supports 12 languages, with special focus on Russian. Despite a significantly smaller training budget than comparable models, Gamayun outperforms LLaMA3.2-1B (9T tokens) on all considered benchmarks, and surpasses Qwen2.5-1.5B (18T tokens) on a wide range of English and multilingual tasks. It matches or exceeds Qwen3 (36T tokens) on most tasks outside advanced STEM, achieving state-of-the-art results in Russian, including the MERA benchmark, among the models of comparable size (1-2B parameters).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21580v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alexander Podolskiy, Semen Molokov, Timofey Gerasin, Maksim Titov, Alexey Rukhovich, Artem Khrapov, Kirill Morozov, Evgeny Tetin, Constantine Korikov, Pavel Efimov, Polina Lazukova, Yuliya Skripkar, Nikita Okhotnikov, Irina Piontkovskaya, Meng Xiaojun, Zou Xueyi, Zhang Zhenhe</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Sample Polarity in Reinforcement Learning with Verifiable Rewards</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21625</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21625v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large reasoning models (LRMs) are typically trained using reinforcement learning with verifiable reward (RLVR) to enhance their reasoning abilities. In this paradigm, policies are updated using both positive and negative self-generated rollouts, which correspond to distinct sample polarities. In this paper, we provide a systematic investigation into how these sample polarities affect RLVR training dynamics and behaviors. We find that positive samples sharpen existing correct reasoning patterns, while negative samples encourage exploration of new reasoning paths. We further explore how adjusting the advantage values of positive and negative samples at both the sample level and the token level affects RLVR training. Based on these insights, we propose an Adaptive and Asymmetric token-level Advantage shaping method for Policy Optimization, namely A3PO, that more precisely allocates advantage signals to key tokens across different polarities. Experiments across five reasoning benchmarks demonstrate the effectiveness of our approach.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21625v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xinyu Tang, Yuliang Zhan, Zhixun Li, Wayne Xin Zhao, Zhenduo Zhang, Zujie Wen, Zhiqiang Zhang, Jun Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heaven-Sent or Hell-Bent? Benchmarking the Intelligence and Defectiveness of LLM Hallucinations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21635</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21635v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Hallucinations in large language models (LLMs) are commonly regarded as errors to be minimized. However, recent perspectives suggest that some hallucinations may encode creative or epistemically valuable content, a dimension that remains underquantified in current literature. Existing hallucination detection methods primarily focus on factual consistency, struggling to handle heterogeneous scientific tasks and balance creativity with accuracy. To address these challenges, we propose HIC-Bench, a novel evaluation framework that categorizes hallucinations into Intelligent Hallucinations (IH) and Defective Hallucinations (DH), enabling systematic investigation of their interplay in LLM creativity. HIC-Bench features three core characteristics: (1) Structured IH/DH Assessment. using a multi-dimensional metric matrix integrating Torrance Tests of Creative Thinking (TTCT) metrics (Originality, Feasibility, Value) with hallucination-specific dimensions (scientific plausibility, factual deviation); (2) Cross-Domain Applicability. spanning ten scientific domains with open-ended innovation tasks; and (3) Dynamic Prompt Optimization. leveraging the Dynamic Hallucination Prompt (DHP) to guide models toward creative and reliable outputs. The evaluation process employs multiple LLM judges, averaging scores to mitigate bias, with human annotators verifying IH/DH classifications. Experimental results reveal a nonlinear relationship between IH and DH, demonstrating that creativity and correctness can be jointly optimized. These insights position IH as a catalyst for creativity and reveal the ability of LLM hallucinations to drive scientific innovation.Additionally, the HIC-Bench offers a valuable platform for advancing research into the creative intelligence of LLM hallucinations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21635v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chengxu Yang, Jingling Yuan, Siqi Cai, Jiawei Jiang, Chuang Hu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enabling Conversational Behavior Reasoning Capabilities in Full-Duplex Speech</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21706</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21706v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Human conversation is organized by an implicit chain of thoughts that manifests as timed speech acts. Capturing this causal pathway is key to building natural full-duplex interactive systems. We introduce a framework that enables reasoning over conversational behaviors by modeling this process as causal inference within a Graph-of-Thoughts (GoT). Our approach formalizes the intent-to-action pathway with a hierarchical labeling scheme, predicting high-level communicative intents and low-level speech acts to learn their causal and temporal dependencies. To train this system, we develop a hybrid corpus that pairs controllable, event-rich simulations with human-annotated rationales and real conversational speech. The GoT framework structures streaming predictions as an evolving graph, enabling a multimodal transformer to forecast the next speech act, generate concise justifications for its decisions, and dynamically refine its reasoning. Experiments on both synthetic and real duplex dialogues show that the framework delivers robust behavior detection, produces interpretable reasoning chains, and establishes a foundation for benchmarking conversational reasoning in full duplex spoken dialogue systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21706v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shuchang Pan, Siddharth Banerjee, Dhruv Hebbar, Siddhant Patel, Akshaj Gupta, Kan Jen Cheng, Hanjo Kim, Zeyi Austin Li, Martin Q. Ma, Tingle Li, Gopala Anumanchipalli, Jiachen Lian</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MoRAgent: Parameter Efficient Agent Tuning with Mixture-of-Roles</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21708</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21708v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Despite recent advancements of fine-tuning large language models (LLMs) to facilitate agent tasks, parameter-efficient fine-tuning (PEFT) methodologies for agent remain largely unexplored. In this paper, we introduce three key strategies for PEFT in agent tasks: 1) Inspired by the increasingly dominant Reason+Action paradigm, we first decompose the capabilities necessary for the agent tasks into three distinct roles: reasoner, executor, and summarizer. The reasoner is responsible for comprehending the user's query and determining the next role based on the execution trajectory. The executor is tasked with identifying the appropriate functions and parameters to invoke. The summarizer conveys the distilled information from conversations back to the user. 2) We then propose the Mixture-of-Roles (MoR) framework, which comprises three specialized Low-Rank Adaptation (LoRA) groups, each designated to fulfill a distinct role. By focusing on their respective specialized capabilities and engaging in collaborative interactions, these LoRAs collectively accomplish the agent task. 3) To effectively fine-tune the framework, we develop a multi-role data generation pipeline based on publicly available datasets, incorporating role-specific content completion and reliability verification. We conduct extensive experiments and thorough ablation studies on various LLMs and agent benchmarks, demonstrating the effectiveness of the proposed method. This project is publicly available at https://mor-agent.github.io.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21708v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jing Han, Binwei Yan, Tianyu Guo, Zheyuan Bai, Mengyu Zheng, Hanting Chen, Ying Nie</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Detecting AI-Generated Paraphrases in Bengali: A Comparative Study of Zero-Shot and Fine-Tuned Transformers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21709</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21709v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) can produce text that closely resembles human writing. This capability raises concerns about misuse, including disinformation and content manipulation. Detecting AI-generated text is essential to maintain authenticity and prevent malicious applications. Existing research has addressed detection in multiple languages, but the Bengali language remains largely unexplored. Bengali's rich vocabulary and complex structure make distinguishing human-written and AI-generated text particularly challenging. This study investigates five transformer-based models: XLMRoBERTa-Large, mDeBERTaV3-Base, BanglaBERT-Base, IndicBERT-Base and MultilingualBERT-Base. Zero-shot evaluation shows that all models perform near chance levels (around 50% accuracy) and highlight the need for task-specific fine-tuning. Fine-tuning significantly improves performance, with XLM-RoBERTa, mDeBERTa and MultilingualBERT achieving around 91% on both accuracy and F1-score. IndicBERT demonstrates comparatively weaker performance, indicating limited effectiveness in fine-tuning for this task. This work advances AI-generated text detection in Bengali and establishes a foundation for building robust systems to counter AI-generated content.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21709v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Md. Rakibul Islam, Most. Sharmin Sultana Samu, Md. Zahid Hossain, Farhad Uz Zaman, Md. Kamrozzaman Bhuiyan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Latent Tokens Think? A Causal and Adversarial Analysis of Chain-of-Continuous-Thought</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21711</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21711v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Latent tokens are gaining attention for enhancing reasoning in large language models (LLMs), yet their internal mechanisms remain unclear. This paper examines the problem from a reliability perspective, uncovering fundamental weaknesses: latent tokens function as uninterpretable placeholders rather than encoding faithful reasoning. While resistant to perturbation, they promote shortcut usage over genuine reasoning. We focus on Chain-of-Continuous-Thought (COCONUT), which claims better efficiency and stability than explicit Chain-of-Thought (CoT) while maintaining performance. We investigate this through two complementary approaches. First, steering experiments perturb specific token subsets, namely COCONUT and explicit CoT. Unlike CoT tokens, COCONUT tokens show minimal sensitivity to steering and lack reasoning-critical information. Second, shortcut experiments evaluate models under biased and out-of-distribution settings. Results on MMLU and HotpotQA demonstrate that COCONUT consistently exploits dataset artifacts, inflating benchmark performance without true reasoning. These findings reposition COCONUT as a pseudo-reasoning mechanism: it generates plausible traces that conceal shortcut dependence rather than faithfully representing reasoning processes.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21711v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuyi Zhang, Boyu Tang, Tianjie Ju, Sufeng Duan, Gongshen Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CATCH: A Controllable Theme Detection Framework with Contextualized Clustering and Hierarchical Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21715</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21715v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Theme detection is a fundamental task in user-centric dialogue systems, aiming to identify the latent topic of each utterance without relying on predefined schemas. Unlike intent induction, which operates within fixed label spaces, theme detection requires cross-dialogue consistency and alignment with personalized user preferences, posing significant challenges. Existing methods often struggle with sparse, short utterances for accurate topic representation and fail to capture user-level thematic preferences across dialogues. To address these challenges, we propose CATCH (Controllable Theme Detection with Contextualized Clustering and Hierarchical Generation), a unified framework that integrates three core components: (1) context-aware topic representation, which enriches utterance-level semantics using surrounding topic segments; (2) preference-guided topic clustering, which jointly models semantic proximity and personalized feedback to align themes across dialogue; and (3) a hierarchical theme generation mechanism designed to suppress noise and produce robust, coherent topic labels. Experiments on a multi-domain customer dialogue benchmark (DSTC-12) demonstrate the effectiveness of CATCH with 8B LLM in both theme clustering and topic generation quality.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21715v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rui Ke, Jiahui Xu, Shenghao Yang, Kuang Wang, Feng Jiang, Haizhou Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ara-HOPE: Human-Centric Post-Editing Evaluation for Dialectal Arabic to Modern Standard Arabic Translation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21787</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21787v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Dialectal Arabic to Modern Standard Arabic (DA-MSA) translation is a challenging task in Machine Translation (MT) due to significant lexical, syntactic, and semantic divergences between Arabic dialects and MSA. Existing automatic evaluation metrics and general-purpose human evaluation frameworks struggle to capture dialect-specific MT errors, hindering progress in translation assessment. This paper introduces Ara-HOPE, a human-centric post-editing evaluation framework designed to systematically address these challenges. The framework includes a five-category error taxonomy and a decision-tree annotation protocol. Through comparative evaluation of three MT systems (Arabic-centric Jais, general-purpose GPT-3.5, and baseline NLLB-200), Ara-HOPE effectively highlights systematic performance differences between these systems. The results show that dialect-specific terminology and semantic preservation remain the most persistent challenges in DA-MSA translation. Ara-HOPE establishes a new framework for evaluating Dialectal Arabic MT quality and provides actionable guidance for improving dialect-aware MT systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21787v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Abdullah Alabdullah, Lifeng Han, Chenghua Lin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five Years of SciCap: What We Learned and Future Directions for Scientific Figure Captioning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21789</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21789v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Between 2021 and 2025, the SciCap project grew from a small seed-funded idea at The Pennsylvania State University (Penn State) into one of the central efforts shaping the scientific figure-captioning landscape. Supported by a Penn State seed grant, Adobe, and the Alfred P. Sloan Foundation, what began as our attempt to test whether domain-specific training, which was successful in text models like SciBERT, could also work for figure captions expanded into a multi-institution collaboration. Over these five years, we curated, released, and continually updated a large collection of figure-caption pairs from arXiv papers, conducted extensive automatic and human evaluations on both generated and author-written captions, navigated the rapid rise of large language models (LLMs), launched annual challenges, and built interactive systems that help scientists write better captions. In this piece, we look back at the first five years of SciCap and summarize the key technical and methodological lessons we learned. We then outline five major unsolved challenges and propose directions for the next phase of research in scientific figure captioning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21789v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ting-Hao K. Huang (Sam), Ryan A. Rossi (Sam), Sungchul Kim (Sam), Tong Yu (Sam), Ting-Yao E. Hsu (Sam), Ho Yin (Sam),  Ng, C. Lee Giles</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On The Conceptualization and Societal Impact of Cross-Cultural Bias</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21809</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21809v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Research has shown that while large language models (LLMs) can generate their responses based on cultural context, they are not perfect and tend to generalize across cultures. However, when evaluating the cultural bias of a language technology on any dataset, researchers may choose not to engage with stakeholders actually using that technology in real life, which evades the very fundamental problem they set out to address.
  Inspired by the work done by arXiv:2005.14050v2, I set out to analyse recent literature about identifying and evaluating cultural bias in Natural Language Processing (NLP). I picked out 20 papers published in 2025 about cultural bias and came up with a set of observations to allow NLP researchers in the future to conceptualize bias concretely and evaluate its harms effectively. My aim is to advocate for a robust assessment of the societal impact of language technologies exhibiting cross-cultural bias.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21809v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Vitthal Bhandari</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Method Decoration (DeMe): A Framework for LLM-Driven Adaptive Method Generation in Dynamic IoT Environments</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21817</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21817v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Intelligent IoT systems increasingly rely on large language models (LLMs) to generate task-execution methods for dynamic environments. However, existing approaches lack the ability to systematically produce new methods when facing previously unseen situations, and they often depend on fixed, device-specific logic that cannot adapt to changing environmental conditions.In this paper, we propose Method Decoration (DeMe), a general framework that modifies the method-generation path of an LLM using explicit decorations derived from hidden goals, accumulated learned methods, and environmental feedback. Unlike traditional rule augmentation, decorations in DeMe are not hardcoded; instead, they are extracted from universal behavioral principles, experience, and observed environmental differences. DeMe enables the agent to reshuffle the structure of its method path-through pre-decoration, post-decoration, intermediate-step modification, and step insertion-thereby producing context-aware, safety-aligned, and environment-adaptive methods. Experimental results show that method decoration allows IoT devices to derive ore appropriate methods when confronting unknown or faulty operating conditions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21817v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hong Su</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Reasoning of Large Language Models Integrating Graph-Structured Information for Pest and Disease Control in Tobacco</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21837</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21837v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper proposes a large language model (LLM) approach that integrates graph-structured information for knowledge reasoning in tobacco pest and disease control. Built upon the GraphRAG framework, the proposed method enhances knowledge retrieval and reasoning by explicitly incorporating structured information from a domain-specific knowledge graph. Specifically, LLMs are first leveraged to assist in the construction of a tobacco pest and disease knowledge graph, which organizes key entities such as diseases, symptoms, control methods, and their relationships. Based on this graph, relevant knowledge is retrieved and integrated into the reasoning process to support accurate answer generation. The Transformer architecture is adopted as the core inference model, while a graph neural network (GNN) is employed to learn expressive node representations that capture both local and global relational information within the knowledge graph. A ChatGLM-based model serves as the backbone LLM and is fine-tuned using LoRA to achieve parameter-efficient adaptation. Extensive experimental results demonstrate that the proposed approach consistently outperforms baseline methods across multiple evaluation metrics, significantly improving both the accuracy and depth of reasoning, particularly in complex multi-hop and comparative reasoning scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21837v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Siyu Li, Chenwei Song, Wan Zhou, Xinyi Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AlignAR: Generative Sentence Alignment for Arabic-English Parallel Corpora of Legal and Literary Texts</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21842</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21842v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: High-quality parallel corpora are essential for Machine Translation (MT) research and translation teaching. However, Arabic-English resources remain scarce and existing datasets mainly consist of simple one-to-one mappings. In this paper, we present AlignAR, a generative sentence alignment method, and a new Arabic-English dataset comprising complex legal and literary texts. Our evaluation demonstrates that "Easy" datasets lack the discriminatory power to fully assess alignment methods. By reducing one-to-one mappings in our "Hard" subset, we exposed the limitations of traditional alignment methods. In contrast, LLM-based approaches demonstrated superior robustness, achieving an overall F1-score of 85.5%, a 9% improvement over previous methods. Our datasets and codes are open-sourced at https://github.com/XXX.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21842v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Baorong Huang, Ali Asiri</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HeartBench: Probing Core Dimensions of Anthropomorphic Intelligence in LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21849</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21849v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: While Large Language Models (LLMs) have achieved remarkable success in cognitive and reasoning benchmarks, they exhibit a persistent deficit in anthropomorphic intelligence-the capacity to navigate complex social, emotional, and ethical nuances. This gap is particularly acute in the Chinese linguistic and cultural context, where a lack of specialized evaluation frameworks and high-quality socio-emotional data impedes progress. To address these limitations, we present HeartBench, a framework designed to evaluate the integrated emotional, cultural, and ethical dimensions of Chinese LLMs. Grounded in authentic psychological counseling scenarios and developed in collaboration with clinical experts, the benchmark is structured around a theory-driven taxonomy comprising five primary dimensions and 15 secondary capabilities. We implement a case-specific, rubric-based methodology that translates abstract human-like traits into granular, measurable criteria through a ``reasoning-before-scoring'' evaluation protocol. Our assessment of 13 state-of-the-art LLMs indicates a substantial performance ceiling: even leading models achieve only 60% of the expert-defined ideal score. Furthermore, analysis using a difficulty-stratified ``Hard Set'' reveals a significant performance decay in scenarios involving subtle emotional subtexts and complex ethical trade-offs. HeartBench establishes a standardized metric for anthropomorphic AI evaluation and provides a methodological blueprint for constructing high-quality, human-aligned training data.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21849v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiaxin Liu, Peiyi Tu, Wenyu Chen, Yihong Zhuang, Xinxia Ling, Anji Zhou, Chenxi Wang, Zhuo Han, Zhengkai Yang, Junbo Zhao, Zenan Huang, Yuanyuan Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TimeBill: Time-Budgeted Inference for Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21859</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21859v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) are increasingly deployed in time-critical systems, such as robotics, autonomous driving, embodied intelligence, and industrial automation, where generating accurate responses within a given time budget is crucial for decision-making, control, or safety-critical tasks. However, the auto-regressive generation process of LLMs makes it challenging to model and estimate the end-to-end execution time. Furthermore, existing efficient inference methods based on a fixed key-value (KV) cache eviction ratio struggle to adapt to varying tasks with diverse time budgets, where an improper eviction ratio may lead to incomplete inference or a drop in response performance. In this paper, we propose TimeBill, a novel time-budgeted inference framework for LLMs that balances the inference efficiency and response performance. To be more specific, we propose a fine-grained response length predictor (RLP) and an execution time estimator (ETE) to accurately predict the end-to-end execution time of LLMs. Following this, we develop a time-budgeted efficient inference approach that adaptively adjusts the KV cache eviction ratio based on execution time prediction and the given time budget. Finally, through extensive experiments, we demonstrate the advantages of TimeBill in improving task completion rate and maintaining response performance under various overrun strategies.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21859v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qi Fan, An Zou, Yehan Ma</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the Copyright Gap: Do Large Vision-Language Models Recognize and Respect Copyrighted Content?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21871</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21871v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large vision-language models (LVLMs) have achieved remarkable advancements in multimodal reasoning tasks. However, their widespread accessibility raises critical concerns about potential copyright infringement. Will LVLMs accurately recognize and comply with copyright regulations when encountering copyrighted content (i.e., user input, retrieved documents) in the context? Failure to comply with copyright regulations may lead to serious legal and ethical consequences, particularly when LVLMs generate responses based on copyrighted materials (e.g., retrieved book experts, news reports). In this paper, we present a comprehensive evaluation of various LVLMs, examining how they handle copyrighted content -- such as book excerpts, news articles, music lyrics, and code documentation when they are presented as visual inputs. To systematically measure copyright compliance, we introduce a large-scale benchmark dataset comprising 50,000 multimodal query-content pairs designed to evaluate how effectively LVLMs handle queries that could lead to copyright infringement. Given that real-world copyrighted content may or may not include a copyright notice, the dataset includes query-content pairs in two distinct scenarios: with and without a copyright notice. For the former, we extensively cover four types of copyright notices to account for different cases. Our evaluation reveals that even state-of-the-art closed-source LVLMs exhibit significant deficiencies in recognizing and respecting the copyrighted content, even when presented with the copyright notice. To solve this limitation, we introduce a novel tool-augmented defense framework for copyright compliance, which reduces infringement risks in all scenarios. Our findings underscore the importance of developing copyright-aware LVLMs to ensure the responsible and lawful use of copyrighted content.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21871v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Naen Xu, Jinghuai Zhang, Changjiang Li, Hengyu An, Chunyi Zhou, Jun Wang, Boyu Xu, Yuyuan Li, Tianyu Du, Shouling Ji</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CricBench: A Multilingual Benchmark for Evaluating LLMs in Cricket Analytics</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21877</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21877v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Cricket is the second most popular sport globally, commanding a massive following of over 2.5 billion fans globally. Enthusiasts and analysts frequently seek advanced statistical insights, such as long-term historical performance trends or complex player comparisons, that are often unavailable through standard web searches. While Large Language Models (LLMs) have advanced significantly in Text-to-SQL tasks, their capability to handle the domain-specific nuances, complex schema variations, and multilingual requirements inherent to sports analytics remains under-explored. To investigate this potential capability gap, we present CricBench, a comprehensive benchmark suite for evaluating LLMs on specialized cricket data. To curate a "Gold Standard" dataset, we collaborate with domain experts in cricket and SQL to manually author complex queries, ensuring logical correctness. Recognizing linguistic diversity, we construct the benchmark in both English and Hindi, establishing a framework that is open for further extension to other regional languages. We evaluate six state-of-the-art models, including GPT-4o, Claude 3.7 Sonnet, and open-source models, using a strict evaluation protocol. Our results reveal that high performance on general benchmarks does not guarantee success in specialized domains. While the open-weights reasoning model DeepSeek R1 achieves state-of-the-art performance (50.6%), surpassing proprietary giants like Claude 3.7 Sonnet (47.7%) and GPT-4o (33.7%), it still exhibits a significant accuracy drop when moving from general benchmarks (BIRD) to CricBench. Furthermore, we observe that code-mixed Hindi queries frequently yield parity or higher accuracy compared to English, challenging the assumption that English is the optimal prompt language for specialized SQL tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21877v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Vaibhav Devraj, Dhruv Kumar, Jagat Sesh Challa</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explainable Statute Prediction via Attention-based Model and LLM Prompting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21902</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21902v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this paper, we explore the problem of automatic statute prediction where for a given case description, a subset of relevant statutes are to be predicted. Here, the term "statute" refers to a section, a sub-section, or an article of any specific Act. Addressing this problem would be useful in several applications such as AI-assistant for lawyers and legal question answering system. For better user acceptance of such Legal AI systems, we believe the predictions should also be accompanied by human understandable explanations. We propose two techniques for addressing this problem of statute prediction with explanations -- (i) AoS (Attention-over-Sentences) which uses attention over sentences in a case description to predict statutes relevant for it and (ii) LLMPrompt which prompts an LLM to predict as well as explain relevance of a certain statute. AoS uses smaller language models, specifically sentence transformers and is trained in a supervised manner whereas LLMPrompt uses larger language models in a zero-shot manner and explores both standard as well as Chain-of-Thought (CoT) prompting techniques. Both these models produce explanations for their predictions in human understandable forms. We compare statute prediction performance of both the proposed techniques with each other as well as with a set of competent baselines, across two popular datasets. Also, we evaluate the quality of the generated explanations through an automated counter-factual manner as well as through human evaluation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21902v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sachin Pawar, Girish Keshav Palshikar, Anindita Sinha Banerjee, Nitin Ramrakhiyani, Basit Ali</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate Speculative Decoding with Sparse Computation in Verification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21911</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21911v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Speculative decoding accelerates autoregressive language model inference by verifying multiple draft tokens in parallel. However, the verification stage often becomes the dominant computational bottleneck, especially for long-context inputs and mixture-of-experts (MoE) models. Existing sparsification methods are designed primarily for standard token-by-token autoregressive decoding to remove substantial computational redundancy in LLMs. This work systematically adopts different sparse methods on the verification stage of the speculative decoding and identifies structured redundancy across multiple dimensions. Based on these observations, we propose a sparse verification framework that jointly sparsifies attention, FFN, and MoE components during the verification stage to reduce the dominant computation cost. The framework further incorporates an inter-draft token and inter-layer retrieval reuse strategy to further reduce redundant computation without introducing additional training. Extensive experiments across summarization, question answering, and mathematical reasoning datasets demonstrate that the proposed methods achieve favorable efficiency-accuracy trade-offs, while maintaining stable acceptance length.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21911v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jikai Wang, Jianchao Tan, Yuxuan Hu, Jiayu Qin, Yerui Sun, Yuchen Xie, Xunliang Cai, Juntao Li, Min Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SWE-RM: Execution-free Feedback For Software Engineering Agents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21919</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21919v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Execution-based feedback like unit testing is widely used in the development of coding agents through test-time scaling (TTS) and reinforcement learning (RL). This paradigm requires scalable and reliable collection of unit test cases to provide accurate feedback, and the resulting feedback is often sparse and cannot effectively distinguish between trajectories that are both successful or both unsuccessful. In contrast, execution-free feedback from reward models can provide more fine-grained signals without depending on unit test cases. Despite this potential, execution-free feedback for realistic software engineering (SWE) agents remains underexplored. Aiming to develop versatile reward models that are effective across TTS and RL, however, we observe that two verifiers with nearly identical TTS performance can nevertheless yield very different results in RL. Intuitively, TTS primarily reflects the model's ability to select the best trajectory, but this ability does not necessarily generalize to RL. To address this limitation, we identify two additional aspects that are crucial for RL training: classification accuracy and calibration. We then conduct comprehensive controlled experiments to investigate how to train a robust reward model that performs well across these metrics. In particular, we analyze the impact of various factors such as training data scale, policy mixtures, and data source composition. Guided by these investigations, we introduce SWE-RM, an accurate and robust reward model adopting a mixture-of-experts architecture with 30B total parameters and 3B activated during inference. SWE-RM substantially improves SWE agents on both TTS and RL performance. For example, it increases the accuracy of Qwen3-Coder-Flash from 51.6% to 62.0%, and Qwen3-Coder-Max from 67.0% to 74.6% on SWE-Bench Verified using TTS, achieving new state-of-the-art performance among open-source models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21919v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>KaShun Shum, Binyuan Hui, Jiawei Chen, Lei Zhang, X. W., Jiaxi Yang, Yuzhen Huang, Junyang Lin, Junxian He</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Broken Words, Broken Performance: Effect of Tokenization on Performance of LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21933</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21933v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Tokenization is the first step in training any Large Language Model (LLM), where the text is split into a sequence of tokens as per the model's fixed vocabulary. This tokenization in LLMs is different from the traditional tokenization in NLP where the text is split into a sequence of "natural" words. In LLMs, a natural word may also be broken into multiple tokens due to limited vocabulary size of the LLMs (e.g., Mistral's tokenizer splits "martial" into "mart" and "ial"). In this paper, we hypothesize that such breaking of natural words negatively impacts LLM performance on various NLP tasks. To quantify this effect, we propose a set of penalty functions that compute a tokenization penalty for a given text for a specific LLM, indicating how "bad" the tokenization is. We establish statistical significance of our hypothesis on multiple NLP tasks for a set of different LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21933v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sachin Pawar, Manoj Apte, Kshitij Jadhav, Girish Keshav Palshikar, Nitin Ramrakhiyani</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-attention vector output similarities reveal how machines pay attention</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21956</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21956v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The self-attention mechanism has significantly advanced the field of natural language processing, facilitating the development of advanced language-learning machines. Although its utility is widely acknowledged, the precise mechanisms of self-attention underlying its advanced learning and the quantitative characterization of this learning process remains an open research question. This study introduces a new approach for quantifying information processing within the self-attention mechanism. The analysis conducted on the BERT-12 architecture reveals that, in the final layers, the attention map focuses on sentence separator tokens, suggesting a practical approach to text segmentation based on semantic features. Based on the vector space emerging from the self-attention heads, a context similarity matrix, measuring the scalar product between two token vectors was derived, revealing distinct similarities between different token vector pairs within each head and layer. The findings demonstrated that different attention heads within an attention block focused on different linguistic characteristics, such as identifying token repetitions in a given text or recognizing a token of common appearance in the text and its surrounding context. This specialization is also reflected in the distribution of distances between token vectors with high similarity as the architecture progresses. The initial attention layers exhibit substantially long-range similarities; however, as the layers progress, a more short-range similarity develops, culminating in a preference for attention heads to create strong similarities within the same sentence. Finally, the behavior of individual heads was analyzed by examining the uniqueness of their most common tokens in their high similarity elements. Each head tends to focus on a unique token from the text and builds similarity pairs centered around it.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21956v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tal Halevi, Yarden Tzach, Ronit D. Gross, Shalom Rosner, Ido Kanter</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Context as a Tool: Context Management for Long-Horizon SWE-Agents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.22087</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.22087v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Agents based on large language models have recently shown strong potential on real-world software engineering (SWE) tasks that require long-horizon interaction with repository-scale codebases. However, most existing agents rely on append-only context maintenance or passively triggered compression heuristics, which often lead to context explosion, semantic drift, and degraded reasoning in long-running interactions. We propose CAT, a new context management paradigm that elevates context maintenance to a callable tool integrated into the decision-making process of agents. CAT formalizes a structured context workspace consisting of stable task semantics, condensed long-term memory, and high-fidelity short-term interactions, and enables agents to proactively compress historical trajectories into actionable summaries at appropriate milestones. To support context management for SWE-agents, we propose a trajectory-level supervision framework, CAT-GENERATOR, based on an offline data construction pipeline that injects context-management actions into complete interaction trajectories. Using this framework, we train a context-aware model, SWE-Compressor. Experiments on SWE-Bench-Verified demonstrate that SWE-Compressor reaches a 57.6% solved rate and significantly outperforms ReAct-based agents and static compression baselines, while maintaining stable and scalable long-horizon reasoning under a bounded context budget.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.22087v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shukai Liu, Jian Yang, Bo Jiang, Yizhi Li, Jinyang Guo, Xianglong Liu, Bryan Dai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing TrGLUE and SentiTurca: A Comprehensive Benchmark for Turkish General Language Understanding and Sentiment Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.22100</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.22100v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Evaluating the performance of various model architectures, such as transformers, large language models (LLMs), and other NLP systems, requires comprehensive benchmarks that measure performance across multiple dimensions. Among these, the evaluation of natural language understanding (NLU) is particularly critical as it serves as a fundamental criterion for assessing model capabilities. Thus, it is essential to establish benchmarks that enable thorough evaluation and analysis of NLU abilities from diverse perspectives. While the GLUE benchmark has set a standard for evaluating English NLU, similar benchmarks have been developed for other languages, such as CLUE for Chinese, FLUE for French, and JGLUE for Japanese. However, no comparable benchmark currently exists for the Turkish language. To address this gap, we introduce TrGLUE, a comprehensive benchmark encompassing a variety of NLU tasks for Turkish. In addition, we present SentiTurca, a specialized benchmark for sentiment analysis. To support researchers, we also provide fine-tuning and evaluation code for transformer-based models, facilitating the effective use of these benchmarks. TrGLUE comprises Turkish-native corpora curated to mirror the domains and task formulations of GLUE-style evaluations, with labels obtained through a semi-automated pipeline that combines strong LLM-based annotation, cross-model agreement checks, and subsequent human validation. This design prioritizes linguistic naturalness, minimizes direct translation artifacts, and yields a scalable, reproducible workflow. With TrGLUE, our goal is to establish a robust evaluation framework for Turkish NLU, empower researchers with valuable resources, and provide insights into generating high-quality semi-automated datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.22100v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Duygu Altinok</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Query Carefully: Detecting the Unanswerables in Text-to-SQL Tasks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21345</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21345v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Text-to-SQL systems allow non-SQL experts to interact with relational databases using natural language. However, their tendency to generate executable SQL for ambiguous, out-of-scope, or unanswerable queries introduces a hidden risk, as outputs may be misinterpreted as correct. This risk is especially serious in biomedical contexts, where precision is critical. We therefore present Query Carefully, a pipeline that integrates LLM-based SQL generation with explicit detection and handling of unanswerable inputs. Building on the OncoMX component of ScienceBenchmark, we construct OncoMX-NAQ (No-Answer Questions), a set of 80 no-answer questions spanning 8 categories (non-SQL, out-of-schema/domain, and multiple ambiguity types). Our approach employs llama3.3:70b with schema-aware prompts, explicit No-Answer Rules (NAR), and few-shot examples drawn from both answerable and unanswerable questions. We evaluate SQL exact match, result accuracy, and unanswerable-detection accuracy. On the OncoMX dev split, few-shot prompting with answerable examples increases result accuracy, and adding unanswerable examples does not degrade performance. On OncoMX-NAQ, balanced prompting achieves the highest unanswerable-detection accuracy (0.8), with near-perfect results for structurally defined categories (non-SQL, missing columns, out-of-domain) but persistent challenges for missing-value queries (0.5) and column ambiguity (0.3). A lightweight user interface surfaces interim SQL, execution results, and abstentions, supporting transparent and reliable text-to-SQL in biomedical applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21345v1</guid>
      <category>cs.DB</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jasmin Saxer (Institute of Computer Science, Zurich University of Applied Sciences, Winterthur, Switzerland), Isabella Maria Aigner (Institute of Medical Virology, University of Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland), Luise Linzmeier (Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, University Hospital Zurich, University of Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland), Andreas Weiler (Institute of Computer Science, Zurich University of Applied Sciences, Winterthur, Switzerland), Kurt Stockinger (Institute of Computer Science, Zurich University of Applied Sciences, Winterthur, Switzerland)</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MotionTeller: Multi-modal Integration of Wearable Time-Series with LLMs for Health and Behavioral Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21506</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21506v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: As wearable sensing becomes increasingly pervasive, a key challenge remains: how can we generate natural language summaries from raw physiological signals such as actigraphy - minute-level movement data collected via accelerometers? In this work, we introduce MotionTeller, a generative framework that natively integrates minute-level wearable activity data with large language models (LLMs). MotionTeller combines a pretrained actigraphy encoder with a lightweight projection module that maps behavioral embeddings into the token space of a frozen decoder-only LLM, enabling free-text, autoregressive generation of daily behavioral summaries. We construct a novel dataset of 54383 (actigraphy, text) pairs derived from real-world NHANES recordings, and train the model using cross-entropy loss with supervision only on the language tokens. MotionTeller achieves high semantic fidelity (BERTScore-F1 = 0.924) and lexical accuracy (ROUGE-1 = 0.722), outperforming prompt-based baselines by 7 percent in ROUGE-1. The average training loss converges to 0.38 by epoch 15, indicating stable optimization. Qualitative analysis confirms that MotionTeller captures circadian structure and behavioral transitions, while PCA plots reveal enhanced cluster alignment in embedding space post-training. Together, these results position MotionTeller as a scalable, interpretable system for transforming wearable sensor data into fluent, human-centered descriptions, introducing new pathways for behavioral monitoring, clinical review, and personalized health interventions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21506v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aiwei Zhang, Arvind Pillai, Andrew Campbell, Nicholas C. Jacobson</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perplexity-Aware Data Scaling Law: Perplexity Landscapes Predict Performance for Continual Pre-training</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21515</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21515v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Continual Pre-training (CPT) serves as a fundamental approach for adapting foundation models to domain-specific applications. Scaling laws for pre-training define a power-law relationship between dataset size and the test loss of an LLM. However, the marginal gains from simply increasing data for CPT diminish rapidly, yielding suboptimal data utilization and inefficient training. To address this challenge, we propose a novel perplexity-aware data scaling law to establish a predictive relationship between the perplexity landscape of domain-specific data and the test loss. Our approach leverages the perplexity derived from the pre-trained model on domain data as a proxy for estimating the knowledge gap, effectively quantifying the informational perplexity landscape of candidate training samples. By fitting this scaling law across diverse perplexity regimes, we enable adaptive selection of high-utility data subsets, prioritizing content that maximizes knowledge absorption while minimizing redundancy and noise. Extensive experiments demonstrate that our method consistently identifies near-optimal training subsets and achieves superior performance on both medical and general-domain benchmarks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21515v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lei Liu, Hao Zhu, Yue Shen, Zhixuan Chu, Jian Wang, Jinjie Gu, Kui Ren</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human-AI Interaction Alignment: Designing, Evaluating, and Evolving Value-Centered AI For Reciprocal Human-AI Futures</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21551</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21551v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The rapid integration of generative AI into everyday life underscores the need to move beyond unidirectional alignment models that only adapt AI to human values. This workshop focuses on bidirectional human-AI alignment, a dynamic, reciprocal process where humans and AI co-adapt through interaction, evaluation, and value-centered design. Building on our past CHI 2025 BiAlign SIG and ICLR 2025 Workshop, this workshop will bring together interdisciplinary researchers from HCI, AI, social sciences and more domains to advance value-centered AI and reciprocal human-AI collaboration. We focus on embedding human and societal values into alignment research, emphasizing not only steering AI toward human values but also enabling humans to critically engage with and evolve alongside AI systems. Through talks, interdisciplinary discussions, and collaborative activities, participants will explore methods for interactive alignment, frameworks for societal impact evaluation, and strategies for alignment in dynamic contexts. This workshop aims to bridge the disciplines' gaps and establish a shared agenda for responsible, reciprocal human-AI futures.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21551v1</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hua Shen (Cassandra), Tiffany Knearem (Cassandra), Divy Thakkar (Cassandra), Pat Pataranutaporn (Cassandra), Anoop Sinha (Cassandra),  Yike (Cassandra),  Shi, Jenny T. Liang, Lama Ahmad, Tanu Mitra, Brad A. Myers, Yang Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Codebooks as Effective Priors for Neural Speech Compression</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21653</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21653v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Speech codecs are traditionally optimized for waveform fidelity, allocating bits to preserve acoustic detail even when much of it can be inferred from linguistic structure. This leads to inefficient compression and suboptimal performance on downstream recognition tasks. We propose SemDAC, a semantic-aware neural audio codec that leverages semantic codebooks as effective priors for speech compression. In SemDAC, the first quantizer in a residual vector quantization (RVQ) stack is distilled from HuBERT features to produce semantic tokens that capture phonetic content, while subsequent quantizers model residual acoustics. A FiLM-conditioned decoder reconstructs audio conditioned on the semantic tokens, improving efficiency in the use of acoustic codebooks. Despite its simplicity, this design proves highly effective: SemDAC outperforms DAC across perceptual metrics and achieves lower WER when running Whisper on reconstructed speech, all while operating at substantially lower bitrates (e.g., 0.95 kbps vs. 2.5 kbps for DAC). These results demonstrate that semantic codebooks provide an effective inductive bias for neural speech compression, producing compact yet recognition-friendly representations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21653v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Liuyang Bai, Weiyi Lu, Li Guo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Information Theoretic Perspective on Agentic System Design</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21720</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21720v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Agentic language model (LM) systems power modern applications like "Deep Research" and "Claude Code," and leverage multi-LM architectures to overcome context limitations. Beneath their apparent diversity lies a recurring pattern: smaller "compressor" LMs (that can even run locally) distill raw context into compact text that is then consumed by larger "predictor" LMs. Despite their popularity, the design of compressor-predictor systems remains largely ad hoc, with little guidance on how compressor and predictor choices shape downstream performance. In practice, attributing gains to compression versus prediction requires costly, task-specific pairwise sweeps. We argue that these agentic system design questions are, at root, information-theoretic. Viewing the compressor LM as a noisy channel, we introduce a simple estimator of mutual information between the context and its compression to quantify compression quality in a task-independent way. We show that mutual information strongly predicts downstream performance, independent of any specific task. Through an information-theoretic framework, we perform a comprehensive empirical analysis across five datasets and three model families. Results reveal that larger compressors not only are more accurate, but also more token-efficient, conveying more bits of information per token. A 7B Qwen-2.5 compressor, for instance, is $1.6\times$ more accurate, $4.6\times$ more concise, and conveys $5.5\times$ more bits of mutual information per token than its 1.5B sibling. Across datasets, scaling compressors is substantially more effective than scaling predictors, enabling larger on-device compressors to pair with smaller cloud predictors. Applied to a Deep Research system, these principles enable local compressors as small as 3B parameters to recover $99\%$ of frontier-LM accuracy at $26\%$ of API costs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21720v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IT</category>
      <category>math.IT</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shizhe He, Avanika Narayan, Ishan S. Khare, Scott W. Linderman, Christopher R\'e, Dan Biderman</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward Secure and Compliant AI: Organizational Standards and Protocols for NLP Model Lifecycle Management</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.22060</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.22060v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Natural Language Processing (NLP) systems are increasingly used in sensitive domains such as healthcare, finance, and government, where they handle large volumes of personal and regulated data. However, these systems introduce distinct risks related to security, privacy, and regulatory compliance that are not fully addressed by existing AI governance frameworks. This paper introduces the Secure and Compliant NLP Lifecycle Management Framework (SC-NLP-LMF), a comprehensive six-phase model designed to ensure the secure operation of NLP systems from development to retirement. The framework, developed through a systematic PRISMA-based review of 45 peer-reviewed and regulatory sources, aligns with leading standards, including NIST AI RMF, ISO/IEC 42001:2023, the EU AI Act, and MITRE ATLAS. It integrates established methods for bias detection, privacy protection (differential privacy, federated learning), secure deployment, explainability, and secure model decommissioning. A healthcare case study illustrates how SC-NLP-LMF detects emerging terminology drift (e.g., COVID-related language) and guides compliant model updates. The framework offers organizations a practical, lifecycle-wide structure for developing, deploying, and maintaining secure and accountable NLP systems in high-risk environments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.22060v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sunil Arora, John Hastings</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unifying Learning Dynamics and Generalization in Transformers Scaling Law</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.22088</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.22088v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The scaling law, a cornerstone of Large Language Model (LLM) development, predicts improvements in model performance with increasing computational resources. Yet, while empirically validated, its theoretical underpinnings remain poorly understood. This work formalizes the learning dynamics of transformer-based language models as an ordinary differential equation (ODE) system, then approximates this process to kernel behaviors. Departing from prior toy-model analyses, we rigorously analyze stochastic gradient descent (SGD) training for multi-layer transformers on sequence-to-sequence data with arbitrary data distribution, closely mirroring real-world conditions. Our analysis characterizes the convergence of generalization error to the irreducible risk as computational resources scale with data, especially during the optimization process.
  We establish a theoretical upper bound on excess risk characterized by a distinct phase transition. In the initial optimization phase, the excess risk decays exponentially relative to the computational cost ${\sf C}$. However, once a specific resource allocation threshold is crossed, the system enters a statistical phase, where the generalization error follows a power-law decay of $\Theta(\mathsf{C}^{-1/6})$. Beyond this unified framework, our theory derives isolated scaling laws for model size, training time, and dataset size, elucidating how each variable independently governs the upper bounds of generalization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.22088v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chiwun Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A2P-Vis: an Analyzer-to-Presenter Agentic Pipeline for Visual Insights Generation and Reporting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.22101</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.22101v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Automating end-to-end data science pipeline with AI agents still stalls on two gaps: generating insightful, diverse visual evidence and assembling it into a coherent, professional report. We present A2P-Vis, a two-part, multi-agent pipeline that turns raw datasets into a high-quality data-visualization report. The Data Analyzer orchestrates profiling, proposes diverse visualization directions, generates and executes plotting code, filters low-quality figures with a legibility checker, and elicits candidate insights that are automatically scored for depth, correctness, specificity, depth and actionability. The Presenter then orders topics, composes chart-grounded narratives from the top-ranked insights, writes justified transitions, and revises the document for clarity and consistency, yielding a coherent, publication-ready report. Together, these agents convert raw data into curated materials (charts + vetted insights) and into a readable narrative without manual glue work. We claim that by coupling a quality-assured Analyzer with a narrative Presenter, A2P-Vis operationalizes co-analysis end-to-end, improving the real-world usefulness of automated data analysis for practitioners. For the complete dataset report, please see: https://www.visagent.org/api/output/f2a3486d-2c3b-4825-98d4-5af25a819f56.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.22101v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>1st Workshop on GenAI, Agents, and the Future of VIS (VIS x GenAI), November 2025, Vienna, Austria</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Shuyu Gan, Renxiang Wang, James Mooney, Dongyeop Kang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MAD: Multi-Alignment MEG-to-Text Decoding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.01512</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.01512v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Deciphering language from brain activity is a crucial task in brain-computer interface (BCI) research. Non-invasive cerebral signaling techniques including electroencephalography (EEG) and magnetoencephalography (MEG) are becoming increasingly popular due to their safety and practicality, avoiding invasive electrode implantation. However, current works under-investigated three points: 1) a predominant focus on EEG with limited exploration of MEG, which provides superior signal quality; 2) poor performance on unseen text, indicating the need for models that can better generalize to diverse linguistic contexts; 3) insufficient integration of information from other modalities, which could potentially constrain our capacity to comprehensively understand the intricate dynamics of brain activity.
  This study presents a novel approach for translating MEG signals into text using a speech-decoding framework with multiple alignments. Our method is the first to introduce an end-to-end multi-alignment framework for totally unseen text generation directly from MEG signals. We achieve an impressive BLEU-1 score on the \textit{GWilliams} dataset, significantly outperforming the baseline from 5.49 to 6.86 on the BLEU-1 metric. This improvement demonstrates the advancement of our model towards real-world applications and underscores its potential in advancing BCI research. Code is available at $\href{https://github.com/NeuSpeech/MAD-MEG2text}{https://github.com/NeuSpeech/MAD-MEG2text}$.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.01512v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yiqian Yang, Hyejeong Jo, Yiqun Duan, Qiang Zhang, Jinni Zhou, Xuming Hu, Won Hee Lee, Renjing Xu, Hui Xiong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GroupDebate: Enhancing the Efficiency of Multi-Agent Debate Using Group Discussion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.14051</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.14051v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In recent years, Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated remarkable capabilities across diverse NLP tasks. Extensive research has explored how to enhance the logical reasoning abilities such as Chain-of-Thought, Chain-of-Thought with Self-Consistency, Tree-Of-Thoughts, and multi-agent debates. In the context of multi-agent debates, significant performance improvements can be achieved with an increasing number of agents and debate rounds. However, the escalation in the number of agents and debate rounds can drastically raise the tokens cost of debates, thereby limiting the scalability of the multi-agent debate technique. To better harness the advantages of multi-agent debates in logical reasoning tasks, this paper proposes a method to significantly reduce token cost in multi-agent debates. This approach involves dividing all agents into multiple debate groups, with agents engaging in debates within their respective groups and sharing interim debate results between groups. Comparative experiments across multiple datasets have demonstrated that this method can reduce the total tokens by up to 51.7% during debates and while potentially enhancing accuracy by as much as 25%. Our method significantly enhances the performance and efficiency of interactions in the multi-agent debate.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.14051v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tongxuan Liu, Xingyu Wang, Weizhe Huang, Wenjiang Xu, Yuting Zeng, Lei Jiang, Hailong Yang, Jing Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don't Pay Attention, PLANT It: Pretraining Attention via Learning-to-Rank</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.23066</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.23066v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: State-of-the-art Extreme Multi-Label Text Classification models rely on multi-label attention to focus on key tokens in input text, but learning good attention weights is challenging. We introduce PLANT - Pretrained and Leveraged Attention - a plug-and-play strategy for initializing attention. PLANT works by planting label-specific attention using a pretrained Learning-to-Rank model guided by mutual information gain. This architecture-agnostic approach integrates seamlessly with large language model backbones such as Mistral-7B, LLaMA3-8B, DeepSeek-V3, and Phi-3. PLANT outperforms state-of-the-art methods across tasks including ICD coding, legal topic classification, and content recommendation. Gains are especially pronounced in few-shot settings, with substantial improvements on rare labels. Ablation studies confirm that attention initialization is a key driver of these gains. For code and trained models, see https://github.com/debjyotiSRoy/xcube/tree/plant</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.23066v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Debjyoti Saha Roy, Byron C. Wallace, Javed A. Aslam</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Exploration of Higher Education Course Evaluation by Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.02455</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.02455v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Course evaluation plays a critical role in ensuring instructional quality and guiding curriculum development in higher education. However, traditional evaluation methods, such as student surveys, classroom observations, and expert reviews, are often constrained by subjectivity, high labor costs, and limited scalability. With recent advancements in large language models (LLMs), new opportunities have emerged for generating consistent, fine-grained, and scalable course evaluations. This study investigates the use of three representative LLMs for automated course evaluation at both the micro level (classroom discussion analysis) and the macro level (holistic course review). Using classroom interaction transcripts and a dataset of 100 courses from a major institution in China, we demonstrate that LLMs can extract key pedagogical features and generate structured evaluation results aligned with expert judgement. A fine-tuned version of Llama shows superior reliability, producing score distributions with greater differentiation and stronger correlation with human evaluators than its counterparts. The results highlight three major findings: (1) LLMs can reliably perform systematic and interpretable course evaluations at both the micro and macro levels; (2) fine-tuning and prompt engineering significantly enhance evaluation accuracy and consistency; and (3) LLM-generated feedback provides actionable insights for teaching improvement. These findings illustrate the promise of LLM-based evaluation as a practical tool for supporting quality assurance and educational decision-making in large-scale higher education settings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.02455v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bo Yuan, Jiazi Hu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comparison of DeepSeek and Other LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.03688</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.03688v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recently, DeepSeek has been the focus of attention in and beyond the AI community. An interesting problem is how DeepSeek compares to other large language models (LLMs). There are many tasks an LLM can do, and in this paper, we use the task of "predicting an outcome using a short text" for comparison. We consider two settings, an authorship classification setting and a citation classification setting. In the first one, the goal is to determine whether a short text is written by human or AI. In the second one, the goal is to classify a citation to one of four types using the textual content. For each experiment, we compare DeepSeek with $4$ popular LLMs: Claude, Gemini, GPT, and Llama.
  We find that, in terms of classification accuracy, DeepSeek outperforms Gemini, GPT, and Llama in most cases, but underperforms Claude. We also find that DeepSeek is comparably slower than others but with a low cost to use, while Claude is much more expensive than all the others. Finally, we find that in terms of similarity, the output of DeepSeek is most similar to those of Gemini and Claude (and among all $5$ LLMs, Claude and Gemini have the most similar outputs).
  In this paper, we also present a fully-labeled dataset collected by ourselves, and propose a recipe where we can use the LLMs and a recent data set, MADStat, to generate new data sets. The datasets in our paper can be used as benchmarks for future study on LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.03688v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tianchen Gao, Jiashun Jin, Zheng Tracy Ke, Gabriel Moryoussef</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Multi-turn Task Completion in Task-Oriented Dialog Systems via Prompt Chaining and Fine-Grained Feedback</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.13298</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.13298v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Task-oriented dialog (TOD) systems facilitate users in accomplishing complex, multi-turn tasks through natural language. While instruction-tuned large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated strong performance on a range of single-turn NLP tasks, they often struggle with reliable multi-turn task completion in TOD settings, particularly when generating API calls required to interact with external systems. To address this, we introduce RealTOD, a novel framework that improves LLM-based TOD systems through (1) prompt chaining and (2) fine-grained feedback. Prompt chaining enables zero-shot generalization to new domains by automatically synthesizing a schema-aligned in-context example for the target task. Fine-grained feedback verifies each generated API call against the domain schema, identifies specific errors, and provides targeted correction prompts. To evaluate task completion reliability, we introduce full API Call Accuracy as a robust metric, along with detailed sub-metrics to capture common failure modes. We conduct extensive experiments on the SGD and BiTOD benchmarks using four LLMs. RealTOD improves Full API accuracy, surpassing state-of-the-art AutoTOD by 37.10% on SGD and supervised learning-based baseline SimpleTOD by 10.32% on BiTOD. Human evaluations further confirm that LLMs integrated with RealTOD achieve superior task completion, fluency, and informativeness compared to existing methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.13298v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Moghis Fereidouni, Md Sajid Ahmed, Adib Mosharrof, A. B. Siddique</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Causal Lens for Evaluating Faithfulness Metrics</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.18848</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.18848v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) offer natural language explanations as an alternative to feature attribution methods for model interpretability. However, despite their plausibility, they may not reflect the model's true reasoning faithfully. While several faithfulness metrics have been proposed, they are often evaluated in isolation, making principled comparisons between them difficult. We present Causal Diagnosticity, a testbed framework for evaluating faithfulness metrics for natural language explanations. We use the concept of diagnosticity, and employ model-editing methods to generate faithful-unfaithful explanation pairs. Our benchmark includes four tasks: fact-checking, analogy, object counting, and multi-hop reasoning. We evaluate prominent faithfulness metrics, including post-hoc explanation and chain-of-thought methods. Diagnostic performance varies across tasks and models, with Filler Tokens performing best overall. Additionally, continuous metrics are generally more diagnostic than binary ones but can be sensitive to noise and model choice. Our results highlight the need for more robust faithfulness metrics.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.18848v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>stat.ME</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kerem Zaman, Shashank Srivastava</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AnesSuite: A Comprehensive Benchmark and Dataset Suite for Anesthesiology Reasoning in LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.02404</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.02404v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The application of large language models (LLMs) in the medical field has garnered significant attention, yet their reasoning capabilities in more specialized domains like anesthesiology remain underexplored. To bridge this gap, we introduce AnesSuite, the first comprehensive dataset suite specifically designed for anesthesiology reasoning in LLMs. The suite features AnesBench, an evaluation benchmark tailored to assess anesthesiology-related reasoning across three levels: factual retrieval (System 1), hybrid reasoning (System 1.x), and complex decision-making (System 2). Alongside this benchmark, the suite includes three training datasets that provide an infrastructure for continued pre-training (CPT), supervised fine-tuning (SFT), and reinforcement learning with verifiable rewards (RLVR). Leveraging this suite, we develop Morpheus, the first baseline model collection for anesthesiology reasoning. Despite undergoing limited training with SFT and group relative policy optimization (GRPO), Morpheus demonstrates substantial performance improvements, rivaling the performance of larger-scale models. Furthermore, through comprehensive evaluations and experiments, we analyze the key factors influencing anesthesiology reasoning performance, including model characteristics, training strategies and training data. Both AnesSuite and Morpheus will be open-sourced at https://github.com/MiliLab/AnesSuite.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.02404v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiang Feng, Wentao Jiang, Zengmao Wang, Yong Luo, Pingbo Xu, Baosheng Yu, Hua Jin, Bo Du, Jing Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bidirectional Mamba for Single-Cell Data: Efficient Context Learning with Biological Fidelity</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.16956</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.16956v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-seq) enables high-resolution analysis of cellular heterogeneity, but its complexity, which is marked by high dimensionality, sparsity, and batch effects, which poses major computational challenges. Transformer-based models have made significant advances in this domain but are often limited by their quadratic complexity and suboptimal handling of long-range dependencies. In this work, we introduce GeneMamba, a scalable and efficient foundation model for single-cell transcriptomics built on state space modeling. Leveraging the Bi-Mamba architecture, GeneMamba captures bidirectional gene context with linear-time complexity, offering substantial computational gains over transformer baselines. The model is pretrained on nearly 30 million cells and incorporates biologically informed objectives, including pathway-aware contrastive loss and rank-based gene encoding. We evaluate GeneMamba across diverse tasks, including multi-batch integration, cell type annotation, and gene-gene correlation, demonstrating strong performance, interpretability, and robustness. These results position GeneMamba as a practical and powerful alternative to transformer-based methods, advancing the development of biologically grounded, scalable tools for large-scale single-cell data analysis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.16956v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>q-bio.GN</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Cong Qi, Hanzhang Fang, Tianxing Hu, Siqi Jiang, Wei Zhi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ToTRL: Unlock LLM Tree-of-Thoughts Reasoning Potential through Puzzles Solving</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.12717</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.12717v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) demonstrate significant reasoning capabilities, particularly through long chain-of-thought (CoT) processes, which can be elicited by reinforcement learning (RL). However, prolonged CoT reasoning presents limitations, primarily verbose outputs due to excessive introspection. The reasoning process in these LLMs often appears to follow a trial-and-error methodology rather than a systematic, logical deduction. In contrast, tree-of-thoughts (ToT) offers a conceptually more advanced approach by modeling reasoning as an exploration within a tree structure. This reasoning structure facilitates the parallel generation and evaluation of multiple reasoning branches, allowing for the active identification, assessment, and pruning of unproductive paths. This process can potentially lead to improved performance and reduced token costs. Building upon the long CoT capability of LLMs, we introduce tree-of-thoughts RL (ToTRL), a novel on-policy RL framework with a rule-based reward. ToTRL is designed to guide LLMs in developing the parallel ToT strategy based on the sequential CoT strategy. Furthermore, we employ LLMs as players in a puzzle game during the ToTRL training process. Solving puzzle games inherently necessitates exploring interdependent choices and managing multiple constraints, which requires the construction and exploration of a thought tree, providing challenging tasks for cultivating the ToT reasoning capability. Our empirical evaluations demonstrate that our ToTQwen3-8B model, trained with our ToTRL, achieves significant improvement in performance and reasoning efficiency on complex reasoning tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.12717v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haoyuan Wu, Xueyi Chen, Rui Ming, Jilong Gao, Shoubo Hu, Zhuolun He, Bei Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing Expert Specialization for Better MoE</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.22323</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.22323v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Mixture-of-Experts (MoE) models enable efficient scaling of large language models (LLMs) by activating only a subset of experts per input. However, we observe that the commonly used auxiliary load balancing loss often leads to expert overlap and overly uniform routing, which hinders expert specialization and degrades overall performance during post-training. To address this, we propose a simple yet effective solution that introduces two complementary objectives: (1) an orthogonality loss to encourage experts to process distinct types of tokens, and (2) a variance loss to encourage more discriminative routing decisions. Gradient-level analysis demonstrates that these objectives are compatible with the existing auxiliary loss and contribute to optimizing the training process. Experimental results over various model architectures and across multiple benchmarks show that our method significantly enhances expert specialization. Notably, our method improves classic MoE baselines with auxiliary loss by up to 23.79%, while also maintaining load balancing in downstream tasks, without any architectural modifications or additional components. We will release our code to contribute to the community.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.22323v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hongcan Guo, Haolang Lu, Guoshun Nan, Bolun Chu, Jialin Zhuang, Yuan Yang, Wenhao Che, Sicong Leng, Qimei Cui, Xudong Jiang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Learning Mind of Language Models: A Cognitive Framework and Empirical Study</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.13464</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.13464v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have shown impressive capabilities across tasks such as mathematics, coding, and reasoning, yet their learning ability, which is crucial for adapting to dynamic environments and acquiring new knowledge, remains underexplored. In this work, we address this gap by introducing a framework inspired by cognitive psychology and education. Specifically, we decompose general learning ability into three distinct, complementary dimensions: Learning from Instructor (acquiring knowledge via explicit guidance), Learning from Concept (internalizing abstract structures and generalizing to new contexts), and Learning from Experience (adapting through accumulated exploration and feedback). We conduct a comprehensive empirical study across the three learning dimensions and identify several insightful findings, such as (i) interaction improves learning; (ii) conceptual understanding is scale-emergent and benefits larger models; and (iii) LLMs are effective few-shot learners but not many-shot learners. Based on our framework and empirical findings, we introduce a benchmark that provides a unified and realistic evaluation of LLMs' general learning abilities across three learning cognition dimensions. It enables diagnostic insights and supports evaluation and development of more adaptive and human-like models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.13464v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhengyu Hu, Jianxun Lian, Zheyuan Xiao, Seraphina Zhang, Tianfu Wang, Nicholas Jing Yuan, Xing Xie, Hui Xiong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>StepFun-Formalizer: Unlocking the Autoformalization Potential of LLMs through Knowledge-Reasoning Fusion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.04440</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.04440v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Autoformalization aims to translate natural-language mathematical statements into a formal language. While LLMs have accelerated progress in this area, existing methods still suffer from low accuracy. We identify two key abilities for effective autoformalization: comprehensive mastery of formal-language domain knowledge, and reasoning capability of natural language problem understanding and informal-formal alignment. Without the former, a model cannot identify the correct formal objects; without the latter, it struggles to interpret real-world contexts and map them precisely into formal expressions. To address these gaps, we introduce ThinkingF, a data synthesis and training pipeline that improves both abilities. First, we construct two datasets: one by distilling and selecting large-scale examples rich in formal knowledge, and another by generating informal-to-formal reasoning trajectories guided by expert-designed templates. We then apply SFT and RLVR with these datasets to further fuse and refine the two abilities. The resulting 7B and 32B models exhibit both comprehensive formal knowledge and strong informal-to-formal reasoning. Notably, StepFun-Formalizer-32B achieves SOTA BEq@1 scores of 40.5% on FormalMATH-Lite and 26.7% on ProverBench, surpassing all prior general-purpose and specialized models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.04440v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yutong Wu, Di Huang, Ruosi Wan, Yue Peng, Shijie Shang, Chenrui Cao, Lei Qi, Rui Zhang, Zidong Du, Jie Yan, Xing Hu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DySK-Attn: A Framework for Efficient, Real-Time Knowledge Updating in Large Language Models via Dynamic Sparse Knowledge Attention</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.07185</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.07185v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) suffer from a critical limitation: their knowledge is static and quickly becomes outdated. Retraining these massive models is computationally prohibitive, while existing knowledge editing techniques can be slow and may introduce unforeseen side effects. To address this, we propose DySK-Attn, a novel framework that enables LLMs to efficiently integrate real-time knowledge from a dynamic external source. Our approach synergizes an LLM with a dynamic Knowledge Graph (KG) that can be updated instantaneously. The core of our framework is a sparse knowledge attention mechanism, which allows the LLM to perform a coarse-to-fine grained search, efficiently identifying and focusing on a small, highly relevant subset of facts from the vast KG. This mechanism avoids the high computational cost of dense attention over the entire knowledge base and mitigates noise from irrelevant information. We demonstrate through extensive experiments on time-sensitive question-answering tasks that DySK-Attn significantly outperforms strong baselines, including standard Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) and model editing techniques, in both factual accuracy for updated knowledge and computational efficiency. Our framework offers a scalable and effective solution for building LLMs that can stay current with the ever-changing world.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.07185v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kabir Khan, Priya Sharma, Arjun Mehta, Neha Gupta, Ravi Narayanan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Economics in Large Language Models: Exploring Model Behavior and Incentive Design under Resource Constraints</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.10426</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.10426v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are limited by substantial computational cost. We introduce a "computational economics" framework that treats an LLM as an internal economy of resource-constrained agents (attention heads and neuron blocks) that must allocate scarce computation to maximize task utility. First, we show empirically that when computation is scarce, standard LLMs reallocate attention toward high-value tokens while preserving accuracy. Building on this observation, we propose an incentive-driven training paradigm that augments the task loss with a differentiable computation cost term, encouraging sparse and efficient activations. On GLUE (MNLI, STS-B, CoLA) and WikiText-103, the method yields a family of models that trace a Pareto frontier and consistently dominate post-hoc pruning; for a similar accuracy we obtain roughly a forty percent reduction in FLOPS and lower latency, together with more interpretable attention patterns. These results indicate that economic principles offer a principled route to designing efficient, adaptive, and more transparent LLMs under strict resource constraints.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.10426v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sandeep Reddy, Kabir Khan, Rohit Patil, Ananya Chakraborty, Faizan A. Khan, Swati Kulkarni, Arjun Verma, Neha Singh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Cultural Gene of Large Language Models: A Study on the Impact of Cross-Corpus Training on Model Values and Biases</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.12411</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.12411v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are deployed globally, yet their underlying cultural and ethical assumptions remain underexplored. We propose the notion of a "cultural gene" -- a systematic value orientation that LLMs inherit from their training corpora -- and introduce a Cultural Probe Dataset (CPD) of 200 prompts targeting two classic cross-cultural dimensions: Individualism-Collectivism (IDV) and Power Distance (PDI). Using standardized zero-shot prompts, we compare a Western-centric model (GPT-4) and an Eastern-centric model (ERNIE Bot). Human annotation shows significant and consistent divergence across both dimensions. GPT-4 exhibits individualistic and low-power-distance tendencies (IDV score approx 1.21; PDI score approx -1.05), while ERNIE Bot shows collectivistic and higher-power-distance tendencies (IDV approx -0.89; PDI approx 0.76); differences are statistically significant (p &lt; 0.001). We further compute a Cultural Alignment Index (CAI) against Hofstede's national scores and find GPT-4 aligns more closely with the USA (e.g., IDV CAI approx 0.91; PDI CAI approx 0.88) whereas ERNIE Bot aligns more closely with China (IDV CAI approx 0.85; PDI CAI approx 0.81). Qualitative analyses of dilemma resolution and authority-related judgments illustrate how these orientations surface in reasoning. Our results support the view that LLMs function as statistical mirrors of their cultural corpora and motivate culturally aware evaluation and deployment to avoid algorithmic cultural hegemony.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.12411v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Emanuel Z. Fenech-Borg, Tilen P. Meznaric-Kos, Milica D. Lekovic-Bojovic, Arni J. Hentze-Djurhuus</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trusted Uncertainty in Large Language Models: A Unified Framework for Confidence Calibration and Risk-Controlled Refusal</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.01455</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.01455v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Deployed language models must decide not only what to answer but also when not to answer. We present UniCR, a unified framework that turns heterogeneous uncertainty evidence including sequence likelihoods, self-consistency dispersion, retrieval compatibility, and tool or verifier feedback into a calibrated probability of correctness and then enforces a user-specified error budget via principled refusal. UniCR learns a lightweight calibration head with temperature scaling and proper scoring, supports API-only models through black-box features, and offers distribution-free guarantees using conformal risk control. For long-form generation, we align confidence with semantic fidelity by supervising on atomic factuality scores derived from retrieved evidence, reducing confident hallucinations while preserving coverage. Experiments on short-form QA, code generation with execution tests, and retrieval-augmented long-form QA show consistent improvements in calibration metrics, lower area under the risk-coverage curve, and higher coverage at fixed risk compared to entropy or logit thresholds, post-hoc calibrators, and end-to-end selective baselines. Analyses reveal that evidence contradiction, semantic dispersion, and tool inconsistency are the dominant drivers of abstention, yielding informative user-facing refusal messages. The result is a portable recipe of evidence fusion to calibrated probability to risk-controlled decision that improves trustworthiness without fine-tuning the base model and remains valid under distribution shift.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.01455v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Markus Oehri, Giulia Conti, Kaviraj Pather, Alexandre Rossi, Laia Serra, Adrian Parody, Rogvi Johannesen, Aviaja Petersen, Arben Krasniqi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CC-GSEO-Bench: A Content-Centric Benchmark for Measuring Source Influence in Generative Search Engines</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.05607</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.05607v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Generative Search Engines (GSEs) synthesize conversational answers from multiple sources, weakening the long-standing link between search ranking and digital visibility. This shift raises a central question for content creators: How can we reliably quantify a source article's influence on a GSE's synthesized answer across diverse intents and follow-up questions? We introduce CC-GSEO-Bench, a content-centric benchmark that couples a large-scale dataset with a creator-centered evaluation framework. The dataset contains over 1,000 source articles and over 5,000 query-article pairs, organized in a one-to-many structure for article-level evaluation. We ground construction in realistic retrieval by combining seed queries from public QA datasets with limited synthesized augmentation and retaining only queries whose paired source reappears in a follow-up retrieval step. On top of this dataset, we operationalize influence along three core dimensions: Exposure, Faithful Credit, and Causal Impact, and two content-quality dimensions: Readability and Structure, and Trustworthiness and Safety. We aggregate query-level signals over each article's query cluster to summarize influence strength, coverage, and stability, and empirically characterize influence dynamics across representative content patterns.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.05607v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qiyuan Chen, Jiahe Chen, Hongsen Huang, Qian Shao, Jintai Chen, Renjie Hua, Hongxia Xu, Ruijia Wu, Ren Chuan, Jian Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RefactorCoderQA: Benchmarking LLMs for Multi-Domain Coding Question Solutions in Cloud and Edge Deployment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.10436</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.10436v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: To optimize the reasoning and problem-solving capabilities of Large Language Models (LLMs), we propose a novel cloud-edge collaborative architecture that enables a structured multi-agent prompting framework. This framework comprises three specialized components: GuideLLM, a lightweight model deployed at the edge to provide methodological guidance; SolverLLM, a more powerful model hosted in the cloud and responsible for generating code solutions; and JudgeLLM, an automated evaluator for assessing solution correctness and quality. To evaluate and demonstrate the effectiveness of this architecture in realistic settings, we introduce RefactorCoderQA, a comprehensive benchmark designed to evaluate and enhance the performance of LLMs across multi-domain coding tasks. Motivated by the limitations of existing benchmarks, RefactorCoderQA systematically covers multiple technical domains, including Software Engineering, Data Science, Machine Learning, and Natural Language Processing, using authentic coding challenges sourced from Stack Overflow. We propose RefactorCoder-MoE, a fine-tuned mixture-of-experts (MoE) code language model based on DeepSeek-Coder-7B-Instruct, adapted to the RefactorCoderQA benchmark using QLoRA for domain-specific coding question answering. Extensive experiments demonstrate that RefactorCoder-MoE achieves strong and competitive performance, significantly outperforming all evaluated open-source and commercial baselines, with an overall accuracy of 76.84%.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.10436v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shadikur Rahman, Aroosa Hameed, Gautam Srivastava, Syed Muhammad Danish</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BARD: budget-aware reasoning distillation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.01470</link>
      <description>arXiv:2511.01470v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: While long Chain-of-Thought (CoT) distillation effectively transfers reasoning capability to smaller language models, the reasoning process often remains redundant and computational budget uncontrollable, leading to inefficient resource usage. To address this limitation, we propose \textbf{Budget-Aware Reasoning Distillation (BARD)}, a novel framework that simultaneously distills reasoning capability and enables fine-grained control over the reasoning length. BARD uses the thinking budget as a user-specified control signal, allowing the model to dynamically balance reasoning performance and computational efficiency. To achieve this concept, BARD introduces a two-phase training regimen. The first phase, Supervised Fine-Tuning (SFT) on teacher-generated long CoT data compressed to various budget levels, bootstrapping the model's understanding of budget constraints. The second phase leverages Reinforcement Learning (RL) from a reward signal in consideration of reasoning performance and budget fidelity simultaneously. Incorporating the two-phase regimen is crucial to avoiding policy degradation and ensuring that both objectives are optimized jointly. Extensive experiments demonstrate that our method empowers an 8B student model to achieve strong performance on challenging reasoning benchmarks (\textit{AIME24, AIME25, GPQA}) while providing precise and adaptive control over its reasoning length across a wide range of budgets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2511.01470v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lujie Niu, Lei Shen, Yi Jiang, Caixia Yuan, Xiaojie Wang, Wenbo Su, Bo zheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TCM-Eval: An Expert-Level Dynamic and Extensible Benchmark for Traditional Chinese Medicine</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.07148</link>
      <description>arXiv:2511.07148v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated remarkable capabilities in modern medicine, yet their application in Traditional Chinese Medicine (TCM) remains severely limited by the absence of standardized benchmarks and the scarcity of high-quality training data. To address these challenges, we introduce TCM-Eval, the first dynamic and extensible benchmark for TCM, meticulously curated from national medical licensing examinations and validated by TCM experts. Furthermore, we construct a large-scale training corpus and propose Self-Iterative Chain-of-Thought Enhancement (SI-CoTE) to autonomously enrich question-answer pairs with validated reasoning chains through rejection sampling, establishing a virtuous cycle of data and model co-evolution. Using this enriched training data, we develop ZhiMingTang (ZMT), a state-of-the-art LLM specifically designed for TCM, which significantly exceeds the passing threshold for human practitioners. To encourage future research and development, we release a public leaderboard, fostering community engagement and continuous improvement.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2511.07148v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zihao Cheng, Yuheng Lu, Huaiqian Ye, Zeming Liu, Minqi Wang, Jingjing Liu, Zihan Li, Wei Fan, Yuanfang Guo, Ruiji Fu, Shifeng She, Gang Wang, Yunhong Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Forward and Backward: Multi-Objective Reinforcement Learning for Retrieval-Augmented Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.09109</link>
      <description>arXiv:2511.09109v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) has proven to be effective in mitigating hallucinations in large language models, yet its effectiveness remains limited in complex, multi-step reasoning scenarios. Recent efforts have incorporated search-based interactions into RAG, enabling iterative reasoning with real-time retrieval. Most approaches rely on outcome-based supervision, offering no explicit guidance for intermediate steps. This often leads to reward hacking and degraded response quality. We propose Bi-RAR, a novel retrieval-augmented reasoning framework that evaluates each intermediate step jointly in both forward and backward directions. To assess the information completeness of each step, we introduce a bidirectional information distance grounded in Kolmogorov complexity, approximated via language model generation probabilities. This quantification measures both how far the current reasoning is from the answer and how well it addresses the question. To optimize reasoning under these bidirectional signals, we adopt a multi-objective reinforcement learning framework with a cascading reward structure that emphasizes early trajectory alignment. Empirical results on seven question answering benchmarks demonstrate that Bi-RAR surpasses previous methods and enables efficient interaction and reasoning with the search engine during training and inference.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2511.09109v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenda Wei, Yu-An Liu, Ruqing Zhang, Jiafeng Guo, Lixin Su, Shuaiqiang Wang, Dawei Yin, Maarten de Rijke, Xueqi Cheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive Focus Memory for Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.12712</link>
      <description>arXiv:2511.12712v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are increasingly deployed in multi-turn dialogue settings, yet their behavior remains bottlenecked by naive history management strategies. Replaying the full conversation at every turn is simple but costly, while recency-based truncation or static summarization often causes early, high-impact user constraints to drift out of effective context. As a result, models may retain text without reliably applying it when it matters.
  We present Adaptive Focus Memory (AFM), a lightweight context management system that dynamically assigns each past message one of three fidelity levels: Full, Compressed, or Placeholder, based on semantic relevance, temporal decay, and importance classification. AFM packs messages chronologically under a fixed token budget, preserving critical constraints at high fidelity while allowing low-importance context to degrade gracefully.
  We evaluate AFM on two multi-turn dialogue benchmarks designed to stress long-horizon constraint preservation: a safety-critical travel scenario involving a user with a severe peanut allergy, and a policy-critical tax compliance scenario involving an illegal evasion request. Under strict grading that requires both explicit constraint recall and appropriately conditioned generation, AFM succeeds in 83.3 percent of allergy runs where all baseline strategies fail, and preserves correct refusal behavior on the tax benchmark.
  These results demonstrate that effective dialogue memory requires more than retaining prior text. Selectively allocating fidelity across past messages enables reliable constraint preservation under bounded context growth, without modifying model weights or introducing external retrieval infrastructure. We release an open-source implementation of AFM compatible with OpenAI-style chat APIs to support reproducible research and practical deployment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2511.12712v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Christopher Cruz</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>fMRI-LM: Towards a Universal Foundation Model for Language-Aligned fMRI Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.21760</link>
      <description>arXiv:2511.21760v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advances in multimodal large language models (LLMs) have enabled unified reasoning across images, audio, and video, but extending such capability to brain imaging remains largely unexplored. Bridging this gap is essential to link neural activity with semantic cognition and to develop cross-modal brain representations. To this end, we present fMRI-LM, a foundational model that bridges functional MRI (fMRI) and language through a three-stage framework. In Stage 1, we learn a neural tokenizer that maps fMRI into discrete tokens embedded in a language-consistent space. In Stage 2, a pretrained LLM is adapted to jointly model fMRI tokens and text, treating brain activity as a sequence that can be temporally predicted and linguistically described. To overcome the lack of natural fMRI-text pairs, we construct a large descriptive corpus that translates diverse imaging-based features into structured textual descriptors, capturing the low-level organization of fMRI signals. In Stage 3, we perform multi-task, multi-paradigm instruction tuning to endow fMRI-LM with high-level semantic understanding, supporting diverse downstream applications. Across various benchmarks, fMRI-LM achieves strong zero-shot and few-shot performance, and adapts efficiently with parameter-efficient tuning (LoRA), establishing a scalable pathway toward a language-aligned, universal model for structural and semantic understanding of fMRI.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2511.21760v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuxiang Wei, Yanteng Zhang, Xi Xiao, Chengxuan Qian, Tianyang Wang, Vince D. Calhoun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FVA-RAG: Falsification-Verification Alignment for Mitigating Sycophantic Hallucinations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.07015</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.07015v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) reduces hallucinations by grounding answers in retrieved evidence, yet standard retrievers often exhibit retrieval sycophancy: they preferentially surface evidence that supports a user's premise, even when the premise is false. We propose FVA-RAG (Falsification-Verification Alignment RAG), a pipeline that inverts the standard RAG workflow by treating the initial response as a draft hypothesis and explicitly retrieving anti-context to stress-test it. We evaluate on the full TruthfulQA-Generation benchmark (N=817) under a fully frozen protocol with 0 live web calls and identical retrieval budgets across methods. Using gpt-4o for generation and deterministic judging, FVA-RAG achieves 79.80-80.05% accuracy across two independently built frozen corpora , significantly outperforming prompted variants of Self-RAG (71.11-72.22%) and CRAG (71.36-73.93%) with p &lt; 10^-6 according to McNemar's test. FVA-RAG triggers falsification on 24.5-29.3% of queries, demonstrating that targeted counter-evidence retrieval is decisive for mitigating premise-confirming hallucinations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.07015v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mayank Ravishankara</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FineFreq: A Multilingual Character Frequency Dataset from Web-Scale Text</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.09701</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.09701v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We present FineFreq, a large-scale multilingual character frequency dataset derived from the FineWeb and FineWeb2 corpora, covering over 1900 languages and spanning 2013-2025. The dataset contains frequency counts for 96 trillion characters processed from 57 TB of compressed text. For each language, FineFreq provides per-character statistics with aggregate and year-level frequencies, allowing fine-grained temporal analysis. The dataset preserves naturally occurring multilingual features such as cross-script borrowings, emoji, and acronyms without applying artificial filtering. Each character entry includes Unicode metadata (category, script, block), enabling domain-specific or other downstream filtering and analysis. The full dataset is released in both CSV and Parquet formats, with associated metadata, available on GitHub and HuggingFace. https://github.com/Bin-2/FineFreq</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.09701v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Binbin Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-Resolution Reasoning (NRR): A Computational Framework for Contextual Identity and Ambiguity Preservation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.13478</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.13478v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Current AI systems exhibit a fundamental limitation: they resolve ambiguity prematurely. This premature semantic collapse--collapsing multiple valid interpretations into single outputs--stems from classical identity assumptions in neural architectures. We propose Non-Resolution Reasoning (NRR), treating ambiguity retention as a valid reasoning mode. NRR introduces three principles: (1) Non-Identity ($A \neq A$)--the same symbol refers to different entities across contexts; (2) Approximate Identity ($A \approx A$)--entities share partial overlap without being identical; (3) Non-Resolution--conflicting interpretations coexist without forced convergence. We formalize these through Multi-Vector Embeddings, Non-Collapsing Attention, and Contextual Identity Tracking (CIT). Functional verification via Turn 1 Entropy measurement shows NRR-lite maintains high entropy ($H = 0.63$) at ambiguous turns while standard architectures collapse early ($H = 0.10$), demonstrating that NRR preserves interpretive flexibility until context arrives. The question is not whether AI should resolve ambiguity, but when, how, and under whose control.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.13478v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kei Saito</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research on a hybrid LSTM-CNN-Attention model for text-based web content classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.18475</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.18475v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This study presents a hybrid deep learning architecture that integrates LSTM, CNN, and an Attention mechanism to enhance the classification of web content based on text. Pretrained GloVe embeddings are used to represent words as dense vectors that preserve semantic similarity. The CNN layer extracts local n-gram patterns and lexical features, while the LSTM layer models long-range dependencies and sequential structure. The integrated Attention mechanism enables the model to focus selectively on the most informative parts of the input sequence. A 5-fold cross-validation setup was used to assess the robustness and generalizability of the proposed solution. Experimental results show that the hybrid LSTM-CNN-Attention model achieved outstanding performance, with an accuracy of 0.98, precision of 0.94, recall of 0.92, and F1-score of 0.93. These results surpass the performance of baseline models based solely on CNNs, LSTMs, or transformer-based classifiers such as BERT. The combination of neural network components enabled the model to effectively capture both fine-grained text structures and broader semantic context. Furthermore, the use of GloVe embeddings provided an efficient and effective representation of textual data, making the model suitable for integration into systems with real-time or near-real-time requirements. The proposed hybrid architecture demonstrates high effectiveness in text-based web content classification, particularly in tasks requiring both syntactic feature extraction and semantic interpretation. By combining presented mechanisms, the model addresses the limitations of individual architectures and achieves improved generalization. These findings support the broader use of hybrid deep learning approaches in NLP applications, especially where complex, unstructured textual data must be processed and classified with high reliability.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.18475v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.15588/1607-3274-2025-4-10</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Radio Electronics Computer Science Control, no. 4, pp. 105-115, Dec. 24, 2025</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Mykola Kuz, Ihor Lazarovych, Mykola Kozlenko, Mykola Pikuliak, Andrii Kvasniuk</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JEPA-Reasoner: Decoupling Latent Reasoning from Token Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.19171</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.19171v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: While Joint-Embedding Predictive Architecture (JEPA) has emerged as a powerful architecture for learning rich latent representations, it fundamentally lacks generative abilities. Meanwhile, current latent reasoning models remain limited by the token-by-token generation paradigm, which suffers from compounding errors and heavy context dependency. To address these limitations, we proposed JEPA-Reasoner, a novel JEPA-based architecture enhanced with generative ability for latent reasoning. We augment this architecture with a separate action-talker model, Talker, to reconstruct human-readable text from latent representations produced by the JEPA-Reasoner. Our work demonstrated that decoupling latent-space reasoning from token production enables JEPA-Reasoner to produce mixed latent vectors, laying a foundation for multi-threaded reasoning and achieving superior robustness against compounding errors in autoregressive generation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.19171v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bingyang Kelvin Liu, Ziyu Patrick Chen, David P. Woodruff</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MobileWorld: Benchmarking Autonomous Mobile Agents in Agent-User Interactive and MCP-Augmented Environments</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.19432</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.19432v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Among existing online mobile-use benchmarks, AndroidWorld has emerged as the dominant benchmark due to its reproducible environment and deterministic evaluation; however, recent agents achieving over 90% success rates indicate its saturation and motivate the need for a more challenging benchmark. In addition, its environment lacks key application categories, such as e-commerce and enterprise communication, and does not reflect realistic mobile-use scenarios characterized by vague user instructions and hybrid tool usage. We introduce MobileWorld, a substantially more challenging benchmark designed to reflect real-world usage through 201 tasks across 20 applications. MobileWorld derives its difficulty from an emphasis on long-horizon, cross-application workflows, requiring nearly twice as many completion steps on average (27.8 vs. 14.3) and featuring a significantly higher proportion of multi-app tasks (62.2% vs. 9.5%) than AndroidWorld. To overcome the limitations of existing environments, MobileWorld achieves a balance between production-grade utility and reproducible evaluation by utilizing open-source alternatives to industry standards (e.g., Mattermost for Slack). This approach enables a fully observable and controlled environment through source code modification and direct backend database access for precise verification. MobileWorld also introduces novel task categories, including agent-user interaction and Model Context Protocol (MCP)-augmented tasks, for evaluating agents in user-aware, hybrid-tool scenarios. To facilitate evaluation, we develop a planner-executor agentic framework with extended action spaces to support user interactions and MCP calls. Our results reveal a sharp performance drop compared to AndroidWorld, with the best agentic framework and end-to-end model achieving 51.7% and 20.9% success rates, respectively, highlighting ample headroom for future research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.19432v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Quyu Kong, Xu Zhang, Zhenyu Yang, Nolan Gao, Chen Liu, Panrong Tong, Chenglin Cai, Hanzhang Zhou, Jianan Zhang, Liangyu Chen, Zhidan Liu, Steven Hoi, Yue Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HARMON-E: Hierarchical Agentic Reasoning for Multimodal Oncology Notes to Extract Structured Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.19864</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.19864v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Unstructured notes within the electronic health record (EHR) contain rich clinical information vital for cancer treatment decision making and research, yet reliably extracting structured oncology data remains challenging due to extensive variability, specialized terminology, and inconsistent document formats. Manual abstraction, although accurate, is prohibitively costly and unscalable. Existing automated approaches typically address narrow scenarios - either using synthetic datasets, restricting focus to document-level extraction, or isolating specific clinical variables (e.g., staging, biomarkers, histology) - and do not adequately handle patient-level synthesis across the large number of clinical documents containing contradictory information. In this study, we propose an agentic framework that systematically decomposes complex oncology data extraction into modular, adaptive tasks. Specifically, we use large language models (LLMs) as reasoning agents, equipped with context-sensitive retrieval and iterative synthesis capabilities, to exhaustively and comprehensively extract structured clinical variables from real-world oncology notes. Evaluated on a large-scale dataset of over 400,000 unstructured clinical notes and scanned PDF reports spanning 2,250 cancer patients, our method achieves an average F1-score of 0.93, with 100 out of 103 oncology-specific clinical variables exceeding 0.85, and critical variables (e.g., biomarkers and medications) surpassing 0.95. Moreover, integration of the agentic system into a data curation workflow resulted in 0.94 direct manual approval rate, significantly reducing annotation costs. To our knowledge, this constitutes the first exhaustive, end-to-end application of LLM-based agents for structured oncology data extraction at scale</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.19864v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shashi Kant Gupta, Arijeet Pramanik, Jerrin John Thomas, Regina Schwind, Lauren Wiener, Avi Raju, Jeremy Kornbluth, Yanshan Wang, Zhaohui Su, Hrituraj Singh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SpidR: Learning Fast and Stable Linguistic Units for Spoken Language Models Without Supervision</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20308</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20308v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The parallel advances in language modeling and speech representation learning have raised the prospect of learning language directly from speech without textual intermediates. This requires extracting semantic representations directly from speech. Our contributions are threefold. First, we introduce SpidR, a self-supervised speech representation model that efficiently learns representations with highly accessible phonetic information, which makes it particularly suited for textless spoken language modeling. It is trained on raw waveforms using a masked prediction objective combined with self-distillation and online clustering. The intermediate layers of the student model learn to predict assignments derived from the teacher's intermediate layers. This learning objective stabilizes the online clustering procedure compared to previous approaches, resulting in higher quality codebooks. SpidR outperforms wav2vec 2.0, HuBERT, WavLM, and DinoSR on downstream language modeling benchmarks (sWUGGY, sBLIMP, tSC). Second, we systematically evaluate across models and layers the correlation between speech unit quality (ABX, PNMI) and language modeling performance, validating these metrics as reliable proxies. Finally, SpidR significantly reduces pretraining time compared to HuBERT, requiring only one day of pretraining on 16 GPUs, instead of a week. This speedup is enabled by the pretraining method and an efficient codebase, which allows faster iteration and easier experimentation. We open-source the training code and model checkpoints at https://github.com/facebookresearch/spidr.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20308v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Maxime Poli, Mahi Luthra, Youssef Benchekroun, Yosuke Higuchi, Martin Gleize, Jiayi Shen, Robin Algayres, Yu-An Chung, Mido Assran, Juan Pino, Emmanuel Dupoux</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Step-DeepResearch Technical Report</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20491</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20491v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: As LLMs shift toward autonomous agents, Deep Research has emerged as a pivotal metric. However, existing academic benchmarks like BrowseComp often fail to meet real-world demands for open-ended research, which requires robust skills in intent recognition, long-horizon decision-making, and cross-source verification. To address this, we introduce Step-DeepResearch, a cost-effective, end-to-end agent. We propose a Data Synthesis Strategy Based on Atomic Capabilities to reinforce planning and report writing, combined with a progressive training path from agentic mid-training to SFT and RL. Enhanced by a Checklist-style Judger, this approach significantly improves robustness. Furthermore, to bridge the evaluation gap in the Chinese domain, we establish ADR-Bench for realistic deep research scenarios. Experimental results show that Step-DeepResearch (32B) scores 61.4% on Scale AI Research Rubrics. On ADR-Bench, it significantly outperforms comparable models and rivals SOTA closed-source models like OpenAI and Gemini DeepResearch. These findings prove that refined training enables medium-sized models to achieve expert-level capabilities at industry-leading cost-efficiency.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20491v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chen Hu, Haikuo Du, Heng Wang, Lin Lin, Mingrui Chen, Peng Liu, Ruihang Miao, Tianchi Yue, Wang You, Wei Ji, Wei Yuan, Wenjin Deng, Xiaojian Yuan, Xiaoyun Zhang, Xiangyu Liu, Xikai Liu, Yanming Xu, Yicheng Cao, Yifei Zhang, Yongyao Wang, Yubo Shu, Yurong Zhang, Yuxiang Zhang, Zheng Gong, Zhichao Chang, Binyan Li, Dan Ma, Furong Jia, Hongyuan Wang, Jiayu Liu, Jing Bai, Junlan Liu, Manjiao Liu, Na Wang, Qiuping Wu, Qinxin Du, Shiwei Li, Wen Sun, Yifeng Gong, Yonglin Chen, Yuling Zhao, Yuxuan Lin, Ziqi Ren, Zixuan Wang, Aihu Zhang, Brian Li, Buyun Ma, Kang An, Li Xie, Mingliang Li, Pan Li, Shidong Yang, Xi Chen, Xiaojia Liu, Yuchu Luo, Yuan Song, YuanHao Ding, Yuanwei Liang, Zexi Li, Zhaoning Zhang, Zixin Zhang, Binxing Jiao, Daxin Jiang, Jiansheng Chen, Jing Li, Xiangyu Zhang, Yibo Zhu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generative Language Models on Nucleotide Sequences of Human Genes</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2307.10634</link>
      <description>arXiv:2307.10634v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Language models, especially transformer-based ones, have achieved colossal success in NLP. To be precise, studies like BERT for NLU and works like GPT-3 for NLG are very important. If we consider DNA sequences as a text written with an alphabet of four letters representing the nucleotides, they are similar in structure to natural languages. This similarity has led to the development of discriminative language models such as DNABert in the field of DNA-related bioinformatics. To our knowledge, however, the generative side of the coin is still largely unexplored. Therefore, we have focused on the development of an autoregressive generative language model such as GPT-3 for DNA sequences. Since working with whole DNA sequences is challenging without extensive computational resources, we decided to conduct our study on a smaller scale and focus on nucleotide sequences of human genes rather than the whole DNA. This decision has not changed the structure of the problem, as both DNA and genes can be considered as 1D sequences consisting of four different nucleotides without losing much information and without oversimplification. Firstly, we systematically studied an almost entirely unexplored problem and observed that RNNs perform best, while simple techniques such as N-grams are also promising. Another beneficial point was learning how to work with generative models on languages we do not understand, unlike natural languages. The importance of using real-world tasks beyond classical metrics such as perplexity was noted. In addition, we examined whether the data-hungry nature of these models can be altered by selecting a language with minimal vocabulary size, four due to four different types of nucleotides. The reason for reviewing this was that choosing such a language might make the problem easier. However, in this study, we found that this did not change the amount of data required very much.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2307.10634v2</guid>
      <category>q-bio.GN</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1038/s41598-024-72512-x</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Scientific Reports, 2024, 14.1: 22204</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Musa Nuri Ihtiyar, Arzucan Ozgur</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging ASIC AI Chips for Homomorphic Encryption</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.07047</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.07047v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Homomorphic Encryption (HE) provides strong data privacy for cloud services but at the cost of prohibitive computational overhead. While GPUs have emerged as a practical platform for accelerating HE, there remains an order-of-magnitude energy-efficiency gap compared to specialized (but expensive) HE ASICs. This paper explores an alternate direction: leveraging existing AI accelerators, like Google's TPUs with coarse-grained compute and memory architectures, to offer a path toward ASIC-level energy efficiency for HE. However, this architectural paradigm creates a fundamental mismatch with SoTA HE algorithms designed for GPUs. These algorithms rely heavily on: (1) high-precision (32-bit) integer arithmetic to now run on a TPU's low-throughput vector unit, leaving its high-throughput low-precision (8-bit) matrix engine (MXU) idle, and (2) fine-grained data permutations that are inefficient on the TPU's coarse-grained memory subsystem. Consequently, porting GPU-optimized HE libraries to TPUs results in severe resource under-utilization and performance degradation. To tackle above challenges, we introduce CROSS, a compiler framework that systematically transforms HE workloads to align with the TPU's architecture. CROSS makes two key contributions: (1) Basis-Aligned Transformation (BAT), a novel technique that converts high-precision modular arithmetic into dense, low-precision (INT8) matrix multiplications, unlocking and improving the utilization of TPU's MXU for HE, and (2) Memory-Aligned Transformation (MAT), which eliminates costly runtime data reordering by embedding reordering into compute kernels through offline parameter transformation. CROSS (TPU v6e) achieves higher throughput per watt on NTT and HE operators than WarpDrive, FIDESlib, FAB, HEAP, and Cheddar, establishing AI ASIC as the SotA efficient platform for HE operators. Code: https://github.com/EfficientPPML/CROSS</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.07047v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.AR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.PL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jianming Tong, Tianhao Huang, Jingtian Dang, Leo de Castro, Anirudh Itagi, Anupam Golder, Asra Ali, Jeremy Kun, Jevin Jiang,  Arvind, G. Edward Suh, Tushar Krishna</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>X-Boundary: Establishing Exact Safety Boundary to Shield LLMs from Multi-Turn Jailbreaks without Compromising Usability</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09990</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09990v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Despite the rapid development of safety alignment techniques for LLMs, defending against multi-turn jailbreaks is still a challenging task. In this paper, we conduct a comprehensive comparison, revealing that some existing defense methods can improve the robustness of LLMs against multi-turn jailbreaks but compromise usability, i.e., reducing general capabilities or causing the over-refusal problem. From the perspective of mechanism interpretability of LLMs, we discover that these methods fail to establish a boundary that exactly distinguishes safe and harmful feature representations. Therefore, boundary-safe representations close to harmful representations are inevitably disrupted, leading to a decline in usability. To address this issue, we propose X-Boundary to push harmful representations away from boundary-safe representations and obtain an exact distinction boundary. In this way, harmful representations can be precisely erased without disrupting safe ones. Experimental results show that X-Boundary achieves state-of-the-art defense performance against multi-turn jailbreaks, while reducing the over-refusal rate by about 20% and maintaining nearly complete general capability. Furthermore, we theoretically prove and empirically verify that X-Boundary can accelerate the convergence process during training. Please see our code at: https://github.com/AI45Lab/X-Boundary.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09990v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoya Lu, Dongrui Liu, Yi Yu, Luxin Xu, Jing Shao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward building next-generation Geocoding systems: a systematic review</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.18888</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.18888v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Geocoding systems are widely used in both scientific research for spatial analysis and everyday life through location-based services. The quality of geocoded data significantly impacts subsequent processes and applications, underscoring the need for next-generation systems. In response to this demand, this review first characterizes the technical requirements for next-generation geocoding inputs and outputs. We then decompose the geocoding workflow into modular functional units and survey existing implementations. For each component, we identify methodological limitations, articulate domain-specific research questions and hypotheses, and outline evaluation strategies needed. Finally, we identify opportunities to improve next-generation geocoding systems in light of recent technological advances. We envision that this review provides a technical foundation and research agenda for advancing the design, assessment, and deployment of next-generation geocoding systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.18888v2</guid>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhengcong Yin, Daniel W. Goldberg, Binbin Lin, Bing Zhou, Diya Li, Andong Ma, Ziqian Ming, Heng Cai, Zhe Zhang, Shaohua Wang, Shanzhen Gao, Joey Ying Lee, Xiao Li, Da Huo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing TCR-Peptide Interaction Prediction with Pretrained Language Models and Molecular Representations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01433</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01433v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Understanding the binding specificity between T-cell receptors (TCRs) and peptide-major histocompatibility complexes (pMHCs) is central to immunotherapy and vaccine development. However, current predictive models struggle with generalization, especially in data-scarce settings and when faced with novel epitopes. We present LANTERN (Large lAnguage model-powered TCR-Enhanced Recognition Network), a deep learning framework that combines large-scale protein language models with chemical representations of peptides. By encoding TCR \b{eta}-chain sequences using ESM-1b and transforming peptide sequences into SMILES strings processed by MolFormer, LANTERN captures rich biological and chemical features critical for TCR-peptide recognition. Through extensive benchmarking against existing models such as ChemBERTa, TITAN, and NetTCR, LANTERN demonstrates superior performance, particularly in zero-shot and few-shot learning scenarios. Our model also benefits from a robust negative sampling strategy and shows significant clustering improvements via embedding analysis. These results highlight the potential of LANTERN to advance TCR-pMHC binding prediction and support the development of personalized immunotherapies.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01433v2</guid>
      <category>q-bio.QM</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Cong Qi, Hanzhang Fang, Siqi jiang, Tianxing Hu, Zhi Wei</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reward Is Enough: LLMs Are In-Context Reinforcement Learners</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.06303</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.06303v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Reinforcement learning (RL) is a framework for solving sequential decision-making problems. In this work, we demonstrate that, surprisingly, RL emerges during the inference time of large language models (LLMs), a phenomenon we term in-context RL (ICRL). To reveal this capability, we introduce a simple multi-round prompting framework, we call ICRL prompting, for inference-time self-improvement. The goal of ICRL prompting is to guide LLMs to perform reinforcement learning during inference for self-improvement on a given task. After each response, the model receives numerical scalar feedback, denoted as a reward. In the next round, we prompt the LLM again together with a context that concatenates all prior responses and their associated rewards. We consistently observe that response quality improves as the context grows. In other words, the LLM can optimize scalar reward signals during inference, exhibiting behavior analogous to reinforcement learning. We evaluate ICRL prompting on Game of 24, creative writing, ScienceWorld, and Olympiad-level math competitions (AIME and HMMT), demonstrating significant improvements over baselines such as Self-Refine and Reflexion. Notably, even when the reward signals are generated by the same LLM, ICRL prompting still improves performance, highlighting a promising new paradigm for test-time scaling.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.06303v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kefan Song, Amir Moeini, Peng Wang, Lei Gong, Rohan Chandra, Shangtong Zhang, Yanjun Qi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CP-Agent: Agentic Constraint Programming</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.07468</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.07468v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Translating natural language into formal constraint models requires expertise in the problem domain and modeling frameworks. To investigate whether constraint modeling benefits from agentic workflows, we introduce CP-Agent, a Python coding agent using the ReAct framework with a persistent IPython kernel. Domain knowledge is provided through a project prompt of under 50 lines. The agent iteratively executes code, observes the solver's feedback, and refines models based on the execution results.
  We evaluate CP-Agent on CP-Bench's 101 constraint programming problems. We clarified the benchmark to address systematic ambiguities in problem specifications and errors in ground-truth models. On the clarified benchmark, CP-Agent solves all 101 problems. Ablation studies indicate that minimal guidance outperforms detailed procedural scaffolding, and that explicit task management tools have mixed effects on focused modeling tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.07468v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Stefan Szeider</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ControlAudio: Tackling Text-Guided, Timing-Indicated and Intelligible Audio Generation via Progressive Diffusion Modeling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.08878</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.08878v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Text-to-audio (TTA) generation with fine-grained control signals, e.g., precise timing control or intelligible speech content, has been explored in recent works. However, constrained by data scarcity, their generation performance at scale is still compromised. In this study, we recast controllable TTA generation as a multi-task learning problem and introduce a progressive diffusion modeling approach, ControlAudio. Our method adeptly fits distributions conditioned on more fine-grained information, including text, timing, and phoneme features, through a step-by-step strategy. First, we propose a data construction method spanning both annotation and simulation, augmenting condition information in the sequence of text, timing, and phoneme. Second, at the model training stage, we pretrain a diffusion transformer (DiT) on large-scale text-audio pairs, achieving scalable TTA generation, and then incrementally integrate the timing and phoneme features with unified semantic representations, expanding controllability. Finally, at the inference stage, we propose progressively guided generation, which sequentially emphasizes more fine-grained information, aligning inherently with the coarse-to-fine sampling nature of DiT. Extensive experiments show that ControlAudio achieves state-of-the-art performance in terms of temporal accuracy and speech clarity, significantly outperforming existing methods on both objective and subjective evaluations. Demo samples are available at: https://control-audio.github.io/Control-Audio.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.08878v2</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuxuan Jiang, Zehua Chen, Zeqian Ju, Yusheng Dai, Weibei Dou, Jun Zhu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LIBERO-Plus: In-depth Robustness Analysis of Vision-Language-Action Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.13626</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.13626v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Visual-Language-Action (VLA) models report impressive success rates on robotic manipulation benchmarks, yet these results may mask fundamental weaknesses in robustness. We perform a systematic vulnerability analysis by introducing controlled perturbations across seven dimensions: objects layout, camera viewpoints, robot initial states, language instructions, light conditions, background textures and sensor noise. We comprehensively analyzed multiple state-of-the-art models and revealed consistent brittleness beneath apparent competence. Our analysis exposes critical weaknesses: models exhibit extreme sensitivity to perturbation factors, including camera viewpoints and robot initial states, with performance dropping from 95% to below 30% under modest perturbations. Surprisingly, models are largely insensitive to language variations, with further experiments revealing that models tend to ignore language instructions completely. Our findings challenge the assumption that high benchmark scores equate to true competency and highlight the need for evaluation practices that assess reliability under realistic variation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.13626v3</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Senyu Fei, Siyin Wang, Junhao Shi, Zihao Dai, Jikun Cai, Pengfang Qian, Li Ji, Xinzhe He, Shiduo Zhang, Zhaoye Fei, Jinlan Fu, Jingjing Gong, Xipeng Qiu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Training Speed of Tiny Recursive Models with Curriculum Guided Adaptive Recursion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.08653</link>
      <description>arXiv:2511.08653v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Background: Recursive reasoning models achieve strong performance through iterative refinement, allowing small networks to match large language models. However, training is computationally expensive, often requiring 36 GPU-hours for Sudoku extreme. Existing models use fixed recursion depth and uniform supervision weighting, leading to inefficient training. Objectives: We propose CGAR (Curriculum-Guided Adaptive Recursion), applying curriculum learning to architectural depth. CGAR introduces Progressive Depth Curriculum (PDC) to dynamically adjust recursion depth and Hierarchical Supervision Weighting (HSW) to apply exponentially decaying importance to supervision steps. Methods: PDC implements a three-stage schedule transitioning from shallow (2, 1) to full depth (6, 3) configurations, providing 41.4% FLOPs reduction. HSW applies exponential decay to supervision steps, achieving 40% gradient variance reduction and accelerated convergence. Results: On Sudoku-Extreme, CGAR achieves 1.71x training speedup (10.93 to 6.38 hours) with only a 0.63% accuracy drop (86.65% to 86.02%). PDC alone achieves 2.26x speedup with 85.47% accuracy, showing a Pareto improvement in efficiency and quality. HSW provides 1.61x speedup. CGAR-trained models show superior inference efficiency with 100% halting accuracy and 11% fewer reasoning steps. Conclusions: CGAR enables efficient training of recursive models on modest hardware. By treating depth as a scheduled parameter, it achieves substantial savings and prevents overfitting, making these models practical for neurosymbolic AI and program synthesis. https://github.com/Kaleemullahqasim/CGAR and huggingface.co/Kaleemullah/trm-cgar-sudoku.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2511.08653v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.NE</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kaleem Ullah Qasim, Jiashu Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Urban Scientist: Multi-Agent Collaborative Automation for Urban Research</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.07849</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.07849v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Urban research aims to understand how cities operate and evolve as complex adaptive systems. With the rapid growth of urban data and analytical methodologies, the central challenge of the field has shifted from data availability to the integration of heterogeneous data into coherent, verifiable urban knowledge through multidisciplinary approaches. Recent advances in AI, particularly the emergence of large language models (LLMs), have enabled the development of AI scientists capable of autonomous reasoning, hypothesis generation, and data-driven experimentation, demonstrating substantial potential for autonomous urban research. However, most general-purpose AI systems remain misaligned with the domain-specific knowledge, methodological conventions, and inferential standards required in urban studies. Here, we introduce the AI Urban Scientist, a knowledge-driven multi-agent framework designed to support autonomous urban research. Grounded in hypotheses, peer-review feedback, datasets, and research methodologies distilled from large-scale prior studies, the system constructs structured domain knowledge that guides LLM-based agents to automatically generate hypotheses, identify and integrate multi-source urban datasets, conduct empirical analyses and simulations, and iteratively refine analytical methods. Through this process, the framework synthesizes new insights in urban science and accelerates the urban research lifecycle.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.07849v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tong Xia, Jiankun Zhang, Ruiwen You, Ao Xu, Linghao Zhang, Tengyao Tu, Jingzhi Wang, Jinghua Piao, Yunke Zhang, Fengli Xu, Yong Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generative Adversarial Reasoner: Enhancing LLM Reasoning with Adversarial Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.16917</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.16917v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) with explicit reasoning capabilities excel at mathematical reasoning yet still commit process errors, such as incorrect calculations, brittle logic, and superficially plausible but invalid steps. In this paper, we introduce Generative Adversarial Reasoner, an on-policy joint training framework designed to enhance reasoning by co-evolving an LLM reasoner and an LLM-based discriminator through adversarial reinforcement learning. A compute-efficient review schedule partitions each reasoning chain into logically complete slices of comparable length, and the discriminator evaluates each slice's soundness with concise, structured justifications. Learning couples complementary signals: the LLM reasoner is rewarded for logically consistent steps that yield correct answers, while the discriminator earns rewards for correctly detecting errors or distinguishing traces in the reasoning process. This produces dense, well-calibrated, on-policy step-level rewards that supplement sparse exact-match signals, improving credit assignment, increasing sample efficiency, and enhancing overall reasoning quality of LLMs. Across various mathematical benchmarks, the method delivers consistent gains over strong baselines with standard RL post-training. Specifically, on AIME24, we improve DeepSeek-R1-Distill-Qwen-7B from 54.0 to 61.3 (+7.3) and DeepSeek-R1-Distill-Llama-8B from 43.7 to 53.7 (+10.0). The modular discriminator also enables flexible reward shaping for objectives such as teacher distillation, preference alignment, and mathematical proof-based reasoning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.16917v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qihao Liu, Luoxin Ye, Wufei Ma, Yu-Cheng Chou, Alan Yuille</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>External Hippocampus: Topological Cognitive Maps for Guiding Large Language Model Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.18190</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.18190v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: This paper proposes the External Hippocampus framework, which models language model reasoning from a cognitive dynamics perspective as the flow of information energy in semantic space. Unlike traditional weight-space optimization methods, this framework constructs topological cognitive maps through dimensionality reduction projection, enabling precise navigation and intervention of energy flow at test time while avoiding substantial computational requirements and demonstrating predictable intervention patterns. The method effectively addresses the cognitive deadlock problem in multi-step reasoning for small models. Experiments on models &lt;=7B parameters show: map-guided methods achieve 81.20% accuracy on 500 challenging problems (relative baseline +16.80%), reduce reasoning time by &gt;= 15x, with key findings revealing that reasoning stagnation manifests as "Cognitive Vortex" and low-entropy potential wells, while temperature perturbations effectively restart energy flow. The framework requires no additional training, possesses autonomous growth capability, and provides an efficient and controllable topological-aware solution for small model reasoning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.18190v3</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jian Yan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generative Digital Twins: Vision-Language Simulation Models for Executable Industrial Systems</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20387</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20387v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We propose a Vision-Language Simulation Model (VLSM) that unifies visual and textual understanding to synthesize executable FlexScript from layout sketches and natural-language prompts, enabling cross-modal reasoning for industrial simulation systems. To support this new paradigm, the study constructs the first large-scale dataset for generative digital twins, comprising over 120,000 prompt-sketch-code triplets that enable multimodal learning between textual descriptions, spatial structures, and simulation logic. In parallel, three novel evaluation metrics, Structural Validity Rate (SVR), Parameter Match Rate (PMR), and Execution Success Rate (ESR), are proposed specifically for this task to comprehensively evaluate structural integrity, parameter fidelity, and simulator executability. Through systematic ablation across vision encoders, connectors, and code-pretrained language backbones, the proposed models achieve near-perfect structural accuracy and high execution robustness. This work establishes a foundation for generative digital twins that integrate visual reasoning and language understanding into executable industrial simulation systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20387v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>YuChe Hsu, AnJui Wang, TsaiChing Ni, YuanFu Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coherence in the brain unfolds across separable temporal regimes</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20481</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20481v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Coherence in language requires the brain to satisfy two competing temporal demands: gradual accumulation of meaning across extended context and rapid reconfiguration of representations at event boundaries. Despite their centrality to language and thought, how these processes are implemented in the human brain during naturalistic listening remains unclear. Here, we tested whether these two processes can be captured by annotation-free drift and shift signals and whether their neural expression dissociates across large-scale cortical systems. These signals were derived from a large language model (LLM) and formalized contextual drift and event shifts directly from the narrative input. To enable high-precision voxelwise encoding models with stable parameter estimates, we densely sampled one healthy adult across more than 7 hours of listening to thirteen crime stories while collecting ultra high-field (7T) BOLD data. We then modeled the feature-informed hemodynamic response using a regularized encoding framework validated on independent stories. Drift predictions were prevalent in default-mode network hubs, whereas shift predictions were evident bilaterally in the primary auditory cortex and language association cortex. Furthermore, activity in default-mode and parietal networks was best explained by a signal capturing how meaning accumulates and gradually fades over the course of the narrative. Together, these findings show that coherence during language comprehension is implemented through dissociable neural regimes of slow contextual integration and rapid event-driven reconfiguration, offering a mechanistic entry point for understanding disturbances of language coherence in psychiatric disorders.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20481v3</guid>
      <category>q-bio.NC</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Davide Staub, Finn Rabe, Akhil Misra, Yves Pauli, Roya H\"uppi, Ni Yang, Nils Lang, Lars Michels, Victoria Edkins, Sascha Fr\"uhholz, Iris Sommer, Wolfram Hinzen, Philipp Homan</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
