<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CV updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CV</link>
    <description>cs.CV updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CV" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 01:32:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Saturday</day>
      <day>Sunday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>Computer Vision based Automated Quantification of Agricultural Sprayers Boom Displacement</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.19939</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.19939v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Application rate errors when using self-propelled agricultural sprayers for agricultural production remain a concern. Among other factors, spray boom instability is one of the major contributors to application errors. Spray booms' width of 38m, combined with 30 kph driving speeds, varying terrain, and machine dynamics when maneuvering complex field boundaries, make controls of these booms very complex. However, there is no quantitative knowledge on the extent of boom movement to systematically develop a solution that might include boom designs and responsive boom control systems. Therefore, this study was conducted to develop an automated computer vision system to quantify the boom movement of various agricultural sprayers. A computer vision system was developed to track a target on the edge of the sprayer boom in real time. YOLO V7, V8, and V11 neural network models were trained to track the boom's movements in field operations to quantify effective displacement in the vertical and transverse directions. An inclinometer sensor was mounted on the boom to capture boom angles and validate the neural network model output. The results showed that the model could detect the target with more than 90 percent accuracy, and distance estimates of the target on the boom were within 0.026 m of the inclinometer sensor data. This system can quantify the boom movement on the current sprayer and potentially on any other sprayer with minor modifications. The data can be used to make design improvements to make sprayer booms more stable and achieve greater application accuracy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.19939v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aryan Singh Dalal, Sidharth Rai, Rahul Singh, Treman Singh Kaloya, Rahul Harsha Cheppally, Ajay Sharda</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EBC-ZIP: Improving Blockwise Crowd Counting with Zero-Inflated Poisson Regression</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.19955</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.19955v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Density map estimation has become the mainstream paradigm in crowd counting. However, most existing methods overlook the extreme sparsity of ground-truth density maps. In real-world crowd scenes, the vast majority of spatial regions (often over 95%) contain no people, leading to heavily imbalanced count distributions. Ignoring this imbalance can bias models toward overestimating dense regions and underperforming in sparse areas. Furthermore, most loss functions used in density estimation are majorly based on MSE and implicitly assume Gaussian distributions, which are ill-suited for modeling discrete, non-negative count data. In this paper, we propose EBC-ZIP, a crowd counting framework that models the spatial distribution of counts using a Zero-Inflated Poisson (ZIP) regression formulation. Our approach replaces the traditional regression loss with the negative log-likelihood of the ZIP distribution, enabling better handling of zero-heavy distributions while preserving count accuracy. Built upon the recently proposed Enhanced Block Classification (EBC) framework, EBC-ZIP inherits EBC's advantages in preserving the discreteness of targets and ensuring training stability, while further improving performance through a more principled probabilistic loss. We also evaluate EBC-ZIP with backbones of varying computational complexity to assess its scalability. Extensive experiments on four crowd counting benchmarks demonstrate that EBC-ZIP consistently outperforms EBC and achieves state-of-the-art results.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.19955v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yiming Ma, Victor Sanchez, Tanaya Guha</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ToSA: Token Merging with Spatial Awareness</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20066</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20066v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Token merging has emerged as an effective strategy to accelerate Vision Transformers (ViT) by reducing computational costs. However, existing methods primarily rely on the visual token's feature similarity for token merging, overlooking the potential of integrating spatial information, which can serve as a reliable criterion for token merging in the early layers of ViT, where the visual tokens only possess weak visual information. In this paper, we propose ToSA, a novel token merging method that combines both semantic and spatial awareness to guide the token merging process. ToSA leverages the depth image as input to generate pseudo spatial tokens, which serve as auxiliary spatial information for the visual token merging process. With the introduced spatial awareness, ToSA achieves a more informed merging strategy that better preserves critical scene structure. Experimental results demonstrate that ToSA outperforms previous token merging methods across multiple benchmarks on visual and embodied question answering while largely reducing the runtime of the ViT, making it an efficient solution for ViT acceleration. The code will be available at: https://github.com/hsiangwei0903/ToSA</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20066v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hsiang-Wei Huang, Wenhao Chai, Kuang-Ming Chen, Cheng-Yen Yang, Jenq-Neng Hwang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BrokenVideos: A Benchmark Dataset for Fine-Grained Artifact Localization in AI-Generated Videos</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20103</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20103v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent advances in deep generative models have led to significant progress in video generation, yet the fidelity of AI-generated videos remains limited. Synthesized content often exhibits visual artifacts such as temporally inconsistent motion, physically implausible trajectories, unnatural object deformations, and local blurring that undermine realism and user trust. Accurate detection and spatial localization of these artifacts are crucial for both automated quality control and for guiding the development of improved generative models. However, the research community currently lacks a comprehensive benchmark specifically designed for artifact localization in AI generated videos. Existing datasets either restrict themselves to video or frame level detection or lack the fine-grained spatial annotations necessary for evaluating localization methods. To address this gap, we introduce BrokenVideos, a benchmark dataset of 3,254 AI-generated videos with meticulously annotated, pixel-level masks highlighting regions of visual corruption. Each annotation is validated through detailed human inspection to ensure high quality ground truth. Our experiments show that training state of the art artifact detection models and multi modal large language models (MLLMs) on BrokenVideos significantly improves their ability to localize corrupted regions. Through extensive evaluation, we demonstrate that BrokenVideos establishes a critical foundation for benchmarking and advancing research on artifact localization in generative video models. The dataset is available at: https://broken-video-detection-datetsets.github.io/Broken-Video-Detection-Datasets.github.io/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20103v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiahao Lin, Weixuan Peng, Bojia Zi, Yifeng Gao, Xianbiao Qi, Xingjun Ma, Yu-Gang Jiang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From 2D to 3D Cognition: A Brief Survey of General World Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20134</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20134v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: World models have garnered increasing attention in the development of artificial general intelligence (AGI), serving as computational frameworks for learning representations of the external world and forecasting future states. While early efforts focused on 2D visual perception and simulation, recent 3D-aware generative world models have demonstrated the ability to synthesize geometrically consistent, interactive 3D environments, marking a shift toward 3D spatial cognition. Despite rapid progress, the field lacks systematic analysis to categorize emerging techniques and clarify their roles in advancing 3D cognitive world models. This survey addresses this need by introducing a conceptual framework, providing a structured and forward-looking review of world models transitioning from 2D perception to 3D cognition. Within this framework, we highlight two key technological drivers, particularly advances in 3D representations and the incorporation of world knowledge, as fundamental pillars. Building on these, we dissect three core cognitive capabilities that underpin 3D world modeling: 3D physical scene generation, 3D spatial reasoning, and 3D spatial interaction. We further examine the deployment of these capabilities in real-world applications, including embodied AI, autonomous driving, digital twin, and gaming/VR. Finally, we identify challenges across data, modeling, and deployment, and outline future directions for advancing more robust and generalizable 3D world models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20134v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ningwei Xie, Zizi Tian, Lei Yang, Xiao-Ping Zhang, Meng Guo, Jie Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EAR: Erasing Concepts from Unified Autoregressive Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20151</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20151v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Autoregressive (AR) models have achieved unified and strong performance across both visual understanding and image generation tasks. However, removing undesired concepts from AR models while maintaining overall generation quality remains an open challenge. In this paper, we propose Erasure Autoregressive Model (EAR), a fine-tuning method for effective and utility-preserving concept erasure in AR models. Specifically, we introduce Windowed Gradient Accumulation (WGA) strategy to align patch-level decoding with erasure objectives, and Thresholded Loss Masking (TLM) strategy to protect content unrelated to the target concept during fine-tuning. Furthermore, we propose a novel benchmark, Erase Concept Generator and Visual Filter (ECGVF), aim at provide a more rigorous and comprehensive foundation for evaluating concept erasure in AR models. Specifically, we first employ structured templates across diverse large language models (LLMs) to pre-generate a large-scale corpus of target-replacement concept prompt pairs. Subsequently, we generate images from these prompts and subject them to rigorous filtering via a visual classifier to ensure concept fidelity and alignment. Extensive experimental results conducted on the ECGVF benchmark with the AR model Janus-Pro demonstrate that EAR achieves marked improvements in both erasure effectiveness and model utility preservation. Code is available at: https://github.com/immc-lab/ear/</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20151v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haipeng Fan, Shiyuan Zhang,  Baohunesitu, Zihang Guo, Huaiwen Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Loss-Aware Automatic Selection of Structured Pruning Criteria for Deep Neural Network Acceleration</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20152</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20152v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Structured pruning is a well-established technique for compressing neural networks, making it suitable for deployment in resource-limited edge devices. This paper presents an efficient Loss-Aware Automatic Selection of Structured Pruning Criteria (LAASP) for slimming and accelerating deep neural networks. The majority of pruning methodologies employ a sequential process consisting of three stages: 1) training, 2) pruning, and 3) fine-tuning, whereas the proposed pruning technique adopts a pruning-while-training approach that eliminates the first stage and integrates the second and third stages into a single cycle. The automatic selection of magnitude or similarity-based filter pruning criteria from a specified pool of criteria and the specific pruning layer at each pruning iteration is guided by the network's overall loss on a small subset of the training data. To mitigate the abrupt accuracy drop due to pruning, the network is retrained briefly after each reduction of a predefined number of floating-point operations (FLOPs). The optimal pruning rates for each layer in the network are automatically determined, eliminating the need for manual allocation of fixed or variable pruning rates for each layer. Experiments on the VGGNet and ResNet models on the CIFAR-10 and ImageNet benchmark datasets demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed method. In particular, the ResNet56 and ResNet110 models on the CIFAR-10 dataset significantly improve the top-1 accuracy compared to state-of-the-art methods while reducing the network FLOPs by 52\%. Furthermore, the ResNet50 model on the ImageNet dataset reduces FLOPs by more than 42\% with a negligible 0.33\% drop in top-5 accuracy. The source code of this paper is publicly available online - https://github.com/ghimiredhikura/laasp.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20152v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1016/j.imavis.2023.104745</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Image Vision Comput. 136 (2023) 104745</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Deepak Ghimire, Kilho Lee, Seong-heum Kim</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Efficient Exemplar Based Image Editing with Multimodal VLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20155</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20155v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Text-to-Image Diffusion models have enabled a wide array of image editing applications. However, capturing all types of edits through text alone can be challenging and cumbersome. The ambiguous nature of certain image edits is better expressed through an exemplar pair, i.e., a pair of images depicting an image before and after an edit respectively. In this work, we tackle exemplar-based image editing -- the task of transferring an edit from an exemplar pair to a content image(s), by leveraging pretrained text-to-image diffusion models and multimodal VLMs. Even though our end-to-end pipeline is optimization-free, our experiments demonstrate that it still outperforms baselines on multiple types of edits while being ~4x faster.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20155v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Avadhoot Jadhav, Ashutosh Srivastava, Abhinav Java, Silky Singh, Tarun Ram Menta, Surgan Jandial, Balaji Krishnamurthy</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seeing is Believing? Mitigating OCR Hallucinations in Multimodal Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20168</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20168v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent advancements in multimodal large language models have enhanced document understanding by integrating textual and visual information. However, existing models exhibit incompleteness within their paradigm in real-world scenarios, particularly under visual degradation. In such conditions, the current response paradigm often fails to adequately perceive visual degradation and ambiguity, leading to overreliance on linguistic priors or misaligned visual-textual reasoning. This difficulty in recognizing uncertainty frequently results in the generation of hallucinatory content, especially when a precise answer is not feasible. To better demonstrate and analyze this phenomenon and problem, we propose KIE-HVQA, the first benchmark dedicated to evaluating OCR hallucination in degraded document understanding. This dataset includes test samples spanning identity cards and invoices, with simulated real-world degradations for OCR reliability. This setup allows for evaluating models' capacity, under degraded input, to distinguish reliable visual information and answer accordingly, thereby highlighting the challenge of avoiding hallucination on uncertain data. To achieve vision-faithful reasoning and thereby avoid the aforementioned issues, we further introduce a GRPO-based framework featuring a novel reward mechanism. By incorporating a self-awareness of visual uncertainty and an analysis method that initiates refusal to answer to increase task difficulty within our supervised fine-tuning and reinforcement learning framework, we successfully mitigated hallucinations in ambiguous regions. Experiments on Qwen2.5-VL demonstrate that our 7B-parameter model achieves a 22\% absolute improvement in hallucination-free accuracy over GPT-4o on KIE-HVQA and there is no significant performance drop in standard tasks, highlighting both effectiveness and robustness.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20168v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhentao He, Can Zhang, Ziheng Wu, Zhenghao Chen, Yufei Zhan, Yifan Li, Zhao Zhang, Xian Wang, Minghui Qiu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Scalable and Generalizable Earth Observation Data Mining via Foundation Model Composition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20174</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20174v2 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Foundation models are rapidly transforming Earth Observation data mining by enabling generalizable and scalable solutions for key tasks such as scene classification and semantic segmentation. While most efforts in the geospatial domain have focused on developing large models trained from scratch using massive Earth Observation datasets, an alternative strategy that remains underexplored is the reuse and combination of existing pretrained models. In this study, we investigate whether foundation models pretrained on remote sensing and general vision datasets can be effectively combined to improve performance across a diverse set of key Earth Observation tasks. Using the GEO-Bench benchmark, we evaluate several prominent models, including Prithvi, Hiera, and DOFA, on eleven datasets covering a range of spatial resolutions, sensor modalities, and task types. The results show that feature-level ensembling of smaller pretrained models can match or exceed the performance of much larger models, while requiring less training time and computational resources. Moreover, the study highlights the potential of applying knowledge distillation to transfer the strengths of ensembles into more compact models, offering a practical path for deploying foundation models in real-world Earth Observation applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20174v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Man Duc Chuc</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progressive Alignment Degradation Learning for Pansharpening</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20179</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20179v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Deep learning-based pansharpening has been shown to effectively generate high-resolution multispectral (HRMS) images. To create supervised ground-truth HRMS images, synthetic data generated using the Wald protocol is commonly employed. This protocol assumes that networks trained on artificial low-resolution data will perform equally well on high-resolution data. However, well-trained models typically exhibit a trade-off in performance between reduced-resolution and full-resolution datasets. In this paper, we delve into the Wald protocol and find that its inaccurate approximation of real-world degradation patterns limits the generalization of deep pansharpening models. To address this issue, we propose the Progressive Alignment Degradation Module (PADM), which uses mutual iteration between two sub-networks, PAlignNet and PDegradeNet, to adaptively learn accurate degradation processes without relying on predefined operators. Building on this, we introduce HFreqdiff, which embeds high-frequency details into a diffusion framework and incorporates CFB and BACM modules for frequency-selective detail extraction and precise reverse process learning. These innovations enable effective integration of high-resolution panchromatic and multispectral images, significantly enhancing spatial sharpness and quality. Experiments and ablation studies demonstrate the proposed method's superior performance compared to state-of-the-art techniques.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20179v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Enzhe Zhao, Zhichang Guo, Yao Li, Fanghui Song, Boying Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UniCode$^2$: Cascaded Large-scale Codebooks for Unified Multimodal Understanding and Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20214</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20214v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Unified multimodal large language models (MLLMs) have shown promise in jointly advancing multimodal understanding and generation, with visual codebooks discretizing images into tokens for autoregressive modeling. Existing codebook-based methods either rely on small vocabularies (~16K entries) that lack fine-grained semantics or naively scale up, resulting in low token utilization and unstable training. We propose UniCode$^2$, a cascaded codebook framework enabling large-scale, semantically aligned, and stable visual tokenization. By clustering millions of SigLIP sequence embeddings, we build a 500K-entry codebook that preserves vision-language alignment while expanding capacity. Stability is ensured via a cascaded design: a frozen codebook anchors the embedding space, and a trainable codebook refines task-specific semantics. This decoupling promotes high utilization and robust learning. Moreover, the alignment of our visual tokens with textual semantics enables seamless integration with pretrained diffusion decoders, supporting high-quality visual synthesis with minimal adaptation. UniCode^2 delivers strong performance across diverse benchmarks, demonstrating the viability of scaling visual token spaces without sacrificing stability, semantics, or modularity.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20214v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yanzhe Chen (Yen-chieh Chan), Huasong Zhong, Yan Li, Zhenheng Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Bandwidth Allocation for Hybrid Event-RGB Transmission</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20222</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20222v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Event cameras asynchronously capture pixel-level intensity changes with extremely low latency. They are increasingly used in conjunction with RGB cameras for a wide range of vision-related applications. However, a major challenge in these hybrid systems lies in the transmission of the large volume of triggered events and RGB images. To address this, we propose a transmission scheme that retains efficient reconstruction performance of both sources while accomplishing real-time deblurring in parallel. Conventional RGB cameras and event cameras typically capture the same scene in different ways, often resulting in significant redundant information across their outputs. To address this, we develop a joint event and image (E-I) transmission framework to eliminate redundancy and thereby optimize channel bandwidth utilization. Our approach employs Bayesian modeling and the information bottleneck method to disentangle the shared and domain-specific information within the E-I inputs. This disentangled information bottleneck framework ensures both the compactness and informativeness of extracted shared and domain-specific information. Moreover, it adaptively allocates transmission bandwidth based on scene dynamics, i.e., more symbols are allocated to events for dynamic details or to images for static information. Simulation results demonstrate that the proposed scheme not only achieves superior reconstruction quality compared to conventional systems but also delivers enhanced deblurring performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20222v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.SP</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Pujing Yang, Guangyi Zhang, Yunlong Cai, Lei Yu, Guanding Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recognizing Surgical Phases Anywhere: Few-Shot Test-time Adaptation and Task-graph Guided Refinement</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20254</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20254v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The complexity and diversity of surgical workflows, driven by heterogeneous operating room settings, institutional protocols, and anatomical variability, present a significant challenge in developing generalizable models for cross-institutional and cross-procedural surgical understanding. While recent surgical foundation models pretrained on large-scale vision-language data offer promising transferability, their zero-shot performance remains constrained by domain shifts, limiting their utility in unseen surgical environments. To address this, we introduce Surgical Phase Anywhere (SPA), a lightweight framework for versatile surgical workflow understanding that adapts foundation models to institutional settings with minimal annotation. SPA leverages few-shot spatial adaptation to align multi-modal embeddings with institution-specific surgical scenes and phases. It also ensures temporal consistency through diffusion modeling, which encodes task-graph priors derived from institutional procedure protocols. Finally, SPA employs dynamic test-time adaptation, exploiting the mutual agreement between multi-modal phase prediction streams to adapt the model to a given test video in a self-supervised manner, enhancing the reliability under test-time distribution shifts. SPA is a lightweight adaptation framework, allowing hospitals to rapidly customize phase recognition models by defining phases in natural language text, annotating a few images with the phase labels, and providing a task graph defining phase transitions. The experimental results show that the SPA framework achieves state-of-the-art performance in few-shot surgical phase recognition across multiple institutions and procedures, even outperforming full-shot models with 32-shot labeled data. Code is available at https://github.com/CAMMA-public/SPA</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20254v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kun Yuan, Tingxuan Chen, Shi Li, Joel L. Lavanchy, Christian Heiliger, Ege \"Ozsoy, Yiming Huang, Long Bai, Nassir Navab, Vinkle Srivastav, Hongliang Ren, Nicolas Padoy</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Transformer Based Handwriting Recognition System Jointly Using Online and Offline Features</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20255</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20255v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We posit that handwriting recognition benefits from complementary cues carried by the rasterized complex glyph and the pen's trajectory, yet most systems exploit only one modality. We introduce an end-to-end network that performs early fusion of offline images and online stroke data within a shared latent space. A patch encoder converts the grayscale crop into fixed-length visual tokens, while a lightweight transformer embeds the $(x, y, \text{pen})$ sequence. Learnable latent queries attend jointly to both token streams, yielding context-enhanced stroke embeddings that are pooled and decoded under a cross-entropy loss objective. Because integration occurs before any high-level classification, temporal cues reinforce each other during representation learning, producing stronger writer independence. Comprehensive experiments on IAMOn-DB and VNOn-DB demonstrate that our approach achieves state-of-the-art accuracy, exceeding previous bests by up to 1\%. Our study also shows adaptation of this pipeline with gesturification on the ISI-Air dataset. Our code can be found here.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20255v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ayush Lodh, Ritabrata Chakraborty, Shivakumara Palaiahnakote, Umapada Pal</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Mask-Enhanced Dual Reconstruction Network for Few-Shot Fine-Grained Image Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20263</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20263v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Few-shot fine-grained image classification (FS-FGIC) presents a significant challenge, requiring models to distinguish visually similar subclasses with limited labeled examples. Existing methods have critical limitations: metric-based methods lose spatial information and misalign local features, while reconstruction-based methods fail to utilize hierarchical feature information and lack mechanisms to focus on discriminative regions. We propose the Hierarchical Mask-enhanced Dual Reconstruction Network (HMDRN), which integrates dual-layer feature reconstruction with mask-enhanced feature processing to improve fine-grained classification. HMDRN incorporates a dual-layer feature reconstruction and fusion module that leverages complementary visual information from different network hierarchies. Through learnable fusion weights, the model balances high-level semantic representations from the last layer with mid-level structural details from the penultimate layer. Additionally, we design a spatial binary mask-enhanced transformer self-reconstruction module that processes query features through adaptive thresholding while maintaining complete support features, enhancing focus on discriminative regions while filtering background noise. Extensive experiments on three challenging fine-grained datasets demonstrate that HMDRN consistently outperforms state-of-the-art methods across Conv-4 and ResNet-12 backbone architectures. Comprehensive ablation studies validate the effectiveness of each proposed component, revealing that dual-layer reconstruction enhances inter-class discrimination while mask-enhanced transformation reduces intra-class variations. Visualization results provide evidence of HMDRN's superior feature reconstruction capabilities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20263v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ning Luo, Meiyin Hu, Huan Wan, Yanyan Yang, Zhuohang Jiang, Xin Wei</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forensic Study of Paintings Through the Comparison of Fabrics</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20272</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20272v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The study of canvas fabrics in works of art is a crucial tool for authentication, attribution and conservation. Traditional methods are based on thread density map matching, which cannot be applied when canvases do not come from contiguous positions on a roll. This paper presents a novel approach based on deep learning to assess the similarity of textiles. We introduce an automatic tool that evaluates the similarity between canvases without relying on thread density maps. A Siamese deep learning model is designed and trained to compare pairs of images by exploiting the feature representations learned from the scans. In addition, a similarity estimation method is proposed, aggregating predictions from multiple pairs of cloth samples to provide a robust similarity score. Our approach is applied to canvases from the Museo Nacional del Prado, corroborating the hypothesis that plain weave canvases, widely used in painting, can be effectively compared even when their thread densities are similar. The results demonstrate the feasibility and accuracy of the proposed method, opening new avenues for the analysis of masterpieces.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20272v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Juan Jos\'e Murillo-Fuentes, Pablo M. Olmos, Laura Alba-Carcel\'en</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Ideal to Real: Unified and Data-Efficient Dense Prediction for Real-World Scenarios</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20279</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20279v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Dense prediction tasks hold significant importance of computer vision, aiming to learn pixel-wise annotated label for an input image. Despite advances in this field, existing methods primarily focus on idealized conditions, with limited generalization to real-world scenarios and facing the challenging scarcity of real-world data. To systematically study this problem, we first introduce DenseWorld, a benchmark spanning a broad set of 25 dense prediction tasks that correspond to urgent real-world applications, featuring unified evaluation across tasks. Then, we propose DenseDiT, which maximally exploits generative models' visual priors to perform diverse real-world dense prediction tasks through a unified strategy. DenseDiT combines a parameter-reuse mechanism and two lightweight branches that adaptively integrate multi-scale context, working with less than 0.1% additional parameters. Evaluations on DenseWorld reveal significant performance drops in existing general and specialized baselines, highlighting their limited real-world generalization. In contrast, DenseDiT achieves superior results using less than 0.01% training data of baselines, underscoring its practical value for real-world deployment. Our data, and checkpoints and codes are available at https://xcltql666.github.io/DenseDiTProj</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20279v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Changliang Xia, Chengyou Jia, Zhuohang Dang, Minnan Luo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Spatial Boundaries: Spectral-Domain Registration Guided Hyperspectral and Multispectral Blind Fusion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20293</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20293v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The blind fusion of unregistered hyperspectral images (HSIs) and multispectral images (MSIs) has attracted growing attention recently. To address the registration challenge, most existing methods employ spatial transformations on the HSI to achieve alignment with the MSI. However, due to the substantial differences in spatial resolution of the images, the performance of these methods is often unsatisfactory. Moreover, the registration process tends to be time-consuming when dealing with large-sized images in remote sensing. To address these issues, we propose tackling the registration problem from the spectral domain. Initially, a lightweight Spectral Prior Learning (SPL) network is developed to extract spectral features from the HSI and enhance the spectral resolution of the MSI. Following this, the obtained image undergoes spatial downsampling to produce the registered HSI. In this process, subspace representation and cyclic training strategy are employed to improve spectral accuracy of the registered HSI obtained. Next, we propose a blind sparse fusion (BSF) method, which utilizes group sparsity regularization to equivalently promote the low-rankness of the image. This approach not only circumvents the need for rank estimation, but also reduces computational complexity. Then, we employ the Proximal Alternating Optimization (PAO) algorithm to solve the BSF model, and present its convergence analysis. Finally, extensive numerical experiments on simulated and real datasets are conducted to verify the effectiveness of our method in registration and fusion. We also demonstrate its efficacy in enhancing classification performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20293v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kunjing Yang, Libin Zheng, Minru Bai, Ting Lu, Leyuan Fang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ctrl-Z Sampling: Diffusion Sampling with Controlled Random Zigzag Explorations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20294</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20294v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Diffusion models have shown strong performance in conditional generation by progressively denoising Gaussian noise toward a target data distribution. This denoising process can be interpreted as a form of hill climbing in a learned latent space, where the model iteratively refines the sample toward regions of higher probability. However, diffusion models often converge to local optima that are locally visually coherent yet globally inconsistent or conditionally misaligned, due to latent space complexity and suboptimal initialization. Prior efforts attempted to address this by strengthening guidance signals or manipulating the initial noise distribution. We introduce Controlled Random Zigzag Sampling (Ctrl-Z Sampling), a novel sampling strategy designed to detect and escape such local maxima during conditional generation. The method first identifies potential local maxima using a reward model. Upon detection, it injects noise and reverts to a previous, noisier state to escape the current optimization plateau. The reward model then evaluates candidate trajectories, accepting only those that offer improvement, while progressively deeper retreat enables stronger escapes when nearby alternatives fail. This controlled random zigzag process allows dynamic alternation between forward refinement and backward exploration, enhancing both alignment and visual quality in the generated outputs. The proposed Ctrl-Z Sampling is model-agnostic and compatible with existing diffusion frameworks. Experimental results show that Ctrl-Z Sampling substantially improves generation quality with only around 7.6X increase in function evaluations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20294v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shunqi Mao, Wei Guo, Chaoyi Zhang, Weidong Cai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TDiR: Transformer based Diffusion for Image Restoration Tasks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20302</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20302v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Images captured in challenging environments often experience various forms of degradation, including noise, color cast, blur, and light scattering. These effects significantly reduce image quality, hindering their applicability in downstream tasks such as object detection, mapping, and classification. Our transformer-based diffusion model was developed to address image restoration tasks, aiming to improve the quality of degraded images. This model was evaluated against existing deep learning methodologies across multiple quality metrics for underwater image enhancement, denoising, and deraining on publicly available datasets. Our findings demonstrate that the diffusion model, combined with transformers, surpasses current methods in performance. The results of our model highlight the efficacy of diffusion models and transformers in improving the quality of degraded images, consequently expanding their utility in downstream tasks that require high-fidelity visual data.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20302v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Abbas Anwar, Mohammad Shullar, Ali Arshad Nasir, Mudassir Masood, Saeed Anwar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Radiomic fingerprints for knee MR images assessment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20306</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20306v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Accurate interpretation of knee MRI scans relies on expert clinical judgment, often with high variability and limited scalability. Existing radiomic approaches use a fixed set of radiomic features (the signature), selected at the population level and applied uniformly to all patients. While interpretable, these signatures are often too constrained to represent individual pathological variations. As a result, conventional radiomic-based approaches are found to be limited in performance, compared with recent end-to-end deep learning (DL) alternatives without using interpretable radiomic features. We argue that the individual-agnostic nature in current radiomic selection is not central to its intepretability, but is responsible for the poor generalization in our application. Here, we propose a novel radiomic fingerprint framework, in which a radiomic feature set (the fingerprint) is dynamically constructed for each patient, selected by a DL model. Unlike the existing radiomic signatures, our fingerprints are derived on a per-patient basis by predicting the feature relevance in a large radiomic feature pool, and selecting only those that are predictive of clinical conditions for individual patients. The radiomic-selecting model is trained simultaneously with a low-dimensional (considered relatively explainable) logistic regression for downstream classification. We validate our methods across multiple diagnostic tasks including general knee abnormalities, anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) tears, and meniscus tears, demonstrating comparable or superior diagnostic accuracy relative to state-of-the-art end-to-end DL models. More importantly, we show that the interpretability inherent in our approach facilitates meaningful clinical insights and potential biomarker discovery, with detailed discussion, quantitative and qualitative analysis of real-world clinical cases to evidence these advantages.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20306v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yaxi Chen, Simin Ni, Shaheer U. Saeed, Aleksandra Ivanova, Rikin Hargunani, Jie Huang, Chaozong Liu, Yipeng Hu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Burstiness of Faces in Set</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20312</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20312v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Burstiness, a phenomenon observed in text and image retrieval, refers to that particular elements appear more times in a set than a statistically independent model assumes. We argue that in the context of set-based face recognition (SFR), burstiness exists widely and degrades the performance in two aspects: Firstly, the bursty faces, where faces with particular attributes %exist frequently in a face set, dominate the training instances and dominate the training face sets and lead to poor generalization ability to unconstrained scenarios. Secondly, the bursty faces %dominating the evaluation sets interfere with the similarity comparison in set verification and identification when evaluation. To detect the bursty faces in a set, we propose three strategies based on Quickshift++, feature self-similarity, and generalized max-pooling (GMP). We apply the burst detection results on training and evaluation stages to enhance the sampling ratios or contributions of the infrequent faces. When evaluation, we additionally propose the quality-aware GMP that enables awareness of the face quality and robustness to the low-quality faces for the original GMP. We give illustrations and extensive experiments on the SFR benchmarks to demonstrate that burstiness is widespread and suppressing burstiness considerably improves the recognition performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20312v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiong Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Codicology to Code: A Comparative Study of Transformer and YOLO-based Detectors for Layout Analysis in Historical Documents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20326</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20326v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Robust Document Layout Analysis (DLA) is critical for the automated processing and understanding of historical documents with complex page organizations. This paper benchmarks five state-of-the-art object detection architectures on three annotated datasets representing a spectrum of codicological complexity: The e-NDP, a corpus of Parisian medieval registers (1326-1504); CATMuS, a diverse multiclass dataset derived from various medieval and modern sources (ca.12th-17th centuries) and HORAE, a corpus of decorated books of hours (ca.13th-16th centuries). We evaluate two Transformer-based models (Co-DETR, Grounding DINO) against three YOLO variants (AABB, OBB, and YOLO-World). Our findings reveal significant performance variations dependent on model architecture, data set characteristics, and bounding box representation. In the e-NDP dataset, Co-DETR achieves state-of-the-art results (0.752 mAP@.50:.95), closely followed by YOLOv11X-OBB (0.721). Conversely, on the more complex CATMuS and HORAE datasets, the CNN-based YOLOv11x-OBB significantly outperforms all other models (0.564 and 0.568, respectively). This study unequivocally demonstrates that using Oriented Bounding Boxes (OBB) is not a minor refinement but a fundamental requirement for accurately modeling the non-Cartesian nature of historical manuscripts. We conclude that a key trade-off exists between the global context awareness of Transformers, ideal for structured layouts, and the superior generalization of CNN-OBB models for visually diverse and complex documents.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20326v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.DB</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sergio Torres Aguilar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feature Hallucination for Self-supervised Action Recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20342</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20342v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Understanding human actions in videos requires more than raw pixel analysis; it relies on high-level semantic reasoning and effective integration of multimodal features. We propose a deep translational action recognition framework that enhances recognition accuracy by jointly predicting action concepts and auxiliary features from RGB video frames. At test time, hallucination streams infer missing cues, enriching feature representations without increasing computational overhead. To focus on action-relevant regions beyond raw pixels, we introduce two novel domain-specific descriptors. Object Detection Features (ODF) aggregate outputs from multiple object detectors to capture contextual cues, while Saliency Detection Features (SDF) highlight spatial and intensity patterns crucial for action recognition. Our framework seamlessly integrates these descriptors with auxiliary modalities such as optical flow, Improved Dense Trajectories, skeleton data, and audio cues. It remains compatible with state-of-the-art architectures, including I3D, AssembleNet, Video Transformer Network, FASTER, and recent models like VideoMAE V2 and InternVideo2. To handle uncertainty in auxiliary features, we incorporate aleatoric uncertainty modeling in the hallucination step and introduce a robust loss function to mitigate feature noise. Our multimodal self-supervised action recognition framework achieves state-of-the-art performance on multiple benchmarks, including Kinetics-400, Kinetics-600, and Something-Something V2, demonstrating its effectiveness in capturing fine-grained action dynamics.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20342v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lei Wang, Piotr Koniusz</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>InvZW: Invariant Feature Learning via Noise-Adversarial Training for Robust Image Zero-Watermarking</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20370</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20370v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper introduces a novel deep learning framework for robust image zero-watermarking based on distortion-invariant feature learning. As a zero-watermarking scheme, our method leaves the original image unaltered and learns a reference signature through optimization in the feature space. The proposed framework consists of two key modules. In the first module, a feature extractor is trained via noise-adversarial learning to generate representations that are both invariant to distortions and semantically expressive. This is achieved by combining adversarial supervision against a distortion discriminator and a reconstruction constraint to retain image content. In the second module, we design a learning-based multibit zero-watermarking scheme where the trained invariant features are projected onto a set of trainable reference codes optimized to match a target binary message. Extensive experiments on diverse image datasets and a wide range of distortions show that our method achieves state-of-the-art robustness in both feature stability and watermark recovery. Comparative evaluations against existing self-supervised and deep watermarking techniques further highlight the superiority of our framework in generalization and robustness.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20370v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Abdullah All Tanvir, Xin Zhong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploiting Lightweight Hierarchical ViT and Dynamic Framework for Efficient Visual Tracking</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20381</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20381v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Transformer-based visual trackers have demonstrated significant advancements due to their powerful modeling capabilities. However, their practicality is limited on resource-constrained devices because of their slow processing speeds. To address this challenge, we present HiT, a novel family of efficient tracking models that achieve high performance while maintaining fast operation across various devices. The core innovation of HiT lies in its Bridge Module, which connects lightweight transformers to the tracking framework, enhancing feature representation quality. Additionally, we introduce a dual-image position encoding approach to effectively encode spatial information. HiT achieves an impressive speed of 61 frames per second (fps) on the NVIDIA Jetson AGX platform, alongside a competitive AUC of 64.6% on the LaSOT benchmark, outperforming all previous efficient trackers.Building on HiT, we propose DyHiT, an efficient dynamic tracker that flexibly adapts to scene complexity by selecting routes with varying computational requirements. DyHiT uses search area features extracted by the backbone network and inputs them into an efficient dynamic router to classify tracking scenarios. Based on the classification, DyHiT applies a divide-and-conquer strategy, selecting appropriate routes to achieve a superior trade-off between accuracy and speed. The fastest version of DyHiT achieves 111 fps on NVIDIA Jetson AGX while maintaining an AUC of 62.4% on LaSOT.Furthermore, we introduce a training-free acceleration method based on the dynamic routing architecture of DyHiT. This method significantly improves the execution speed of various high-performance trackers without sacrificing accuracy. For instance, our acceleration method enables the state-of-the-art tracker SeqTrack-B256 to achieve a 2.68 times speedup on an NVIDIA GeForce RTX 2080 Ti GPU while maintaining the same AUC of 69.9% on the LaSOT.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20381v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ben Kang, Xin Chen, Jie Zhao, Chunjuan Bo, Dong Wang, Huchuan Lu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Novel Large Vision Foundation Model (LVFM)-based Approach for Generating High-Resolution Canopy Height Maps in Plantations for Precision Forestry Management</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20388</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20388v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Accurate, cost-effective monitoring of plantation aboveground biomass (AGB) is crucial for supporting local livelihoods and carbon sequestration initiatives like the China Certified Emission Reduction (CCER) program. High-resolution canopy height maps (CHMs) are essential for this, but standard lidar-based methods are expensive. While deep learning with RGB imagery offers an alternative, accurately extracting canopy height features remains challenging. To address this, we developed a novel model for high-resolution CHM generation using a Large Vision Foundation Model (LVFM). Our model integrates a feature extractor, a self-supervised feature enhancement module to preserve spatial details, and a height estimator. Tested in Beijing's Fangshan District using 1-meter Google Earth imagery, our model outperformed existing methods, including conventional CNNs. It achieved a mean absolute error of 0.09 m, a root mean square error of 0.24 m, and a correlation of 0.78 against lidar-based CHMs. The resulting CHMs enabled over 90% success in individual tree detection, high accuracy in AGB estimation, and effective tracking of plantation growth, demonstrating strong generalization to non-training areas. This approach presents a promising, scalable tool for evaluating carbon sequestration in both plantations and natural forests.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20388v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shen Tan, Xin Zhang, Liangxiu Han, Huaguo Huang, Han Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Med-Art: Diffusion Transformer for 2D Medical Text-to-Image Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20449</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20449v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Text-to-image generative models have achieved remarkable breakthroughs in recent years. However, their application in medical image generation still faces significant challenges, including small dataset sizes, and scarcity of medical textual data. To address these challenges, we propose Med-Art, a framework specifically designed for medical image generation with limited data. Med-Art leverages vision-language models to generate visual descriptions of medical images which overcomes the scarcity of applicable medical textual data. Med-Art adapts a large-scale pre-trained text-to-image model, PixArt-$\alpha$, based on the Diffusion Transformer (DiT), achieving high performance under limited data. Furthermore, we propose an innovative Hybrid-Level Diffusion Fine-tuning (HLDF) method, which enables pixel-level losses, effectively addressing issues such as overly saturated colors. We achieve state-of-the-art performance on two medical image datasets, measured by FID, KID, and downstream classification performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20449v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Changlu Guo, Anders Nymark Christensen, Morten Rieger Hannemose</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HiWave: Training-Free High-Resolution Image Generation via Wavelet-Based Diffusion Sampling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20452</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20452v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Diffusion models have emerged as the leading approach for image synthesis, demonstrating exceptional photorealism and diversity. However, training diffusion models at high resolutions remains computationally prohibitive, and existing zero-shot generation techniques for synthesizing images beyond training resolutions often produce artifacts, including object duplication and spatial incoherence. In this paper, we introduce HiWave, a training-free, zero-shot approach that substantially enhances visual fidelity and structural coherence in ultra-high-resolution image synthesis using pretrained diffusion models. Our method employs a two-stage pipeline: generating a base image from the pretrained model followed by a patch-wise DDIM inversion step and a novel wavelet-based detail enhancer module. Specifically, we first utilize inversion methods to derive initial noise vectors that preserve global coherence from the base image. Subsequently, during sampling, our wavelet-domain detail enhancer retains low-frequency components from the base image to ensure structural consistency, while selectively guiding high-frequency components to enrich fine details and textures. Extensive evaluations using Stable Diffusion XL demonstrate that HiWave effectively mitigates common visual artifacts seen in prior methods, achieving superior perceptual quality. A user study confirmed HiWave's performance, where it was preferred over the state-of-the-art alternative in more than 80% of comparisons, highlighting its effectiveness for high-quality, ultra-high-resolution image synthesis without requiring retraining or architectural modifications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20452v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tobias Vontobel, Seyedmorteza Sadat, Farnood Salehi, Romann M. Weber</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Deep Learning Approach to Identify Rock Bolts in Complex 3D Point Clouds of Underground Mines Captured Using Mobile Laser Scanners</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20464</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20464v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Rock bolts are crucial components of the subterranean support systems in underground mines that provide adequate structural reinforcement to the rock mass to prevent unforeseen hazards like rockfalls. This makes frequent assessments of such bolts critical for maintaining rock mass stability and minimising risks in underground mining operations. Where manual surveying of rock bolts is challenging due to the low light conditions in the underground mines and the time-intensive nature of the process, automated detection of rock bolts serves as a plausible solution. To that end, this study focuses on the automatic identification of rock bolts within medium to large-scale 3D point clouds obtained from underground mines using mobile laser scanners. Existing techniques for automated rock bolt identification primarily rely on feature engineering and traditional machine learning approaches. However, such techniques lack robustness as these point clouds present several challenges due to data noise, varying environments, and complex surrounding structures. Moreover, the target rock bolts are extremely small objects within large-scale point clouds and are often partially obscured due to the application of reinforcement shotcrete. Addressing these challenges, this paper proposes an approach termed DeepBolt, which employs a novel two-stage deep learning architecture specifically designed for handling severe class imbalance for the automatic and efficient identification of rock bolts in complex 3D point clouds. The proposed method surpasses state-of-the-art semantic segmentation models by up to 42.5% in Intersection over Union (IoU) for rock bolt points. Additionally, it outperforms existing rock bolt identification techniques, achieving a 96.41% precision and 96.96% recall in classifying rock bolts, demonstrating its robustness and effectiveness in complex underground environments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20464v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dibyayan Patra, Pasindu Ranasinghe, Bikram Banerjee, Simit Raval</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI-assisted radiographic analysis in detecting alveolar bone-loss severity and patterns</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20522</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20522v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Periodontitis, a chronic inflammatory disease causing alveolar bone loss, significantly affects oral health and quality of life. Accurate assessment of bone loss severity and pattern is critical for diagnosis and treatment planning. In this study, we propose a novel AI-based deep learning framework to automatically detect and quantify alveolar bone loss and its patterns using intraoral periapical (IOPA) radiographs. Our method combines YOLOv8 for tooth detection with Keypoint R-CNN models to identify anatomical landmarks, enabling precise calculation of bone loss severity. Additionally, YOLOv8x-seg models segment bone levels and tooth masks to determine bone loss patterns (horizontal vs. angular) via geometric analysis. Evaluated on a large, expertly annotated dataset of 1000 radiographs, our approach achieved high accuracy in detecting bone loss severity (intra-class correlation coefficient up to 0.80) and bone loss pattern classification (accuracy 87%). This automated system offers a rapid, objective, and reproducible tool for periodontal assessment, reducing reliance on subjective manual evaluation. By integrating AI into dental radiographic analysis, our framework has the potential to improve early diagnosis and personalized treatment planning for periodontitis, ultimately enhancing patient care and clinical outcomes.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20522v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chathura Wimalasiri, Piumal Rathnayake, Shamod Wijerathne, Sumudu Rasnayaka, Dhanushka Leuke Bandara, Roshan Ragel, Vajira Thambawita, Isuru Nawinne</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pay Less Attention to Deceptive Artifacts: Robust Detection of Compressed Deepfakes on Online Social Networks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20548</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20548v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: With the rapid advancement of deep learning, particularly through generative adversarial networks (GANs) and diffusion models (DMs), AI-generated images, or ``deepfakes", have become nearly indistinguishable from real ones. These images are widely shared across Online Social Networks (OSNs), raising concerns about their misuse. Existing deepfake detection methods overlook the ``block effects" introduced by compression in OSNs, which obscure deepfake artifacts, and primarily focus on raw images, rarely encountered in real-world scenarios. To address these challenges, we propose PLADA (Pay Less Attention to Deceptive Artifacts), a novel framework designed to tackle the lack of paired data and the ineffective use of compressed images. PLADA consists of two core modules: Block Effect Eraser (B2E), which uses a dual-stage attention mechanism to handle block effects, and Open Data Aggregation (ODA), which processes both paired and unpaired data to improve detection. Extensive experiments across 26 datasets demonstrate that PLADA achieves a remarkable balance in deepfake detection, outperforming SoTA methods in detecting deepfakes on OSNs, even with limited paired data and compression. More importantly, this work introduces the ``block effect" as a critical factor in deepfake detection, providing a robust solution for open-world scenarios. Our code is available at https://github.com/ManyiLee/PLADA.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20548v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Manyi Li, Renshuai Tao, Yufan Liu, Chuangchuang Tan, Haotong Qin, Bing Li, Yunchao Wei, Yao Zhao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lightweight Multi-Frame Integration for Robust YOLO Object Detection in Videos</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20550</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20550v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Modern image-based object detection models, such as YOLOv7, primarily process individual frames independently, thus ignoring valuable temporal context naturally present in videos. Meanwhile, existing video-based detection methods often introduce complex temporal modules, significantly increasing model size and computational complexity. In practical applications such as surveillance and autonomous driving, transient challenges including motion blur, occlusions, and abrupt appearance changes can severely degrade single-frame detection performance. To address these issues, we propose a straightforward yet highly effective strategy: stacking multiple consecutive frames as input to a YOLO-based detector while supervising only the output corresponding to a single target frame. This approach leverages temporal information with minimal modifications to existing architectures, preserving simplicity, computational efficiency, and real-time inference capability. Extensive experiments on the challenging MOT20Det and our BOAT360 datasets demonstrate that our method improves detection robustness, especially for lightweight models, effectively narrowing the gap between compact and heavy detection networks. Additionally, we contribute the BOAT360 benchmark dataset, comprising annotated fisheye video sequences captured from a boat, to support future research in multi-frame video object detection in challenging real-world scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20550v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yitong Quan, Benjamin Kiefer, Martin Messmer, Andreas Zell</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AdvMIM: Adversarial Masked Image Modeling for Semi-Supervised Medical Image Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20563</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20563v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Vision Transformer has recently gained tremendous popularity in medical image segmentation task due to its superior capability in capturing long-range dependencies. However, transformer requires a large amount of labeled data to be effective, which hinders its applicability in annotation scarce semi-supervised learning scenario where only limited labeled data is available. State-of-the-art semi-supervised learning methods propose combinatorial CNN-Transformer learning to cross teach a transformer with a convolutional neural network, which achieves promising results. However, it remains a challenging task to effectively train the transformer with limited labeled data. In this paper, we propose an adversarial masked image modeling method to fully unleash the potential of transformer for semi-supervised medical image segmentation. The key challenge in semi-supervised learning with transformer lies in the lack of sufficient supervision signal. To this end, we propose to construct an auxiliary masked domain from original domain with masked image modeling and train the transformer to predict the entire segmentation mask with masked inputs to increase supervision signal. We leverage the original labels from labeled data and pseudo-labels from unlabeled data to learn the masked domain. To further benefit the original domain from masked domain, we provide a theoretical analysis of our method from a multi-domain learning perspective and devise a novel adversarial training loss to reduce the domain gap between the original and masked domain, which boosts semi-supervised learning performance. We also extend adversarial masked image modeling to CNN network. Extensive experiments on three public medical image segmentation datasets demonstrate the effectiveness of our method, where our method outperforms existing methods significantly. Our code is publicly available at https://github.com/zlheui/AdvMIM.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20563v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lei Zhu, Jun Zhou, Rick Siow Mong Goh, Yong Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Show, Tell and Summarize: Dense Video Captioning Using Visual Cue Aided Sentence Summarization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20567</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20567v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this work, we propose a division-and-summarization (DaS) framework for dense video captioning. After partitioning each untrimmed long video as multiple event proposals, where each event proposal consists of a set of short video segments, we extract visual feature (e.g., C3D feature) from each segment and use the existing image/video captioning approach to generate one sentence description for this segment. Considering that the generated sentences contain rich semantic descriptions about the whole event proposal, we formulate the dense video captioning task as a visual cue aided sentence summarization problem and propose a new two stage Long Short Term Memory (LSTM) approach equipped with a new hierarchical attention mechanism to summarize all generated sentences as one descriptive sentence with the aid of visual features. Specifically, the first-stage LSTM network takes all semantic words from the generated sentences and the visual features from all segments within one event proposal as the input, and acts as the encoder to effectively summarize both semantic and visual information related to this event proposal. The second-stage LSTM network takes the output from the first-stage LSTM network and the visual features from all video segments within one event proposal as the input, and acts as the decoder to generate one descriptive sentence for this event proposal. Our comprehensive experiments on the ActivityNet Captions dataset demonstrate the effectiveness of our newly proposed DaS framework for dense video captioning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20567v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhiwang Zhang, Dong Xu, Wanli Ouyang, Chuanqi Tan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Causal Representation Learning with Observational Grouping for CXR Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20582</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20582v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Identifiable causal representation learning seeks to uncover the true causal relationships underlying a data generation process. In medical imaging, this presents opportunities to improve the generalisability and robustness of task-specific latent features. This work introduces the concept of grouping observations to learn identifiable representations for disease classification in chest X-rays via an end-to-end framework. Our experiments demonstrate that these causal representations improve generalisability and robustness across multiple classification tasks when grouping is used to enforce invariance w.r.t race, sex, and imaging views.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20582v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rajat Rasal, Avinash Kori, Ben Glocker</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dense Video Captioning using Graph-based Sentence Summarization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20583</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20583v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recently, dense video captioning has made attractive progress in detecting and captioning all events in a long untrimmed video. Despite promising results were achieved, most existing methods do not sufficiently explore the scene evolution within an event temporal proposal for captioning, and therefore perform less satisfactorily when the scenes and objects change over a relatively long proposal. To address this problem, we propose a graph-based partition-and-summarization (GPaS) framework for dense video captioning within two stages. For the ``partition" stage, a whole event proposal is split into short video segments for captioning at a finer level. For the ``summarization" stage, the generated sentences carrying rich description information for each segment are summarized into one sentence to describe the whole event. We particularly focus on the ``summarization" stage, and propose a framework that effectively exploits the relationship between semantic words for summarization. We achieve this goal by treating semantic words as nodes in a graph and learning their interactions by coupling Graph Convolutional Network (GCN) and Long Short Term Memory (LSTM), with the aid of visual cues. Two schemes of GCN-LSTM Interaction (GLI) modules are proposed for seamless integration of GCN and LSTM. The effectiveness of our approach is demonstrated via an extensive comparison with the state-of-the-arts methods on the two benchmarks ActivityNet Captions dataset and YouCook II dataset.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20583v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhiwang Zhang, Dong Xu, Wanli Ouyang, Luping Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning-Based Distance Estimation for 360{\deg} Single-Sensor Setups</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20586</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20586v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Accurate distance estimation is a fundamental challenge in robotic perception, particularly in omnidirectional imaging, where traditional geometric methods struggle with lens distortions and environmental variability. In this work, we propose a neural network-based approach for monocular distance estimation using a single 360{\deg} fisheye lens camera. Unlike classical trigonometric techniques that rely on precise lens calibration, our method directly learns and infers the distance of objects from raw omnidirectional inputs, offering greater robustness and adaptability across diverse conditions. We evaluate our approach on three 360{\deg} datasets (LOAF, ULM360, and a newly captured dataset Boat360), each representing distinct environmental and sensor setups. Our experimental results demonstrate that the proposed learning-based model outperforms traditional geometry-based methods and other learning baselines in both accuracy and robustness. These findings highlight the potential of deep learning for real-time omnidirectional distance estimation, making our approach particularly well-suited for low-cost applications in robotics, autonomous navigation, and surveillance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20586v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yitong Quan, Benjamin Kiefer, Martin Messmer, Andreas Zell</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TRIM: A Self-Supervised Video Summarization Framework Maximizing Temporal Relative Information and Representativeness</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20588</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20588v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The increasing ubiquity of video content and the corresponding demand for efficient access to meaningful information have elevated video summarization and video highlights as a vital research area. However, many state-of-the-art methods depend heavily either on supervised annotations or on attention-based models, which are computationally expensive and brittle in the face of distribution shifts that hinder cross-domain applicability across datasets. We introduce a pioneering self-supervised video summarization model that captures both spatial and temporal dependencies without the overhead of attention, RNNs, or transformers. Our framework integrates a novel set of Markov process-driven loss metrics and a two-stage self supervised learning paradigm that ensures both performance and efficiency. Our approach achieves state-of-the-art performance on the SUMME and TVSUM datasets, outperforming all existing unsupervised methods. It also rivals the best supervised models, demonstrating the potential for efficient, annotation-free architectures. This paves the way for more generalizable video summarization techniques and challenges the prevailing reliance on complex architectures.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20588v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Pritam Mishra, Coloma Ballester, Dimosthenis Karatzas</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WonderFree: Enhancing Novel View Quality and Cross-View Consistency for 3D Scene Exploration</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20590</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20590v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Interactive 3D scene generation from a single image has gained significant attention due to its potential to create immersive virtual worlds. However, a key challenge in current 3D generation methods is the limited explorability, which cannot render high-quality images during larger maneuvers beyond the original viewpoint, particularly when attempting to move forward into unseen areas. To address this challenge, we propose WonderFree, the first model that enables users to interactively generate 3D worlds with the freedom to explore from arbitrary angles and directions. Specifically, we decouple this challenge into two key subproblems: novel view quality, which addresses visual artifacts and floating issues in novel views, and cross-view consistency, which ensures spatial consistency across different viewpoints. To enhance rendering quality in novel views, we introduce WorldRestorer, a data-driven video restoration model designed to eliminate floaters and artifacts. In addition, a data collection pipeline is presented to automatically gather training data for WorldRestorer, ensuring it can handle scenes with varying styles needed for 3D scene generation. Furthermore, to improve cross-view consistency, we propose ConsistView, a multi-view joint restoration mechanism that simultaneously restores multiple perspectives while maintaining spatiotemporal coherence. Experimental results demonstrate that WonderFree not only enhances rendering quality across diverse viewpoints but also significantly improves global coherence and consistency. These improvements are confirmed by CLIP-based metrics and a user study showing a 77.20% preference for WonderFree over WonderWorld enabling a seamless and immersive 3D exploration experience. The code, model, and data will be publicly available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20590v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chaojun Ni, Jie Li, Haoyun Li, Hengyu Liu, Xiaofeng Wang, Zheng Zhu, Guosheng Zhao, Boyuan Wang, Chenxin Li, Guan Huang, Wenjun Mei</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SFNet: Fusion of Spatial and Frequency-Domain Features for Remote Sensing Image Forgery Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20599</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20599v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The rapid advancement of generative artificial intelligence is producing fake remote sensing imagery (RSI) that is increasingly difficult to detect, potentially leading to erroneous intelligence, fake news, and even conspiracy theories. Existing forgery detection methods typically rely on single visual features to capture predefined artifacts, such as spatial-domain cues to detect forged objects like roads or buildings in RSI, or frequency-domain features to identify artifacts from up-sampling operations in adversarial generative networks (GANs). However, the nature of artifacts can significantly differ depending on geographic terrain, land cover types, or specific features within the RSI. Moreover, these complex artifacts evolve as generative models become more sophisticated. In short, over-reliance on a single visual cue makes existing forgery detectors struggle to generalize across diverse remote sensing data. This paper proposed a novel forgery detection framework called SFNet, designed to identify fake images in diverse remote sensing data by leveraging spatial and frequency domain features. Specifically, to obtain rich and comprehensive visual information, SFNet employs two independent feature extractors to capture spatial and frequency domain features from input RSIs. To fully utilize the complementary domain features, the domain feature mapping module and the hybrid domain feature refinement module(CBAM attention) of SFNet are designed to successively align and fuse the multi-domain features while suppressing redundant information. Experiments on three datasets show that SFNet achieves an accuracy improvement of 4%-15.18% over the state-of-the-art RS forgery detection methods and exhibits robust generalization capabilities. The code is available at https://github.com/GeoX-Lab/RSTI/tree/main/SFNet.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20599v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ji Qi, Xinchang Zhang, Dingqi Ye, Yongjia Ruan, Xin Guo, Shaowen Wang, Haifeng Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video Perception Models for 3D Scene Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20601</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20601v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Traditionally, 3D scene synthesis requires expert knowledge and significant manual effort. Automating this process could greatly benefit fields such as architectural design, robotics simulation, virtual reality, and gaming. Recent approaches to 3D scene synthesis often rely on the commonsense reasoning of large language models (LLMs) or strong visual priors of modern image generation models. However, current LLMs demonstrate limited 3D spatial reasoning ability, which restricts their ability to generate realistic and coherent 3D scenes. Meanwhile, image generation-based methods often suffer from constraints in viewpoint selection and multi-view inconsistencies. In this work, we present Video Perception models for 3D Scene synthesis (VIPScene), a novel framework that exploits the encoded commonsense knowledge of the 3D physical world in video generation models to ensure coherent scene layouts and consistent object placements across views. VIPScene accepts both text and image prompts and seamlessly integrates video generation, feedforward 3D reconstruction, and open-vocabulary perception models to semantically and geometrically analyze each object in a scene. This enables flexible scene synthesis with high realism and structural consistency. For more precise analysis, we further introduce First-Person View Score (FPVScore) for coherence and plausibility evaluation, utilizing continuous first-person perspective to capitalize on the reasoning ability of multimodal large language models. Extensive experiments show that VIPScene significantly outperforms existing methods and generalizes well across diverse scenarios. The code will be released.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20601v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rui Huang, Guangyao Zhai, Zuria Bauer, Marc Pollefeys, Federico Tombari, Leonidas Guibas, Gao Huang, Francis Engelmann</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shape2Animal: Creative Animal Generation from Natural Silhouettes</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20616</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20616v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Humans possess a unique ability to perceive meaningful patterns in ambiguous stimuli, a cognitive phenomenon known as pareidolia. This paper introduces Shape2Animal framework to mimics this imaginative capacity by reinterpreting natural object silhouettes, such as clouds, stones, or flames, as plausible animal forms. Our automated framework first performs open-vocabulary segmentation to extract object silhouette and interprets semantically appropriate animal concepts using vision-language models. It then synthesizes an animal image that conforms to the input shape, leveraging text-to-image diffusion model and seamlessly blends it into the original scene to generate visually coherent and spatially consistent compositions. We evaluated Shape2Animal on a diverse set of real-world inputs, demonstrating its robustness and creative potential. Our Shape2Animal can offer new opportunities for visual storytelling, educational content, digital art, and interactive media design. Our project page is here: https://shape2image.github.io</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20616v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Quoc-Duy Tran, Anh-Tuan Vo, Dinh-Khoi Vo, Tam V. Nguyen, Minh-Triet Tran, Trung-Nghia Le</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joint attitude estimation and 3D neural reconstruction of non-cooperative space objects</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20638</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20638v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Obtaining a better knowledge of the current state and behavior of objects orbiting Earth has proven to be essential for a range of applications such as active debris removal, in-orbit maintenance, or anomaly detection. 3D models represent a valuable source of information in the field of Space Situational Awareness (SSA). In this work, we leveraged Neural Radiance Fields (NeRF) to perform 3D reconstruction of non-cooperative space objects from simulated images. This scenario is challenging for NeRF models due to unusual camera characteristics and environmental conditions : mono-chromatic images, unknown object orientation, limited viewing angles, absence of diffuse lighting etc. In this work we focus primarly on the joint optimization of camera poses alongside the NeRF. Our experimental results show that the most accurate 3D reconstruction is achieved when training with successive images one-by-one. We estimate camera poses by optimizing an uniform rotation and use regularization to prevent successive poses from being too far apart.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20638v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Cl\'ement Forray, Pauline Delporte, Nicolas Delaygue, Florence Genin, Dawa Derksen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disentangled representations of microscopy images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20649</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20649v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Microscopy image analysis is fundamental for different applications, from diagnosis to synthetic engineering and environmental monitoring. Modern acquisition systems have granted the possibility to acquire an escalating amount of images, requiring a consequent development of a large collection of deep learning-based automatic image analysis methods. Although deep neural networks have demonstrated great performance in this field, interpretability, an essential requirement for microscopy image analysis, remains an open challenge.
  This work proposes a Disentangled Representation Learning (DRL) methodology to enhance model interpretability for microscopy image classification. Exploiting benchmark datasets from three different microscopic image domains (plankton, yeast vacuoles, and human cells), we show how a DRL framework, based on transferring a representation learnt from synthetic data, can provide a good trade-off between accuracy and interpretability in this domain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20649v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jacopo Dapueto, Vito Paolo Pastore, Nicoletta Noceti, Francesca Odone</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MMSearch-R1: Incentivizing LMMs to Search</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20670</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20670v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Robust deployment of large multimodal models (LMMs) in real-world scenarios requires access to external knowledge sources, given the complexity and dynamic nature of real-world information. Existing approaches such as retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) and prompt engineered search agents rely on rigid pipelines, often leading to inefficient or excessive search behaviors. We present MMSearch-R1, the first end-to-end reinforcement learning framework that enables LMMs to perform on-demand, multi-turn search in real-world Internet environments. Our framework integrates both image and text search tools, allowing the model to reason about when and how to invoke them guided by an outcome-based reward with a search penalty. To support training, We collect a multimodal search VQA dataset through a semi-automated pipeline that covers diverse visual and textual knowledge needs and curate a search-balanced subset with both search-required and search-free samples, which proves essential for shaping efficient and on-demand search behavior. Extensive experiments on knowledge-intensive and info-seeking VQA tasks show that our model not only outperforms RAG-based baselines of the same model size, but also matches the performance of a larger RAG-based model while reducing search calls by over 30%. We further analyze key empirical findings to offer actionable insights for advancing research in multimodal search.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20670v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jinming Wu, Zihao Deng, Wei Li, Yiding Liu, Bo You, Bo Li, Zejun Ma, Ziwei Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IPFormer: Visual 3D Panoptic Scene Completion with Context-Adaptive Instance Proposals</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20671</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20671v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Semantic Scene Completion (SSC) has emerged as a pivotal approach for jointly learning scene geometry and semantics, enabling downstream applications such as navigation in mobile robotics. The recent generalization to Panoptic Scene Completion (PSC) advances the SSC domain by integrating instance-level information, thereby enhancing object-level sensitivity in scene understanding. While PSC was introduced using LiDAR modality, methods based on camera images remain largely unexplored. Moreover, recent Transformer-based SSC approaches utilize a fixed set of learned queries to reconstruct objects within the scene volume. Although these queries are typically updated with image context during training, they remain static at test time, limiting their ability to dynamically adapt specifically to the observed scene. To overcome these limitations, we propose IPFormer, the first approach that leverages context-adaptive instance proposals at train and test time to address vision-based 3D Panoptic Scene Completion. Specifically, IPFormer adaptively initializes these queries as panoptic instance proposals derived from image context and further refines them through attention-based encoding and decoding to reason about semantic instance-voxel relationships. Experimental results show that our approach surpasses state-of-the-art methods in overall panoptic metrics PQ$^\dagger$ and PQ-All, matches performance in individual metrics, and achieves a runtime reduction exceeding 14$\times$. Furthermore, our ablation studies reveal that dynamically deriving instance proposals from image context, as opposed to random initialization, leads to a 3.62% increase in PQ-All and a remarkable average improvement of 18.65% in combined Thing-metrics. These results highlight our introduction of context-adaptive instance proposals as a pioneering effort in addressing vision-based 3D Panoptic Scene Completion.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20671v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Markus Gross, Aya Fahmy, Danit Niwattananan, Dominik Muhle, Rui Song, Daniel Cremers, Henri Mee{\ss}</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Multi-Modal Spatial Risk Framework for EV Charging Infrastructure Using Remote Sensing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.19860</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.19860v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Electric vehicle (EV) charging infrastructure is increasingly critical to sustainable transport systems, yet its resilience under environmental and infrastructural stress remains underexplored. In this paper, we introduce RSERI-EV, a spatially explicit and multi-modal risk assessment framework that combines remote sensing data, open infrastructure datasets, and spatial graph analytics to evaluate the vulnerability of EV charging stations. RSERI-EV integrates diverse data layers, including flood risk maps, land surface temperature (LST) extremes, vegetation indices (NDVI), land use/land cover (LULC), proximity to electrical substations, and road accessibility to generate a composite Resilience Score. We apply this framework to the country of Wales EV charger dataset to demonstrate its feasibility. A spatial $k$-nearest neighbours ($k$NN) graph is constructed over the charging network to enable neighbourhood-based comparisons and graph-aware diagnostics. Our prototype highlights the value of multi-source data fusion and interpretable spatial reasoning in supporting climate-resilient, infrastructure-aware EV deployment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.19860v1</guid>
      <category>eess.SP</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Oktay Karaku\c{s}, Padraig Corcoran</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Any-Order GPT as Masked Diffusion Model: Decoupling Formulation and Architecture</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.19935</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.19935v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) predominantly use autoregressive (AR) approaches, but masked diffusion models (MDMs) are emerging as viable alternatives. A key challenge in comparing AR and MDM paradigms is their typical architectural difference: AR models are often decoder-only, while MDMs have largely been encoder-only. This practice of changing both the modeling paradigm and architecture simultaneously makes direct comparisons unfair, as it's hard to distinguish whether observed differences stem from the paradigm itself or the architectural shift. This research evaluates MDMs within a decoder-only framework to: (1) equitably compare MDM (as Any-Order AR, or AO-AR) and standard AR paradigms. Our investigation suggests that the standard AO-AR objective, which averages over all token permutations, may benefit from refinement, as many permutations appear less informative compared to the language's inherent left-to-right structure. (2) Investigate architectural influences (decoder-only vs. encoder-only) within MDMs. We demonstrate that while encoder-only MDMs model a simpler conditional probability space, decoder-only MDMs can achieve dramatic generation speedups ($\sim25\times$) and comparable perplexity with temperature annealing despite modeling a vastly larger space, highlighting key trade-offs. This work thus decouples core paradigm differences from architectural influences, offering insights for future model design. Code is available at https://github.com/scxue/AO-GPT-MDM.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.19935v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shuchen Xue, Tianyu Xie, Tianyang Hu, Zijin Feng, Jiacheng Sun, Kenji Kawaguchi, Zhenguo Li, Zhi-Ming Ma</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VoxelOpt: Voxel-Adaptive Message Passing for Discrete Optimization in Deformable Abdominal CT Registration</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.19975</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.19975v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recent developments in neural networks have improved deformable image registration (DIR) by amortizing iterative optimization, enabling fast and accurate DIR results. However, learning-based methods often face challenges with limited training data, large deformations, and tend to underperform compared to iterative approaches when label supervision is unavailable. While iterative methods can achieve higher accuracy in such scenarios, they are considerably slower than learning-based methods. To address these limitations, we propose VoxelOpt, a discrete optimization-based DIR framework that combines the strengths of learning-based and iterative methods to achieve a better balance between registration accuracy and runtime. VoxelOpt uses displacement entropy from local cost volumes to measure displacement signal strength at each voxel, which differs from earlier approaches in three key aspects. First, it introduces voxel-wise adaptive message passing, where voxels with lower entropy receives less influence from their neighbors. Second, it employs a multi-level image pyramid with 27-neighbor cost volumes at each level, avoiding exponential complexity growth. Third, it replaces hand-crafted features or contrastive learning with a pretrained foundational segmentation model for feature extraction. In abdominal CT registration, these changes allow VoxelOpt to outperform leading iterative in both efficiency and accuracy, while matching state-of-the-art learning-based methods trained with label supervision. The source code will be available at https://github.com/tinymilky/VoxelOpt</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.19975v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.SP</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hang Zhang, Yuxi Zhang, Jiazheng Wang, Xiang Chen, Renjiu Hu, Xin Tian, Gaolei Li, Min Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Consensus-Driven Uncertainty for Robotic Grasping based on RGB Perception</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20045</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20045v2 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Deep object pose estimators are notoriously overconfident. A grasping agent that both estimates the 6-DoF pose of a target object and predicts the uncertainty of its own estimate could avoid task failure by choosing not to act under high uncertainty. Even though object pose estimation improves and uncertainty quantification research continues to make strides, few studies have connected them to the downstream task of robotic grasping. We propose a method for training lightweight, deep networks to predict whether a grasp guided by an image-based pose estimate will succeed before that grasp is attempted. We generate training data for our networks via object pose estimation on real images and simulated grasping. We also find that, despite high object variability in grasping trials, networks benefit from training on all objects jointly, suggesting that a diverse variety of objects can nevertheless contribute to the same goal.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20045v2</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Eric C. Joyce, Qianwen Zhao, Nathaniel Burgdorfer, Long Wang, Philippos Mordohai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MIRAGE: A Benchmark for Multimodal Information-Seeking and Reasoning in Agricultural Expert-Guided Conversations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20100</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20100v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We introduce MIRAGE, a new benchmark for multimodal expert-level reasoning and decision-making in consultative interaction settings. Designed for the agriculture domain, MIRAGE captures the full complexity of expert consultations by combining natural user queries, expert-authored responses, and image-based context, offering a high-fidelity benchmark for evaluating models on grounded reasoning, clarification strategies, and long-form generation in a real-world, knowledge-intensive domain. Grounded in over 35,000 real user-expert interactions and curated through a carefully designed multi-step pipeline, MIRAGE spans diverse crop health, pest diagnosis, and crop management scenarios. The benchmark includes more than 7,000 unique biological entities, covering plant species, pests, and diseases, making it one of the most taxonomically diverse benchmarks available for vision-language models, grounded in the real world. Unlike existing benchmarks that rely on well-specified user inputs and closed-set taxonomies, MIRAGE features underspecified, context-rich scenarios with open-world settings, requiring models to infer latent knowledge gaps, handle rare entities, and either proactively guide the interaction or respond. Project Page: https://mirage-benchmark.github.io</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20100v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Vardhan Dongre, Chi Gui, Shubham Garg, Hooshang Nayyeri, Gokhan Tur, Dilek Hakkani-T\"ur, Vikram S. Adve</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MS-IQA: A Multi-Scale Feature Fusion Network for PET/CT Image Quality Assessment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20200</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20200v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Positron Emission Tomography / Computed Tomography (PET/CT) plays a critical role in medical imaging, combining functional and anatomical information to aid in accurate diagnosis. However, image quality degradation due to noise, compression and other factors could potentially lead to diagnostic uncertainty and increase the risk of misdiagnosis. When evaluating the quality of a PET/CT image, both low-level features like distortions and high-level features like organ anatomical structures affect the diagnostic value of the image. However, existing medical image quality assessment (IQA) methods are unable to account for both feature types simultaneously. In this work, we propose MS-IQA, a novel multi-scale feature fusion network for PET/CT IQA, which utilizes multi-scale features from various intermediate layers of ResNet and Swin Transformer, enhancing its ability of perceiving both local and global information. In addition, a multi-scale feature fusion module is also introduced to effectively combine high-level and low-level information through a dynamically weighted channel attention mechanism. Finally, to fill the blank of PET/CT IQA dataset, we construct PET-CT-IQA-DS, a dataset containing 2,700 varying-quality PET/CT images with quality scores assigned by radiologists. Experiments on our dataset and the publicly available LDCTIQAC2023 dataset demonstrate that our proposed model has achieved superior performance against existing state-of-the-art methods in various IQA metrics. This work provides an accurate and efficient IQA method for PET/CT. Our code and dataset are available at https://github.com/MS-IQA/MS-IQA/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20200v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Siqiao Li, Chen Hui, Wei Zhang, Rui Liang, Chenyue Song, Feng Jiang, Haiqi Zhu, Zhixuan Li, Hong Huang, Xiang Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FedBKD: Distilled Federated Learning to Embrace Gerneralization and Personalization on Non-IID Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20245</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20245v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Federated learning (FL) is a decentralized collaborative machine learning (ML) technique. It provides a solution to the issues of isolated data islands and data privacy leakage in industrial ML practices. One major challenge in FL is handling the non-identical and independent distributed (non-IID) data. Current solutions either focus on constructing an all-powerful global model, or customizing personalized local models. Few of them can provide both a well-generalized global model and well-performed local models at the same time. Additionally, many FL solutions to the non-IID problem are benefited from introducing public datasets. However, this will also increase the risk of data leakage. To tackle the problems, we propose a novel data-free distillation framework, Federated Bidirectional Knowledge Distillation (FedBKD). Specifically, we train Generative Adversarial Networks (GAN) for synthetic data. During the GAN training, local models serve as discriminators and their parameters are frozen. The synthetic data is then used for bidirectional distillation between global and local models to achieve knowledge interactions so that performances for both sides are improved. We conduct extensive experiments on 4 benchmarks under different non-IID settings. The results show that FedBKD achieves SOTA performances in every case.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20245v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yushan Zhao, Jinyuan He, Donglai Chen, Weijie Luo, Chong Xie, Ri Zhang, Yonghong Chen, Yan Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>X-SiT: Inherently Interpretable Surface Vision Transformers for Dementia Diagnosis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20267</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20267v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Interpretable models are crucial for supporting clinical decision-making, driving advances in their development and application for medical images. However, the nature of 3D volumetric data makes it inherently challenging to visualize and interpret intricate and complex structures like the cerebral cortex. Cortical surface renderings, on the other hand, provide a more accessible and understandable 3D representation of brain anatomy, facilitating visualization and interactive exploration. Motivated by this advantage and the widespread use of surface data for studying neurological disorders, we present the eXplainable Surface Vision Transformer (X-SiT). This is the first inherently interpretable neural network that offers human-understandable predictions based on interpretable cortical features. As part of X-SiT, we introduce a prototypical surface patch decoder for classifying surface patch embeddings, incorporating case-based reasoning with spatially corresponding cortical prototypes. The results demonstrate state-of-the-art performance in detecting Alzheimer's disease and frontotemporal dementia while additionally providing informative prototypes that align with known disease patterns and reveal classification errors.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20267v1</guid>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fabian Bongratz, Tom Nuno Wolf, Jaume Gual Ramon, Christian Wachinger</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opportunistic Osteoporosis Diagnosis via Texture-Preserving Self-Supervision, Mixture of Experts and Multi-Task Integration</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20282</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20282v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Osteoporosis, characterized by reduced bone mineral density (BMD) and compromised bone microstructure, increases fracture risk in aging populations. While dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry (DXA) is the clinical standard for BMD assessment, its limited accessibility hinders diagnosis in resource-limited regions. Opportunistic computed tomography (CT) analysis has emerged as a promising alternative for osteoporosis diagnosis using existing imaging data. Current approaches, however, face three limitations: (1) underutilization of unlabeled vertebral data, (2) systematic bias from device-specific DXA discrepancies, and (3) insufficient integration of clinical knowledge such as spatial BMD distribution patterns. To address these, we propose a unified deep learning framework with three innovations. First, a self-supervised learning method using radiomic representations to leverage unlabeled CT data and preserve bone texture. Second, a Mixture of Experts (MoE) architecture with learned gating mechanisms to enhance cross-device adaptability. Third, a multi-task learning framework integrating osteoporosis diagnosis, BMD regression, and vertebra location prediction. Validated across three clinical sites and an external hospital, our approach demonstrates superior generalizability and accuracy over existing methods for opportunistic osteoporosis screening and diagnosis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20282v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiaxing Huang, Heng Guo, Le Lu, Fan Yang, Minfeng Xu, Ge Yang, Wei Luo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FundaQ-8: A Clinically-Inspired Scoring Framework for Automated Fundus Image Quality Assessment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20303</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20303v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Automated fundus image quality assessment (FIQA) remains a challenge due to variations in image acquisition and subjective expert evaluations. We introduce FundaQ-8, a novel expert-validated framework for systematically assessing fundus image quality using eight critical parameters, including field coverage, anatomical visibility, illumination, and image artifacts. Using FundaQ-8 as a structured scoring reference, we develop a ResNet18-based regression model to predict continuous quality scores in the 0 to 1 range. The model is trained on 1800 fundus images from real-world clinical sources and Kaggle datasets, using transfer learning, mean squared error optimization, and standardized preprocessing. Validation against the EyeQ dataset and statistical analyses confirm the framework's reliability and clinical interpretability. Incorporating FundaQ-8 into deep learning models for diabetic retinopathy grading also improves diagnostic robustness, highlighting the value of quality-aware training in real-world screening applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20303v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lee Qi Zun, Oscar Wong Jin Hao, Nor Anita Binti Che Omar, Zalifa Zakiah Binti Asnir, Mohamad Sabri bin Sinal Zainal, Goh Man Fye</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Moderately Input-Sensitive Functions: A Case Study in QR Code Decoding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20305</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20305v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The hardness of learning a function that attains a target task relates to its input-sensitivity. For example, image classification tasks are input-insensitive as minor corruptions should not affect the classification results, whereas arithmetic and symbolic computation, which have been recently attracting interest, are highly input-sensitive as each input variable connects to the computation results. This study presents the first learning-based Quick Response (QR) code decoding and investigates learning functions of medium sensitivity. Our experiments reveal that Transformers can successfully decode QR codes, even beyond the theoretical error-correction limit, by learning the structure of embedded texts. They generalize from English-rich training data to other languages and even random strings. Moreover, we observe that the Transformer-based QR decoder focuses on data bits while ignoring error-correction bits, suggesting a decoding mechanism distinct from standard QR code readers.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20305v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kazuki Yoda, Kazuhiko Kawamoto, Hiroshi Kera</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EAGLE: An Efficient Global Attention Lesion Segmentation Model for Hepatic Echinococcosis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20333</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20333v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Hepatic echinococcosis (HE) is a widespread parasitic disease in underdeveloped pastoral areas with limited medical resources. While CNN-based and Transformer-based models have been widely applied to medical image segmentation, CNNs lack global context modeling due to local receptive fields, and Transformers, though capable of capturing long-range dependencies, are computationally expensive. Recently, state space models (SSMs), such as Mamba, have gained attention for their ability to model long sequences with linear complexity. In this paper, we propose EAGLE, a U-shaped network composed of a Progressive Visual State Space (PVSS) encoder and a Hybrid Visual State Space (HVSS) decoder that work collaboratively to achieve efficient and accurate segmentation of hepatic echinococcosis (HE) lesions. The proposed Convolutional Vision State Space Block (CVSSB) module is designed to fuse local and global features, while the Haar Wavelet Transformation Block (HWTB) module compresses spatial information into the channel dimension to enable lossless downsampling. Due to the lack of publicly available HE datasets, we collected CT slices from 260 patients at a local hospital. Experimental results show that EAGLE achieves state-of-the-art performance with a Dice Similarity Coefficient (DSC) of 89.76%, surpassing MSVM-UNet by 1.61%.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20333v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiayan Chen, Kai Li, Yulu Zhao, Jianqiang Huang, Zhan Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Practical insights on the effect of different encodings, ans\"atze and measurements in quantum and hybrid convolutional neural networks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20355</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20355v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This study investigates the design choices of parameterized quantum circuits (PQCs) within quantum and hybrid convolutional neural network (HQNN and QCNN) architectures, applied to the task of satellite image classification using the EuroSAT dataset. We systematically evaluate the performance implications of data encoding techniques, variational ans\"atze, and measurement in approx. 500 distinct model configurations. Our analysis reveals a clear hierarchy of influence on model performance. For hybrid architectures, which were benchmarked against their direct classical equivalents (e.g. the same architecture with the PQCs removed), the data encoding strategy is the dominant factor, with validation accuracy varying over 30% for distinct embeddings. In contrast, the selection of variational ans\"atze and measurement basis had a comparatively marginal effect, with validation accuracy variations remaining below 5%. For purely quantum models, restricted to amplitude encoding, performance was most dependent on the measurement protocol and the data-to-amplitude mapping. The measurement strategy varied the validation accuracy by up to 30% and the encoding mapping by around 8 percentage points.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20355v1</guid>
      <category>quant-ph</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jes\'us Lozano-Cruz, Albert Nieto-Morales, Oriol Ball\'o-Gimbernat, Adan Garriga, Ant\'on Rodr\'iguez-Otero, Alejandro Borrallo-Rentero</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DreamAnywhere: Object-Centric Panoramic 3D Scene Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20367</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20367v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recent advances in text-to-3D scene generation have demonstrated significant potential to transform content creation across multiple industries. Although the research community has made impressive progress in addressing the challenges of this complex task, existing methods often generate environments that are only front-facing, lack visual fidelity, exhibit limited scene understanding, and are typically fine-tuned for either indoor or outdoor settings. In this work, we address these issues and propose DreamAnywhere, a modular system for the fast generation and prototyping of 3D scenes. Our system synthesizes a 360{\deg} panoramic image from text, decomposes it into background and objects, constructs a complete 3D representation through hybrid inpainting, and lifts object masks to detailed 3D objects that are placed in the virtual environment. DreamAnywhere supports immersive navigation and intuitive object-level editing, making it ideal for scene exploration, visual mock-ups, and rapid prototyping -- all with minimal manual modeling. These features make our system particularly suitable for low-budget movie production, enabling quick iteration on scene layout and visual tone without the overhead of traditional 3D workflows. Our modular pipeline is highly customizable as it allows components to be replaced independently. Compared to current state-of-the-art text and image-based 3D scene generation approaches, DreamAnywhere shows significant improvements in coherence in novel view synthesis and achieves competitive image quality, demonstrating its effectiveness across diverse and challenging scenarios. A comprehensive user study demonstrates a clear preference for our method over existing approaches, validating both its technical robustness and practical usefulness.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20367v1</guid>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Edoardo Alberto Dominici, Jozef Hladky, Floor Verhoeven, Lukas Radl, Thomas Deixelberger, Stefan Ainetter, Philipp Drescher, Stefan Hauswiesner, Arno Coomans, Giacomo Nazzaro, Konstantinos Vardis, Markus Steinberger</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fusing Radiomic Features with Deep Representations for Gestational Age Estimation in Fetal Ultrasound Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20407</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20407v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Accurate gestational age (GA) estimation, ideally through fetal ultrasound measurement, is a crucial aspect of providing excellent antenatal care. However, deriving GA from manual fetal biometric measurements depends on the operator and is time-consuming. Hence, automatic computer-assisted methods are demanded in clinical practice. In this paper, we present a novel feature fusion framework to estimate GA using fetal ultrasound images without any measurement information. We adopt a deep learning model to extract deep representations from ultrasound images. We extract radiomic features to reveal patterns and characteristics of fetal brain growth. To harness the interpretability of radiomics in medical imaging analysis, we estimate GA by fusing radiomic features and deep representations. Our framework estimates GA with a mean absolute error of 8.0 days across three trimesters, outperforming current machine learning-based methods at these gestational ages. Experimental results demonstrate the robustness of our framework across different populations in diverse geographical regions. Our code is publicly available on \href{https://github.com/13204942/RadiomicsImageFusion_FetalUS}{GitHub}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20407v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fangyijie Wang, Yuan Liang, Sourav Bhattacharjee, Abey Campbell, Kathleen M. Curran, Gu\'enol\'e Silvestre</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Agentic System for Rare Disease Diagnosis with Traceable Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20430</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20430v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Rare diseases collectively affect over 300 million individuals worldwide, yet timely and accurate diagnosis remains a pervasive challenge. This is largely due to their clinical heterogeneity, low individual prevalence, and the limited familiarity most clinicians have with rare conditions. Here, we introduce DeepRare, the first rare disease diagnosis agentic system powered by a large language model (LLM), capable of processing heterogeneous clinical inputs. The system generates ranked diagnostic hypotheses for rare diseases, each accompanied by a transparent chain of reasoning that links intermediate analytic steps to verifiable medical evidence.
  DeepRare comprises three key components: a central host with a long-term memory module; specialized agent servers responsible for domain-specific analytical tasks integrating over 40 specialized tools and web-scale, up-to-date medical knowledge sources, ensuring access to the most current clinical information. This modular and scalable design enables complex diagnostic reasoning while maintaining traceability and adaptability. We evaluate DeepRare on eight datasets. The system demonstrates exceptional diagnostic performance among 2,919 diseases, achieving 100% accuracy for 1013 diseases. In HPO-based evaluations, DeepRare significantly outperforms other 15 methods, like traditional bioinformatics diagnostic tools, LLMs, and other agentic systems, achieving an average Recall@1 score of 57.18% and surpassing the second-best method (Reasoning LLM) by a substantial margin of 23.79 percentage points. For multi-modal input scenarios, DeepRare achieves 70.60% at Recall@1 compared to Exomiser's 53.20% in 109 cases. Manual verification of reasoning chains by clinical experts achieves 95.40% agreements. Furthermore, the DeepRare system has been implemented as a user-friendly web application http://raredx.cn/doctor.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20430v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weike Zhao, Chaoyi Wu, Yanjie Fan, Xiaoman Zhang, Pengcheng Qiu, Yuze Sun, Xiao Zhou, Yanfeng Wang, Ya Zhang, Yongguo Yu, Kun Sun, Weidi Xie</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HRIBench: Benchmarking Vision-Language Models for Real-Time Human Perception in Human-Robot Interaction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20566</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20566v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Real-time human perception is crucial for effective human-robot interaction (HRI). Large vision-language models (VLMs) offer promising generalizable perceptual capabilities but often suffer from high latency, which negatively impacts user experience and limits VLM applicability in real-world scenarios. To systematically study VLM capabilities in human perception for HRI and performance-latency trade-offs, we introduce HRIBench, a visual question-answering (VQA) benchmark designed to evaluate VLMs across a diverse set of human perceptual tasks critical for HRI. HRIBench covers five key domains: (1) non-verbal cue understanding, (2) verbal instruction understanding, (3) human-robot object relationship understanding, (4) social navigation, and (5) person identification. To construct HRIBench, we collected data from real-world HRI environments to curate questions for non-verbal cue understanding, and leveraged publicly available datasets for the remaining four domains. We curated 200 VQA questions for each domain, resulting in a total of 1000 questions for HRIBench. We then conducted a comprehensive evaluation of both state-of-the-art closed-source and open-source VLMs (N=11) on HRIBench. Our results show that, despite their generalizability, current VLMs still struggle with core perceptual capabilities essential for HRI. Moreover, none of the models within our experiments demonstrated a satisfactory performance-latency trade-off suitable for real-time deployment, underscoring the need for future research on developing smaller, low-latency VLMs with improved human perception capabilities. HRIBench and our results can be found in this Github repository: https://github.com/interaction-lab/HRIBench.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20566v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhonghao Shi, Enyu Zhao, Nathaniel Dennler, Jingzhen Wang, Xinyang Xu, Kaleen Shrestha, Mengxue Fu, Daniel Seita, Maja Matari\'c</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weighted Mean Frequencies: a handcraft Fourier feature for 4D Flow MRI segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20614</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20614v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In recent decades, the use of 4D Flow MRI images has enabled the quantification of velocity fields within a volume of interest and along the cardiac cycle. However, the lack of resolution and the presence of noise in these biomarkers are significant issues. As indicated by recent studies, it appears that biomarkers such as wall shear stress are particularly impacted by the poor resolution of vessel segmentation. The Phase Contrast Magnetic Resonance Angiography (PC-MRA) is the state-of-the-art method to facilitate segmentation. The objective of this work is to introduce a new handcraft feature that provides a novel visualisation of 4D Flow MRI images, which is useful in the segmentation task. This feature, termed Weighted Mean Frequencies (WMF), is capable of revealing the region in three dimensions where a voxel has been passed by pulsatile flow. Indeed, this feature is representative of the hull of all pulsatile velocity voxels. The value of the feature under discussion is illustrated by two experiments. The experiments involved segmenting 4D Flow MRI images using optimal thresholding and deep learning methods. The results obtained demonstrate a substantial enhancement in terms of IoU and Dice, with a respective increase of 0.12 and 0.13 in comparison with the PC-MRA feature, as evidenced by the deep learning task. This feature has the potential to yield valuable insights that could inform future segmentation processes in other vascular regions, such as the heart or the brain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20614v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Simon Perrin, S\'ebastien Levilly, Huajun Sun, Harold Mouch\`ere, Jean-Michel Serfaty</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EditP23: 3D Editing via Propagation of Image Prompts to Multi-View</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.20652</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.20652v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We present EditP23, a method for mask-free 3D editing that propagates 2D image edits to multi-view representations in a 3D-consistent manner. In contrast to traditional approaches that rely on text-based prompting or explicit spatial masks, EditP23 enables intuitive edits by conditioning on a pair of images: an original view and its user-edited counterpart. These image prompts are used to guide an edit-aware flow in the latent space of a pre-trained multi-view diffusion model, allowing the edit to be coherently propagated across views. Our method operates in a feed-forward manner, without optimization, and preserves the identity of the original object, in both structure and appearance. We demonstrate its effectiveness across a range of object categories and editing scenarios, achieving high fidelity to the source while requiring no manual masks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.20652v1</guid>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Roi Bar-On, Dana Cohen-Bar, Daniel Cohen-Or</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KD-DETR: Knowledge Distillation for Detection Transformer with Consistent Distillation Points Sampling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2211.08071</link>
      <description>arXiv:2211.08071v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: DETR is a novel end-to-end transformer architecture object detector, which significantly outperforms classic detectors when scaling up. In this paper, we focus on the compression of DETR with knowledge distillation. While knowledge distillation has been well-studied in classic detectors, there is a lack of researches on how to make it work effectively on DETR. We first provide experimental and theoretical analysis to point out that the main challenge in DETR distillation is the lack of consistent distillation points. Distillation points refer to the corresponding inputs of the predictions for student to mimic, which have different formulations in CNN detector and DETR, and reliable distillation requires sufficient distillation points which are consistent between teacher and student.
  Based on this observation, we propose the first general knowledge distillation paradigm for DETR (KD-DETR) with consistent distillation points sampling, for both homogeneous and heterogeneous distillation. Specifically, we decouple detection and distillation tasks by introducing a set of specialized object queries to construct distillation points for DETR. We further propose a general-to-specific distillation points sampling strategy to explore the extensibility of KD-DETR. Extensive experiments validate the effectiveness and generalization of KD-DETR. For both single-scale DAB-DETR and multis-scale Deformable DETR and DINO, KD-DETR boost the performance of student model with improvements of $2.6\%-5.2\%$. We further extend KD-DETR to heterogeneous distillation, and achieves $2.1\%$ improvement by distilling the knowledge from DINO to Faster R-CNN with ResNet-50, which is comparable with homogeneous distillation methods.The code is available at https://github.com/wennyuhey/KD-DETR.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2211.08071v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yu Wang, Xin Li, Shengzhao Weng, Gang Zhang, Haixiao Yue, Haocheng Feng, Junyu Han, Errui Ding</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low-light Pedestrian Detection in Visible and Infrared Image Feeds: Issues and Challenges</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.08557</link>
      <description>arXiv:2311.08557v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Pedestrian detection has become a cornerstone for several high-level tasks, including autonomous driving, intelligent transportation, and traffic surveillance. There are several works focussed on pedestrian detection using visible images, mainly in the daytime. However, this task is very intriguing when the environmental conditions change to poor lighting or nighttime. Recently, new ideas have been spurred to use alternative sources, such as Far InfraRed (FIR) temperature sensor feeds for detecting pedestrians in low-light conditions. This study reviews recent developments in low-light pedestrian detection approaches. It systematically categorizes and analyses various algorithms from region-based to non-region-based and graph-based learning methodologies by highlighting their methodologies, implementation issues, and challenges. It also outlines the key benchmark datasets that can be used for research and development of advanced pedestrian detection algorithms, particularly in low-light situations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2311.08557v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Thangarajah Akilan, Hrishikesh Vachhani</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MambaMorph: a Mamba-based Framework for Medical MR-CT Deformable Registration</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.13934</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.13934v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Capturing voxel-wise spatial correspondence across distinct modalities is crucial for medical image analysis. However, current registration approaches are not practical enough in terms of registration accuracy and clinical applicability. In this paper, we introduce MambaMorph, a novel multi-modality deformable registration framework. Specifically, MambaMorph utilizes a Mamba-based registration module and a fine-grained, yet simple, feature extractor for efficient long-range correspondence modeling and high-dimensional feature learning, respectively. Additionally, we develop a well-annotated brain MR-CT registration dataset, SR-Reg, to address the scarcity of data in multi-modality registration. To validate MambaMorph's multi-modality registration capabilities, we conduct quantitative experiments on both our SR-Reg dataset and a public T1-T2 dataset. The experimental results on both datasets demonstrate that MambaMorph significantly outperforms the current state-of-the-art learning-based registration methods in terms of registration accuracy. Further study underscores the efficiency of the Mamba-based registration module and the lightweight feature extractor, which achieve notable registration quality while maintaining reasonable computational costs and speeds. We believe that MambaMorph holds significant potential for practical applications in medical image registration. The code for MambaMorph is available at: https://github.com/Guo-Stone/MambaMorph.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.13934v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tao Guo, Yinuo Wang, Shihao Shu, Weimin Yuan, Diansheng Chen, Zhouping Tang, Cai Meng, Xiangzhi Bai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FluoroSAM: A Language-promptable Foundation Model for Flexible X-ray Image Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.08059</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.08059v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Language promptable X-ray image segmentation would enable greater flexibility for human-in-the-loop workflows in diagnostic and interventional precision medicine. Prior efforts have contributed task-specific models capable of solving problems within a narrow scope, but expanding to broader use requires additional data, annotations, and training time. Recently, language-aligned foundation models (LFMs) -- machine learning models trained on large amounts of highly variable image and text data thus enabling broad applicability -- have emerged as promising tools for automated image analysis. Existing foundation models for medical image analysis focus on scenarios and modalities where large, richly annotated datasets are available. However, the X-ray imaging modality features highly variable image appearance and applications, from diagnostic chest X-rays to interventional fluoroscopy, with varying availability of data. To pave the way toward an LFM for comprehensive and language-aligned analysis of arbitrary medical X-ray images, we introduce FluoroSAM, a language-promptable variant of the Segment Anything Model, trained from scratch on 3M synthetic X-ray images from a wide variety of human anatomies, imaging geometries, and viewing angles. These include pseudo-ground truth masks for 128 organ types and 464 tools with associated text descriptions. FluoroSAM is capable of segmenting myriad anatomical structures and tools based on natural language prompts, thanks to the novel incorporation of vector quantization (VQ) of text embeddings in the training process. We demonstrate FluoroSAM's performance quantitatively on real X-ray images and showcase on several applications how FluoroSAM is a key enabler for rich human-machine interaction in the X-ray image acquisition and analysis context. Code is available at https://github.com/arcadelab/fluorosam.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.08059v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Benjamin D. Killeen, Liam J. Wang, Blanca Inigo, Han Zhang, Mehran Armand, Russell H. Taylor, Greg Osgood, Mathias Unberath</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neural Graph Map: Dense Mapping with Efficient Loop Closure Integration</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.03633</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.03633v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Neural field-based SLAM methods typically employ a single, monolithic field as their scene representation. This prevents efficient incorporation of loop closure constraints and limits scalability. To address these shortcomings, we propose a novel RGB-D neural mapping framework in which the scene is represented by a collection of lightweight neural fields which are dynamically anchored to the pose graph of a sparse visual SLAM system. Our approach shows the ability to integrate large-scale loop closures, while requiring only minimal reintegration. Furthermore, we verify the scalability of our approach by demonstrating successful building-scale mapping taking multiple loop closures into account during the optimization, and show that our method outperforms existing state-of-the-art approaches on large scenes in terms of quality and runtime. Our code is available open-source at https://github.com/KTH-RPL/neural_graph_mapping.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.03633v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Leonard Bruns, Jun Zhang, Patric Jensfelt</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MagicPose4D: Crafting Articulated Models with Appearance and Motion Control</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.14017</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.14017v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: With the success of 2D and 3D visual generative models, there is growing interest in generating 4D content. Existing methods primarily rely on text prompts to produce 4D content, but they often fall short of accurately defining complex or rare motions. To address this limitation, we propose MagicPose4D, a novel framework for refined control over both appearance and motion in 4D generation. Unlike current 4D generation methods, MagicPose4D accepts monocular videos or mesh sequences as motion prompts, enabling precise and customizable motion control. MagicPose4D comprises two key modules: (i) Dual-Phase 4D Reconstruction Module, which operates in two phases. The first phase focuses on capturing the model's shape using accurate 2D supervision and less accurate but geometrically informative 3D pseudo-supervision without imposing skeleton constraints. The second phase extracts the 3D motion (skeleton poses) using more accurate pseudo-3D supervision, obtained in the first phase and introduces kinematic chain-based skeleton constraints to ensure physical plausibility. Additionally, we propose a Global-local Chamfer loss that aligns the overall distribution of predicted mesh vertices with the supervision while maintaining part-level alignment without extra annotations. (ii) Cross-category Motion Transfer Module, which leverages the extracted motion from the 4D reconstruction module and uses a kinematic-chain-based skeleton to achieve cross-category motion transfer. It ensures smooth transitions between frames through dynamic rigidity, facilitating robust generalization without additional training. Through extensive experiments, we demonstrate that MagicPose4D significantly improves the accuracy and consistency of 4D content generation, outperforming existing methods in various benchmarks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.14017v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>TMLR 2025</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Hao Zhang, Di Chang, Fang Li, Mohammad Soleymani, Narendra Ahuja</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GlyphPattern: An Abstract Pattern Recognition Benchmark for Vision-Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05894</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05894v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Vision-Language Models (VLMs) building upon the foundation of powerful large language models have made rapid progress in reasoning across visual and textual data. While VLMs perform well on vision tasks that they are trained on, our results highlight key challenges in abstract pattern recognition. We present GlyphPattern, a 954 item dataset that pairs 318 human-written descriptions of visual patterns from 40 writing systems with three visual presentation styles.
  GlyphPattern evaluates abstract pattern recognition in VLMs, requiring models to understand and judge natural language descriptions of visual patterns. GlyphPattern patterns are drawn from a large-scale cognitive science investigation of human writing systems; as a result, they are rich in spatial reference and compositionality. Our experiments show that GlyphPattern is challenging for state-of-the-art VLMs (GPT-4o achieves only 55% accuracy), with marginal gains from few-shot prompting. Our detailed error analysis reveals challenges at multiple levels, including visual processing, natural language understanding, and pattern generalization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05894v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Findings of the ACL 2025</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Zixuan Wu, Yoolim Kim, Carolyn Jane Anderson</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ReconX: Reconstruct Any Scene from Sparse Views with Video Diffusion Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.16767</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.16767v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Advancements in 3D scene reconstruction have transformed 2D images from the real world into 3D models, producing realistic 3D results from hundreds of input photos. Despite great success in dense-view reconstruction scenarios, rendering a detailed scene from insufficient captured views is still an ill-posed optimization problem, often resulting in artifacts and distortions in unseen areas. In this paper, we propose ReconX, a novel 3D scene reconstruction paradigm that reframes the ambiguous reconstruction challenge as a temporal generation task. The key insight is to unleash the strong generative prior of large pre-trained video diffusion models for sparse-view reconstruction. However, 3D view consistency struggles to be accurately preserved in directly generated video frames from pre-trained models. To address this, given limited input views, the proposed ReconX first constructs a global point cloud and encodes it into a contextual space as the 3D structure condition. Guided by the condition, the video diffusion model then synthesizes video frames that are both detail-preserved and exhibit a high degree of 3D consistency, ensuring the coherence of the scene from various perspectives. Finally, we recover the 3D scene from the generated video through a confidence-aware 3D Gaussian Splatting optimization scheme. Extensive experiments on various real-world datasets show the superiority of our ReconX over state-of-the-art methods in terms of quality and generalizability.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.16767v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fangfu Liu, Wenqiang Sun, Hanyang Wang, Yikai Wang, Haowen Sun, Junliang Ye, Jun Zhang, Yueqi Duan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toddlers' Active Gaze Behavior Supports Self-Supervised Object Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.01969</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.01969v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Toddlers learn to recognize objects from different viewpoints with almost no supervision. During this learning, they execute frequent eye and head movements that shape their visual experience. It is presently unclear if and how these behaviors contribute to toddlers' emerging object recognition abilities. To answer this question, we here combine head-mounted eye tracking during dyadic play with unsupervised machine learning. We approximate toddlers' central visual field experience by cropping image regions from a head-mounted camera centered on the current gaze location estimated via eye tracking. This visual stream feeds an unsupervised computational model of toddlers' learning, which constructs visual representations that slowly change over time. Our experiments demonstrate that toddlers' gaze strategy supports the learning of invariant object representations. Our analysis also shows that the limited size of the central visual field where acuity is high is crucial for this. Overall, our work reveals how toddlers' gaze behavior may support their development of view-invariant object recognition.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.01969v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhengyang Yu, Arthur Aubret, Marcel C. Raabe, Jane Yang, Chen Yu, Jochen Triesch</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USP-Gaussian: Unifying Spike-based Image Reconstruction, Pose Correction and Gaussian Splatting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.10504</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.10504v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Spike cameras, as an innovative neuromorphic camera that captures scenes with the 0-1 bit stream at 40 kHz, are increasingly employed for the 3D reconstruction task via Neural Radiance Fields (NeRF) or 3D Gaussian Splatting (3DGS). Previous spike-based 3D reconstruction approaches often employ a casecased pipeline: starting with high-quality image reconstruction from spike streams based on established spike-to-image reconstruction algorithms, then progressing to camera pose estimation and 3D reconstruction. However, this cascaded approach suffers from substantial cumulative errors, where quality limitations of initial image reconstructions negatively impact pose estimation, ultimately degrading the fidelity of the 3D reconstruction. To address these issues, we propose a synergistic optimization framework, \textbf{USP-Gaussian}, that unifies spike-based image reconstruction, pose correction, and Gaussian splatting into an end-to-end framework. Leveraging the multi-view consistency afforded by 3DGS and the motion capture capability of the spike camera, our framework enables a joint iterative optimization that seamlessly integrates information between the spike-to-image network and 3DGS. Experiments on synthetic datasets with accurate poses demonstrate that our method surpasses previous approaches by effectively eliminating cascading errors. Moreover, we integrate pose optimization to achieve robust 3D reconstruction in real-world scenarios with inaccurate initial poses, outperforming alternative methods by effectively reducing noise and preserving fine texture details. Our code, data and trained models will be available at https://github.com/chenkang455/USP-Gaussian.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.10504v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kang Chen, Jiyuan Zhang, Zecheng Hao, Yajing Zheng, Tiejun Huang, Zhaofei Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ULSR-GS: Ultra Large-scale Surface Reconstruction Gaussian Splatting with Multi-View Geometric Consistency</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.01402</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.01402v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: While Gaussian Splatting (GS) demonstrates efficient and high-quality scene rendering and small area surface extraction ability, it falls short in handling large-scale aerial image surface extraction tasks. To overcome this, we present ULSR-GS, a framework dedicated to high-fidelity surface extraction in ultra-large-scale scenes, addressing the limitations of existing GS-based mesh extraction methods. Specifically, we propose a point-to-photo partitioning approach combined with a multi-view optimal view matching principle to select the best training images for each sub-region. Additionally, during training, ULSR-GS employs a densification strategy based on multi-view geometric consistency to enhance surface extraction details. Experimental results demonstrate that ULSR-GS outperforms other state-of-the-art GS-based works on large-scale aerial photogrammetry benchmark datasets, significantly improving surface extraction accuracy in complex urban environments. Project page: https://ulsrgs.github.io.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.01402v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhuoxiao Li, Shanliang Yao, Taoyu Wu, Yong Yue, Wufan Zhao, Rongjun Qin, Angel F. Garcia-Fernandez, Andrew Levers, Xiaohui Zhu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Adaptive Lighting via Channel-Aware Guidance</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.01493</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.01493v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Learning lighting adaptation is a crucial step in achieving good visual perception and supporting downstream vision tasks. Current research often addresses individual light-related challenges, such as high dynamic range imaging and exposure correction, in isolation. However, we identify shared fundamental properties across these tasks: i) different color channels have different light properties, and ii) the channel differences reflected in the spatial and frequency domains are different. Leveraging these insights, we introduce the channel-aware Learning Adaptive Lighting Network (LALNet), a multi-task framework designed to handle multiple light-related tasks efficiently. Specifically, LALNet incorporates color-separated features that highlight the unique light properties of each color channel, integrated with traditional color-mixed features by Light Guided Attention (LGA). The LGA utilizes color-separated features to guide color-mixed features focusing on channel differences and ensuring visual consistency across all channels. Additionally, LALNet employs dual domain channel modulation for generating color-separated features and a mixed channel modulation and light state space module for producing color-mixed features. Extensive experiments on four representative light-related tasks demonstrate that LALNet significantly outperforms state-of-the-art methods on benchmark tests and requires fewer computational resources. We provide an anonymous online demo at https://xxxxxx2025.github.io/LALNet/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.01493v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qirui Yang, Peng-Tao Jiang, Hao Zhang, Jinwei Chen, Bo Li, Huanjing Yue, Jingyu Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World-Consistent Data Generation for Vision-and-Language Navigation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.06413</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.06413v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Vision-and-Language Navigation (VLN) is a challenging task that requires an agent to navigate through photorealistic environments following natural-language instructions. One main obstacle existing in VLN is data scarcity, leading to poor generalization performance over unseen environments. Though data argumentation is a promising way for scaling up the dataset, how to generate VLN data both diverse and world-consistent remains problematic. To cope with this issue, we propose the world-consistent data generation (WCGEN), an efficacious data-augmentation framework satisfying both diversity and world-consistency, aimed at enhancing the generalization of agents to novel environments. Roughly, our framework consists of two stages, the trajectory stage which leverages a point-cloud based technique to ensure spatial coherency among viewpoints, and the viewpoint stage which adopts a novel angle synthesis method to guarantee spatial and wraparound consistency within the entire observation. By accurately predicting viewpoint changes with 3D knowledge, our approach maintains the world-consistency during the generation procedure. Experiments on a wide range of datasets verify the effectiveness of our method, demonstrating that our data augmentation strategy enables agents to achieve new state-of-the-art results on all navigation tasks, and is capable of enhancing the VLN agents' generalization ability to unseen environments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.06413v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yu Zhong, Rui Zhang, Zihao Zhang, Shuo Wang, Chuan Fang, Xishan Zhang, Jiaming Guo, Shaohui Peng, Di Huang, Yanyang Yan, Xing Hu, Qi Guo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matching-Free Depth Recovery from Structured Light</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.07113</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.07113v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We introduce a novel approach for depth estimation using images obtained from monocular structured light systems. In contrast to many existing methods that depend on image matching, our technique employs a density voxel grid to represent scene geometry. This grid is trained through self-supervised differentiable volume rendering. Our method leverages color fields derived from the projected patterns in structured light systems during the rendering process, facilitating the isolated optimization of the geometry field. This innovative approach leads to faster convergence and high-quality results. Additionally, we integrate normalized device coordinates (NDC), a distortion loss, and a distinctive surface-based color loss to enhance geometric fidelity. Experimental results demonstrate that our method outperforms current matching-based techniques in terms of geometric performance in few-shot scenarios, achieving an approximately 30% reduction in average estimated depth errors for both synthetic scenes and real-world captured scenes. Moreover, our approach allows for rapid training, being approximately three times faster than previous matching-free methods that utilize implicit representations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.07113v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhuohang Yu, Kai Wang, Kun Huang, Juyong Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring AI-based System Design for Pixel-level Protected Health Information Detection in Medical Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.09552</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.09552v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: De-identification of medical images is a critical step to ensure privacy during data sharing in research and clinical settings. The initial step in this process involves detecting Protected Health Information (PHI), which can be found in image metadata or imprinted within image pixels. Despite the importance of such systems, there has been limited evaluation of existing AI-based solutions, creating barriers to the development of reliable and robust tools. In this study, we present an AI-based pipeline for PHI detection, comprising three key modules: text detection, text extraction, and text analysis. We benchmark three models - YOLOv11, EasyOCR, and GPT-4o - across different setups corresponding to these modules, evaluating their performance on two different datasets encompassing multiple imaging modalities and PHI categories. Our findings indicate that the optimal setup involves utilizing dedicated vision and language models for each module, which achieves a commendable balance in performance, latency, and cost associated with the usage of Large Language Models (LLMs). Additionally, we show that the application of LLMs not only involves identifying PHI content but also enhances OCR tasks and facilitates an end-to-end PHI detection pipeline, showcasing promising outcomes through our analysis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.09552v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tuan Truong, Ivo M. Baltruschat, Mark Klemens, Grit Werner, Matthias Lenga</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VICCA: Visual Interpretation and Comprehension of Chest X-ray Anomalies in Generated Report Without Human Feedback</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.17726</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.17726v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: As artificial intelligence (AI) becomes increasingly central to healthcare, the demand for explainable and trustworthy models is paramount. Current report generation systems for chest X-rays (CXR) often lack mechanisms for validating outputs without expert oversight, raising concerns about reliability and interpretability. To address these challenges, we propose a novel multimodal framework designed to enhance the semantic alignment and localization accuracy of AI-generated medical reports. Our framework integrates two key modules: a Phrase Grounding Model, which identifies and localizes pathologies in CXR images based on textual prompts, and a Text-to-Image Diffusion Module, which generates synthetic CXR images from prompts while preserving anatomical fidelity. By comparing features between the original and generated images, we introduce a dual-scoring system: one score quantifies localization accuracy, while the other evaluates semantic consistency. This approach significantly outperforms existing methods, achieving state-of-the-art results in pathology localization and text-to-image alignment. The integration of phrase grounding with diffusion models, coupled with the dual-scoring evaluation system, provides a robust mechanism for validating report quality, paving the way for more trustworthy and transparent AI in medical imaging.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.17726v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1016/j.mlwa.2025.100684</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Machine Learning with Applications, Volume 21, 2025, 100684, ISSN 2666-8270</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Sayeh Gholipour Picha, Dawood Al Chanti, Alice Caplier</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MatSwap: Light-aware material transfers in images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.07784</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.07784v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We present MatSwap, a method to transfer materials to designated surfaces in an image photorealistically. Such a task is non-trivial due to the large entanglement of material appearance, geometry, and lighting in a photograph. In the literature, material editing methods typically rely on either cumbersome text engineering or extensive manual annotations requiring artist knowledge and 3D scene properties that are impractical to obtain. In contrast, we propose to directly learn the relationship between the input material -- as observed on a flat surface -- and its appearance within the scene, without the need for explicit UV mapping. To achieve this, we rely on a custom light- and geometry-aware diffusion model. We fine-tune a large-scale pre-trained text-to-image model for material transfer using our synthetic dataset, preserving its strong priors to ensure effective generalization to real images. As a result, our method seamlessly integrates a desired material into the target location in the photograph while retaining the identity of the scene. We evaluate our method on synthetic and real images and show that it compares favorably to recent work both qualitatively and quantitatively. We release our code and data on https://github.com/astra-vision/MatSwap</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.07784v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ivan Lopes, Valentin Deschaintre, Yannick Hold-Geoffroy, Raoul de Charette</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diffusion Models Through a Global Lens: Are They Culturally Inclusive?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.08914</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.08914v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Text-to-image diffusion models have recently enabled the creation of visually compelling, detailed images from textual prompts. However, their ability to accurately represent various cultural nuances remains an open question. In our work, we introduce CultDiff benchmark, evaluating state-of-the-art diffusion models whether they can generate culturally specific images spanning ten countries. We show that these models often fail to generate cultural artifacts in architecture, clothing, and food, especially for underrepresented country regions, by conducting a fine-grained analysis of different similarity aspects, revealing significant disparities in cultural relevance, description fidelity, and realism compared to real-world reference images. With the collected human evaluations, we develop a neural-based image-image similarity metric, namely, CultDiff-S, to predict human judgment on real and generated images with cultural artifacts. Our work highlights the need for more inclusive generative AI systems and equitable dataset representation over a wide range of cultures.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.08914v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zahra Bayramli, Ayhan Suleymanzade, Na Min An, Huzama Ahmad, Eunsu Kim, Junyeong Park, James Thorne, Alice Oh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Image Super-Resolution with Guarantees via Conformalized Generative Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09664</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09664v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The increasing use of generative ML foundation models for image restoration tasks such as super-resolution calls for robust and interpretable uncertainty quantification methods. We address this need by presenting a novel approach based on conformal prediction techniques to create a 'confidence mask' capable of reliably and intuitively communicating where the generated image can be trusted. Our method is adaptable to any black-box generative model, including those locked behind an opaque API, requires only easily attainable data for calibration, and is highly customizable via the choice of a local image similarity metric. We prove strong theoretical guarantees for our method that span fidelity error control (according to our local image similarity metric), reconstruction quality, and robustness in the face of data leakage. Finally, we empirically evaluate these results and establish our method's solid performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09664v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Eduardo Adame, Daniel Csillag, Guilherme Tegoni Goedert</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FGS-SLAM: Fourier-based Gaussian Splatting for Real-time SLAM with Sparse and Dense Map Fusion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.01109</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.01109v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: 3D gaussian splatting has advanced simultaneous localization and mapping (SLAM) technology by enabling real-time positioning and the construction of high-fidelity maps. However, the uncertainty in gaussian position and initialization parameters introduces challenges, often requiring extensive iterative convergence and resulting in redundant or insufficient gaussian representations. To address this, we introduce a novel adaptive densification method based on Fourier frequency domain analysis to establish gaussian priors for rapid convergence. Additionally, we propose constructing independent and unified sparse and dense maps, where a sparse map supports efficient tracking via Generalized Iterative Closest Point (GICP) and a dense map creates high-fidelity visual representations. This is the first SLAM system leveraging frequency domain analysis to achieve high-quality gaussian mapping in real-time. Experimental results demonstrate an average frame rate of 36 FPS on Replica and TUM RGB-D datasets, achieving competitive accuracy in both localization and mapping.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.01109v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yansong Xu, Junlin Li, Wei Zhang, Siyu Chen, Shengyong Zhang, Yuquan Leng, Weijia Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robust Multimodal Learning for Ophthalmic Disease Grading via Disentangled Representation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.05319</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.05319v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper discusses how ophthalmologists often rely on multimodal data to improve diagnostic accuracy. However, complete multimodal data is rare in real-world applications due to a lack of medical equipment and concerns about data privacy. Traditional deep learning methods typically address these issues by learning representations in latent space. However, the paper highlights two key limitations of these approaches: (i) Task-irrelevant redundant information (e.g., numerous slices) in complex modalities leads to significant redundancy in latent space representations. (ii) Overlapping multimodal representations make it difficult to extract unique features for each modality. To overcome these challenges, the authors propose the Essence-Point and Disentangle Representation Learning (EDRL) strategy, which integrates a self-distillation mechanism into an end-to-end framework to enhance feature selection and disentanglement for more robust multimodal learning. Specifically, the Essence-Point Representation Learning module selects discriminative features that improve disease grading performance. The Disentangled Representation Learning module separates multimodal data into modality-common and modality-unique representations, reducing feature entanglement and enhancing both robustness and interpretability in ophthalmic disease diagnosis. Experiments on multimodal ophthalmology datasets show that the proposed EDRL strategy significantly outperforms current state-of-the-art methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.05319v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xinkun Wang, Yifang Wang, Senwei Liang, Feilong Tang, Chengzhi Liu, Ming Hu, Chao Hu, Junjun He, Zongyuan Ge, Imran Razzak</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From $\mathcal{O}(n^{2})$ to $\mathcal{O}(n)$ Parameters: Quantum Self-Attention in Vision Transformers for Biomedical Image Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.07294</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.07294v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We demonstrate that quantum vision transformers (QViTs), vision transformers (ViTs) with self-attention (SA) mechanisms replaced by quantum self-attention (QSA) mechanisms, can match state-of-the-art (SOTA) biomedical image classifiers while using 99.99% fewer parameters. QSAs are produced by replacing linear SA layers with parameterised quantum neural networks (QNNs), producing a QSA mechanism and reducing parameter scaling from $\mathcal{O}(n^2)$ to $\mathcal{O}(n)$. On RetinaMNIST, our ultra parameter-efficient QViT outperforms 13/14 SOTA methods including CNNs and ViTs, achieving 56.5% accuracy, just 0.88% below the top MedMamba model while using 99.99% fewer parameters (1K vs 14.5M) and 89% fewer GFLOPs. We present the first investigation of knowledge distillation (KD) from classical to quantum vision transformers in biomedical image classification, showing that QViTs maintain comparable performance to classical ViTs across eight diverse datasets spanning multiple modalities, with improved QSA parameter-efficiency. Our higher-qubit architecture benefitted more from KD pre-training, suggesting a scaling relationship between QSA parameters and KD effectiveness. These findings establish QSA as a practical architectural choice toward parameter-efficient biomedical image analysis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.07294v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Thomas Boucher, John Whittle, Evangelos B. Mazomenos</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MaizeField3D: A Curated 3D Point Cloud and Procedural Model Dataset of Field-Grown Maize from a Diversity Panel</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.07813</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.07813v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The development of artificial intelligence (AI) and machine learning (ML) based tools for 3D phenotyping, especially for maize, has been limited due to the lack of large and diverse 3D datasets. 2D image datasets fail to capture essential structural details such as leaf architecture, plant volume, and spatial arrangements that 3D data provide. To address this limitation, we present MaizeField3D (https://baskargroup.github.io/MaizeField3D/), a curated dataset of 3D point clouds of field-grown maize plants from a diverse genetic panel, designed to be AI-ready for advancing agricultural research. Our dataset includes 1,045 high-quality point clouds of field-grown maize collected using a terrestrial laser scanner (TLS). Point clouds of 520 plants from this dataset were segmented and annotated using a graph-based segmentation method to isolate individual leaves and stalks, ensuring consistent labeling across all samples. This labeled data was then used for fitting procedural models that provide a structured parametric representation of the maize plants. The leaves of the maize plants in the procedural models are represented using Non-Uniform Rational B-Spline (NURBS) surfaces that were generated using a two-step optimization process combining gradient-free and gradient-based methods. We conducted rigorous manual quality control on all datasets, correcting errors in segmentation, ensuring accurate leaf ordering, and validating metadata annotations. The dataset also includes metadata detailing plant morphology and quality, alongside multi-resolution subsampled point cloud data (100k, 50k, 10k points), which can be readily used for different downstream computational tasks. MaizeField3D will serve as a comprehensive foundational dataset for AI-driven phenotyping, plant structural analysis, and 3D applications in agricultural research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.07813v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Elvis Kimara, Mozhgan Hadadi, Jackson Godbersen, Aditya Balu, Talukder Jubery, Yawei Li, Adarsh Krishnamurthy, Patrick S. Schnable, Baskar Ganapathysubramanian</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Siamese Network to Detect If Two Iris Images Are Monozygotic</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.09749</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.09749v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This study presents the first automated classifier designed to determine whether a pair of iris images originates from monozygotic individuals, addressing a previously untackled problem in biometric recognition. In Daugman-style iris recognition, the textures of the left and right irises of the same person are traditionally considered as being as different as the irises of two unrelated persons. However, previous research indicates that humans can detect that two iris images are from different eyes of the same person, or eyes of monozygotic twins, with an accuracy of about 80%. In this work, we employ a Siamese network architecture and contrastive learning to categorize a pair of iris images as coming from monozygotic or non-monozygotic irises. This could potentially be applied, for example, as a fast, noninvasive test to determine if twins are monozygotic or non-monozygotic. We construct a dataset comprising both synthetic monozygotic pairs (images of different irises of the same individual) and natural monozygotic pairs (images of different images from persons who are identical twins), in addition to non-monozygotic pairs from unrelated individuals, ensuring a comprehensive evaluation of the model's capabilities. To gain deeper insights into the learned representations, we train and analyze three variants of the model using (1) the original input images, (2) iris-only images (masking everything but the iris region), and (3) non-iris-only images (masking the iris region). This comparison reveals that both iris texture and surrounding ocular structure contain information useful for the model to classify the image pairs as monozygotic or non-monozygotic. Our approach achieves accuracy levels using the full iris image that exceed those previously reported for human classification of monozygotic iris pairs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.09749v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yongle Yuan, Kevin W. Bowyer</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LPOSS: Label Propagation Over Patches and Pixels for Open-vocabulary Semantic Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.19777</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.19777v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We propose a training-free method for open-vocabulary semantic segmentation using Vision-and-Language Models (VLMs). Our approach enhances the initial per-patch predictions of VLMs through label propagation, which jointly optimizes predictions by incorporating patch-to-patch relationships. Since VLMs are primarily optimized for cross-modal alignment and not for intra-modal similarity, we use a Vision Model (VM) that is observed to better capture these relationships. We address resolution limitations inherent to patch-based encoders by applying label propagation at the pixel level as a refinement step, significantly improving segmentation accuracy near class boundaries. Our method, called LPOSS+, performs inference over the entire image, avoiding window-based processing and thereby capturing contextual interactions across the full image. LPOSS+ achieves state-of-the-art performance among training-free methods, across a diverse set of datasets. Code: https://github.com/vladan-stojnic/LPOSS</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.19777v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Vladan Stojni\'c, Yannis Kalantidis, Ji\v{r}\'i Matas, Giorgos Tolias</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shape and Texture Recognition in Large Vision-Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.23062</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.23062v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Shapes and textures are the basic building blocks of visual perception. The ability to identify shapes regardless of orientation, texture, or context, and to recognize textures and materials independently of their associated objects, is essential for a general visual understanding of the world. This work introduces the Large Shape and Textures dataset (LAS&amp;T), a giant collection of highly diverse shapes and textures, created by unsupervised extraction of patterns from natural images. This dataset is used to benchmark how effectively leading Large Vision-Language Models (LVLMs) understand shapes, textures, and materials in 2D and 3D scenes. For shape recognition, we test the models' ability to match images of identical shapes that differ in orientation, texture, color, or environment. Our results show that the shape recognition capabilities of the LVLMs remain significantly below human performance. LVLMs rely predominantly on high-level and semantic features and struggle with abstract shapes lacking clear class associations. For texture and material recognition, we evaluated the models' ability to identify images with identical textures and materials across different objects and environments. Interestingly, leading LVLMs approach human-level performance in recognizing materials in 3D scenes, yet substantially underperform humans when identifying simpler more abstract 2D textures. These results are consistent across a wide range of leading VLMs (GPT/Gemini/LLama/Qwen) and foundation vision models (DINO/CLIP), exposing major deficiencies in the ability of leading models to understand fundamental visual concepts. In contrast, simple nets trained directly for these tasks achieve high accuracy. The LAS&amp;T dataset, featuring over 600,000 images for 2D/3D shape, texture, and material recognition and retrieval, is publicly available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.23062v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sagi Eppel, Mor Bismut, Alona Faktor-Strugatski</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Skin Color Measurement from Dermatoscopic Images: An Evaluation on a Synthetic Dataset</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.04494</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.04494v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper presents a comprehensive evaluation of skin color measurement methods from dermatoscopic images using a synthetic dataset (S-SYNTH) with controlled ground-truth melanin content, lesion shapes, hair models, and 18 distinct lighting conditions. This allows for rigorous assessment of the robustness and invariance to lighting conditions. We assess four classes of image colorimetry approaches: segmentation-based, patch-based, color quantization, and neural networks. We use these methods to estimate the Individual Typology Angle (ITA) and Fitzpatrick types from dermatoscopic images. Our results show that segmentation-based and color quantization methods yield robust, lighting-invariant estimates, whereas patch-based approaches exhibit significant lighting-dependent biases that require calibration. Furthermore, neural network models, particularly when combined with heavy blurring to reduce overfitting, can provide light-invariant Fitzpatrick predictions, although their generalization to real-world images remains unverified. We conclude with practical recommendations for designing fair and reliable skin color estimation methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.04494v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Marin Ben\v{c}evi\'c, Robert \v{S}ojo, Irena Gali\'c</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time-Aware Auto White Balance in Mobile Photography</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.05623</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.05623v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Cameras rely on auto white balance (AWB) to correct undesirable color casts caused by scene illumination and the camera's spectral sensitivity. This is typically achieved using an illuminant estimator that determines the global color cast solely from the color information in the camera's raw sensor image. Mobile devices provide valuable additional metadata-such as capture timestamp and geolocation-that offers strong contextual clues to help narrow down the possible illumination solutions. This paper proposes a lightweight illuminant estimation method that incorporates such contextual metadata, along with additional capture information and image colors, into a compact model (~5K parameters), achieving promising results, matching or surpassing larger models. To validate our method, we introduce a dataset of 3,224 smartphone images with contextual metadata collected at various times of day and under diverse lighting conditions. The dataset includes ground-truth illuminant colors, determined using a color chart, and user-preferred illuminants validated through a user study, providing a comprehensive benchmark for AWB evaluation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.05623v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mahmoud Afifi, Luxi Zhao, Abhijith Punnappurath, Mohammed A. Abdelsalam, Ran Zhang, Michael S. Brown</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WoundAmbit: Bridging State-of-the-Art Semantic Segmentation and Real-World Wound Care</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.06185</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.06185v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Chronic wounds affect a large population, particularly the elderly and diabetic patients, who often exhibit limited mobility and co-existing health conditions. Automated wound monitoring via mobile image capture can reduce in-person physician visits by enabling remote tracking of wound size. Semantic segmentation is key to this process, yet wound segmentation remains underrepresented in medical imaging research. To address this, we benchmark state-of-the-art deep learning models from general-purpose vision, medical imaging, and top methods from public wound challenges. For a fair comparison, we standardize training, data augmentation, and evaluation, conducting cross-validation to minimize partitioning bias. We also assess real-world deployment aspects, including generalization to an out-of-distribution wound dataset, computational efficiency, and interpretability. Additionally, we propose a reference object-based approach to convert AI-generated masks into clinically relevant wound size estimates and evaluate this, along with mask quality, for the five best architectures based on physician assessments. Overall, the transformer-based TransNeXt showed the highest levels of generalizability. Despite variations in inference times, all models processed at least one image per second on the CPU, which is deemed adequate for the intended application. Interpretability analysis typically revealed prominent activations in wound regions, emphasizing focus on clinically relevant features. Expert evaluation showed high mask approval for all analyzed models, with VWFormer and ConvNeXtS backbone performing the best. Size retrieval accuracy was similar across models, and predictions closely matched expert annotations. Finally, we demonstrate how our AI-driven wound size estimation framework, WoundAmbit, is integrated into a custom telehealth system.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.06185v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Vanessa Borst, Timo Dittus, Tassilo Dege, Astrid Schmieder, Samuel Kounev</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TT3D: Table Tennis 3D Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.10035</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.10035v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Sports analysis requires processing large amounts of data, which is time-consuming and costly. Advancements in neural networks have significantly alleviated this burden, enabling highly accurate ball tracking in sports broadcasts. However, relying solely on 2D ball tracking is limiting, as it depends on the camera's viewpoint and falls short of supporting comprehensive game analysis. To address this limitation, we propose a novel approach for reconstructing precise 3D ball trajectories from online table tennis match recordings. Our method leverages the underlying physics of the ball's motion to identify the bounce state that minimizes the reprojection error of the ball's flying trajectory, hence ensuring an accurate and reliable 3D reconstruction. A key advantage of our approach is its ability to infer ball spin without relying on human pose estimation or racket tracking, which are often unreliable or unavailable in broadcast footage. We developed an automated camera calibration method capable of reliably tracking camera movements. Additionally, we adapted an existing 3D pose estimation model, which lacks depth motion capture, to accurately track player movements. Together, these contributions enable the full 3D reconstruction of a table tennis rally.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.10035v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Thomas Gossard, Andreas Ziegler, Andreas Zell</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visual and Textual Prompts in VLLMs for Enhancing Emotion Recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.17224</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.17224v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Vision Large Language Models (VLLMs) exhibit promising potential for multi-modal understanding, yet their application to video-based emotion recognition remains limited by insufficient spatial and contextual awareness. Traditional approaches, which prioritize isolated facial features, often neglect critical non-verbal cues such as body language, environmental context, and social interactions, leading to reduced robustness in real-world scenarios. To address this gap, we propose Set-of-Vision-Text Prompting (SoVTP), a novel framework that enhances zero-shot emotion recognition by integrating spatial annotations (e.g., bounding boxes, facial landmarks), physiological signals (facial action units), and contextual cues (body posture, scene dynamics, others' emotions) into a unified prompting strategy. SoVTP preserves holistic scene information while enabling fine-grained analysis of facial muscle movements and interpersonal dynamics. Extensive experiments show that SoVTP achieves substantial improvements over existing visual prompting methods, demonstrating its effectiveness in enhancing VLLMs' video emotion recognition capabilities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.17224v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhifeng Wang, Qixuan Zhang, Peter Zhang, Wenjia Niu, Kaihao Zhang, Ramesh Sankaranarayana, Sabrina Caldwell, Tom Gedeon</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VideoRFT: Incentivizing Video Reasoning Capability in MLLMs via Reinforced Fine-Tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.12434</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.12434v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Reinforcement fine-tuning (RFT) has shown great promise in achieving humanlevel reasoning capabilities of Large Language Models (LLMs), and has recently been extended to MLLMs. Nevertheless, reasoning about videos, which is a fundamental aspect of human intelligence, remains a persistent challenge due to the complex logic, temporal and causal structures inherent in video data. To fill this gap, we propose VIDEORFT, a novel approach that extends the RFT paradigm to cultivate human-like video reasoning capabilities in MLLMs. VIDEORFT follows the standard two-stage scheme in RFT: supervised fine-tuning (SFT) with chain-of-thought (CoT) annotations, followed by reinforcement learning (RL) to improve generalization. A central challenge to achieve this in the video domain lies in the scarcity of large-scale, high-quality video CoT datasets. We address this by building a fully automatic CoT curation pipeline. First, we devise a cognitioninspired prompting strategy to elicit a reasoning LLM to generate preliminary CoTs based solely on rich, structured, and literal representations of video content. Subsequently, these CoTs are revised by a visual-language model conditioned on the actual video, ensuring visual consistency and reducing visual hallucinations. This pipeline results in two new datasets - VideoRFT-CoT-102K for SFT and VideoRFT-RL-310K for RL. To further strengthen the RL phase, we introduce a novel semantic-consistency reward that explicitly promotes the alignment between textual reasoning and visual evidence. This reward encourages the model to produce coherent, context-aware reasoning outputs grounded in visual input. Extensive experiments show that VIDEORFT achieves state-of-the-art performance on six video reasoning benchmarks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.12434v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qi Wang, Yanrui Yu, Ye Yuan, Rui Mao, Tianfei Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It's not you, it's me -- Global urban visual perception varies across demographics and personalities</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.12758</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.12758v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Understanding people's preferences and needs is crucial for urban planning decisions, yet current approaches often combine them from multi-cultural and multi-city populations, obscuring important demographic differences and risking amplifying biases. We conducted a large-scale urban visual perception survey of streetscapes worldwide using street view imagery, examining how demographics -- including gender, age, income, education, race and ethnicity, and, for the first time, personality traits -- shape perceptions among 1,000 participants, with balanced demographics, from five countries and 45 nationalities. This dataset, introduced as Street Perception Evaluation Considering Socioeconomics (SPECS), exhibits statistically significant differences in perception scores in six traditionally used indicators (safe, lively, wealthy, beautiful, boring, and depressing) and four new ones we propose (live nearby, walk, cycle, green) among demographics and personalities. We revealed that location-based sentiments are carried over in people's preferences when comparing urban streetscapes with other cities. Further, we compared the perception scores based on where participants and streetscapes are from. We found that an off-the-shelf machine learning model trained on an existing global perception dataset tends to overestimate positive indicators and underestimate negative ones compared to human responses, suggesting that targeted intervention should consider locals' perception. Our study aspires to rectify the myopic treatment of street perception, which rarely considers demographics or personality traits.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.12758v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Matias Quintana, Youlong Gu, Xiucheng Liang, Yujun Hou, Koichi Ito, Yihan Zhu, Mahmoud Abdelrahman, Filip Biljecki</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temporal Differential Fields for 4D Motion Modeling via Image-to-Video Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.17333</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.17333v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Temporal modeling on regular respiration-induced motions is crucial to image-guided clinical applications. Existing methods cannot simulate temporal motions unless high-dose imaging scans including starting and ending frames exist simultaneously. However, in the preoperative data acquisition stage, the slight movement of patients may result in dynamic backgrounds between the first and last frames in a respiratory period. This additional deviation can hardly be removed by image registration, thus affecting the temporal modeling. To address that limitation, we pioneeringly simulate the regular motion process via the image-to-video (I2V) synthesis framework, which animates with the first frame to forecast future frames of a given length. Besides, to promote the temporal consistency of animated videos, we devise the Temporal Differential Diffusion Model to generate temporal differential fields, which measure the relative differential representations between adjacent frames. The prompt attention layer is devised for fine-grained differential fields, and the field augmented layer is adopted to better interact these fields with the I2V framework, promoting more accurate temporal variation of synthesized videos. Extensive results on ACDC cardiac and 4D Lung datasets reveal that our approach simulates 4D videos along the intrinsic motion trajectory, rivaling other competitive methods on perceptual similarity and temporal consistency. Codes will be available soon.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.17333v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xin You, Minghui Zhang, Hanxiao Zhang, Jie Yang, Nassir Navab</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ZigzagPointMamba: Spatial-Semantic Mamba for Point Cloud Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.21381</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.21381v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: State Space models (SSMs) such as PointMamba enable efficient feature extraction for point cloud self-supervised learning with linear complexity, outperforming Transformers in computational efficiency. However, existing PointMamba-based methods depend on complex token ordering and random masking, which disrupt spatial continuity and local semantic correlations. We propose ZigzagPointMamba to tackle these challenges. The core of our approach is a simple zigzag scan path that globally sequences point cloud tokens, enhancing spatial continuity by preserving the proximity of spatially adjacent point tokens. Nevertheless, random masking undermines local semantic modeling in self-supervised learning. To address this, we introduce a Semantic-Siamese Masking Strategy (SMS), which masks semantically similar tokens to facilitate reconstruction by integrating local features of original and similar tokens. This overcomes the dependence on isolated local features and enables robust global semantic modeling. Our pre-trained ZigzagPointMamba weights significantly improve downstream tasks, achieving a 1.59% mIoU gain on ShapeNetPart for part segmentation, a 0.4% higher accuracy on ModelNet40 for classification, and 0.19%, 1.22%, and 0.72% higher accuracies respectively for the classification tasks on the OBJ-BG, OBJ-ONLY, and PB-T50-RS subsets of ScanObjectNN.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.21381v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Linshuang Diao, Dayong Ren, Sensen Song, Yurong Qian</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PanoWan: Lifting Diffusion Video Generation Models to 360{\deg} with Latitude/Longitude-aware Mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.22016</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.22016v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Panoramic video generation enables immersive 360{\deg} content creation, valuable in applications that demand scene-consistent world exploration. However, existing panoramic video generation models struggle to leverage pre-trained generative priors from conventional text-to-video models for high-quality and diverse panoramic videos generation, due to limited dataset scale and the gap in spatial feature representations. In this paper, we introduce PanoWan to effectively lift pre-trained text-to-video models to the panoramic domain, equipped with minimal modules. PanoWan employs latitude-aware sampling to avoid latitudinal distortion, while its rotated semantic denoising and padded pixel-wise decoding ensure seamless transitions at longitude boundaries. To provide sufficient panoramic videos for learning these lifted representations, we contribute PanoVid, a high-quality panoramic video dataset with captions and diverse scenarios. Consequently, PanoWan achieves state-of-the-art performance in panoramic video generation and demonstrates robustness for zero-shot downstream tasks. Our project page is available at https://panowan.variantconst.com.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.22016v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yifei Xia, Shuchen Weng, Siqi Yang, Jingqi Liu, Chengxuan Zhu, Minggui Teng, Zijian Jia, Han Jiang, Boxin Shi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ViStoryBench: Comprehensive Benchmark Suite for Story Visualization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.24862</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.24862v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Story visualization, which aims to generate a sequence of visually coherent images aligning with a given narrative and reference images, has seen significant progress with recent advancements in generative models. To further enhance the performance of story visualization frameworks in real-world scenarios, we introduce a comprehensive evaluation benchmark, ViStoryBench. We collect a diverse dataset encompassing various story types and artistic styles, ensuring models are evaluated across multiple dimensions such as different plots (e.g., comedy, horror) and visual aesthetics (e.g., anime, 3D renderings). ViStoryBench is carefully curated to balance narrative structures and visual elements, featuring stories with single and multiple protagonists to test models' ability to maintain character consistency. Additionally, it includes complex plots and intricate world-building to challenge models in generating accurate visuals. To ensure comprehensive comparisons, our benchmark incorporates a wide range of evaluation metrics assessing critical aspects. This structured and multifaceted framework enables researchers to thoroughly identify both the strengths and weaknesses of different models, fostering targeted improvements.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.24862v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Cailin Zhuang, Ailin Huang, Wei Cheng, Jingwei Wu, Yaoqi Hu, Jiaqi Liao, Zhewei Huang, Hongyuan Wang, Xinyao Liao, Weiwei Cai, Hengyuan Xu, Xuanyang Zhang, Xianfang Zeng, Gang Yu, Chi Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TIIF-Bench: How Does Your T2I Model Follow Your Instructions?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.02161</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.02161v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The rapid advancements of Text-to-Image (T2I) models have ushered in a new phase of AI-generated content, marked by their growing ability to interpret and follow user instructions. However, existing T2I model evaluation benchmarks fall short in limited prompt diversity and complexity, as well as coarse evaluation metrics, making it difficult to evaluate the fine-grained alignment performance between textual instructions and generated images. In this paper, we present TIIF-Bench (Text-to-Image Instruction Following Benchmark), aiming to systematically assess T2I models' ability in interpreting and following intricate textual instructions. TIIF-Bench comprises a set of 5000 prompts organized along multiple dimensions, which are categorized into three levels of difficulties and complexities. To rigorously evaluate model robustness to varying prompt lengths, we provide a short and a long version for each prompt with identical core semantics. Two critical attributes, i.e., text rendering and style control, are introduced to evaluate the precision of text synthesis and the aesthetic coherence of T2I models. In addition, we collect 100 high-quality designer level prompts that encompass various scenarios to comprehensively assess model performance. Leveraging the world knowledge encoded in large vision language models, we propose a novel computable framework to discern subtle variations in T2I model outputs. Through meticulous benchmarking of mainstream T2I models on TIIF-Bench, we analyze the pros and cons of current T2I models and reveal the limitations of current T2I benchmarks. Project Page: https://a113n-w3i.github.io/TIIF_Bench/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.02161v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xinyu Wei, Jinrui Zhang, Zeqing Wang, Hongyang Wei, Zhen Guo, Lei Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dark Channel-Assisted Depth-from-Defocus from a Single Image</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.06643</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.06643v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We estimate scene depth from a single defocus-blurred image using the dark channel as a complementary cue, leveraging its ability to capture local statistics and scene structure. Traditional depth-from-defocus (DFD) methods use multiple images with varying apertures or focus. Single-image DFD is underexplored due to its inherent challenges. Few attempts have focused on depth-from-defocus (DFD) from a single defocused image because the problem is underconstrained. Our method uses the relationship between local defocus blur and contrast variations as depth cues to improve scene structure estimation. The pipeline is trained end-to-end with adversarial learning. Experiments on real data demonstrate that incorporating the dark channel prior into single-image DFD provides meaningful depth estimation, validating our approach.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.06643v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Moushumi Medhi, Rajiv Ranjan Sahay</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>C3S3: Complementary Competition and Contrastive Selection for Semi-Supervised Medical Image Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.07368</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.07368v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: For the immanent challenge of insufficiently annotated samples in the medical field, semi-supervised medical image segmentation (SSMIS) offers a promising solution. Despite achieving impressive results in delineating primary target areas, most current methodologies struggle to precisely capture the subtle details of boundaries. This deficiency often leads to significant diagnostic inaccuracies. To tackle this issue, we introduce C3S3, a novel semi-supervised segmentation model that synergistically integrates complementary competition and contrastive selection. This design significantly sharpens boundary delineation and enhances overall precision. Specifically, we develop an Outcome-Driven Contrastive Learning module dedicated to refining boundary localization. Additionally, we incorporate a Dynamic Complementary Competition module that leverages two high-performing sub-networks to generate pseudo-labels, thereby further improving segmentation quality. The proposed C3S3 undergoes rigorous validation on two publicly accessible datasets, encompassing the practices of both MRI and CT scans. The results demonstrate that our method achieves superior performance compared to previous cutting-edge competitors. Especially, on the 95HD and ASD metrics, our approach achieves a notable improvement of at least 6%, highlighting the significant advancements. The code is available at https://github.com/Y-TARL/C3S3.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.07368v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiaying He, Yitong Lin, Jiahe Chen, Honghui Xu, Jianwei Zheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cross-Frame Representation Alignment for Fine-Tuning Video Diffusion Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09229</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.09229v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Fine-tuning Video Diffusion Models (VDMs) at the user level to generate videos that reflect specific attributes of training data presents notable challenges, yet remains underexplored despite its practical importance. Meanwhile, recent work such as Representation Alignment (REPA) has shown promise in improving the convergence and quality of DiT-based image diffusion models by aligning, or assimilating, its internal hidden states with external pretrained visual features, suggesting its potential for VDM fine-tuning. In this work, we first propose a straightforward adaptation of REPA for VDMs and empirically show that, while effective for convergence, it is suboptimal in preserving semantic consistency across frames. To address this limitation, we introduce Cross-frame Representation Alignment (CREPA), a novel regularization technique that aligns hidden states of a frame with external features from neighboring frames. Empirical evaluations on large-scale VDMs, including CogVideoX-5B and Hunyuan Video, demonstrate that CREPA improves both visual fidelity and cross-frame semantic coherence when fine-tuned with parameter-efficient methods such as LoRA. We further validate CREPA across diverse datasets with varying attributes, confirming its broad applicability.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.09229v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sungwon Hwang, Hyojin Jang, Kinam Kim, Minho Park, Jaegul Choo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fine-Grained Perturbation Guidance via Attention Head Selection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.10978</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.10978v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent guidance methods in diffusion models steer reverse sampling by perturbing the model to construct an implicit weak model and guide generation away from it. Among these approaches, attention perturbation has demonstrated strong empirical performance in unconditional scenarios where classifier-free guidance is not applicable. However, existing attention perturbation methods lack principled approaches for determining where perturbations should be applied, particularly in Diffusion Transformer (DiT) architectures where quality-relevant computations are distributed across layers. In this paper, we investigate the granularity of attention perturbations, ranging from the layer level down to individual attention heads, and discover that specific heads govern distinct visual concepts such as structure, style, and texture quality. Building on this insight, we propose "HeadHunter", a systematic framework for iteratively selecting attention heads that align with user-centric objectives, enabling fine-grained control over generation quality and visual attributes. In addition, we introduce SoftPAG, which linearly interpolates each selected head's attention map toward an identity matrix, providing a continuous knob to tune perturbation strength and suppress artifacts. Our approach not only mitigates the oversmoothing issues of existing layer-level perturbation but also enables targeted manipulation of specific visual styles through compositional head selection. We validate our method on modern large-scale DiT-based text-to-image models including Stable Diffusion 3 and FLUX.1, demonstrating superior performance in both general quality enhancement and style-specific guidance. Our work provides the first head-level analysis of attention perturbation in diffusion models, uncovering interpretable specialization within attention layers and enabling practical design of effective perturbation strategies.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.10978v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Donghoon Ahn, Jiwon Kang, Sanghyun Lee, Minjae Kim, Jaewon Min, Wooseok Jang, Saungwu Lee, Sayak Paul, Susung Hong, Seungryong Kim</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CLAIM: Clinically-Guided LGE Augmentation for Realistic and Diverse Myocardial Scar Synthesis and Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.15549</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.15549v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Deep learning-based myocardial scar segmentation from late gadolinium enhancement (LGE) cardiac MRI has shown great potential for accurate and timely diagnosis and treatment planning for structural cardiac diseases. However, the limited availability and variability of LGE images with high-quality scar labels restrict the development of robust segmentation models. To address this, we introduce CLAIM: \textbf{C}linically-Guided \textbf{L}GE \textbf{A}ugmentation for Real\textbf{i}stic and Diverse \textbf{M}yocardial Scar Synthesis and Segmentation framework, a framework for anatomically grounded scar generation and segmentation. At its core is the SMILE module (Scar Mask generation guided by cLinical knowledgE), which conditions a diffusion-based generator on the clinically adopted AHA 17-segment model to synthesize images with anatomically consistent and spatially diverse scar patterns. In addition, CLAIM employs a joint training strategy in which the scar segmentation network is optimized alongside the generator, aiming to enhance both the realism of synthesized scars and the accuracy of the scar segmentation performance. Experimental results show that CLAIM produces anatomically coherent scar patterns and achieves higher Dice similarity with real scar distributions compared to baseline models. Our approach enables controllable and realistic myocardial scar synthesis and has demonstrated utility for downstream medical imaging task. Code is available at https://github.com/farheenjabeen/CLAIM-Scar-Synthesis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.15549v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Farheen Ramzan, Yusuf Kiberu, Nikesh Jathanna, Shahnaz Jamil-Copley, Richard H. Clayton, Chen Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VLN-R1: Vision-Language Navigation via Reinforcement Fine-Tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.17221</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.17221v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Vision-Language Navigation (VLN) is a core challenge in embodied AI, requiring agents to navigate real-world environments using natural language instructions. Current language model-based navigation systems operate on discrete topological graphs, limiting path planning to predefined node connections. We propose VLN-R1, an end-to-end framework that leverages Large Vision-Language Models (LVLM) to directly translate egocentric video streams into continuous navigation actions, adopting GRPO-based training inspired by DeepSeek-R1. To enable effective training, we first construct the VLN-Ego dataset using a 3D simulator, Habitat, and propose Long-Short Memory Sampling to balance historical and current observations. While large language models can supervise complete textual instructions, they lack fine-grained action-level control. Our framework employs a two-stage training approach: a) Supervised fine-tuning (SFT) to align the model's action sequence text predictions with expert demonstrations, followed by b) Reinforcement fine-tuning (RFT) enhanced with a Time-Decayed Reward (TDR) mechanism that strategically weights multi-step future actions. Experimental results show VLN-R1 achieves strong performance on VLN-CE benchmark. VLN-R1 proves LVLMs can drive embodied navigation and enhance task-specific reasoning through data-efficient, reward-driven post-training.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.17221v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhangyang Qi, Zhixiong Zhang, Yizhou Yu, Jiaqi Wang, Hengshuang Zhao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BeltCrack: the First Sequential-image Industrial Conveyor Belt Crack Detection Dataset and Its Baseline with Triple-domain Feature Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.17892</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.17892v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Conveyor belts are important equipment in modern industry, widely applied in production and manufacturing. Their health is much critical to operational efficiency and safety. Cracks are a major threat to belt health. Currently, considering safety, how to intelligently detect belt cracks is catching an increasing attention. To implement the intelligent detection with machine learning, real crack samples are believed to be necessary. However, existing crack datasets primarily focus on pavement scenarios or synthetic data, no real-world industrial belt crack datasets at all. Cracks are a major threat to belt health. Furthermore, to validate usability and effectiveness, we propose a special baseline method with triple-domain ($i.e.$, time-space-frequency) feature hierarchical fusion learning for the two whole-new datasets. Experimental results demonstrate the availability and effectiveness of our dataset. Besides, they also show that our baseline is obviously superior to other similar detection methods. Our datasets and source codes are available at https://github.com/UESTC-nnLab/BeltCrack.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.17892v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jianghong Huang, Luping Ji, Xin Ma, Mao Ye</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PP-DocBee2: Improved Baselines with Efficient Data for Multimodal Document Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.18023</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.18023v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This report introduces PP-DocBee2, an advanced version of the PP-DocBee, designed to enhance multimodal document understanding. Built on a large multimodal model architecture, PP-DocBee2 addresses the limitations of its predecessor through key technological improvements, including enhanced synthetic data quality, improved visual feature fusion strategy, and optimized inference methodologies. These enhancements yield an $11.4\%$ performance boost on internal benchmarks for Chinese business documents, and reduce inference latency by $73.0\%$ to the vanilla version. A key innovation of our work is a data quality optimization strategy for multimodal document tasks. By employing a large-scale multimodal pre-trained model to evaluate data, we apply a novel statistical criterion to filter outliers, ensuring high-quality training data. Inspired by insights into underutilized intermediate features in multimodal models, we enhance the ViT representational capacity by decomposing it into layers and applying a novel feature fusion strategy to improve complex reasoning. The source code and pre-trained model are available at \href{https://github.com/PaddlePaddle/PaddleMIX}{https://github.com/PaddlePaddle/PaddleMIX}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.18023v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kui Huang, Xinrong Chen, Wenyu Lv, Jincheng Liao, Guanzhong Wang, Yi Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OmniGen2: Exploration to Advanced Multimodal Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.18871</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.18871v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this work, we introduce OmniGen2, a versatile and open-source generative model designed to provide a unified solution for diverse generation tasks, including text-to-image, image editing, and in-context generation. Unlike OmniGen v1, OmniGen2 features two distinct decoding pathways for text and image modalities, utilizing unshared parameters and a decoupled image tokenizer. This design enables OmniGen2 to build upon existing multimodal understanding models without the need to re-adapt VAE inputs, thereby preserving the original text generation capabilities. To facilitate the training of OmniGen2, we developed comprehensive data construction pipelines, encompassing image editing and in-context generation data. Additionally, we introduce a reflection mechanism tailored for image generation tasks and curate a dedicated reflection dataset based on OmniGen2. Despite its relatively modest parameter size, OmniGen2 achieves competitive results on multiple task benchmarks, including text-to-image and image editing. To further evaluate in-context generation, also referred to as subject-driven tasks, we introduce a new benchmark named OmniContext. OmniGen2 achieves state-of-the-art performance among open-source models in terms of consistency. We will release our models, training code, datasets, and data construction pipeline to support future research in this field. Project Page: https://vectorspacelab.github.io/OmniGen2; GitHub Link: https://github.com/VectorSpaceLab/OmniGen2</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.18871v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chenyuan Wu, Pengfei Zheng, Ruiran Yan, Shitao Xiao, Xin Luo, Yueze Wang, Wanli Li, Xiyan Jiang, Yexin Liu, Junjie Zhou, Ze Liu, Ziyi Xia, Chaofan Li, Haoge Deng, Jiahao Wang, Kun Luo, Bo Zhang, Defu Lian, Xinlong Wang, Zhongyuan Wang, Tiejun Huang, Zheng Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EvDetMAV: Generalized MAV Detection from Moving Event Cameras</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.19416</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.19416v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Existing micro aerial vehicle (MAV) detection methods mainly rely on the target's appearance features in RGB images, whose diversity makes it difficult to achieve generalized MAV detection. We notice that different types of MAVs share the same distinctive features in event streams due to their high-speed rotating propellers, which are hard to see in RGB images. This paper studies how to detect different types of MAVs from an event camera by fully exploiting the features of propellers in the original event stream. The proposed method consists of three modules to extract the salient and spatio-temporal features of the propellers while filtering out noise from background objects and camera motion. Since there are no existing event-based MAV datasets, we introduce a novel MAV dataset for the community. This is the first event-based MAV dataset comprising multiple scenarios and different types of MAVs. Without training, our method significantly outperforms state-of-the-art methods and can deal with challenging scenarios, achieving a precision rate of 83.0\% (+30.3\%) and a recall rate of 81.5\% (+36.4\%) on the proposed testing dataset. The dataset and code are available at: https://github.com/WindyLab/EvDetMAV.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.19416v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters, 2025</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Yin Zhang, Zian Ning, Xiaoyu Zhang, Shiliang Guo, Peidong Liu, Shiyu Zhao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sampling Matters in Explanations: Towards Trustworthy Attribution Analysis Building Block in Visual Models through Maximizing Explanation Certainty</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.19442</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.19442v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Image attribution analysis seeks to highlight the feature representations learned by visual models such that the highlighted feature maps can reflect the pixel-wise importance of inputs. Gradient integration is a building block in the attribution analysis by integrating the gradients from multiple derived samples to highlight the semantic features relevant to inferences. Such a building block often combines with other information from visual models such as activation or attention maps to form ultimate explanations. Yet, our theoretical analysis demonstrates that the extent to the alignment of the sample distribution in gradient integration with respect to natural image distribution gives a lower bound of explanation certainty. Prior works add noise into images as samples and the noise distributions can lead to low explanation certainty. Counter-intuitively, our experiment shows that extra information can saturate neural networks. To this end, building trustworthy attribution analysis needs to settle the sample distribution misalignment problem. Instead of adding extra information into input images, we present a semi-optimal sampling approach by suppressing features from inputs. The sample distribution by suppressing features is approximately identical to the distribution of natural images. Our extensive quantitative evaluation on large scale dataset ImageNet affirms that our approach is effective and able to yield more satisfactory explanations against state-of-the-art baselines throughout all experimental models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.19442v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.5281/zenodo.8204453</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>In Proceedings of the Irish Machine Vision and Image Processing Conference 2023 (IMVIP2023)</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>R\'ois\'in Luo, James McDermott, Colm O'Riordan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Supervised Multimodal NeRF for Autonomous Driving</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.19615</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.19615v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this paper, we propose a Neural Radiance Fields (NeRF) based framework, referred to as Novel View Synthesis Framework (NVSF). It jointly learns the implicit neural representation of space and time-varying scene for both LiDAR and Camera. We test this on a real-world autonomous driving scenario containing both static and dynamic scenes. Compared to existing multimodal dynamic NeRFs, our framework is self-supervised, thus eliminating the need for 3D labels. For efficient training and faster convergence, we introduce heuristic-based image pixel sampling to focus on pixels with rich information. To preserve the local features of LiDAR points, a Double Gradient based mask is employed. Extensive experiments on the KITTI-360 dataset show that, compared to the baseline models, our framework has reported best performance on both LiDAR and Camera domain. Code of the model is available at https://github.com/gaurav00700/Selfsupervised-NVSF</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.19615v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gaurav Sharma, Ravi Kothari, Josef Schmid</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Prototype Is Enough: Single-Prototype Activation for Interpretable Image Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.19808</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.19808v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this paper, we propose ProtoSolo, a novel deep neural architecture for interpretable image classification inspired by prototypical networks such as ProtoPNet. Existing prototype networks usually rely on the collaborative decision-making of multiple prototypes to achieve the classification and interpretation of a single category. In contrast, ProtoSolo only requires the activation of a single prototype to complete the classification. This allows the network to explain each category decision by only providing the features that are most similar to the prototype of that category, significantly reducing the cognitive complexity of the explanation. Secondly, we propose a feature-based comparison method, which uses feature map instead of full-channel feature vector as the object of similarity comparison and prototype learning. This design enables ProtoSolo to utilize richer global information for classification while relying on a single prototype activation. In addition, we propose a non-prototype projection learning strategy, which preserves the information association between the prototype and the training image patches while avoiding the sharp change of the network structure caused by the projection operation, thus avoiding its negative impact on the classification performance. Experiments on the CUB-200-2011 and Stanford Cars datasets show that ProtoSolo achieves superior performance in classification tasks and reaches the best level in terms of cognitive complexity of explanations compared to state-of-the-art interpretable methods. The code is available at https://github.com/pyt19/ProtoSolo.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.19808v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yitao Peng, Lianghua He, Die Hu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screen Them All: High-Throughput Pan-Cancer Genetic and Phenotypic Biomarker Screening from H&amp;E Whole Slide Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09554</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.09554v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Molecular assays are standard of care for detecting genomic alterations in cancer prognosis and therapy selection but are costly, tissue-destructive and time-consuming. Artificial intelligence (AI) applied to routine hematoxylin and eosin (H&amp;E)-stained whole slide images (WSIs) offers a fast and economical alternative for screening molecular biomarkers. We introduce OmniScreen, a high-throughput AI-based system leveraging Virchow2 embeddings extracted from 60,529 cancer patients with paired 489-gene MSK-IMPACT targeted biomarker panel and WSIs. Unlike conventional approaches that train separate models for each biomarker, OmniScreen employs a unified model to predict a broad range of clinically relevant biomarkers across cancers, including low-prevalence targets impractical to model individually. OmniScreen reliably identifies therapeutic targets and shared phenotypic features across common and rare tumors. We investigate the biomarker prediction probabilities and accuracies of OmniScreen in relation to tumor area, cohort size, histologic subtype alignment, and pathway-level morphological patterns. These findings underscore the potential of OmniScreen for routine clinical screening.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.09554v3</guid>
      <category>q-bio.QM</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yi Kan Wang, Ludmila Tylditatova, Jeremy D. Kunz, Gerard Oakley, Bonnie Kar Bo Chow, Ran A. Godrich, Matthew C. H. Lee, Hamed Aghdam, Alican Bozkurt, Michal Zelechowski, Chad Vanderbilt, Christopher Kanan, Juan A. Retamero, Peter Hamilton, Razik Yousfi, Thomas J. Fuchs, David S. Klimstra, Siqi Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mamba Policy: Towards Efficient 3D Diffusion Policy with Hybrid Selective State Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.07163</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.07163v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Diffusion models have been widely employed in the field of 3D manipulation due to their efficient capability to learn distributions, allowing for precise prediction of action trajectories. However, diffusion models typically rely on large parameter UNet backbones as policy networks, which can be challenging to deploy on resource-constrained devices. Recently, the Mamba model has emerged as a promising solution for efficient modeling, offering low computational complexity and strong performance in sequence modeling. In this work, we propose the Mamba Policy, a lighter but stronger policy that reduces the parameter count by over 80% compared to the original policy network while achieving superior performance. Specifically, we introduce the XMamba Block, which effectively integrates input information with conditional features and leverages a combination of Mamba and Attention mechanisms for deep feature extraction. Extensive experiments demonstrate that the Mamba Policy excels on the Adroit, Dexart, and MetaWorld datasets, requiring significantly fewer computational resources. Additionally, we highlight the Mamba Policy's enhanced robustness in long-horizon scenarios compared to baseline methods and explore the performance of various Mamba variants within the Mamba Policy framework. Real-world experiments are also conducted to further validate its effectiveness. Our open-source project page can be found at https://andycao1125.github.io/mamba_policy/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.07163v2</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiahang Cao, Qiang Zhang, Jingkai Sun, Jiaxu Wang, Hao Cheng, Yulin Li, Jun Ma, Kun Wu, Zhiyuan Xu, Yecheng Shao, Wen Zhao, Gang Han, Yijie Guo, Renjing Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WAFFLE: Finetuning Multi-Modal Model for Automated Front-End Development</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.18362</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.18362v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Web development involves turning UI designs into functional webpages, which can be difficult for both beginners and experienced developers due to the complexity of HTML's hierarchical structures and styles. While Large Language Models (LLMs) have shown promise in generating source code, two major challenges persist in UI-to-HTML code generation: (1) effectively representing HTML's hierarchical structure for LLMs, and (2) bridging the gap between the visual nature of UI designs and the text-based format of HTML code. To tackle these challenges, we introduce Waffle, a new fine-tuning strategy that uses a structure-aware attention mechanism to improve LLMs' understanding of HTML's structure and a contrastive fine-tuning approach to align LLMs' understanding of UI images and HTML code. Models fine-tuned with Waffle show up to 9.00 pp (percentage point) higher HTML match, 0.0982 higher CW-SSIM, 32.99 higher CLIP, and 27.12 pp higher LLEM on our new benchmark WebSight-Test and an existing benchmark Design2Code, outperforming current fine-tuning methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.18362v2</guid>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shanchao Liang, Nan Jiang, Shangshu Qian, Lin Tan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bounding-box Watermarking: Defense against Model Extraction Attacks on Object Detectors</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.13047</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.13047v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Deep neural networks (DNNs) deployed in a cloud often allow users to query models via the APIs. However, these APIs expose the models to model extraction attacks (MEAs). In this attack, the attacker attempts to duplicate the target model by abusing the responses from the API. Backdoor-based DNN watermarking is known as a promising defense against MEAs, wherein the defender injects a backdoor into extracted models via API responses. The backdoor is used as a watermark of the model; if a suspicious model has the watermark (i.e., backdoor), it is verified as an extracted model. This work focuses on object detection (OD) models. Existing backdoor attacks on OD models are not applicable for model watermarking as the defense against MEAs on a realistic threat model. Our proposed approach involves inserting a backdoor into extracted models via APIs by stealthily modifying the bounding-boxes (BBs) of objects detected in queries while keeping the OD capability. In our experiments on three OD datasets, the proposed approach succeeded in identifying the extracted models with 100% accuracy in a wide variety of experimental scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.13047v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Satoru Koda, Ikuya Morikawa</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predictive Modeling, Pattern Recognition, and Spatiotemporal Representations of Plant Growth in Simulated and Controlled Environments: A Comprehensive Review</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.10538</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.10538v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Accurate predictions and representations of plant growth patterns in simulated and controlled environments are important for addressing various challenges in plant phenomics research. This review explores various works on state-of-the-art predictive pattern recognition techniques, focusing on the spatiotemporal modeling of plant traits and the integration of dynamic environmental interactions. We provide a comprehensive examination of deterministic, probabilistic, and generative modeling approaches, emphasizing their applications in high-throughput phenotyping and simulation-based plant growth forecasting. Key topics include regressions and neural network-based representation models for the task of forecasting, limitations of existing experiment-based deterministic approaches, and the need for dynamic frameworks that incorporate uncertainty and evolving environmental feedback. This review surveys advances in 2D and 3D structured data representations through functional-structural plant models and conditional generative models. We offer a perspective on opportunities for future works, emphasizing the integration of domain-specific knowledge to data-driven methods, improvements to available datasets, and the implementation of these techniques toward real-world applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.10538v3</guid>
      <category>q-bio.QM</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mohamed Debbagh, Shangpeng Sun, Mark Lefsrud</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Provably Improving Generalization of Few-Shot Models with Synthetic Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.24190</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.24190v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Few-shot image classification remains challenging due to the scarcity of labeled training examples. Augmenting them with synthetic data has emerged as a promising way to alleviate this issue, but models trained on synthetic samples often face performance degradation due to the inherent gap between real and synthetic distributions. To address this limitation, we develop a theoretical framework that quantifies the impact of such distribution discrepancies on supervised learning, specifically in the context of image classification. More importantly, our framework suggests practical ways to generate good synthetic samples and to train a predictor with high generalization ability. Building upon this framework, we propose a novel theoretical-based algorithm that integrates prototype learning to optimize both data partitioning and model training, effectively bridging the gap between real few-shot data and synthetic data. Extensive experiments results show that our approach demonstrates superior performance compared to state-of-the-art methods, outperforming them across multiple datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.24190v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lan-Cuong Nguyen, Quan Nguyen-Tri, Bang Tran Khanh, Dung D. Le, Long Tran-Thanh, Khoat Than</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Coarse to Continuous: Progressive Refinement Implicit Neural Representation for Motion-Robust Anisotropic MRI Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.16210</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.16210v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In motion-robust magnetic resonance imaging (MRI), slice-to-volume reconstruction is critical for recovering anatomically consistent 3D brain volumes from 2D slices, especially under accelerated acquisitions or patient motion. However, this task remains challenging due to hierarchical structural disruptions. It includes local detail loss from k-space undersampling, global structural aliasing caused by motion, and volumetric anisotropy. Therefore, we propose a progressive refinement implicit neural representation (PR-INR) framework. Our PR-INR unifies motion correction, structural refinement, and volumetric synthesis within a geometry-aware coordinate space. Specifically, a motion-aware diffusion module is first employed to generate coarse volumetric reconstructions that suppress motion artifacts and preserve global anatomical structures. Then, we introduce an implicit detail restoration module that performs residual refinement by aligning spatial coordinates with visual features. It corrects local structures and enhances boundary precision. Further, a voxel continuous-aware representation module represents the image as a continuous function over 3D coordinates. It enables accurate inter-slice completion and high-frequency detail recovery. We evaluate PR-INR on five public MRI datasets under various motion conditions (3% and 5% displacement), undersampling rates (4x and 8x) and slice resolutions (scale = 5). Experimental results demonstrate that PR-INR outperforms state-of-the-art methods in both quantitative reconstruction metrics and visual quality. It further shows generalization and robustness across diverse unseen domains.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.16210v2</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhenxuan Zhang, Lipei Zhang, Yanqi Cheng, Zi Wang, Fanwen Wang, Haosen Zhang, Yue Yang, Yinzhe Wu, Jiahao Huang, Angelica I Aviles-Rivero, Zhifan Gao, Guang Yang, Peter J. Lally</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DRO-Augment Framework: Robustness by Synergizing Wasserstein Distributionally Robust Optimization and Data Augmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.17874</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.17874v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In many real-world applications, ensuring the robustness and stability of deep neural networks (DNNs) is crucial, particularly for image classification tasks that encounter various input perturbations. While data augmentation techniques have been widely adopted to enhance the resilience of a trained model against such perturbations, there remains significant room for improvement in robustness against corrupted data and adversarial attacks simultaneously. To address this challenge, we introduce DRO-Augment, a novel framework that integrates Wasserstein Distributionally Robust Optimization (W-DRO) with various data augmentation strategies to improve the robustness of the models significantly across a broad spectrum of corruptions. Our method outperforms existing augmentation methods under severe data perturbations and adversarial attack scenarios while maintaining the accuracy on the clean datasets on a range of benchmark datasets, including but not limited to CIFAR-10-C, CIFAR-100-C, MNIST, and Fashion-MNIST. On the theoretical side, we establish novel generalization error bounds for neural networks trained using a computationally efficient, variation-regularized loss function closely related to the W-DRO problem.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.17874v2</guid>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiaming Hu, Debarghya Mukherjee, Ioannis Ch. Paschalidis</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LVPNet: A Latent-variable-based Prediction-driven End-to-end Framework for Lossless Compression of Medical Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.17983</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.17983v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Autoregressive Initial Bits is a framework that integrates sub-image autoregression and latent variable modeling, demonstrating its advantages in lossless medical image compression. However, in existing methods, the image segmentation process leads to an even distribution of latent variable information across each sub-image, which in turn causes posterior collapse and inefficient utilization of latent variables. To deal with these issues, we propose a prediction-based end-to-end lossless medical image compression method named LVPNet, leveraging global latent variables to predict pixel values and encoding predicted probabilities for lossless compression. Specifically, we introduce the Global Multi-scale Sensing Module (GMSM), which extracts compact and informative latent representations from the entire image, effectively capturing spatial dependencies within the latent space. Furthermore, to mitigate the information loss introduced during quantization, we propose the Quantization Compensation Module (QCM), which learns the distribution of quantization errors and refines the quantized features to compensate for quantization loss. Extensive experiments on challenging benchmarks demonstrate that our method achieves superior compression efficiency compared to state-of-the-art lossless image compression approaches, while maintaining competitive inference speed. The code is at https://github.com/scy-Jackel/LVPNet.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.17983v2</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chenyue Song, Chen Hui, Qing Lin, Wei Zhang, Siqiao Li, Haiqi Zhu, Zhixuan Li, Shengping Zhang, Shaohui Liu, Feng Jiang, Xiang Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morse: Dual-Sampling for Lossless Acceleration of Diffusion Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.18251</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.18251v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In this paper, we present Morse, a simple dual-sampling framework for accelerating diffusion models losslessly. The key insight of Morse is to reformulate the iterative generation (from noise to data) process via taking advantage of fast jump sampling and adaptive residual feedback strategies. Specifically, Morse involves two models called Dash and Dot that interact with each other. The Dash model is just the pre-trained diffusion model of any type, but operates in a jump sampling regime, creating sufficient space for sampling efficiency improvement. The Dot model is significantly faster than the Dash model, which is learnt to generate residual feedback conditioned on the observations at the current jump sampling point on the trajectory of the Dash model, lifting the noise estimate to easily match the next-step estimate of the Dash model without jump sampling. By chaining the outputs of the Dash and Dot models run in a time-interleaved fashion, Morse exhibits the merit of flexibly attaining desired image generation performance while improving overall runtime efficiency. With our proposed weight sharing strategy between the Dash and Dot models, Morse is efficient for training and inference. Our method shows a lossless speedup of 1.78X to 3.31X on average over a wide range of sampling step budgets relative to 9 baseline diffusion models on 6 image generation tasks. Furthermore, we show that our method can be also generalized to improve the Latent Consistency Model (LCM-SDXL, which is already accelerated with consistency distillation technique) tailored for few-step text-to-image synthesis. The code and models are available at https://github.com/deep-optimization/Morse.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.18251v2</guid>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chao Li, Jiawei Fan, Anbang Yao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TCDiff++: An End-to-end Trajectory-Controllable Diffusion Model for Harmonious Music-Driven Group Choreography</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.18671</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.18671v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Music-driven dance generation has garnered significant attention due to its wide range of industrial applications, particularly in the creation of group choreography. During the group dance generation process, however, most existing methods still face three primary issues: multi-dancer collisions, single-dancer foot sliding and abrupt swapping in the generation of long group dance. In this paper, we propose TCDiff++, a music-driven end-to-end framework designed to generate harmonious group dance. Specifically, to mitigate multi-dancer collisions, we utilize a dancer positioning embedding to better maintain the relative positioning among dancers. Additionally, we incorporate a distance-consistency loss to ensure that inter-dancer distances remain within plausible ranges. To address the issue of single-dancer foot sliding, we introduce a swap mode embedding to indicate dancer swapping patterns and design a Footwork Adaptor to refine raw motion, thereby minimizing foot sliding. For long group dance generation, we present a long group diffusion sampling strategy that reduces abrupt position shifts by injecting positional information into the noisy input. Furthermore, we integrate a Sequence Decoder layer to enhance the model's ability to selectively process long sequences. Extensive experiments demonstrate that our TCDiff++ achieves state-of-the-art performance, particularly in long-duration scenarios, ensuring high-quality and coherent group dance generation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.18671v3</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuqin Dai, Wanlu Zhu, Ronghui Li, Xiu Li, Zhenyu Zhang, Jun Li, Jian Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
