<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CV updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CV</link>
    <description>cs.CV updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CV" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 05:00:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Saturday</day>
      <day>Sunday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>LS-GAN: Human Motion Synthesis with Latent-space GANs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01449</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01449v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Human motion synthesis conditioned on textual input has gained significant attention in recent years due to its potential applications in various domains such as gaming, film production, and virtual reality. Conditioned Motion synthesis takes a text input and outputs a 3D motion corresponding to the text. While previous works have explored motion synthesis using raw motion data and latent space representations with diffusion models, these approaches often suffer from high training and inference times. In this paper, we introduce a novel framework that utilizes Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs) in the latent space to enable faster training and inference while achieving results comparable to those of the state-of-the-art diffusion methods. We perform experiments on the HumanML3D, HumanAct12 benchmarks and demonstrate that a remarkably simple GAN in the latent space achieves a FID of 0.482 with more than 91% in FLOPs reduction compared to latent diffusion model. Our work opens up new possibilities for efficient and high-quality motion synthesis using latent space GANs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01449v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Avinash Amballa, Gayathri Akkinapalli, Vinitra Muralikrishnan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAFER: Sharpness Aware layer-selective Finetuning for Enhanced Robustness in vision transformers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01529</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01529v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Vision transformers (ViTs) have become essential backbones in advanced computer vision applications and multi-modal foundation models. Despite their strengths, ViTs remain vulnerable to adversarial perturbations, comparable to or even exceeding the vulnerability of convolutional neural networks (CNNs). Furthermore, the large parameter count and complex architecture of ViTs make them particularly prone to adversarial overfitting, often compromising both clean and adversarial accuracy.
  This paper mitigates adversarial overfitting in ViTs through a novel, layer-selective fine-tuning approach: SAFER. Instead of optimizing the entire model, we identify and selectively fine-tune a small subset of layers most susceptible to overfitting, applying sharpness-aware minimization to these layers while freezing the rest of the model. Our method consistently enhances both clean and adversarial accuracy over baseline approaches. Typical improvements are around 5%, with some cases achieving gains as high as 20% across various ViT architectures and datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01529v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bhavna Gopal, Huanrui Yang, Mark Horton, Yiran Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Task-Driven Fixation Network: An Efficient Architecture with Fixation Selection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01548</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01548v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper presents a novel neural network architecture featuring automatic fixation point selection, designed to efficiently address complex tasks with reduced network size and computational overhead. The proposed model consists of: a low-resolution channel that captures low-resolution global features from input images; a high-resolution channel that sequentially extracts localized high-resolution features; and a hybrid encoding module that integrates the features from both channels. A defining characteristic of the hybrid encoding module is the inclusion of a fixation point generator, which dynamically produces fixation points, enabling the high-resolution channel to focus on regions of interest. The fixation points are generated in a task-driven manner, enabling the automatic selection of regions of interest. This approach avoids exhaustive high-resolution analysis of the entire image, maintaining task performance and computational efficiency.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01548v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shuguang Wang, Yuanjing Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Click-Calib: A Robust Extrinsic Calibration Method for Surround-View Systems</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01557</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01557v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Surround-View System (SVS) is an essential component in Advanced Driver Assistance System (ADAS) and requires precise calibrations. However, conventional offline extrinsic calibration methods are cumbersome and time-consuming as they rely heavily on physical patterns. Additionally, these methods primarily focus on short-range areas surrounding the vehicle, resulting in lower calibration quality in more distant zones. To address these limitations, we propose Click-Calib, a pattern-free approach for offline SVS extrinsic calibration. Without requiring any special setup, the user only needs to click a few keypoints on the ground in natural scenes. Unlike other offline calibration approaches, Click-Calib optimizes camera poses over a wide range by minimizing reprojection distance errors of keypoints, thereby achieving accurate calibrations at both short and long distances. Furthermore, Click-Calib supports both single-frame and multiple-frame modes, with the latter offering even better results. Evaluations on our in-house dataset and the public WoodScape dataset demonstrate its superior accuracy and robustness compared to baseline methods. Code is avalaible at https://github.com/lwangvaleo/click_calib.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01557v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lihao Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>D$^3$-Human: Dynamic Disentangled Digital Human from Monocular Video</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01589</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01589v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We introduce D$^3$-Human, a method for reconstructing Dynamic Disentangled Digital Human geometry from monocular videos. Past monocular video human reconstruction primarily focuses on reconstructing undecoupled clothed human bodies or only reconstructing clothing, making it difficult to apply directly in applications such as animation production. The challenge in reconstructing decoupled clothing and body lies in the occlusion caused by clothing over the body. To this end, the details of the visible area and the plausibility of the invisible area must be ensured during the reconstruction process. Our proposed method combines explicit and implicit representations to model the decoupled clothed human body, leveraging the robustness of explicit representations and the flexibility of implicit representations. Specifically, we reconstruct the visible region as SDF and propose a novel human manifold signed distance field (hmSDF) to segment the visible clothing and visible body, and then merge the visible and invisible body. Extensive experimental results demonstrate that, compared with existing reconstruction schemes, D$^3$-Human can achieve high-quality decoupled reconstruction of the human body wearing different clothing, and can be directly applied to clothing transfer and animation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01589v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Honghu Chen, Bo Peng, Yunfan Tao, Juyong Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive Homophily Clustering: A Structure Homophily Graph Learning with Adaptive Filter for Hyperspectral Image</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01595</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01595v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Hyperspectral image (HSI) clustering has been a fundamental but challenging task with zero training labels. Currently, some deep graph clustering methods have been successfully explored for HSI due to their outstanding performance in effective spatial structural information encoding. Nevertheless, insufficient structural information utilization, poor feature presentation ability, and weak graph update capability limit their performance. Thus, in this paper, a homophily structure graph learning with an adaptive filter clustering method (AHSGC) for HSI is proposed. Specifically, homogeneous region generation is first developed for HSI processing and constructing the original graph. Afterward, an adaptive filter graph encoder is designed to adaptively capture the high and low frequency features on the graph for subsequence processing. Then, a graph embedding clustering self-training decoder is developed with KL Divergence, with which the pseudo-label is generated for network training. Meanwhile, homophily-enhanced structure learning is introduced to update the graph according to the clustering task, in which the orient correlation estimation is adopted to estimate the node connection, and graph edge sparsification is designed to adjust the edges in the graph dynamically. Finally, a joint network optimization is introduced to achieve network self-training and update the graph. The K-means is adopted to express the latent features. Extensive experiments and repeated comparative analysis have verified that our AHSGC contains high clustering accuracy, low computational complexity, and strong robustness. The code source will be available at https://github.com/DY-HYX.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01595v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yao Ding, Weijie Kang, Aitao Yang, Zhili Zhang, Junyang Zhao, Jie Feng, Danfeng Hong, Qinhe Zheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Few-shot Implicit Function Generation via Equivariance</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01601</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01601v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Implicit Neural Representations (INRs) have emerged as a powerful framework for representing continuous signals. However, generating diverse INR weights remains challenging due to limited training data. We introduce Few-shot Implicit Function Generation, a new problem setup that aims to generate diverse yet functionally consistent INR weights from only a few examples. This is challenging because even for the same signal, the optimal INRs can vary significantly depending on their initializations. To tackle this, we propose EquiGen, a framework that can generate new INRs from limited data. The core idea is that functionally similar networks can be transformed into one another through weight permutations, forming an equivariance group. By projecting these weights into an equivariant latent space, we enable diverse generation within these groups, even with few examples. EquiGen implements this through an equivariant encoder trained via contrastive learning and smooth augmentation, an equivariance-guided diffusion process, and controlled perturbations in the equivariant subspace. Experiments on 2D image and 3D shape INR datasets demonstrate that our approach effectively generates diverse INR weights while preserving their functional properties in few-shot scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01601v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Suizhi Huang, Xingyi Yang, Hongtao Lu, Xinchao Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google is all you need: Semi-Supervised Transfer Learning Strategy For Light Multimodal Multi-Task Classification Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01611</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01611v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: As the volume of digital image data increases, the effectiveness of image classification intensifies. This study introduces a robust multi-label classification system designed to assign multiple labels to a single image, addressing the complexity of images that may be associated with multiple categories (ranging from 1 to 19, excluding 12). We propose a multi-modal classifier that merges advanced image recognition algorithms with Natural Language Processing (NLP) models, incorporating a fusion module to integrate these distinct modalities. The purpose of integrating textual data is to enhance the accuracy of label prediction by providing contextual understanding that visual analysis alone cannot fully capture. Our proposed classification model combines Convolutional Neural Networks (CNN) for image processing with NLP techniques for analyzing textual description (i.e., captions). This approach includes rigorous training and validation phases, with each model component verified and analyzed through ablation experiments. Preliminary results demonstrate the classifier's accuracy and efficiency, highlighting its potential as an automatic image-labeling system.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01611v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haixu Liu, Penghao Jiang, Zerui Tao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Merging Context Clustering with Visual State Space Models for Medical Image Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01618</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01618v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Medical image segmentation demands the aggregation of global and local feature representations, posing a challenge for current methodologies in handling both long-range and short-range feature interactions. Recently, vision mamba (ViM) models have emerged as promising solutions for addressing model complexities by excelling in long-range feature iterations with linear complexity. However, existing ViM approaches overlook the importance of preserving short-range local dependencies by directly flattening spatial tokens and are constrained by fixed scanning patterns that limit the capture of dynamic spatial context information. To address these challenges, we introduce a simple yet effective method named context clustering ViM (CCViM), which incorporates a context clustering module within the existing ViM models to segment image tokens into distinct windows for adaptable local clustering. Our method effectively combines long-range and short-range feature interactions, thereby enhancing spatial contextual representations for medical image segmentation tasks. Extensive experimental evaluations on diverse public datasets, i.e., Kumar, CPM17, ISIC17, ISIC18, and Synapse demonstrate the superior performance of our method compared to current state-of-the-art methods. Our code can be found at https://github.com/zymissy/CCViM.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01618v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yun Zhu, Dong Zhang, Yi Lin, Yifei Feng, Jinhui Tang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ACE: Anti-Editing Concept Erasure in Text-to-Image Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01633</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01633v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent advance in text-to-image diffusion models have significantly facilitated the generation of high-quality images, but also raising concerns about the illegal creation of harmful content, such as copyrighted images. Existing concept erasure methods achieve superior results in preventing the production of erased concept from prompts, but typically perform poorly in preventing undesired editing. To address this issue, we propose an Anti-Editing Concept Erasure (ACE) method, which not only erases the target concept during generation but also filters out it during editing. Specifically, we propose to inject the erasure guidance into both conditional and the unconditional noise prediction, enabling the model to effectively prevent the creation of erasure concepts during both editing and generation. Furthermore, a stochastic correction guidance is introduced during training to address the erosion of unrelated concepts. We conducted erasure editing experiments with representative editing methods (i.e., LEDITS++ and MasaCtrl) to erase IP characters, and the results indicate that our ACE effectively filters out target concepts in both types of edits. Additional experiments on erasing explicit concepts and artistic styles further demonstrate that our ACE performs favorably against state-of-the-art methods. Our code will be publicly available at https://github.com/120L020904/ACE.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01633v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zihao Wang, Yuxiang Wei, Fan Li, Renjing Pei, Hang Xu, Wangmeng Zuo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncertainty and Energy based Loss Guided Semi-Supervised Semantic Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01640</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01640v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Semi-supervised (SS) semantic segmentation exploits both labeled and unlabeled images to overcome tedious and costly pixel-level annotation problems. Pseudolabel supervision is one of the core approaches of training networks with both pseudo labels and ground-truth labels. This work uses aleatoric or data uncertainty and energy based modeling in intersection-union pseudo supervised network.The aleatoric uncertainty is modeling the inherent noise variations of the data in a network with two predictive branches. The per-pixel variance parameter obtained from the network gives a quantitative idea about the data uncertainty. Moreover, energy-based loss realizes the potential of generative modeling on the downstream SS segmentation task. The aleatoric and energy loss are applied in conjunction with pseudo-intersection labels, pseudo-union labels, and ground-truth on the respective network branch. The comparative analysis with state-of-the-art methods has shown improvement in performance metrics.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01640v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rini Smita Thakur, Vinod K. Kurmi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iCBIR-Sli: Interpretable Content-Based Image Retrieval with 2D Slice Embeddings</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01642</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01642v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Current methods for searching brain MR images rely on text-based approaches, highlighting a significant need for content-based image retrieval (CBIR) systems. Directly applying 3D brain MR images to machine learning models offers the benefit of effectively learning the brain's structure; however, building the generalized model necessitates a large amount of training data. While models that consider depth direction and utilize continuous 2D slices have demonstrated success in segmentation and classification tasks involving 3D data, concerns remain. Specifically, using general 2D slices may lead to the oversight of pathological features and discontinuities in depth direction information. Furthermore, to the best of the authors' knowledge, there have been no attempts to develop a practical CBIR system that preserves the entire brain's structural information. In this study, we propose an interpretable CBIR method for brain MR images, named iCBIR-Sli (Interpretable CBIR with 2D Slice Embedding), which, for the first time globally, utilizes a series of 2D slices. iCBIR-Sli addresses the challenges associated with using 2D slices by effectively aggregating slice information, thereby achieving low-dimensional representations with high completeness, usability, robustness, and interoperability, which are qualities essential for effective CBIR. In retrieval evaluation experiments utilizing five publicly available brain MR datasets (ADNI2/3, OASIS3/4, AIBL) for Alzheimer's disease and cognitively normal, iCBIR-Sli demonstrated top-1 retrieval performance (macro F1 = 0.859), comparable to existing deep learning models explicitly designed for classification, without the need for an external classifier. Additionally, the method provided high interpretability by clearly identifying the brain regions indicative of the searched-for disease.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01642v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Proceedings of the SPIE Medical Imaging, 16-20 February, 2025, San Diego, California, US</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Shuhei Tomoshige, Hayato Muraki, Kenichi Oishi, Hitoshi Iyatomi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HLV-1K: A Large-scale Hour-Long Video Benchmark for Time-Specific Long Video Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01645</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01645v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Multimodal large language models have become a popular topic in deep visual understanding due to many promising real-world applications. However, hour-long video understanding, spanning over one hour and containing tens of thousands of visual frames, remains under-explored because of 1) challenging long-term video analyses, 2) inefficient large-model approaches, and 3) lack of large-scale benchmark datasets. Among them, in this paper, we focus on building a large-scale hour-long long video benchmark, HLV-1K, designed to evaluate long video understanding models. HLV-1K comprises 1009 hour-long videos with 14,847 high-quality question answering (QA) and multi-choice question asnwering (MCQA) pairs with time-aware query and diverse annotations, covering frame-level, within-event-level, cross-event-level, and long-term reasoning tasks. We evaluate our benchmark using existing state-of-the-art methods and demonstrate its value for testing deep long video understanding capabilities at different levels and for various tasks. This includes promoting future long video understanding tasks at a granular level, such as deep understanding of long live videos, meeting recordings, and movies.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01645v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Heqing Zou (Xiao Jie), Tianze Luo (Xiao Jie), Guiyang Xie (Xiao Jie),  Victor (Xiao Jie),  Zhang, Fengmao Lv, Guangcong Wang, Junyang Chen, Zhuochen Wang, Hansheng Zhang, Huaijian Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual Mutual Learning Network with Global-local Awareness for RGB-D Salient Object Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01648</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01648v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: RGB-D salient object detection (SOD), aiming to highlight prominent regions of a given scene by jointly modeling RGB and depth information, is one of the challenging pixel-level prediction tasks. Recently, the dual-attention mechanism has been devoted to this area due to its ability to strengthen the detection process. However, most existing methods directly fuse attentional cross-modality features under a manual-mandatory fusion paradigm without considering the inherent discrepancy between the RGB and depth, which may lead to a reduction in performance. Moreover, the long-range dependencies derived from global and local information make it difficult to leverage a unified efficient fusion strategy. Hence, in this paper, we propose the GL-DMNet, a novel dual mutual learning network with global-local awareness. Specifically, we present a position mutual fusion module and a channel mutual fusion module to exploit the interdependencies among different modalities in spatial and channel dimensions. Besides, we adopt an efficient decoder based on cascade transformer-infused reconstruction to integrate multi-level fusion features jointly. Extensive experiments on six benchmark datasets demonstrate that our proposed GL-DMNet performs better than 24 RGB-D SOD methods, achieving an average improvement of ~3% across four evaluation metrics compared to the second-best model (S3Net). Codes and results are available at https://github.com/kingkung2016/GL-DMNet.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01648v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kang Yi, Haoran Tang, Yumeng Li, Jing Xu, Jun Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EAUWSeg: Eliminating annotation uncertainty in weakly-supervised medical image segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01658</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01658v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Weakly-supervised medical image segmentation is gaining traction as it requires only rough annotations rather than accurate pixel-to-pixel labels, thereby reducing the workload for specialists. Although some progress has been made, there is still a considerable performance gap between the label-efficient methods and fully-supervised one, which can be attributed to the uncertainty nature of these weak labels. To address this issue, we propose a novel weak annotation method coupled with its learning framework EAUWSeg to eliminate the annotation uncertainty. Specifically, we first propose the Bounded Polygon Annotation (BPAnno) by simply labeling two polygons for a lesion. Then, the tailored learning mechanism that explicitly treat bounded polygons as two separated annotations is proposed to learn invariant feature by providing adversarial supervision signal for model training. Subsequently, a confidence-auxiliary consistency learner incorporates with a classification-guided confidence generator is designed to provide reliable supervision signal for pixels in uncertain region by leveraging the feature presentation consistency across pixels within the same category as well as class-specific information encapsulated in bounded polygons annotation. Experimental results demonstrate that EAUWSeg outperforms existing weakly-supervised segmentation methods. Furthermore, compared to fully-supervised counterparts, the proposed method not only delivers superior performance but also costs much less annotation workload. This underscores the superiority and effectiveness of our approach.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01658v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wang Lituan, Zhang Lei, Wang Yan, Wang Zhenbin, Zhang Zhenwei, Zhang Yi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PG-SAG: Parallel Gaussian Splatting for Fine-Grained Large-Scale Urban Buildings Reconstruction via Semantic-Aware Grouping</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01677</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01677v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: 3D Gaussian Splatting (3DGS) has emerged as a transformative method in the field of real-time novel synthesis. Based on 3DGS, recent advancements cope with large-scale scenes via spatial-based partition strategy to reduce video memory and optimization time costs. In this work, we introduce a parallel Gaussian splatting method, termed PG-SAG, which fully exploits semantic cues for both partitioning and Gaussian kernel optimization, enabling fine-grained building surface reconstruction of large-scale urban areas without downsampling the original image resolution. First, the Cross-modal model - Language Segment Anything is leveraged to segment building masks. Then, the segmented building regions is grouped into sub-regions according to the visibility check across registered images. The Gaussian kernels for these sub-regions are optimized in parallel with masked pixels. In addition, the normal loss is re-formulated for the detected edges of masks to alleviate the ambiguities in normal vectors on edges. Finally, to improve the optimization of 3D Gaussians, we introduce a gradient-constrained balance-load loss that accounts for the complexity of the corresponding scenes, effectively minimizing the thread waiting time in the pixel-parallel rendering stage as well as the reconstruction lost. Extensive experiments are tested on various urban datasets, the results demonstrated the superior performance of our PG-SAG on building surface reconstruction, compared to several state-of-the-art 3DGS-based methods. Project Web:https://github.com/TFWang-9527/PG-SAG.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01677v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tengfei Wang, Xin Wang, Yongmao Hou, Yiwei Xu, Wendi Zhang, Zongqian Zhan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IAM: Enhancing RGB-D Instance Segmentation with New Benchmarks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01685</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01685v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Image segmentation is a vital task for providing human assistance and enhancing autonomy in our daily lives. In particular, RGB-D segmentation-leveraging both visual and depth cues-has attracted increasing attention as it promises richer scene understanding than RGB-only methods. However, most existing efforts have primarily focused on semantic segmentation and thus leave a critical gap. There is a relative scarcity of instance-level RGB-D segmentation datasets, which restricts current methods to broad category distinctions rather than fully capturing the fine-grained details required for recognizing individual objects. To bridge this gap, we introduce three RGB-D instance segmentation benchmarks, distinguished at the instance level. These datasets are versatile, supporting a wide range of applications from indoor navigation to robotic manipulation. In addition, we present an extensive evaluation of various baseline models on these benchmarks. This comprehensive analysis identifies both their strengths and shortcomings, guiding future work toward more robust, generalizable solutions. Finally, we propose a simple yet effective method for RGB-D data integration. Extensive evaluations affirm the effectiveness of our approach, offering a robust framework for advancing toward more nuanced scene understanding.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01685v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aecheon Jung, Soyun Choi, Junhong Min, Sungeun Hong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative Gait Analysis from Single RGB Videos Using a Dual-Input Transformer-Based Network</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01689</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01689v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Gait and movement analysis have become a well-established clinical tool for diagnosing health conditions, monitoring disease progression for a wide spectrum of diseases, and to implement and assess treatment, surgery and or rehabilitation interventions. However, quantitative motion assessment remains limited to costly motion capture systems and specialized personnel, restricting its accessibility and broader application. Recent advancements in deep neural networks have enabled quantitative movement analysis using single-camera videos, offering an accessible alternative to conventional motion capture systems. In this paper, we present an efficient approach for clinical gait analysis through a dual-pattern input convolutional Transformer network. The proposed system leverages a dual-input Transformer model to estimate essential gait parameters from single RGB videos captured by a single-view camera. The system demonstrates high accuracy in estimating critical metrics such as the gait deviation index (GDI), knee flexion angle, step length, and walking cadence, validated on a dataset of individuals with movement disorders. Notably, our approach surpasses state-of-the-art methods in various scenarios, using fewer resources and proving highly suitable for clinical application, particularly in resource-constrained environments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01689v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hiep Dinh, Son Le, My Than, Minh Ho, Nicolas Vuillerme, Hieu Pham</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VidFormer: A novel end-to-end framework fused by 3DCNN and Transformer for Video-based Remote Physiological Measurement</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01691</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01691v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Remote physiological signal measurement based on facial videos, also known as remote photoplethysmography (rPPG), involves predicting changes in facial vascular blood flow from facial videos. While most deep learning-based methods have achieved good results, they often struggle to balance performance across small and large-scale datasets due to the inherent limitations of convolutional neural networks (CNNs) and Transformer. In this paper, we introduce VidFormer, a novel end-to-end framework that integrates 3-Dimension Convolutional Neural Network (3DCNN) and Transformer models for rPPG tasks. Initially, we conduct an analysis of the traditional skin reflection model and subsequently introduce an enhanced model for the reconstruction of rPPG signals. Based on this improved model, VidFormer utilizes 3DCNN and Transformer to extract local and global features from input data, respectively. To enhance the spatiotemporal feature extraction capabilities of VidFormer, we incorporate temporal-spatial attention mechanisms tailored for both 3DCNN and Transformer. Additionally, we design a module to facilitate information exchange and fusion between the 3DCNN and Transformer. Our evaluation on five publicly available datasets demonstrates that VidFormer outperforms current state-of-the-art (SOTA) methods. Finally, we discuss the essential roles of each VidFormer module and examine the effects of ethnicity, makeup, and exercise on its performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01691v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiachen Li, Shisheng Guo, Longzhen Tang, Cuolong Cui, Lingjiang Kong, Xiaobo Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrossView-GS: Cross-view Gaussian Splatting For Large-scale Scene Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01695</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01695v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: 3D Gaussian Splatting (3DGS) has emerged as a prominent method for scene representation and reconstruction, leveraging densely distributed Gaussian primitives to enable real-time rendering of high-resolution images. While existing 3DGS methods perform well in scenes with minor view variation, large view changes in cross-view scenes pose optimization challenges for these methods. To address these issues, we propose a novel cross-view Gaussian Splatting method for large-scale scene reconstruction, based on dual-branch fusion. Our method independently reconstructs models from aerial and ground views as two independent branches to establish the baselines of Gaussian distribution, providing reliable priors for cross-view reconstruction during both initialization and densification. Specifically, a gradient-aware regularization strategy is introduced to mitigate smoothing issues caused by significant view disparities. Additionally, a unique Gaussian supplementation strategy is utilized to incorporate complementary information of dual-branch into the cross-view model. Extensive experiments on benchmark datasets demonstrate that our method achieves superior performance in novel view synthesis compared to state-of-the-art methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01695v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chenhao Zhang, Yuanping Cao, Lei Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robust Self-Paced Hashing for Cross-Modal Retrieval with Noisy Labels</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01699</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01699v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Cross-modal hashing (CMH) has appeared as a popular technique for cross-modal retrieval due to its low storage cost and high computational efficiency in large-scale data. Most existing methods implicitly assume that multi-modal data is correctly labeled, which is expensive and even unattainable due to the inevitable imperfect annotations (i.e., noisy labels) in real-world scenarios. Inspired by human cognitive learning, a few methods introduce self-paced learning (SPL) to gradually train the model from easy to hard samples, which is often used to mitigate the effects of feature noise or outliers. It is a less-touched problem that how to utilize SPL to alleviate the misleading of noisy labels on the hash model. To tackle this problem, we propose a new cognitive cross-modal retrieval method called Robust Self-paced Hashing with Noisy Labels (RSHNL), which can mimic the human cognitive process to identify the noise while embracing robustness against noisy labels. Specifically, we first propose a contrastive hashing learning (CHL) scheme to improve multi-modal consistency, thereby reducing the inherent semantic gap. Afterward, we propose center aggregation learning (CAL) to mitigate the intra-class variations. Finally, we propose Noise-tolerance Self-paced Hashing (NSH) that dynamically estimates the learning difficulty for each instance and distinguishes noisy labels through the difficulty level. For all estimated clean pairs, we further adopt a self-paced regularizer to gradually learn hash codes from easy to hard. Extensive experiments demonstrate that the proposed RSHNL performs remarkably well over the state-of-the-art CMH methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01699v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ruitao Pu, Yuan Sun, Yang Qin, Zhenwen Ren, Xiaomin Song, Huiming Zheng, Dezhong Peng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aesthetic Matters in Music Perception for Image Stylization: A Emotion-driven Music-to-Visual Manipulation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01700</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01700v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Emotional information is essential for enhancing human-computer interaction and deepening image understanding. However, while deep learning has advanced image recognition, the intuitive understanding and precise control of emotional expression in images remain challenging. Similarly, music research largely focuses on theoretical aspects, with limited exploration of its emotional dimensions and their integration with visual arts. To address these gaps, we introduce EmoMV, an emotion-driven music-to-visual manipulation method that manipulates images based on musical emotions. EmoMV combines bottom-up processing of music elements-such as pitch and rhythm-with top-down application of these emotions to visual aspects like color and lighting. We evaluate EmoMV using a multi-scale framework that includes image quality metrics, aesthetic assessments, and EEG measurements to capture real-time emotional responses. Our results demonstrate that EmoMV effectively translates music's emotional content into visually compelling images, advancing multimodal emotional integration and opening new avenues for creative industries and interactive technologies.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01700v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junjie Xu, Xingjiao Wu, Tanren Yao, Zihao Zhang, Jiayang Bei, Wu Wen, Liang He</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MoVE-KD: Knowledge Distillation for VLMs with Mixture of Visual Encoders</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01709</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01709v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Visual encoders are fundamental components in vision-language models (VLMs), each showcasing unique strengths derived from various pre-trained visual foundation models. To leverage the various capabilities of these encoders, recent studies incorporate multiple encoders within a single VLM, leading to a considerable increase in computational cost. In this paper, we present Mixture-of-Visual-Encoder Knowledge Distillation (MoVE-KD), a novel framework that distills the unique proficiencies of multiple vision encoders into a single, efficient encoder model. Specifically, to mitigate conflicts and retain the unique characteristics of each teacher encoder, we employ low-rank adaptation (LoRA) and mixture-of-experts (MoEs) to selectively activate specialized knowledge based on input features, enhancing both adaptability and efficiency. To regularize the KD process and enhance performance, we propose an attention-based distillation strategy that adaptively weighs the different visual encoders and emphasizes valuable visual tokens, reducing the burden of replicating comprehensive but distinct features from multiple teachers. Comprehensive experiments on popular VLMs, such as LLaVA and LLaVA-NeXT, validate the effectiveness of our method. The code will be released.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01709v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiajun Cao, Yuan Zhang, Tao Huang, Ming Lu, Qizhe Zhang, Ruichuan An, Ningning MA, Shanghang Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Large Vision Model in Street Scene Semantic Understanding through Leveraging Posterior Optimization Trajectory</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01710</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01710v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: To improve the generalization of the autonomous driving (AD) perception model, vehicles need to update the model over time based on the continuously collected data. As time progresses, the amount of data fitted by the AD model expands, which helps to improve the AD model generalization substantially. However, such ever-expanding data is a double-edged sword for the AD model. Specifically, as the fitted data volume grows to exceed the the AD model's fitting capacities, the AD model is prone to under-fitting. To address this issue, we propose to use a pretrained Large Vision Models (LVMs) as backbone coupled with downstream perception head to understand AD semantic information. This design can not only surmount the aforementioned under-fitting problem due to LVMs' powerful fitting capabilities, but also enhance the perception generalization thanks to LVMs' vast and diverse training data. On the other hand, to mitigate vehicles' computational burden of training the perception head while running LVM backbone, we introduce a Posterior Optimization Trajectory (POT)-Guided optimization scheme (POTGui) to accelerate the convergence. Concretely, we propose a POT Generator (POTGen) to generate posterior (future) optimization direction in advance to guide the current optimization iteration, through which the model can generally converge within 10 epochs. Extensive experiments demonstrate that the proposed method improves the performance by over 66.48\% and converges faster over 6 times, compared to the existing state-of-the-art approach.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01710v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wei-Bin Kou, Qingfeng Lin, Ming Tang, Shuai Wang, Rongguang Ye, Guangxu Zhu, Yik-Chung Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloth-Splatting: 3D Cloth State Estimation from RGB Supervision</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01715</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01715v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We introduce Cloth-Splatting, a method for estimating 3D states of cloth from RGB images through a prediction-update framework. Cloth-Splatting leverages an action-conditioned dynamics model for predicting future states and uses 3D Gaussian Splatting to update the predicted states. Our key insight is that coupling a 3D mesh-based representation with Gaussian Splatting allows us to define a differentiable map between the cloth state space and the image space. This enables the use of gradient-based optimization techniques to refine inaccurate state estimates using only RGB supervision. Our experiments demonstrate that Cloth-Splatting not only improves state estimation accuracy over current baselines but also reduces convergence time.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01715v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alberta Longhini, Marcel B\"usching, Bardienus P. Duisterhof, Jens Lundell, Jeffrey Ichnowski, M{\aa}rten Bj\"orkman, Danica Kragic</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KeyNode-Driven Geometry Coding for Real-World Scanned Human Dynamic Mesh Compression</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01717</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01717v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The compression of real-world scanned 3D human dynamic meshes is an emerging research area, driven by applications such as telepresence, virtual reality, and 3D digital streaming. Unlike synthesized dynamic meshes with fixed topology, scanned dynamic meshes often not only have varying topology across frames but also scan defects such as holes and outliers, increasing the complexity of prediction and compression. Additionally, human meshes often combine rigid and non-rigid motions, making accurate prediction and encoding significantly more difficult compared to objects that exhibit purely rigid motion. To address these challenges, we propose a compression method designed for real-world scanned human dynamic meshes, leveraging embedded key nodes. The temporal motion of each vertex is formulated as a distance-weighted combination of transformations from neighboring key nodes, requiring the transmission of solely the key nodes' transformations. To enhance the quality of the KeyNode-driven prediction, we introduce an octree-based residual coding scheme and a Dual-direction prediction mode, which uses I-frames from both directions. Extensive experiments demonstrate that our method achieves significant improvements over the state-of-the-art, with an average bitrate saving of 24.51% across the evaluated sequences, particularly excelling at low bitrates.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01717v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <category>eess.SP</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Huong Hoang, Truong Nguyen, Pamela Cosman</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interpretable Face Anti-Spoofing: Enhancing Generalization with Multimodal Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01720</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01720v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Face Anti-Spoofing (FAS) is essential for ensuring the security and reliability of facial recognition systems. Most existing FAS methods are formulated as binary classification tasks, providing confidence scores without interpretation. They exhibit limited generalization in out-of-domain scenarios, such as new environments or unseen spoofing types. In this work, we introduce a multimodal large language model (MLLM) framework for FAS, termed Interpretable Face Anti-Spoofing (I-FAS), which transforms the FAS task into an interpretable visual question answering (VQA) paradigm. Specifically, we propose a Spoof-aware Captioning and Filtering (SCF) strategy to generate high-quality captions for FAS images, enriching the model's supervision with natural language interpretations. To mitigate the impact of noisy captions during training, we develop a Lopsided Language Model (L-LM) loss function that separates loss calculations for judgment and interpretation, prioritizing the optimization of the former. Furthermore, to enhance the model's perception of global visual features, we design a Globally Aware Connector (GAC) to align multi-level visual representations with the language model. Extensive experiments on standard and newly devised One to Eleven cross-domain benchmarks, comprising 12 public datasets, demonstrate that our method significantly outperforms state-of-the-art methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01720v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Guosheng Zhang, Keyao Wang, Haixiao Yue, Ajian Liu, Gang Zhang, Kun Yao, Errui Ding, Jingdong Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AR4D: Autoregressive 4D Generation from Monocular Videos</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01722</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01722v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent advancements in generative models have ignited substantial interest in dynamic 3D content creation (\ie, 4D generation). Existing approaches primarily rely on Score Distillation Sampling (SDS) to infer novel-view videos, typically leading to issues such as limited diversity, spatial-temporal inconsistency and poor prompt alignment, due to the inherent randomness of SDS. To tackle these problems, we propose AR4D, a novel paradigm for SDS-free 4D generation. Specifically, our paradigm consists of three stages. To begin with, for a monocular video that is either generated or captured, we first utilize pre-trained expert models to create a 3D representation of the first frame, which is further fine-tuned to serve as the canonical space. Subsequently, motivated by the fact that videos happen naturally in an autoregressive manner, we propose to generate each frame's 3D representation based on its previous frame's representation, as this autoregressive generation manner can facilitate more accurate geometry and motion estimation. Meanwhile, to prevent overfitting during this process, we introduce a progressive view sampling strategy, utilizing priors from pre-trained large-scale 3D reconstruction models. To avoid appearance drift introduced by autoregressive generation, we further incorporate a refinement stage based on a global deformation field and the geometry of each frame's 3D representation. Extensive experiments have demonstrated that AR4D can achieve state-of-the-art 4D generation without SDS, delivering greater diversity, improved spatial-temporal consistency, and better alignment with input prompts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01722v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hanxin Zhu, Tianyu He, Xiqian Yu, Junliang Guo, Zhibo Chen, Jiang Bian</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IGAF: Incremental Guided Attention Fusion for Depth Super-Resolution</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01723</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01723v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Accurate depth estimation is crucial for many fields, including robotics, navigation, and medical imaging. However, conventional depth sensors often produce low-resolution (LR) depth maps, making detailed scene perception challenging. To address this, enhancing LR depth maps to high-resolution (HR) ones has become essential, guided by HR-structured inputs like RGB or grayscale images. We propose a novel sensor fusion methodology for guided depth super-resolution (GDSR), a technique that combines LR depth maps with HR images to estimate detailed HR depth maps. Our key contribution is the Incremental guided attention fusion (IGAF) module, which effectively learns to fuse features from RGB images and LR depth maps, producing accurate HR depth maps. Using IGAF, we build a robust super-resolution model and evaluate it on multiple benchmark datasets. Our model achieves state-of-the-art results compared to all baseline models on the NYU v2 dataset for $\times 4$, $\times 8$, and $\times 16$ upsampling. It also outperforms all baselines in a zero-shot setting on the Middlebury, Lu, and RGB-D-D datasets. Code, environments, and models are available on GitHub.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01723v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.3390/s25010024</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Sensors 2025, 25, 24</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Athanasios Tragakis, Chaitanya Kaul, Kevin J. Mitchell, Hang Dai, Roderick Murray-Smith, Daniele Faccio</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-modal classification of forest biodiversity potential from 2D orthophotos and 3D airborne laser scanning point clouds</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01728</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01728v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Accurate assessment of forest biodiversity is crucial for ecosystem management and conservation. While traditional field surveys provide high-quality assessments, they are labor-intensive and spatially limited. This study investigates whether deep learning-based fusion of close-range sensing data from 2D orthophotos (12.5 cm resolution) and 3D airborne laser scanning (ALS) point clouds (8 points/m^2) can enhance biodiversity assessment. We introduce the BioVista dataset, comprising 44.378 paired samples of orthophotos and ALS point clouds from temperate forests in Denmark, designed to explore multi-modal fusion approaches for biodiversity potential classification. Using deep neural networks (ResNet for orthophotos and PointVector for ALS point clouds), we investigate each data modality's ability to assess forest biodiversity potential, achieving mean accuracies of 69.4% and 72.8%, respectively. We explore two fusion approaches: a confidence-based ensemble method and a feature-level concatenation strategy, with the latter achieving a mean accuracy of 75.5%. Our results demonstrate that spectral information from orthophotos and structural information from ALS point clouds effectively complement each other in forest biodiversity assessment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01728v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Simon B. Jensen, Stefan Oehmcke, Andreas M{\o}gelmose, Meysam Madadi, Christian Igel, Sergio Escalera, Thomas B. Moeslund</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Augmentation Matters: A Mix-Paste Method for X-Ray Prohibited Item Detection under Noisy Annotations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01733</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01733v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Automatic X-ray prohibited item detection is vital for public safety. Existing deep learning-based methods all assume that the annotations of training X-ray images are correct. However, obtaining correct annotations is extremely hard if not impossible for large-scale X-ray images, where item overlapping is ubiquitous.As a result, X-ray images are easily contaminated with noisy annotations, leading to performance deterioration of existing methods.In this paper, we address the challenging problem of training a robust prohibited item detector under noisy annotations (including both category noise and bounding box noise) from a novel perspective of data augmentation, and propose an effective label-aware mixed patch paste augmentation method (Mix-Paste). Specifically, for each item patch, we mix several item patches with the same category label from different images and replace the original patch in the image with the mixed patch. In this way, the probability of containing the correct prohibited item within the generated image is increased. Meanwhile, the mixing process mimics item overlapping, enabling the model to learn the characteristics of X-ray images. Moreover, we design an item-based large-loss suppression (LLS) strategy to suppress the large losses corresponding to potentially positive predictions of additional items due to the mixing operation. We show the superiority of our method on X-ray datasets under noisy annotations. In addition, we evaluate our method on the noisy MS-COCO dataset to showcase its generalization ability. These results clearly indicate the great potential of data augmentation to handle noise annotations. The source code is released at https://github.com/wscds/Mix-Paste.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01733v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1109/TIFS.2024.3516546</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Ruikang Chen, Yan Yan, Jing-Hao Xue, Yang Lu, Hanzi Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Age Estimation to Age-Invariant Face Recognition: Generalized Age Feature Extraction Using Order-Enhanced Contrastive Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01760</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01760v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Generalized age feature extraction is crucial for age-related facial analysis tasks, such as age estimation and age-invariant face recognition (AIFR). Despite the recent successes of models in homogeneous-dataset experiments, their performance drops significantly in cross-dataset evaluations. Most of these models fail to extract generalized age features as they only attempt to map extracted features with training age labels directly without explicitly modeling the natural progression of aging. In this paper, we propose Order-Enhanced Contrastive Learning (OrdCon), which aims to extract generalized age features to minimize the domain gap across different datasets and scenarios. OrdCon aligns the direction vector of two features with either the natural aging direction or its reverse to effectively model the aging process. The method also leverages metric learning which is incorporated with a novel soft proxy matching loss to ensure that features are positioned around the center of each age cluster with minimum intra-class variance. We demonstrate that our proposed method achieves comparable results to state-of-the-art methods on various benchmark datasets in homogeneous-dataset evaluations for both age estimation and AIFR. In cross-dataset experiments, our method reduces the mean absolute error by about 1.38 in average for age estimation task and boosts the average accuracy for AIFR by 1.87%.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01760v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haoyi Wang, Victor Sanchez, Chang-Tsun Li, Nathan Clarke</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adverse Weather Conditions Augmentation of LiDAR Scenes with Latent Diffusion Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01761</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01761v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: LiDAR scenes constitute a fundamental source for several autonomous driving applications. Despite the existence of several datasets, scenes from adverse weather conditions are rarely available. This limits the robustness of downstream machine learning models, and restrains the reliability of autonomous driving systems in particular locations and seasons. Collecting feature-diverse scenes under adverse weather conditions is challenging due to seasonal limitations. Generative models are therefore essentials, especially for generating adverse weather conditions for specific driving scenarios. In our work, we propose a latent diffusion process constituted by autoencoder and latent diffusion models. Moreover, we leverage the clear condition LiDAR scenes with a postprocessing step to improve the realism of the generated adverse weather condition scenes.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01761v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Andrea Matteazzi, Pascal Colling, Michael Arnold, Dietmar Tutsch</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LogicAD: Explainable Anomaly Detection via VLM-based Text Feature Extraction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01767</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01767v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Logical image understanding involves interpreting and reasoning about the relationships and consistency within an image's visual content. This capability is essential in applications such as industrial inspection, where logical anomaly detection is critical for maintaining high-quality standards and minimizing costly recalls. Previous research in anomaly detection (AD) has relied on prior knowledge for designing algorithms, which often requires extensive manual annotations, significant computing power, and large amounts of data for training. Autoregressive, multimodal Vision Language Models (AVLMs) offer a promising alternative due to their exceptional performance in visual reasoning across various domains. Despite this, their application to logical AD remains unexplored. In this work, we investigate using AVLMs for logical AD and demonstrate that they are well-suited to the task. Combining AVLMs with format embedding and a logic reasoner, we achieve SOTA performance on public benchmarks, MVTec LOCO AD, with an AUROC of 86.0% and F1-max of 83.7%, along with explanations of anomalies. This significantly outperforms the existing SOTA method by a large margin.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01767v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Er Jin, Qihui Feng, Yongli Mou, Stefan Decker, Gerhard Lakemeyer, Oliver Simons, Johannes Stegmaier</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TCPFormer: Learning Temporal Correlation with Implicit Pose Proxy for 3D Human Pose Estimation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01770</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01770v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent multi-frame lifting methods have dominated the 3D human pose estimation. However, previous methods ignore the intricate dependence within the 2D pose sequence and learn single temporal correlation. To alleviate this limitation, we propose TCPFormer, which leverages an implicit pose proxy as an intermediate representation. Each proxy within the implicit pose proxy can build one temporal correlation therefore helping us learn more comprehensive temporal correlation of human motion. Specifically, our method consists of three key components: Proxy Update Module (PUM), Proxy Invocation Module (PIM), and Proxy Attention Module (PAM). PUM first uses pose features to update the implicit pose proxy, enabling it to store representative information from the pose sequence. PIM then invocates and integrates the pose proxy with the pose sequence to enhance the motion semantics of each pose. Finally, PAM leverages the above mapping between the pose sequence and pose proxy to enhance the temporal correlation of the whole pose sequence. Experiments on the Human3.6M and MPI-INF-3DHP datasets demonstrate that our proposed TCPFormer outperforms the previous state-of-the-art methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01770v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiajie Liu, Mengyuan Liu, Hong Liu, Wenhao Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ingredients: Blending Custom Photos with Video Diffusion Transformers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01790</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01790v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper presents a powerful framework to customize video creations by incorporating multiple specific identity (ID) photos, with video diffusion Transformers, referred to as \texttt{Ingredients}. Generally, our method consists of three primary modules: (\textbf{i}) a facial extractor that captures versatile and precise facial features for each human ID from both global and local perspectives; (\textbf{ii}) a multi-scale projector that maps face embeddings into the contextual space of image query in video diffusion transformers; (\textbf{iii}) an ID router that dynamically combines and allocates multiple ID embedding to the corresponding space-time regions. Leveraging a meticulously curated text-video dataset and a multi-stage training protocol, \texttt{Ingredients} demonstrates superior performance in turning custom photos into dynamic and personalized video content. Qualitative evaluations highlight the advantages of proposed method, positioning it as a significant advancement toward more effective generative video control tools in Transformer-based architecture, compared to existing methods. The data, code, and model weights are publicly available at: \url{https://github.com/feizc/Ingredients}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01790v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhengcong Fei, Debang Li, Di Qiu, Changqian Yu, Mingyuan Fan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Minimal Subset Approach for Efficient and Scalable Loop Closure</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01791</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01791v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Loop closure detection in large-scale and long-term missions can be computationally demanding due to the need to identify, verify, and process numerous candidate pairs to establish edge connections for the pose graph optimization. Keyframe sampling mitigates this by reducing the number of frames stored and processed in the back-end system. In this article, we address the gap in optimized keyframe sampling for the combined problem of pose graph optimization and loop closure detection. Our Minimal Subset Approach (MSA) employs an optimization strategy with two key factors, redundancy minimization and information preservation, within a sliding window framework to efficiently reduce redundant keyframes, while preserving essential information. This method delivers comparable performance to baseline approaches, while enhancing scalability and reducing computational overhead. Finally, we evaluate MSA on relevant publicly available datasets, showcasing that it consistently performs across a wide range of environments, without requiring any manual parameter tuning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01791v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nikolaos Stathoulopoulos, Christoforos Kanellakis, George Nikolakopoulos</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JoyGen: Audio-Driven 3D Depth-Aware Talking-Face Video Editing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01798</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01798v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Significant progress has been made in talking-face video generation research; however, precise lip-audio synchronization and high visual quality remain challenging in editing lip shapes based on input audio. This paper introduces JoyGen, a novel two-stage framework for talking-face generation, comprising audio-driven lip motion generation and visual appearance synthesis. In the first stage, a 3D reconstruction model and an audio2motion model predict identity and expression coefficients respectively. Next, by integrating audio features with a facial depth map, we provide comprehensive supervision for precise lip-audio synchronization in facial generation. Additionally, we constructed a Chinese talking-face dataset containing 130 hours of high-quality video. JoyGen is trained on the open-source HDTF dataset and our curated dataset. Experimental results demonstrate superior lip-audio synchronization and visual quality achieved by our method.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01798v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qili Wang, Dajiang Wu, Zihang Xu, Junshi Huang, Jun Lv</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MoEE: Mixture of Emotion Experts for Audio-Driven Portrait Animation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01808</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01808v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The generation of talking avatars has achieved significant advancements in precise audio synchronization. However, crafting lifelike talking head videos requires capturing a broad spectrum of emotions and subtle facial expressions. Current methods face fundamental challenges: a)the absence of frameworks for modeling single basic emotional expressions, which restricts the generation of complex emotions such as compound emotions; b)the lack of comprehensive datasets rich in human emotional expressions, which limits the potential of models. To address these challenges, we propose the following innovations: 1)the Mixture of Emotion Experts (MoEE) model, which decouples six fundamental emotions to enable the precise synthesis of both singular and compound emotional states; 2)the DH-FaceEmoVid-150 dataset, specifically curated to include six prevalent human emotional expressions as well as four types of compound emotions, thereby expanding the training potential of emotion-driven models. Furthermore, to enhance the flexibility of emotion control, we propose an emotion-to-latents module that leverages multimodal inputs, aligning diverse control signals-such as audio, text, and labels-to ensure more varied control inputs as well as the ability to control emotions using audio alone. Through extensive quantitative and qualitative evaluations, we demonstrate that the MoEE framework, in conjunction with the DH-FaceEmoVid-150 dataset, excels in generating complex emotional expressions and nuanced facial details, setting a new benchmark in the field. These datasets will be publicly released.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01808v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Huaize Liu, Wenzhang Sun, Donglin Di, Shibo Sun, Jiahui Yang, Changqing Zou, Hujun Bao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncertainty-Aware Label Refinement on Hypergraphs for Personalized Federated Facial Expression Recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01816</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01816v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Most facial expression recognition (FER) models are trained on large-scale expression data with centralized learning. Unfortunately, collecting a large amount of centralized expression data is difficult in practice due to privacy concerns of facial images. In this paper, we investigate FER under the framework of personalized federated learning, which is a valuable and practical decentralized setting for real-world applications. To this end, we develop a novel uncertainty-Aware label refineMent on hYpergraphs (AMY) method. For local training, each local model consists of a backbone, an uncertainty estimation (UE) block, and an expression classification (EC) block. In the UE block, we leverage a hypergraph to model complex high-order relationships between expression samples and incorporate these relationships into uncertainty features. A personalized uncertainty estimator is then introduced to estimate reliable uncertainty weights of samples in the local client. In the EC block, we perform label propagation on the hypergraph, obtaining high-quality refined labels for retraining an expression classifier. Based on the above, we effectively alleviate heterogeneous sample uncertainty across clients and learn a robust personalized FER model in each client. Experimental results on two challenging real-world facial expression databases show that our proposed method consistently outperforms several state-of-the-art methods. This indicates the superiority of hypergraph modeling for uncertainty estimation and label refinement on the personalized federated FER task. The source code will be released at https://github.com/mobei1006/AMY.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01816v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1109/TCSVT.2024.3513973 10.1109/TCSVT.2024.3513973 10.1109/TCSVT.2024.3513973</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems for Video Technology, 2024</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Hu Ding, Yan Yan, Yang Lu, Jing-Hao Xue, Hanzi Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MoColl: Agent-Based Specific and General Model Collaboration for Image Captioning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01834</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01834v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Image captioning is a critical task at the intersection of computer vision and natural language processing, with wide-ranging applications across various domains. For complex tasks such as diagnostic report generation, deep learning models require not only domain-specific image-caption datasets but also the incorporation of relevant general knowledge to provide contextual accuracy. Existing approaches exhibit inherent limitations: specialized models excel in capturing domain-specific details but lack generalization, while vision-language models (VLMs) built on large language models (LLMs) leverage general knowledge but struggle with domain-specific adaptation. To address these limitations, this paper proposes a novel agent-enhanced model collaboration framework, which we called \textbf{MoColl}, designed to effectively integrate domain-specific and general knowledge. Specifically, our approach is to decompose complex image captioning tasks into a series of interconnected question-answer subtasks. A trainable visual question answering (VQA) model is employed as a specialized tool to focus on domain-specific visual analysis, answering task-specific questions based on image content. Concurrently, an LLM-based agent with general knowledge formulates these questions and synthesizes the resulting question-answer pairs into coherent captions. Beyond its role in leveraging the VQA model, the agent further guides its training to enhance its domain-specific capabilities. Experimental results on radiology report generation validate the effectiveness of the proposed framework, demonstrating significant improvements in the quality of generated reports.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01834v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Pu Yang, Bin Dong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dedicated Inference Engine and Binary-Weight Neural Networks for Lightweight Instance Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01841</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01841v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Reducing computational costs is an important issue for development of embedded systems. Binary-weight Neural Networks (BNNs), in which weights are binarized and activations are quantized, are employed to reduce computational costs of various kinds of applications. In this paper, a design methodology of hardware architecture for inference engines is proposed to handle modern BNNs with two operation modes. Multiply-Accumulate (MAC) operations can be simplified by replacing multiply operations with bitwise operations. The proposed method can effectively reduce the gate count of inference engines by removing a part of computational costs from the hardware system. The architecture of MAC operations can calculate the inference results of BNNs efficiently with only 52% of hardware costs compared with the related works. To show that the inference engine can handle practical applications, two lightweight networks which combine the backbones of SegNeXt and the decoder of SparseInst for instance segmentation are also proposed. The output results of the lightweight networks are computed using only bitwise operations and add operations. The proposed inference engine has lower hardware costs than related works. The experimental results show that the proposed inference engine can handle the proposed instance-segmentation networks and achieves higher accuracy than YOLACT on the "Person" category although the model size is 77.7$\times$ smaller compared with YOLACT.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01841v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tse-Wei Chen, Wei Tao, Dongyue Zhao, Kazuhiro Mima, Tadayuki Ito, Kinya Osa, Masami Kato</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Segmentation for Sequential Historical Maps by Learning from Only One Map</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01845</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01845v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Historical maps are valuable resources that capture detailed geographical information from the past. However, these maps are typically available in printed formats, which are not conducive to modern computer-based analyses. Digitizing these maps into a machine-readable format enables efficient computational analysis. In this paper, we propose an automated approach to digitization using deep-learning-based semantic segmentation, which assigns a semantic label to each pixel in scanned historical maps. A key challenge in this process is the lack of ground-truth annotations required for training deep neural networks, as manual labeling is time-consuming and labor-intensive. To address this issue, we introduce a weakly-supervised age-tracing strategy for model fine-tuning. This approach exploits the similarity in appearance and land-use patterns between historical maps from neighboring time periods to guide the training process. Specifically, model predictions for one map are utilized as pseudo-labels for training on maps from adjacent time periods. Experiments conducted on our newly curated \textit{Hameln} dataset demonstrate that the proposed age-tracing strategy significantly enhances segmentation performance compared to baseline models. In the best-case scenario, the mean Intersection over Union (mIoU) achieved 77.3\%, reflecting an improvement of approximately 20\% over baseline methods. Additionally, the fine-tuned model achieved an average overall accuracy of 97\%, highlighting the effectiveness of our approach for digitizing historical maps.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01845v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yunshuang Yuan, Frank Thiemann, Monika Sester</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UAV-DETR: Efficient End-to-End Object Detection for Unmanned Aerial Vehicle Imagery</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01855</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01855v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Unmanned aerial vehicle object detection (UAV-OD) has been widely used in various scenarios. However, most existing UAV-OD algorithms rely on manually designed components, which require extensive tuning. End-to-end models that do not depend on such manually designed components are mainly designed for natural images, which are less effective for UAV imagery. To address such challenges, this paper proposes an efficient detection transformer (DETR) framework tailored for UAV imagery, i.e., UAV-DETR. The framework includes a multi-scale feature fusion with frequency enhancement module, which captures both spatial and frequency information at different scales. In addition, a frequency-focused down-sampling module is presented to retain critical spatial details during down-sampling. A semantic alignment and calibration module is developed to align and fuse features from different fusion paths. Experimental results demonstrate the effectiveness and generalization of our approach across various UAV imagery datasets. On the VisDrone dataset, our method improves AP by 3.1\% and $\text{AP}_{50}$ by 4.2\% over the baseline. Similar enhancements are observed on the UAVVaste dataset. The project page: https://github.com/ValiantDiligent/UAV-DETR</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01855v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Huaxiang Zhang, Kai Liu, Zhongxue Gan, Guo-Niu Zhu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Hard and Soft Shadow Removal via Dual-Branch Separation Network and Vision Transformer</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01864</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01864v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Image shadow removal is a crucial task in computer vision. In real-world scenes, shadows alter image color and brightness, posing challenges for perception and texture recognition. Traditional and deep learning methods often overlook the distinct needs for handling hard and soft shadows, thereby lacking detailed processing to specifically address each type of shadow in images.We propose a dual-path model that processes these shadows separately using specially designed loss functions to accomplish the hard and soft shadow removal. The model classifies shadow types and processes them through appropriate paths to produce shadow-free outputs, integrating a Vision Transformer with UNet++ for enhanced edge detail and feature fusion. Our model outperforms state-of-the-art methods and achieves 2.905 RMSE value on the ISTD dataset, which demonstrates greater effectiveness than typical single-path approaches.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01864v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiajia Liang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ANTHROPOS-V: benchmarking the novel task of Crowd Volume Estimation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01877</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01877v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We introduce the novel task of Crowd Volume Estimation (CVE), defined as the process of estimating the collective body volume of crowds using only RGB images. Besides event management and public safety, CVE can be instrumental in approximating body weight, unlocking weight sensitive applications such as infrastructure stress assessment, and assuring even weight balance. We propose the first benchmark for CVE, comprising ANTHROPOS-V, a synthetic photorealistic video dataset featuring crowds in diverse urban environments. Its annotations include each person's volume, SMPL shape parameters, and keypoints. Also, we explore metrics pertinent to CVE, define baseline models adapted from Human Mesh Recovery and Crowd Counting domains, and propose a CVE specific methodology that surpasses baselines. Although synthetic, the weights and heights of individuals are aligned with the real-world population distribution across genders, and they transfer to the downstream task of CVE from real images. Benchmark and code are available at github.com/colloroneluca/Crowd-Volume-Estimation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01877v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Luca Collorone, Stefano D'Arrigo, Massimiliano Pappa, Guido Maria D'Amely di Melendugno, Giovanni Ficarra, Fabio Galasso</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Virgo: A Preliminary Exploration on Reproducing o1-like MLLM</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01904</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01904v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recently, slow-thinking reasoning systems, built upon large language models (LLMs), have garnered widespread attention by scaling the thinking time during inference. There is also growing interest in adapting this capability to multimodal large language models (MLLMs). Given that MLLMs handle more complex data semantics across different modalities, it is intuitively more challenging to implement multimodal slow-thinking systems.
  To address this issue, in this paper, we explore a straightforward approach by fine-tuning a capable MLLM with a small amount of textual long-form thought data, resulting in a multimodal slow-thinking system, Virgo (Visual reasoning with long thought). We find that these long-form reasoning processes, expressed in natural language, can be effectively transferred to MLLMs. Moreover, it seems that such textual reasoning data can be even more effective than visual reasoning data in eliciting the slow-thinking capacities of MLLMs. While this work is preliminary, it demonstrates that slow-thinking capacities are fundamentally associated with the language model component, which can be transferred across modalities or domains. This finding can be leveraged to guide the development of more powerful slow-thinking reasoning systems. We release our resources at https://github.com/RUCAIBox/Virgo.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01904v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yifan Du, Zikang Liu, Yifan Li, Wayne Xin Zhao, Yuqi Huo, Bingning Wang, Weipeng Chen, Zheng Liu, Zhongyuan Wang, Ji-Rong Wen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Detecting and Mitigating Adversarial Attacks on Deep Learning-Based MRI Reconstruction Without Any Retraining</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01908</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01908v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Deep learning (DL) methods, especially those based on physics-driven DL, have become the state-of-the-art for reconstructing sub-sampled magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) data. However, studies have shown that these methods are susceptible to small adversarial input perturbations, or attacks, resulting in major distortions in the output images. Various strategies have been proposed to reduce the effects of these attacks, but they require retraining and may lower reconstruction quality for non-perturbed/clean inputs. In this work, we propose a novel approach for detecting and mitigating adversarial attacks on MRI reconstruction models without any retraining. Our detection strategy is based on the idea of cyclic measurement consistency. The output of the model is mapped to another set of MRI measurements for a different sub-sampling pattern, and this synthesized data is reconstructed with the same model. Intuitively, without an attack, the second reconstruction is expected to be consistent with the first, while with an attack, disruptions are present. Subsequently, this idea is extended to devise a novel objective function, which is minimized within a small ball around the attack input for mitigation. Experimental results show that our method substantially reduces the impact of adversarial perturbations across different datasets, attack types/strengths and PD-DL networks, and qualitatively and quantitatively outperforms conventional mitigation methods that involve retraining.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01908v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mahdi Saberi, Chi Zhang, Mehmet Akcakaya</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transformer-Driven Inverse Problem Transform for Fast Blind Hyperspectral Image Dehazing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01924</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01924v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Hyperspectral dehazing (HyDHZ) has become a crucial signal processing technology to facilitate the subsequent identification and classification tasks, as the airborne visible/infrared imaging spectrometer (AVIRIS) data portal reports a massive portion of haze-corrupted areas in typical hyperspectral remote sensing images. The idea of inverse problem transform (IPT) has been proposed in recent remote sensing literature in order to reformulate a hardly tractable inverse problem (e.g., HyDHZ) into a relatively simple one. Considering the emerging spectral super-resolution (SSR) technique, which spectrally upsamples multispectral data to hyperspectral data, we aim to solve the challenging HyDHZ problem by reformulating it as an SSR problem. Roughly speaking, the proposed algorithm first automatically selects some uncorrupted/informative spectral bands, from which SSR is applied to spectrally upsample the selected bands in the feature space, thereby obtaining a clean hyperspectral image (HSI). The clean HSI is then further refined by a deep transformer network to obtain the final dehazed HSI, where a global attention mechanism is designed to capture nonlocal information. There are very few HyDHZ works in existing literature, and this article introduces the powerful spatial-spectral transformer into HyDHZ for the first time. Remarkably, the proposed transformer-driven IPT-based HyDHZ (T2HyDHZ) is a blind algorithm without requiring the user to manually select the corrupted region. Extensive experiments demonstrate the superiority of T2HyDHZ with less color distortion.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01924v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1109/TGRS.2024.3349479</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Po-Wei Tang, Chia-Hsiang Lin, Yangrui Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mitigating Hallucination for Large Vision Language Model by Inter-Modality Correlation Calibration Decoding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01926</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01926v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large vision-language models (LVLMs) have shown remarkable capabilities in visual-language understanding for downstream multi-modal tasks. Despite their success, LVLMs still suffer from generating hallucinations in complex generation tasks, leading to inconsistencies between visual inputs and generated content. To address this issue, some approaches have introduced inference-time interventions, such as contrastive decoding and attention rectification, to reduce overreliance on language priors. However, these approaches overlook hallucinations stemming from spurious inter-modality correlations. In this paper, we propose an Inter-Modality Correlation Calibration Decoding (IMCCD) method to mitigate hallucinations in LVLMs in a training-free manner. In this method, we design a Cross-Modal Value-Enhanced Decoding(CMVED) module to alleviate hallucination by a novel contrastive decoding mechanism. During the estimation of distorted distribution, CMVED masks the value vectors associated with significant cross-modal attention weights, which address both uni-modality overreliance and misleading inter-modality correlations. Additionally, a Content-Driven Attention Refinement(CDAR) module refines cross-modal attention weights, guiding LVLMs to focus on important visual content. Experimental results on diverse hallucination benchmarks validate the superiority of our method over existing state-of-the-art techniques in reducing hallucinations in LVLM text generation. Our code will be available at https://github.com/lijm48/IMCCD.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01926v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiaming Li, Jiacheng Zhang, Zequn Jie, Lin Ma, Guanbin Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging Classification and Segmentation in Osteosarcoma Assessment via Foundation and Discrete Diffusion Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01932</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01932v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Osteosarcoma, the most common primary bone cancer, often requires accurate necrosis assessment from whole slide images (WSIs) for effective treatment planning and prognosis. However, manual assessments are subjective and prone to variability. In response, we introduce FDDM, a novel framework bridging the gap between patch classification and region-based segmentation. FDDM operates in two stages: patch-based classification, followed by region-based refinement, enabling cross-patch information intergation. Leveraging a newly curated dataset of osteosarcoma images, FDDM demonstrates superior segmentation performance, achieving up to a 10% improvement mIOU and a 32.12% enhancement in necrosis rate estimation over state-of-the-art methods. This framework sets a new benchmark in osteosarcoma assessment, highlighting the potential of foundation models and diffusion-based refinements in complex medical imaging tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01932v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Manh Duong Nguyen, Dac Thai Nguyen, Trung Viet Nguyen, Homi Yamada, Huy Hieu Pham, Phi Le Nguyen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VideoLifter: Lifting Videos to 3D with Fast Hierarchical Stereo Alignment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01949</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01949v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Efficiently reconstructing accurate 3D models from monocular video is a key challenge in computer vision, critical for advancing applications in virtual reality, robotics, and scene understanding. Existing approaches typically require pre-computed camera parameters and frame-by-frame reconstruction pipelines, which are prone to error accumulation and entail significant computational overhead. To address these limitations, we introduce VideoLifter, a novel framework that leverages geometric priors from a learnable model to incrementally optimize a globally sparse to dense 3D representation directly from video sequences. VideoLifter segments the video sequence into local windows, where it matches and registers frames, constructs consistent fragments, and aligns them hierarchically to produce a unified 3D model. By tracking and propagating sparse point correspondences across frames and fragments, VideoLifter incrementally refines camera poses and 3D structure, minimizing reprojection error for improved accuracy and robustness. This approach significantly accelerates the reconstruction process, reducing training time by over 82% while surpassing current state-of-the-art methods in visual fidelity and computational efficiency.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01949v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenyan Cong, Kevin Wang, Jiahui Lei, Colton Stearns, Yuanhao Cai, Dilin Wang, Rakesh Ranjan, Matt Feiszli, Leonidas Guibas, Zhangyang Wang, Weiyao Wang, Zhiwen Fan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VITA-1.5: Towards GPT-4o Level Real-Time Vision and Speech Interaction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01957</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01957v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) have typically focused on integrating visual and textual modalities, with less emphasis placed on the role of speech in enhancing interaction. However, speech plays a crucial role in multimodal dialogue systems, and implementing high-performance in both vision and speech tasks remains a significant challenge due to the fundamental modality differences. In this paper, we propose a carefully designed multi-stage training methodology that progressively trains LLM to understand both visual and speech information, ultimately enabling fluent vision and speech interaction. Our approach not only preserves strong vision-language capacity, but also enables efficient speech-to-speech dialogue capabilities without separate ASR and TTS modules, significantly accelerating multimodal end-to-end response speed. By comparing our method against state-of-the-art counterparts across benchmarks for image, video, and speech tasks, we demonstrate that our model is equipped with both strong visual and speech capabilities, making near real-time vision and speech interaction.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01957v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chaoyou Fu, Haojia Lin, Xiong Wang, Yi-Fan Zhang, Yunhang Shen, Xiaoyu Liu, Yangze Li, Zuwei Long, Heting Gao, Ke Li, Xiawu Zheng, Rongrong Ji, Xing Sun, Caifeng Shan, Ran He</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Real-Time Computational Visual Aberration Correcting Display Through High-Contrast Inverse Blurring</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01450</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01450v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This paper presents a framework for developing a live vision-correcting display (VCD) to address refractive visual aberrations without the need for traditional vision correction devices like glasses or contact lenses, particularly in scenarios where wearing them may be inconvenient. We achieve this correction through deconvolution of the displayed image using a point spread function (PSF) associated with the viewer's eye. We address ringing artefacts using a masking technique applied to the prefiltered image. We also enhance the display's contrast and reduce color distortion by operating in the YUV/YCbCr color space, where deconvolution is performed solely on the luma (brightness) channel. Finally, we introduce a technique to calculate a real-time PSF that adapts based on the viewer's spherical coordinates relative to the screen. This ensures that the PSF remains accurate and undistorted even when the viewer observes the display from an angle relative to the screen normal, thereby providing consistent visual correction regardless of the viewing angle. The results of our display demonstrate significant improvements in visual clarity, achieving a structural similarity index (SSIM) of 83.04%, highlighting the effectiveness of our approach.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01450v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Akhilesh Balaji, Dhruv Ramu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SS-CTML: Self-Supervised Cross-Task Mutual Learning for CT Image Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01456</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01456v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Supervised deep-learning (SDL) techniques with paired training datasets have been widely studied for X-ray computed tomography (CT) image reconstruction. However, due to the difficulties of obtaining paired training datasets in clinical routine, the SDL methods are still away from common uses in clinical practices. In recent years, self-supervised deep-learning (SSDL) techniques have shown great potential for the studies of CT image reconstruction. In this work, we propose a self-supervised cross-task mutual learning (SS-CTML) framework for CT image reconstruction. Specifically, a sparse-view scanned and a limited-view scanned sinogram data are first extracted from a full-view scanned sinogram data, which results in three individual reconstruction tasks, i.e., the full-view CT (FVCT) reconstruction, the sparse-view CT (SVCT) reconstruction, and limited-view CT (LVCT) reconstruction. Then, three neural networks are constructed for the three reconstruction tasks. Considering that the ultimate goals of the three tasks are all to reconstruct high-quality CT images, we therefore construct a set of cross-task mutual learning objectives for the three tasks, in which way, the three neural networks can be self-supervised optimized by learning from each other. Clinical datasets are adopted to evaluate the effectiveness of the proposed framework. Experimental results demonstrate that the SS-CTML framework can obtain promising CT image reconstruction performance in terms of both quantitative and qualitative measurements.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01456v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gaofeng Chen, Yaoduo Zhang, Li Huang, Pengfei Wang, Wenyu Zhang, Dong Zeng, Jianhua Ma, Ji He</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GDSR: Global-Detail Integration through Dual-Branch Network with Wavelet Losses for Remote Sensing Image Super-Resolution</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01460</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01460v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In recent years, deep neural networks, including Convolutional Neural Networks, Transformers, and State Space Models, have achieved significant progress in Remote Sensing Image (RSI) Super-Resolution (SR). However, existing SR methods typically overlook the complementary relationship between global and local dependencies. These methods either focus on capturing local information or prioritize global information, which results in models that are unable to effectively capture both global and local features simultaneously. Moreover, their computational cost becomes prohibitive when applied to large-scale RSIs. To address these challenges, we introduce the novel application of Receptance Weighted Key Value (RWKV) to RSI-SR, which captures long-range dependencies with linear complexity. To simultaneously model global and local features, we propose the Global-Detail dual-branch structure, GDSR, which performs SR reconstruction by paralleling RWKV and convolutional operations to handle large-scale RSIs. Furthermore, we introduce the Global-Detail Reconstruction Module (GDRM) as an intermediary between the two branches to bridge their complementary roles. In addition, we propose Wavelet Loss, a loss function that effectively captures high-frequency detail information in images, thereby enhancing the visual quality of SR, particularly in terms of detail reconstruction. Extensive experiments on several benchmarks, including AID, AID_CDM, RSSRD-QH, and RSSRD-QH_CDM, demonstrate that GSDR outperforms the state-of-the-art Transformer-based method HAT by an average of 0.05 dB in PSNR, while using only 63% of its parameters and 51% of its FLOPs, achieving an inference speed 2.9 times faster. Furthermore, the Wavelet Loss shows excellent generalization across various architectures, providing a novel perspective for RSI-SR enhancement.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01460v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qiwei Zhu, Kai Li, Guojing Zhang, Xiaoying Wang, Jianqiang Huang, Xilai Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Estimation of 3T MR images from 1.5T images regularized with Physics based Constraint</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01464</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01464v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Limited accessibility to high field MRI scanners (such as 7T, 11T) has motivated the development of post-processing methods to improve low field images. Several existing post-processing methods have shown the feasibility to improve 3T images to produce 7T-like images [3,18]. It has been observed that improving lower field (LF, &lt;=1.5T) images comes with additional challenges due to poor image quality such as the function mapping 1.5T and higher field (HF, 3T) images is more complex than the function relating 3T and 7T images [10]. Except for [10], no method has been addressed to improve &lt;=1.5T MRI images. Further, most of the existing methods [3,18] including [10] require example images, and also often rely on pixel to pixel correspondences between LF and HF images which are usually inaccurate for &lt;=1.5T images. The focus of this paper is to address the unsupervised framework for quality improvement of 1.5T images and avoid the expensive requirements of example images and associated image registration. The LF and HF images are assumed to be related by a linear transformation (LT). The unknown HF image and unknown LT are estimated in alternate minimization framework. Further, a physics based constraint is proposed that provides an additional non-linear function relating LF and HF images in order to achieve the desired high contrast in estimated HF image. The experimental results demonstrate that the proposed approach provides processed 1.5T images, i.e., estimated 3T-like images with improved image quality, and is comparably better than the existing methods addressing similar problems. The improvement in image quality is also shown to provide better tissue segmentation and volume quantification as compared to scanner acquired 1.5T images.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01464v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>physics.med-ph</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1007/978-3-031-43999-5_13</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Medical Image Computing and Computer Assisted Intervention - MICCAI 2023. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol 14229. Springer, Cham</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Prabhjot Kaur, Atul Singh Minhas, Chirag Kamal Ahuja, Anil Kumar Sao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tech Report: Divide and Conquer 3D Real-Time Reconstruction for Improved IGS</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01465</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01465v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Tracking surgical modifications based on endoscopic videos is technically feasible and of great clinical advantages; however, it still remains challenging. This report presents a modular pipeline to divide and conquer the clinical challenges in the process. The pipeline integrates frame selection, depth estimation, and 3D reconstruction components, allowing for flexibility and adaptability in incorporating new methods. Recent advancements, including the integration of Depth-Anything V2 and EndoDAC for depth estimation, as well as improvements in the Iterative Closest Point (ICP) alignment process, are detailed. Experiments conducted on the Hamlyn dataset demonstrate the effectiveness of the integrated methods. System capability and limitations are both discussed.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01465v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yicheng Zhu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unleashing Correlation and Continuity for Hyperspectral Reconstruction from RGB Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01481</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01481v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Reconstructing Hyperspectral Images (HSI) from RGB images can yield high spatial resolution HSI at a lower cost, demonstrating significant application potential. This paper reveals that local correlation and global continuity of the spectral characteristics are crucial for HSI reconstruction tasks. Therefore, we fully explore these inter-spectral relationships and propose a Correlation and Continuity Network (CCNet) for HSI reconstruction from RGB images. For the correlation of local spectrum, we introduce the Group-wise Spectral Correlation Modeling (GrSCM) module, which efficiently establishes spectral band similarity within a localized range. For the continuity of global spectrum, we design the Neighborhood-wise Spectral Continuity Modeling (NeSCM) module, which employs memory units to recursively model the progressive variation characteristics at the global level. In order to explore the inherent complementarity of these two modules, we design the Patch-wise Adaptive Fusion (PAF) module to efficiently integrate global continuity features into the spectral features in a patch-wise adaptive manner. These innovations enhance the quality of reconstructed HSI. We perform comprehensive comparison and ablation experiments on the mainstream datasets NTIRE2022 and NTIRE2020 for the spectral reconstruction task. Compared to the current advanced spectral reconstruction algorithms, our designed algorithm achieves State-Of-The-Art (SOTA) performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01481v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fuxiang Feng, Runmin Cong, Shoushui Wei, Yipeng Zhang, Jun Li, Sam Kwong, Wei Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An unsupervised method for MRI recovery: Deep image prior with structured sparsity</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01482</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01482v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Objective: To propose and validate an unsupervised MRI reconstruction method that does not require fully sampled k-space data. Materials and Methods: The proposed method, deep image prior with structured sparsity (DISCUS), extends the deep image prior (DIP) by introducing group sparsity to frame-specific code vectors, enabling the discovery of a low-dimensional manifold for capturing temporal variations. \discus was validated using four studies: (I) simulation of a dynamic Shepp-Logan phantom to demonstrate its manifold discovery capabilities, (II) comparison with compressed sensing and DIP-based methods using simulated single-shot late gadolinium enhancement (LGE) image series from six distinct digital cardiac phantoms in terms of normalized mean square error (NMSE) and structural similarity index measure (SSIM), (III) evaluation on retrospectively undersampled single-shot LGE data from eight patients, and (IV) evaluation on prospectively undersampled single-shot LGE data from eight patients, assessed via blind scoring from two expert readers. Results: DISCUS outperformed competing methods, demonstrating superior reconstruction quality in terms of NMSE and SSIM (Studies I--III) and expert reader scoring (Study IV). Discussion: An unsupervised image reconstruction method is presented and validated on simulated and measured data. These developments can benefit applications where acquiring fully sampled data is challenging.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01482v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>eess.SP</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Muhammad Ahmad Sultan, Chong Chen, Yingmin Liu, Katarzyna Gil, Karolina Zareba, Rizwan Ahmad</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Embedding Similarity Guided License Plate Super Resolution</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01483</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01483v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Super-resolution (SR) techniques play a pivotal role in enhancing the quality of low-resolution images, particularly for applications such as security and surveillance, where accurate license plate recognition is crucial. This study proposes a novel framework that combines pixel-based loss with embedding similarity learning to address the unique challenges of license plate super-resolution (LPSR). The introduced pixel and embedding consistency loss (PECL) integrates a Siamese network and applies contrastive loss to force embedding similarities to improve perceptual and structural fidelity. By effectively balancing pixel-wise accuracy with embedding-level consistency, the framework achieves superior alignment of fine-grained features between high-resolution (HR) and super-resolved (SR) license plates. Extensive experiments on the CCPD dataset validate the efficacy of the proposed framework, demonstrating consistent improvements over state-of-the-art methods in terms of PSNR_RGB, PSNR_Y and optical character recognition (OCR) accuracy. These results highlight the potential of embedding similarity learning to advance both perceptual quality and task-specific performance in extreme super-resolution scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01483v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Abderrezzaq Sendjasni, Mohamed-Chaker Larabi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crossing Language Borders: A Pipeline for Indonesian Manhwa Translation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01629</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01629v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In this project, we develop a practical and efficient solution for automating the Manhwa translation from Indonesian to English. Our approach combines computer vision, text recognition, and natural language processing techniques to streamline the traditionally manual process of Manhwa(Korean comics) translation. The pipeline includes fine-tuned YOLOv5xu for speech bubble detection, Tesseract for OCR and fine-tuned MarianMT for machine translation. By automating these steps, we aim to make Manhwa more accessible to a global audience while saving time and effort compared to manual translation methods. While most Manhwa translation efforts focus on Japanese-to-English, we focus on Indonesian-to-English translation to address the challenges of working with low-resource languages. Our model shows good results at each step and was able to translate from Indonesian to English efficiently.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01629v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nithyasri Narasimhan, Sagarika Singh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SNeRV: Spectra-preserving Neural Representation for Video</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01681</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01681v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Neural representation for video (NeRV), which employs a neural network to parameterize video signals, introduces a novel methodology in video representations. However, existing NeRV-based methods have difficulty in capturing fine spatial details and motion patterns due to spectral bias, in which a neural network learns high-frequency (HF) components at a slower rate than low-frequency (LF) components. In this paper, we propose spectra-preserving NeRV (SNeRV) as a novel approach to enhance implicit video representations by efficiently handling various frequency components. SNeRV uses 2D discrete wavelet transform (DWT) to decompose video into LF and HF features, preserving spatial structures and directly addressing the spectral bias issue. To balance the compactness, we encode only the LF components, while HF components that include fine textures are generated by a decoder. Specialized modules, including a multi-resolution fusion unit (MFU) and a high-frequency restorer (HFR), are integrated into a backbone to facilitate the representation. Furthermore, we extend SNeRV to effectively capture temporal correlations between adjacent video frames, by casting the extension as additional frequency decomposition to a temporal domain. This approach allows us to embed spatio-temporal LF features into the network, using temporally extended up-sampling blocks (TUBs). Experimental results demonstrate that SNeRV outperforms existing NeRV models in capturing fine details and achieves enhanced reconstruction, making it a promising approach in the field of implicit video representations. The codes are available at https://github.com/qwertja/SNeRV.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01681v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1007/978-3-031-73001-6_19</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Jina Kim, Jihoo Lee, Je-Won Kang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Fiducial Marker Placement for Satellite Proximity Operations Using Observability Gramians</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01704</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01704v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This paper investigates optimal fiducial marker placement on the surface of a satellite performing relative proximity operations with an observer satellite. The absolute and relative translation and attitude equations of motion for the satellite pair are modeled using dual quaternions. The observability of the relative dual quaternion system is analyzed using empirical observability Gramian methods. The optimal placement of a fiducial marker set, in which each marker gives simultaneous optical range and attitude measurements, is determined for the pair of satellites. A geostationary flyby between the observing body (chaser) and desired (target) satellites is numerically simulated and the optimal fiducial placement sets of five and ten on the surface of the desired satellite are solved. It is shown that the optimal solution maximizes the distance between fiducial markers and selects marker locations that are most sensitive to measuring changes in the state during the nonlinear trajectory, despite being visible for less time than other candidate marker locations. Definitions and properties of quaternions and dual quaternions, and parallels between the two, are presented alongside the relative motion model.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01704v1</guid>
      <category>eess.SY</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.SY</category>
      <category>math.OC</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nicholas B. Andrews, Kristi A. Morgansen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laparoscopic Scene Analysis for Intraoperative Visualisation of Gamma Probe Signals in Minimally Invasive Cancer Surgery</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01752</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01752v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Cancer remains a significant health challenge worldwide, with a new diagnosis occurring every two minutes in the UK. Surgery is one of the main treatment options for cancer. However, surgeons rely on the sense of touch and naked eye with limited use of pre-operative image data to directly guide the excision of cancerous tissues and metastases due to the lack of reliable intraoperative visualisation tools. This leads to increased costs and harm to the patient where the cancer is removed with positive margins, or where other critical structures are unintentionally impacted. There is therefore a pressing need for more reliable and accurate intraoperative visualisation tools for minimally invasive surgery to improve surgical outcomes and enhance patient care.
  A recent miniaturised cancer detection probe (i.e., SENSEI developed by Lightpoint Medical Ltd.) leverages the cancer-targeting ability of nuclear agents to more accurately identify cancer intra-operatively using the emitted gamma signal. However, the use of this probe presents a visualisation challenge as the probe is non-imaging and is air-gapped from the tissue, making it challenging for the surgeon to locate the probe-sensing area on the tissue surface. Geometrically, the sensing area is defined as the intersection point between the gamma probe axis and the tissue surface in 3D space but projected onto the 2D laparoscopic image. Hence, in this thesis, tool tracking, pose estimation, and segmentation tools were developed first, followed by laparoscope image depth estimation algorithms and 3D reconstruction methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01752v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>physics.med-ph</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Baoru Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compressed Domain Prior-Guided Video Super-Resolution for Cloud Gaming Content</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01773</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01773v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Cloud gaming is an advanced form of Internet service that necessitates local terminals to decode within limited resources and time latency. Super-Resolution (SR) techniques are often employed on these terminals as an efficient way to reduce the required bit-rate bandwidth for cloud gaming. However, insufficient attention has been paid to SR of compressed game video content. Most SR networks amplify block artifacts and ringing effects in decoded frames while ignoring edge details of game content, leading to unsatisfactory reconstruction results. In this paper, we propose a novel lightweight network called Coding Prior-Guided Super-Resolution (CPGSR) to address the SR challenges in compressed game video content. First, we design a Compressed Domain Guided Block (CDGB) to extract features of different depths from coding priors, which are subsequently integrated with features from the U-net backbone. Then, a series of re-parameterization blocks are utilized for reconstruction. Ultimately, inspired by the quantization in video coding, we propose a partitioned focal frequency loss to effectively guide the model's focus on preserving high-frequency information. Extensive experiments demonstrate the advancement of our approach.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01773v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qizhe Wang, Qian Yin, Zhimeng Huang, Weijia Jiang, Yi Su, Siwei Ma, Jiaqi Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Universal Online Temporal Calibration for Optimization-based Visual-Inertial Navigation Systems</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01788</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01788v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: 6-Degree of Freedom (6DoF) motion estimation with a combination of visual and inertial sensors is a growing area with numerous real-world applications. However, precise calibration of the time offset between these two sensor types is a prerequisite for accurate and robust tracking. To address this, we propose a universal online temporal calibration strategy for optimization-based visual-inertial navigation systems. Technically, we incorporate the time offset td as a state parameter in the optimization residual model to align the IMU state to the corresponding image timestamp using td, angular velocity and translational velocity. This allows the temporal misalignment td to be optimized alongside other tracking states during the process. As our method only modifies the structure of the residual model, it can be applied to various optimization-based frameworks with different tracking frontends. We evaluate our calibration method with both EuRoC and simulation data and extensive experiments demonstrate that our approach provides more accurate time offset estimation and faster convergence, particularly in the presence of noisy sensor data.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01788v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yunfei Fan, Tianyu Zhao, Linan Guo, Chen Chen, Xin Wang, Fengyi Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EnerVerse: Envisioning Embodied Future Space for Robotics Manipulation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01895</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01895v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We introduce EnerVerse, a comprehensive framework for embodied future space generation specifically designed for robotic manipulation tasks. EnerVerse seamlessly integrates convolutional and bidirectional attention mechanisms for inner-chunk space modeling, ensuring low-level consistency and continuity. Recognizing the inherent redundancy in video data, we propose a sparse memory context combined with a chunkwise unidirectional generative paradigm to enable the generation of infinitely long sequences. To further augment robotic capabilities, we introduce the Free Anchor View (FAV) space, which provides flexible perspectives to enhance observation and analysis. The FAV space mitigates motion modeling ambiguity, removes physical constraints in confined environments, and significantly improves the robot's generalization and adaptability across various tasks and settings. To address the prohibitive costs and labor intensity of acquiring multi-camera observations, we present a data engine pipeline that integrates a generative model with 4D Gaussian Splatting (4DGS). This pipeline leverages the generative model's robust generalization capabilities and the spatial constraints provided by 4DGS, enabling an iterative enhancement of data quality and diversity, thus creating a data flywheel effect that effectively narrows the sim-to-real gap. Finally, our experiments demonstrate that the embodied future space generation prior substantially enhances policy predictive capabilities, resulting in improved overall performance, particularly in long-range robotic manipulation tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01895v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Siyuan Huang, Liliang Chen, Pengfei Zhou, Shengcong Chen, Zhengkai Jiang, Yue Hu, Peng Gao, Hongsheng Li, Maoqing Yao, Guanghui Ren</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exoplanet Detection via Differentiable Rendering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01912</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01912v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Direct imaging of exoplanets is crucial for advancing our understanding of planetary systems beyond our solar system, but it faces significant challenges due to the high contrast between host stars and their planets. Wavefront aberrations introduce speckles in the telescope science images, which are patterns of diffracted starlight that can mimic the appearance of planets, complicating the detection of faint exoplanet signals. Traditional post-processing methods, operating primarily in the image intensity domain, do not integrate wavefront sensing data. These data, measured mainly for adaptive optics corrections, have been overlooked as a potential resource for post-processing, partly due to the challenge of the evolving nature of wavefront aberrations. In this paper, we present a differentiable rendering approach that leverages these wavefront sensing data to improve exoplanet detection. Our differentiable renderer models wave-based light propagation through a coronagraphic telescope system, allowing gradient-based optimization to significantly improve starlight subtraction and increase sensitivity to faint exoplanets. Simulation experiments based on the James Webb Space Telescope configuration demonstrate the effectiveness of our approach, achieving substantial improvements in contrast and planet detection limits. Our results showcase how the computational advancements enabled by differentiable rendering can revitalize previously underexploited wavefront data, opening new avenues for enhancing exoplanet imaging and characterization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01912v1</guid>
      <category>astro-ph.EP</category>
      <category>astro-ph.IM</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Brandon Y. Feng, Rodrigo Ferrer-Ch\'avez, Aviad Levis, Jason J. Wang, Katherine L. Bouman, William T. Freeman</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncertainty-Driven Action Quality Assessment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2207.14513</link>
      <description>arXiv:2207.14513v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Automatic action quality assessment (AQA) has attracted increasing attention due to its wide applications. However, most existing AQA methods employ deterministic models to predict the final score for each action, while overlooking the subjectivity and diversity among expert judges during the scoring process. In this paper, we propose a novel probabilistic model, named Uncertainty-Driven AQA (UD-AQA), to utilize and capture the diversity among multiple judge scores. Specifically, we design a Conditional Variational Auto-Encoder (CVAE)-based module to encode the uncertainty in expert assessment, where multiple judge scores can be produced by sampling latent features from the learned latent space multiple times. To further utilize the uncertainty, we generate the estimation of uncertainty for each prediction, which is employed to re-weight AQA regression loss, effectively reducing the influence of uncertain samples during training. Moreover, we further design an uncertainty-guided training strategy to dynamically adjust the learning order of the samples from low uncertainty to high uncertainty. The experiments show that our proposed method achieves competitive results on three benchmarks including the Olympic events MTL-AQA and FineDiving, and the surgical skill JIGSAWS datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2207.14513v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Caixia Zhou, Yaping Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Cross-Dataset Performance of Distracted Driving Detection With Score Softmax Classifier And Dynamic Gaussian Smoothing Supervision</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.05202</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.05202v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Deep neural networks enable real-time monitoring of in-vehicle drivers, facilitating the timely prediction of distractions, fatigue, and potential hazards. This technology is now integral to intelligent transportation systems. Recent research has exposed unreliable cross-dataset driver behavior recognition due to a limited number of data samples and background noise. In this paper, we propose a Score-Softmax classifier, which reduces the model overconfidence by enhancing category independence. Imitating the human scoring process, we designed a two-dimensional dynamic supervisory matrix consisting of one-dimensional Gaussian-smoothed labels. The dynamic loss descent direction and Gaussian smoothing increase the uncertainty of training to prevent the model from falling into noise traps. Furthermore, we introduce a simple and convenient multi-channel information fusion method;it addresses the fusion issue among arbitrary Score-Softmax classification heads. We conducted cross-dataset experiments using the SFDDD, AUCDD, and the 100-Driver datasets, demonstrating that Score-Softmax improves cross-dataset performance without modifying the model architecture. The experiments indicate that the Score-Softmax classifier reduces the interference of background noise, enhancing the robustness of the model. It increases the cross-dataset accuracy by 21.34%, 11.89%, and 18.77% on the three datasets, respectively. The code is publicly available at https://github.com/congduan-HNU/SSoftmax.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.05202v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1109/TIV.2024.3412198</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Cong Duan, Zixuan Liu, Jiahao Xia, Minghai Zhang, Jiacai Liao, Libo Cao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Globally Scalable Glacier Mapping by Deep Learning Matches Expert Delineation Accuracy</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.15113</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.15113v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Accurate global glacier mapping is critical for understanding climate change impacts. Despite its importance, automated glacier mapping at a global scale remains largely unexplored. Here we address this gap and propose Glacier-VisionTransformer-U-Net (GlaViTU), a convolutional-transformer deep learning model, and five strategies for multitemporal global-scale glacier mapping using open satellite imagery. Assessing the spatial, temporal and cross-sensor generalisation shows that our best strategy achieves intersection over union &gt;0.85 on previously unobserved images in most cases, which drops to &gt;0.75 for debris-rich areas such as High-Mountain Asia and increases to &gt;0.90 for regions dominated by clean ice. A comparative validation against human expert uncertainties in terms of area and distance deviations underscores GlaViTU performance, approaching or matching expert-level delineation. Adding synthetic aperture radar data, namely, backscatter and interferometric coherence, increases the accuracy in all regions where available. The calibrated confidence for glacier extents is reported making the predictions more reliable and interpretable. We also release a benchmark dataset that covers 9% of glaciers worldwide. Our results support efforts towards automated multitemporal and global glacier mapping.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.15113v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1038/s41467-024-54956-x</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Nat Commun 16, 43 (2025)</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Konstantin A. Maslov, Claudio Persello, Thomas Schellenberger, Alfred Stein</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S-NeRF++: Autonomous Driving Simulation via Neural Reconstruction and Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.02112</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.02112v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Autonomous driving simulation system plays a crucial role in enhancing self-driving data and simulating complex and rare traffic scenarios, ensuring navigation safety. However, traditional simulation systems, which often heavily rely on manual modeling and 2D image editing, struggled with scaling to extensive scenes and generating realistic simulation data. In this study, we present S-NeRF++, an innovative autonomous driving simulation system based on neural reconstruction. Trained on widely-used self-driving datasets such as nuScenes and Waymo, S-NeRF++ can generate a large number of realistic street scenes and foreground objects with high rendering quality as well as offering considerable flexibility in manipulation and simulation. Specifically, S-NeRF++ is an enhanced neural radiance field for synthesizing large-scale scenes and moving vehicles, with improved scene parameterization and camera pose learning. The system effectively utilizes noisy and sparse LiDAR data to refine training and address depth outliers, ensuring high-quality reconstruction and novel-view rendering. It also provides a diverse foreground asset bank by reconstructing and generating different foreground vehicles to support comprehensive scenario creation.Moreover, we have developed an advanced foreground-background fusion pipeline that skillfully integrates illumination and shadow effects, further enhancing the realism of our simulations. With the high-quality simulated data provided by our S-NeRF++, we found the perception methods enjoy performance boosts on several autonomous driving downstream tasks, further demonstrating our proposed simulator's effectiveness.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.02112v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yurui Chen, Junge Zhang, Ziyang Xie, Wenye Li, Feihu Zhang, Jiachen Lu, Li Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spiking-PhysFormer: Camera-Based Remote Photoplethysmography with Parallel Spike-driven Transformer</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.04798</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.04798v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Artificial neural networks (ANNs) can help camera-based remote photoplethysmography (rPPG) in measuring cardiac activity and physiological signals from facial videos, such as pulse wave, heart rate and respiration rate with better accuracy. However, most existing ANN-based methods require substantial computing resources, which poses challenges for effective deployment on mobile devices. Spiking neural networks (SNNs), on the other hand, hold immense potential for energy-efficient deep learning owing to their binary and event-driven architecture. To the best of our knowledge, we are the first to introduce SNNs into the realm of rPPG, proposing a hybrid neural network (HNN) model, the Spiking-PhysFormer, aimed at reducing power consumption. Specifically, the proposed Spiking-PhyFormer consists of an ANN-based patch embedding block, SNN-based transformer blocks, and an ANN-based predictor head. First, to simplify the transformer block while preserving its capacity to aggregate local and global spatio-temporal features, we design a parallel spike transformer block to replace sequential sub-blocks. Additionally, we propose a simplified spiking self-attention mechanism that omits the value parameter without compromising the model's performance. Experiments conducted on four datasets-PURE, UBFC-rPPG, UBFC-Phys, and MMPD demonstrate that the proposed model achieves a 12.4\% reduction in power consumption compared to PhysFormer. Additionally, the power consumption of the transformer block is reduced by a factor of 12.2, while maintaining decent performance as PhysFormer and other ANN-based models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.04798v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mingxuan Liu, Jiankai Tang, Yongli Chen, Haoxiang Li, Jiahao Qi, Siwei Li, Kegang Wang, Jie Gan, Yuntao Wang, Hong Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Scale Denoising in the Feature Space for Low-Light Instance Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18307</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.18307v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Instance segmentation for low-light imagery remains largely unexplored due to the challenges imposed by such conditions, for example shot noise due to low photon count, color distortions and reduced contrast. In this paper, we propose an end-to-end solution to address this challenging task. Our proposed method implements weighted non-local blocks (wNLB) in the feature extractor. This integration enables an inherent denoising process at the feature level. As a result, our method eliminates the need for aligned ground truth images during training, thus supporting training on real-world low-light datasets. We introduce additional learnable weights at each layer in order to enhance the network's adaptability to real-world noise characteristics, which affect different feature scales in different ways. Experimental results on several object detectors show that the proposed method outperforms the pretrained networks with an Average Precision (AP) improvement of at least +7.6, with the introduction of wNLB further enhancing AP by upto +1.3.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.18307v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Joanne Lin, Nantheera Anantrasirichai, David Bull</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ViiNeuS: Volumetric Initialization for Implicit Neural Surface reconstruction of urban scenes with limited image overlap</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.10344</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.10344v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Neural implicit surface representation methods have recently shown impressive 3D reconstruction results. However, existing solutions struggle to reconstruct driving scenes due to their large size, highly complex nature and their limited visual observation overlap. Hence, to achieve accurate reconstructions, additional supervision data such as LiDAR, strong geometric priors, and long training times are required. To tackle such limitations, we present ViiNeuS, a new hybrid implicit surface learning method that efficiently initializes the signed distance field to reconstruct large driving scenes from 2D street view images. ViiNeuS's hybrid architecture models two separate implicit fields: one representing the volumetric density of the scene, and another one representing the signed distance to the surface. To accurately reconstruct urban outdoor driving scenarios, we introduce a novel volume-rendering strategy that relies on self-supervised probabilistic density estimation to sample points near the surface and transition progressively from volumetric to surface representation. Our solution permits a proper and fast initialization of the signed distance field without relying on any geometric prior on the scene, compared to concurrent methods. By conducting extensive experiments on four outdoor driving datasets, we show that ViiNeuS can learn an accurate and detailed 3D surface representation of various urban scene while being two times faster to train compared to previous state-of-the-art solutions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.10344v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hala Djeghim, Nathan Piasco, Moussab Bennehar, Luis Rold\~ao, Dzmitry Tsishkou, D\'esir\'e Sidib\'e</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pushing the Boundaries of Text to Motion with Arbitrary Text: A New Task</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.14745</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.14745v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Text to Motion aims to generate human motions from texts. Existing settings rely on limited Action Texts that include action labels, which limits flexibility and practicability in scenarios difficult to describe directly. This paper extends limited Action Texts to arbitrary ones. Scene texts without explicit action labels can enhance the practicality of models in complex and diverse industries such as virtual human interaction, robot behavior generation, and film production, while also supporting the exploration of potential implicit behavior patterns. However, newly introduced Scene Texts may yield multiple reasonable output results, causing significant challenges in existing data, framework, and evaluation. To address this practical issue, we first create a new dataset HUMANML3D++ by extending texts of the largest existing dataset HUMANML3D. Secondly, we propose a simple yet effective framework that extracts action instructions from arbitrary texts and subsequently generates motions. Furthermore, we also benchmark this new setting with multi-solution metrics to address the inadequacies of existing single-solution metrics. Extensive experiments indicate that Text to Motion in this realistic setting is challenging, fostering new research in this practical direction.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.14745v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Runqi Wang, Caoyuan Ma, Guopeng Li, Hanrui Xu, Yuke Li, Zheng Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metric3Dv2: A Versatile Monocular Geometric Foundation Model for Zero-shot Metric Depth and Surface Normal Estimation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.15506</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.15506v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We introduce Metric3D v2, a geometric foundation model for zero-shot metric depth and surface normal estimation from a single image, which is crucial for metric 3D recovery. While depth and normal are geometrically related and highly complimentary, they present distinct challenges. SoTA monocular depth methods achieve zero-shot generalization by learning affine-invariant depths, which cannot recover real-world metrics. Meanwhile, SoTA normal estimation methods have limited zero-shot performance due to the lack of large-scale labeled data. To tackle these issues, we propose solutions for both metric depth estimation and surface normal estimation. For metric depth estimation, we show that the key to a zero-shot single-view model lies in resolving the metric ambiguity from various camera models and large-scale data training. We propose a canonical camera space transformation module, which explicitly addresses the ambiguity problem and can be effortlessly plugged into existing monocular models. For surface normal estimation, we propose a joint depth-normal optimization module to distill diverse data knowledge from metric depth, enabling normal estimators to learn beyond normal labels. Equipped with these modules, our depth-normal models can be stably trained with over 16 million of images from thousands of camera models with different-type annotations, resulting in zero-shot generalization to in-the-wild images with unseen camera settings. Our method enables the accurate recovery of metric 3D structures on randomly collected internet images, paving the way for plausible single-image metrology. Our project page is at https://JUGGHM.github.io/Metric3Dv2.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.15506v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1109/TPAMI.2024.3444912</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence, vol. 46, no. 12, pp. 10579-10596, 2024</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Mu Hu, Wei Yin, Chi Zhang, Zhipeng Cai, Xiaoxiao Long, Kaixuan Wang, Hao Chen, Gang Yu, Chunhua Shen, Shaojie Shen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Salient Patch Identification for Interpretable Fundus Disease Localization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.14334</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.14334v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: With the widespread application of deep learning technology in medical image analysis, the effective explanation of model predictions and improvement of diagnostic accuracy have become urgent problems that need to be solved. Attribution methods have become key tools to help doctors better understand the diagnostic basis of models, and are used to explain and localize diseases in medical images. However, previous methods suffer from inaccurate and incomplete localization problems for fundus diseases with complex and diverse structures. To solve these problems, we propose a weakly supervised interpretable fundus disease localization method called hierarchical salient patch identification (HSPI) that can achieve interpretable disease localization using only image-level labels and a neural network classifier (NNC). First, we propose salient patch identification (SPI), which divides the image into several patches and optimizes consistency loss to identify which patch in the input image is most important for the network's prediction, in order to locate the disease. Second, we propose a hierarchical identification strategy to force SPI to analyze the importance of different areas to neural network classifier's prediction to comprehensively locate disease areas. Conditional peak focusing is then introduced to ensure that the mask vector can accurately locate the disease area. Finally, we propose patch selection based on multi-sized intersections to filter out incorrectly or additionally identified non-disease regions. We conduct disease localization experiments on fundus image datasets and achieve the best performance on multiple evaluation metrics compared to previous interpretable attribution methods. Additional ablation studies are conducted to verify the effectiveness of each method.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.14334v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>IEEE BIBM 2024</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Yitao Peng, Lianghua He, Die Hu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flow Priors for Linear Inverse Problems via Iterative Corrupted Trajectory Matching</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.18816</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.18816v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Generative models based on flow matching have attracted significant attention for their simplicity and superior performance in high-resolution image synthesis. By leveraging the instantaneous change-of-variables formula, one can directly compute image likelihoods from a learned flow, making them enticing candidates as priors for downstream tasks such as inverse problems. In particular, a natural approach would be to incorporate such image probabilities in a maximum-a-posteriori (MAP) estimation problem. A major obstacle, however, lies in the slow computation of the log-likelihood, as it requires backpropagating through an ODE solver, which can be prohibitively slow for high-dimensional problems. In this work, we propose an iterative algorithm to approximate the MAP estimator efficiently to solve a variety of linear inverse problems. Our algorithm is mathematically justified by the observation that the MAP objective can be approximated by a sum of $N$ ``local MAP'' objectives, where $N$ is the number of function evaluations. By leveraging Tweedie's formula, we show that we can perform gradient steps to sequentially optimize these objectives. We validate our approach for various linear inverse problems, such as super-resolution, deblurring, inpainting, and compressed sensing, and demonstrate that we can outperform other methods based on flow matching. Code is available at https://github.com/YasminZhang/ICTM.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.18816v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yasi Zhang, Peiyu Yu, Yaxuan Zhu, Yingshan Chang, Feng Gao, Ying Nian Wu, Oscar Leong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PAFUSE: Part-based Diffusion for 3D Whole-Body Pose Estimation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10220</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.10220v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We introduce a novel approach for 3D whole-body pose estimation, addressing the challenge of scale -- and deformability -- variance across body parts brought by the challenge of extending the 17 major joints on the human body to fine-grained keypoints on the face and hands. In addition to addressing the challenge of exploiting motion in unevenly sampled data, we combine stable diffusion to a hierarchical part representation which predicts the relative locations of fine-grained keypoints within each part (e.g., face) with respect to the part's local reference frame. On the H3WB dataset, our method greatly outperforms the current state of the art, which fails to exploit the temporal information. We also show considerable improvements compared to other spatiotemporal 3D human-pose estimation approaches that fail to account for the body part specificities. Code is available at https://github.com/valeoai/PAFUSE.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.10220v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nermin Samet, C\'edric Rommel, David Picard, Eduardo Valle</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Balanced Residual Distillation Learning for 3D Point Cloud Class-Incremental Semantic Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.01356</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.01356v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Class-incremental learning (CIL) enables continuous learning of new classes while mitigating catastrophic forgetting of old ones. For the performance breakthrough of CIL, it is essential yet challenging to effectively refine past knowledge from the base model and balance it with new learning. However, such a challenge has not been considered in current research. This work proposes a balanced residual distillation learning framework (BRDL) to address this gap and advance CIL performance. BRDL introduces a residual distillation strategy to dynamically refine past knowledge by expanding the network structure and a balanced pseudo-label learning strategy to mitigate class bias and balance learning between old and new classes. We apply the proposed BRDL to a challenging 3D point cloud semantic segmentation task where the data is unordered and unstructured. Extensive experimental results demonstrate that BRDL sets a new benchmark with an outstanding balance capability in class-biased scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.01356v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuanzhi Su, Siyuan Chen, Yuan-Gen Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prompt-Based Segmentation at Multiple Resolutions and Lighting Conditions using Segment Anything Model 2</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06970</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06970v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper provides insights on the effectiveness of the zero shot, prompt-based Segment Anything Model (SAM) and its updated versions, SAM 2 and SAM 2.1, along with the non-promptable conventional neural network (CNN), for segmenting solar panels in RGB aerial remote sensing imagery. The study evaluates these models across diverse lighting conditions, spatial resolutions, and prompt strategies. SAM 2 showed slight improvements over SAM, while SAM 2.1 demonstrated notable improvements, particularly in sub-optimal lighting and low resolution conditions. SAM models, when prompted by user-defined boxes, outperformed CNN in all scenarios; in particular, user-box prompts were found crucial for achieving reasonable performance in low resolution data. Additionally, under high resolution, YOLOv9 automatic prompting outperformed user-points prompting by providing reliable prompts to SAM. Under low resolution, SAM 2.1 prompted by user points showed similar performance to SAM 2.1 prompted by YOLOv9, highlighting its zero shot improvements with a single click. In high resolution with optimal lighting imagery, Eff-UNet outperformed SAMs prompted by YOLOv9, while under sub-optimal lighting conditions, Eff-UNet, and SAM 2.1 prompted by YOLOv9, had similar performance. However, SAM is more resource-intensive, and despite improved inference time of SAM 2.1, Eff-UNet is more suitable for automatic segmentation in high resolution data. This research details strengths and limitations of each model and outlines the robustness of user-prompted image segmentation models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06970v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Osher Rafaeli, Tal Svoray, Roni Blushtein-Livnon, Ariel Nahlieli</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attribution Analysis Meets Model Editing: Advancing Knowledge Correction in Vision Language Models with VisEdit</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09916</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.09916v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Model editing aims to correct outdated or erroneous knowledge in large models without costly retraining. Recent research discovered that the mid-layer representation of the subject's final token in a prompt has a strong influence on factual predictions, and developed Large Language Model (LLM) editing techniques based on this observation. However, for Vision-LLMs (VLLMs), how visual representations impact the predictions from a decoder-only language model remains largely unexplored. To the best of our knowledge, model editing for VLLMs has not been extensively studied in the literature. In this work, we employ the contribution allocation and noise perturbation methods to measure the contributions of visual representations for token predictions. Our attribution analysis shows that visual representations in mid-to-later layers that are highly relevant to the prompt contribute significantly to predictions. Based on these insights, we propose VisEdit, a novel model editor for VLLMs that effectively corrects knowledge by editing intermediate visual representations in regions important to the edit prompt. We evaluated VisEdit using multiple VLLM backbones and public VLLM editing benchmark datasets. The results show the superiority of VisEdit over the strong baselines adapted from existing state-of-the-art editors for LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.09916v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qizhou Chen, Taolin Zhang, Chengyu Wang, Xiaofeng He, Dakan Wang, Tingting Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward Robust Early Detection of Alzheimer's Disease via an Integrated Multimodal Learning Approach</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.16343</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.16343v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Alzheimer's Disease (AD) is a complex neurodegenerative disorder marked by memory loss, executive dysfunction, and personality changes. Early diagnosis is challenging due to subtle symptoms and varied presentations, often leading to misdiagnosis with traditional unimodal diagnostic methods due to their limited scope. This study introduces an advanced multimodal classification model that integrates clinical, cognitive, neuroimaging, and EEG data to enhance diagnostic accuracy. The model incorporates a feature tagger with a tabular data coding architecture and utilizes the TimesBlock module to capture intricate temporal patterns in Electroencephalograms (EEG) data. By employing Cross-modal Attention Aggregation module, the model effectively fuses Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) spatial information with EEG temporal data, significantly improving the distinction between AD, Mild Cognitive Impairment, and Normal Cognition. Simultaneously, we have constructed the first AD classification dataset that includes three modalities: EEG, MRI, and tabular data. Our innovative approach aims to facilitate early diagnosis and intervention, potentially slowing the progression of AD. The source code and our private ADMC dataset are available at https://github.com/JustlfC03/MSTNet.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.16343v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>ICASSP 2025</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Yifei Chen, Shenghao Zhu, Zhaojie Fang, Chang Liu, Binfeng Zou, Yuhe Wang, Shuo Chang, Fan Jia, Feiwei Qin, Jin Fan, Yong Peng, Changmiao Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generic Objects as Pose Probes for Few-shot View Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.16690</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.16690v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Radiance fields including NeRFs and 3D Gaussians demonstrate great potential in high-fidelity rendering and scene reconstruction, while they require a substantial number of posed images as inputs. COLMAP is frequently employed for preprocessing to estimate poses, while it necessitates a large number of feature matches to operate effectively, and it struggles with scenes characterized by sparse features, large baselines between images, or a limited number of input images. We aim to tackle few-view NeRF reconstruction using only 3 to 6 unposed scene images. Traditional methods often use calibration boards but they are not common in images. We propose a novel idea of utilizing everyday objects, commonly found in both images and real life, as "pose probes". The probe object is automatically segmented by SAM, whose shape is initialized from a cube. We apply a dual-branch volume rendering optimization (object NeRF and scene NeRF) to constrain the pose optimization and jointly refine the geometry. Specifically, object poses of two views are first estimated by PnP matching in an SDF representation, which serves as initial poses. PnP matching, requiring only a few features, is suitable for feature-sparse scenes. Additional views are incrementally incorporated to refine poses from preceding views. In experiments, PoseProbe achieves state-of-the-art performance in both pose estimation and novel view synthesis across multiple datasets. We demonstrate its effectiveness, particularly in few-view and large-baseline scenes where COLMAP struggles. In ablations, using different objects in a scene yields comparable performance. Our project page is available at: \href{https://zhirui-gao.github.io/PoseProbe.github.io/}{this https URL}</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.16690v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhirui Gao, Renjiao Yi, Chenyang Zhu, Ke Zhuang, Wei Chen, Kai Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FUSED-Net: Detecting Traffic Signs with Limited Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.14852</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.14852v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Automatic Traffic Sign Recognition is paramount in modern transportation systems, motivating several research endeavors to focus on performance improvement by utilizing large-scale datasets. As the appearance of traffic signs varies across countries, curating large-scale datasets is often impractical; and requires efficient models that can produce satisfactory performance using limited data. In this connection, we present 'FUSED-Net', built-upon Faster RCNN for traffic sign detection, enhanced by Unfrozen Parameters, Pseudo-Support Sets, Embedding Normalization, and Domain Adaptation while reducing data requirement. Unlike traditional approaches, we keep all parameters unfrozen during training, enabling FUSED-Net to learn from limited samples. The generation of a Pseudo-Support Set through data augmentation further enhances performance by compensating for the scarcity of target domain data. Additionally, Embedding Normalization is incorporated to reduce intra-class variance, standardizing feature representation. Domain Adaptation, achieved by pre-training on a diverse traffic sign dataset distinct from the target domain, improves model generalization. Evaluating FUSED-Net on the BDTSD dataset, we achieved 2.4x, 2.2x, 1.5x, and 1.3x improvements of mAP in 1-shot, 3-shot, 5-shot, and 10-shot scenarios, respectively compared to the state-of-the-art Few-Shot Object Detection (FSOD) models. Additionally, we outperform state-of-the-art works on the cross-domain FSOD benchmark under several scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.14852v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Md. Atiqur Rahman, Nahian Ibn Asad, Md. Mushfiqul Haque Omi, Md. Bakhtiar Hasan, Sabbir Ahmed, Md. Hasanul Kabir</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EventHallusion: Diagnosing Event Hallucinations in Video LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.16597</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.16597v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recently, Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) have made significant progress in the video comprehension field. Despite remarkable content reasoning and instruction following capabilities they demonstrated, the hallucination problem of these VideoLLMs is less explored compared with its counterpart in the image domain. To mitigate this gap, we propose EventHallusion, a novel benchmark that focuses on assessing the VideoLLMs' hallucination toward event, the crux of video analysis. From a hallucination attribution perspective, our EventHallusion benchmark is curated to assess a VideoLLM's susceptibility toward language priors and vision-language biases. On the other hand, we also propose a simple yet effective method, called Temporal Contrastive Decoding (TCD), to tackle the hallucination problems of VideoLLMs. The proposed TCD method rectifies the model's bias toward its priors during the decoding stage by comparing the original video with a modified version, in which temporal cues are disrupted. Through comprehensive evaluation of eight open-source and two closed-source VideoLLMs on the proposed EventHallusion benchmark, we observe that the open-source models suffer significantly from hallucination problems, whereas the closed-source ones perform markedly better. By further equipping open-source VideoLLMs with the proposed TCD approach, evident performance improvements are achieved across most metrics in the EventHallusion benchmark. Our codes and benchmark data are available at https://github.com/Stevetich/EventHallusion.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.16597v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiacheng Zhang, Yang Jiao, Shaoxiang Chen, Na Zhao, Jingjing Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TVBench: Redesigning Video-Language Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.07752</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.07752v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models have demonstrated impressive performance when integrated with vision models even enabling video understanding. However, evaluating these video models presents its own unique challenges, for which several benchmarks have been proposed. In this paper, we show that the currently most used video-language benchmarks can be solved without requiring much temporal reasoning. We identified three main issues in existing datasets: (i) static information from single frames is often sufficient to solve the tasks (ii) the text of the questions and candidate answers is overly informative, allowing models to answer correctly without relying on any visual input (iii) world knowledge alone can answer many of the questions, making the benchmarks a test of knowledge replication rather than visual reasoning. In addition, we found that open-ended question-answering benchmarks for video understanding suffer from similar issues while the automatic evaluation process with LLMs is unreliable, making it an unsuitable alternative. As a solution, we propose TVBench, a novel open-source video multiple-choice question-answering benchmark, and demonstrate through extensive evaluations that it requires a high level of temporal understanding. Surprisingly, we find that most recent state-of-the-art video-language models perform similarly to random performance on TVBench, with only a few models such as Qwen2-VL, and Tarsier clearly surpassing this baseline.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.07752v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Daniel Cores, Michael Dorkenwald, Manuel Mucientes, Cees G. M. Snoek, Yuki M. Asano</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>InvSeg: Test-Time Prompt Inversion for Semantic Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.11473</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.11473v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Visual-textual correlations in the attention maps derived from text-to-image diffusion models are proven beneficial to dense visual prediction tasks, e.g., semantic segmentation. However, a significant challenge arises due to the input distributional discrepancy between the context-rich sentences used for image generation and the isolated class names typically used in semantic segmentation. This discrepancy hinders diffusion models from capturing accurate visual-textual correlations. To solve this, we propose InvSeg, a test-time prompt inversion method that tackles open-vocabulary semantic segmentation by inverting image-specific visual context into text prompt embedding space, leveraging structure information derived from the diffusion model's reconstruction process to enrich text prompts so as to associate each class with a structure-consistent mask. Specifically, we introduce Contrastive Soft Clustering (CSC) to align derived masks with the image's structure information, softly selecting anchors for each class and calculating weighted distances to push inner-class pixels closer while separating inter-class pixels, thereby ensuring mask distinction and internal consistency. By incorporating sample-specific context, InvSeg learns context-rich text prompts in embedding space and achieves accurate semantic alignment across modalities. Experiments show that InvSeg achieves state-of-the-art performance on the PASCAL VOC, PASCAL Context and COCO Object datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.11473v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiayi Lin, Jiabo Huang, Jian Hu, Shaogang Gong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Vision-Language Model Safety through Progressive Concept-Bottleneck-Driven Alignment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.11543</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.11543v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Benefiting from the powerful capabilities of Large Language Models (LLMs), pre-trained visual encoder models connected to LLMs form Vision Language Models (VLMs). However, recent research shows that the visual modality in VLMs is highly vulnerable, allowing attackers to bypass safety alignment in LLMs through visually transmitted content, launching harmful attacks. To address this challenge, we propose a progressive concept-based alignment strategy, PSA-VLM, which incorporates safety modules as concept bottlenecks to enhance visual modality safety alignment. By aligning model predictions with specific safety concepts, we improve defenses against risky images, enhancing explainability and controllability while minimally impacting general performance. Our method is obtained through two-stage training. The low computational cost of the first stage brings very effective performance improvement, and the fine-tuning of the language model in the second stage further improves the safety performance. Our method achieves state-of-the-art results on popular VLM safety benchmark.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.11543v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhendong Liu, Yuanbi Nie, Yingshui Tan, Jiaheng Liu, Xiangyu Yue, Qiushi Cui, Chongjun Wang, Xiaoyong Zhu, Bo Zheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CompetitorFormer: Competitor Transformer for 3D Instance Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.14179</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.14179v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Transformer-based methods have become the dominant approach for 3D instance segmentation. These methods predict instance masks via instance queries, ranking them by classification confidence and IoU scores to select the top prediction as the final outcome. However, it has been observed that the current models employ a fixed and higher number of queries than the instances present within a scene. In such instances, multiple queries predict the same instance, yet only a single query is ultimately optimized. The close scores of queries in the lower-level decoders make it challenging for the dominant query to distinguish itself rapidly, which ultimately impairs the model's accuracy and convergence efficiency. This phenomenon is referred to as inter-query competition. To address this challenge, we put forth a series of plug-and-play competition-oriented designs, collectively designated as the CompetitorFormer, with the aim of reducing competition and facilitating a dominant query. Experiments showed that integrating our designs with state-of-the-art frameworks consistently resulted in significant performance improvements in 3D instance segmentation across a range of datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.14179v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Duanchu Wang (School of Electronic Engineering, Xidian University), Jing Liu (School of Software Engineering, Xian Jiaotong University), Haoran Gong (School of Software Engineering, Xian Jiaotong University), Yinghui Quan (School of Electronic Engineering, Xidian University), Di Wang (School of Software Engineering, Xian Jiaotong University)</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FastTrackTr:Towards Fast Multi-Object Tracking with Transformers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.15811</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.15811v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Transformer-based multi-object tracking (MOT) methods have captured the attention of many researchers in recent years. However, these models often suffer from slow inference speeds due to their structure or other issues. To address this problem, we revisited the Joint Detection and Tracking (JDT) method by looking back at past approaches. By integrating the original JDT approach with some advanced theories, this paper employs an efficient method of information transfer between frames on the DETR, constructing a fast and novel JDT-type MOT framework: FastTrackTr. Thanks to the superiority of this information transfer method, our approach not only reduces the number of queries required during tracking but also avoids the excessive introduction of network structures, ensuring model simplicity. Experimental results indicate that our method has the potential to achieve real-time tracking and exhibits competitive tracking accuracy across multiple datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.15811v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Pan Liao, Feng Yang, Di Wu, Jinwen Yu, Wenhui Zhao, Bo Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I$^2$OL-Net: Intra-Inter Objectness Learning Network for Point-Supervised X-Ray Prohibited Item Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.03811</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.03811v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Automatic detection of prohibited items in X-ray images plays a crucial role in public security. However, existing methods rely heavily on labor-intensive box annotations. To address this, we investigate X-ray prohibited item detection under labor-efficient point supervision and develop an intra-inter objectness learning network (I$^2$OL-Net). I$^2$OL-Net consists of two key modules: an intra-modality objectness learning (intra-OL) module and an inter-modality objectness learning (inter-OL) module. The intra-OL module designs a local focus Gaussian masking block and a global random Gaussian masking block to collaboratively learn the objectness in X-ray images. Meanwhile, the inter-OL module introduces the wavelet decomposition-based adversarial learning block and the objectness block, effectively reducing the modality discrepancy and transferring the objectness knowledge learned from natural images with box annotations to X-ray images. Based on the above, I$^2$OL-Net greatly alleviates the problem of part domination caused by severe intra-class variations in X-ray images. Experimental results on four X-ray datasets show that I$^2$OL-Net can achieve superior performance with a significant reduction of annotation cost, thus enhancing its accessibility and practicality.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.03811v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sanjoeng Wong, Yan Yan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TryOffAnyone: Tiled Cloth Generation from a Dressed Person</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.08573</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.08573v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The fashion industry is increasingly leveraging computer vision and deep learning technologies to enhance online shopping experiences and operational efficiencies. In this paper, we address the challenge of generating high-fidelity tiled garment images essential for personalized recommendations, outfit composition, and virtual try-on systems from photos of garments worn by models. Inspired by the success of Latent Diffusion Models (LDMs) in image-to-image translation, we propose a novel approach utilizing a fine-tuned StableDiffusion model. Our method features a streamlined single-stage network design, which integrates garmentspecific masks to isolate and process target clothing items effectively. By simplifying the network architecture through selective training of transformer blocks and removing unnecessary crossattention layers, we significantly reduce computational complexity while achieving state-of-the-art performance on benchmark datasets like VITON-HD. Experimental results demonstrate the effectiveness of our approach in producing high-quality tiled garment images for both full-body and half-body inputs. Code and model are available at: https://github.com/ixarchakos/try-off-anyone</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.08573v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ioannis Xarchakos, Theodoros Koukopoulos</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cross-View Geo-Localization with Street-View and VHR Satellite Imagery in Decentrality Settings</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.11529</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.11529v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Cross-View Geo-Localization tackles the challenge of image geo-localization in GNSS-denied environments, including disaster response scenarios, urban canyons, and dense forests, by matching street-view query images with geo-tagged aerial-view reference images. However, current research often relies on benchmarks and methods that assume center-aligned settings or account for only limited decentrality, which we define as the offset of the query image relative to the reference image center. Such assumptions fail to reflect real-world scenarios, where reference databases are typically pre-established without the possibility of ensuring perfect alignment for each query image. Moreover, decentrality is a critical factor warranting deeper investigation, as larger decentrality can substantially improve localization efficiency but comes at the cost of declines in localization accuracy. To address this limitation, we introduce DReSS (Decentrality Related Street-view and Satellite-view dataset), a novel dataset designed to evaluate cross-view geo-localization with a large geographic scope and diverse landscapes, emphasizing the decentrality issue. Meanwhile, we propose AuxGeo (Auxiliary Enhanced Geo-Localization) to further study the decentrality issue, which leverages a multi-metric optimization strategy with two novel modules: the Bird's-eye view Intermediary Module (BIM) and the Position Constraint Module (PCM). These modules improve the localization accuracy despite the decentrality problem. Extensive experiments demonstrate that AuxGeo outperforms previous methods on our proposed DReSS dataset, mitigating the issue of large decentrality, and also achieves state-of-the-art performance on existing public datasets such as CVUSA, CVACT, and VIGOR.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.11529v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Panwang Xia, Lei Yu, Yi Wan, Qiong Wu, Peiqi Chen, Liheng Zhong, Yongxiang Yao, Dong Wei, Xinyi Liu, Lixiang Ru, Yingying Zhang, Jiangwei Lao, Jingdong Chen, Ming Yang, Yongjun Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Level Embedding and Alignment Network with Consistency and Invariance Learning for Cross-View Geo-Localization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.14819</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.14819v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Cross-View Geo-Localization (CVGL) involves determining the localization of drone images by retrieving the most similar GPS-tagged satellite images. However, the imaging gaps between platforms are often significant and the variations in viewpoints are substantial, which limits the ability of existing methods to effectively associate cross-view features and extract consistent and invariant characteristics. Moreover, existing methods often overlook the problem of increased computational and storage requirements when improving model performance. To handle these limitations, we propose a lightweight enhanced alignment network, called the Multi-Level Embedding and Alignment Network (MEAN). The MEAN network uses a progressive multi-level enhancement strategy, global-to-local associations, and cross-domain alignment, enabling feature communication across levels. This allows MEAN to effectively connect features at different levels and learn robust cross-view consistent mappings and modality-invariant features. Moreover, MEAN adopts a shallow backbone network combined with a lightweight branch design, effectively reducing parameter count and computational complexity. Experimental results on the University-1652 and SUES-200 datasets demonstrate that MEAN reduces parameter count by 62.17% and computational complexity by 70.99% compared to state-of-the-art models, while maintaining competitive or even superior performance. Our code and models will be released on https://github.com/ISChenawei/MEAN.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.14819v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhongwei Chen, Zhao-Xu Yang, Hai-Jun Rong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PB-UAP: Hybrid Universal Adversarial Attack For Image Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.16651</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.16651v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: With the rapid advancement of deep learning, the model robustness has become a significant research hotspot, \ie, adversarial attacks on deep neural networks. Existing works primarily focus on image classification tasks, aiming to alter the model's predicted labels. Due to the output complexity and deeper network architectures, research on adversarial examples for segmentation models is still limited, particularly for universal adversarial perturbations. In this paper, we propose a novel universal adversarial attack method designed for segmentation models, which includes dual feature separation and low-frequency scattering modules. The two modules guide the training of adversarial examples in the pixel and frequency space, respectively. Experiments demonstrate that our method achieves high attack success rates surpassing the state-of-the-art methods, and exhibits strong transferability across different models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.16651v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yufei Song, Ziqi Zhou, Minghui Li, Xianlong Wang, Hangtao Zhang, Menghao Deng, Wei Wan, Shengshan Hu, Leo Yu Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Consistent Spatio-Temporal Correspondence for Robust Visual Odometry</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.16923</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.16923v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent approaches to VO have significantly improved performance by using deep networks to predict optical flow between video frames. However, existing methods still suffer from noisy and inconsistent flow matching, making it difficult to handle challenging scenarios and long-sequence estimation. To overcome these challenges, we introduce Spatio-Temporal Visual Odometry (STVO), a novel deep network architecture that effectively leverages inherent spatio-temporal cues to enhance the accuracy and consistency of multi-frame flow matching. With more accurate and consistent flow matching, STVO can achieve better pose estimation through the bundle adjustment (BA). Specifically, STVO introduces two innovative components: 1) the Temporal Propagation Module that utilizes multi-frame information to extract and propagate temporal cues across adjacent frames, maintaining temporal consistency; 2) the Spatial Activation Module that utilizes geometric priors from the depth maps to enhance spatial consistency while filtering out excessive noise and incorrect matches. Our STVO achieves state-of-the-art performance on TUM-RGBD, EuRoc MAV, ETH3D and KITTI Odometry benchmarks. Notably, it improves accuracy by 77.8% on ETH3D benchmark and 38.9% on KITTI Odometry benchmark over the previous best methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.16923v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhaoxing Zhang, Junda Cheng, Gangwei Xu, Xiaoxiang Wang, Can Zhang, Xin Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Balanced 3DGS: Gaussian-wise Parallelism Rendering with Fine-Grained Tiling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.17378</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.17378v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: 3D Gaussian Splatting (3DGS) is increasingly attracting attention in both academia and industry owing to its superior visual quality and rendering speed. However, training a 3DGS model remains a time-intensive task, especially in load imbalance scenarios where workload diversity among pixels and Gaussian spheres causes poor renderCUDA kernel performance. We introduce Balanced 3DGS, a Gaussian-wise parallelism rendering with fine-grained tiling approach in 3DGS training process, perfectly solving load-imbalance issues. First, we innovatively introduce the inter-block dynamic workload distribution technique to map workloads to Streaming Multiprocessor(SM) resources within a single GPU dynamically, which constitutes the foundation of load balancing. Second, we are the first to propose the Gaussian-wise parallel rendering technique to significantly reduce workload divergence inside a warp, which serves as a critical component in addressing load imbalance. Based on the above two methods, we further creatively put forward the fine-grained combined load balancing technique to uniformly distribute workload across all SMs, which boosts the forward renderCUDA kernel performance by up to 7.52x. Besides, we present a self-adaptive render kernel selection strategy during the 3DGS training process based on different load-balance situations, which effectively improves training efficiency.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.17378v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hao Gui, Lin Hu, Rui Chen, Mingxiao Huang, Yuxin Yin, Jin Yang, Yong Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TAB: Transformer Attention Bottlenecks enable User Intervention and Debugging in Vision-Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18675</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18675v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Multi-head self-attention (MHSA) is a key component of Transformers, a widely popular architecture in both language and vision. Multiple heads intuitively enable different parallel processes over the same input. Yet, they also obscure the attribution of each input patch to the output of a model. We propose a novel 1-head Transformer Attention Bottleneck (TAB) layer, inserted after the traditional MHSA architecture, to serve as an attention bottleneck for interpretability and intervention. Unlike standard self-attention, TAB constrains the total attention over all patches to $\in [0, 1]$. That is, when the total attention is 0, no visual information is propagated further into the network and the vision-language model (VLM) would default to a generic, image-independent response. To demonstrate the advantages of TAB, we train VLMs with TAB to perform image difference captioning. Over three datasets, our models perform similarly to baseline VLMs in captioning but the bottleneck is superior in localizing changes and in identifying when no changes occur. TAB is the first architecture to enable users to intervene by editing attention, which often produces expected outputs by VLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18675v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Pooyan Rahmanzadehgervi, Hung Huy Nguyen, Rosanne Liu, Long Mai, Anh Totti Nguyen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Table Recognition with Vision LLMs: A Benchmark and Neighbor-Guided Toolchain Reasoner</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.20662</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.20662v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Pre-trained foundation models have recently significantly progressed in structured table understanding and reasoning. However, despite advancements in areas such as table semantic understanding and table question answering, recognizing the structure and content of unstructured tables using Vision Large Language Models (VLLMs) remains under-explored. In this work, we address this research gap by employing VLLMs in a training-free reasoning paradigm. First, we design a benchmark with various hierarchical dimensions relevant to table recognition. Subsequently, we conduct in-depth evaluations using pre-trained VLLMs, finding that low-quality image input is a significant bottleneck in the recognition process. Drawing inspiration from these findings, we propose the Neighbor-Guided Toolchain Reasoner (NGTR) framework, which is characterized by integrating multiple lightweight models for low-level visual processing operations aimed at mitigating issues with low-quality input images. Specifically, we utilize a neighbor retrieval mechanism to guide the generation of multiple tool invocation plans, transferring tool selection experiences from similar neighbors to the given input, thereby facilitating suitable tool selection. Additionally, we introduce a reflection module to supervise the tool invocation process. Extensive experiments on public table recognition datasets demonstrate that our approach significantly enhances the recognition capabilities of the vanilla VLLMs. We believe that the designed benchmark and the proposed NGTR framework could provide an alternative solution in table recognition.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.20662v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yitong Zhou, Mingyue Cheng, Qingyang Mao, Qi Liu, Feiyang Xu, Xin Li, Enhong Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Prompt Adjustment for Multi-Label Class-Incremental Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.00340</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.00340v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Significant advancements have been made in single label incremental learning (SLCIL),yet the more practical and challenging multi label class incremental learning (MLCIL) remains understudied. Recently,visual language models such as CLIP have achieved good results in classification tasks. However,directly using CLIP to solve MLCIL issue can lead to catastrophic forgetting. To tackle this issue, we integrate an improved data replay mechanism and prompt loss to curb knowledge forgetting. Specifically,our model enhances the prompt information to better adapt to multi-label classification tasks and employs confidence-based replay strategy to select representative samples. Moreover, the prompt loss significantly reduces the model's forgetting of previous knowledge. Experimental results demonstrate that our method has substantially improved the performance of MLCIL tasks across multiple benchmark datasets,validating its effectiveness.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.00340v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haifeng Zhao, Yuguang Jin, Leilei Ma</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FGAseg: Fine-Grained Pixel-Text Alignment for Open-Vocabulary Semantic Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.00877</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.00877v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Open-vocabulary segmentation aims to identify and segment specific regions and objects based on text-based descriptions. A common solution is to leverage powerful vision-language models (VLMs), such as CLIP, to bridge the gap between vision and text information. However, VLMs are typically pretrained for image-level vision-text alignment, focusing on global semantic features. In contrast, segmentation tasks require fine-grained pixel-level alignment and detailed category boundary information, which VLMs alone cannot provide. As a result, information extracted directly from VLMs can't meet the requirements of segmentation tasks. To address this limitation, we propose FGAseg, a model designed for fine-grained pixel-text alignment and category boundary supplementation. The core of FGAseg is a Pixel-Level Alignment module that employs a cross-modal attention mechanism and a text-pixel alignment loss to refine the coarse-grained alignment from CLIP, achieving finer-grained pixel-text semantic alignment. Additionally, to enrich category boundary information, we introduce the alignment matrices as optimizable pseudo-masks during forward propagation and propose Category Information Supplementation module. These pseudo-masks, derived from cosine and convolutional similarity, provide essential global and local boundary information between different categories. By combining these two strategies, FGAseg effectively enhances pixel-level alignment and category boundary information, addressing key challenges in open-vocabulary segmentation. Extensive experiments demonstrate that FGAseg outperforms existing methods on open-vocabulary semantic segmentation benchmarks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.00877v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bingyu Li, Da Zhang, Zhiyuan Zhao, Junyu Gao, Xuelong Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2.5 Years in Class: A Multimodal Textbook for Vision-Language Pretraining</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.00958</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.00958v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Compared to image-text pair data, interleaved corpora enable Vision-Language Models (VLMs) to understand the world more naturally like humans. However, such existing datasets are crawled from webpage, facing challenges like low knowledge density, loose image-text relations, and poor logical coherence between images. On the other hand, the internet hosts vast instructional videos (e.g., online geometry courses) that are widely used by humans to learn foundational subjects, yet these valuable resources remain underexplored in VLM training. In this paper, we introduce a high-quality \textbf{multimodal textbook} corpus with richer foundational knowledge for VLM pretraining. It collects over 2.5 years of instructional videos, totaling 22,000 class hours. We first use an LLM-proposed taxonomy to systematically gather instructional videos. Then we progressively extract and refine visual (keyframes), audio (ASR), and textual knowledge (OCR) from the videos, and organize as an image-text interleaved corpus based on temporal order. Compared to its counterparts, our video-centric textbook offers more coherent context, richer knowledge, and better image-text alignment. Experiments demonstrate its superb pretraining performance, particularly in knowledge- and reasoning-intensive tasks like ScienceQA and MathVista. Moreover, VLMs pre-trained on our textbook exhibit outstanding interleaved context awareness, leveraging visual and textual cues in their few-shot context for task solving~\footnote{Our code are available at \url{https://github.com/DAMO-NLP-SG/multimodal_textbook}}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.00958v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenqi Zhang, Hang Zhang, Xin Li, Jiashuo Sun, Yongliang Shen, Weiming Lu, Deli Zhao, Yueting Zhuang, Lidong Bing</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ZeroFlow: Overcoming Catastrophic Forgetting is Easier than You Think</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01045</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01045v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Backpropagation provides a generalized configuration for overcoming catastrophic forgetting. Like, SGD and Adam are commonly used for weight updates in continual learning and continual pre-training. In practice, permission to access gradient information is not always granted (the gradient ban), such as black-box APIs, hardware limitations, and non-differentiable systems. To bridge this gap, we introduce the first benchmark ZeroFlow to evaluate gradient-free optimization algorithms for overcoming forgetting. This benchmark examines a suite of forward pass methods across multiple methods, forgetting scenarios, and datasets. We find that forward passes alone are enough to overcome forgetting. Our findings reveal new optimization principles that highlight the potential of forward-pass in mitigating forgetting, managing task conflicts, and reducing memory demands, alongside novel enhancements that further mitigate forgetting with just one forward pass. This work provides essential insights and tools for advancing forward pass methods to overcome forgetting.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01045v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tao Feng, Wei Li, Didi Zhu, Hangjie Yuan, Wendi Zheng, Dan Zhang, Jie Tang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conditional Consistency Guided Image Translation and Enhancement</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01223</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01223v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Consistency models have emerged as a promising alternative to diffusion models, offering high-quality generative capabilities through single-step sample generation. However, their application to multi-domain image translation tasks, such as cross-modal translation and low-light image enhancement remains largely unexplored. In this paper, we introduce Conditional Consistency Models (CCMs) for multi-domain image translation by incorporating additional conditional inputs. We implement these modifications by introducing task-specific conditional inputs that guide the denoising process, ensuring that the generated outputs retain structural and contextual information from the corresponding input domain. We evaluate CCMs on 10 different datasets demonstrating their effectiveness in producing high-quality translated images across multiple domains. Code is available at https://github.com/amilbhagat/Conditional-Consistency-Models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01223v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Amil Bhagat, Milind Jain, A. V. Subramanyam</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SVFR: A Unified Framework for Generalized Video Face Restoration</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01235</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01235v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Face Restoration (FR) is a crucial area within image and video processing, focusing on reconstructing high-quality portraits from degraded inputs. Despite advancements in image FR, video FR remains relatively under-explored, primarily due to challenges related to temporal consistency, motion artifacts, and the limited availability of high-quality video data. Moreover, traditional face restoration typically prioritizes enhancing resolution and may not give as much consideration to related tasks such as facial colorization and inpainting. In this paper, we propose a novel approach for the Generalized Video Face Restoration (GVFR) task, which integrates video BFR, inpainting, and colorization tasks that we empirically show to benefit each other. We present a unified framework, termed as stable video face restoration (SVFR), which leverages the generative and motion priors of Stable Video Diffusion (SVD) and incorporates task-specific information through a unified face restoration framework. A learnable task embedding is introduced to enhance task identification. Meanwhile, a novel Unified Latent Regularization (ULR) is employed to encourage the shared feature representation learning among different subtasks. To further enhance the restoration quality and temporal stability, we introduce the facial prior learning and the self-referred refinement as auxiliary strategies used for both training and inference. The proposed framework effectively combines the complementary strengths of these tasks, enhancing temporal coherence and achieving superior restoration quality. This work advances the state-of-the-art in video FR and establishes a new paradigm for generalized video face restoration. Code and video demo are available at https://github.com/wangzhiyaoo/SVFR.git.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01235v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhiyao Wang, Xu Chen, Chengming Xu, Junwei Zhu, Xiaobin Hu, Jiangning Zhang, Chengjie Wang, Yuqi Liu, Yiyi Zhou, Rongrong Ji</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free-Form Motion Control: A Synthetic Video Generation Dataset with Controllable Camera and Object Motions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01425</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01425v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Controlling the movements of dynamic objects and the camera within generated videos is a meaningful yet challenging task. Due to the lack of datasets with comprehensive motion annotations, existing algorithms can not simultaneously control the motions of both camera and objects, resulting in limited controllability over generated contents. To address this issue and facilitate the research in this field, we introduce a Synthetic Dataset for Free-Form Motion Control (SynFMC). The proposed SynFMC dataset includes diverse objects and environments and covers various motion patterns according to specific rules, simulating common and complex real-world scenarios. The complete 6D pose information facilitates models learning to disentangle the motion effects from objects and the camera in a video. To validate the effectiveness and generalization of SynFMC, we further propose a method, Free-Form Motion Control (FMC). FMC enables independent or simultaneous control of object and camera movements, producing high-fidelity videos. Moreover, it is compatible with various personalized text-to-image (T2I) models for different content styles. Extensive experiments demonstrate that the proposed FMC outperforms previous methods across multiple scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01425v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xincheng Shuai, Henghui Ding, Zhenyuan Qin, Hao Luo, Xingjun Ma, Dacheng Tao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GPT4Scene: Understand 3D Scenes from Videos with Vision-Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01428</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01428v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In recent years, 2D Vision-Language Models (VLMs) have made significant strides in image-text understanding tasks. However, their performance in 3D spatial comprehension, which is critical for embodied intelligence, remains limited. Recent advances have leveraged 3D point clouds and multi-view images as inputs, yielding promising results. However, we propose exploring a purely vision-based solution inspired by human perception, which merely relies on visual cues for 3D spatial understanding. This paper empirically investigates the limitations of VLMs in 3D spatial knowledge, revealing that their primary shortcoming lies in the lack of global-local correspondence between the scene and individual frames. To address this, we introduce GPT4Scene, a novel visual prompting paradigm in VLM training and inference that helps build the global-local relationship, significantly improving the 3D spatial understanding of indoor scenes. Specifically, GPT4Scene constructs a 3D Bird's Eye View (BEV) image from the video and marks consistent object IDs across both frames and the BEV image. The model then inputs the concatenated BEV image and video frames with markers. In zero-shot evaluations, GPT4Scene improves performance over closed-source VLMs like GPT-4o. Additionally, we prepare a processed video dataset consisting of 165K text annotation to fine-tune open-source VLMs, achieving state-of-the-art performance on all 3D understanding tasks. Surprisingly, after training with the GPT4Scene paradigm, VLMs consistently improve during inference, even without visual prompting and BEV image as explicit correspondence. It demonstrates that the proposed paradigm helps VLMs develop an intrinsic ability to understand 3D scenes, which paves the way for a noninvasive approach to extending pre-trained VLMs for 3D scene understanding.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01428v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhangyang Qi, Zhixiong Zhang, Ye Fang, Jiaqi Wang, Hengshuang Zhao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SwinVFTR: A Novel Volumetric Feature-learning Transformer for 3D OCT Fluid Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2303.09233</link>
      <description>arXiv:2303.09233v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Accurately segmenting fluid in 3D optical coherence tomography (OCT) images is critical for detecting eye diseases but remains challenging. Traditional autoencoder-based methods struggle with resolution loss and information recovery. While transformer-based models improve segmentation, they arent optimized for 3D OCT volumes, which vary by vendor and extraction technique. To address this, we propose SwinVFTR, a transformer architecture for precise fluid segmentation in 3D OCT images. SwinVFTR employs channel-wise volumetric sampling and a shifted window transformer block to improve fluid localization. Moreover, a novel volumetric attention block enhances spatial and depth-wise attention. Trained using multi-class dice loss, SwinVFTR outperforms existing models on Spectralis, Cirrus, and Topcon OCT datasets, achieving mean dice scores of 0.72, 0.59, and 0.68, respectively, along with superior performance in mean intersection-over-union (IOU) and structural similarity (SSIM) metrics.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2303.09233v3</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Khondker Fariha Hossain, Sharif Amit Kamran, Alireza Tavakkoli, George Bebis, Sal Baker</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Runtime Stealthy Perception Attacks against DNN-based Adaptive Cruise Control Systems</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2307.08939</link>
      <description>arXiv:2307.08939v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Adaptive Cruise Control (ACC) is a widely used driver assistance technology for maintaining the desired speed and safe distance to the leading vehicle. This paper evaluates the security of the deep neural network (DNN) based ACC systems under runtime stealthy perception attacks that strategically inject perturbations into camera data to cause forward collisions. We present a context-aware strategy for the selection of the most critical times for triggering the attacks and a novel optimization-based method for the adaptive generation of image perturbations at runtime. We evaluate the effectiveness of the proposed attack using an actual vehicle, a publicly available driving dataset, and a realistic simulation platform with the control software from a production ACC system, a physical-world driving simulator, and interventions by the human driver and safety features such as Advanced Emergency Braking System (AEBS). Experimental results show that the proposed attack achieves 142.9 times higher success rate in causing hazards and 82.6% higher evasion rate than baselines, while being stealthy and robust to real-world factors and dynamic changes in the environment. This study highlights the role of human drivers and basic safety mechanisms in preventing attacks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2307.08939v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3708821.3710832</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Xugui Zhou, Anqi Chen, Maxfield Kouzel, Haotian Ren, Morgan McCarty, Cristina Nita-Rotaru, Homa Alemzadeh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPCR: Holistic Proxy-based Contrastive Replay for Online Continual Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2309.15038</link>
      <description>arXiv:2309.15038v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Online continual learning, aimed at developing a neural network that continuously learns new data from a single pass over an online data stream, generally suffers from catastrophic forgetting. Existing replay-based methods alleviate forgetting by replaying partial old data in a proxy-based or contrastive-based replay manner, each with its own shortcomings. Our previous work proposes a novel replay-based method called proxy-based contrastive replay (PCR), which handles the shortcomings by achieving complementary advantages of both replay manners. In this work, we further conduct gradient and limitation analysis of PCR. The analysis results show that PCR still can be further improved in feature extraction, generalization, and anti-forgetting capabilities of the model. Hence, we develop a more advanced method named holistic proxy-based contrastive replay (HPCR). HPCR consists of three components, each tackling one of the limitations of PCR. The contrastive component conditionally incorporates anchor-to-sample pairs to PCR, improving the feature extraction ability. The second is a temperature component that decouples the temperature coefficient into two parts based on their gradient impacts and sets different values for them to enhance the generalization ability. The third is a distillation component that constrains the learning process with additional loss terms to improve the anti-forgetting ability. Experiments on four datasets consistently demonstrate the superiority of HPCR over various state-of-the-art methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2309.15038v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Huiwei Lin, Shanshan Feng, Baoquan Zhang, Xutao Li, Yunming Ye</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FS-Net: Full Scale Network and Adaptive Threshold for Improving Extraction of Micro-Retinal Vessel Structures</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.08059</link>
      <description>arXiv:2311.08059v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Retinal vascular segmentation, a widely researched topic in biomedical image processing, aims to reduce the workload of ophthalmologists in treating and detecting retinal disorders. Segmenting retinal vessels presents unique challenges; previous techniques often failed to effectively segment branches and microvascular structures. Recent neural network approaches struggle to balance local and global properties and frequently miss tiny end vessels, hindering the achievement of desired results. To address these issues in retinal vessel segmentation, we propose a comprehensive micro-vessel extraction mechanism based on an encoder-decoder neural network architecture. This network includes residual, encoder booster, bottleneck enhancement, squeeze, and excitation building blocks. These components synergistically enhance feature extraction and improve the prediction accuracy of the segmentation map. Our solution has been evaluated using the DRIVE, CHASE-DB1, and STARE datasets, yielding competitive results compared to previous studies. The AUC and accuracy on the DRIVE dataset are 0.9884 and 0.9702, respectively. For the CHASE-DB1 dataset, these scores are 0.9903 and 0.9755, respectively, and for the STARE dataset, they are 0.9916 and 0.9750. Given its accurate and robust performance, the proposed approach is a solid candidate for being implemented in real-life diagnostic centers and aiding ophthalmologists.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2311.08059v4</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Melaku N. Getahun, Oleg Y. Rogov, Dmitry V. Dylov, Andrey Somov, Ahmed Bouridane, Rifat Hamoudi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Multi-modal Vulnerability of Diffusion Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.01369</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.01369v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Diffusion models have been widely deployed in various image generation tasks, demonstrating an extraordinary connection between image and text modalities. Although prior studies have explored the vulnerability of diffusion models from the perspectives of text and image modalities separately, the current research landscape has not yet thoroughly investigated the vulnerabilities that arise from the integration of multiple modalities, specifically through the joint analysis of textual and visual features. In this paper, we are the first to visualize both text and image feature space embedded by diffusion models and observe a significant difference. The prompts are embedded chaotically in the text feature space, while in the image feature space they are clustered according to their subjects. These fascinating findings may underscore a potential misalignment in robustness between the two modalities that exists within diffusion models. Based on this observation, we propose MMP-Attack, which leverages multi-modal priors (MMP) to manipulate the generation results of diffusion models by appending a specific suffix to the original prompt. Specifically, our goal is to induce diffusion models to generate a specific object while simultaneously eliminating the original object. Our MMP-Attack shows a notable advantage over existing studies with superior manipulation capability and efficiency. Our code is publicly available at \url{https://github.com/ydc123/MMP-Attack}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.01369v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dingcheng Yang, Yang Bai, Xiaojun Jia, Yang Liu, Xiaochun Cao, Wenjian Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agent Planning with World Knowledge Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.14205</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.14205v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Recent endeavors towards directly using large language models (LLMs) as agent models to execute interactive planning tasks have shown commendable results. Despite their achievements, however, they still struggle with brainless trial-and-error in global planning and generating hallucinatory actions in local planning due to their poor understanding of the ``real'' physical world. Imitating humans' mental world knowledge model which provides global prior knowledge before the task and maintains local dynamic knowledge during the task, in this paper, we introduce parametric World Knowledge Model (WKM) to facilitate agent planning. Concretely, we steer the agent model to self-synthesize knowledge from both expert and sampled trajectories. Then we develop WKM, providing prior task knowledge to guide the global planning and dynamic state knowledge to assist the local planning. Experimental results on three complex real-world simulated datasets with three state-of-the-art open-source LLMs, Mistral-7B, Gemma-7B, and Llama-3-8B, demonstrate that our method can achieve superior performance compared to various strong baselines. Besides, we analyze to illustrate that our WKM can effectively alleviate the blind trial-and-error and hallucinatory action issues, providing strong support for the agent's understanding of the world. Other interesting findings include: 1) our instance-level task knowledge can generalize better to unseen tasks, 2) weak WKM can guide strong agent model planning, and 3) unified WKM training has promising potential for further development. The code is available at https://github.com/zjunlp/WKM.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.14205v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shuofei Qiao, Runnan Fang, Ningyu Zhang, Yuqi Zhu, Xiang Chen, Shumin Deng, Yong Jiang, Pengjun Xie, Fei Huang, Huajun Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Circuits in Pretrained Transformers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.17969</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.17969v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The remarkable capabilities of modern large language models are rooted in their vast repositories of knowledge encoded within their parameters, enabling them to perceive the world and engage in reasoning. The inner workings of how these models store knowledge have long been a subject of intense interest and investigation among researchers. To date, most studies have concentrated on isolated components within these models, such as the Multilayer Perceptrons and attention head. In this paper, we delve into the computation graph of the language model to uncover the knowledge circuits that are instrumental in articulating specific knowledge. The experiments, conducted with GPT2 and TinyLLAMA, have allowed us to observe how certain information heads, relation heads, and Multilayer Perceptrons collaboratively encode knowledge within the model. Moreover, we evaluate the impact of current knowledge editing techniques on these knowledge circuits, providing deeper insights into the functioning and constraints of these editing methodologies. Finally, we utilize knowledge circuits to analyze and interpret language model behaviors such as hallucinations and in-context learning. We believe the knowledge circuits hold potential for advancing our understanding of Transformers and guiding the improved design of knowledge editing. Code and data are available in https://github.com/zjunlp/KnowledgeCircuits.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.17969v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yunzhi Yao, Ningyu Zhang, Zekun Xi, Mengru Wang, Ziwen Xu, Shumin Deng, Huajun Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CT-AGRG: Automated Abnormality-Guided Report Generation from 3D Chest CT Volumes</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.11965</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.11965v5 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The rapid increase of computed tomography (CT) scans and their time-consuming manual analysis have created an urgent need for robust automated analysis techniques in clinical settings. These aim to assist radiologists and help them managing their growing workload. Existing methods typically generate entire reports directly from 3D CT images, without explicitly focusing on observed abnormalities. This unguided approach often results in repetitive content or incomplete reports, failing to prioritize anomaly-specific descriptions. We propose a new anomaly-guided report generation model, which first predicts abnormalities and then generates targeted descriptions for each. Evaluation on a public dataset demonstrates significant improvements in report quality and clinical relevance. We extend our work by conducting an ablation study to demonstrate its effectiveness.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.11965v5</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Theo Di Piazza</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation Metric for Quality Control and Generative Models in Histopathology Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.01034</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.01034v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Our study introduces ResNet-L2 (RL2), a novel metric for evaluating generative models and image quality in histopathology, addressing limitations of traditional metrics, such as Frechet inception distance (FID), when the data is scarce. RL2 leverages ResNet features with a normalizing flow to calculate RMSE distance in the latent space, providing reliable assessments across diverse histopathology datasets. We evaluated the performance of RL2 on degradation types, such as blur, Gaussian noise, salt-and-pepper noise, and rectangular patches, as well as diffusion processes. RL2's monotonic response to increasing degradation makes it well-suited for models that assess image quality, proving a valuable advancement for evaluating image generation techniques in histopathology. It can also be used to discard low-quality patches while sampling from a whole slide image. It is also significantly lighter and faster compared to traditional metrics and requires fewer images to give stable metric value.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.01034v2</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>q-bio.QM</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Pranav Jeevan, Neeraj Nixon, Abhijeet Patil, Amit Sethi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XLSTM-HVED: Cross-Modal Brain Tumor Segmentation and MRI Reconstruction Method Using Vision XLSTM and Heteromodal Variational Encoder-Decoder</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.07804</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.07804v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Neurogliomas are among the most aggressive forms of cancer, presenting considerable challenges in both treatment and monitoring due to their unpredictable biological behavior. Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) is currently the preferred method for diagnosing and monitoring gliomas. However, the lack of specific imaging techniques often compromises the accuracy of tumor segmentation during the imaging process. To address this issue, we introduce the XLSTM-HVED model. This model integrates a hetero-modal encoder-decoder framework with the Vision XLSTM module to reconstruct missing MRI modalities. By deeply fusing spatial and temporal features, it enhances tumor segmentation performance. The key innovation of our approach is the Self-Attention Variational Encoder (SAVE) module, which improves the integration of modal features. Additionally, it optimizes the interaction of features between segmentation and reconstruction tasks through the Squeeze-Fusion-Excitation Cross Awareness (SFECA) module. Our experiments using the BraTS 2024 dataset demonstrate that our model significantly outperforms existing advanced methods in handling cases where modalities are missing. Our source code is available at https://github.com/Quanato607/XLSTM-HVED.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.07804v2</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>ISBI 2025</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Shenghao Zhu, Yifei Chen, Shuo Jiang, Weihong Chen, Chang Liu, Yuanhan Wang, Xu Chen, Yifan Ke, Feiwei Qin, Changmiao Wang, Zhu Zhu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging Simplicity and Sophistication using GLinear: A Novel Architecture for Enhanced Time Series Prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01087</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01087v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Time Series Forecasting (TSF) is an important application across many fields. There is a debate about whether Transformers, despite being good at understanding long sequences, struggle with preserving temporal relationships in time series data. Recent research suggests that simpler linear models might outperform or at least provide competitive performance compared to complex Transformer-based models for TSF tasks. In this paper, we propose a novel data-efficient architecture, GLinear, for multivariate TSF that exploits periodic patterns to provide better accuracy. It also provides better prediction accuracy by using a smaller amount of historical data compared to other state-of-the-art linear predictors. Four different datasets (ETTh1, Electricity, Traffic, and Weather) are used to evaluate the performance of the proposed predictor. A performance comparison with state-of-the-art linear architectures (such as NLinear, DLinear, and RLinear) and transformer-based time series predictor (Autoformer) shows that the GLinear, despite being parametrically efficient, significantly outperforms the existing architectures in most cases of multivariate TSF. We hope that the proposed GLinear opens new fronts of research and development of simpler and more sophisticated architectures for data and computationally efficient time-series analysis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01087v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.ET</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Syed Tahir Hussain Rizvi, Neel Kanwal, Muddasar Naeem, Alfredo Cuzzocrea, Antonio Coronato</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
