<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CV updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CV</link>
    <description>cs.CV updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CV" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 05:00:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Saturday</day>
      <day>Sunday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>DEFEND: A Large-scale 1M Dataset and Foundation Model for Tobacco Addiction Prevention</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.13950</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.13950v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: While tobacco advertising innovates at unprecedented speed, traditional surveillance methods remain frozen in time, especially in the context of social media. The lack of large-scale, comprehensive datasets and sophisticated monitoring systems has created a widening gap between industry advancement and public health oversight. This paper addresses this critical challenge by introducing Tobacco-1M, a comprehensive dataset of one million tobacco product images with hierarchical labels spanning 75 product categories, and DEFEND, a novel foundation model for tobacco product understanding. Our approach integrates a Feature Enhancement Module for rich multimodal representation learning, a Local-Global Visual Coherence mechanism for detailed feature discrimination, and an Enhanced Image-Text Alignment strategy for precise product characterization. Experimental results demonstrate DEFEND's superior performance, achieving 83.1% accuracy in product classification and 73.8% in visual question-answering tasks, outperforming existing methods by significant margins. Moreover, the model exhibits robust zero-shot learning capabilities with 45.6% accuracy on novel product categories. This work provides regulatory bodies and public health researchers with powerful tools for monitoring emerging tobacco products and marketing strategies, potentially revolutionizing approaches to tobacco control and public health surveillance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.13950v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Naga VS Raviteja Chappa, Matthew Shepard, Connor McCurtain, Charlotte McCormick, Page Daniel Dobbs, Khoa Luu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Fast, Scalable, and Robust Deep Learning-based Iterative Reconstruction Framework for Accelerated Industrial Cone-beam X-ray Computed Tomography</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.13961</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.13961v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Cone-beam X-ray Computed Tomography (XCT) with large detectors and corresponding large-scale 3D reconstruction plays a pivotal role in micron-scale characterization of materials and parts across various industries. In this work, we present a novel deep neural network-based iterative algorithm that integrates an artifact reduction-trained CNN as a prior model with automated regularization parameter selection, tailored for large-scale industrial cone-beam XCT data. Our method achieves high-quality 3D reconstructions even for extremely dense thick metal parts - which traditionally pose challenges to industrial CT images - in just a few iterations. Furthermore, we show the generalizability of our approach to out-of-distribution scans obtained under diverse scanning conditions. Our method effectively handles significant noise and streak artifacts, surpassing state-of-the-art supervised learning methods trained on the same data.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.13961v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aniket Pramanik, Obaidullah Rahman, Singanallur V. Venkatakrishnan, Amirkoushyar Ziabari</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Procedural Generation of 3D Maize Plant Architecture from LIDAR Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.13963</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.13963v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This study introduces a robust framework for generating procedural 3D models of maize (Zea mays) plants from LiDAR point cloud data, offering a scalable alternative to traditional field-based phenotyping. Our framework leverages Non-Uniform Rational B-Spline (NURBS) surfaces to model the leaves of maize plants, combining Particle Swarm Optimization (PSO) for an initial approximation of the surface and a differentiable programming framework for precise refinement of the surface to fit the point cloud data. In the first optimization phase, PSO generates an approximate NURBS surface by optimizing its control points, aligning the surface with the LiDAR data, and providing a reliable starting point for refinement. The second phase uses NURBS-Diff, a differentiable programming framework, to enhance the accuracy of the initial fit by refining the surface geometry and capturing intricate leaf details. Our results demonstrate that, while PSO establishes a robust initial fit, the integration of differentiable NURBS significantly improves the overall quality and fidelity of the reconstructed surface. This hierarchical optimization strategy enables accurate 3D reconstruction of maize leaves across diverse genotypes, facilitating the subsequent extraction of complex traits like phyllotaxy. We demonstrate our approach on diverse genotypes of field-grown maize plants. All our codes are open-source to democratize these phenotyping approaches.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.13963v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mozhgan Hadadi, Mehdi Saraeian, Jackson Godbersen, Talukder Jubery, Yawei Li, Lakshmi Attigala, Aditya Balu, Soumik Sarkar, Patrick S. Schnable, Adarsh Krishnamurthy, Baskar Ganapathysubramanian</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing the Understanding and Evaluation of AR-Generated Scenes: When Vision-Language Models Shine and Stumble</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.13964</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.13964v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Augmented Reality (AR) enhances the real world by integrating virtual content, yet ensuring the quality, usability, and safety of AR experiences presents significant challenges. Could Vision-Language Models (VLMs) offer a solution for the automated evaluation of AR-generated scenes? Could Vision-Language Models (VLMs) offer a solution for the automated evaluation of AR-generated scenes? In this study, we evaluate the capabilities of three state-of-the-art commercial VLMs -- GPT, Gemini, and Claude -- in identifying and describing AR scenes. For this purpose, we use DiverseAR, the first AR dataset specifically designed to assess VLMs' ability to analyze virtual content across a wide range of AR scene complexities. Our findings demonstrate that VLMs are generally capable of perceiving and describing AR scenes, achieving a True Positive Rate (TPR) of up to 93\% for perception and 71\% for description. While they excel at identifying obvious virtual objects, such as a glowing apple, they struggle when faced with seamlessly integrated content, such as a virtual pot with realistic shadows. Our results highlight both the strengths and the limitations of VLMs in understanding AR scenarios. We identify key factors affecting VLM performance, including virtual content placement, rendering quality, and physical plausibility. This study underscores the potential of VLMs as tools for evaluating the quality of AR experiences.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.13964v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lin Duan, Yanming Xiu, Maria Gorlatova</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FedDAG: Federated Domain Adversarial Generation Towards Generalizable Medical Image Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.13967</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.13967v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Federated domain generalization aims to train a global model from multiple source domains and ensure its generalization ability to unseen target domains. {Due to the target domain being with unknown domain shifts, attempting to approximate these gaps by source domains may be the key to improving model generalization capability.} Existing works mainly focus on sharing and recombining local domain-specific attributes to increase data diversity and simulate potential domain shifts. {However, these methods may be insufficient since only the local attribute recombination can be hard to touch the out-of-distribution of global data.} In this paper, we propose a simple-yet-efficient framework named Federated Domain Adversarial Generation (FedDAG). {It aims to simulate the domain shift and improve the model generalization by adversarially generating novel domains different from local and global source domains.} Specifically, it generates novel-style images by maximizing the instance-level feature discrepancy between original and generated images and trains a generalizable task model by minimizing their feature discrepancy. {Further, we observed that FedDAG could cause different performance improvements for local models. It may be due to inherent data isolation and heterogeneity among clients, exacerbating the imbalance in their generalization contributions to the global model.} {Ignoring this imbalance can lead the global model's generalization ability to be sub-optimal, further limiting the novel domain generation procedure. } Thus, to mitigate this imbalance, FedDAG hierarchically aggregates local models at the within-client and across-client levels by using the sharpness concept to evaluate client model generalization contributions. {Extensive experiments across four medical benchmarks demonstrate FedDAG's ability to enhance generalization in federated medical scenarios.}</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.13967v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haoxuan Che, Yifei Wu, Haibo Jin, Yong Xia, Hao Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Triplet Synthesis For Enhancing Composed Image Retrieval via Counterfactual Image Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.13968</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.13968v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Composed Image Retrieval (CIR) provides an effective way to manage and access large-scale visual data. Construction of the CIR model utilizes triplets that consist of a reference image, modification text describing desired changes, and a target image that reflects these changes. For effectively training CIR models, extensive manual annotation to construct high-quality training datasets, which can be time-consuming and labor-intensive, is required. To deal with this problem, this paper proposes a novel triplet synthesis method by leveraging counterfactual image generation. By controlling visual feature modifications via counterfactual image generation, our approach automatically generates diverse training triplets without any manual intervention. This approach facilitates the creation of larger and more expressive datasets, leading to the improvement of CIR model's performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.13968v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kenta Uesugi, Naoki Saito, Keisuke Maeda, Takahiro Ogawa, Miki Haseyama</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>InsTex: Indoor Scenes Stylized Texture Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.13969</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.13969v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Generating high-quality textures for 3D scenes is crucial for applications in interior design, gaming, and augmented/virtual reality (AR/VR). Although recent advancements in 3D generative models have enhanced content creation, significant challenges remain in achieving broad generalization and maintaining style consistency across multiple viewpoints. Current methods, such as 2D diffusion models adapted for 3D texturing, suffer from lengthy processing times and visual artifacts, while approaches driven by 3D data often fail to generalize effectively. To overcome these challenges, we introduce InsTex, a two-stage architecture designed to generate high-quality, style-consistent textures for 3D indoor scenes. InsTex utilizes depth-to-image diffusion priors in a coarse-to-fine pipeline, first generating multi-view images with a pre-trained 2D diffusion model and subsequently refining the textures for consistency. Our method supports both textual and visual prompts, achieving state-of-the-art results in visual quality and quantitative metrics, and demonstrates its effectiveness across various 3D texturing applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.13969v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yunfan Zhang, Zhiwei Xiong, Zhiqi Shen, Guosheng Lin, Hao Wang, Nicolas Vun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GS-LiDAR: Generating Realistic LiDAR Point Clouds with Panoramic Gaussian Splatting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.13971</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.13971v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: LiDAR novel view synthesis (NVS) has emerged as a novel task within LiDAR simulation, offering valuable simulated point cloud data from novel viewpoints to aid in autonomous driving systems. However, existing LiDAR NVS methods typically rely on neural radiance fields (NeRF) as their 3D representation, which incurs significant computational costs in both training and rendering. Moreover, NeRF and its variants are designed for symmetrical scenes, making them ill-suited for driving scenarios. To address these challenges, we propose GS-LiDAR, a novel framework for generating realistic LiDAR point clouds with panoramic Gaussian splatting. Our approach employs 2D Gaussian primitives with periodic vibration properties, allowing for precise geometric reconstruction of both static and dynamic elements in driving scenarios. We further introduce a novel panoramic rendering technique with explicit ray-splat intersection, guided by panoramic LiDAR supervision. By incorporating intensity and ray-drop spherical harmonic (SH) coefficients into the Gaussian primitives, we enhance the realism of the rendered point clouds. Extensive experiments on KITTI-360 and nuScenes demonstrate the superiority of our method in terms of quantitative metrics, visual quality, as well as training and rendering efficiency.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.13971v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junzhe Jiang, Chun Gu, Yurui Chen, Li Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Spatio-temporal Graph Network Allowing Incomplete Trajectory Input for Pedestrian Trajectory Prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.13973</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.13973v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Pedestrian trajectory prediction is important in the research of mobile robot navigation in environments with pedestrians. Most pedestrian trajectory prediction algorithms require the input historical trajectories to be complete. If a pedestrian is unobservable in any frame in the past, then its historical trajectory become incomplete, the algorithm will not predict its future trajectory. To address this limitation, we propose the STGN-IT, a spatio-temporal graph network allowing incomplete trajectory input, which can predict the future trajectories of pedestrians with incomplete historical trajectories. STGN-IT uses the spatio-temporal graph with an additional encoding method to represent the historical trajectories and observation states of pedestrians. Moreover, STGN-IT introduces static obstacles in the environment that may affect the future trajectories as nodes to further improve the prediction accuracy. A clustering algorithm is also applied in the construction of spatio-temporal graphs. Experiments on public datasets show that STGN-IT outperforms state of the art algorithms on these metrics.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.13973v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Juncen Long, Gianluca Bardaro, Simone Mentasti, Matteo Matteucci</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3DGS$^2$: Near Second-order Converging 3D Gaussian Splatting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.13975</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.13975v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: 3D Gaussian Splatting (3DGS) has emerged as a mainstream solution for novel view synthesis and 3D reconstruction. By explicitly encoding a 3D scene using a collection of Gaussian kernels, 3DGS achieves high-quality rendering with superior efficiency. As a learning-based approach, 3DGS training has been dealt with the standard stochastic gradient descent (SGD) method, which offers at most linear convergence. Consequently, training often requires tens of minutes, even with GPU acceleration. This paper introduces a (near) second-order convergent training algorithm for 3DGS, leveraging its unique properties. Our approach is inspired by two key observations. First, the attributes of a Gaussian kernel contribute independently to the image-space loss, which endorses isolated and local optimization algorithms. We exploit this by splitting the optimization at the level of individual kernel attributes, analytically constructing small-size Newton systems for each parameter group, and efficiently solving these systems on GPU threads. This achieves Newton-like convergence per training image without relying on the global Hessian. Second, kernels exhibit sparse and structured coupling across input images. This property allows us to effectively utilize spatial information to mitigate overshoot during stochastic training. Our method converges an order faster than standard GPU-based 3DGS training, requiring over $10\times$ fewer iterations while maintaining or surpassing the quality of the compared with the SGD-based 3DGS reconstructions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.13975v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lei Lan, Tianjia Shao, Zixuan Lu, Yu Zhang, Chenfanfu Jiang, Yin Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced PEC-YOLO for Detecting Improper Safety Gear Wearing Among Power Line Workers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.13981</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.13981v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: To address the high risks associated with improper use of safety gear in complex power line environments, where target occlusion and large variance are prevalent, this paper proposes an enhanced PEC-YOLO object detection algorithm. The method integrates deep perception with multi-scale feature fusion, utilizing PConv and EMA attention mechanisms to enhance feature extraction efficiency and minimize model complexity. The CPCA attention mechanism is incorporated into the SPPF module, improving the model's ability to focus on critical information and enhance detection accuracy, particularly in challenging conditions. Furthermore, the introduction of the BiFPN neck architecture optimizes the utilization of low-level and high-level features, enhancing feature representation through adaptive fusion and context-aware mechanism. Experimental results demonstrate that the proposed PEC-YOLO achieves a 2.7% improvement in detection accuracy compared to YOLOv8s, while reducing model parameters by 42.58%. Under identical conditions, PEC-YOLO outperforms other models in detection speed, meeting the stringent accuracy requirements for safety gear detection in construction sites. This study contributes to the development of efficient and accurate intelligent monitoring systems for ensuring worker safety in hazardous environments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.13981v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chen Zuguo, Kuang Aowei, Huang Yi, Jin Jie</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attribute-based Visual Reprogramming for Image Classification with CLIP</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.13982</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.13982v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Visual reprogramming (VR) reuses pre-trained vision models for downstream image classification tasks by adding trainable noise patterns to inputs. When applied to vision-language models (e.g., CLIP), existing VR approaches follow the same pipeline used in vision models (e.g., ResNet, ViT), where ground-truth class labels are inserted into fixed text templates to guide the optimization of VR patterns. This label-based approach, however, overlooks the rich information and diverse attribute-guided textual representations that CLIP can exploit, which may lead to the misclassification of samples. In this paper, we propose Attribute-based Visual Reprogramming (AttrVR) for CLIP, utilizing descriptive attributes (DesAttrs) and distinctive attributes (DistAttrs), which respectively represent common and unique feature descriptions for different classes. Besides, as images of the same class may reflect different attributes after VR, AttrVR iteratively refines patterns using the $k$-nearest DesAttrs and DistAttrs for each image sample, enabling more dynamic and sample-specific optimization. Theoretically, AttrVR is shown to reduce intra-class variance and increase inter-class separation. Empirically, it achieves superior performance in 12 downstream tasks for both ViT-based and ResNet-based CLIP. The success of AttrVR facilitates more effective integration of VR from unimodal vision models into vision-language models. Our code is available at https://github.com/tmlr-group/AttrVR.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.13982v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chengyi Cai, Zesheng Ye, Lei Feng, Jianzhong Qi, Feng Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CGI: Identifying Conditional Generative Models with Example Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.13991</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.13991v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Generative models have achieved remarkable performance recently, and thus model hubs have emerged. Existing model hubs typically assume basic text matching is sufficient to search for models. However, in reality, due to different abstractions and the large number of models in model hubs, it is not easy for users to review model descriptions and example images, choosing which model best meets their needs. Therefore, it is necessary to describe model functionality wisely so that future users can efficiently search for the most suitable model for their needs. Efforts to address this issue remain limited. In this paper, we propose Conditional Generative Model Identification (CGI), which aims to provide an effective way to identify the most suitable model using user-provided example images rather than requiring users to manually review a large number of models with example images. To address this problem, we propose the PromptBased Model Identification (PMI) , which can adequately describe model functionality and precisely match requirements with specifications. To evaluate PMI approach and promote related research, we provide a benchmark comprising 65 models and 9100 identification tasks. Extensive experimental and human evaluation results demonstrate that PMI is effective. For instance, 92% of models are correctly identified with significantly better FID scores when four example images are provided.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.13991v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhi Zhou, Hao-Zhe Tan, Peng-Xiao Song, Lan-Zhe Guo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CSAOT: Cooperative Multi-Agent System for Active Object Tracking</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.13994</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.13994v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Object Tracking is essential for many computer vision applications, such as autonomous navigation, surveillance, and robotics. Unlike Passive Object Tracking (POT), which relies on static camera viewpoints to detect and track objects across consecutive frames, Active Object Tracking (AOT) requires a controller agent to actively adjust its viewpoint to maintain visual contact with a moving target in complex environments. Existing AOT solutions are predominantly single-agent-based, which struggle in dynamic and complex scenarios due to limited information gathering and processing capabilities, often resulting in suboptimal decision-making. Alleviating these limitations necessitates the development of a multi-agent system where different agents perform distinct roles and collaborate to enhance learning and robustness in dynamic and complex environments. Although some multi-agent approaches exist for AOT, they typically rely on external auxiliary agents, which require additional devices, making them costly. In contrast, we introduce the Collaborative System for Active Object Tracking (CSAOT), a method that leverages multi-agent deep reinforcement learning (MADRL) and a Mixture of Experts (MoE) framework to enable multiple agents to operate on a single device, thereby improving tracking performance and reducing costs. Our approach enhances robustness against occlusions and rapid motion while optimizing camera movements to extend tracking duration. We validated the effectiveness of CSAOT on various interactive maps with dynamic and stationary obstacles.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.13994v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hy Nguyen, Bao Pham, Hung Du, Srikanth Thudumu, Rajesh Vasa, Kon Mouzakis</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Persian Lip Reading in Surena-V Humanoid Robot for Human-Robot Interaction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.13996</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.13996v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Lip reading is vital for robots in social settings, improving their ability to understand human communication. This skill allows them to communicate more easily in crowded environments, especially in caregiving and customer service roles. Generating a Persian Lip-reading dataset, this study integrates Persian lip-reading technology into the Surena-V humanoid robot to improve its speech recognition capabilities. Two complementary methods are explored, an indirect method using facial landmark tracking and a direct method leveraging convolutional neural networks (CNNs) and long short-term memory (LSTM) networks. The indirect method focuses on tracking key facial landmarks, especially around the lips, to infer movements, while the direct method processes raw video data for action and speech recognition. The best-performing model, LSTM, achieved 89\% accuracy and has been successfully implemented into the Surena-V robot for real-time human-robot interaction. The study highlights the effectiveness of these methods, particularly in environments where verbal communication is limited.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.13996v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ali Farshian Abbasi, Aghil Yousefi-Koma, Soheil Dehghani Firouzabadi, Parisa Rashidi, Alireza Naeini</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing kelp forest detection in remote sensing images using crowdsourced labels with Mixed Vision Transformers and ConvNeXt segmentation models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14001</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14001v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Kelp forests, as foundation species, are vital to marine ecosystems, providing essential food and habitat for numerous organisms. This study explores the integration of crowdsourced labels with advanced artificial intelligence models to develop a fast and accurate kelp canopy detection pipeline using Landsat images. Building on the success of a machine learning competition, where this approach ranked third and performed consistently well on both local validation and public and private leaderboards, the research highlights the effectiveness of combining Mixed Vision Transformers (MIT) with ConvNeXt models. Training these models on various image sizes significantly enhanced the accuracy of the ensemble results. U-Net emerged as the best segmentation architecture, with UpperNet also contributing to the final ensemble. Key Landsat bands, such as ShortWave InfraRed (SWIR1) and Near-InfraRed (NIR), were crucial while altitude data was used in postprocessing to eliminate false positives on land. The methodology achieved a high detection rate, accurately identifying about three out of four pixels containing kelp canopy while keeping false positives low. Despite the medium resolution of Landsat satellites, their extensive historical coverage makes them effective for studying kelp forests. This work also underscores the potential of combining machine learning models with crowdsourced data for effective and scalable environmental monitoring. All running code for training all models and inference can be found at https://github.com/IoannisNasios/Kelp_Forests.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14001v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1080/01431161.2024.2448307</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Ioannis Nasios</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ME-CPT: Multi-Task Enhanced Cross-Temporal Point Transformer for Urban 3D Change Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14004</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14004v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The point clouds collected by the Airborne Laser Scanning (ALS) system provide accurate 3D information of urban land covers. By utilizing multi-temporal ALS point clouds, semantic changes in urban area can be captured, demonstrating significant potential in urban planning, emergency management, and infrastructure maintenance. Existing 3D change detection methods struggle to efficiently extract multi-class semantic information and change features, still facing the following challenges: (1) the difficulty of accurately modeling cross-temporal point clouds spatial relationships for effective change feature extraction; (2) class imbalance of change samples which hinders distinguishability of semantic features; (3) the lack of real-world datasets for 3D semantic change detection. To resolve these challenges, we propose the Multi-task Enhanced Cross-temporal Point Transformer (ME-CPT) network. ME-CPT establishes spatiotemporal correspondences between point cloud across different epochs and employs attention mechanisms to jointly extract semantic change features, facilitating information exchange and change comparison. Additionally, we incorporate a semantic segmentation task and through the multi-task training strategy, further enhance the distinguishability of semantic features, reducing the impact of class imbalance in change types. Moreover, we release a 22.5 $km^2$ 3D semantic change detection dataset, offering diverse scenes for comprehensive evaluation. Experiments on multiple datasets show that the proposed MT-CPT achieves superior performance compared to existing state-of-the-art methods. The source code and dataset will be released upon acceptance at \url{https://github.com/zhangluqi0209/ME-CPT}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14004v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Luqi Zhang, Haiping Wang, Chong Liu, Zhen Dong, Bisheng Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Device-aware Optical Adversarial Attack for a Portable Projector-camera System</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14005</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14005v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Deep-learning-based face recognition (FR) systems are susceptible to adversarial examples in both digital and physical domains. Physical attacks present a greater threat to deployed systems as adversaries can easily access the input channel, allowing them to provide malicious inputs to impersonate a victim. This paper addresses the limitations of existing projector-camera-based adversarial light attacks in practical FR setups. By incorporating device-aware adaptations into the digital attack algorithm, such as resolution-aware and color-aware adjustments, we mitigate the degradation from digital to physical domains. Experimental validation showcases the efficacy of our proposed algorithm against real and spoof adversaries, achieving high physical similarity scores in FR models and state-of-the-art commercial systems. On average, there is only a 14% reduction in scores from digital to physical attacks, with high attack success rate in both white- and black-box scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14005v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ning Jiang (School of Software &amp; Microelectronics, Peking University, Beijing, China, Mashang Consumer Finance Co., Ltd., Chongqing, China), Yanhong Liu (Mashang Consumer Finance Co., Ltd., Chongqing, China), Dingheng Zeng (Mashang Consumer Finance Co., Ltd., Chongqing, China), Yue Feng (Mashang Consumer Finance Co., Ltd., Chongqing, China), Weihong Deng (Mashang Consumer Finance Co., Ltd., Chongqing, China), Ying Li (School of Software &amp; Microelectronics, Peking University, Beijing, China)</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INDIGO+: A Unified INN-Guided Probabilistic Diffusion Algorithm for Blind and Non-Blind Image Restoration</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14014</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14014v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Generative diffusion models are becoming one of the most popular prior in image restoration (IR) tasks due to their remarkable ability to generate realistic natural images. Despite achieving satisfactory results, IR methods based on diffusion models present several limitations. First of all, most non-blind approaches require an analytical expression of the degradation model to guide the sampling process. Secondly, most existing blind approaches rely on families of pre-defined degradation models for training their deep networks. The above issues limit the flexibility of these approaches and so their ability to handle real-world degradation tasks. In this paper, we propose a novel INN-guided probabilistic diffusion algorithm for non-blind and blind image restoration, namely INDIGO and BlindINDIGO, which combines the merits of the perfect reconstruction property of invertible neural networks (INN) with the strong generative capabilities of pre-trained diffusion models. Specifically, we train the forward process of the INN to simulate an arbitrary degradation process and use the inverse to obtain an intermediate image that we use to guide the reverse diffusion sampling process through a gradient step. We also introduce an initialization strategy, to further improve the performance and inference speed of our algorithm. Experiments demonstrate that our algorithm obtains competitive results compared with recently leading methods both quantitatively and visually on synthetic and real-world low-quality images.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14014v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1109/jstsp.2024.3454957</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Di You, Pier Luigi Dragotti</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implicit Neural Surface Deformation with Explicit Velocity Fields</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14038</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14038v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this work, we introduce the first unsupervised method that simultaneously predicts time-varying neural implicit surfaces and deformations between pairs of point clouds. We propose to model the point movement using an explicit velocity field and directly deform a time-varying implicit field using the modified level-set equation. This equation utilizes an iso-surface evolution with Eikonal constraints in a compact formulation, ensuring the integrity of the signed distance field. By applying a smooth, volume-preserving constraint to the velocity field, our method successfully recovers physically plausible intermediate shapes. Our method is able to handle both rigid and non-rigid deformations without any intermediate shape supervision. Our experimental results demonstrate that our method significantly outperforms existing works, delivering superior results in both quality and efficiency.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14038v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lu Sang, Zehranaz Canfes, Dongliang Cao, Florian Bernard, Daniel Cremers</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM-guided Instance-level Image Manipulation with Diffusion U-Net Cross-Attention Maps</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14046</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14046v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The advancement of text-to-image synthesis has introduced powerful generative models capable of creating realistic images from textual prompts. However, precise control over image attributes remains challenging, especially at the instance level. While existing methods offer some control through fine-tuning or auxiliary information, they often face limitations in flexibility and accuracy. To address these challenges, we propose a pipeline leveraging Large Language Models (LLMs), open-vocabulary detectors, cross-attention maps and intermediate activations of diffusion U-Net for instance-level image manipulation. Our method detects objects mentioned in the prompt and present in the generated image, enabling precise manipulation without extensive training or input masks. By incorporating cross-attention maps, our approach ensures coherence in manipulated images while controlling object positions. Our method enables precise manipulations at the instance level without fine-tuning or auxiliary information such as masks or bounding boxes. Code is available at https://github.com/Palandr123/DiffusionU-NetLLM</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14046v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Andrey Palaev, Adil Khan, Syed M. Ahsan Kazmi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting CLIP: Efficient Alignment of 3D MRI and Tabular Data using Domain-Specific Foundation Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14051</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14051v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Multi-modal models require aligned, shared embedding spaces. However, common CLIP-based approaches need large amounts of samples and do not natively support 3D or tabular data, both of which are crucial in the medical domain. To address these issues, we revisit CLIP-style alignment by training a domain-specific 3D foundation model as an image encoder and demonstrate that modality alignment is feasible with only 62 MRI scans. Our approach is enabled by a simple embedding accumulation strategy required for training in 3D, which scales the amount of negative pairs across batches in order to stabilize training. We perform a thorough evaluation of various design choices, including the choice of backbone and loss functions, and evaluate the proposed methodology on zero-shot classification and image-retrieval tasks. While zero-shot image-retrieval remains challenging, zero-shot classification results demonstrate that the proposed approach can meaningfully align the representations of 3D MRI with tabular data.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14051v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jakob Krogh Petersen, Valdemar Licht, Mads Nielsen, Asbj{\o}rn Munk</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prior Knowledge Injection into Deep Learning Models Predicting Gene Expression from Whole Slide Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14056</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14056v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Cancer diagnosis and prognosis primarily depend on clinical parameters such as age and tumor grade, and are increasingly complemented by molecular data, such as gene expression, from tumor sequencing. However, sequencing is costly and delays oncology workflows. Recent advances in Deep Learning allow to predict molecular information from morphological features within Whole Slide Images (WSIs), offering a cost-effective proxy of the molecular markers. While promising, current methods lack the robustness to fully replace direct sequencing. Here we aim to improve existing methods by introducing a model-agnostic framework that allows to inject prior knowledge on gene-gene interactions into Deep Learning architectures, thereby increasing accuracy and robustness. We design the framework to be generic and flexibly adaptable to a wide range of architectures. In a case study on breast cancer, our strategy leads to an average increase of 983 significant genes (out of 25,761) across all 18 experiments, with 14 generalizing to an increase on an independent dataset. Our findings reveal a high potential for injection of prior knowledge to increase gene expression prediction performance from WSIs across a wide range of architectures.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14056v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Max Hallemeesch, Marija Pizurica, Paloma Rabaey, Olivier Gevaert, Thomas Demeester, Kathleen Marchal</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Expanding on the BRIAR Dataset: A Comprehensive Whole Body Biometric Recognition Resource at Extreme Distances and Real-World Scenarios (Collections 1-4)</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14070</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14070v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The state-of-the-art in biometric recognition algorithms and operational systems has advanced quickly in recent years providing high accuracy and robustness in more challenging collection environments and consumer applications. However, the technology still suffers greatly when applied to non-conventional settings such as those seen when performing identification at extreme distances or from elevated cameras on buildings or mounted to UAVs. This paper summarizes an extension to the largest dataset currently focused on addressing these operational challenges, and describes its composition as well as methodologies of collection, curation, and annotation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14070v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gavin Jager, David Cornett III, Gavin Glenn, Deniz Aykac, Christi Johnson, Robert Zhang, Ryan Shivers, David Bolme, Laura Davies, Scott Dolvin, Nell Barber, Joel Brogan, Nick Burchfield, Carl Dukes, Andrew Duncan, Regina Ferrell, Austin Garrett, Jim Goddard, Jairus Hines, Bart Murphy, Sean Pharris, Brandon Stockwell, Leanne Thompson, Matthew Yohe</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>StreamingRAG: Real-time Contextual Retrieval and Generation Framework</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14101</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14101v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Extracting real-time insights from multi-modal data streams from various domains such as healthcare, intelligent transportation, and satellite remote sensing remains a challenge. High computational demands and limited knowledge scope restrict the applicability of Multi-Modal Large Language Models (MM-LLMs) on these data streams. Traditional Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) systems address knowledge limitations of these models, but suffer from slow preprocessing, making them unsuitable for real-time analysis. We propose StreamingRAG, a novel RAG framework designed for streaming data. StreamingRAG constructs evolving knowledge graphs capturing scene-object-entity relationships in real-time. The knowledge graph achieves temporal-aware scene representations using MM-LLMs and enables timely responses for specific events or user queries. StreamingRAG addresses limitations in existing methods, achieving significant improvements in real-time analysis (5-6x faster throughput), contextual accuracy (through a temporal knowledge graph), and reduced resource consumption (using lightweight models by 2-3x).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14101v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Murugan Sankaradas, Ravi K. Rajendran, Srimat T. Chakradhar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SelfPrompt: Confidence-Aware Semi-Supervised Tuning for Robust Vision-Language Model Adaptation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14148</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14148v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present SelfPrompt, a novel prompt-tuning approach for vision-language models (VLMs) in a semi-supervised learning setup. Existing methods for tuning VLMs in semi-supervised setups struggle with the negative impact of the miscalibrated VLMs on pseudo-labelling, and the accumulation of noisy pseudo-labels. SelfPrompt addresses these challenges by introducing a cluster-guided pseudo-labelling method that improves pseudo-label accuracy, and a confidence-aware semi-supervised learning module that maximizes the utilization of unlabelled data by combining supervised learning and weakly-supervised learning. Additionally, we investigate our method in an active semi-supervised learning setup, where the labelled set is strategically selected to ensure the best utilization of a limited labelling budget. To this end, we propose a weakly-supervised sampling technique that selects a diverse and representative labelled set, which can be seamlessly integrated into existing methods to enhance their performance. We conduct extensive evaluations across 13 datasets, significantly surpassing state-of-the-art performances with average improvements of 6.23% in standard semi-supervised learning, 6.25% in active semi-supervised learning, and 4.9% in base-to-novel generalization, using a 2-shot setup. Furthermore, SelfPrompt shows excellent generalization in single-shot settings, achieving an average improvement of 11.78%.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14148v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shuvendu Roy, Ali Etemad</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Defect Detection Using Instance Segmentation for NDI</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14149</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14149v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Ultrasonic testing is a common Non-Destructive Inspection (NDI) method used in aerospace manufacturing. However, the complexity and size of the ultrasonic scans make it challenging to identify defects through visual inspection or machine learning models. Using computer vision techniques to identify defects from ultrasonic scans is an evolving research area. In this study, we used instance segmentation to identify the presence of defects in the ultrasonic scan images of composite panels that are representative of real components manufactured in aerospace. We used two models based on Mask-RCNN (Detectron 2) and YOLO 11 respectively. Additionally, we implemented a simple statistical pre-processing technique that reduces the burden of requiring custom-tailored pre-processing techniques. Our study demonstrates the feasibility and effectiveness of using instance segmentation in the NDI pipeline by significantly reducing data pre-processing time, inspection time, and overall costs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14149v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ashiqur Rahman, Venkata Devesh Reddy Seethi, Austin Yunker, Zachary Kral, Rajkumar Kettimuthu, Hamed Alhoori</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing MRI Reconstruction: A Systematic Review of Deep Learning and Compressed Sensing Integration</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14158</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14158v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) is a non-invasive imaging modality and provides comprehensive anatomical and functional insights into the human body. However, its long acquisition times can lead to patient discomfort, motion artifacts, and limiting real-time applications. To address these challenges, strategies such as parallel imaging have been applied, which utilize multiple receiver coils to speed up the data acquisition process. Additionally, compressed sensing (CS) is a method that facilitates image reconstruction from sparse data, significantly reducing image acquisition time by minimizing the amount of data collection needed. Recently, deep learning (DL) has emerged as a powerful tool for improving MRI reconstruction. It has been integrated with parallel imaging and CS principles to achieve faster and more accurate MRI reconstructions. This review comprehensively examines DL-based techniques for MRI reconstruction. We categorize and discuss various DL-based methods, including end-to-end approaches, unrolled optimization, and federated learning, highlighting their potential benefits. Our systematic review highlights significant contributions and underscores the potential of DL in MRI reconstruction. Additionally, we summarize key results and trends in DL-based MRI reconstruction, including quantitative metrics, the dataset, acceleration factors, and the progress of and research interest in DL techniques over time. Finally, we discuss potential future directions and the importance of DL-based MRI reconstruction in advancing medical imaging. To facilitate further research in this area, we provide a GitHub repository that includes up-to-date DL-based MRI reconstruction publications and public datasets-https://github.com/mosaf/Awesome-DL-based-CS-MRI.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14158v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>physics.med-ph</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mojtaba Safari, Zach Eidex, Chih-Wei Chang, Richard L. J. Qiu, Xiaofeng Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Multimodal Entity Linking with Jaccard Distance-based Conditional Contrastive Learning and Contextual Visual Augmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14166</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14166v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Previous research on multimodal entity linking (MEL) has primarily employed contrastive learning as the primary objective. However, using the rest of the batch as negative samples without careful consideration, these studies risk leveraging easy features and potentially overlook essential details that make entities unique. In this work, we propose JD-CCL (Jaccard Distance-based Conditional Contrastive Learning), a novel approach designed to enhance the ability to match multimodal entity linking models. JD-CCL leverages meta-information to select negative samples with similar attributes, making the linking task more challenging and robust. Additionally, to address the limitations caused by the variations within the visual modality among mentions and entities, we introduce a novel method, CVaCPT (Contextual Visual-aid Controllable Patch Transform). It enhances visual representations by incorporating multi-view synthetic images and contextual textual representations to scale and shift patch representations. Experimental results on benchmark MEL datasets demonstrate the strong effectiveness of our approach.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14166v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Cong-Duy Nguyen, Xiaobao Wu, Thong Nguyen, Shuai Zhao, Khoi Le, Viet-Anh Nguyen, Feng Yichao, Anh Tuan Luu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dreamweaver: Learning Compositional World Representations from Pixels</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14174</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14174v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Humans have an innate ability to decompose their perceptions of the world into objects and their attributes, such as colors, shapes, and movement patterns. This cognitive process enables us to imagine novel futures by recombining familiar concepts. However, replicating this ability in artificial intelligence systems has proven challenging, particularly when it comes to modeling videos into compositional concepts and generating unseen, recomposed futures without relying on auxiliary data, such as text, masks, or bounding boxes. In this paper, we propose Dreamweaver, a neural architecture designed to discover hierarchical and compositional representations from raw videos and generate compositional future simulations. Our approach leverages a novel Recurrent Block-Slot Unit (RBSU) to decompose videos into their constituent objects and attributes. In addition, Dreamweaver uses a multi-future-frame prediction objective to capture disentangled representations for dynamic concepts more effectively as well as static concepts. In experiments, we demonstrate our model outperforms current state-of-the-art baselines for world modeling when evaluated under the DCI framework across multiple datasets. Furthermore, we show how the modularized concept representations of our model enable compositional imagination, allowing the generation of novel videos by recombining attributes from different objects.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14174v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junyeob Baek, Yi-Fu Wu, Gautam Singh, Sungjin Ahn</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post-hoc Spurious Correlation Neutralization with Single-Weight Fictitious Class Unlearning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14182</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14182v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Neural network training tends to exploit the simplest features as shortcuts to greedily minimize training loss. However, some of these features might be spuriously correlated with the target labels, leading to incorrect predictions by the model. Several methods have been proposed to address this issue. Focusing on suppressing the spurious correlations with model training, they not only incur additional training cost, but also have limited practical utility as the model misbehavior due to spurious relations is usually discovered after its deployment. It is also often overlooked that spuriousness is a subjective notion. Hence, the precise questions that must be investigated are; to what degree a feature is spurious, and how we can proportionally distract the model's attention from it for reliable prediction. To this end, we propose a method that enables post-hoc neutralization of spurious feature impact, controllable to an arbitrary degree. We conceptualize spurious features as fictitious sub-classes within the original classes, which can be eliminated by a class removal scheme. We then propose a unique precise class removal technique that employs a single-weight modification, which entails negligible performance compromise for the remaining classes. We perform extensive experiments, demonstrating that by editing just a single weight in a post-hoc manner, our method achieves highly competitive, or better performance against the state-of-the-art methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14182v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shahin Hakemi, Naveed Akhtar, Ghulam Mubashar Hassan, Ajmal Mian</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Precision Fabric Defect Detection via Adaptive Shape Convolutions and Large Kernel Spatial Modeling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14190</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14190v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Detecting fabric defects in the textile industry remains a challenging task due to the diverse and complex nature of defect patterns. Traditional methods often suffer from slow inference speeds, limited accuracy, and inadequate recognition rates, particularly in scenarios involving intricate or subtle defects. To overcome these limitations, we introduce Fab-ASLKS, an advanced fabric defect detection framework built upon the YOLOv8s architecture. Fab-ASLKS incorporates two key modules: (1) the Adaptive Shape Convolution Module (ASCM), which leverages adaptive shape convolution within the Neck to enhance feature fusion and improve efficiency by extending the capabilities of the standard C2f structure, and (2) the Large Kernel Shift Convolution Module (LKSCM), designed to emulate large kernel effects within the Backbone, enabling superior spatial information extraction. These modules collaboratively optimize feature extraction and information integration across the network. Extensive experiments conducted on the Tianchi fabric defect detection dataset demonstrate that Fab-ASLKS achieves a 5% improvement in mAP@50 over the baseline, showcasing its capability to deliver high precision and efficiency.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14190v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shuai Wang, Yang Xu, Hui Zheng, Baotian Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ENTER: Event Based Interpretable Reasoning for VideoQA</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14194</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14194v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this paper, we present ENTER, an interpretable Video Question Answering (VideoQA) system based on event graphs. Event graphs convert videos into graphical representations, where video events form the nodes and event-event relationships (temporal/causal/hierarchical) form the edges. This structured representation offers many benefits: 1) Interpretable VideoQA via generated code that parses event-graph; 2) Incorporation of contextual visual information in the reasoning process (code generation) via event graphs; 3) Robust VideoQA via Hierarchical Iterative Update of the event graphs. Existing interpretable VideoQA systems are often top-down, disregarding low-level visual information in the reasoning plan generation, and are brittle. While bottom-up approaches produce responses from visual data, they lack interpretability. Experimental results on NExT-QA, IntentQA, and EgoSchema demonstrate that not only does our method outperform existing top-down approaches while obtaining competitive performance against bottom-up approaches, but more importantly, offers superior interpretability and explainability in the reasoning process.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14194v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hammad Ayyubi, Junzhang Liu, Ali Asgarov, Zaber Ibn Abdul Hakim, Najibul Haque Sarker, Zhecan Wang, Chia-Wei Tang, Hani Alomari, Md. Atabuzzaman, Xudong Lin, Naveen Reddy Dyava, Shih-Fu Chang, Chris Thomas</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VideoShield: Regulating Diffusion-based Video Generation Models via Watermarking</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14195</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14195v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Artificial Intelligence Generated Content (AIGC) has advanced significantly, particularly with the development of video generation models such as text-to-video (T2V) models and image-to-video (I2V) models. However, like other AIGC types, video generation requires robust content control. A common approach is to embed watermarks, but most research has focused on images, with limited attention given to videos. Traditional methods, which embed watermarks frame-by-frame in a post-processing manner, often degrade video quality. In this paper, we propose VideoShield, a novel watermarking framework specifically designed for popular diffusion-based video generation models. Unlike post-processing methods, VideoShield embeds watermarks directly during video generation, eliminating the need for additional training. To ensure video integrity, we introduce a tamper localization feature that can detect changes both temporally (across frames) and spatially (within individual frames). Our method maps watermark bits to template bits, which are then used to generate watermarked noise during the denoising process. Using DDIM Inversion, we can reverse the video to its original watermarked noise, enabling straightforward watermark extraction. Additionally, template bits allow precise detection for potential temporal and spatial modification. Extensive experiments across various video models (both T2V and I2V models) demonstrate that our method effectively extracts watermarks and detects tamper without compromising video quality. Furthermore, we show that this approach is applicable to image generation models, enabling tamper detection in generated images as well. Codes and models are available at \href{https://github.com/hurunyi/VideoShield}{https://github.com/hurunyi/VideoShield}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14195v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Runyi Hu, Jie Zhang, Yiming Li, Jiwei Li, Qing Guo, Han Qiu, Tianwei Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Token Reduction during Generation for Vision Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14204</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14204v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Vision-Language Models (VLMs) have achieved notable success in multimodal tasks but face practical limitations due to the quadratic complexity of decoder attention mechanisms and autoregressive generation. Existing methods like FASTV and VTW have achieved notable results in reducing redundant visual tokens, but these approaches focus on pruning tokens in a single forward pass without systematically analyzing the redundancy of visual tokens throughout the entire generation process. In this paper, we introduce a dynamic pruning strategy tailored for VLMs, namedDynamic Rate (DyRate), which progressively adjusts the compression rate during generation. Our analysis of the distribution of attention reveals that the importance of visual tokens decreases throughout the generation process, inspiring us to adopt a more aggressive compression rate. By integrating a lightweight predictor based on attention distribution, our approach enables flexible adjustment of pruning rates based on the attention distribution. Our experimental results demonstrate that our method not only reduces computational demands but also maintains the quality of responses.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14204v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoyu Liang, Chaofeng Guan, Jiaying Lu, Huiyao Chen, Huan Wang, Haoji Hu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PuzzleGPT: Emulating Human Puzzle-Solving Ability for Time and Location Prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14210</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14210v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The task of predicting time and location from images is challenging and requires complex human-like puzzle-solving ability over different clues. In this work, we formalize this ability into core skills and implement them using different modules in an expert pipeline called PuzzleGPT. PuzzleGPT consists of a perceiver to identify visual clues, a reasoner to deduce prediction candidates, a combiner to combinatorially combine information from different clues, a web retriever to get external knowledge if the task can't be solved locally, and a noise filter for robustness. This results in a zero-shot, interpretable, and robust approach that records state-of-the-art performance on two datasets -- TARA and WikiTilo. PuzzleGPT outperforms large VLMs such as BLIP-2, InstructBLIP, LLaVA, and even GPT-4V, as well as automatically generated reasoning pipelines like VisProg, by at least 32% and 38%, respectively. It even rivals or surpasses finetuned models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14210v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hammad Ayyubi, Xuande Feng, Junzhang Liu, Xudong Lin, Zhecan Wang, Shih-Fu Chang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Detection and Classification of Acute Lymphoblastic Leukemia Utilizing Deep Transfer Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14228</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14228v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: A mutation in the DNA of a single cell that compromises its function initiates leukemia,leading to the overproduction of immature white blood cells that encroach upon the space required for the generation of healthy blood cells.Leukemia is treatable if identified in its initial stages. However,its diagnosis is both arduous and time consuming. This study proposes a novel approach for diagnosing leukemia across four stages Benign,Early,Pre,and Pro using deep learning techniques.We employed two Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) models as MobileNetV2 with an altered head and a custom model. The custom model consists of multiple convolutional layers,each paired with corresponding max pooling layers.We utilized MobileNetV2 with ImageNet weights,adjusting the head to integrate the final results.The dataset used is the publicly available "Acute Lymphoblastic Leukemia (ALL) Image Dataset", and we applied the Synthetic Minority Oversampling Technique (SMOTE) to augment and balance the training dataset.The custom model achieved an accuracy of 98.6%, while MobileNetV2 attained a superior accuracy of 99.69%. The pretrained model showed promising results,indicating an increased likelihood of real-world application.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14228v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Md. Abu Ahnaf Mollick, Md. Mahfujur Rahman, D. M. Asadujjaman, Abdullah Tamim, Nosin Anjum Dristi, Md. Takbir Hossen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GreedyPixel: Fine-Grained Black-Box Adversarial Attack Via Greedy Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14230</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14230v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: A critical requirement for deep learning models is ensuring their robustness against adversarial attacks. These attacks commonly introduce noticeable perturbations, compromising the visual fidelity of adversarial examples. Another key challenge is that while white-box algorithms can generate effective adversarial perturbations, they require access to the model gradients, limiting their practicality in many real-world scenarios. Existing attack mechanisms struggle to achieve similar efficacy without access to these gradients. In this paper, we introduce GreedyPixel, a novel pixel-wise greedy algorithm designed to generate high-quality adversarial examples using only query-based feedback from the target model. GreedyPixel improves computational efficiency in what is typically a brute-force process by perturbing individual pixels in sequence, guided by a pixel-wise priority map. This priority map is constructed by ranking gradients obtained from a surrogate model, providing a structured path for perturbation. Our results demonstrate that GreedyPixel achieves attack success rates comparable to white-box methods without the need for gradient information, and surpasses existing algorithms in black-box settings, offering higher success rates, reduced computational time, and imperceptible perturbations. These findings underscore the advantages of GreedyPixel in terms of attack efficacy, time efficiency, and visual quality.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14230v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hanrui Wang, Ching-Chun Chang, Chun-Shien Lu, Christopher Leckie, Isao Echizen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Micro-macro Wavelet-based Gaussian Splatting for 3D Reconstruction from Unconstrained Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14231</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14231v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: 3D reconstruction from unconstrained image collections presents substantial challenges due to varying appearances and transient occlusions. In this paper, we introduce Micro-macro Wavelet-based Gaussian Splatting (MW-GS), a novel approach designed to enhance 3D reconstruction by disentangling scene representations into global, refined, and intrinsic components. The proposed method features two key innovations: Micro-macro Projection, which allows Gaussian points to capture details from feature maps across multiple scales with enhanced diversity; and Wavelet-based Sampling, which leverages frequency domain information to refine feature representations and significantly improve the modeling of scene appearances. Additionally, we incorporate a Hierarchical Residual Fusion Network to seamlessly integrate these features. Extensive experiments demonstrate that MW-GS delivers state-of-the-art rendering performance, surpassing existing methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14231v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yihui Li, Chengxin Lv, Hongyu Yang, Di Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Point-LN: A Lightweight Framework for Efficient Point Cloud Classification Using Non-Parametric Positional Encoding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14238</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14238v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We introduce Point-LN, a novel lightweight framework engineered for efficient 3D point cloud classification. Point-LN integrates essential non-parametric components-such as Farthest Point Sampling (FPS), k-Nearest Neighbors (k-NN), and non-learnable positional encoding-with a streamlined learnable classifier that significantly enhances classification accuracy while maintaining a minimal parameter footprint. This hybrid architecture ensures low computational costs and rapid inference speeds, making Point-LN ideal for real-time and resource-constrained applications. Comprehensive evaluations on benchmark datasets, including ModelNet40 and ScanObjectNN, demonstrate that Point-LN achieves competitive performance compared to state-of-the-art methods, all while offering exceptional efficiency. These results establish Point-LN as a robust and scalable solution for diverse point cloud classification tasks, highlighting its potential for widespread adoption in various computer vision applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14238v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Marzieh Mohammadi, Amir Salarpour, Pedram MohajerAnsari</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Neural Networks for One-to-Many Mapping in Image Enhancement</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14265</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14265v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In image enhancement tasks, such as low-light and underwater image enhancement, a degraded image can correspond to multiple plausible target images due to dynamic photography conditions, such as variations in illumination. This naturally results in a one-to-many mapping challenge. To address this, we propose a Bayesian Enhancement Model (BEM) that incorporates Bayesian Neural Networks (BNNs) to capture data uncertainty and produce diverse outputs. To achieve real-time inference, we introduce a two-stage approach: Stage I employs a BNN to model the one-to-many mappings in the low-dimensional space, while Stage II refines fine-grained image details using a Deterministic Neural Network (DNN). To accelerate BNN training and convergence, we introduce a dynamic \emph{Momentum Prior}. Extensive experiments on multiple low-light and underwater image enhancement benchmarks demonstrate the superiority of our method over deterministic models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14265v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Guoxi Huang, Nantheera Anantrasirichai, Fei Ye, Zipeng Qi, RuiRui Lin, Qirui Yang, David Bull</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global Semantic-Guided Sub-image Feature Weight Allocation in High-Resolution Large Vision-Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14276</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14276v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: As the demand for high-resolution image processing in Large Vision-Language Models (LVLMs) grows, sub-image partitioning has become a popular approach for mitigating visual information loss associated with fixed-resolution processing. However, existing partitioning methods uniformly process sub-images, resulting in suboptimal image understanding. In this work, we reveal that the sub-images with higher semantic relevance to the entire image encapsulate richer visual information for preserving the model's visual understanding ability. Therefore, we propose the Global Semantic-guided Weight Allocator (GSWA) module, which dynamically allocates weights to sub-images based on their relative information density, emulating human visual attention mechanisms. This approach enables the model to focus on more informative regions, overcoming the limitations of uniform treatment. We integrate GSWA into the InternVL2-2B framework to create SleighVL, a lightweight yet high-performing model. Extensive experiments demonstrate that SleighVL outperforms models with comparable parameters and remains competitive with larger models. Our work provides a promising direction for more efficient and contextually aware high-resolution image processing in LVLMs, advancing multimodal system development.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14276v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuxuan Liang, Xu Li, Xiaolei Chen, Haotian Chen, Yi Zheng, Chenghang Lai, Bin Li, Xiangyang Xue</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dense-SfM: Structure from Motion with Dense Consistent Matching</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14277</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14277v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present Dense-SfM, a novel Structure from Motion (SfM) framework designed for dense and accurate 3D reconstruction from multi-view images. Sparse keypoint matching, which traditional SfM methods often rely on, limits both accuracy and point density, especially in texture-less areas. Dense-SfM addresses this limitation by integrating dense matching with a Gaussian Splatting (GS) based track extension which gives more consistent, longer feature tracks. To further improve reconstruction accuracy, Dense-SfM is equipped with a multi-view kernelized matching module leveraging transformer and Gaussian Process architectures, for robust track refinement across multi-views. Evaluations on the ETH3D and Texture-Poor SfM datasets show that Dense-SfM offers significant improvements in accuracy and density over state-of-the-art methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14277v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>JongMin Lee, Sungjoo Yoo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TD-RD: A Top-Down Benchmark with Real-Time Framework for Road Damage Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14302</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14302v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Object detection has witnessed remarkable advancements over the past decade, largely driven by breakthroughs in deep learning and the proliferation of large scale datasets. However, the domain of road damage detection remains relatively under explored, despite its critical significance for applications such as infrastructure maintenance and road safety. This paper addresses this gap by introducing a novel top down benchmark that offers a complementary perspective to existing datasets, specifically tailored for road damage detection. Our proposed Top Down Road Damage Detection Dataset (TDRD) includes three primary categories of road damage cracks, potholes, and patches captured from a top down viewpoint. The dataset consists of 7,088 high resolution images, encompassing 12,882 annotated instances of road damage. Additionally, we present a novel real time object detection framework, TDYOLOV10, designed to handle the unique challenges posed by the TDRD dataset. Comparative studies with state of the art models demonstrate competitive baseline results. By releasing TDRD, we aim to accelerate research in this crucial area. A sample of the dataset will be made publicly available upon the paper's acceptance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14302v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xi Xiao, Zhengji Li, Wentao Wang, Jiacheng Xie, Houjie Lin, Swalpa Kumar Roy, Tianyang Wang, Min Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Additive Manufacturing Processes Protocol Prediction by Artificial Intelligence using X-ray Computed Tomography data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14306</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14306v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The quality of the part fabricated from the Additive Manufacturing (AM) process depends upon the process parameters used, and therefore, optimization is required for apt quality. A methodology is proposed to set these parameters non-iteratively without human intervention. It utilizes Artificial Intelligence (AI) to fully automate the process, with the capability to self-train any apt AI model by further assimilating the training data.This study includes three commercially available 3D printers for soft material printing based on the Material Extrusion (MEX) AM process. The samples are 3D printed for six different AM process parameters obtained by varying layer height and nozzle speed. The novelty part of the methodology is incorporating an AI-based image segmentation step in the decision-making stage that uses quality inspected training data from the Non-Destructive Testing (NDT) method. The performance of the trained AI model is compared with the two software tools based on the classical thresholding method. The AI-based Artificial Neural Network (ANN) model is trained from NDT-assessed and AI-segmented data to automate the selection of optimized process parameters. The AI-based model is 99.3 % accurate, while the best available commercial classical image method is 83.44 % accurate. The best value of overall R for training ANN is 0.82. The MEX process gives a 22.06 % porosity error relative to the design. The NDT-data trained two AI models integrated into a series pipeline for optimal process parameters are proposed and verified by classical optimization and mechanical testing methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14306v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>physics.app-ph</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sunita Khod, Akshay Dvivedi, Mayank Goswami</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Primitive Relations for Compositional Zero-Shot Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14308</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14308v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Compositional Zero-Shot Learning (CZSL) aims to identify unseen state-object compositions by leveraging knowledge learned from seen compositions. Existing approaches often independently predict states and objects, overlooking their relationships. In this paper, we propose a novel framework, learning primitive relations (LPR), designed to probabilistically capture the relationships between states and objects. By employing the cross-attention mechanism, LPR considers the dependencies between states and objects, enabling the model to infer the likelihood of unseen compositions. Experimental results demonstrate that LPR outperforms state-of-the-art methods on all three CZSL benchmark datasets in both closed-world and open-world settings. Through qualitative analysis, we show that LPR leverages state-object relationships for unseen composition prediction.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14308v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Insu Lee, Jiseob Kim, Kyuhong Shim, Byonghyo Shim</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BrainGuard: Privacy-Preserving Multisubject Image Reconstructions from Brain Activities</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14309</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14309v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Reconstructing perceived images from human brain activity forms a crucial link between human and machine learning through Brain-Computer Interfaces. Early methods primarily focused on training separate models for each individual to account for individual variability in brain activity, overlooking valuable cross-subject commonalities. Recent advancements have explored multisubject methods, but these approaches face significant challenges, particularly in data privacy and effectively managing individual variability. To overcome these challenges, we introduce BrainGuard, a privacy-preserving collaborative training framework designed to enhance image reconstruction from multisubject fMRI data while safeguarding individual privacy. BrainGuard employs a collaborative global-local architecture where individual models are trained on each subject's local data and operate in conjunction with a shared global model that captures and leverages cross-subject patterns. This architecture eliminates the need to aggregate fMRI data across subjects, thereby ensuring privacy preservation. To tackle the complexity of fMRI data, BrainGuard integrates a hybrid synchronization strategy, enabling individual models to dynamically incorporate parameters from the global model. By establishing a secure and collaborative training environment, BrainGuard not only protects sensitive brain data but also improves the image reconstructions accuracy. Extensive experiments demonstrate that BrainGuard sets a new benchmark in both high-level and low-level metrics, advancing the state-of-the-art in brain decoding through its innovative design.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14309v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhibo Tian, Ruijie Quan, Fan Ma, Kun Zhan, Yi Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PAID: A Framework of Product-Centric Advertising Image Design</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14316</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14316v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In E-commerce platforms, a full advertising image is composed of a background image and marketing taglines. Automatic ad image design reduces human costs and plays a crucial role. For the convenience of users, a novel automatic framework named Product-Centric Advertising Image Design (PAID) is proposed in this work. PAID takes the product foreground image, required taglines, and target size as input and creates an ad image automatically. PAID consists of four sequential stages: prompt generation, layout generation, background image generation, and graphics rendering. Different expert models are trained to conduct these sub-tasks. A visual language model (VLM) based prompt generation model is leveraged to produce a product-matching background prompt. The layout generation model jointly predicts text and image layout according to the background prompt, product, and taglines to achieve the best harmony. An SDXL-based layout-controlled inpainting model is trained to generate an aesthetic background image. Previous ad image design methods take a background image as input and then predict the layout of taglines, which limits the spatial layout due to fixed image content. Innovatively, our PAID adjusts the stages to produce an unrestricted layout. To complete the PAID framework, we created two high-quality datasets, PITA and PIL. Extensive experimental results show that PAID creates more visually pleasing advertising images than previous methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14316v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hongyu Chen, Min Zhou, Jing Jiang, Jiale Chen, Yang Lu, Bo Xiao, Tiezheng Ge, Bo Zheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nautilus: Locality-aware Autoencoder for Scalable Mesh Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14317</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14317v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Triangle meshes are fundamental to 3D applications, enabling efficient modification and rasterization while maintaining compatibility with standard rendering pipelines. However, current automatic mesh generation methods typically rely on intermediate representations that lack the continuous surface quality inherent to meshes. Converting these representations into meshes produces dense, suboptimal outputs. Although recent autoregressive approaches demonstrate promise in directly modeling mesh vertices and faces, they are constrained by the limitation in face count, scalability, and structural fidelity. To address these challenges, we propose Nautilus, a locality-aware autoencoder for artist-like mesh generation that leverages the local properties of manifold meshes to achieve structural fidelity and efficient representation. Our approach introduces a novel tokenization algorithm that preserves face proximity relationships and compresses sequence length through locally shared vertices and edges, enabling the generation of meshes with an unprecedented scale of up to 5,000 faces. Furthermore, we develop a Dual-stream Point Conditioner that provides multi-scale geometric guidance, ensuring global consistency and local structural fidelity by capturing fine-grained geometric features. Extensive experiments demonstrate that Nautilus significantly outperforms state-of-the-art methods in both fidelity and scalability.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14317v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuxuan Wang, Xuanyu Yi, Haohan Weng, Qingshan Xu, Xiaokang Wei, Xianghui Yang, Chunchao Guo, Long Chen, Hanwang Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Benchmarking and Robust Learning for Noise-Free Ego-Motion and 3D Reconstruction from Noisy Video</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14319</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14319v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We aim to redefine robust ego-motion estimation and photorealistic 3D reconstruction by addressing a critical limitation: the reliance on noise-free data in existing models. While such sanitized conditions simplify evaluation, they fail to capture the unpredictable, noisy complexities of real-world environments. Dynamic motion, sensor imperfections, and synchronization perturbations lead to sharp performance declines when these models are deployed in practice, revealing an urgent need for frameworks that embrace and excel under real-world noise. To bridge this gap, we tackle three core challenges: scalable data generation, comprehensive benchmarking, and model robustness enhancement. First, we introduce a scalable noisy data synthesis pipeline that generates diverse datasets simulating complex motion, sensor imperfections, and synchronization errors. Second, we leverage this pipeline to create Robust-Ego3D, a benchmark rigorously designed to expose noise-induced performance degradation, highlighting the limitations of current learning-based methods in ego-motion accuracy and 3D reconstruction quality. Third, we propose Correspondence-guided Gaussian Splatting (CorrGS), a novel test-time adaptation method that progressively refines an internal clean 3D representation by aligning noisy observations with rendered RGB-D frames from clean 3D map, enhancing geometric alignment and appearance restoration through visual correspondence. Extensive experiments on synthetic and real-world data demonstrate that CorrGS consistently outperforms prior state-of-the-art methods, particularly in scenarios involving rapid motion and dynamic illumination.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14319v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaohao Xu, Tianyi Zhang, Shibo Zhao, Xiang Li, Sibo Wang, Yongqi Chen, Ye Li, Bhiksha Raj, Matthew Johnson-Roberson, Sebastian Scherer, Xiaonan Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correlation-Based Band Selection for Hyperspectral Image Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14338</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14338v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Hyperspectral images offer extensive spectral information about ground objects across multiple spectral bands. However, the large volume of data can pose challenges during processing. Typically, adjacent bands in hyperspectral data are highly correlated, leading to the use of only a few selected bands for various applications. In this work, we present a correlation-based band selection approach for hyperspectral image classification. Our approach calculates the average correlation between bands using correlation coefficients to identify the relationships among different bands. Afterward, we select a subset of bands by analyzing the average correlation and applying a threshold-based method. This allows us to isolate and retain bands that exhibit lower inter-band dependencies, ensuring that the selected bands provide diverse and non-redundant information. We evaluate our proposed approach on two standard benchmark datasets: Pavia University (PA) and Salinas Valley (SA), focusing on image classification tasks. The experimental results demonstrate that our method performs competitively with other standard band selection approaches.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14338v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dibyabha Deb, Ujjwal Verma</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Causal-Inspired Multitask Learning for Video-Based Human Pose Estimation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14356</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14356v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Video-based human pose estimation has long been a fundamental yet challenging problem in computer vision. Previous studies focus on spatio-temporal modeling through the enhancement of architecture design and optimization strategies. However, they overlook the causal relationships in the joints, leading to models that may be overly tailored and thus estimate poorly to challenging scenes. Therefore, adequate causal reasoning capability, coupled with good interpretability of model, are both indispensable and prerequisite for achieving reliable results. In this paper, we pioneer a causal perspective on pose estimation and introduce a causal-inspired multitask learning framework, consisting of two stages. \textit{In the first stage}, we try to endow the model with causal spatio-temporal modeling ability by introducing two self-supervision auxiliary tasks. Specifically, these auxiliary tasks enable the network to infer challenging keypoints based on observed keypoint information, thereby imbuing causal reasoning capabilities into the model and making it robust to challenging scenes. \textit{In the second stage}, we argue that not all feature tokens contribute equally to pose estimation. Prioritizing causal (keypoint-relevant) tokens is crucial to achieve reliable results, which could improve the interpretability of the model. To this end, we propose a Token Causal Importance Selection module to identify the causal tokens and non-causal tokens (\textit{e.g.}, background and objects). Additionally, non-causal tokens could provide potentially beneficial cues but may be redundant. We further introduce a non-causal tokens clustering module to merge the similar non-causal tokens. Extensive experiments show that our method outperforms state-of-the-art methods on three large-scale benchmark datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14356v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haipeng Chen, Sifan Wu, Zhigang Wang, Yifang Yin, Yingying Jiao, Yingda Lyu, Zhenguang Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low-rank Prompt Interaction for Continual Vision-Language Retrieval</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14369</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14369v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Research on continual learning in multi-modal tasks has been receiving increasing attention. However, most existing work overlooks the explicit cross-modal and cross-task interactions. In this paper, we innovatively propose the Low-rank Prompt Interaction (LPI) to address this general problem of multi-modal understanding, which considers both cross-modal and cross-task interactions. Specifically, as for the former, we employ multi-modal correlation modules for corresponding Transformer layers. Considering that the training parameters scale to the number of layers and tasks, we propose low-rank interaction-augmented decomposition to avoid memory explosion while enhancing the cross-modal association through sharing and separating common-specific low-rank factors. In addition, due to the multi-modal semantic differences carried by the low-rank initialization, we adopt hierarchical low-rank contrastive learning to ensure training robustness. As for the latter, we initially employ a visual analysis and identify that different tasks have clear distinctions in proximity. Therefore, we introduce explicit task contrastive constraints in the prompt learning process based on task semantic distances. Experiments on two retrieval tasks show performance improvements with the introduction of a minimal number of parameters, demonstrating the effectiveness of our method. Code is available at https://github.com/Kelvin-ywc/LPI.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14369v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weicai Yan, Ye Wang, Wang Lin, Zirun Guo, Zhou Zhao, Tao Jin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVOCSemRPL: Class-Variance Optimized Clustering, Semantic Information Injection and Restricted Pseudo Labeling based Improved Semi-Supervised Few-Shot Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14401</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14401v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Few-shot learning has been extensively explored to address problems where the amount of labeled samples is very limited for some classes. In the semi-supervised few-shot learning setting, substantial quantities of unlabeled samples are available. Such unlabeled samples are generally cheaper to obtain and can be used to improve the few-shot learning performance of the model. Some of the recent methods for this setting rely on clustering to generate pseudo-labels for the unlabeled samples. Since the quality of the representation learned by the model heavily influences the effectiveness of clustering, this might also lead to incorrect labeling of the unlabeled samples and consequently lead to a drop in the few-shot learning performance. We propose an approach for semi-supervised few-shot learning that performs a class-variance optimized clustering in order to improve the effectiveness of clustering the labeled and unlabeled samples in this setting. It also optimizes the clustering-based pseudo-labeling process using a restricted pseudo-labeling approach and performs semantic information injection in order to improve the semi-supervised few-shot learning performance of the model. We experimentally demonstrate that our proposed approach significantly outperforms recent state-of-the-art methods on the benchmark datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14401v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rhythm Baghel, Souvik Maji, Pratik Mazumder</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kolmogorov Arnold Neural Interpolator for Downscaling and Correcting Meteorological Fields from In-Situ Observations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14404</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14404v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Obtaining accurate weather forecasts at station locations is a critical challenge due to systematic biases arising from the mismatch between multi-scale, continuous atmospheric characteristic and their discrete, gridded representations. Previous works have primarily focused on modeling gridded meteorological data, inherently neglecting the off-grid, continuous nature of atmospheric states and leaving such biases unresolved. To address this, we propose the Kolmogorov Arnold Neural Interpolator (KANI), a novel framework that redefines meteorological field representation as continuous neural functions derived from discretized grids. Grounded in the Kolmogorov Arnold theorem, KANI captures the inherent continuity of atmospheric states and leverages sparse in-situ observations to correct these biases systematically. Furthermore, KANI introduces an innovative zero-shot downscaling capability, guided by high-resolution topographic textures without requiring high-resolution meteorological fields for supervision. Experimental results across three sub-regions of the continental United States indicate that KANI achieves an accuracy improvement of 40.28% for temperature and 67.41% for wind speed, highlighting its significant improvement over traditional interpolation methods. This enables continuous neural representation of meteorological variables through neural networks, transcending the limitations of conventional grid-based representations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14404v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zili Liu, Hao Chen, Lei Bai, Wenyuan Li, Zhengxia Zou, Zhenwei Shi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Context-CrackNet: A Context-Aware Framework for Precise Segmentation of Tiny Cracks in Pavement images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14413</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14413v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The accurate detection and segmentation of pavement distresses, particularly tiny and small cracks, are critical for early intervention and preventive maintenance in transportation infrastructure. Traditional manual inspection methods are labor-intensive and inconsistent, while existing deep learning models struggle with fine-grained segmentation and computational efficiency. To address these challenges, this study proposes Context-CrackNet, a novel encoder-decoder architecture featuring the Region-Focused Enhancement Module (RFEM) and Context-Aware Global Module (CAGM). These innovations enhance the model's ability to capture fine-grained local details and global contextual dependencies, respectively. Context-CrackNet was rigorously evaluated on ten publicly available crack segmentation datasets, covering diverse pavement distress scenarios. The model consistently outperformed 9 state-of-the-art segmentation frameworks, achieving superior performance metrics such as mIoU and Dice score, while maintaining competitive inference efficiency. Ablation studies confirmed the complementary roles of RFEM and CAGM, with notable improvements in mIoU and Dice score when both modules were integrated. Additionally, the model's balance of precision and computational efficiency highlights its potential for real-time deployment in large-scale pavement monitoring systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14413v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Blessing Agyei Kyem, Joshua Kofi Asamoah, Armstrong Aboah</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Human Pose Estimation Through Focused Human and Joint Regions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14439</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14439v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Human pose estimation has given rise to a broad spectrum of novel and compelling applications, including action recognition, sports analysis, as well as surveillance. However, accurate video pose estimation remains an open challenge. One aspect that has been overlooked so far is that existing methods learn motion clues from all pixels rather than focusing on the target human body, making them easily misled and disrupted by unimportant information such as background changes or movements of other people. Additionally, while the current Transformer-based pose estimation methods has demonstrated impressive performance with global modeling, they struggle with local context perception and precise positional identification. In this paper, we try to tackle these challenges from three aspects: (1) We propose a bilayer Human-Keypoint Mask module that performs coarse-to-fine visual token refinement, which gradually zooms in on the target human body and keypoints while masking out unimportant figure regions. (2) We further introduce a novel deformable cross attention mechanism and a bidirectional separation strategy to adaptively aggregate spatial and temporal motion clues from constrained surrounding contexts. (3) We mathematically formulate the deformable cross attention, constraining that the model focuses solely on the regions centered at the target person body. Empirically, our method achieves state-of-the-art performance on three large-scale benchmark datasets. A remarkable highlight is that our method achieves an 84.8 mean Average Precision (mAP) on the challenging wrist joint, which significantly outperforms the 81.5 mAP achieved by the current state-of-the-art method on the PoseTrack2017 dataset.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14439v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yingying Jiao, Zhigang Wang, Zhenguang Liu, Shaojing Fan, Sifan Wu, Zheqi Wu, Zhuoyue Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Triple Path Enhanced Neural Architecture Search for Multimodal Fake News Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14455</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14455v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Multimodal fake news detection has become one of the most crucial issues on social media platforms. Although existing methods have achieved advanced performance, two main challenges persist: (1) Under-performed multimodal news information fusion due to model architecture solidification, and (2) weak generalization ability on partial-modality contained fake news. To meet these challenges, we propose a novel and flexible triple path enhanced neural architecture search model MUSE. MUSE includes two dynamic paths for detecting partial-modality contained fake news and a static path for exploiting potential multimodal correlations. Experimental results show that MUSE achieves stable performance improvement over the baselines.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14455v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bo Xu, Qiujie Xie, Jiahui Zhou, Linlin Zong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BILLNET: A Binarized Conv3D-LSTM Network with Logic-gated residual architecture for hardware-efficient video inference</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14495</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14495v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Long Short-Term Memory (LSTM) and 3D convolution (Conv3D) show impressive results for many video-based applications but require large memory and intensive computing. Motivated by recent works on hardware-algorithmic co-design towards efficient inference, we propose a compact binarized Conv3D-LSTM model architecture called BILLNET, compatible with a highly resource-constrained hardware. Firstly, BILLNET proposes to factorize the costly standard Conv3D by two pointwise convolutions with a grouped convolution in-between. Secondly, BILLNET enables binarized weights and activations via a MUX-OR-gated residual architecture. Finally, to efficiently train BILLNET, we propose a multi-stage training strategy enabling to fully quantize LSTM layers. Results on Jester dataset show that our method can obtain high accuracy with extremely low memory and computational budgets compared to existing Conv3D resource-efficient models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14495v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1109/SiPS55645.2022.9919206</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>2022 IEEE Workshop on Signal Processing Systems (SiPS), Rennes, France, 2022, pp. 1-6</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Van Thien Nguyen, William Guicquero, Gilles Sicard</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep-BrownConrady: Prediction of Camera Calibration and Distortion Parameters Using Deep Learning and Synthetic Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14510</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14510v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This research addresses the challenge of camera calibration and distortion parameter prediction from a single image using deep learning models. The main contributions of this work are: (1) demonstrating that a deep learning model, trained on a mix of real and synthetic images, can accurately predict camera and lens parameters from a single image, and (2) developing a comprehensive synthetic dataset using the AILiveSim simulation platform. This dataset includes variations in focal length and lens distortion parameters, providing a robust foundation for model training and testing. The training process predominantly relied on these synthetic images, complemented by a small subset of real images, to explore how well models trained on synthetic data can perform calibration tasks on real-world images. Traditional calibration methods require multiple images of a calibration object from various orientations, which is often not feasible due to the lack of such images in publicly available datasets. A deep learning network based on the ResNet architecture was trained on this synthetic dataset to predict camera calibration parameters following the Brown-Conrady lens model. The ResNet architecture, adapted for regression tasks, is capable of predicting continuous values essential for accurate camera calibration in applications such as autonomous driving, robotics, and augmented reality.
  Keywords: Camera calibration, distortion, synthetic data, deep learning, residual networks (ResNet), AILiveSim, horizontal field-of-view, principal point, Brown-Conrady Model.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14510v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Faiz Muhammad Chaudhry, Jarno Ralli, Jerome Leudet, Fahad Sohrab, Farhad Pakdaman, Pierre Corbani, Moncef Gabbouj</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PARASIDE: An Automatic Paranasal Sinus Segmentation and Structure Analysis Tool for MRI</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14514</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14514v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Chronic rhinosinusitis (CRS) is a common and persistent sinus imflammation that affects 5 - 12\% of the general population. It significantly impacts quality of life and is often difficult to assess due to its subjective nature in clinical evaluation. We introduce PARASIDE, an automatic tool for segmenting air and soft tissue volumes of the structures of the sinus maxillaris, frontalis, sphenodalis and ethmoidalis in T1 MRI. By utilizing that segmentation, we can quantify feature relations that have been observed only manually and subjectively before. We performed an exemplary study and showed both volume and intensity relations between structures and radiology reports. While the soft tissue segmentation is good, the automated annotations of the air volumes are excellent. The average intensity over air structures are consistently below those of the soft tissues, close to perfect separability. Healthy subjects exhibit lower soft tissue volumes and lower intensities. Our developed system is the first automated whole nasal segmentation of 16 structures, and capable of calculating medical relevant features such as the Lund-Mackay score.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14514v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hendrik M\"oller, Lukas Krautschick, Matan Atad, Robert Graf, Chia-Jung Busch, Achim Beule, Christian Scharf, Lars Kaderali, Bjoern Menze, Daniel Rueckert, Jan Kirschke, Fabian Schwitzing</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Training-Free Style and Content Transfer by Leveraging U-Net Skip Connections in Stable Diffusion 2.*</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14524</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14524v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Despite significant recent advances in image generation with diffusion models, their internal latent representations remain poorly understood. Existing works focus on the bottleneck layer (h-space) of Stable Diffusion's U-Net or leverage the cross-attention, self-attention, or decoding layers. Our model, SkipInject takes advantage of U-Net's skip connections. We conduct thorough analyses on the role of the skip connections and find that the residual connections passed by the third encoder block carry most of the spatial information of the reconstructed image, splitting the content from the style. We show that injecting the representations from this block can be used for text-based editing, precise modifications, and style transfer. We compare our methods state-of-the-art style transfer and image editing methods and demonstrate that our method obtains the best content alignment and optimal structural preservation tradeoff.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14524v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ludovica Schaerf, Andrea Alfarano, Fabrizio Silvestri, Leonardo Impett</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CheapNVS: Real-Time On-Device Narrow-Baseline Novel View Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14533</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14533v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Single-view novel view synthesis (NVS) is a notorious problem due to its ill-posed nature, and often requires large, computationally expensive approaches to produce tangible results. In this paper, we propose CheapNVS: a fully end-to-end approach for narrow baseline single-view NVS based on a novel, efficient multiple encoder/decoder design trained in a multi-stage fashion. CheapNVS first approximates the laborious 3D image warping with lightweight learnable modules that are conditioned on the camera pose embeddings of the target view, and then performs inpainting on the occluded regions in parallel to achieve significant performance gains. Once trained on a subset of Open Images dataset, CheapNVS outperforms the state-of-the-art despite being 10 times faster and consuming 6% less memory. Furthermore, CheapNVS runs comfortably in real-time on mobile devices, reaching over 30 FPS on a Samsung Tab 9+.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14533v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Konstantinos Georgiadis, Mehmet Kerim Yucel, Albert Saa-Garriga</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trick-GS: A Balanced Bag of Tricks for Efficient Gaussian Splatting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14534</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14534v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Gaussian splatting (GS) for 3D reconstruction has become quite popular due to their fast training, inference speeds and high quality reconstruction. However, GS-based reconstructions generally consist of millions of Gaussians, which makes them hard to use on computationally constrained devices such as smartphones. In this paper, we first propose a principled analysis of advances in efficient GS methods. Then, we propose Trick-GS, which is a careful combination of several strategies including (1) progressive training with resolution, noise and Gaussian scales, (2) learning to prune and mask primitives and SH bands by their significance, and (3) accelerated GS training framework. Trick-GS takes a large step towards resource-constrained GS, where faster run-time, smaller and faster-convergence of models is of paramount concern. Our results on three datasets show that Trick-GS achieves up to 2x faster training, 40x smaller disk size and 2x faster rendering speed compared to vanilla GS, while having comparable accuracy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14534v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Anil Armagan, Albert Sa\`a-Garriga, Bruno Manganelli, Mateusz Nowak, Mehmet Kerim Yucel</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Encoder-Decoder Flow Through Shared Structures</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14535</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14535v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Dense prediction tasks have enjoyed a growing complexity of encoder architectures, decoders, however, have remained largely the same. They rely on individual blocks decoding intermediate feature maps sequentially. We introduce banks, shared structures that are used by each decoding block to provide additional context in the decoding process. These structures, through applying them via resampling and feature fusion, improve performance on depth estimation for state-of-the-art transformer-based architectures on natural and synthetic images whilst training on large-scale datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14535v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Frederik Laboyrie, Mehmet Kerim Yucel, Albert Saa-Garriga</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging ChatGPT's Multimodal Vision Capabilities to Rank Satellite Images by Poverty Level: Advancing Tools for Social Science Research</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14546</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14546v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper investigates the novel application of Large Language Models (LLMs) with vision capabilities to analyze satellite imagery for village-level poverty prediction. Although LLMs were originally designed for natural language understanding, their adaptability to multimodal tasks, including geospatial analysis, has opened new frontiers in data-driven research. By leveraging advancements in vision-enabled LLMs, we assess their ability to provide interpretable, scalable, and reliable insights into human poverty from satellite images. Using a pairwise comparison approach, we demonstrate that ChatGPT can rank satellite images based on poverty levels with accuracy comparable to domain experts. These findings highlight both the promise and the limitations of LLMs in socioeconomic research, providing a foundation for their integration into poverty assessment workflows. This study contributes to the ongoing exploration of unconventional data sources for welfare analysis and opens pathways for cost-effective, large-scale poverty monitoring.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14546v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hamid Sarmadi, Ola Hall, Thorsteinn R\"ognvaldsson, Mattias Ohlsson</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large-scale and Fine-grained Vision-language Pre-training for Enhanced CT Image Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14548</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14548v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Artificial intelligence (AI) shows great potential in assisting radiologists to improve the efficiency and accuracy of medical image interpretation and diagnosis. However, a versatile AI model requires large-scale data and comprehensive annotations, which are often impractical in medical settings. Recent studies leverage radiology reports as a naturally high-quality supervision for medical images, using contrastive language-image pre-training (CLIP) to develop language-informed models for radiological image interpretation. Nonetheless, these approaches typically contrast entire images with reports, neglecting the local associations between imaging regions and report sentences, which may undermine model performance and interoperability. In this paper, we propose a fine-grained vision-language model (fVLM) for anatomy-level CT image interpretation. Specifically, we explicitly match anatomical regions of CT images with corresponding descriptions in radiology reports and perform contrastive pre-training for each anatomy individually. Fine-grained alignment, however, faces considerable false-negative challenges, mainly from the abundance of anatomy-level healthy samples and similarly diseased abnormalities. To tackle this issue, we propose identifying false negatives of both normal and abnormal samples and calibrating contrastive learning from patient-level to disease-aware pairing. We curated the largest CT dataset to date, comprising imaging and report data from 69,086 patients, and conducted a comprehensive evaluation of 54 major and important disease diagnosis tasks across 15 main anatomies. Experimental results demonstrate the substantial potential of fVLM in versatile medical image interpretation. In the zero-shot classification task, we achieved an average AUC of 81.3% on 54 diagnosis tasks, surpassing CLIP and supervised methods by 12.9% and 8.0%, respectively.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14548v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhongyi Shui, Jianpeng Zhang, Weiwei Cao, Sinuo Wang, Ruizhe Guo, Le Lu, Lin Yang, Xianghua Ye, Tingbo Liang, Qi Zhang, Ling Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visual Localization via Semantic Structures in Autonomous Photovoltaic Power Plant Inspection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14587</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14587v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Inspection systems utilizing unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs) equipped with thermal cameras are increasingly popular for the maintenance of photovoltaic (PV) power plants. However, automation of the inspection task is a challenging problem as it requires precise navigation to capture images from optimal distances and viewing angles.
  This paper presents a novel localization pipeline that directly integrates PV module detection with UAV navigation, allowing precise positioning during inspection. Detections are used to identify the power plant structures in the image and associate these with the power plant model. We define visually recognizable anchor points for the initial association and use object tracking to discern global associations. We present three distinct methods for visual segmentation of PV modules based on traditional computer vision, deep learning, and their fusion, and we evaluate their performance in relation to the proposed localization pipeline.
  The presented methods were verified and evaluated using custom aerial inspection data sets, demonstrating their robustness and applicability for real-time navigation. Additionally, we evaluate the influence of the power plant model's precision on the localization methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14587v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Viktor Koz\'ak, Karel Ko\v{s}nar, Jan Chudoba, Miroslav Kulich, Libor P\v{r}eu\v{c}il</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geometric Mean Improves Loss For Few-Shot Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14593</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14593v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Few-shot learning (FSL) is a challenging task in machine learning, demanding a model to render discriminative classification by using only a few labeled samples. In the literature of FSL, deep models are trained in a manner of metric learning to provide metric in a feature space which is well generalizable to classify samples of novel classes; in the space, even a few amount of labeled training examples can construct an effective classifier. In this paper, we propose a novel FSL loss based on \emph{geometric mean} to embed discriminative metric into deep features. In contrast to the other losses such as utilizing arithmetic mean in softmax-based formulation, the proposed method leverages geometric mean to aggregate pair-wise relationships among samples for enhancing discriminative metric across class categories. The proposed loss is not only formulated in a simple form but also is thoroughly analyzed in theoretical ways to reveal its favorable characteristics which are favorable for learning feature metric in FSL. In the experiments on few-shot image classification tasks, the method produces competitive performance in comparison to the other losses.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14593v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tong Wu, Takumi Kobayashi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3DLabelProp: Geometric-Driven Domain Generalization for LiDAR Semantic Segmentation in Autonomous Driving</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14605</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14605v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Domain generalization aims to find ways for deep learning models to maintain their performance despite significant domain shifts between training and inference datasets. This is particularly important for models that need to be robust or are costly to train. LiDAR perception in autonomous driving is impacted by both of these concerns, leading to the emergence of various approaches. This work addresses the challenge by proposing a geometry-based approach, leveraging the sequential structure of LiDAR sensors, which sets it apart from the learning-based methods commonly found in the literature. The proposed method, called 3DLabelProp, is applied on the task of LiDAR Semantic Segmentation (LSS). Through extensive experimentation on seven datasets, it is demonstrated to be a state-of-the-art approach, outperforming both naive and other domain generalization methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14605v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jules Sanchez, Jean-Emmanuel Deschaud, Fran\c{c}ois Goulette</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ReferDINO: Referring Video Object Segmentation with Visual Grounding Foundations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14607</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14607v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Referring video object segmentation (RVOS) aims to segment target objects throughout a video based on a text description. Despite notable progress in recent years, current RVOS models remain struggle to handle complicated object descriptions due to their limited video-language understanding. To address this limitation, we present \textbf{ReferDINO}, an end-to-end RVOS model that inherits strong vision-language understanding from the pretrained visual grounding foundation models, and is further endowed with effective temporal understanding and object segmentation capabilities. In ReferDINO, we contribute three technical innovations for effectively adapting the foundation models to RVOS: 1) an object-consistent temporal enhancer that capitalizes on the pretrained object-text representations to enhance temporal understanding and object consistency; 2) a grounding-guided deformable mask decoder that integrates text and grounding conditions to generate accurate object masks; 3) a confidence-aware query pruning strategy that significantly improves the object decoding efficiency without compromising performance. We conduct extensive experiments on five public RVOS benchmarks to demonstrate that our proposed ReferDINO outperforms state-of-the-art methods significantly. Project page: \url{https://isee-laboratory.github.io/ReferDINO}</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14607v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tianming Liang, Kun-Yu Lin, Chaolei Tan, Jianguo Zhang, Wei-Shi Zheng, Jian-Fang Hu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SyncAnimation: A Real-Time End-to-End Framework for Audio-Driven Human Pose and Talking Head Animation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14646</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14646v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Generating talking avatar driven by audio remains a significant challenge. Existing methods typically require high computational costs and often lack sufficient facial detail and realism, making them unsuitable for applications that demand high real-time performance and visual quality. Additionally, while some methods can synchronize lip movement, they still face issues with consistency between facial expressions and upper body movement, particularly during silent periods. In this paper, we introduce SyncAnimation, the first NeRF-based method that achieves audio-driven, stable, and real-time generation of speaking avatar by combining generalized audio-to-pose matching and audio-to-expression synchronization. By integrating AudioPose Syncer and AudioEmotion Syncer, SyncAnimation achieves high-precision poses and expression generation, progressively producing audio-synchronized upper body, head, and lip shapes. Furthermore, the High-Synchronization Human Renderer ensures seamless integration of the head and upper body, and achieves audio-sync lip. The project page can be found at https://syncanimation.github.io</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14646v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yujian Liu, Shidang Xu, Jing Guo, Dingbin Wang, Zairan Wang, Xianfeng Tan, Xiaoli Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Unified Structured Light Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14659</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14659v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Structured light (SL) 3D reconstruction captures the precise surface shape of objects, providing high-accuracy 3D data essential for industrial inspection and robotic vision systems. However, current research on optimizing projection patterns in SL 3D reconstruction faces two main limitations: each scene requires separate training of calibration parameters, and optimization is restricted to specific types of SL, which restricts their application range. To tackle these limitations, we present a unified framework for SL optimization, adaptable to diverse lighting conditions, object types, and different types of SL. Our framework quickly determines the optimal projection pattern using only a single projected image. Key contributions include a novel global matching method for projectors, enabling precise projector-camera alignment with just one projected image, and a new projection compensation model with a photometric adjustment module to reduce artifacts from out-of-gamut clipping. Experimental results show our method achieves superior decoding accuracy across various objects, SL patterns, and lighting conditions, significantly outperforming previous methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14659v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tinglei Wan, Tonghua Su, Zhongjie Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MatAnyone: Stable Video Matting with Consistent Memory Propagation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14677</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14677v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Auxiliary-free human video matting methods, which rely solely on input frames, often struggle with complex or ambiguous backgrounds. To address this, we propose MatAnyone, a robust framework tailored for target-assigned video matting. Specifically, building on a memory-based paradigm, we introduce a consistent memory propagation module via region-adaptive memory fusion, which adaptively integrates memory from the previous frame. This ensures semantic stability in core regions while preserving fine-grained details along object boundaries. For robust training, we present a larger, high-quality, and diverse dataset for video matting. Additionally, we incorporate a novel training strategy that efficiently leverages large-scale segmentation data, boosting matting stability. With this new network design, dataset, and training strategy, MatAnyone delivers robust and accurate video matting results in diverse real-world scenarios, outperforming existing methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14677v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Peiqing Yang, Shangchen Zhou, Jixin Zhao, Qingyi Tao, Chen Change Loy</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Vision Mamba: Leveraging Bidirectional State Space Model for Efficient Spherical Manifold Representation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14679</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14679v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Attention-based methods have demonstrated exceptional performance in modelling long-range dependencies on spherical cortical surfaces, surpassing traditional Geometric Deep Learning (GDL) models. However, their extensive inference time and high memory demands pose challenges for application to large datasets with limited computing resources. Inspired by the state space model in computer vision, we introduce the attention-free Vision Mamba (Vim) to spherical surfaces, presenting a domain-agnostic architecture for analyzing data on spherical manifolds. Our method achieves surface patching by representing spherical data as a sequence of triangular patches derived from a subdivided icosphere. The proposed Surface Vision Mamba (SiM) is evaluated on multiple neurodevelopmental phenotype regression tasks using cortical surface metrics from neonatal brains. Experimental results demonstrate that SiM outperforms both attention- and GDL-based methods, delivering 4.8 times faster inference and achieving 91.7% lower memory consumption compared to the Surface Vision Transformer (SiT) under the Ico-4 grid partitioning. Sensitivity analysis further underscores the potential of SiM to identify subtle cognitive developmental patterns. The code is available at https://github.com/Rongzhao-He/surface-vision-mamba.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14679v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rongzhao He, Weihao Zheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Approach to Designing CV Systems for Medical Applications: Data, Architecture and AI</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14689</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14689v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper introduces an innovative software system for fundus image analysis that deliberately diverges from the conventional screening approach, opting not to predict specific diagnoses. Instead, our methodology mimics the diagnostic process by thoroughly analyzing both normal and pathological features of fundus structures, leaving the ultimate decision-making authority in the hands of healthcare professionals. Our initiative addresses the need for objective clinical analysis and seeks to automate and enhance the clinical workflow of fundus image examination. The system, from its overarching architecture to the modular analysis design powered by artificial intelligence (AI) models, aligns seamlessly with ophthalmological practices. Our unique approach utilizes a combination of state-of-the-art deep learning methods and traditional computer vision algorithms to provide a comprehensive and nuanced analysis of fundus structures. We present a distinctive methodology for designing medical applications, using our system as an illustrative example. Comprehensive verification and validation results demonstrate the efficacy of our approach in revolutionizing fundus image analysis, with potential applications across various medical domains.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14689v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dmitry Ryabtsev, Boris Vasilyev, Sergey Shershakov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Relightable Full-Body Gaussian Codec Avatars</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14726</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14726v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We propose Relightable Full-Body Gaussian Codec Avatars, a new approach for modeling relightable full-body avatars with fine-grained details including face and hands. The unique challenge for relighting full-body avatars lies in the large deformations caused by body articulation and the resulting impact on appearance caused by light transport. Changes in body pose can dramatically change the orientation of body surfaces with respect to lights, resulting in both local appearance changes due to changes in local light transport functions, as well as non-local changes due to occlusion between body parts. To address this, we decompose the light transport into local and non-local effects. Local appearance changes are modeled using learnable zonal harmonics for diffuse radiance transfer. Unlike spherical harmonics, zonal harmonics are highly efficient to rotate under articulation. This allows us to learn diffuse radiance transfer in a local coordinate frame, which disentangles the local radiance transfer from the articulation of the body. To account for non-local appearance changes, we introduce a shadow network that predicts shadows given precomputed incoming irradiance on a base mesh. This facilitates the learning of non-local shadowing between the body parts. Finally, we use a deferred shading approach to model specular radiance transfer and better capture reflections and highlights such as eye glints. We demonstrate that our approach successfully models both the local and non-local light transport required for relightable full-body avatars, with a superior generalization ability under novel illumination conditions and unseen poses.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14726v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shaofei Wang, Tomas Simon, Igor Santesteban, Timur Bagautdinov, Junxuan Li, Vasu Agrawal, Fabian Prada, Shoou-I Yu, Pace Nalbone, Matt Gramlich, Roman Lubachersky, Chenglei Wu, Javier Romero, Jason Saragih, Michael Zollhoefer, Andreas Geiger, Siyu Tang, Shunsuke Saito</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HERMES: A Unified Self-Driving World Model for Simultaneous 3D Scene Understanding and Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14729</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14729v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Driving World Models (DWMs) have become essential for autonomous driving by enabling future scene prediction. However, existing DWMs are limited to scene generation and fail to incorporate scene understanding, which involves interpreting and reasoning about the driving environment. In this paper, we present a unified Driving World Model named HERMES. We seamlessly integrate 3D scene understanding and future scene evolution (generation) through a unified framework in driving scenarios. Specifically, HERMES leverages a Bird's-Eye View (BEV) representation to consolidate multi-view spatial information while preserving geometric relationships and interactions. We also introduce world queries, which incorporate world knowledge into BEV features via causal attention in the Large Language Model (LLM), enabling contextual enrichment for understanding and generation tasks. We conduct comprehensive studies on nuScenes and OmniDrive-nuScenes datasets to validate the effectiveness of our method. HERMES achieves state-of-the-art performance, reducing generation error by 32.4% and improving understanding metrics such as CIDEr by 8.0%. The model and code will be publicly released at https://github.com/LMD0311/HERMES.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14729v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xin Zhou, Dingkang Liang, Sifan Tu, Xiwu Chen, Yikang Ding, Dingyuan Zhang, Feiyang Tan, Hengshuang Zhao, Xiang Bai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced deep architecture pruning using single filter performance</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.12880</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.12880v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Pruning the parameters and structure of neural networks reduces the computational complexity, energy consumption, and latency during inference. Recently, a novel underlying mechanism for successful deep learning (DL) was presented based on a method that quantitatively measures the single filter performance in each layer of a DL architecture, and a new comprehensive mechanism of how deep learning works was presented. Herein, we demonstrate how this understanding paves the path to highly dilute the convolutional layers of deep architectures without affecting their overall accuracy using applied filter cluster connections (AFCC). AFCC is exemplified on VGG-11 and EfficientNet-B0 architectures trained on CIFAR-100, and its high pruning outperforms other techniques using the same pruning magnitude. Additionally, this technique is broadened to single nodal performance and highly pruning of fully connected layers, suggesting a possible implementation to considerably reduce the complexity of over-parameterized AI tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.12880v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yarden Tzach, Yuval Meir, Ronit D. Gross, Ofek Tevet, Ella Koresh, Ido Kanter</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LiCAR: pseudo-RGB LiDAR image for CAR segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.13960</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.13960v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: With the advancement of computing resources, an increasing number of Neural Networks (NNs) are appearing for image detection and segmentation appear. However, these methods usually accept as input a RGB 2D image. On the other side, Light Detection And Ranging (LiDAR) sensors with many layers provide images that are similar to those obtained from a traditional low resolution RGB camera. Following this principle, a new dataset for segmenting cars in pseudo-RGB images has been generated. This dataset combines the information given by the LiDAR sensor into a Spherical Range Image (SRI), concretely the reflectivity, near infrared and signal intensity 2D images. These images are then fed into instance segmentation NNs. These NNs segment the cars that appear in these images, having as result a Bounding Box (BB) and mask precision of 88% and 81.5% respectively with You Only Look Once (YOLO)-v8 large. By using this segmentation NN, some trackers have been applied so as to follow each car segmented instance along a video feed, having great performance in real world experiments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.13960v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ignacio de Loyola P\'aez-Ubieta, Edison P. Velasco-S\'anchez, Santiago T. Puente</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patch-Based and Non-Patch-Based inputs Comparison into Deep Neural Models: Application for the Segmentation of Retinal Diseases on Optical Coherence Tomography Volumes</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.13970</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.13970v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Worldwide, sight loss is commonly occurred by retinal diseases, with age-related macular degeneration (AMD) being a notable facet that affects elderly patients. Approaching 170 million persons wide-ranging have been spotted with AMD, a figure anticipated to rise to 288 million by 2040. For visualizing retinal layers, optical coherence tomography (OCT) dispenses the most compelling non-invasive method. Frequent patient visits have increased the demand for automated analysis of retinal diseases, and deep learning networks have shown promising results in both image and pixel-level 2D scan classification. However, when relying solely on 2D data, accuracy may be impaired, especially when localizing fluid volume diseases. The goal of automatic techniques is to outperform humans in manually recognizing illnesses in medical data. In order to further understand the benefit of deep learning models, we studied the effects of the input size. The dice similarity coefficient (DSC) metric showed a human performance score of 0.71 for segmenting various retinal diseases. Yet, the deep models surpassed human performance to establish a new era of advancement of segmenting the diseases on medical images. However, to further improve the performance of the models, overlapping patches enhanced the performance of the deep models compared to feeding the full image. The highest score for a patch-based model in the DSC metric was 0.88 in comparison to the score of 0.71 for the same model in non-patch-based for SRF fluid segmentation. The objective of this article is to show a fair comparison between deep learning models in relation to the input (Patch-Based vs. NonPatch-Based).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.13970v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Khaled Al-Saih, Fares Al-Shargie, Mohammed Isam Al-hiyali, Reham Alhejaili</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthetic CT image generation from CBCT: A Systematic Review</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.13972</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.13972v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The generation of synthetic CT (sCT) images from cone-beam CT (CBCT) data using deep learning methodologies represents a significant advancement in radiation oncology. This systematic review, following PRISMA guidelines and using the PICO model, comprehensively evaluates the literature from 2014 to 2024 on the generation of sCT images for radiation therapy planning in oncology. A total of 35 relevant studies were identified and analyzed, revealing the prevalence of deep learning approaches in the generation of sCT. This review comprehensively covers synthetic CT generation based on CBCT and proton-based studies. Some of the commonly employed architectures explored are convolutional neural networks (CNNs), generative adversarial networks (GANs), transformers, and diffusion models. Evaluation metrics including mean absolute error (MAE), root mean square error (RMSE), peak signal-to-noise ratio (PSNR) and structural similarity index (SSIM) consistently demonstrate the comparability of sCT images with gold-standard planning CTs (pCT), indicating their potential to improve treatment precision and patient outcomes. Challenges such as field-of-view (FOV) disparities and integration into clinical workflows are discussed, along with recommendations for future research and standardization efforts. In general, the findings underscore the promising role of sCT-based approaches in personalized treatment planning and adaptive radiation therapy, with potential implications for improved oncology treatment delivery and patient care.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.13972v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alzahra Altalib, Scott McGregor, Chunhui Li, Alessandro Perelli</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pilot: Building the Federated Multimodal Instruction Tuning Framework</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.13985</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.13985v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In this paper, we explore a novel federated multimodal instruction tuning task(FedMIT), which is significant for collaboratively fine-tuning MLLMs on different types of multimodal instruction data on distributed devices. To solve the new task, we propose a federated multimodal instruction tuning framework(Pilot). Our framework integrates two stages of "adapter on adapter" into the connector of the vision encoder and the LLM. In stage 1, we extract task-specific features and client-specific features from visual information. In stage 2, we build the cross-task Mixture-of-Adapters(CT-MoA) module to perform cross-task interaction. Each client can not only capture personalized information of local data and learn task-related multimodal information, but also learn general knowledge from other tasks. In addition, we introduce an adaptive parameter aggregation strategy for text training parameters, which optimizes parameter aggregation by calculating weights based on the euclidean distance between parameters, so that parameter aggregation can benefit from positive effects to the greatest extent while effectively reducing negative effects. Our framework can collaboratively exploit distributed data from different local clients to learn cross-task knowledge without being affected by the task heterogeneity during instruction tuning. The effectiveness of our method is verified in two different cross-task scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.13985v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Baochen Xiong, Xiaoshan Yang, Yaguang Song, Yaowei Wang, Changsheng Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MCRL4OR: Multimodal Contrastive Representation Learning for Off-Road Environmental Perception</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.13988</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.13988v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Most studies on environmental perception for autonomous vehicles (AVs) focus on urban traffic environments, where the objects/stuff to be perceived are mainly from man-made scenes and scalable datasets with dense annotations can be used to train supervised learning models. By contrast, it is hard to densely annotate a large-scale off-road driving dataset manually due to the inherently unstructured nature of off-road environments. In this paper, we propose a Multimodal Contrastive Representation Learning approach for Off-Road environmental perception, namely MCRL4OR. This approach aims to jointly learn three encoders for processing visual images, locomotion states, and control actions by aligning the locomotion states with the fused features of visual images and control actions within a contrastive learning framework. The causation behind this alignment strategy is that the inertial locomotion state is the result of taking a certain control action under the current landform/terrain condition perceived by visual sensors. In experiments, we pre-train the MCRL4OR with a large-scale off-road driving dataset and adopt the learned multimodal representations for various downstream perception tasks in off-road driving scenarios. The superior performance in downstream tasks demonstrates the advantages of the pre-trained multimodal representations. The codes can be found in \url{https://github.com/1uciusy/MCRL4OR}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.13988v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yi Yang, Zhang Zhang, Liang Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Multiphase CT for Quality Enhancement of Portal Venous CT: Utility for Pancreas Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14013</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14013v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Multiphase CT studies are routinely obtained in clinical practice for diagnosis and management of various diseases, such as cancer. However, the CT studies can be acquired with low radiation doses, different scanners, and are frequently affected by motion and metal artifacts. Prior approaches have targeted the quality improvement of one specific CT phase (e.g., non-contrast CT). In this work, we hypothesized that leveraging multiple CT phases for the quality enhancement of one phase may prove advantageous for downstream tasks, such as segmentation. A 3D progressive fusion and non-local (PFNL) network was developed. It was trained with three degraded (low-quality) phases (non-contrast, arterial, and portal venous) to enhance the quality of the portal venous phase. Then, the effect of scan quality enhancement was evaluated using a proxy task of pancreas segmentation, which is useful for tracking pancreatic cancer. The proposed approach improved the pancreas segmentation by 3% over the corresponding low-quality CT scan. To the best of our knowledge, we are the first to harness multiphase CT for scan quality enhancement and improved pancreas segmentation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14013v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xinya Wang, Tejas Sudharshan Mathai, Boah Kim, Ronald M. Summers</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SIDDA: SInkhorn Dynamic Domain Adaptation for Image Classification with Equivariant Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14048</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14048v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Modern neural networks (NNs) often do not generalize well in the presence of a "covariate shift"; that is, in situations where the training and test data distributions differ, but the conditional distribution of classification labels remains unchanged. In such cases, NN generalization can be reduced to a problem of learning more domain-invariant features. Domain adaptation (DA) methods include a range of techniques aimed at achieving this; however, these methods have struggled with the need for extensive hyperparameter tuning, which then incurs significant computational costs. In this work, we introduce SIDDA, an out-of-the-box DA training algorithm built upon the Sinkhorn divergence, that can achieve effective domain alignment with minimal hyperparameter tuning and computational overhead. We demonstrate the efficacy of our method on multiple simulated and real datasets of varying complexity, including simple shapes, handwritten digits, and real astronomical observations. SIDDA is compatible with a variety of NN architectures, and it works particularly well in improving classification accuracy and model calibration when paired with equivariant neural networks (ENNs). We find that SIDDA enhances the generalization capabilities of NNs, achieving up to a $\approx40\%$ improvement in classification accuracy on unlabeled target data. We also study the efficacy of DA on ENNs with respect to the varying group orders of the dihedral group $D_N$, and find that the model performance improves as the degree of equivariance increases. Finally, we find that SIDDA enhances model calibration on both source and target data--achieving over an order of magnitude improvement in the ECE and Brier score. SIDDA's versatility, combined with its automated approach to domain alignment, has the potential to advance multi-dataset studies by enabling the development of highly generalizable models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14048v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>astro-ph.GA</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sneh Pandya, Purvik Patel, Brian D. Nord, Mike Walmsley, Aleksandra \'Ciprijanovi\'c</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient 2D CT Foundation Model for Contrast Phase Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14066</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14066v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Purpose: The purpose of this study is to harness the efficiency of a 2D foundation model to develop a robust phase classifier that is resilient to domain shifts.
  Materials and Methods: This retrospective study utilized three public datasets from separate institutions. A 2D foundation model was trained on the DeepLesion dataset (mean age: 51.2, s.d.: 17.6; 2398 males) to generate embeddings from 2D CT slices for downstream contrast phase classification. The classifier was trained on the VinDr Multiphase dataset and externally validated on the WAW-TACE dataset. The 2D model was also compared to three 3D supervised models.
  Results: On the VinDr dataset (146 male, 63 female, 56 unidentified), the model achieved near-perfect AUROC scores and F1 scores of 99.2%, 94.2%, and 93.1% for non-contrast, arterial, and venous phases, respectively. The `Other' category scored lower (F1: 73.4%) due to combining multiple contrast phases into one class. On the WAW-TACE dataset (mean age: 66.1, s.d.: 10.0; 185 males), the model showed strong performance with AUROCs of 91.0% and 85.6%, and F1 scores of 87.3% and 74.1% for non-contrast and arterial phases. Venous phase performance was lower, with AUROC and F1 scores of 81.7% and 70.2% respectively, due to label mismatches. Compared to 3D supervised models, the approach trained faster, performed as well or better, and showed greater robustness to domain shifts.
  Conclusion: The robustness of the 2D Foundation model may be potentially useful for automation of hanging protocols and data orchestration for clinical deployment of AI algorithms.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14066v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Benjamin Hou, Tejas Sudharshan Mathai, Pritam Mukherjee, Xinya Wang, Ronald M. Summers, Zhiyong Lub</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reinforcement Learning Platform for Adversarial Black-box Attacks with Custom Distortion Filters</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14122</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14122v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We present a Reinforcement Learning Platform for Adversarial Black-box untargeted and targeted attacks, RLAB, that allows users to select from various distortion filters to create adversarial examples. The platform uses a Reinforcement Learning agent to add minimum distortion to input images while still causing misclassification by the target model. The agent uses a novel dual-action method to explore the input image at each step to identify sensitive regions for adding distortions while removing noises that have less impact on the target model. This dual action leads to faster and more efficient convergence of the attack. The platform can also be used to measure the robustness of image classification models against specific distortion types. Also, retraining the model with adversarial samples significantly improved robustness when evaluated on benchmark datasets. The proposed platform outperforms state-of-the-art methods in terms of the average number of queries required to cause misclassification. This advances trustworthiness with a positive social impact.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14122v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Soumyendu Sarkar, Ashwin Ramesh Babu, Sajad Mousavi, Vineet Gundecha, Sahand Ghorbanpour, Avisek Naug, Ricardo Luna Gutierrez, Antonio Guillen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fully Guided Neural Schr\"odinger bridge for Brain MR image synthesis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14171</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14171v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Multi-modal brain MRI provides essential complementary information for clinical diagnosis. However, acquiring all modalities is often challenging due to time and cost constraints. To address this, various methods have been proposed to generate missing modalities from available ones. Traditional approaches can be broadly categorized into two main types: paired and unpaired methods. While paired methods offer superior performance, obtaining large-scale paired datasets is challenging in real-world scenarios. Conversely, unpaired methods facilitate large-scale data collection but struggle to preserve critical image features, such as tumors. In this paper, we propose Fully Guided Schr\"odinger Bridges (FGSB), a novel framework based on Neural Schr\"odinger Bridges, to overcome these limitations. FGSB achieves stable, high-quality generation of missing modalities using minimal paired data. Furthermore, when provided with ground truth or a segmentation network for specific regions, FGSB can generate missing modalities while preserving these critical areas with reduced data requirements. Our proposed model consists of two consecutive phases. 1) Generation Phase: Fuses a generated image, a paired reference image, and Gaussian noise, employing iterative refinement to mitigate issues such as mode collapse and improve generation quality 2) Training Phase: Learns the mapping from the generated image to the target modality. Experiments demonstrate that FGSB achieves comparable generation performance to methods trained on large datasets, while using data from only two subjects. Moreover, the utilization of lesion information with FGSB significantly enhances its ability to preserve crucial lesion features.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14171v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hanyeol Yang, Sunggyu Kim, Yongseon Yoo, Jong-min Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UltraLightSqueezeNet: A Deep Learning Architecture for Malaria Classification with up to 54x fewer trainable parameters for resource constrained devices</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14172</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14172v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Lightweight deep learning approaches for malaria detection have gained attention for their potential to enhance diagnostics in resource constrained environments. For our study, we selected SqueezeNet1.1 as it is one of the most popular lightweight architectures. SqueezeNet1.1 is a later version of SqueezeNet1.0 and is 2.4 times more computationally efficient than the original model. We proposed and implemented three ultra-lightweight architecture variants to SqueezeNet1.1 architecture, namely Variant 1 (one fire module), Variant 2 (two fire modules), and Variant 3 (four fire modules), which are even more compact than SqueezeNetV1.1 (eight fire modules). These models were implemented to evaluate the best performing variant that achieves superior computational efficiency without sacrificing accuracy in malaria blood cell classification. The models were trained and evaluated using the NIH Malaria dataset. We assessed each model's performance based on metrics including accuracy, recall, precision, F1-score, and Area Under the Curve (AUC). The results show that the SqueezeNet1.1 model achieves the highest performance across all metrics, with a classification accuracy of 97.12%. Variant 3 (four fire modules) offers a competitive alternative, delivering almost identical results (accuracy 96.55%) with a 6x reduction in computational overhead compared to SqueezeNet1.1. Variant 2 and Variant 1 perform slightly lower than Variant 3, with Variant 2 (two fire modules) reducing computational overhead by 28x, and Variant 1 (one fire module) achieving a 54x reduction in trainable parameters compared to SqueezeNet1.1. These findings demonstrate that our SqueezeNet1.1 architecture variants provide a flexible approach to malaria detection, enabling the selection of a variant that balances resource constraints and performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14172v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Suresh Babu Nettur, Shanthi Karpurapu, Unnati Nettur, Likhit Sagar Gajja, Sravanthy Myneni, Akhil Dusi, Lalithya Posham</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sparse Mixture-of-Experts for Non-Uniform Noise Reduction in MRI Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14198</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14198v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) is an essential diagnostic tool in clinical settings, but its utility is often hindered by noise artifacts introduced during the imaging process.Effective denoising is critical for enhancing image quality while preserving anatomical structures. However, traditional denoising methods, which often assume uniform noise distributions, struggle to handle the non-uniform noise commonly present in MRI images. In this paper, we introduce a novel approach leveraging a sparse mixture-of-experts framework for MRI image denoising. Each expert is a specialized denoising convolutional neural network fine-tuned to target specific noise characteristics associated with different image regions. Our method demonstrates superior performance over state-of-the-art denoising techniques on both synthetic and real-world brain MRI datasets. Furthermore, we show that it generalizes effectively to unseen datasets, highlighting its robustness and adaptability.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14198v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zeyun Deng, Joseph Campbell</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Only Teach Once: Learn One-Shot Bimanual Robotic Manipulation from Video Demonstrations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14208</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14208v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Bimanual robotic manipulation is a long-standing challenge of embodied intelligence due to its characteristics of dual-arm spatial-temporal coordination and high-dimensional action spaces. Previous studies rely on pre-defined action taxonomies or direct teleoperation to alleviate or circumvent these issues, often making them lack simplicity, versatility and scalability. Differently, we believe that the most effective and efficient way for teaching bimanual manipulation is learning from human demonstrated videos, where rich features such as spatial-temporal positions, dynamic postures, interaction states and dexterous transitions are available almost for free. In this work, we propose the YOTO (You Only Teach Once), which can extract and then inject patterns of bimanual actions from as few as a single binocular observation of hand movements, and teach dual robot arms various complex tasks. Furthermore, based on keyframes-based motion trajectories, we devise a subtle solution for rapidly generating training demonstrations with diverse variations of manipulated objects and their locations. These data can then be used to learn a customized bimanual diffusion policy (BiDP) across diverse scenes. In experiments, YOTO achieves impressive performance in mimicking 5 intricate long-horizon bimanual tasks, possesses strong generalization under different visual and spatial conditions, and outperforms existing visuomotor imitation learning methods in accuracy and efficiency. Our project link is https://hnuzhy.github.io/projects/YOTO.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14208v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Huayi Zhou, Ruixiang Wang, Yunxin Tai, Yueci Deng, Guiliang Liu, Kui Jia</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CDI: Blind Image Restoration Fidelity Evaluation based on Consistency with Degraded Image</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14264</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14264v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recent advancements in Blind Image Restoration (BIR) methods, based on Generative Adversarial Networks and Diffusion Models, have significantly improved visual quality. However, they present significant challenges for Image Quality Assessment (IQA), as the existing Full-Reference IQA methods often rate images with high perceptual quality poorly. In this paper, we reassess the Solution Non-Uniqueness and Degradation Indeterminacy issues of BIR, and propose constructing a specific BIR IQA system. In stead of directly comparing a restored image with a reference image, the BIR IQA evaluates fidelity by calculating the Consistency with Degraded Image (CDI). Specifically, we propose a wavelet domain Reference Guided CDI algorithm, which can acquire the consistency with a degraded image for various types without requiring knowledge of degradation parameters. The supported degradation types include down sampling, blur, noise, JPEG and complex combined degradations etc. In addition, we propose a Reference Agnostic CDI, enabling BIR fidelity evaluation without reference images. Finally, in order to validate the rationality of CDI, we create a new Degraded Images Switch Display Comparison Dataset (DISDCD) for subjective evaluation of BIR fidelity. Experiments conducted on DISDCD verify that CDI is markedly superior to common Full Reference IQA methods for BIR fidelity evaluation. The source code and the DISDCD dataset will be publicly available shortly.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14264v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaojun Tang, Jingru Wang, Guangwei Huang, Guannan Chen, Rui Zheng, Lian Huai, Yuyu Liu, Xingqun Jiang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning-Powered Classification of Thoracic Diseases in Chest X-Rays</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14279</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14279v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Chest X-rays play a pivotal role in diagnosing respiratory diseases such as pneumonia, tuberculosis, and COVID-19, which are prevalent and present unique diagnostic challenges due to overlapping visual features and variability in image quality. Severe class imbalance and the complexity of medical images hinder automated analysis. This study leverages deep learning techniques, including transfer learning on pre-trained models (AlexNet, ResNet, and InceptionNet), to enhance disease detection and classification. By fine-tuning these models and incorporating focal loss to address class imbalance, significant performance improvements were achieved. Grad-CAM visualizations further enhance model interpretability, providing insights into clinically relevant regions influencing predictions. The InceptionV3 model, for instance, achieved a 28% improvement in AUC and a 15% increase in F1-Score. These findings highlight the potential of deep learning to improve diagnostic workflows and support clinical decision-making.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14279v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yiming Lei, Michael Nguyen, Tzu Chia Liu, Hyounkyun Oh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Snapshot multi-spectral imaging through defocusing and a Fourier imager network</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14287</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14287v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Multi-spectral imaging, which simultaneously captures the spatial and spectral information of a scene, is widely used across diverse fields, including remote sensing, biomedical imaging, and agricultural monitoring. Here, we introduce a snapshot multi-spectral imaging approach employing a standard monochrome image sensor with no additional spectral filters or customized components. Our system leverages the inherent chromatic aberration of wavelength-dependent defocusing as a natural source of physical encoding of multi-spectral information; this encoded image information is rapidly decoded via a deep learning-based multi-spectral Fourier Imager Network (mFIN). We experimentally tested our method with six illumination bands and demonstrated an overall accuracy of 92.98% for predicting the illumination channels at the input and achieved a robust multi-spectral image reconstruction on various test objects. This deep learning-powered framework achieves high-quality multi-spectral image reconstruction using snapshot image acquisition with a monochrome image sensor and could be useful for applications in biomedicine, industrial quality control, and agriculture, among others.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14287v1</guid>
      <category>physics.optics</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>physics.app-ph</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xilin Yang, Michael John Fanous, Hanlong Chen, Ryan Lee, Paloma Casteleiro Costa, Yuhang Li, Luzhe Huang, Yijie Zhang, Aydogan Ozcan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automatic detection and prediction of nAMD activity change in retinal OCT using Siamese networks and Wasserstein Distance for ordinality</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14323</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14323v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Neovascular age-related macular degeneration (nAMD) is a leading cause of vision loss among older adults, where disease activity detection and progression prediction are critical for nAMD management in terms of timely drug administration and improving patient outcomes. Recent advancements in deep learning offer a promising solution for predicting changes in AMD from optical coherence tomography (OCT) retinal volumes. In this work, we proposed deep learning models for the two tasks of the public MARIO Challenge at MICCAI 2024, designed to detect and forecast changes in nAMD severity with longitudinal retinal OCT. For the first task, we employ a Vision Transformer (ViT) based Siamese Network to detect changes in AMD severity by comparing scan embeddings of a patient from different time points. To train a model to forecast the change after 3 months, we exploit, for the first time, an Earth Mover (Wasserstein) Distance-based loss to harness the ordinal relation within the severity change classes. Both models ranked high on the preliminary leaderboard, demonstrating that their predictive capabilities could facilitate nAMD treatment management.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14323v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Taha Emre, Teresa Ara\'ujo, Marzieh Oghbaie, Dmitrii Lachinov, Guilherme Aresta, Hrvoje Bogunovi\'c</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ECTIL: Label-efficient Computational Tumour Infiltrating Lymphocyte (TIL) assessment in breast cancer: Multicentre validation in 2,340 patients with breast cancer</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14379</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14379v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The level of tumour-infiltrating lymphocytes (TILs) is a prognostic factor for patients with (triple-negative) breast cancer (BC). Computational TIL assessment (CTA) has the potential to assist pathologists in this labour-intensive task, but current CTA models rely heavily on many detailed annotations. We propose and validate a fundamentally simpler deep learning based CTA that can be trained in only ten minutes on hundredfold fewer pathologist annotations. We collected whole slide images (WSIs) with TILs scores and clinical data of 2,340 patients with BC from six cohorts including three randomised clinical trials. Morphological features were extracted from whole slide images (WSIs) using a pathology foundation model. Our label-efficient Computational stromal TIL assessment model (ECTIL) directly regresses the TILs score from these features. ECTIL trained on only a few hundred samples (ECTIL-TCGA) showed concordance with the pathologist over five heterogeneous external cohorts (r=0.54-0.74, AUROC=0.80-0.94). Training on all slides of five cohorts (ECTIL-combined) improved results on a held-out test set (r=0.69, AUROC=0.85). Multivariable Cox regression analyses indicated that every 10% increase of ECTIL scores was associated with improved overall survival independent of clinicopathological variables (HR 0.86, p&lt;0.01), similar to the pathologist score (HR 0.87, p&lt;0.001). We demonstrate that ECTIL is highly concordant with an expert pathologist and obtains a similar hazard ratio. ECTIL has a fundamentally simpler design than existing methods and can be trained on orders of magnitude fewer annotations. Such a CTA may be used to pre-screen patients for, e.g., immunotherapy clinical trial inclusion, or as a tool to assist clinicians in the diagnostic work-up of patients with BC. Our model is available under an open source licence (https://github.com/nki-ai/ectil).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14379v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yoni Schirris, Rosie Voorthuis, Mark Opdam, Marte Liefaard, Gabe S Sonke, Gwen Dackus, Vincent de Jong, Yuwei Wang, Annelot Van Rossum, Tessa G Steenbruggen, Lars C Steggink, Liesbeth G. E. de Vries, Marc van de Vijver, Roberto Salgado, Efstratios Gavves, Paul J van Diest, Sabine C Linn, Jonas Teuwen, Renee Menezes, Marleen Kok, Hugo Horlings</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Registration of Longitudinal Liver Examinations for Tumor Progress Assessment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14483</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14483v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Assessing cancer progression in liver CT scans is a clinical challenge, requiring a comparison of scans at different times for the same patient. Practitioners must identify existing tumors, compare them with prior exams, identify new tumors, and evaluate overall disease evolution. This process is particularly complex in liver examinations due to misalignment between exams caused by several factors. Indeed, longitudinal liver examinations can undergo different non-pathological and pathological changes due to non-rigid deformations, the appearance or disappearance of pathologies, and other variations. In such cases, existing registration approaches, mainly based on intrinsic features may distort tumor regions, biasing the tumor progress evaluation step and the corresponding diagnosis. This work proposes a registration method based only on geometrical and anatomical information from liver segmentation, aimed at aligning longitudinal liver images for aided diagnosis. The proposed method is trained and tested on longitudinal liver CT scans, with 317 patients for training and 53 for testing. Our experimental results support our claims by showing that our method is better than other registration techniques by providing a smoother deformation while preserving the tumor burden (total volume of tissues considered as tumor) within the volume. Qualitative results emphasize the importance of smooth deformations in preserving tumor appearance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14483v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>physics.med-ph</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Walid Yassine, Martin Charachon, C\'eline Hudelot, Roberto Ardon</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Note on Implementation Errors in Recent Adaptive Attacks Against Multi-Resolution Self-Ensembles</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14496</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14496v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This note documents an implementation issue in recent adaptive attacks (Zhang et al. [2024]) against the multi-resolution self-ensemble defense (Fort and Lakshminarayanan [2024]). The implementation allowed adversarial perturbations to exceed the standard $L_\infty = 8/255$ bound by up to a factor of 20$\times$, reaching magnitudes of up to $L_\infty = 160/255$. When attacks are properly constrained within the intended bounds, the defense maintains non-trivial robustness. Beyond highlighting the importance of careful validation in adversarial machine learning research, our analysis reveals an intriguing finding: properly bounded adaptive attacks against strong multi-resolution self-ensembles often align with human perception, suggesting the need to reconsider how we measure adversarial robustness.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14496v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Stanislav Fort</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LiDAR-Based Vehicle Detection and Tracking for Autonomous Racing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14502</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14502v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Autonomous racing provides a controlled environment for testing the software and hardware of autonomous vehicles operating at their performance limits. Competitive interactions between multiple autonomous racecars however introduce challenging and potentially dangerous scenarios. Accurate and consistent vehicle detection and tracking is crucial for overtaking maneuvers, and low-latency sensor processing is essential to respond quickly to hazardous situations. This paper presents the LiDAR-based perception algorithms deployed on Team PoliMOVE's autonomous racecar, which won multiple competitions in the Indy Autonomous Challenge series. Our Vehicle Detection and Tracking pipeline is composed of a novel fast Point Cloud Segmentation technique and a specific Vehicle Pose Estimation methodology, together with a variable-step Multi-Target Tracking algorithm. Experimental results demonstrate the algorithm's performance, robustness, computational efficiency, and suitability for autonomous racing applications, enabling fully autonomous overtaking maneuvers at velocities exceeding 275 km/h.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14502v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Marcello Cellina, Matteo Corno, Sergio Matteo Savaresi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scene Understanding Enabled Semantic Communication with Open Channel Coding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14520</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14520v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: As communication systems transition from symbol transmission to conveying meaningful information, sixth-generation (6G) networks emphasize semantic communication. This approach prioritizes high-level semantic information, improving robustness and reducing redundancy across modalities like text, speech, and images. However, traditional semantic communication faces limitations, including static coding strategies, poor generalization, and reliance on task-specific knowledge bases that hinder adaptability. To overcome these challenges, we propose a novel system combining scene understanding, Large Language Models (LLMs), and open channel coding, named \textbf{OpenSC}. Traditional systems rely on fixed domain-specific knowledge bases, limiting their ability to generalize. Our open channel coding approach leverages shared, publicly available knowledge, enabling flexible, adaptive encoding. This dynamic system reduces reliance on static task-specific data, enhancing adaptability across diverse tasks and environments. Additionally, we use scene graphs for structured semantic encoding, capturing object relationships and context to improve tasks like Visual Question Answering (VQA). Our approach selectively encodes key semantic elements, minimizing redundancy and improving transmission efficiency. Experimental results show significant improvements in both semantic understanding and efficiency, advancing the potential of adaptive, generalizable semantic communication in 6G networks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14520v1</guid>
      <category>eess.SP</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhe Xiang, Fei Yu, Quan Deng, Yuandi Li, Zhiguo Wan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved Vessel Segmentation with Symmetric Rotation-Equivariant U-Net</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14592</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14592v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Automated segmentation plays a pivotal role in medical image analysis and computer-assisted interventions. Despite the promising performance of existing methods based on convolutional neural networks (CNNs), they neglect useful equivariant properties for images, such as rotational and reflection equivariance. This limitation can decrease performance and lead to inconsistent predictions, especially in applications like vessel segmentation where explicit orientation is absent. While existing equivariant learning approaches attempt to mitigate these issues, they substantially increase learning cost, model size, or both. To overcome these challenges, we propose a novel application of an efficient symmetric rotation-equivariant (SRE) convolutional (SRE-Conv) kernel implementation to the U-Net architecture, to learn rotation and reflection-equivariant features, while also reducing the model size dramatically. We validate the effectiveness of our method through improved segmentation performance on retina vessel fundus imaging. Our proposed SRE U-Net not only significantly surpasses standard U-Net in handling rotated images, but also outperforms existing equivariant learning methods and does so with a reduced number of trainable parameters and smaller memory cost. The code is available at https://github.com/OnofreyLab/sre_conv_segm_isbi2025.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14592v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiazhen Zhang, Yuexi Du, Nicha C. Dvornek, John A. Onofrey</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Foundation Models for Medical Image Classification through a Benchmark Study on MedMNIST</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14685</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14685v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Foundation models are widely employed in medical image analysis, due to their high adaptability and generalizability for downstream tasks. With the increasing number of foundation models being released, model selection has become an important issue. In this work, we study the capabilities of foundation models in medical image classification tasks by conducting a benchmark study on the MedMNIST dataset. Specifically, we adopt various foundation models ranging from convolutional to Transformer-based models and implement both end-to-end training and linear probing for all classification tasks. The results demonstrate the significant potential of these pre-trained models when transferred for medical image classification. We further conduct experiments with different image sizes and various sizes of training data. By analyzing all the results, we provide preliminary, yet useful insights and conclusions on this topic.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14685v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fuping Wu, Bartlomiej W. Papiez</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stroke classification using Virtual Hybrid Edge Detection from in silico electrical impedance tomography data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14704</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14704v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Electrical impedance tomography (EIT) is a non-invasive imaging method for recovering the internal conductivity of a physical body from electric boundary measurements. EIT combined with machine learning has shown promise for the classification of strokes. However, most previous works have used raw EIT voltage data as network inputs. We build upon a recent development which suggested the use of special noise-robust Virtual Hybrid Edge Detection (VHED) functions as network inputs, although that work used only highly simplified and mathematically ideal models. In this work we strengthen the case for the use of EIT, and VHED functions especially, for stroke classification. We design models with high detail and mathematical realism to test the use of VHED functions as inputs. Virtual patients are created using a physically detailed 2D head model which includes features known to create challenges in real-world imaging scenarios. Conductivity values are drawn from statistically realistic distributions, and phantoms are afflicted with either hemorrhagic or ischemic strokes of various shapes and sizes. Simulated noisy EIT electrode data, generated using the realistic Complete Electrode Model (CEM) as opposed to the mathematically ideal continuum model, is processed to obtain VHED functions. We compare the use of VHED functions as inputs against the alternative paradigm of using raw EIT voltages. Our results show that (i) stroke classification can be performed with high accuracy using 2D EIT data from physically detailed and mathematically realistic models, and (ii) in the presence of noise, VHED functions outperform raw data as network inputs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14704v1</guid>
      <category>math.AP</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.NA</category>
      <category>math.NA</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Juan Pablo Agnelli, Fernando S. Moura, Siiri Rautio, Melody Alsaker, Rashmi Murthy, Matti Lassas, Samuli Siltanen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Confocal Laser Scanning Microscopy with Adaptive Physics Informed Deep Autoencoders</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14709</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14709v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We present a physics-informed deep learning framework to address common limitations in Confocal Laser Scanning Microscopy (CLSM), such as diffraction limited resolution, noise, and undersampling due to low laser power conditions. The optical system's point spread function (PSF) and common CLSM image degradation mechanisms namely photon shot noise, dark current noise, motion blur, speckle noise, and undersampling were modeled and were directly included into model architecture. The model reconstructs high fidelity images from heavily noisy inputs by using convolutional and transposed convolutional layers. Following the advances in compressed sensing, our approach significantly reduces data acquisition requirements without compromising image resolution. The proposed method was extensively evaluated on simulated CLSM images of diverse structures, including lipid droplets, neuronal networks, and fibrillar systems. Comparisons with traditional deconvolution algorithms such as Richardson-Lucy (RL), non-negative least squares (NNLS), and other methods like Total Variation (TV) regularization, Wiener filtering, and Wavelet denoising demonstrate the superiority of the network in restoring fine structural details with high fidelity. Assessment metrics like Structural Similarity Index (SSIM) and Peak Signal to Noise Ratio (PSNR), underlines that the AdaptivePhysicsAutoencoder achieved robust image enhancement across diverse CLSM conditions, helping faster acquisition, reduced photodamage, and reliable performance in low light and sparse sampling scenarios holding promise for applications in live cell imaging, dynamic biological studies, and high throughput material characterization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14709v1</guid>
      <category>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zaheer Ahmad, Junaid Shabeer, Usman Saleem, Tahir Qadeer, Abdul Sami, Zahira El Khalidi, Saad Mehmood</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mitigating GenAI-powered Evidence Pollution for Out-of-Context Multimodal Misinformation Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.14728</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.14728v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: While large generative artificial intelligence (GenAI) models have achieved significant success, they also raise growing concerns about online information security due to their potential misuse for generating deceptive content. Out-of-context (OOC) multimodal misinformation detection, which often retrieves Web evidence to identify the repurposing of images in false contexts, faces the issue of reasoning over GenAI-polluted evidence to derive accurate predictions. Existing works simulate GenAI-powered pollution at the claim level with stylistic rewriting to conceal linguistic cues, and ignore evidence-level pollution for such information-seeking applications. In this work, we investigate how polluted evidence affects the performance of existing OOC detectors, revealing a performance degradation of more than 9 percentage points. We propose two strategies, cross-modal evidence reranking and cross-modal claim-evidence reasoning, to address the challenges posed by polluted evidence. Extensive experiments on two benchmark datasets show that these strategies can effectively enhance the robustness of existing out-of-context detectors amidst polluted evidence.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.14728v1</guid>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zehong Yan, Peng Qi, Wynne Hsu, Mong Li Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COLT: Cyclic Overlapping Lottery Tickets for Faster Pruning of Convolutional Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2212.12770</link>
      <description>arXiv:2212.12770v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Pruning refers to the elimination of trivial weights from neural networks. The sub-networks within an overparameterized model produced after pruning are often called Lottery tickets. This research aims to generate winning lottery tickets from a set of lottery tickets that can achieve similar accuracy to the original unpruned network. We introduce a novel winning ticket called Cyclic Overlapping Lottery Ticket (COLT) by data splitting and cyclic retraining of the pruned network from scratch. We apply a cyclic pruning algorithm that keeps only the overlapping weights of different pruned models trained on different data segments. Our results demonstrate that COLT can achieve similar accuracies (obtained by the unpruned model) while maintaining high sparsities. We show that the accuracy of COLT is on par with the winning tickets of Lottery Ticket Hypothesis (LTH) and, at times, is better. Moreover, COLTs can be generated using fewer iterations than tickets generated by the popular Iterative Magnitude Pruning (IMP) method. In addition, we also notice COLTs generated on large datasets can be transferred to small ones without compromising performance, demonstrating its generalizing capability. We conduct all our experiments on Cifar-10, Cifar-100 &amp; TinyImageNet datasets and report superior performance than the state-of-the-art methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2212.12770v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Md. Ismail Hossain, Mohammed Rakib, M. M. Lutfe Elahi, Nabeel Mohammed, Shafin Rahman</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Skip-WaveNet: A Wavelet based Multi-scale Architecture to Trace Snow Layers in Radar Echograms</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.19574</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.19574v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Airborne radar sensors capture the profile of snow layers present on top of an ice sheet. Accurate tracking of these layers is essential to calculate their thicknesses, which are required to investigate the contribution of polar ice cap melt to sea-level rise. However, automatically processing the radar echograms to detect the underlying snow layers is a challenging problem. In our work, we develop wavelet-based multi-scale deep learning architectures for these radar echograms to improve snow layer detection. These architectures estimate the layer depths with a mean absolute error of 3.31 pixels and 94.3% average precision, achieving higher generalizability as compared to state-of-the-art snow layer detection networks. These depth estimates also agree well with physically drilled stake measurements. Such robust architectures can be used on echograms from future missions to efficiently trace snow layers, estimate their individual thicknesses and thus support sea-level rise projection models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.19574v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1017/eds.2024.25</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Environmental Data Science, Volume 3, 2024, e39</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Debvrat Varshney, Masoud Yari, Oluwanisola Ibikunle, Jilu Li, John Paden, Aryya Gangopadhyay, Maryam Rahnemoonfar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exposure Bracketing Is All You Need For A High-Quality Image</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.00766</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.00766v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: It is highly desired but challenging to acquire high-quality photos with clear content in low-light environments. Although multi-image processing methods (using burst, dual-exposure, or multi-exposure images) have made significant progress in addressing this issue, they typically focus on specific restoration or enhancement problems, and do not fully explore the potential of utilizing multiple images. Motivated by the fact that multi-exposure images are complementary in denoising, deblurring, high dynamic range imaging, and super-resolution, we propose to utilize exposure bracketing photography to get a high-quality image by combining these tasks in this work. Due to the difficulty in collecting real-world pairs, we suggest a solution that first pre-trains the model with synthetic paired data and then adapts it to real-world unlabeled images. In particular, a temporally modulated recurrent network (TMRNet) and self-supervised adaptation method are proposed. Moreover, we construct a data simulation pipeline to synthesize pairs and collect real-world images from 200 nighttime scenarios. Experiments on both datasets show that our method performs favorably against the state-of-the-art multi-image processing ones. Code and datasets are available at https://github.com/cszhilu1998/BracketIRE.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.00766v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhilu Zhang, Shuohao Zhang, Renlong Wu, Zifei Yan, Wangmeng Zuo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASCNet: Asymmetric Sampling Correction Network for Infrared Image Destriping</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.15578</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.15578v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In a real-world infrared imaging system, effectively learning a consistent stripe noise removal model is essential. Most existing destriping methods cannot precisely reconstruct images due to cross-level semantic gaps and insufficient characterization of the global column features. To tackle this problem, we propose a novel infrared image destriping method, called Asymmetric Sampling Correction Network (ASCNet), that can effectively capture global column relationships and embed them into a U-shaped framework, providing comprehensive discriminative representation and seamless semantic connectivity. Our ASCNet consists of three core elements: Residual Haar Discrete Wavelet Transform (RHDWT), Pixel Shuffle (PS), and Column Non-uniformity Correction Module (CNCM). Specifically, RHDWT is a novel downsampler that employs double-branch modeling to effectively integrate stripe-directional prior knowledge and data-driven semantic interaction to enrich the feature representation. Observing the semantic patterns crosstalk of stripe noise, PS is introduced as an upsampler to prevent excessive apriori decoding and performing semantic-bias-free image reconstruction. After each sampling, CNCM captures the column relationships in long-range dependencies. By incorporating column, spatial, and self-dependence information, CNCM well establishes a global context to distinguish stripes from the scene's vertical structures. Extensive experiments on synthetic data, real data, and infrared small target detection tasks demonstrate that the proposed method outperforms state-of-the-art single-image destriping methods both visually and quantitatively. Our code will be made publicly available at https://github.com/xdFai/ASCNet.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.15578v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shuai Yuan, Hanlin Qin, Xiang Yan, Shiqi Yang, Shuowen Yang, Naveed Akhtar, Huixin Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Adaptive Cost-Sensitive Learning and Recursive Denoising Framework for Imbalanced SVM Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.08378</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.08378v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Category imbalance is one of the most popular and important issues in the domain of classification. Emotion classification model trained on imbalanced datasets easily leads to unreliable prediction. The traditional machine learning method tends to favor the majority class, which leads to the lack of minority class information in the model. Moreover, most existing models will produce abnormal sensitivity issues or performance degradation. We propose a robust learning algorithm based on adaptive cost-sensitivity and recursive denoising, which is a generalized framework and can be incorporated into most stochastic optimization algorithms. The proposed method uses the dynamic kernel distance optimization model between the sample and the decision boundary, which makes full use of the sample's prior information. In addition, we also put forward an effective method to filter noise, the main idea of which is to judge the noise by finding the nearest neighbors of the minority class. In order to evaluate the strength of the proposed method, we not only carry out experiments on standard datasets but also apply it to emotional classification problems with different imbalance rates (IR). Experimental results show that the proposed general framework is superior to traditional methods in Accuracy, G-mean, Recall and F1-score.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.08378v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lu Jiang, Qi Wang, Yuhang Chang, Jianing Song, Haoyue Fu, Xiaochun Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ComPC: Completing a 3D Point Cloud with 2D Diffusion Priors</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.06814</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.06814v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: 3D point clouds directly collected from objects through sensors are often incomplete due to self-occlusion. Conventional methods for completing these partial point clouds rely on manually organized training sets and are usually limited to object categories seen during training. In this work, we propose a test-time framework for completing partial point clouds across unseen categories without any requirement for training. Leveraging point rendering via Gaussian Splatting, we develop techniques of Partial Gaussian Initialization, Zero-shot Fractal Completion, and Point Cloud Extraction that utilize priors from pre-trained 2D diffusion models to infer missing regions and extract uniform completed point clouds. Experimental results on both synthetic and real-world scanned point clouds demonstrate that our approach outperforms existing methods in completing a variety of objects. Our project page is at \url{https://tianxinhuang.github.io/projects/ComPC/}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.06814v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tianxin Huang, Zhiwen Yan, Yuyang Zhao, Gim Hee Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New Cross-Space Total Variation Regularization Model for Color Image Restoration with Quaternion Blur Operator</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.12114</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.12114v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The cross-channel deblurring problem in color image processing is difficult to solve due to the complex coupling and structural blurring of color pixels. Until now, there are few efficient algorithms that can reduce color artifacts in deblurring process. To solve this challenging problem, we present a novel cross-space total variation (CSTV) regularization model for color image deblurring by introducing a quaternion blur operator and a cross-color space regularization functional. The existence and uniqueness of the solution is proved and a new L-curve method is proposed to find a balance of regularization terms on different color spaces. The Euler-Lagrange equation is derived to show that CSTV has taken into account the coupling of all color channels and the local smoothing within each color channel. A quaternion operator splitting method is firstly proposed to enhance the ability of color artifacts reduction of the CSTV regularization model. This strategy also applies to the well-known color deblurring models. Numerical experiments on color image databases illustrate the efficiency and effectiveness of the new model and algorithms. The color images restored by them successfully maintain the color and spatial information and are of higher quality in terms of PSNR, SSIM, MSE and CIEde2000 than the restorations of the-state-of-the-art methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.12114v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.NA</category>
      <category>math.NA</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhigang Jia, Yuelian Xiang, Meixiang Zhao, Tingting Wu, Michael K. Ng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive Retention &amp; Correction: Test-Time Training for Continual Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.14318</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.14318v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Continual learning, also known as lifelong learning or incremental learning, refers to the process by which a model learns from a stream of incoming data over time. A common problem in continual learning is the classification layer's bias towards the most recent task. Traditionally, methods have relied on incorporating data from past tasks during training to mitigate this issue. However, the recent shift in continual learning to memory-free environments has rendered these approaches infeasible. In this study, we propose a solution focused on the testing phase. We first introduce a simple Out-of-Task Detection method, OTD, designed to accurately identify samples from past tasks during testing. Leveraging OTD, we then propose: (1) an Adaptive Retention mechanism for dynamically tuning the classifier layer on past task data; (2) an Adaptive Correction mechanism for revising predictions when the model classifies data from previous tasks into classes from the current task. We name our approach Adaptive Retention &amp; Correction (ARC). While designed for memory-free environments, ARC also proves effective in memory-based settings. Extensive experiments show that our proposed method can be plugged in to virtually any existing continual learning approach without requiring any modifications to its training procedure. Specifically, when integrated with state-of-the-art approaches, ARC achieves an average performance increase of 2.7% and 2.6% on the CIFAR-100 and Imagenet-R datasets, respectively.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.14318v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haoran Chen, Micah Goldblum, Zuxuan Wu, Yu-Gang Jiang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dysca: A Dynamic and Scalable Benchmark for Evaluating Perception Ability of LVLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.18849</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.18849v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Currently many benchmarks have been proposed to evaluate the perception ability of the Large Vision-Language Models (LVLMs). However, most benchmarks conduct questions by selecting images from existing datasets, resulting in the potential data leakage. Besides, these benchmarks merely focus on evaluating LVLMs on the realistic style images and clean scenarios, leaving the multi-stylized images and noisy scenarios unexplored. In response to these challenges, we propose a dynamic and scalable benchmark named Dysca for evaluating LVLMs by leveraging synthesis images. Specifically, we leverage Stable Diffusion and design a rule-based method to dynamically generate novel images, questions and the corresponding answers. We consider 51 kinds of image styles and evaluate the perception capability in 20 subtasks. Moreover, we conduct evaluations under 4 scenarios (i.e., Clean, Corruption, Print Attacking and Adversarial Attacking) and 3 question types (i.e., Multi-choices, True-or-false and Free-form). Thanks to the generative paradigm, Dysca serves as a scalable benchmark for easily adding new subtasks and scenarios. A total of 24 advanced open-source LVLMs and 2 close-source LVLMs are evaluated on Dysca, revealing the drawbacks of current LVLMs. The benchmark is released at \url{https://github.com/Robin-WZQ/Dysca}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.18849v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jie Zhang, Zhongqi Wang, Mengqi Lei, Zheng Yuan, Bei Yan, Shiguang Shan, Xilin Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PreMix: Addressing Label Scarcity in Whole Slide Image Classification with Pre-trained Multiple Instance Learning Aggregators</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.01162</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.01162v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Multiple instance learning (MIL) has emerged as a powerful framework for weakly supervised whole slide image (WSI) classification, enabling slide-level predictions without requiring detailed patch-level annotations. However, a key limitation of MIL lies in the underexplored potential of pre-training the MIL aggregator. Most existing approaches train it from scratch, resulting in performance heavily dependent on the number of labeled WSIs, while overlooking the abundance of unlabeled WSIs available in real-world scenarios. To address this, we propose PreMix, a novel framework that leverages a non-contrastive pre-training method, Barlow Twins, augmented with the Slide Mixing approach to generate additional positive pairs and enhance feature learning, particularly under limited labeled WSI conditions. Fine-tuning with Mixup and Manifold Mixup further enhances robustness by effectively handling the diverse sizes of gigapixel WSIs. Experimental results demonstrate that integrating HIPT into PreMix achieves an average F1 improvement of 4.7% over the baseline HIPT across various WSI training datasets and label sizes. These findings underscore its potential to advance WSI classification with limited labeled data and its applicability to real-world histopathology practices. The code is available at https://anonymous.4open.science/r/PreMix</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.01162v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bryan Wong, Mun Yong Yi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HeightLane: BEV Heightmap guided 3D Lane Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08270</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08270v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Accurate 3D lane detection from monocular images presents significant challenges due to depth ambiguity and imperfect ground modeling. Previous attempts to model the ground have often used a planar ground assumption with limited degrees of freedom, making them unsuitable for complex road environments with varying slopes. Our study introduces HeightLane, an innovative method that predicts a height map from monocular images by creating anchors based on a multi-slope assumption. This approach provides a detailed and accurate representation of the ground. HeightLane employs the predicted heightmap along with a deformable attention-based spatial feature transform framework to efficiently convert 2D image features into 3D bird's eye view (BEV) features, enhancing spatial understanding and lane structure recognition. Additionally, the heightmap is used for the positional encoding of BEV features, further improving their spatial accuracy. This explicit view transformation bridges the gap between front-view perceptions and spatially accurate BEV representations, significantly improving detection performance. To address the lack of the necessary ground truth (GT) height map in the original OpenLane dataset, we leverage the Waymo dataset and accumulate its LiDAR data to generate a height map for the drivable area of each scene. The GT heightmaps are used to train the heightmap extraction module from monocular images. Extensive experiments on the OpenLane validation set show that HeightLane achieves state-of-the-art performance in terms of F-score, highlighting its potential in real-world applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08270v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chaesong Park, Eunbin Seo, Jongwoo Lim</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Token Turing Machines are Efficient Vision Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.07613</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.07613v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We propose Vision Token Turing Machines (ViTTM), an efficient, low-latency, memory-augmented Vision Transformer (ViT). Our approach builds on Neural Turing Machines and Token Turing Machines, which were applied to NLP and sequential visual understanding tasks. ViTTMs are designed for non-sequential computer vision tasks such as image classification and segmentation. Our model creates two sets of tokens: process tokens and memory tokens; process tokens pass through encoder blocks and read-write from memory tokens at each encoder block in the network, allowing them to store and retrieve information from memory. By ensuring that there are fewer process tokens than memory tokens, we are able to reduce the inference time of the network while maintaining its accuracy. On ImageNet-1K, the state-of-the-art ViT-B has median latency of 529.5ms and 81.0% accuracy, while our ViTTM-B is 56% faster (234.1ms), with 2.4 times fewer FLOPs, with an accuracy of 82.9%. On ADE20K semantic segmentation, ViT-B achieves 45.65mIoU at 13.8 frame-per-second (FPS) whereas our ViTTM-B model acheives a 45.17 mIoU with 26.8 FPS (+94%).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.07613v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Purvish Jajal, Nick John Eliopoulos, Benjamin Shiue-Hal Chou, George K. Thiruvathukal, James C. Davis, Yung-Hsiang Lu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-Situ Fine-Tuning of Wildlife Models in IoT-Enabled Camera Traps for Efficient Adaptation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.07796</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.07796v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Resource-constrained IoT devices increasingly rely on deep learning models for inference tasks in remote environments. However, these models experience significant accuracy drops due to domain shifts when encountering variations in lighting, weather, and seasonal conditions. While cloud-based retraining can address this issue, many IoT deployments operate with limited connectivity and energy constraints, making traditional fine-tuning approaches impractical. We explore this challenge through the lens of wildlife ecology, where camera traps must maintain accurate species classification across changing seasons, weather, and habitats without reliable connectivity. We introduce WildFit, an autonomous in-situ adaptation framework that leverages the key insight that background scenes change more frequently than the visual characteristics of monitored species. WildFit combines background-aware synthesis to generate training samples on-device with drift-aware fine-tuning that triggers model updates only when necessary to conserve resources. Through extensive evaluation on multiple camera trap deployments, we demonstrate that WildFit significantly improves accuracy while greatly reducing adaptation overhead compared to traditional approaches.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.07796v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mohammad Mehdi Rastikerdar, Jin Huang, Hui Guan, Deepak Ganesan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From One to the Power of Many: Invariance to Multi-LiDAR Perception from Single-Sensor Datasets</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.18592</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.18592v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recently, LiDAR segmentation methods for autonomous vehicles, powered by deep neural networks, have experienced steep growth in performance on classic benchmarks, such as nuScenes and SemanticKITTI. However, there are still large gaps in performance when deploying models trained on such single-sensor setups to modern vehicles with multiple high-resolution LiDAR sensors. In this work, we introduce a new metric for feature-level invariance which can serve as a proxy to measure cross-domain generalization without requiring labeled data. Additionally, we propose two application-specific data augmentations, which facilitate better transfer to multi-sensor LiDAR setups, when trained on single-sensor datasets. We provide experimental evidence on both simulated and real data, that our proposed augmentations improve invariance across LiDAR setups, leading to improved generalization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.18592v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Marc Uecker, J. Marius Z\"ollner</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ControlAR: Controllable Image Generation with Autoregressive Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.02705</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.02705v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Autoregressive (AR) models have reformulated image generation as next-token prediction, demonstrating remarkable potential and emerging as strong competitors to diffusion models. However, control-to-image generation, akin to ControlNet, remains largely unexplored within AR models. Although a natural approach, inspired by advancements in Large Language Models, is to tokenize control images into tokens and prefill them into the autoregressive model before decoding image tokens, it still falls short in generation quality compared to ControlNet and suffers from inefficiency. To this end, we introduce ControlAR, an efficient and effective framework for integrating spatial controls into autoregressive image generation models. Firstly, we explore control encoding for AR models and propose a lightweight control encoder to transform spatial inputs (e.g., canny edges or depth maps) into control tokens. Then ControlAR exploits the conditional decoding method to generate the next image token conditioned on the per-token fusion between control and image tokens, similar to positional encodings. Compared to prefilling tokens, using conditional decoding significantly strengthens the control capability of AR models but also maintains the model's efficiency. Furthermore, the proposed ControlAR surprisingly empowers AR models with arbitrary-resolution image generation via conditional decoding and specific controls. Extensive experiments can demonstrate the controllability of the proposed ControlAR for the autoregressive control-to-image generation across diverse inputs, including edges, depths, and segmentation masks. Furthermore, both quantitative and qualitative results indicate that ControlAR surpasses previous state-of-the-art controllable diffusion models, e.g., ControlNet++. Code, models, and demo will soon be available at https://github.com/hustvl/ControlAR.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.02705v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zongming Li, Tianheng Cheng, Shoufa Chen, Peize Sun, Haocheng Shen, Longjin Ran, Xiaoxin Chen, Wenyu Liu, Xinggang Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Encoder-Decoder Architecture for Accurate Monocular Depth Estimation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.11610</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.11610v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Estimating depth from a single 2D image is a challenging task due to the lack of stereo or multi-view data, which are typically required for depth perception. In state-of-the-art architectures, the main challenge is to efficiently capture complex objects and fine-grained details, which are often difficult to predict. This paper introduces a novel deep learning-based approach using an enhanced encoder-decoder architecture, where the Inception-ResNet-v2 model serves as the encoder. This is the first instance of utilizing Inception-ResNet-v2 as an encoder for monocular depth estimation, demonstrating improved performance over previous models. It incorporates multi-scale feature extraction to enhance depth prediction accuracy across various object sizes and distances. We propose a composite loss function comprising depth loss, gradient edge loss, and Structural Similarity Index Measure (SSIM) loss, with fine-tuned weights to optimize the weighted sum, ensuring a balance across different aspects of depth estimation. Experimental results on the KITTI dataset show that our model achieves a significantly faster inference time of 0.019 seconds, outperforming vision transformers in efficiency while maintaining good accuracy. On the NYU Depth V2 dataset, the model establishes state-of-the-art performance, with an Absolute Relative Error (ARE) of 0.064, a Root Mean Square Error (RMSE) of 0.228, and an accuracy of 89.3% for $\delta$ &lt; 1.25. These metrics demonstrate that our model can accurately and efficiently predict depth even in challenging scenarios, providing a practical solution for real-time applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.11610v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dabbrata Das, Argho Deb Das, Farhan Sadaf</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S3PT: Scene Semantics and Structure Guided Clustering to Boost Self-Supervised Pre-Training for Autonomous Driving</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.23085</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.23085v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent self-supervised clustering-based pre-training techniques like DINO and Cribo have shown impressive results for downstream detection and segmentation tasks. However, real-world applications such as autonomous driving face challenges with imbalanced object class and size distributions and complex scene geometries. In this paper, we propose S3PT a novel scene semantics and structure guided clustering to provide more scene-consistent objectives for self-supervised training. Specifically, our contributions are threefold: First, we incorporate semantic distribution consistent clustering to encourage better representation of rare classes such as motorcycles or animals. Second, we introduce object diversity consistent spatial clustering, to handle imbalanced and diverse object sizes, ranging from large background areas to small objects such as pedestrians and traffic signs. Third, we propose a depth-guided spatial clustering to regularize learning based on geometric information of the scene, thus further refining region separation on the feature level. Our learned representations significantly improve performance in downstream semantic segmentation and 3D object detection tasks on the nuScenes, nuImages, and Cityscapes datasets and show promising domain translation properties.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.23085v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Maciej K. Wozniak, Hariprasath Govindarajan, Marvin Klingner, Camille Maurice, B Ravi Kiran, Senthil Yogamani</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Interpretable X-ray Style Transfer via Trainable Local Laplacian Filter</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.07072</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.07072v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Radiologists have preferred visual impressions or 'styles' of X-ray images that are manually adjusted to their needs to support their diagnostic performance. In this work, we propose an automatic and interpretable X-ray style transfer by introducing a trainable version of the Local Laplacian Filter (LLF). From the shape of the LLF's optimized remap function, the characteristics of the style transfer can be inferred and reliability of the algorithm can be ensured. Moreover, we enable the LLF to capture complex X-ray style features by replacing the remap function with a Multi-Layer Perceptron (MLP) and adding a trainable normalization layer. We demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed method by transforming unprocessed mammographic X-ray images into images that match the style of target mammograms and achieve a Structural Similarity Index (SSIM) of 0.94 compared to 0.82 of the baseline LLF style transfer method from Aubry et al.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.07072v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dominik Eckert, Ludwig Ritschl, Christopher Syben, Christian H\"ummer, Julia Wicklein, Marcel Beister, Steffen Kappler, Sebastian Stober</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the Visual Gap: Fine-Tuning Multimodal Models with Knowledge-Adapted Captions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.09018</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.09018v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent research increasingly focuses on training vision-language models (VLMs) with long, detailed image captions. However, small-scale VLMs often struggle to balance the richness of these captions with the risk of hallucinating content during fine-tuning. In this paper, we explore how well VLMs adapt to such captions. To quantify caption quality, we propose Decomposed NLI (DNLI), an evaluation framework that breaks down generated captions into individual propositions, assessing each in isolation. This fine-grained analysis reveals a critical balance between capturing descriptive details and preventing hallucinations. Our findings show that simply reducing caption complexity or employing standard data curation techniques does not effectively resolve this issue. To tackle this challenge, we introduce Knowledge Adapted (KnowAda) fine-tuning, a data-centric approach that automatically adapts training data with the model's existing knowledge and visual understanding. KnowAda minimizes hallucinations while preserving high descriptiveness. We validate this approach across several small-scale VLMs (up to 7B parameters) and dense caption datasets, demonstrating that KnowAda effectively balances hallucination reduction and descriptiveness. Our results show that KnowAda outperforms various baselines in both automatic metrics and human evaluations. We will release our code and models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.09018v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Moran Yanuka, Assaf Ben Kish, Yonatan Bitton, Idan Szpektor, Raja Giryes</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LoFi: Vision-Aided Label Generator for Wi-Fi Localization and Tracking</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.05074</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.05074v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Data-driven Wi-Fi localization and tracking have shown great promise due to their lower reliance on specialized hardware compared to model-based methods. However, most existing data collection techniques provide only coarse-grained ground truth or a limited number of labeled points, significantly hindering the advancement of data-driven approaches. While systems like lidar can deliver precise ground truth, their high costs make them inaccessible to many users. To address these challenges, we propose LoFi, a vision-aided label generator for Wi-Fi localization and tracking. LoFi can generate ground truth position coordinates solely from 2D images, offering high precision, low cost, and ease of use. Utilizing our method, we have compiled a Wi-Fi tracking and localization dataset using the ESP32-S3 and a webcam, which will be open-sourced along with the code upon publication.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.05074v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.SP</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zijian Zhao, Tingwei Chen, Fanyi Meng, Zhijie Cai, Hang Li, Xiaoyang Li, Guangxu Zhu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Vector Quantization for Unsupervised Action Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.17640</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.17640v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this work, we address unsupervised temporal action segmentation, which segments a set of long, untrimmed videos into semantically meaningful segments that are consistent across videos. While recent approaches combine representation learning and clustering in a single step for this task, they do not cope with large variations within temporal segments of the same class. To address this limitation, we propose a novel method, termed Hierarchical Vector Quantization (HVQ), that consists of two subsequent vector quantization modules. This results in a hierarchical clustering where the additional subclusters cover the variations within a cluster. We demonstrate that our approach captures the distribution of segment lengths much better than the state of the art. To this end, we introduce a new metric based on the Jensen-Shannon Distance (JSD) for unsupervised temporal action segmentation. We evaluate our approach on three public datasets, namely Breakfast, YouTube Instructional and IKEA ASM. Our approach outperforms the state of the art in terms of F1 score, recall and JSD.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.17640v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Federico Spurio, Emad Bahrami, Gianpiero Francesca, Juergen Gall</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ViPCap: Retrieval Text-Based Visual Prompts for Lightweight Image Captioning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.19289</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.19289v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent lightweight image captioning models using retrieved data mainly focus on text prompts. However, previous works only utilize the retrieved text as text prompts, and the visual information relies only on the CLIP visual embedding. Because of this issue, there is a limitation that the image descriptions inherent in the prompt are not sufficiently reflected in the visual embedding space. To tackle this issue, we propose ViPCap, a novel retrieval text-based visual prompt for lightweight image captioning. ViPCap leverages the retrieved text with image information as visual prompts to enhance the ability of the model to capture relevant visual information. By mapping text prompts into the CLIP space and generating multiple randomized Gaussian distributions, our method leverages sampling to explore randomly augmented distributions and effectively retrieves the semantic features that contain image information. These retrieved features are integrated into the image and designated as the visual prompt, leading to performance improvements on the datasets such as COCO, Flickr30k, and NoCaps. Experimental results demonstrate that ViPCap significantly outperforms prior lightweight captioning models in efficiency and effectiveness, demonstrating the potential for a plug-and-play solution. The source code is available at https://github.com/taewhankim/VIPCAP.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.19289v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Taewhan Kim, Soeun Lee, Si-Woo Kim, Dong-Jin Kim</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interpretable Face Anti-Spoofing: Enhancing Generalization with Multimodal Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01720</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01720v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Face Anti-Spoofing (FAS) is essential for ensuring the security and reliability of facial recognition systems. Most existing FAS methods are formulated as binary classification tasks, providing confidence scores without interpretation. They exhibit limited generalization in out-of-domain scenarios, such as new environments or unseen spoofing types. In this work, we introduce a multimodal large language model (MLLM) framework for FAS, termed Interpretable Face Anti-Spoofing (I-FAS), which transforms the FAS task into an interpretable visual question answering (VQA) paradigm. Specifically, we propose a Spoof-aware Captioning and Filtering (SCF) strategy to generate high-quality captions for FAS images, enriching the model's supervision with natural language interpretations. To mitigate the impact of noisy captions during training, we develop a Lopsided Language Model (L-LM) loss function that separates loss calculations for judgment and interpretation, prioritizing the optimization of the former. Furthermore, to enhance the model's perception of global visual features, we design a Globally Aware Connector (GAC) to align multi-level visual representations with the language model. Extensive experiments on standard and newly devised One to Eleven cross-domain benchmarks, comprising 12 public datasets, demonstrate that our method significantly outperforms state-of-the-art methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01720v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Guosheng Zhang, Keyao Wang, Haixiao Yue, Ajian Liu, Gang Zhang, Kun Yao, Errui Ding, Jingdong Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tarsier2: Advancing Large Vision-Language Models from Detailed Video Description to Comprehensive Video Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.07888</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.07888v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We introduce Tarsier2, a state-of-the-art large vision-language model (LVLM) designed for generating detailed and accurate video descriptions, while also exhibiting superior general video understanding capabilities. Tarsier2 achieves significant advancements through three key upgrades: (1) Scaling pre-training data from 11M to 40M video-text pairs, enriching both volume and diversity; (2) Performing fine-grained temporal alignment during supervised fine-tuning; (3) Using model-based sampling to automatically construct preference data and applying DPO training for optimization. Extensive experiments show that Tarsier2-7B consistently outperforms leading proprietary models, including GPT-4o and Gemini 1.5 Pro, in detailed video description tasks. On the DREAM-1K benchmark, Tarsier2-7B improves F1 by 2.8% over GPT-4o and 5.8% over Gemini-1.5-Pro. In human side-by-side evaluations, Tarsier2-7B shows a +8.6% performance advantage over GPT-4o and +24.9% over Gemini-1.5-Pro. Tarsier2-7B also sets new state-of-the-art results across 15 public benchmarks, spanning tasks such as video question-answering, video grounding, hallucination test, and embodied question-answering, demonstrating its versatility as a robust generalist vision-language model.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.07888v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Liping Yuan, Jiawei Wang, Haomiao Sun, Yuchen Zhang, Yuan Lin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PhyDeformer: High-Quality Non-Rigid Garment Registration with Physics-Awareness</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.10455</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.10455v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We present PhyDeformer, a new deformation method for high-quality garment mesh registration. It operates in two phases: In the first phase, a garment grading is performed to achieve a coarse 3D alignment between the mesh template and the target mesh, accounting for proportional scaling and fit (e.g. length, size). Then, the graded mesh is refined to align with the fine-grained details of the 3D target through an optimization coupled with the Jacobian-based deformation framework. Both quantitative and qualitative evaluations on synthetic and real garments highlight the effectiveness of our method.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.10455v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Boyang Yu, Frederic Cordier, Hyewon Seo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teacher Encoder-Student Decoder Denoising Guided Segmentation Network for Anomaly Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.12104</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.12104v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Visual anomaly detection is a highly challenging task, often categorized as a one-class classification and segmentation problem. Recent studies have demonstrated that the student-teacher (S-T) framework effectively addresses this challenge. However, most S-T frameworks rely solely on pre-trained teacher networks to guide student networks in learning multi-scale similar features, overlooking the potential of the student networks to enhance learning through multi-scale feature fusion. In this study, we propose a novel model named PFADSeg, which integrates a pre-trained teacher network, a denoising student network with multi-scale feature fusion, and a guided anomaly segmentation network into a unified framework. By adopting a unique teacher-encoder and student-decoder denoising mode, the model improves the student network's ability to learn from teacher network features. Furthermore, an adaptive feature fusion mechanism is introduced to train a self-supervised segmentation network that synthesizes anomaly masks autonomously, significantly increasing detection performance. Evaluated on the MVTec AD dataset, PFADSeg achieves state-of-the-art results with an image-level AUC of 98.9%, a pixel-level mean precision of 76.4%, and an instance-level mean precision of 78.7%.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.12104v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shixuan Song, Hao Chen, Shu Hu, Xin Wang, Jinrong Hu, Xi Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-aspect Knowledge Distillation with Large Language Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.13341</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.13341v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advancements in deep learning have significantly improved performance on computer vision tasks. Previous image classification methods primarily modify model architectures or add features, and they optimize models using cross-entropy loss on class logits. Since they focus on classifying images with considering class labels, these methods may struggle to learn various \emph{aspects} of classes (e.g., natural positions and shape changes). Rethinking the previous approach from a novel view, we propose a multi-aspect knowledge distillation method using Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs). Our approach involves: 1) querying Large Language Model with multi-aspect questions relevant to the knowledge we want to transfer to the model, 2) extracting corresponding logits from MLLM, and 3) expanding the model's output dimensions to distill these multi-aspect logits. We then apply cross-entropy loss to class logits and binary cross-entropy loss to multi-aspect logits. Through our method, the model can learn not only the knowledge about visual aspects but also the abstract and complex aspects that require a deeper understanding. We primarily apply our method to image classification, and to explore the potential for extending our model, we expand it to other tasks, such as object detection. In all experimental results, our method improves the performance of the baselines. Additionally, we analyze the effect of multi-aspect knowledge distillation. These results demonstrate that our method can transfer knowledge about various aspects to the model and the aspect knowledge can enhance model performance in computer vision tasks. This paper demonstrates the great potential of multi-aspect knowledge distillation, and we believe it offers a promising direction for future research in computer vision and beyond.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.13341v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Taegyeong Lee, Jinsik Bang, Soyeong Kwon, Taehwan Kim</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-Prompt-One-Story: Free-Lunch Consistent Text-to-Image Generation Using a Single Prompt</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.13554</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.13554v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Text-to-image generation models can create high-quality images from input prompts. However, they struggle to support the consistent generation of identity-preserving requirements for storytelling. Existing approaches to this problem typically require extensive training in large datasets or additional modifications to the original model architectures. This limits their applicability across different domains and diverse diffusion model configurations. In this paper, we first observe the inherent capability of language models, coined context consistency, to comprehend identity through context with a single prompt. Drawing inspiration from the inherent context consistency, we propose a novel training-free method for consistent text-to-image (T2I) generation, termed "One-Prompt-One-Story" (1Prompt1Story). Our approach 1Prompt1Story concatenates all prompts into a single input for T2I diffusion models, initially preserving character identities. We then refine the generation process using two novel techniques: Singular-Value Reweighting and Identity-Preserving Cross-Attention, ensuring better alignment with the input description for each frame. In our experiments, we compare our method against various existing consistent T2I generation approaches to demonstrate its effectiveness through quantitative metrics and qualitative assessments. Code is available at https://github.com/byliutao/1Prompt1Story.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.13554v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tao Liu, Kai Wang, Senmao Li, Joost van de Weijer, Fahad Shahbaz Khan, Shiqi Yang, Yaxing Wang, Jian Yang, Ming-Ming Cheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>POLAR-Sim: Augmenting NASA's POLAR Dataset for Data-Driven Lunar Perception and Rover Simulation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2309.12397</link>
      <description>arXiv:2309.12397v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: NASA's POLAR dataset contains approximately 2,600 pairs of high dynamic range stereo photos captured across 13 varied terrain scenarios, including areas with sparse or dense rock distributions, craters, and rocks of different sizes. The purpose of these photos is to spur development in robotics, AI-based perception, and autonomous navigation. Acknowledging a scarcity of lunar images from around the lunar poles, NASA Ames produced on Earth but in controlled conditions images that resemble rover operating conditions from these regions of the Moon. We report on the outcomes of an effort aimed at accomplishing two tasks. In Task 1, we provided bounding boxes and semantic segmentation information for all the images in NASA's POLAR dataset. This effort resulted in 23,000 labels and semantic segmentation annotations pertaining to rocks, shadows, and craters. In Task 2, we generated the digital twins of the 13 scenarios that have been used to produce all the photos in the POLAR dataset. Specifically, for each of these scenarios, we produced individual meshes, texture information, and material properties associated with the ground and the rocks in each scenario. This allows anyone with a camera model to synthesize images associated with any of the 13 scenarios of the POLAR dataset. Effectively, one can generate as many semantically labeled synthetic images as desired -- with different locations and exposure values in the scene, for different positions of the sun, with or without the presence of active illumination, etc. The benefit of this work is twofold. Using outcomes of Task 1, one can train and/or test perception algorithms that deal with Moon images. For Task 2, one can produce as much data as desired to train and test AI algorithms that are anticipated to work in lunar conditions. All the outcomes of this work are available in a public repository for unfettered use and distribution.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2309.12397v2</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bo-Hsun Chen, Peter Negrut, Thomas Liang, Nevindu Batagoda, Harry Zhang, Dan Negrut</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>REP: Resource-Efficient Prompting for Rehearsal-Free Continual Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.04772</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.04772v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Recent rehearsal-free methods, guided by prompts, generally excel in vision-related continual learning (CL) scenarios with continuously drifting data. To be deployable on real-world devices, these methods must contain high resource efficiency during training. In this paper, we introduce Resource-Efficient Prompting (REP), which targets improving the resource efficiency of prompt-based rehearsal-free methods. Our key focus is on avoiding catastrophic trade-offs with accuracy while trimming computational and memory costs during prompt learning. We achieve this by exploiting swift prompt selection that enhances input data using a carefully provisioned model, and by developing adaptive token merging (AToM) and layer dropping (ALD) algorithms for the prompt updating stage. AToM and ALD perform selective skipping across the data and model dimensions without compromising task-specific features while learning new tasks. We validate REP's superior resource efficiency over current state-of-the-art ViT- and CNN-based methods through extensive experiments on three image classification datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.04772v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sungho Jeon, Xinyue Ma, Kwang In Kim, Myeongjae Jeon</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heuristic-Free Multi-Teacher Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.12724</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.12724v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We introduce Teacher2Task, a novel framework for multi-teacher learning that eliminates the need for manual aggregation heuristics. Existing multi-teacher methods typically rely on such heuristics to combine predictions from multiple teachers, often resulting in sub-optimal aggregated labels and the propagation of aggregation errors. Teacher2Task addresses these limitations by introducing teacher-specific input tokens and reformulating the training process. Instead of relying on aggregated labels, the framework transforms the training data, consisting of ground truth labels and annotations from N teachers, into N+1 distinct tasks: N auxiliary tasks that predict the labeling styles of the N individual teachers, and one primary task that focuses on the ground truth labels. This approach, drawing upon principles from multiple learning paradigms, demonstrates strong empirical results across a range of architectures, modalities, and tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.12724v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Huy Thong Nguyen, En-Hung Chu, Lenord Melvix, Jazon Jiao, Chunglin Wen, Benjamin Louie</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning Based Segmentation of Blood Vessels from H&amp;E Stained Oesophageal Adenocarcinoma Whole-Slide Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.12323</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.12323v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Blood vessels (BVs) play a critical role in the Tumor Micro-Environment (TME), potentially influencing cancer progression and treatment response. However, manually quantifying BVs in Hematoxylin and Eosin (H&amp;E) stained images is challenging and labor-intensive due to their heterogeneous appearances. We propose a novel approach of constructing guiding maps to improve the performance of state-of-the-art segmentation models for BV segmentation, the guiding maps encourage the models to learn representative features of BVs. This is particularly beneficial for computational pathology, where labeled training data is often limited and large models are prone to overfitting. We have quantitative and qualitative results to demonstrate the efficacy of our approach in improving segmentation accuracy. In future, we plan to validate this method to segment BVs across various tissue types and investigate the role of cellular structures in relation to BVs in the TME.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.12323v2</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiaqi Lv, Stefan S Antonowicz, Shan E Ahmed Raza</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
