<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CV updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CV</link>
    <description>cs.CV updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CV" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 04:00:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Sunday</day>
      <day>Saturday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring OCR-augmented Generation for Bilingual VQA</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02543</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02543v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We investigate OCR-augmented generation with Vision Language Models (VLMs), exploring tasks in Korean and English toward multilingualism. To support research in this domain, we train and release KLOCR, a strong bilingual OCR baseline trained on 100M instances to augment VLMs with OCR ability. To complement existing VQA benchmarks, we curate KOCRBench for Korean VQA, and analyze different prompting methods. Extensive experiments show that OCR-extracted text significantly boosts performance across open source and commercial models. Our work offers new insights into OCR-augmented generation for bilingual VQA. Model, code, and data are available at https://github.com/JHLee0513/KLOCR.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02543v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>JoonHo Lee, Sunho Park</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle-RLAIF: An Improved Fine-Tuning Framework for Multi-modal Video Models through Reinforcement Learning from Ranking Feedback</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02561</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02561v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent advances in large video-language models (VLMs) rely on extensive fine-tuning techniques that strengthen alignment between textual and visual comprehension. Leading pipelines typically pair supervised fine-tuning (SFT) with reinforcement learning from preference data to enhance video comprehension. However, as VLMs scale in parameter size, so does the cost of gathering enough human feedback. To make fine-tuning more cost-effective, recent frameworks explore reinforcement learning with AI feedback (RLAIF), which replace human preference with AI as a judge. Current RLAIF frameworks rely on a specialized reward model trained with video narratives to create calibrated scalar rewards-- an expensive and restrictive pipeline. We propose Oracle-RLAIF, a novel framework that replaces the trained reward model with a more general Oracle ranker which acts as a drop-in model ranking candidate model responses rather than scoring them. Alongside Oracle-RLAIF, we introduce $GRPO_{rank}$, a novel rank-based loss function based on Group Relative Policy Optimization (GRPO) that directly optimizes ordinal feedback with rank-aware advantages. Empirically, we demonstrate that Oracle-RLAIF consistently outperforms leading VLMs using existing fine-tuning methods when evaluated across various video comprehension benchmarks. Oracle-RLAIF paves the path to creating flexible and data-efficient frameworks for aligning large multi-modal video models with reinforcement learning from rank rather than score.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02561v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Derek Shi, Ruben Glatt, Christine Klymko, Shubham Mohole, Hongjun Choi, Shashank Kushwaha, Sam Sakla, Felipe Leno da Silva</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PhysHMR: Learning Humanoid Control Policies from Vision for Physically Plausible Human Motion Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02566</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02566v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Reconstructing physically plausible human motion from monocular videos remains a challenging problem in computer vision and graphics. Existing methods primarily focus on kinematics-based pose estimation, often leading to unrealistic results due to the lack of physical constraints. To address such artifacts, prior methods have typically relied on physics-based post-processing following the initial kinematics-based motion estimation. However, this two-stage design introduces error accumulation, ultimately limiting the overall reconstruction quality. In this paper, we present PhysHMR, a unified framework that directly learns a visual-to-action policy for humanoid control in a physics-based simulator, enabling motion reconstruction that is both physically grounded and visually aligned with the input video. A key component of our approach is the pixel-as-ray strategy, which lifts 2D keypoints into 3D spatial rays and transforms them into global space. These rays are incorporated as policy inputs, providing robust global pose guidance without depending on noisy 3D root predictions. This soft global grounding, combined with local visual features from a pretrained encoder, allows the policy to reason over both detailed pose and global positioning. To overcome the sample inefficiency of reinforcement learning, we further introduce a distillation scheme that transfers motion knowledge from a mocap-trained expert to the vision-conditioned policy, which is then refined using physically motivated reinforcement learning rewards. Extensive experiments demonstrate that PhysHMR produces high-fidelity, physically plausible motion across diverse scenarios, outperforming prior approaches in both visual accuracy and physical realism.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02566v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qiao Feng, Yiming Huang, Yufu Wang, Jiatao Gu, Lingjie Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the power of partnership: How humans and machines can work together to improve face recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02570</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02570v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Human review of consequential decisions by face recognition algorithms creates a "collaborative" human-machine system. Individual differences between people and machines, however, affect whether collaboration improves or degrades accuracy in any given case. We establish the circumstances under which combining human and machine face identification decisions improves accuracy. Using data from expert and non-expert face identifiers, we examined the benefits of human-human and human-machine collaborations. The benefits of collaboration increased as the difference in baseline accuracy between collaborators decreased-following the Proximal Accuracy Rule (PAR). This rule predicted collaborative (fusion) benefit across a wide range of baseline abilities, from people with no training to those with extensive training. Using the PAR, we established a critical fusion zone, where humans are less accurate than the machine, but fusing the two improves system accuracy. This zone was surprisingly large. We implemented "intelligent human-machine fusion" by selecting people with the potential to increase the accuracy of a high-performing machine. Intelligent fusion was more accurate than the machine operating alone and more accurate than combining all human and machine judgments. The highest system-wide accuracy achievable with human-only partnerships was found by graph theory. This fully human system approximated the average performance achieved by intelligent human-machine collaboration. However, intelligent human-machine collaboration more effectively minimized the impact of low-performing humans on system-wide accuracy. The results demonstrate a meaningful role for both humans and machines in assuring accurate face identification. This study offers an evidence-based road map for the intelligent use of AI in face identification.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02570v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>P. Jonathon Phillips (Information Access Division, National Institute of Standards and Technology, Gaithersburg, MD), Geraldine Jeckeln (School of Behavioral and Brain Sciences, The University of Texas at Dallas, Richardson, TX), Carina A. Hahn (Information Access Division, National Institute of Standards and Technology, Gaithersburg, MD), Amy N. Yates (Information Access Division, National Institute of Standards and Technology, Gaithersburg, MD), Peter C. Fontana (Information Access Division, National Institute of Standards and Technology, Gaithersburg, MD), Alice J. O'Toole (School of Behavioral and Brain Sciences, The University of Texas at Dallas, Richardson, TX)</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Confident are Video Models? Empowering Video Models to Express their Uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02571</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02571v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Generative video models demonstrate impressive text-to-video capabilities, spurring widespread adoption in many real-world applications. However, like large language models (LLMs), video generation models tend to hallucinate, producing plausible videos even when they are factually wrong. Although uncertainty quantification (UQ) of LLMs has been extensively studied in prior work, no UQ method for video models exists, raising critical safety concerns. To our knowledge, this paper represents the first work towards quantifying the uncertainty of video models. We present a framework for uncertainty quantification of generative video models, consisting of: (i) a metric for evaluating the calibration of video models based on robust rank correlation estimation with no stringent modeling assumptions; (ii) a black-box UQ method for video models (termed S-QUBED), which leverages latent modeling to rigorously decompose predictive uncertainty into its aleatoric and epistemic components; and (iii) a UQ dataset to facilitate benchmarking calibration in video models. By conditioning the generation task in the latent space, we disentangle uncertainty arising due to vague task specifications from that arising from lack of knowledge. Through extensive experiments on benchmark video datasets, we demonstrate that S-QUBED computes calibrated total uncertainty estimates that are negatively correlated with the task accuracy and effectively computes the aleatoric and epistemic constituents.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02571v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhiting Mei, Ola Shorinwa, Anirudha Majumdar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PEO: Training-Free Aesthetic Quality Enhancement in Pre-Trained Text-to-Image Diffusion Models with Prompt Embedding Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02599</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02599v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper introduces a novel approach to aesthetic quality improvement in pre-trained text-to-image diffusion models when given a simple prompt. Our method, dubbed Prompt Embedding Optimization (PEO), leverages a pre-trained text-to-image diffusion model as a backbone and optimizes the text embedding of a given simple and uncurated prompt to enhance the visual quality of the generated image. We achieve this by a tripartite objective function that improves the aesthetic fidelity of the generated image, ensures adherence to the optimized text embedding, and minimal divergence from the initial prompt. The latter is accomplished through a prompt preservation term. Additionally, PEO is training-free and backbone-independent. Quantitative and qualitative evaluations confirm the effectiveness of the proposed method, exceeding or equating the performance of state-of-the-art text-to-image and prompt adaptation methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02599v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hovhannes Margaryan, Bo Wan, Tinne Tuytelaars</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ego-Exo 3D Hand Tracking in the Wild with a Mobile Multi-Camera Rig</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02601</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02601v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Accurate 3D tracking of hands and their interactions with the world in unconstrained settings remains a significant challenge for egocentric computer vision. With few exceptions, existing datasets are predominantly captured in controlled lab setups, limiting environmental diversity and model generalization. To address this, we introduce a novel marker-less multi-camera system designed to capture precise 3D hands and objects, which allows for nearly unconstrained mobility in genuinely in-the-wild conditions. We combine a lightweight, back-mounted capture rig with eight exocentric cameras, and a user-worn Meta Quest 3 headset, which contributes two egocentric views. We design an ego-exo tracking pipeline to generate accurate 3D hand pose ground truth from this system, and rigorously evaluate its quality. By collecting an annotated dataset featuring synchronized multi-view images and precise 3D hand poses, we demonstrate the capability of our approach to significantly reduce the trade-off between environmental realism and 3D annotation accuracy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02601v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Patrick Rim, Kun He, Kevin Harris, Braden Copple, Shangchen Han, Sizhe An, Ivan Shugurov, Tomas Hodan, He Wen, Xu Xie</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Input-Aware Sparse Attention for Real-Time Co-Speech Video Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02617</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02617v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Diffusion models can synthesize realistic co-speech video from audio for various applications, such as video creation and virtual agents. However, existing diffusion-based methods are slow due to numerous denoising steps and costly attention mechanisms, preventing real-time deployment. In this work, we distill a many-step diffusion video model into a few-step student model. Unfortunately, directly applying recent diffusion distillation methods degrades video quality and falls short of real-time performance. To address these issues, our new video distillation method leverages input human pose conditioning for both attention and loss functions. We first propose using accurate correspondence between input human pose keypoints to guide attention to relevant regions, such as the speaker's face, hands, and upper body. This input-aware sparse attention reduces redundant computations and strengthens temporal correspondences of body parts, improving inference efficiency and motion coherence. To further enhance visual quality, we introduce an input-aware distillation loss that improves lip synchronization and hand motion realism. By integrating our input-aware sparse attention and distillation loss, our method achieves real-time performance with improved visual quality compared to recent audio-driven and input-driven methods. We also conduct extensive experiments showing the effectiveness of our algorithmic design choices.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02617v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Beijia Lu, Ziyi Chen, Jing Xiao, Jun-Yan Zhu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Generative Continual Learning using Functional LoRA: FunLoRA</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02631</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02631v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Continual adaptation of deep generative models holds tremendous potential and critical importance, given their rapid and expanding usage in text and vision based applications. Incremental training, however, remains highly challenging due to catastrophic forgetting phenomenon, which makes it difficult for neural networks to effectively incorporate new knowledge. A common strategy consists in retraining the generative model on its own synthetic data in order to mitigate forgetting. Yet, such an approach faces two major limitations: (i) the continually increasing training time eventually becomes intractable, and (ii) reliance on synthetic data inevitably leads to long-term performance degradation, since synthetic samples lack the richness of real training data. In this paper, we attenuate these issues by designing a novel and more expressive conditioning mechanism for generative models based on low rank adaptation (LoRA), that exclusively employs rank 1 matrices, whose reparametrized matrix rank is functionally increased using carefully selected functions -- and dubbed functional LoRA: FunLoRA. Using this dynamic conditioning, the generative model is guaranteed to avoid catastrophic forgetting and needs only to be trained on data from the current task. Extensive experiments using flow-matching based models trained from scratch, showcase that our proposed parameter-efficient fine-tuning (PEFT) method surpasses prior state-of-the-art results based on diffusion models, reaching higher classification accuracy scores, while only requiring a fraction of the memory cost and sampling time.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02631v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Victor Enescu, Hichem Sahbi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sequence-Preserving Dual-FoV Defense for Traffic Sign and Light Recognition in Autonomous Vehicles</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02642</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02642v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Traffic light and sign recognition are key for Autonomous Vehicles (AVs) because perception mistakes directly influence navigation and safety. In addition to digital adversarial attacks, models are vulnerable to existing perturbations (glare, rain, dirt, or graffiti), which could lead to dangerous misclassifications. The current work lacks consideration of temporal continuity, multistatic field-of-view (FoV) sensing, and robustness to both digital and natural degradation. This study proposes a dual FoV, sequence-preserving robustness framework for traffic lights and signs in the USA based on a multi-source dataset built on aiMotive, Udacity, Waymo, and self-recorded videos from the region of Texas. Mid and long-term sequences of RGB images are temporally aligned for four operational design domains (ODDs): highway, night, rainy, and urban. Over a series of experiments on a real-life application of anomaly detection, this study outlines a unified three-layer defense stack framework that incorporates feature squeezing, defensive distillation, and entropy-based anomaly detection, as well as sequence-wise temporal voting for further enhancement. The evaluation measures included accuracy, attack success rate (ASR), risk-weighted misclassification severity, and confidence stability. Physical transferability was confirmed using probes for recapture. The results showed that the Unified Defense Stack achieved 79.8mAP and reduced the ASR to 18.2%, which is superior to YOLOv8, YOLOv9, and BEVFormer, while reducing the high-risk misclassification to 32%.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02642v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Abhishek Joshi, Jahnavi Krishna Koda, Abhishek Phadke</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smart-GRPO: Smartly Sampling Noise for Efficient RL of Flow-Matching Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02654</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02654v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent advancements in flow-matching have enabled high-quality text-to-image generation. However, the deterministic nature of flow-matching models makes them poorly suited for reinforcement learning, a key tool for improving image quality and human alignment. Prior work has introduced stochasticity by perturbing latents with random noise, but such perturbations are inefficient and unstable. We propose Smart-GRPO, the first method to optimize noise perturbations for reinforcement learning in flow-matching models. Smart-GRPO employs an iterative search strategy that decodes candidate perturbations, evaluates them with a reward function, and refines the noise distribution toward higher-reward regions. Experiments demonstrate that Smart-GRPO improves both reward optimization and visual quality compared to baseline methods. Our results suggest a practical path toward reinforcement learning in flow-matching frameworks, bridging the gap between efficient training and human-aligned generation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02654v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Benjamin Yu, Jackie Liu, Justin Cui</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FSFSplatter: Build Surface and Novel Views with Sparse-Views within 3min</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02691</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02691v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Gaussian Splatting has become a leading reconstruction technique, known for its high-quality novel view synthesis and detailed reconstruction. However, most existing methods require dense, calibrated views. Reconstructing from free sparse images often leads to poor surface due to limited overlap and overfitting. We introduce FSFSplatter, a new approach for fast surface reconstruction from free sparse images. Our method integrates end-to-end dense Gaussian initialization, camera parameter estimation, and geometry-enhanced scene optimization. Specifically, FSFSplatter employs a large Transformer to encode multi-view images and generates a dense and geometrically consistent Gaussian scene initialization via a self-splitting Gaussian head. It eliminates local floaters through contribution-based pruning and mitigates overfitting to limited views by leveraging depth and multi-view feature supervision with differentiable camera parameters during rapid optimization. FSFSplatter outperforms current state-of-the-art methods on widely used DTU and Replica.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02691v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yibin Zhao, Yihan Pan, Jun Nan, Jianjun Yi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MoGIC: Boosting Motion Generation via Intention Understanding and Visual Context</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02722</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02722v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Existing text-driven motion generation methods often treat synthesis as a bidirectional mapping between language and motion, but remain limited in capturing the causal logic of action execution and the human intentions that drive behavior. The absence of visual grounding further restricts precision and personalization, as language alone cannot specify fine-grained spatiotemporal details. We propose MoGIC, a unified framework that integrates intention modeling and visual priors into multimodal motion synthesis. By jointly optimizing multimodal-conditioned motion generation and intention prediction, MoGIC uncovers latent human goals, leverages visual priors to enhance generation, and exhibits versatile multimodal generative capability. We further introduce a mixture-of-attention mechanism with adaptive scope to enable effective local alignment between conditional tokens and motion subsequences. To support this paradigm, we curate Mo440H, a 440-hour benchmark from 21 high-quality motion datasets. Experiments show that after finetuning, MoGIC reduces FID by 38.6\% on HumanML3D and 34.6\% on Mo440H, surpasses LLM-based methods in motion captioning with a lightweight text head, and further enables intention prediction and vision-conditioned generation, advancing controllable motion synthesis and intention understanding. The code is available at https://github.com/JunyuShi02/MoGIC</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02722v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junyu Shi, Yong Sun, Zhiyuan Zhang, Lijiang Liu, Zhengjie Zhang, Yuxin He, Qiang Nie</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Tokens to Nodes: Semantic-Guided Motion Control for Dynamic 3D Gaussian Splatting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02732</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02732v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Dynamic 3D reconstruction from monocular videos remains difficult due to the ambiguity inferring 3D motion from limited views and computational demands of modeling temporally varying scenes. While recent sparse control methods alleviate computation by reducing millions of Gaussians to thousands of control points, they suffer from a critical limitation: they allocate points purely by geometry, leading to static redundancy and dynamic insufficiency. We propose a motion-adaptive framework that aligns control density with motion complexity. Leveraging semantic and motion priors from vision foundation models, we establish patch-token-node correspondences and apply motion-adaptive compression to concentrate control points in dynamic regions while suppressing redundancy in static backgrounds. Our approach achieves flexible representational density adaptation through iterative voxelization and motion tendency scoring, directly addressing the fundamental mismatch between control point allocation and motion complexity. To capture temporal evolution, we introduce spline-based trajectory parameterization initialized by 2D tracklets, replacing MLP-based deformation fields to achieve smoother motion representation and more stable optimization. Extensive experiments demonstrate significant improvements in reconstruction quality and efficiency over existing state-of-the-art methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02732v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jianing Chen, Zehao Li, Yujun Cai, Hao Jiang, Shuqin Gao, Honglong Zhao, Tianlu Mao, Yucheng Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Net2Net: When Un-trained Meets Pre-trained Networks for Robust Real-World Denoising</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02733</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02733v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Traditional denoising methods for noise removal have largely relied on handcrafted priors, often perform well in controlled environments but struggle to address the complexity and variability of real noise. In contrast, deep learning-based approaches have gained prominence for learning noise characteristics from large datasets, but these methods frequently require extensive labeled data and may not generalize effectively across diverse noise types and imaging conditions. In this paper, we present an innovative method, termed as Net2Net, that combines the strengths of untrained and pre-trained networks to tackle the challenges of real-world noise removal. The innovation of Net2Net lies in its combination of unsupervised DIP and supervised pre-trained model DRUNet by regularization by denoising (RED). The untrained network adapts to the unique noise characteristics of each input image without requiring labeled data, while the pre-trained network leverages learned representations from large-scale datasets to deliver robust denoising performance. This hybrid framework enhances generalization across varying noise patterns and improves performance, particularly in scenarios with limited training data. Extensive experiments on benchmark datasets demonstrate the superiority of our method for real-world noise removal.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02733v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weimin Yuan, Cai Meng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retrv-R1: A Reasoning-Driven MLLM Framework for Universal and Efficient Multimodal Retrieval</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02745</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02745v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The success of DeepSeek-R1 demonstrates the immense potential of using reinforcement learning (RL) to enhance LLMs' reasoning capabilities. This paper introduces Retrv-R1, the first R1-style MLLM specifically designed for multimodal universal retrieval, achieving higher performance by employing step-by-step reasoning to produce more accurate retrieval results. We find that directly applying the methods of DeepSeek-R1 to retrieval tasks is not feasible, mainly due to (1) the high computational cost caused by the large token consumption required for multiple candidates with reasoning processes, and (2) the instability and suboptimal results when directly applying RL to train for retrieval tasks. To address these issues, Retrv-R1 introduces an information compression module with a details inspection mechanism, which enhances computational efficiency by reducing the number of tokens while ensuring that critical information for challenging candidates is preserved. Furthermore, a new training paradigm is proposed, including an activation stage using a retrieval-tailored synthetic CoT dataset for more effective optimization, followed by RL with a novel curriculum reward to improve both performance and efficiency. Incorporating these novel designs, Retrv-R1 achieves SOTA performance, high efficiency, and strong generalization ability, as demonstrated by experiments across multiple benchmarks and tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02745v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lanyun Zhu, Deyi Ji, Tianrun Chen, Haiyang Wu, Shiqi Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Test-time Adaptation for Object Recognition and Detection with Vision-language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02750</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02750v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Vision-language models (VLMs) such as CLIP and Grounding DINO have achieved remarkable success in object recognition and detection. However, their performance often degrades under real-world distribution shifts. Test-time adaptation (TTA) aims to mitigate this issue by adapting models during inference. Existing methods either rely on computationally expensive backpropagation, which hinders real-time deployment, or focus solely on likelihood adaptation, which overlooks the critical role of the prior. Our prior work, Bayesian Class Adaptation (BCA), addressed these shortcomings for object recognition by introducing a training-free framework that incorporates adaptive priors. Building upon this foundation, we now present Bayesian Class Adaptation plus (BCA+), a unified, training-free framework for TTA for both object recognition and detection. BCA+ introduces a dynamic cache that adaptively stores and updates class embeddings, spatial scales (for detection), and, crucially, adaptive class priors derived from historical predictions. We formulate adaptation as a Bayesian inference problem, where final predictions are generated by fusing the initial VLM output with a cache-based prediction. This cache-based prediction combines a dynamically updated likelihood (measuring feature and scale similarity) and a prior (reflecting the evolving class distribution). This dual-adaptation mechanism, coupled with uncertainty-guided fusion, enables BCA+ to correct both the model's semantic understanding and its contextual confidence. As a training-free method requiring no backpropagation, BCA+ is highly efficient. Extensive experiments demonstrate that BCA+ achieves state-of-the-art performance on both recognition and detection benchmarks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02750v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lihua Zhou, Mao Ye, Shuaifeng Li, Nianxin Li, Jinlin Wu, Xiatian Zhu, Lei Deng, Hongbin Liu, Jiebo Luo, Zhen Lei</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Generalized Category Discovery for Brain Tumor Classification in Digital Pathology</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02760</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02760v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Accurate brain tumor classification is critical for intra-operative decision making in neuro-oncological surgery. However, existing approaches are restricted to a fixed set of predefined classes and are therefore unable to capture patterns of tumor types not available during training. Unsupervised learning can extract general-purpose features, but it lacks the ability to incorporate prior knowledge from labelled data, and semi-supervised methods often assume that all potential classes are represented in the labelled data. Generalized Category Discovery (GCD) aims to bridge this gap by categorizing both known and unknown classes within unlabelled data. To reflect the hierarchical structure of brain tumor taxonomies, in this work, we introduce Hierarchical Generalized Category Discovery for Brain Tumor Classification (HGCD-BT), a novel approach that integrates hierarchical clustering with contrastive learning. Our method extends contrastive learning based GCD by incorporating a novel semi-supervised hierarchical clustering loss. We evaluate HGCD-BT on OpenSRH, a dataset of stimulated Raman histology brain tumor images, achieving a +28% improvement in accuracy over state-of-the-art GCD methods for patch-level classification, particularly in identifying previously unseen tumor categories. Furthermore, we demonstrate the generalizability of HGCD-BT on slide-level classification of hematoxylin and eosin stained whole-slide images from the Digital Brain Tumor Atlas, confirming its utility across imaging modalities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02760v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Matthias Perkonigg, Patrick Rockenschaub, Georg G\"obel, Adelheid W\"ohrer</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AdaRD-key: Adaptive Relevance-Diversity Keyframe Sampling for Long-form Video understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02778</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02778v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Understanding long-form videos remains a significant challenge for vision--language models (VLMs) due to their extensive temporal length and high information density. Most current multimodal large language models (MLLMs) rely on uniform sampling, which often overlooks critical moments, leading to incorrect responses to queries. In parallel, many keyframe selection approaches impose rigid temporal spacing: once a frame is chosen, an exclusion window suppresses adjacent timestamps to reduce redundancy. While effective at limiting overlap, this strategy frequently misses short, fine-grained cues near important events. Other methods instead emphasize visual diversity but neglect query relevance. We propose AdaRD-Key, a training-free keyframe sampling module for query-driven long-form video understanding. AdaRD-Key maximizes a unified Relevance--Diversity Max-Volume (RD-MV) objective, combining a query-conditioned relevance score with a log-determinant diversity component to yield informative yet non-redundant frames. To handle broad queries with weak alignment to the video, AdaRD-Key employs a lightweight relevance-aware gating mechanism; when the relevance distribution indicates weak alignment, the method seamlessly shifts into a diversity-only mode, enhancing coverage without additional supervision. Our pipeline is training-free, computationally efficient (running in real time on a single GPU), and compatible with existing VLMs in a plug-and-play manner. Extensive experiments on LongVideoBench and Video-MME demonstrate state-of-the-art performance, particularly on long-form videos. Code available at https://github.com/Xian867/AdaRD-Key.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02778v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xian Zhang, Zexi Wu, Zinuo Li, Hongming Xu, Luqi Gong, Farid Boussaid, Naoufel Werghi, Mohammed Bennamoun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reasoning Riddles: How Explainability Reveals Cognitive Limits in Vision-Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02780</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02780v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Vision-Language Models (VLMs) excel at many multimodal tasks, yet their cognitive processes remain opaque on complex lateral thinking challenges like rebus puzzles. While recent work has demonstrated these models struggle significantly with rebus puzzle solving, the underlying reasoning processes and failure patterns remain largely unexplored. We address this gap through a comprehensive explainability analysis that moves beyond performance metrics to understand how VLMs approach these complex lateral thinking challenges. Our study contributes a systematically annotated dataset of 221 rebus puzzles across six cognitive categories, paired with an evaluation framework that separates reasoning quality from answer correctness. We investigate three prompting strategies designed to elicit different types of explanatory processes and reveal critical insights into VLM cognitive processes. Our findings demonstrate that reasoning quality varies dramatically across puzzle categories, with models showing systematic strengths in visual composition while exhibiting fundamental limitations in absence interpretation and cultural symbolism. We also discover that prompting strategy substantially influences both cognitive approach and problem-solving effectiveness, establishing explainability as an integral component of model performance rather than a post-hoc consideration.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02780v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>COLM 2025: First Workshop on the Application of LLM Explainability to Reasoning and Planning</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Prahitha Movva</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OTR: Synthesizing Overlay Text Dataset for Text Removal</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02787</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02787v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Text removal is a crucial task in computer vision with applications such as privacy preservation, image editing, and media reuse. While existing research has primarily focused on scene text removal in natural images, limitations in current datasets hinder out-of-domain generalization or accurate evaluation. In particular, widely used benchmarks such as SCUT-EnsText suffer from ground truth artifacts due to manual editing, overly simplistic text backgrounds, and evaluation metrics that do not capture the quality of generated results. To address these issues, we introduce an approach to synthesizing a text removal benchmark applicable to domains other than scene texts. Our dataset features text rendered on complex backgrounds using object-aware placement and vision-language model-generated content, ensuring clean ground truth and challenging text removal scenarios. The dataset is available at https://huggingface.co/datasets/cyberagent/OTR .</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02787v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3746027.3758297</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Jan Zdenek, Wataru Shimoda, Kota Yamaguchi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Align Your Query: Representation Alignment for Multimodality Medical Object Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02789</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02789v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Medical object detection suffers when a single detector is trained on mixed medical modalities (e.g., CXR, CT, MRI) due to heterogeneous statistics and disjoint representation spaces. To address this challenge, we turn to representation alignment, an approach that has proven effective for bringing features from different sources into a shared space. Specifically, we target the representations of DETR-style object queries and propose a simple, detector-agnostic framework to align them with modality context. First, we define modality tokens: compact, text-derived embeddings encoding imaging modality that are lightweight and require no extra annotations. We integrate the modality tokens into the detection process via Multimodality Context Attention (MoCA), mixing object-query representations via self-attention to propagate modality context within the query set. This preserves DETR-style architectures and adds negligible latency while injecting modality cues into object queries. We further introduce QueryREPA, a short pretraining stage that aligns query representations to their modality tokens using a task-specific contrastive objective with modality-balanced batches. Together, MoCA and QueryREPA produce modality-aware, class-faithful queries that transfer effectively to downstream training. Across diverse modalities trained altogether, the proposed approach consistently improves AP with minimal overhead and no architectural modifications, offering a practical path toward robust multimodality medical object detection. Project page: https://araseo.github.io/alignyourquery/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02789v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ara Seo, Bryan Sangwoo Kim, Hyungjin Chung, Jong Chul Ye</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MaskCD: Mitigating LVLM Hallucinations by Image Head Masked Contrastive Decoding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02790</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02790v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large vision-language models (LVLMs) have shown remarkable performance in visual-language understanding for downstream multimodal tasks. While their capabilities are improving, problems emerge simultaneously. Among those problems, the hallucinations have attracted much attention, which stands for the phenomenon where LVLMs generate contradictory content to their input visual and text contents. Many approaches have been proposed to deal with this issue, such as contrastive decoding and attention manipulation. However, contrastive decoding methods struggle in constructing appropriate contrastive samples, and attention manipulation methods are highly sensitive, lacking stability. In this work, we propose image head Masked Contrastive Decoding (MaskCD). Our approach utilizes the "image heads" in LVLMs, masking them to construct contrastive samples for contrastive decoding. We evaluated MaskCD on LLaVA-1.5-7b and Qwen-VL-7b, using various benchmarks such as CHAIR, POPE, AMBER and MME. The results demonstrate that MaskCD effectively alleviates the phenomenon of hallucinations and retains the general capabilities of LVLMs. Corresponding resources could be found at: https://github.com/Deng-Jingyuan/MaskCD .</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02790v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jingyuan Deng, Yujiu Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VERNIER: an open-source software pushing marker pose estimation down to the micrometer and nanometer scales</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02791</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02791v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Pose estimation is still a challenge at the small scales. Few solutions exist to capture the 6 degrees of freedom of an object with nanometric and microradians resolutions over relatively large ranges. Over the years, we have proposed several fiducial marker and pattern designs to achieve reliable performance for various microscopy applications. Centimeter ranges are possible using pattern encoding methods, while nanometer resolutions can be achieved using phase processing of the periodic frames. This paper presents VERNIER, an open source phase processing software designed to provide fast and reliable pose measurement based on pseudo-periodic patterns. Thanks to a phase-based local thresholding algorithm, the software has proven to be particularly robust to noise, defocus and occlusion. The successive steps of the phase processing are presented, as well as the different types of patterns that address different application needs. The implementation procedure is illustrated with synthetic and experimental images. Finally, guidelines are given for selecting the appropriate pattern design and microscope magnification lenses as a function of the desired performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02791v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Patrick Sandoz, Antoine N. Andr\'e, Guillaume J. Laurent</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Med-K2N: Flexible K-to-N Modality Translation for Medical Image Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02815</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02815v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Cross-modal medical image synthesis research focuses on reconstructing missing imaging modalities from available ones to support clinical diagnosis. Driven by clinical necessities for flexible modality reconstruction, we explore K to N medical generation, where three critical challenges emerge: How can we model the heterogeneous contributions of different modalities to various target tasks? How can we ensure fusion quality control to prevent degradation from noisy information? How can we maintain modality identity consistency in multi-output generation? Driven by these clinical necessities, and drawing inspiration from SAM2's sequential frame paradigm and clinicians' progressive workflow of incrementally adding and selectively integrating multi-modal information, we treat multi-modal medical data as sequential frames with quality-driven selection mechanisms. Our key idea is to "learn" adaptive weights for each modality-task pair and "memorize" beneficial fusion patterns through progressive enhancement. To achieve this, we design three collaborative modules: PreWeightNet for global contribution assessment, ThresholdNet for adaptive filtering, and EffiWeightNet for effective weight computation. Meanwhile, to maintain modality identity consistency, we propose the Causal Modality Identity Module (CMIM) that establishes causal constraints between generated images and target modality descriptions using vision-language modeling. Extensive experimental results demonstrate that our proposed Med-K2N outperforms state-of-the-art methods by significant margins on multiple benchmarks. Source code is available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02815v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Feng Yuan, Yifan Gao, Yuehua Ye, Haoyue Li, Xin Gao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ELMF4EggQ: Ensemble Learning with Multimodal Feature Fusion for Non-Destructive Egg Quality Assessment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02876</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02876v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Accurate, non-destructive assessment of egg quality is critical for ensuring food safety, maintaining product standards, and operational efficiency in commercial poultry production. This paper introduces ELMF4EggQ, an ensemble learning framework that employs multimodal feature fusion to classify egg grade and freshness using only external attributes - image, shape, and weight. A novel, publicly available dataset of 186 brown-shelled eggs was constructed, with egg grade and freshness levels determined through laboratory-based expert assessments involving internal quality measurements, such as yolk index and Haugh unit. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first study to apply machine learning methods for internal egg quality assessment using only external, non-invasive features, and the first to release a corresponding labeled dataset. The proposed framework integrates deep features extracted from external egg images with structural characteristics such as egg shape and weight, enabling a comprehensive representation of each egg. Image feature extraction is performed using top-performing pre-trained CNN models (ResNet152, DenseNet169, and ResNet152V2), followed by PCA-based dimensionality reduction, SMOTE augmentation, and classification using multiple machine learning algorithms. An ensemble voting mechanism combines predictions from the best-performing classifiers to enhance overall accuracy. Experimental results demonstrate that the multimodal approach significantly outperforms image-only and tabular (shape and weight) only baselines, with the multimodal ensemble approach achieving 86.57% accuracy in grade classification and 70.83% in freshness prediction. All code and data are publicly available at https://github.com/Kenshin-Keeps/Egg_Quality_Prediction_ELMF4EggQ, promoting transparency, reproducibility, and further research in this domain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02876v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Md Zahim Hassan, Md. Osama, Muhammad Ashad Kabir, Md. Saiful Islam, Zannatul Naim</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Patch to Caption Them All: A Unified Zero-Shot Captioning Framework</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02898</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02898v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Zero-shot captioners are recently proposed models that utilize common-space vision-language representations to caption images without relying on paired image-text data. To caption an image, they proceed by textually decoding a text-aligned image feature, but they limit their scope to global representations and whole-image captions. We present \frameworkName{}, a unified framework for zero-shot captioning that shifts from an image-centric to a patch-centric paradigm, enabling the captioning of arbitrary regions without the need of region-level supervision. Instead of relying on global image representations, we treat individual patches as atomic captioning units and aggregate them to describe arbitrary regions, from single patches to non-contiguous areas and entire images. We analyze the key ingredients that enable current latent captioners to work in our novel proposed framework. Experiments demonstrate that backbones producing meaningful, dense visual features, such as DINO, are key to achieving state-of-the-art performance in multiple region-based captioning tasks. Compared to other baselines and state-of-the-art competitors, our models achieve better performance on zero-shot dense, region-set, and a newly introduced trace captioning task, highlighting the effectiveness of patch-wise semantic representations for scalable caption generation. Project page at https://paciosoft.com/Patch-ioner/ .</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02898v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lorenzo Bianchi, Giacomo Pacini, Fabio Carrara, Nicola Messina, Giuseppe Amato, Fabrizio Falchi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Training-Free Out-Of-Distribution Segmentation With Foundation Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02909</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02909v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Detecting unknown objects in semantic segmentation is crucial for safety-critical applications such as autonomous driving. Large vision foundation models, includ- ing DINOv2, InternImage, and CLIP, have advanced visual representation learn- ing by providing rich features that generalize well across diverse tasks. While their strength in closed-set semantic tasks is established, their capability to detect out- of-distribution (OoD) regions in semantic segmentation remains underexplored. In this work, we investigate whether foundation models fine-tuned on segmen- tation datasets can inherently distinguish in-distribution (ID) from OoD regions without any outlier supervision. We propose a simple, training-free approach that utilizes features from the InternImage backbone and applies K-Means clustering alongside confidence thresholding on raw decoder logits to identify OoD clusters. Our method achieves 50.02 Average Precision on the RoadAnomaly benchmark and 48.77 on the benchmark of ADE-OoD with InternImage-L, surpassing several supervised and unsupervised baselines. These results suggest a promising direc- tion for generic OoD segmentation methods that require minimal assumptions or additional data.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02909v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Laith Nayal, Hadi Salloum, Ahmad Taha, Yaroslav Kholodov, Alexander Gasnikov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don't Just Chase "Highlighted Tokens" in MLLMs: Revisiting Visual Holistic Context Retention</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02912</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02912v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Despite their powerful capabilities, Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) suffer from considerable computational overhead due to their reliance on massive visual tokens. Recent studies have explored token pruning to alleviate this problem, which typically uses text-vision cross-attention or [\texttt{CLS}] attention to assess and discard redundant visual tokens. In this work, we identify a critical limitation of such attention-first pruning approaches, i.e., they tend to preserve semantically similar tokens, resulting in pronounced performance drops under high pruning ratios. To this end, we propose {HoloV}, a simple yet effective, plug-and-play visual token pruning framework for efficient inference. Distinct from previous attention-first schemes, HoloV rethinks token retention from a holistic perspective. By adaptively distributing the pruning budget across different spatial crops, HoloV ensures that the retained tokens capture the global visual context rather than isolated salient features. This strategy minimizes representational collapse and maintains task-relevant information even under aggressive pruning. Experimental results demonstrate that our HoloV achieves superior performance across various tasks, MLLM architectures, and pruning ratios compared to SOTA methods. For instance, LLaVA1.5 equipped with HoloV preserves 95.8\% of the original performance after pruning 88.9\% of visual tokens, achieving superior efficiency-accuracy trade-offs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02912v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xin Zou, Di Lu, Yizhou Wang, Yibo Yan, Yuanhuiyi Lyu, Xu Zheng, Linfeng Zhang, Xuming Hu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zero-Shot Robustness of Vision Language Models Via Confidence-Aware Weighting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02913</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02913v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Vision-language models like CLIP demonstrate impressive zero-shot generalization but remain highly vulnerable to adversarial attacks. In this work, we propose Confidence-Aware Weighting (CAW) to enhance zero-shot robustness in vision-language models. CAW consists of two components: (1) a Confidence-Aware loss that prioritizes uncertain adversarial examples by scaling the KL divergence between clean and adversarial predictions, and (2) a feature alignment regularization that preserves semantic consistency by minimizing the distance between frozen and fine-tuned image encoder features on adversarial inputs. These components work jointly to improve both clean and robust accuracy without sacrificing generalization. Extensive experiments on TinyImageNet and 14 additional datasets show that CAW outperforms recent methods such as PMG-AFT and TGA-ZSR under strong attacks like AutoAttack, while using less memory.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02913v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nikoo Naghavian, Mostafa Tavassolipour</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multimodal Carotid Risk Stratification with Large Vision-Language Models: Benchmarking, Fine-Tuning, and Clinical Insights</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02922</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02922v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Reliable risk assessment for carotid atheromatous disease remains a major clinical challenge, as it requires integrating diverse clinical and imaging information in a manner that is transparent and interpretable to clinicians. This study investigates the potential of state-of-the-art and recent large vision-language models (LVLMs) for multimodal carotid plaque assessment by integrating ultrasound imaging (USI) with structured clinical, demographic, laboratory, and protein biomarker data. A framework that simulates realistic diagnostic scenarios through interview-style question sequences is proposed, comparing a range of open-source LVLMs, including both general-purpose and medically tuned models. Zero-shot experiments reveal that even if they are very powerful, not all LVLMs can accurately identify imaging modality and anatomy, while all of them perform poorly in accurate risk classification. To address this limitation, LLaVa-NeXT-Vicuna is adapted to the ultrasound domain using low-rank adaptation (LoRA), resulting in substantial improvements in stroke risk stratification. The integration of multimodal tabular data in the form of text further enhances specificity and balanced accuracy, yielding competitive performance compared to prior convolutional neural network (CNN) baselines trained on the same dataset. Our findings highlight both the promise and limitations of LVLMs in ultrasound-based cardiovascular risk prediction, underscoring the importance of multimodal integration, model calibration, and domain adaptation for clinical translation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02922v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Daphne Tsolissou, Theofanis Ganitidis, Konstantinos Mitsis, Stergios CHristodoulidis, Maria Vakalopoulou, Konstantina Nikita</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flip Distribution Alignment VAE for Multi-Phase MRI Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02970</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02970v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Separating shared and independent features is crucial for multi-phase contrast-enhanced (CE) MRI synthesis. However, existing methods use deep autoencoder generators with low parameter efficiency and lack interpretable training strategies. In this paper, we propose Flip Distribution Alignment Variational Autoencoder (FDA-VAE), a lightweight feature-decoupled VAE model for multi-phase CE MRI synthesis. Our method encodes input and target images into two latent distributions that are symmetric concerning a standard normal distribution, effectively separating shared and independent features. The Y-shaped bidirectional training strategy further enhances the interpretability of feature separation. Experimental results show that compared to existing deep autoencoder-based end-to-end synthesis methods, FDA-VAE significantly reduces model parameters and inference time while effectively improving synthesis quality. The source code is publicly available at https://github.com/QianMuXiao/FDA-VAE.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02970v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1007/978-3-032-05185-1_21</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Medical Image Computing and Computer Assisted Intervention (MICCAI), 2025, 208-218</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoyan Kui, Qianmu Xiao, Qqinsong Li, Zexin Ji, JIelin Zhang, Beiji Zou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TIT-Score: Evaluating Long-Prompt Based Text-to-Image Alignment via Text-to-Image-to-Text Consistency</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02987</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02987v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: With the rapid advancement of large multimodal models (LMMs), recent text-to-image (T2I) models can generate high-quality images and demonstrate great alignment to short prompts. However, they still struggle to effectively understand and follow long and detailed prompts, displaying inconsistent generation. To address this challenge, we introduce LPG-Bench, a comprehensive benchmark for evaluating long-prompt-based text-to-image generation. LPG-Bench features 200 meticulously crafted prompts with an average length of over 250 words, approaching the input capacity of several leading commercial models. Using these prompts, we generate 2,600 images from 13 state-of-the-art models and further perform comprehensive human-ranked annotations. Based on LPG-Bench, we observe that state-of-the-art T2I alignment evaluation metrics exhibit poor consistency with human preferences on long-prompt-based image generation. To address the gap, we introduce a novel zero-shot metric based on text-to-image-to-text consistency, termed TIT, for evaluating long-prompt-generated images. The core concept of TIT is to quantify T2I alignment by directly comparing the consistency between the raw prompt and the LMM-produced description on the generated image, which includes an efficient score-based instantiation TIT-Score and a large-language-model (LLM) based instantiation TIT-Score-LLM. Extensive experiments demonstrate that our framework achieves superior alignment with human judgment compared to CLIP-score, LMM-score, etc., with TIT-Score-LLM attaining a 7.31% absolute improvement in pairwise accuracy over the strongest baseline. LPG-Bench and TIT methods together offer a deeper perspective to benchmark and foster the development of T2I models. All resources will be made publicly available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02987v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Juntong Wang, Huiyu Duan, Jiarui Wang, Ziheng Jia, Guangtao Zhai, Xiongkuo Min</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Scalable and Consistent 3D Editing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02994</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02994v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: 3D editing - the task of locally modifying the geometry or appearance of a 3D asset - has wide applications in immersive content creation, digital entertainment, and AR/VR. However, unlike 2D editing, it remains challenging due to the need for cross-view consistency, structural fidelity, and fine-grained controllability. Existing approaches are often slow, prone to geometric distortions, or dependent on manual and accurate 3D masks that are error-prone and impractical. To address these challenges, we advance both the data and model fronts. On the data side, we introduce 3DEditVerse, the largest paired 3D editing benchmark to date, comprising 116,309 high-quality training pairs and 1,500 curated test pairs. Built through complementary pipelines of pose-driven geometric edits and foundation model-guided appearance edits, 3DEditVerse ensures edit locality, multi-view consistency, and semantic alignment. On the model side, we propose 3DEditFormer, a 3D-structure-preserving conditional transformer. By enhancing image-to-3D generation with dual-guidance attention and time-adaptive gating, 3DEditFormer disentangles editable regions from preserved structure, enabling precise and consistent edits without requiring auxiliary 3D masks. Extensive experiments demonstrate that our framework outperforms state-of-the-art baselines both quantitatively and qualitatively, establishing a new standard for practical and scalable 3D editing. Dataset and code will be released. Project: https://www.lv-lab.org/3DEditFormer/</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02994v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ruihao Xia, Yang Tang, Pan Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Not every day is a sunny day: Synthetic cloud injection for deep land cover segmentation robustness evaluation across data sources</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.03006</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.03006v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Supervised deep learning for land cover semantic segmentation (LCS) relies on labeled satellite data. However, most existing Sentinel-2 datasets are cloud-free, which limits their usefulness in tropical regions where clouds are common. To properly evaluate the extent of this problem, we developed a cloud injection algorithm that simulates realistic cloud cover, allowing us to test how Sentinel-1 radar data can fill in the gaps caused by cloud-obstructed optical imagery. We also tackle the issue of losing spatial and/or spectral details during encoder downsampling in deep networks. To mitigate this loss, we propose a lightweight method that injects Normalized Difference Indices (NDIs) into the final decoding layers, enabling the model to retain key spatial features with minimal additional computation. Injecting NDIs enhanced land cover segmentation performance on the DFC2020 dataset, yielding improvements of 1.99% for U-Net and 2.78% for DeepLabV3 on cloud-free imagery. Under cloud-covered conditions, incorporating Sentinel-1 data led to significant performance gains across all models compared to using optical data alone, highlighting the effectiveness of radar-optical fusion in challenging atmospheric scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.03006v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sara Mobsite, Renaud Hostache, Laure Berti Equille, Emmanuel Roux, Joris Guerin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PocketSR: The Super-Resolution Expert in Your Pocket Mobiles</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.03012</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.03012v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Real-world image super-resolution (RealSR) aims to enhance the visual quality of in-the-wild images, such as those captured by mobile phones. While existing methods leveraging large generative models demonstrate impressive results, the high computational cost and latency make them impractical for edge deployment. In this paper, we introduce PocketSR, an ultra-lightweight, single-step model that brings generative modeling capabilities to RealSR while maintaining high fidelity. To achieve this, we design LiteED, a highly efficient alternative to the original computationally intensive VAE in SD, reducing parameters by 97.5% while preserving high-quality encoding and decoding. Additionally, we propose online annealing pruning for the U-Net, which progressively shifts generative priors from heavy modules to lightweight counterparts, ensuring effective knowledge transfer and further optimizing efficiency. To mitigate the loss of prior knowledge during pruning, we incorporate a multi-layer feature distillation loss. Through an in-depth analysis of each design component, we provide valuable insights for future research. PocketSR, with a model size of 146M parameters, processes 4K images in just 0.8 seconds, achieving a remarkable speedup over previous methods. Notably, it delivers performance on par with state-of-the-art single-step and even multi-step RealSR models, making it a highly practical solution for edge-device applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.03012v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haoze Sun, Linfeng Jiang, Fan Li, Renjing Pei, Zhixin Wang, Yong Guo, Jiaqi Xu, Haoyu Chen, Jin Han, Fenglong Song, Yujiu Yang, Wenbo Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When and Where do Events Switch in Multi-Event Video Generation?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.03049</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.03049v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Text-to-video (T2V) generation has surged in response to challenging questions, especially when a long video must depict multiple sequential events with temporal coherence and controllable content. Existing methods that extend to multi-event generation omit an inspection of the intrinsic factor in event shifting. The paper aims to answer the central question: When and where multi-event prompts control event transition during T2V generation. This work introduces MEve, a self-curated prompt suite for evaluating multi-event text-to-video (T2V) generation, and conducts a systematic study of two representative model families, i.e., OpenSora and CogVideoX. Extensive experiments demonstrate the importance of early intervention in denoising steps and block-wise model layers, revealing the essential factor for multi-event video generation and highlighting the possibilities for multi-event conditioning in future models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.03049v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ruotong Liao, Guowen Huang, Qing Cheng, Thomas Seidl, Daniel Cremers, Volker Tresp</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>InsideOut: An EfficientNetV2-S Based Deep Learning Framework for Robust Multi-Class Facial Emotion Recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.03066</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.03066v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Facial Emotion Recognition (FER) is a key task in affective computing, enabling applications in human-computer interaction, e-learning, healthcare, and safety systems. Despite advances in deep learning, FER remains challenging due to occlusions, illumination and pose variations, subtle intra-class differences, and dataset imbalance that hinders recognition of minority emotions. We present InsideOut, a reproducible FER framework built on EfficientNetV2-S with transfer learning, strong data augmentation, and imbalance-aware optimization. The approach standardizes FER2013 images, applies stratified splitting and augmentation, and fine-tunes a lightweight classification head with class-weighted loss to address skewed distributions. InsideOut achieves 62.8% accuracy with a macro averaged F1 of 0.590 on FER2013, showing competitive results compared to conventional CNN baselines. The novelty lies in demonstrating that efficient architectures, combined with tailored imbalance handling, can provide practical, transparent, and reproducible FER solutions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.03066v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ahsan Farabi, Israt Khandaker, Ibrahim Khalil Shanto, Md Abdul Ahad Minhaz, Tanisha Zaman</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Drives Compositional Generalization in Visual Generative Models?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.03075</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.03075v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Compositional generalization, the ability to generate novel combinations of known concepts, is a key ingredient for visual generative models. Yet, not all mechanisms that enable or inhibit it are fully understood. In this work, we conduct a systematic study of how various design choices influence compositional generalization in image and video generation in a positive or negative way. Through controlled experiments, we identify two key factors: (i) whether the training objective operates on a discrete or continuous distribution, and (ii) to what extent conditioning provides information about the constituent concepts during training. Building on these insights, we show that relaxing the MaskGIT discrete loss with an auxiliary continuous JEPA-based objective can improve compositional performance in discrete models like MaskGIT.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.03075v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Karim Farid, Rajat Sahay, Yumna Ali Alnaggar, Simon Schrodi, Volker Fischer, Cordelia Schmid, Thomas Brox</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Latent Diffusion Unlearning: Protecting Against Unauthorized Personalization Through Trajectory Shifted Perturbations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.03089</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.03089v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Text-to-image diffusion models have demonstrated remarkable effectiveness in rapid and high-fidelity personalization, even when provided with only a few user images. However, the effectiveness of personalization techniques has lead to concerns regarding data privacy, intellectual property protection, and unauthorized usage. To mitigate such unauthorized usage and model replication, the idea of generating ``unlearnable'' training samples utilizing image poisoning techniques has emerged. Existing methods for this have limited imperceptibility as they operate in the pixel space which results in images with noise and artifacts. In this work, we propose a novel model-based perturbation strategy that operates within the latent space of diffusion models. Our method alternates between denoising and inversion while modifying the starting point of the denoising trajectory: of diffusion models. This trajectory-shifted sampling ensures that the perturbed images maintain high visual fidelity to the original inputs while being resistant to inversion and personalization by downstream generative models. This approach integrates unlearnability into the framework of Latent Diffusion Models (LDMs), enabling a practical and imperceptible defense against unauthorized model adaptation. We validate our approach on four benchmark datasets to demonstrate robustness against state-of-the-art inversion attacks. Results demonstrate that our method achieves significant improvements in imperceptibility ($\sim 8 \% -10\%$ on perceptual metrics including PSNR, SSIM, and FID) and robustness ( $\sim 10\%$ on average across five adversarial settings), highlighting its effectiveness in safeguarding sensitive data.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.03089v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3746027.3755112</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Naresh Kumar Devulapally, Shruti Agarwal, Tejas Gokhale, Vishnu Suresh Lokhande</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geometry Meets Vision: Revisiting Pretrained Semantics in Distilled Fields</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.03104</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.03104v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Semantic distillation in radiance fields has spurred significant advances in open-vocabulary robot policies, e.g., in manipulation and navigation, founded on pretrained semantics from large vision models. While prior work has demonstrated the effectiveness of visual-only semantic features (e.g., DINO and CLIP) in Gaussian Splatting and neural radiance fields, the potential benefit of geometry-grounding in distilled fields remains an open question. In principle, visual-geometry features seem very promising for spatial tasks such as pose estimation, prompting the question: Do geometry-grounded semantic features offer an edge in distilled fields? Specifically, we ask three critical questions: First, does spatial-grounding produce higher-fidelity geometry-aware semantic features? We find that image features from geometry-grounded backbones contain finer structural details compared to their counterparts. Secondly, does geometry-grounding improve semantic object localization? We observe no significant difference in this task. Thirdly, does geometry-grounding enable higher-accuracy radiance field inversion? Given the limitations of prior work and their lack of semantics integration, we propose a novel framework SPINE for inverting radiance fields without an initial guess, consisting of two core components: coarse inversion using distilled semantics, and fine inversion using photometric-based optimization. Surprisingly, we find that the pose estimation accuracy decreases with geometry-grounded features. Our results suggest that visual-only features offer greater versatility for a broader range of downstream tasks, although geometry-grounded features contain more geometric detail. Notably, our findings underscore the necessity of future research on effective strategies for geometry-grounding that augment the versatility and performance of pretrained semantic features.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.03104v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhiting Mei, Ola Shorinwa, Anirudha Majumdar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GeoComplete: Geometry-Aware Diffusion for Reference-Driven Image Completion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.03110</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.03110v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Reference-driven image completion, which restores missing regions in a target view using additional images, is particularly challenging when the target view differs significantly from the references. Existing generative methods rely solely on diffusion priors and, without geometric cues such as camera pose or depth, often produce misaligned or implausible content. We propose GeoComplete, a novel framework that incorporates explicit 3D structural guidance to enforce geometric consistency in the completed regions, setting it apart from prior image-only approaches. GeoComplete introduces two key ideas: conditioning the diffusion process on projected point clouds to infuse geometric information, and applying target-aware masking to guide the model toward relevant reference cues. The framework features a dual-branch diffusion architecture. One branch synthesizes the missing regions from the masked target, while the other extracts geometric features from the projected point cloud. Joint self-attention across branches ensures coherent and accurate completion. To address regions visible in references but absent in the target, we project the target view into each reference to detect occluded areas, which are then masked during training. This target-aware masking directs the model to focus on useful cues, enhancing performance in difficult scenarios. By integrating a geometry-aware dual-branch diffusion architecture with a target-aware masking strategy, GeoComplete offers a unified and robust solution for geometry-conditioned image completion. Experiments show that GeoComplete achieves a 17.1 PSNR improvement over state-of-the-art methods, significantly boosting geometric accuracy while maintaining high visual quality.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.03110v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Beibei Lin, Tingting Chen, Robby T. Tan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taming Text-to-Sounding Video Generation via Advanced Modality Condition and Interaction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.03117</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.03117v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This study focuses on a challenging yet promising task, Text-to-Sounding-Video (T2SV) generation, which aims to generate a video with synchronized audio from text conditions, meanwhile ensuring both modalities are aligned with text. Despite progress in joint audio-video training, two critical challenges still remain unaddressed: (1) a single, shared text caption where the text for video is equal to the text for audio often creates modal interference, confusing the pretrained backbones, and (2) the optimal mechanism for cross-modal feature interaction remains unclear. To address these challenges, we first propose the Hierarchical Visual-Grounded Captioning (HVGC) framework that generates pairs of disentangled captions, a video caption, and an audio caption, eliminating interference at the conditioning stage. Based on HVGC, we further introduce BridgeDiT, a novel dual-tower diffusion transformer, which employs a Dual CrossAttention (DCA) mechanism that acts as a robust ``bridge" to enable a symmetric, bidirectional exchange of information, achieving both semantic and temporal synchronization. Extensive experiments on three benchmark datasets, supported by human evaluations, demonstrate that our method achieves state-of-the-art results on most metrics. Comprehensive ablation studies further validate the effectiveness of our contributions, offering key insights for the future T2SV task. All the codes and checkpoints will be publicly released.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.03117v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kaisi Guan, Xihua Wang, Zhengfeng Lai, Xin Cheng, Peng Zhang, XiaoJiang Liu, Ruihua Song, Meng Cao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HAVIR: HierArchical Vision to Image Reconstruction using CLIP-Guided Versatile Diffusion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.03122</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.03122v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The reconstruction of visual information from brain activity fosters interdisciplinary integration between neuroscience and computer vision. However, existing methods still face challenges in accurately recovering highly complex visual stimuli. This difficulty stems from the characteristics of natural scenes: low-level features exhibit heterogeneity, while high-level features show semantic entanglement due to contextual overlaps. Inspired by the hierarchical representation theory of the visual cortex, we propose the HAVIR model, which separates the visual cortex into two hierarchical regions and extracts distinct features from each. Specifically, the Structural Generator extracts structural information from spatial processing voxels and converts it into latent diffusion priors, while the Semantic Extractor converts semantic processing voxels into CLIP embeddings. These components are integrated via the Versatile Diffusion model to synthesize the final image. Experimental results demonstrate that HAVIR enhances both the structural and semantic quality of reconstructions, even in complex scenes, and outperforms existing models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.03122v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shiyi Zhang, Dong Liang, Hairong Zheng, Yihang Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mask2IV: Interaction-Centric Video Generation via Mask Trajectories</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.03135</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.03135v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Generating interaction-centric videos, such as those depicting humans or robots interacting with objects, is crucial for embodied intelligence, as they provide rich and diverse visual priors for robot learning, manipulation policy training, and affordance reasoning. However, existing methods often struggle to model such complex and dynamic interactions. While recent studies show that masks can serve as effective control signals and enhance generation quality, obtaining dense and precise mask annotations remains a major challenge for real-world use. To overcome this limitation, we introduce Mask2IV, a novel framework specifically designed for interaction-centric video generation. It adopts a decoupled two-stage pipeline that first predicts plausible motion trajectories for both actor and object, then generates a video conditioned on these trajectories. This design eliminates the need for dense mask inputs from users while preserving the flexibility to manipulate the interaction process. Furthermore, Mask2IV supports versatile and intuitive control, allowing users to specify the target object of interaction and guide the motion trajectory through action descriptions or spatial position cues. To support systematic training and evaluation, we curate two benchmarks covering diverse action and object categories across both human-object interaction and robotic manipulation scenarios. Extensive experiments demonstrate that our method achieves superior visual realism and controllability compared to existing baselines.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.03135v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gen Li, Bo Zhao, Jianfei Yang, Laura Sevilla-Lara</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ReeMark: Reeb Graphs for Simulating Patterns of Life in Spatiotemporal Trajectories</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.03152</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.03152v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Accurately modeling human mobility is critical for urban planning, epidemiology, and traffic management. In this work, we introduce Markovian Reeb Graphs, a novel framework for simulating spatiotemporal trajectories that preserve Patterns of Life (PoLs) learned from baseline data. By combining individual- and population-level mobility structures within a probabilistic topological model, our approach generates realistic future trajectories that capture both consistency and variability in daily life. Evaluations on the Urban Anomalies dataset (Atlanta and Berlin subsets) using the Jensen-Shannon Divergence (JSD) across population- and agent-level metrics demonstrate that the proposed method achieves strong fidelity while remaining data- and compute-efficient. These results position Markovian Reeb Graphs as a scalable framework for trajectory simulation with broad applicability across diverse urban environments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.03152v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CE</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Anantajit Subrahmanya, Chandrakanth Gudavalli, Connor Levenson, Umang Garg, B. S. Manjunath</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SpineBench: A Clinically Salient, Level-Aware Benchmark Powered by the SpineMed-450k Corpus</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.03160</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.03160v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Spine disorders affect 619 million people globally and are a leading cause of disability, yet AI-assisted diagnosis remains limited by the lack of level-aware, multimodal datasets. Clinical decision-making for spine disorders requires sophisticated reasoning across X-ray, CT, and MRI at specific vertebral levels. However, progress has been constrained by the absence of traceable, clinically-grounded instruction data and standardized, spine-specific benchmarks. To address this, we introduce SpineMed, an ecosystem co-designed with practicing spine surgeons. It features SpineMed-450k, the first large-scale dataset explicitly designed for vertebral-level reasoning across imaging modalities with over 450,000 instruction instances, and SpineBench, a clinically-grounded evaluation framework. SpineMed-450k is curated from diverse sources, including textbooks, guidelines, open datasets, and ~1,000 de-identified hospital cases, using a clinician-in-the-loop pipeline with a two-stage LLM generation method (draft and revision) to ensure high-quality, traceable data for question-answering, multi-turn consultations, and report generation. SpineBench evaluates models on clinically salient axes, including level identification, pathology assessment, and surgical planning. Our comprehensive evaluation of several recently advanced large vision-language models (LVLMs) on SpineBench reveals systematic weaknesses in fine-grained, level-specific reasoning. In contrast, our model fine-tuned on SpineMed-450k demonstrates consistent and significant improvements across all tasks. Clinician assessments confirm the diagnostic clarity and practical utility of our model's outputs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.03160v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ming Zhao, Wenhui Dong, Yang Zhang, Xiang Zheng, Zhonghao Zhang, Zian Zhou, Yunzhi Guan, Liukun Xu, Wei Peng, Zhaoyang Gong, Zhicheng Zhang, Dachuan Li, Xiaosheng Ma, Yuli Ma, Jianing Ni, Changjiang Jiang, Lixia Tian, Qixin Chen, Kaishun Xia, Pingping Liu, Tongshun Zhang, Zhiqiang Liu, Zhongan Bi, Chenyang Si, Tiansheng Sun, Caifeng Shan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UniShield: An Adaptive Multi-Agent Framework for Unified Forgery Image Detection and Localization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.03161</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.03161v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: With the rapid advancements in image generation, synthetic images have become increasingly realistic, posing significant societal risks, such as misinformation and fraud. Forgery Image Detection and Localization (FIDL) thus emerges as essential for maintaining information integrity and societal security. Despite impressive performances by existing domain-specific detection methods, their practical applicability remains limited, primarily due to their narrow specialization, poor cross-domain generalization, and the absence of an integrated adaptive framework. To address these issues, we propose UniShield, the novel multi-agent-based unified system capable of detecting and localizing image forgeries across diverse domains, including image manipulation, document manipulation, DeepFake, and AI-generated images. UniShield innovatively integrates a perception agent with a detection agent. The perception agent intelligently analyzes image features to dynamically select suitable detection models, while the detection agent consolidates various expert detectors into a unified framework and generates interpretable reports. Extensive experiments show that UniShield achieves state-of-the-art results, surpassing both existing unified approaches and domain-specific detectors, highlighting its superior practicality, adaptiveness, and scalability.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.03161v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qing Huang, Zhipei Xu, Xuanyu Zhang, Jian Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ROGR: Relightable 3D Objects using Generative Relighting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.03163</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.03163v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We introduce ROGR, a novel approach that reconstructs a relightable 3D model of an object captured from multiple views, driven by a generative relighting model that simulates the effects of placing the object under novel environment illuminations. Our method samples the appearance of the object under multiple lighting environments, creating a dataset that is used to train a lighting-conditioned Neural Radiance Field (NeRF) that outputs the object's appearance under any input environmental lighting. The lighting-conditioned NeRF uses a novel dual-branch architecture to encode the general lighting effects and specularities separately. The optimized lighting-conditioned NeRF enables efficient feed-forward relighting under arbitrary environment maps without requiring per-illumination optimization or light transport simulation. We evaluate our approach on the established TensoIR and Stanford-ORB datasets, where it improves upon the state-of-the-art on most metrics, and showcase our approach on real-world object captures.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.03163v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiapeng Tang, Matthew Lavine, Dor Verbin, Stephan J. Garbin, Matthias Nie{\ss}ner, Ricardo Martin Brualla, Pratul P. Srinivasan, Philipp Henzler</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Prompt Generation for Interactive 3D Medical Image Segmentation Training</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.03189</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.03189v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Interactive 3D biomedical image segmentation requires efficient models that can iteratively refine predictions based on user prompts. Current foundation models either lack volumetric awareness or suffer from limited interactive capabilities. We propose a training strategy that combines dynamic volumetric prompt generation with content-aware adaptive cropping to optimize the use of the image encoder. Our method simulates realistic user interaction patterns during training while addressing the computational challenges of learning from sequential refinement feedback on a single GPU. For efficient training, we initialize our network using the publicly available weights from the nnInteractive segmentation model. Evaluation on the \textbf{Foundation Models for Interactive 3D Biomedical Image Segmentation} competition demonstrates strong performance with an average final Dice score of 0.6385, normalized surface distance of 0.6614, and area-under-the-curve metrics of 2.4799 (Dice) and 2.5671 (NSD).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.03189v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tidiane Camaret Ndir, Alexander Pfefferle, Robin Tibor Schirrmeister</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Product-Quantised Image Representation for High-Quality Image Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.03191</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.03191v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Product quantisation (PQ) is a classical method for scalable vector encoding, yet it has seen limited usage for latent representations in high-fidelity image generation. In this work, we introduce PQGAN, a quantised image autoencoder that integrates PQ into the well-known vector quantisation (VQ) framework of VQGAN. PQGAN achieves a noticeable improvement over state-of-the-art methods in terms of reconstruction performance, including both quantisation methods and their continuous counterparts. We achieve a PSNR score of 37dB, where prior work achieves 27dB, and are able to reduce the FID, LPIPS, and CMMD score by up to 96%. Our key to success is a thorough analysis of the interaction between codebook size, embedding dimensionality, and subspace factorisation, with vector and scalar quantisation as special cases. We obtain novel findings, such that the performance of VQ and PQ behaves in opposite ways when scaling the embedding dimension. Furthermore, our analysis shows performance trends for PQ that help guide optimal hyperparameter selection. Finally, we demonstrate that PQGAN can be seamlessly integrated into pre-trained diffusion models. This enables either a significantly faster and more compute-efficient generation, or a doubling of the output resolution at no additional cost, positioning PQ as a strong extension for discrete latent representation in image synthesis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.03191v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Denis Zavadski, Nikita Philip Tatsch, Carsten Rother</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memory Forcing: Spatio-Temporal Memory for Consistent Scene Generation on Minecraft</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.03198</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.03198v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Autoregressive video diffusion models have proved effective for world modeling and interactive scene generation, with Minecraft gameplay as a representative application. To faithfully simulate play, a model must generate natural content while exploring new scenes and preserve spatial consistency when revisiting explored areas. Under limited computation budgets, it must compress and exploit historical cues within a finite context window, which exposes a trade-off: Temporal-only memory lacks long-term spatial consistency, whereas adding spatial memory strengthens consistency but may degrade new scene generation quality when the model over-relies on insufficient spatial context. We present Memory Forcing, a learning framework that pairs training protocols with a geometry-indexed spatial memory. Hybrid Training exposes distinct gameplay regimes, guiding the model to rely on temporal memory during exploration and incorporate spatial memory for revisits. Chained Forward Training extends autoregressive training with model rollouts, where chained predictions create larger pose variations and encourage reliance on spatial memory for maintaining consistency. Point-to-Frame Retrieval efficiently retrieves history by mapping currently visible points to their source frames, while Incremental 3D Reconstruction maintains and updates an explicit 3D cache. Extensive experiments demonstrate that Memory Forcing achieves superior long-term spatial consistency and generative quality across diverse environments, while maintaining computational efficiency for extended sequences.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.03198v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junchao Huang, Xinting Hu, Boyao Han, Shaoshuai Shi, Zhuotao Tian, Tianyu He, Li Jiang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MonSTeR: a Unified Model for Motion, Scene, Text Retrieval</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.03200</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.03200v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Intention drives human movement in complex environments, but such movement can only happen if the surrounding context supports it. Despite the intuitive nature of this mechanism, existing research has not yet provided tools to evaluate the alignment between skeletal movement (motion), intention (text), and the surrounding context (scene). In this work, we introduce MonSTeR, the first MOtioN-Scene-TExt Retrieval model. Inspired by the modeling of higher-order relations, MonSTeR constructs a unified latent space by leveraging unimodal and cross-modal representations. This allows MonSTeR to capture the intricate dependencies between modalities, enabling flexible but robust retrieval across various tasks. Our results show that MonSTeR outperforms trimodal models that rely solely on unimodal representations. Furthermore, we validate the alignment of our retrieval scores with human preferences through a dedicated user study. We demonstrate the versatility of MonSTeR's latent space on zero-shot in-Scene Object Placement and Motion Captioning. Code and pre-trained models are available at github.com/colloroneluca/MonSTeR.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.03200v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Luca Collorone, Matteo Gioia, Massimiliano Pappa, Paolo Leoni, Giovanni Ficarra, Or Litany, Indro Spinelli, Fabio Galasso</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Test-Time Defense Against Adversarial Attacks via Stochastic Resonance of Latent Ensembles</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.03224</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.03224v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We propose a test-time defense mechanism against adversarial attacks: imperceptible image perturbations that significantly alter the predictions of a model. Unlike existing methods that rely on feature filtering or smoothing, which can lead to information loss, we propose to "combat noise with noise" by leveraging stochastic resonance to enhance robustness while minimizing information loss. Our approach introduces small translational perturbations to the input image, aligns the transformed feature embeddings, and aggregates them before mapping back to the original reference image. This can be expressed in a closed-form formula, which can be deployed on diverse existing network architectures without introducing additional network modules or fine-tuning for specific attack types. The resulting method is entirely training-free, architecture-agnostic, and attack-agnostic. Empirical results show state-of-the-art robustness on image classification and, for the first time, establish a generic test-time defense for dense prediction tasks, including stereo matching and optical flow, highlighting the method's versatility and practicality. Specifically, relative to clean (unperturbed) performance, our method recovers up to 68.1% of the accuracy loss on image classification, 71.9% on stereo matching, and 29.2% on optical flow under various types of adversarial attacks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.03224v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dong Lao, Yuxiang Zhang, Haniyeh Ehsani Oskouie, Yangchao Wu, Alex Wong, Stefano Soatto</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MIXER: Mixed Hyperspherical Random Embedding Neural Network for Texture Recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.03228</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.03228v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Randomized neural networks for representation learning have consistently achieved prominent results in texture recognition tasks, effectively combining the advantages of both traditional techniques and learning-based approaches. However, existing approaches have so far focused mainly on improving cross-information prediction, without introducing significant advancements to the overall randomized network architecture. In this paper, we propose Mixer, a novel randomized neural network for texture representation learning. At its core, the method leverages hyperspherical random embeddings coupled with a dual-branch learning module to capture both intra- and inter-channel relationships, further enhanced by a newly formulated optimization problem for building rich texture representations. Experimental results have shown the interesting results of the proposed approach across several pure texture benchmarks, each with distinct characteristics and challenges. The source code will be available upon publication.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.03228v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ricardo T. Fares, Lucas C. Ribas</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving GUI Grounding with Explicit Position-to-Coordinate Mapping</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.03230</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.03230v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: GUI grounding, the task of mapping natural-language instructions to pixel coordinates, is crucial for autonomous agents, yet remains difficult for current VLMs. The core bottleneck is reliable patch-to-pixel mapping, which breaks when extrapolating to high-resolution displays unseen during training. Current approaches generate coordinates as text tokens directly from visual features, forcing the model to infer complex position-to-pixel mappings implicitly; as a result, accuracy degrades and failures proliferate on new resolutions. We address this with two complementary innovations. First, RULER tokens serve as explicit coordinate markers, letting the model reference positions similar to gridlines on a map and adjust rather than generate coordinates from scratch. Second, Interleaved MRoPE (I-MRoPE) improves spatial encoding by ensuring that width and height dimensions are represented equally, addressing the asymmetry of standard positional schemes. Experiments on ScreenSpot, ScreenSpot-V2, and ScreenSpot-Pro show consistent gains in grounding accuracy, with the largest improvements on high-resolution interfaces. By providing explicit spatial guidance rather than relying on implicit learning, our approach enables more reliable GUI automation across diverse resolutions and platforms.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.03230v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Suyuchen Wang, Tianyu Zhang, Ahmed Masry, Christopher Pal, Spandana Gella, Bang Liu, Perouz Taslakian</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LEAML: Label-Efficient Adaptation to Out-of-Distribution Visual Tasks for Multimodal Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.03232</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.03232v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) have achieved strong performance on general visual benchmarks but struggle with out-of-distribution (OOD) tasks in specialized domains such as medical imaging, where labeled data is limited and expensive. We introduce LEAML, a label-efficient adaptation framework that leverages both scarce labeled VQA samples and abundant unlabeled images. Our approach generates domain-relevant pseudo question-answer pairs for unlabeled data using a QA generator regularized by caption distillation. Importantly, we selectively update only those neurons most relevant to question-answering, enabling the QA Generator to efficiently acquire domain-specific knowledge during distillation. Experiments on gastrointestinal endoscopy and sports VQA demonstrate that LEAML consistently outperforms standard fine-tuning under minimal supervision, highlighting the effectiveness of our proposed LEAML framework.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.03232v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ci-Siang Lin, Min-Hung Chen, Yu-Yang Sheng, Yu-Chiang Frank Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secure and Robust Watermarking for AI-generated Images: A Comprehensive Survey</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02384</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02384v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The rapid advancement of generative artificial intelligence (Gen-AI) has facilitated the effortless creation of high-quality images, while simultaneously raising critical concerns regarding intellectual property protection, authenticity, and accountability. Watermarking has emerged as a promising solution to these challenges by distinguishing AI-generated images from natural content, ensuring provenance, and fostering trustworthy digital ecosystems. This paper presents a comprehensive survey of the current state of AI-generated image watermarking, addressing five key dimensions: (1) formalization of image watermarking systems; (2) an overview and comparison of diverse watermarking techniques; (3) evaluation methodologies with respect to visual quality, capacity, and detectability; (4) vulnerabilities to malicious attacks; and (5) prevailing challenges and future directions. The survey aims to equip researchers with a holistic understanding of AI-generated image watermarking technologies, thereby promoting their continued development.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02384v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jie Cao, Qi Li, Zelin Zhang, Jianbing Ni</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glaucoma Detection and Structured OCT Report Generation via a Fine-tuned Multimodal Large Language Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02403</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02403v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Objective: To develop an explainable multimodal large language model (MM-LLM) that (1) screens optic nerve head (ONH) OCT circle scans for quality and (2) generates structured clinical reports that include glaucoma diagnosis and sector-wise retinal nerve fiber layer (RNFL) thinning assessments. Design: Retrospective cohort study of 1,310 subjects contributing 43,849 Spectralis ONH OCT circle scans (1,331 glaucomatous and 867 healthy eyes) from the DIGS and ADAGES cohorts. Methods: A MM-LLM (Llama 3.2 Vision-Instruct model) was fine-tuned to generate clinical descriptions of OCT imaging data. Training data included paired OCT images and automatically generated, structured clinical reports that described global and sectoral RNFL thinning. Poor-quality scans were labeled as unusable and paired with a fixed refusal statement. The model was evaluated on a held-out test set for three tasks: quality assessment, glaucoma detection, and RNFL thinning classification across seven anatomical sectors. Evaluation metrics included accuracy, sensitivity, specificity, precision, and F1-score. Model description quality was also evaluated using standard text evaluation metrics. Results: The model achieved 0.90 accuracy and 0.98 specificity for quality triage. For glaucoma detection, accuracy was 0.86 (sensitivity 0.91, specificity 0.73, F1-score 0.91). RNFL thinning prediction accuracy ranged from 0.83 to 0.94, with highest performance in global and temporal sectors. Text generation scores showed strong alignment with reference reports (BLEU: 0.82; ROUGE-1: 0.94; ROUGE-2: 0.87; ROUGE-L: 0.92; BERTScore-F1: 0.99). Conclusions: The fine-tuned MM-LLM generated accurate clinical descriptions based on OCT imaging. The model achieved high accuracy in identifying image quality issues and detecting glaucoma. The model also provided sectoral descriptions of RNFL thinning to help support clinical OCT evaluation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02403v1</guid>
      <category>q-bio.QM</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jalil Jalili, Yashraj Gavhane, Evan Walker, Anna Heinke, Christopher Bowd, Akram Belghith, Massimo A. Fazio, Christopher A. Girkin, C. Gustavo De Moraes, Jeffrey M. Liebmann, Sally L. Baxter, Robert N. Weinreb, Linda M. Zangwill, Mark Christopher</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Words That Make Language Models Perceive</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02425</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02425v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) trained purely on text ostensibly lack any direct perceptual experience, yet their internal representations are implicitly shaped by multimodal regularities encoded in language. We test the hypothesis that explicit sensory prompting can surface this latent structure, bringing a text-only LLM into closer representational alignment with specialist vision and audio encoders. When a sensory prompt tells the model to 'see' or 'hear', it cues the model to resolve its next-token predictions as if they were conditioned on latent visual or auditory evidence that is never actually supplied. Our findings reveal that lightweight prompt engineering can reliably activate modality-appropriate representations in purely text-trained LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02425v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sophie L. Wang, Phillip Isola, Brian Cheung</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SIMSplat: Predictive Driving Scene Editing with Language-aligned 4D Gaussian Splatting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02469</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02469v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Driving scene manipulation with sensor data is emerging as a promising alternative to traditional virtual driving simulators. However, existing frameworks struggle to generate realistic scenarios efficiently due to limited editing capabilities. To address these challenges, we present SIMSplat, a predictive driving scene editor with language-aligned Gaussian splatting. As a language-controlled editor, SIMSplat enables intuitive manipulation using natural language prompts. By aligning language with Gaussian-reconstructed scenes, it further supports direct querying of road objects, allowing precise and flexible editing. Our method provides detailed object-level editing, including adding new objects and modifying the trajectories of both vehicles and pedestrians, while also incorporating predictive path refinement through multi-agent motion prediction to generate realistic interactions among all agents in the scene. Experiments on the Waymo dataset demonstrate SIMSplat's extensive editing capabilities and adaptability across a wide range of scenarios. Project page: https://sungyeonparkk.github.io/simsplat/</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02469v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sung-Yeon Park, Adam Lee, Juanwu Lu, Can Cui, Luyang Jiang, Rohit Gupta, Kyungtae Han, Ahmadreza Moradipari, Ziran Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning a distance measure from the information-estimation geometry of data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02514</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02514v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We introduce the Information-Estimation Metric (IEM), a novel form of distance function derived from an underlying continuous probability density over a domain of signals. The IEM is rooted in a fundamental relationship between information theory and estimation theory, which links the log-probability of a signal with the errors of an optimal denoiser, applied to noisy observations of the signal. In particular, the IEM between a pair of signals is obtained by comparing their denoising error vectors over a range of noise amplitudes. Geometrically, this amounts to comparing the score vector fields of the blurred density around the signals over a range of blur levels. We prove that the IEM is a valid global metric and derive a closed-form expression for its local second-order approximation, which yields a Riemannian metric. For Gaussian-distributed signals, the IEM coincides with the Mahalanobis distance. But for more complex distributions, it adapts, both locally and globally, to the geometry of the distribution. In practice, the IEM can be computed using a learned denoiser (analogous to generative diffusion models) and solving a one-dimensional integral. To demonstrate the value of our framework, we learn an IEM on the ImageNet database. Experiments show that this IEM is competitive with or outperforms state-of-the-art supervised image quality metrics in predicting human perceptual judgments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02514v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.IT</category>
      <category>eess.SP</category>
      <category>math.IT</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Guy Ohayon, Pierre-Etienne H. Fiquet, Florentin Guth, Jona Ball\'e, Eero P. Simoncelli</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A UAV-Based VNIR Hyperspectral Benchmark Dataset for Landmine and UXO Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02700</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02700v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This paper introduces a novel benchmark dataset of Visible and Near-Infrared (VNIR) hyperspectral imagery acquired via an unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV) platform for landmine and unexploded ordnance (UXO) detection research. The dataset was collected over a controlled test field seeded with 143 realistic surrogate landmine and UXO targets, including surface, partially buried, and fully buried configurations. Data acquisition was performed using a Headwall Nano-Hyperspec sensor mounted on a multi-sensor drone platform, flown at an altitude of approximately 20.6 m, capturing 270 contiguous spectral bands spanning 398-1002 nm. Radiometric calibration, orthorectification, and mosaicking were performed followed by reflectance retrieval using a two-point Empirical Line Method (ELM), with reference spectra acquired using an SVC spectroradiometer. Cross-validation against six reference objects yielded RMSE values below 1.0 and SAM values between 1 and 6 degrees in the 400-900 nm range, demonstrating high spectral fidelity. The dataset is released alongside raw radiance cubes, GCP/AeroPoint data, and reference spectra to support reproducible research. This contribution fills a critical gap in open-access UAV-based hyperspectral data for landmine detection and offers a multi-sensor benchmark when combined with previously published drone-based electromagnetic induction (EMI) data from the same test field.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02700v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.SP</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sagar Lekhak, Emmett J. Ientilucci, Jasper Baur, Susmita Ghosh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Statistical Method for Attack-Agnostic Adversarial Attack Detection with Compressive Sensing Comparison</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02707</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02707v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Adversarial attacks present a significant threat to modern machine learning systems. Yet, existing detection methods often lack the ability to detect unseen attacks or detect different attack types with a high level of accuracy. In this work, we propose a statistical approach that establishes a detection baseline before a neural network's deployment, enabling effective real-time adversarial detection. We generate a metric of adversarial presence by comparing the behavior of a compressed/uncompressed neural network pair. Our method has been tested against state-of-the-art techniques, and it achieves near-perfect detection across a wide range of attack types. Moreover, it significantly reduces false positives, making it both reliable and practical for real-world applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02707v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chinthana Wimalasuriya, Spyros Tragoudas</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Image Enhancement Based on Pigment Representation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02713</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02713v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This paper presents a novel and efficient image enhancement method based on pigment representation. Unlike conventional methods where the color transformation is restricted to pre-defined color spaces like RGB, our method dynamically adapts to input content by transforming RGB colors into a high-dimensional feature space referred to as \textit{pigments}. The proposed pigment representation offers adaptability and expressiveness, achieving superior image enhancement performance. The proposed method involves transforming input RGB colors into high-dimensional pigments, which are then reprojected individually and blended to refine and aggregate the information of the colors in pigment spaces. Those pigments are then transformed back into RGB colors to generate an enhanced output image. The transformation and reprojection parameters are derived from the visual encoder which adaptively estimates such parameters based on the content in the input image. Extensive experimental results demonstrate the superior performance of the proposed method over state-of-the-art methods in image enhancement tasks, including image retouching and tone mapping, while maintaining relatively low computational complexity and small model size.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02713v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Se-Ho Lee, Keunsoo Ko, Seung-Wook Kim</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dale meets Langevin: A Multiplicative Denoising Diffusion Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02730</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02730v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Gradient descent has proven to be a powerful and effective technique for optimization in numerous machine learning applications. Recent advances in computational neuroscience have shown that learning in standard gradient descent optimization formulation is not consistent with learning in biological systems. This has opened up interesting avenues for building biologically inspired learning techniques. One such approach is inspired by Dale's law, which states that inhibitory and excitatory synapses do not swap roles during the course of learning. The resulting exponential gradient descent optimization scheme leads to log-normally distributed synaptic weights. Interestingly, the density that satisfies the Fokker-Planck equation corresponding to the stochastic differential equation (SDE) with geometric Brownian motion (GBM) is the log-normal density. Leveraging this connection, we start with the SDE governing geometric Brownian motion, and show that discretizing the corresponding reverse-time SDE yields a multiplicative update rule, which surprisingly, coincides with the sampling equivalent of the exponential gradient descent update founded on Dale's law. Furthermore, we propose a new formalism for multiplicative denoising score-matching, subsuming the loss function proposed by Hyvaerinen for non-negative data. Indeed, log-normally distributed data is positive and the proposed score-matching formalism turns out to be a natural fit. This allows for training of score-based models for image data and results in a novel multiplicative update scheme for sample generation starting from a log-normal density. Experimental results on MNIST, Fashion MNIST, and Kuzushiji datasets demonstrate generative capability of the new scheme. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first instance of a biologically inspired generative model employing multiplicative updates, founded on geometric Brownian motion.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02730v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nishanth Shetty, Madhava Prasath, Chandra Sekhar Seelamantula</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GCVAMD: A Modified CausalVAE Model for Causal Age-related Macular Degeneration Risk Factor Detection and Prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02781</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02781v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Age Related Macular Degeneration(AMD) has been one of the most leading causes of permanent vision impairment in ophthalmology. Though treatments, such as anti VEGF drugs or photodynamic therapies, were developed to slow down the degenerative process of AMD, there is still no specific cure to reverse vision loss caused by AMD. Thus, for AMD, detecting existence of risk factors of AMD or AMD itself within the patient retina in early stages is a crucial task to reduce the possibility of vision impairment. Apart from traditional approaches, deep learning based methods, especially attention mechanism based CNNs and GradCAM based XAI analysis on OCT scans, exhibited successful performance in distinguishing AMD retina from normal retinas, making it possible to use AI driven models to aid medical diagnosis and analysis by ophthalmologists regarding AMD. However, though having significant success, previous works mostly focused on prediction performance itself, not pathologies or underlying causal mechanisms of AMD, which can prohibit intervention analysis on specific factors or even lead to less reliable decisions. Thus, this paper introduces a novel causal AMD analysis model: GCVAMD, which incorporates a modified CausalVAE approach that can extract latent causal factors from only raw OCT images. By considering causality in AMD detection, GCVAMD enables causal inference such as treatment simulation or intervention analysis regarding major risk factors: drusen and neovascularization, while returning informative latent causal features that can enhance downstream tasks. Results show that through GCVAMD, drusen status and neovascularization status can be identified with AMD causal mechanisms in GCVAMD latent spaces, which can in turn be used for various tasks from AMD detection(classification) to intervention analysis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02781v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Daeyoung Kim</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Work Zones challenge VLM Trajectory Planning: Toward Mitigation and Robust Autonomous Driving</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02803</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02803v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Visual Language Models (VLMs), with powerful multimodal reasoning capabilities, are gradually integrated into autonomous driving by several automobile manufacturers to enhance planning capability in challenging environments. However, the trajectory planning capability of VLMs in work zones, which often include irregular layouts, temporary traffic control, and dynamically changing geometric structures, is still unexplored. To bridge this gap, we conduct the \textit{first} systematic study of VLMs for work zone trajectory planning, revealing that mainstream VLMs fail to generate correct trajectories in $68.0%$ of cases. To better understand these failures, we first identify candidate patterns via subgraph mining and clustering analysis, and then confirm the validity of $8$ common failure patterns through human verification. Building on these findings, we propose REACT-Drive, a trajectory planning framework that integrates VLMs with Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG). Specifically, REACT-Drive leverages VLMs to convert prior failure cases into constraint rules and executable trajectory planning code, while RAG retrieves similar patterns in new scenarios to guide trajectory generation. Experimental results on the ROADWork dataset show that REACT-Drive yields a reduction of around $3\times$ in average displacement error relative to VLM baselines under evaluation with Qwen2.5-VL. In addition, REACT-Drive yields the lowest inference time ($0.58$s) compared with other methods such as fine-tuning ($17.90$s). We further conduct experiments using a real vehicle in 15 work zone scenarios in the physical world, demonstrating the strong practicality of REACT-Drive.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02803v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yifan Liao, Zhen Sun, Xiaoyun Qiu, Zixiao Zhao, Wenbing Tang, Xinlei He, Xinhu Zheng, Tianwei Zhang, Xinyi Huang, Xingshuo Han</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Representing Beauty: Towards a Participatory but Objective Latent Aesthetics</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02869</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02869v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: What does it mean for a machine to recognize beauty? While beauty remains a culturally and experientially compelling but philosophically elusive concept, deep learning systems increasingly appear capable of modeling aesthetic judgment. In this paper, we explore the capacity of neural networks to represent beauty despite the immense formal diversity of objects for which the term applies. By drawing on recent work on cross-model representational convergence, we show how aesthetic content produces more similar and aligned representations between models which have been trained on distinct data and modalities - while unaesthetic images do not produce more aligned representations. This finding implies that the formal structure of beautiful images has a realist basis - rather than only as a reflection of socially constructed values. Furthermore, we propose that these realist representations exist because of a joint grounding of aesthetic form in physical and cultural substance. We argue that human perceptual and creative acts play a central role in shaping these the latent spaces of deep learning systems, but that a realist basis for aesthetics shows that machines are not mere creative parrots but can produce novel creative insights from the unique vantage point of scale. Our findings suggest that human-machine co-creation is not merely possible, but foundational - with beauty serving as a teleological attractor in both cultural production and machine perception.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02869v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alexander Michael Rusnak</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PyRadiomics-cuda: a GPU-accelerated 3D features extraction from medical images within PyRadiomics</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02894</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02894v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: PyRadiomics-cuda is a GPU-accelerated extension of the PyRadiomics library, designed to address the computational challenges of extracting three-dimensional shape features from medical images. By offloading key geometric computations to GPU hardware it dramatically reduces processing times for large volumetric datasets. The system maintains full compatibility with the original PyRadiomics API, enabling seamless integration into existing AI workflows without code modifications. This transparent acceleration facilitates efficient, scalable radiomics analysis, supporting rapid feature extraction essential for high-throughput AI pipeline. Tests performed on a typical computational cluster, budget and home devices prove usefulness in all scenarios. PyRadiomics-cuda is implemented in Python and C/CUDA and is freely available under the BSD license at https://github.com/mis-wut/pyradiomics-CUDA Additionally PyRadiomics-cuda test suite is available at https://github.com/mis-wut/pyradiomics-cuda-data-gen. It provides detailed handbook and sample scripts suited for different kinds of workflows plus detailed installation instructions. The dataset used for testing is available at Kaggle https://www.kaggle.com/datasets/sabahesaraki/kidney-tumor-segmentation-challengekits-19</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02894v1</guid>
      <category>cs.DC</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jakub Lisowski, Piotr Tyrakowski, Szymon Zygu{\l}a, Krzysztof Kaczmarski</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confidence and Dispersity as Signals: Unsupervised Model Evaluation and Ranking</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02956</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.02956v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Assessing model generalization under distribution shift is essential for real-world deployment, particularly when labeled test data is unavailable. This paper presents a unified and practical framework for unsupervised model evaluation and ranking in two common deployment settings: (1) estimating the accuracy of a fixed model on multiple unlabeled test sets (dataset-centric evaluation), and (2) ranking a set of candidate models on a single unlabeled test set (model-centric evaluation). We demonstrate that two intrinsic properties of model predictions, namely confidence (which reflects prediction certainty) and dispersity (which captures the diversity of predicted classes), together provide strong and complementary signals for generalization. We systematically benchmark a set of confidence-based, dispersity-based, and hybrid metrics across a wide range of model architectures, datasets, and distribution shift types. Our results show that hybrid metrics consistently outperform single-aspect metrics on both dataset-centric and model-centric evaluation settings. In particular, the nuclear norm of the prediction matrix provides robust and accurate performance across tasks, including real-world datasets, and maintains reliability under moderate class imbalance. These findings offer a practical and generalizable basis for unsupervised model assessment in deployment scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02956v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weijian Deng, Weijie Tu, Ibrahim Radwan, Mohammad Abu Alsheikh, Stephen Gould, Liang Zheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neural Posterior Estimation with Autoregressive Tiling for Detecting Objects in Astronomical Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.03074</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.03074v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Upcoming astronomical surveys will produce petabytes of high-resolution images of the night sky, providing information about billions of stars and galaxies. Detecting and characterizing the astronomical objects in these images is a fundamental task in astronomy -- and a challenging one, as most of these objects are faint and many visually overlap with other objects. We propose an amortized variational inference procedure to solve this instance of small-object detection. Our key innovation is a family of spatially autoregressive variational distributions that partition and order the latent space according to a $K$-color checkerboard pattern. By construction, the conditional independencies of this variational family mirror those of the posterior distribution. We fit the variational distribution, which is parameterized by a convolutional neural network, using neural posterior estimation (NPE) to minimize an expectation of the forward KL divergence. Using images from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey, our method achieves state-of-the-art performance. We further demonstrate that the proposed autoregressive structure greatly improves posterior calibration.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.03074v1</guid>
      <category>stat.AP</category>
      <category>astro-ph.IM</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jeffrey Regier</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MM-Nav: Multi-View VLA Model for Robust Visual Navigation via Multi-Expert Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.03142</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.03142v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Visual navigation policy is widely regarded as a promising direction, as it mimics humans by using egocentric visual observations for navigation. However, optical information of visual observations is difficult to be explicitly modeled like LiDAR point clouds or depth maps, which subsequently requires intelligent models and large-scale data. To this end, we propose to leverage the intelligence of the Vision-Language-Action (VLA) model to learn diverse navigation capabilities from synthetic expert data in a teacher-student manner. Specifically, we implement the VLA model, MM-Nav, as a multi-view VLA (with 360 observations) based on pretrained large language models and visual foundation models. For large-scale navigation data, we collect expert data from three reinforcement learning (RL) experts trained with privileged depth information in three challenging tailor-made environments for different navigation capabilities: reaching, squeezing, and avoiding. We iteratively train our VLA model using data collected online from RL experts, where the training ratio is dynamically balanced based on performance on individual capabilities. Through extensive experiments in synthetic environments, we demonstrate that our model achieves strong generalization capability. Moreover, we find that our student VLA model outperforms the RL teachers, demonstrating the synergistic effect of integrating multiple capabilities. Extensive real-world experiments further confirm the effectiveness of our method.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.03142v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tianyu Xu, Jiawei Chen, Jiazhao Zhang, Wenyao Zhang, Zekun Qi, Minghan Li, Zhizheng Zhang, He Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wave-GMS: Lightweight Multi-Scale Generative Model for Medical Image Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.03216</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.03216v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: For equitable deployment of AI tools in hospitals and healthcare facilities, we need Deep Segmentation Networks that offer high performance and can be trained on cost-effective GPUs with limited memory and large batch sizes. In this work, we propose Wave-GMS, a lightweight and efficient multi-scale generative model for medical image segmentation. Wave-GMS has a substantially smaller number of trainable parameters, does not require loading memory-intensive pretrained vision foundation models, and supports training with large batch sizes on GPUs with limited memory. We conducted extensive experiments on four publicly available datasets (BUS, BUSI, Kvasir-Instrument, and HAM10000), demonstrating that Wave-GMS achieves state-of-the-art segmentation performance with superior cross-domain generalizability, while requiring only ~2.6M trainable parameters. Code is available at https://github.com/ATPLab-LUMS/Wave-GMS.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.03216v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Talha Ahmed, Nehal Ahmed Shaikh, Hassan Mohy-ud-Din</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Filter-Guided Diffusion for Controllable Image Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2306.17141</link>
      <description>arXiv:2306.17141v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advances in diffusion-based generative models have shown incredible promise for zero shot image-to-image translation and editing. Most of these approaches work by combining or replacing network-specific features used in the generation of new images with those taken from the inversion of some guide image. Methods of this type are considered the current state-of-the-art in training-free approaches, but have some notable limitations: they tend to be costly in runtime and memory, and often depend on deterministic sampling that limits variation in generated results. We propose Filter-Guided Diffusion (FGD), an alternative approach that leverages fast filtering operations during the diffusion process to support finer control over the strength and frequencies of guidance and can work with non-deterministic samplers to produce greater variety. With its efficiency, FGD can be sampled over multiple seeds and hyperparameters in less time than a single run of other SOTA methods to produce superior results based on structural and semantic metrics. We conduct extensive quantitative and qualitative experiments to evaluate the performance of FGD in translation tasks and also demonstrate its potential in localized editing when used with masks. Project page: https://filterguideddiffusion.github.io/</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2306.17141v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zeqi Gu, Ethan Yang, Abe Davis</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unified Domain Adaptive Semantic Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.13254</link>
      <description>arXiv:2311.13254v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Unsupervised Domain Adaptive Semantic Segmentation (UDA-SS) aims to transfer the supervision from a labeled source domain to an unlabeled target domain. The majority of existing UDA-SS works typically consider images whilst recent attempts have extended further to tackle videos by modeling the temporal dimension. Although the two lines of research share the major challenges -- overcoming the underlying domain distribution shift, their studies are largely independent, resulting in fragmented insights, a lack of holistic understanding, and missed opportunities for cross-pollination of ideas. This fragmentation prevents the unification of methods, leading to redundant efforts and suboptimal knowledge transfer across image and video domains. Under this observation, we advocate unifying the study of UDA-SS across video and image scenarios, enabling a more comprehensive understanding, synergistic advancements, and efficient knowledge sharing. To that end, we explore the unified UDA-SS from a general data augmentation perspective, serving as a unifying conceptual framework, enabling improved generalization, and potential for cross-pollination of ideas, ultimately contributing to the overall progress and practical impact of this field of research. Specifically, we propose a Quad-directional Mixup (QuadMix) method, characterized by tackling distinct point attributes and feature inconsistencies through four-directional paths for intra- and inter-domain mixing in a feature space. To deal with temporal shifts with videos, we incorporate optical flow-guided feature aggregation across spatial and temporal dimensions for fine-grained domain alignment. Extensive experiments show that our method outperforms the state-of-the-art works by large margins on four challenging UDA-SS benchmarks. Our source code and models will be released at https://github.com/ZHE-SAPI/UDASS.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2311.13254v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1109/TPAMI.2025.3562999</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Z. Zhang, G. Wu, J. Zhang, X. Zhu, D. Tao, and T. Chai, Unified Domain Adaptive Semantic Segmentation, IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence, vol. 47, no. 8, pp. 6731-6748, Aug. 2025</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Zhe Zhang, Gaochang Wu, Jing Zhang, Xiatian Zhu, Dacheng Tao, Tianyou Chai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparing YOLOv8 and Mask R-CNN for instance segmentation in complex orchard environments</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.07935</link>
      <description>arXiv:2312.07935v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Instance segmentation is an important image processing operation for agricultural automation, providing precise delineation of individual objects within images and enabling tasks such as selective harvesting and precision pruning. This study compares the one stage YOLOv8 model with the two stage Mask R CNN model for instance segmentation under varying orchard conditions across two datasets. Dataset 1, collected in the dormant season, contains images of apple trees without foliage and was used to train multi object segmentation models delineating branches and trunks. Dataset 2, collected in the early growing season, includes canopy images with green foliage and immature apples and was used to train single object segmentation models delineating fruitlets. Results showed YOLOv8 outperformed Mask R CNN with higher precision and near perfect recall at a confidence threshold of 0.5. For Dataset 1, YOLOv8 achieved precision 0.90 and recall 0.95 compared to 0.81 and 0.81 for Mask R CNN. For Dataset 2, YOLOv8 reached precision 0.93 and recall 0.97 compared to 0.85 and 0.88. Inference times were also lower for YOLOv8, at 10.9 ms and 7.8 ms, versus 15.6 ms and 12.8 ms for Mask R CNN. These findings demonstrate superior accuracy and efficiency of YOLOv8 for real time orchard automation tasks such as robotic harvesting and fruit thinning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2312.07935v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1016/j.aiia.2024.07.001</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Artificial Intelligence in Agriculture, 2025</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Ranjan Sapkota, Dawood Ahmed, Manoj Karkee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RACCooN: A Versatile Instructional Video Editing Framework with Auto-Generated Narratives</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.18406</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.18406v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent video generative models primarily rely on carefully written text prompts for specific tasks, like inpainting or style editing. They require labor-intensive textual descriptions for input videos, hindering their flexibility to adapt personal/raw videos to user specifications. This paper proposes RACCooN, a versatile and user-friendly video-to-paragraph-to-video generative framework that supports multiple video editing capabilities such as removal, addition, and modification, through a unified pipeline. RACCooN consists of two principal stages: Video-to-Paragraph (V2P) and Paragraph-to-Video (P2V). In the V2P stage, we automatically describe video scenes in well-structured natural language, capturing both the holistic context and focused object details. Subsequently, in the P2V stage, users can optionally refine these descriptions to guide the video diffusion model, enabling various modifications to the input video, such as removing, changing subjects, and/or adding new objects. The proposed approach stands out from other methods through several significant contributions: (1) RACCooN suggests a multi-granular spatiotemporal pooling strategy to generate well-structured video descriptions, capturing both the broad context and object details without requiring complex human annotations, simplifying precise video content editing based on text for users. (2) Our video generative model incorporates auto-generated narratives or instructions to enhance the quality and accuracy of the generated content. (3) RACCooN also plans to imagine new objects in a given video, so users simply prompt the model to receive a detailed video editing plan for complex video editing. The proposed framework demonstrates impressive versatile capabilities in video-to-paragraph generation, video content editing, and can be incorporated into other SoTA video generative models for further enhancement.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.18406v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jaehong Yoon, Shoubin Yu, Mohit Bansal</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Survey of Defenses against AI-generated Visual Media: Detection, Disruption, and Authentication</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10575</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.10575v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Deep generative models have demonstrated impressive performance in various computer vision applications, including image synthesis, video generation, and medical analysis. Despite their significant advancements, these models may be used for malicious purposes, such as misinformation, deception, and copyright violation. In this paper, we provide a systematic and timely review of research efforts on defenses against AI-generated visual media, covering detection, disruption, and authentication. We review existing methods and summarize the mainstream defense-related tasks within a unified passive and proactive framework. Moreover, we survey the derivative tasks concerning the trustworthiness of defenses, such as their robustness and fairness. For each task, we formulate its general pipeline and propose a taxonomy based on methodological strategies that are uniformly applicable to the primary subtasks. Additionally, we summarize the commonly used evaluation datasets, criteria, and metrics. Finally, by analyzing the reviewed studies, we provide insights into current research challenges and suggest possible directions for future research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.10575v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jingyi Deng, Chenhao Lin, Zhengyu Zhao, Shuai Liu, Qian Wang, Chao Shen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward a Holistic Evaluation of Robustness in CLIP Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.01534</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.01534v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Contrastive Language-Image Pre-training (CLIP) models have shown significant potential, particularly in zero-shot classification across diverse distribution shifts. Building on existing evaluations of overall classification robustness, this work aims to provide a more comprehensive assessment of CLIP by introducing several new perspectives. First, we investigate their robustness to variations in specific visual factors. Second, we assess two critical safety objectives--confidence uncertainty and out-of-distribution detection--beyond mere classification accuracy. Third, we evaluate the finesse with which CLIP models bridge the image and text modalities. Fourth, we extend our examination to 3D awareness in CLIP models, moving beyond traditional 2D image understanding. Finally, we explore the interaction between vision and language encoders within modern large multimodal models (LMMs) that utilize CLIP as the visual backbone, focusing on how this interaction impacts classification robustness. In each aspect, we consider the impact of six factors on CLIP models: model architecture, training distribution, training set size, fine-tuning, contrastive loss, and test-time prompts. Our study uncovers several previously unknown insights into CLIP. For instance, the architecture of the visual encoder in CLIP plays a significant role in their robustness against 3D corruption. CLIP models tend to exhibit a bias towards shape when making predictions. Moreover, this bias tends to diminish after fine-tuning on ImageNet. Vision-language models like LLaVA, leveraging the CLIP vision encoder, could exhibit benefits in classification performance for challenging categories over CLIP alone. Our findings are poised to offer valuable guidance for enhancing the robustness and reliability of CLIP models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.01534v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weijie Tu, Weijian Deng, Tom Gedeon</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fine-grained Abnormality Prompt Learning for Zero-shot Anomaly Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.10289</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.10289v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Current zero-shot anomaly detection (ZSAD) methods show remarkable success in prompting large pre-trained vision-language models to detect anomalies in a target dataset without using any dataset-specific training or demonstration. However, these methods often focus on crafting/learning prompts that capture only coarse-grained semantics of abnormality, e.g., high-level semantics like "damaged", "imperfect", or "defective" objects. They therefore have limited capability in recognizing diverse abnormality details that deviate from these general abnormal patterns in various ways. To address this limitation, we propose FAPrompt, a novel framework designed to learn Fine-grained Abnormality Prompts for accurate ZSAD. To this end, a novel Compound Abnormality Prompt learning (CAP) module is introduced in FAPrompt to learn a set of complementary, decomposed abnormality prompts, where abnormality prompts are enforced to model diverse abnormal patterns derived from the same normality semantic. On the other hand, the fine-grained abnormality patterns can be different from one dataset to another. To enhance the cross-dataset generalization, another novel module, namely Data-dependent Abnormality Prior learning (DAP), is introduced in FAPrompt to learn a sample-wise abnormality prior from abnormal features of each test image to dynamically adapt the abnormality prompts to individual test images. Comprehensive experiments on 19 real-world datasets, covering both industrial defects and medical anomalies, demonstrate that FAPrompt substantially outperforms state-of-the-art methods in both image- and pixel-level ZSAD tasks. Code is available at https://github.com/mala-lab/FAPrompt.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.10289v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiawen Zhu, Yew-Soon Ong, Chunhua Shen, Guansong Pang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ranked from Within: Ranking Large Multimodal Models Without Labels</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.06461</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.06461v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Can the relative performance of a pre-trained large multimodal model (LMM) be predicted without access to labels? As LMMs proliferate, it becomes increasingly important to develop efficient ways to choose between them when faced with new data or tasks. The usual approach does the equivalent of giving the models an exam and marking them. We opt to avoid marking and the associated labor of determining the ground-truth answers. Instead, we explore other signals elicited and ascertain how well the models know their own limits, evaluating the effectiveness of these signals at unsupervised model ranking. We evaluate $47$ state-of-the-art LMMs (\eg, LLaVA) across $9$ visual question answering benchmarks, analyzing how well uncertainty-based metrics can predict relative model performance. Our findings show that uncertainty scores derived from softmax distributions provide a robust and consistent basis for ranking models across various tasks. This facilitates the ranking of LMMs on unlabeled data, providing a practical approach for selecting models for diverse target domains without requiring manual annotation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.06461v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weijie Tu, Weijian Deng, Dylan Campbell, Yu Yao, Jiyang Zheng, Tom Gedeon, Tongliang Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SoccerSynth-Detection: A Synthetic Dataset for Soccer Player Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.09281</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.09281v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In soccer video analysis, player detection is essential for identifying key events and reconstructing tactical positions. The presence of numerous players and frequent occlusions, combined with copyright restrictions, severely restricts the availability of datasets, leaving limited options such as SoccerNet-Tracking and SportsMOT. These datasets suffer from a lack of diversity, which hinders algorithms from adapting effectively to varied soccer video contexts. To address these challenges, we developed SoccerSynth-Detection, the first synthetic dataset designed for the detection of synthetic soccer players. It includes a broad range of random lighting and textures, as well as simulated camera motion blur. We validated its efficacy using the object detection model (Yolov8n) against real-world datasets (SoccerNet-Tracking and SportsMoT). In transfer tests, it matched the performance of real datasets and significantly outperformed them in images with motion blur; in pre-training tests, it demonstrated its efficacy as a pre-training dataset, significantly enhancing the algorithm's overall performance. Our work demonstrates the potential of synthetic datasets to replace real datasets for algorithm training in the field of soccer video analysis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.09281v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haobin Qin, Calvin Yeung, Rikuhei Umemoto, Keisuke Fujii</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CBVLM: Training-free Explainable Concept-based Large Vision Language Models for Medical Image Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.12266</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.12266v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The main challenges limiting the adoption of deep learning-based solutions in medical workflows are the availability of annotated data and the lack of interpretability of such systems. Concept Bottleneck Models (CBMs) tackle the latter by constraining the model output on a set of predefined and human-interpretable concepts. However, the increased interpretability achieved through these concept-based explanations implies a higher annotation burden. Moreover, if a new concept needs to be added, the whole system needs to be retrained. Inspired by the remarkable performance shown by Large Vision-Language Models (LVLMs) in few-shot settings, we propose a simple, yet effective, methodology, CBVLM, which tackles both of the aforementioned challenges. First, for each concept, we prompt the LVLM to answer if the concept is present in the input image. Then, we ask the LVLM to classify the image based on the previous concept predictions. Moreover, in both stages, we incorporate a retrieval module responsible for selecting the best examples for in-context learning. By grounding the final diagnosis on the predicted concepts, we ensure explainability, and by leveraging the few-shot capabilities of LVLMs, we drastically lower the annotation cost. We validate our approach with extensive experiments across four medical datasets and twelve LVLMs (both generic and medical) and show that CBVLM consistently outperforms CBMs and task-specific supervised methods without requiring any training and using just a few annotated examples. More information on our project page: https://cristianopatricio.github.io/CBVLM/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.12266v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Cristiano Patr\'icio, Isabel Rio-Torto, Jaime S. Cardoso, Lu\'is F. Teixeira, Jo\~ao C. Neves</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gate-Shift-Pose: Enhancing Action Recognition in Sports with Skeleton Information</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.04470</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.04470v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper introduces Gate-Shift-Pose, an enhanced version of Gate-Shift-Fuse networks, designed for athlete fall classification in figure skating by integrating skeleton pose data alongside RGB frames. We evaluate two fusion strategies: early-fusion, which combines RGB frames with Gaussian heatmaps of pose keypoints at the input stage, and late-fusion, which employs a multi-stream architecture with attention mechanisms to combine RGB and pose features. Experiments on the FR-FS dataset demonstrate that Gate-Shift-Pose significantly outperforms the RGB-only baseline, improving accuracy by up to 40% with ResNet18 and 20% with ResNet50. Early-fusion achieves the highest accuracy (98.08%) with ResNet50, leveraging the model's capacity for effective multimodal integration, while late-fusion is better suited for lighter backbones like ResNet18. These results highlight the potential of multimodal architectures for sports action recognition and the critical role of skeleton pose information in capturing complex motion patterns. Visit the project page at https://edowhite.github.io/Gate-Shift-Pose</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.04470v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Edoardo Bianchi, Oswald Lanz</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EFC++: Elastic Feature Consolidation with Prototype Re-balancing for Cold Start Exemplar-free Incremental Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.10439</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.10439v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Exemplar-free Class Incremental Learning (EFCIL) aims to learn from a sequence of tasks without having access to previous task data. In this paper, we consider the challenging Cold Start scenario in which insufficient data is available in the first task to learn a high-quality backbone. This is especially challenging for EFCIL since it requires high plasticity, resulting in feature drift which is difficult to compensate for in the exemplar-free setting. To address this problem, we propose an effective approach to consolidate feature representations by regularizing drift in directions highly relevant to previous tasks while employing prototypes to reduce task-recency bias. Our approach, which we call Elastic Feature Consolidation++ (EFC++) exploits a tractable second-order approximation of feature drift based on a proposed Empirical Feature Matrix (EFM). The EFM induces a pseudo-metric in feature space which we use to regularize feature drift in important directions and to update Gaussian prototypes. In addition, we introduce a post-training prototype re-balancing phase that updates classifiers to compensate for feature drift. Experimental results on CIFAR-100, Tiny-ImageNet, ImageNet-Subset, ImageNet-1K and DomainNet demonstrate that EFC++ is better able to learn new tasks by maintaining model plasticity and significantly outperforms the state-of-the-art.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.10439v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Simone Magistri, Tomaso Trinci, Albin Soutif-Cormerais, Joost van de Weijer, Andrew D. Bagdanov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vehicle-Scene Interaction: A Text-Driven 3D Lidar Place Recognition Method for Autonomous Driving</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.18035</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.18035v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Environment description-based localization in large-scale point cloud maps constructed through remote sensing is critically significant for the advancement of large-scale autonomous systems, such as delivery robots operating in the last mile. However, current approaches encounter challenges due to the inability of point cloud encoders to effectively capture local details and long-range spatial relationships, as well as a significant modality gap between text and point cloud representations. To address these challenges, we present Des4Pos, a novel two-stage text-driven remote sensing localization framework. In the coarse stage, the point-cloud encoder utilizes the Multi-scale Fusion Attention Mechanism (MFAM) to enhance local geometric features, followed by a bidirectional Long Short-Term Memory (LSTM) module to strengthen global spatial relationships. Concurrently, the Stepped Text Encoder (STE) integrates cross-modal prior knowledge from CLIP [1] and aligns text and point-cloud features using this prior knowledge, effectively bridging modality discrepancies. In the fine stage, we introduce a Cascaded Residual Attention (CRA) module to fuse cross-modal features and predict relative localization offsets, thereby achieving greater localization precision. Experiments on the KITTI360Pose test set demonstrate that Des4Pos achieves state-of-the-art performance in text-to-point-cloud place recognition. Specifically, it attains a top-1 accuracy of 40% and a top-10 accuracy of 77% under a 5-meter radius threshold, surpassing the best existing methods by 7% and 7%, respectively.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.18035v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tianyi Shang, Zhenyu Li, Pengjie Xu, Zhaojun Deng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AlignDiT: Multimodal Aligned Diffusion Transformer for Synchronized Speech Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20629</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.20629v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this paper, we address the task of multimodal-to-speech generation, which aims to synthesize high-quality speech from multiple input modalities: text, video, and reference audio. This task has gained increasing attention due to its wide range of applications, such as film production, dubbing, and virtual avatars. Despite recent progress, existing methods still suffer from limitations in speech intelligibility, audio-video synchronization, speech naturalness, and voice similarity to the reference speaker. To address these challenges, we propose AlignDiT, a multimodal Aligned Diffusion Transformer that generates accurate, synchronized, and natural-sounding speech from aligned multimodal inputs. Built upon the in-context learning capability of the DiT architecture, AlignDiT explores three effective strategies to align multimodal representations. Furthermore, we introduce a novel multimodal classifier-free guidance mechanism that allows the model to adaptively balance information from each modality during speech synthesis. Extensive experiments demonstrate that AlignDiT significantly outperforms existing methods across multiple benchmarks in terms of quality, synchronization, and speaker similarity. Moreover, AlignDiT exhibits strong generalization capability across various multimodal tasks, such as video-to-speech synthesis and visual forced alignment, consistently achieving state-of-the-art performance. The demo page is available at https://mm.kaist.ac.kr/projects/AlignDiT.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.20629v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jeongsoo Choi, Ji-Hoon Kim, Kim Sung-Bin, Tae-Hyun Oh, Joon Son Chung</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Monocular Height Estimation via Sparse LiDAR-Guided Correction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.06905</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.06905v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Monocular height estimation (MHE) from very-high-resolution (VHR) remote sensing imagery via deep learning is notoriously challenging due to the lack of sufficient structural information. Conventional digital elevation models (DEMs), typically derived from airborne LiDAR or multi-view stereo, remain costly and geographically limited. Recently, models trained on synthetic data and refined through domain adaptation have shown remarkable performance in MHE, yet it remains unclear how these models make predictions or how reliable they truly are. In this paper, we investigate a state-of-the-art MHE model trained purely on synthetic data to explore where the model looks when making height predictions. Through systematic analyses, we find that the model relies heavily on shadow cues, a factor that can lead to overestimation or underestimation of heights when shadows deviate from expected norms. Furthermore, the inherent difficulty of evaluating regression tasks with the human eye underscores additional limitations of purely synthetic training. To address these issues, we propose a novel correction pipeline that integrates sparse, imperfect global LiDAR measurements (ICESat-2) with deep-learning outputs to improve local accuracy and achieve spatially consistent corrections. Our method comprises two stages: pre-processing raw ICESat-2 data, followed by a random forest-based approach to densely refine height estimates. Experiments in three representative urban regions -- Saint-Omer, Tokyo, and Sao Paulo -- reveal substantial error reductions, with mean absolute error (MAE) decreased by 22.8\%, 6.9\%, and 4.9\%, respectively. These findings highlight the critical role of shadow awareness in synthetic data-driven models and demonstrate how fusing imperfect real-world LiDAR data can bolster the robustness of MHE, paving the way for more reliable and scalable 3D mapping solutions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.06905v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jian Song, Hongruixuan Chen, Naoto Yokoya</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SkillFormer: Unified Multi-View Video Understanding for Proficiency Estimation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.08665</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.08665v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Assessing human skill levels in complex activities is a challenging problem with applications in sports, rehabilitation, and training. In this work, we present SkillFormer, a parameter-efficient architecture for unified multi-view proficiency estimation from egocentric and exocentric videos. Building on the TimeSformer backbone, SkillFormer introduces a CrossViewFusion module that fuses view-specific features using multi-head cross-attention, learnable gating, and adaptive self-calibration. We leverage Low-Rank Adaptation to fine-tune only a small subset of parameters, significantly reducing training costs. In fact, when evaluated on the EgoExo4D dataset, SkillFormer achieves state-of-the-art accuracy in multi-view settings while demonstrating remarkable computational efficiency, using 4.5x fewer parameters and requiring 3.75x fewer training epochs than prior baselines. It excels in multiple structured tasks, confirming the value of multi-view integration for fine-grained skill assessment. Project page at https://edowhite.github.io/SkillFormer</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.08665v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Edoardo Bianchi, Antonio Liotta</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So-Fake: Benchmarking and Explaining Social Media Image Forgery Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.18660</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.18660v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advances in AI-powered generative models have enabled the creation of increasingly realistic synthetic images, posing significant risks to information integrity and public trust on social media platforms. While robust detection frameworks and diverse, large-scale datasets are essential to mitigate these risks, existing academic efforts remain limited in scope: current datasets lack the diversity, scale, and realism required for social media contexts, while detection methods struggle with generalization to unseen generative technologies. To bridge this gap, we introduce So-Fake-Set, a comprehensive social media-oriented dataset with over 2 million high-quality images, diverse generative sources, and photorealistic imagery synthesized using 35 state-of-the-art generative models. To rigorously evaluate cross-domain robustness, we establish a novel and large-scale (100K) out-of-domain benchmark (So-Fake-OOD) featuring synthetic imagery from commercial models explicitly excluded from the training distribution, creating a realistic testbed for evaluating real-world performance. Leveraging these resources, we present So-Fake-R1, an advanced vision-language framework that employs reinforcement learning for highly accurate forgery detection, precise localization, and explainable inference through interpretable visual rationales. Extensive experiments show that So-Fake-R1 outperforms the second-best method, with a 1.3% gain in detection accuracy and a 4.5% increase in localization IoU. By integrating a scalable dataset, a challenging OOD benchmark, and an advanced detection framework, this work establishes a new foundation for social media-centric forgery detection research. The code, models, and datasets will be released publicly.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.18660v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhenglin Huang, Tianxiao Li, Xiangtai Li, Haiquan Wen, Yiwei He, Jiangning Zhang, Hao Fei, Xi Yang, Xiaowei Huang, Bei Peng, Guangliang Cheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photography Perspective Composition: Towards Aesthetic Perspective Recommendation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.20655</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.20655v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Traditional photography composition approaches are dominated by 2D cropping-based methods. However, these methods fall short when scenes contain poorly arranged subjects. Professional photographers often employ perspective adjustment as a form of 3D recomposition, modifying the projected 2D relationships between subjects while maintaining their actual spatial positions to achieve better compositional balance. Inspired by this artistic practice, we propose photography perspective composition (PPC), extending beyond traditional cropping-based methods. However, implementing the PPC faces significant challenges: the scarcity of perspective transformation datasets and undefined assessment criteria for perspective quality. To address these challenges, we present three key contributions: (1) An automated framework for building PPC datasets through expert photographs. (2) A video generation approach that demonstrates the transformation process from less favorable to aesthetically enhanced perspectives. (3) A perspective quality assessment (PQA) model constructed based on human performance. Our approach is concise and requires no additional prompt instructions or camera trajectories, helping and guiding ordinary users to enhance their composition skills.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.20655v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lujian Yao, Siming Zheng, Xinbin Yuan, Zhuoxuan Cai, Pu Wu, Jinwei Chen, Bo Li, Peng-Tao Jiang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting Reweighted Risk for Calibration: AURC, Focal, and Inverse Focal Loss</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.23463</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.23463v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Several variants of reweighted risk functionals, such as focal loss, inverse focal loss, and the Area Under the Risk--Coverage Curve (AURC), have been proposed for improving model calibration, yet their theoretical connections to calibration errors remain unclear. In this paper, we revisit a broad class of weighted risk functions commonly used in deep learning and establish a principled connection between calibration error and selective classification. We show that minimizing calibration error is closely linked to the selective classification paradigm and demonstrate that optimizing selective risk in low-confidence region naturally leads to improved calibration. This loss shares a similar reweighting strategy with dual focal loss but offers greater flexibility through the choice of confidence score functions (CSFs). Our approach uses a bin-based cumulative distribution function (CDF) approximation, enabling efficient gradient-based optimization without requiring expensive sorting and achieving $O(nK)$ complexity. Empirical evaluations demonstrate that our method achieves competitive calibration performance across a range of datasets and model architectures.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.23463v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Han Zhou, Sebastian G. Gruber, Teodora Popordanoska, Matthew B. Blaschko</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PATS: Proficiency-Aware Temporal Sampling for Multi-View Sports Skill Assessment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.04996</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.04996v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Automated sports skill assessment requires capturing fundamental movement patterns that distinguish expert from novice performance, yet current video sampling methods disrupt the temporal continuity essential for proficiency evaluation. To this end, we introduce Proficiency-Aware Temporal Sampling (PATS), a novel sampling strategy that preserves complete fundamental movements within continuous temporal segments for multi-view skill assessment. PATS adaptively segments videos to ensure each analyzed portion contains full execution of critical performance components, repeating this process across multiple segments to maximize information coverage while maintaining temporal coherence. Evaluated on the EgoExo4D benchmark with SkillFormer, PATS surpasses the state-of-the-art accuracy across all viewing configurations (+0.65% to +3.05%) and delivers substantial gains in challenging domains (+26.22% bouldering, +2.39% music, +1.13% basketball). Systematic analysis reveals that PATS successfully adapts to diverse activity characteristics-from high-frequency sampling for dynamic sports to fine-grained segmentation for sequential skills-demonstrating its effectiveness as an adaptive approach to temporal sampling that advances automated skill assessment for real-world applications. Visit our project page at https://edowhite.github.io/PATS</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.04996v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Edoardo Bianchi, Antonio Liotta</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HopaDIFF: Holistic-Partial Aware Fourier Conditioned Diffusion for Referring Human Action Segmentation in Multi-Person Scenarios</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09650</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.09650v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Action segmentation is a core challenge in high-level video understanding, aiming to partition untrimmed videos into segments and assign each a label from a predefined action set. Existing methods primarily address single-person activities with fixed action sequences, overlooking multi-person scenarios. In this work, we pioneer textual reference-guided human action segmentation in multi-person settings, where a textual description specifies the target person for segmentation. We introduce the first dataset for Referring Human Action Segmentation, i.e., RHAS133, built from 133 movies and annotated with 137 fine-grained actions with 33h video data, together with textual descriptions for this new task. Benchmarking existing action segmentation methods on RHAS133 using VLM-based feature extractors reveals limited performance and poor aggregation of visual cues for the target person. To address this, we propose a holistic-partial aware Fourier-conditioned diffusion framework, i.e., HopaDIFF, leveraging a novel cross-input gate attentional xLSTM to enhance holistic-partial long-range reasoning and a novel Fourier condition to introduce more fine-grained control to improve the action segmentation generation. HopaDIFF achieves state-of-the-art results on RHAS133 in diverse evaluation settings. The dataset and code are available at https://github.com/KPeng9510/HopaDIFF.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.09650v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kunyu Peng, Junchao Huang, Xiangsheng Huang, Di Wen, Junwei Zheng, Yufan Chen, Kailun Yang, Jiamin Wu, Chongqing Hao, Rainer Stiefelhagen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SP-VLA: A Joint Model Scheduling and Token Pruning Approach for VLA Model Acceleration</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.12723</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.12723v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Vision-Language-Action (VLA) models have attracted increasing attention for their strong control capabilities. However, their high computational cost and low execution frequency hinder their suitability for real-time tasks such as robotic manipulation and autonomous navigation. Existing VLA acceleration methods primarily focus on structural optimization, overlooking the fact that these models operate in sequential decision-making environments. As a result, temporal redundancy in sequential action generation and spatial redundancy in visual input remain unaddressed. To this end, we propose SP-VLA, a unified framework that accelerates VLA models by jointly scheduling models and pruning tokens. Specifically, we design an action-aware model scheduling mechanism that reduces temporal redundancy by dynamically switching between VLA model and a lightweight generator. Inspired by the human motion pattern of focusing on key decision points while relying on intuition for other actions, we categorize VLA actions into deliberative and intuitive, assigning the former to the VLA model and the latter to the lightweight generator, enabling frequency-adaptive execution through collaborative model scheduling. To address spatial redundancy, we further develop a spatio-semantic dual-aware token pruning method. Tokens are classified into spatial and semantic types and pruned based on their dual-aware importance to accelerate VLA inference. These two mechanisms work jointly to guide the VLA in focusing on critical actions and salient visual information, achieving effective acceleration while maintaining high accuracy. Extensive experiments show that our method achieves 1.5$\times$ lossless acceleration in LIBERO and 2.4$\times$ in SimplerEnv, with up to 6% average performance gain. Inference frequency and latency improve by 2.2$\times$ in SimplerEnv and 1.4$\times$ in LIBERO.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.12723v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ye Li, Yuan Meng, Zewen Sun, Kangye Ji, Chen Tang, Jiajun Fan, Xinzhu Ma, Shutao Xia, Zhi Wang, Wenwu Zhu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Long Videos to Engaging Clips: A Human-Inspired Video Editing Framework with Multimodal Narrative Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.02790</link>
      <description>arXiv:2507.02790v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The rapid growth of online video content, especially on short video platforms, has created a growing demand for efficient video editing techniques that can condense long-form videos into concise and engaging clips. Existing automatic editing methods predominantly rely on textual cues from ASR transcripts and end-to-end segment selection, often neglecting the rich visual context and leading to incoherent outputs. In this paper, we propose a human-inspired automatic video editing framework (HIVE) that leverages multimodal narrative understanding to address these limitations. Our approach incorporates character extraction, dialogue analysis, and narrative summarization through multimodal large language models, enabling a holistic understanding of the video content. To further enhance coherence, we apply scene-level segmentation and decompose the editing process into three subtasks: highlight detection, opening/ending selection, and pruning of irrelevant content. To facilitate research in this area, we introduce DramaAD, a novel benchmark dataset comprising over 800 short drama episodes and 500 professionally edited advertisement clips. Experimental results demonstrate that our framework consistently outperforms existing baselines across both general and advertisement-oriented editing tasks, significantly narrowing the quality gap between automatic and human-edited videos.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2507.02790v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiangfeng Wang, Xiao Li, Yadong Wei, Xueyu Song, Yang Song, Xiaoqiang Xia, Fangrui Zeng, Zaiyi Chen, Liu Liu, Gu Xu, Tong Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RichControl: Structure- and Appearance-Rich Training-Free Spatial Control for Text-to-Image Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.02792</link>
      <description>arXiv:2507.02792v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Text-to-image (T2I) diffusion models have shown remarkable success in generating high-quality images from text prompts. Recent efforts extend these models to incorporate conditional images (e.g., canny edge) for fine-grained spatial control. Among them, feature injection methods have emerged as a training-free alternative to traditional fine-tuning-based approaches. However, they often suffer from structural misalignment, condition leakage, and visual artifacts, especially when the condition image diverges significantly from natural RGB distributions. Through an empirical analysis of existing methods, we identify a key limitation: the sampling schedule of condition features, previously unexplored, fails to account for the evolving interplay between structure preservation and domain alignment throughout diffusion steps. Inspired by this observation, we propose a flexible training-free framework that decouples the sampling schedule of condition features from the denoising process, and systematically investigate the spectrum of feature injection schedules for a higher-quality structure guidance in the feature space. Specifically, we find that condition features sampled from a single timestep are sufficient, yielding a simple yet efficient schedule that balances structure alignment and appearance quality. We further enhance the sampling process by introducing a restart refinement schedule, and improve the visual quality with an appearance-rich prompting strategy. Together, these designs enable training-free generation that is both structure-rich and appearance-rich. Extensive experiments show that our approach achieves state-of-the-art results across diverse zero-shot conditioning scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2507.02792v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Liheng Zhang, Lexi Pang, Hang Ye, Xiaoxuan Ma, Yizhou Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VOTE: Vision-Language-Action Optimization with Trajectory Ensemble Voting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.05116</link>
      <description>arXiv:2507.05116v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent large-scale Vision Language Action (VLA) models have shown superior performance in robotic manipulation tasks guided by natural language. However, current VLA models suffer from two drawbacks: (i) generation of massive tokens leading to high inference latency and increased training cost, and (ii) insufficient utilization of generated actions resulting in potential performance loss. To address these issues, we develop a training framework to finetune VLA models for generating significantly fewer action tokens with high parallelism, effectively reducing inference latency and training cost. Furthermore, we introduce an inference optimization technique with a novel voting-based ensemble strategy to combine current and previous action predictions, improving the utilization of generated actions and overall performance. Our results demonstrate that we achieve superior performance compared with state-of-the-art VLA models, achieving significantly higher success rates and 39$\times$ faster inference than OpenVLA with 46 Hz throughput on edge platforms, demonstrating practical deployability. The code is available at https://github.com/LukeLIN-web/VOTE.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2507.05116v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Juyi Lin, Amir Taherin, Arash Akbari, Arman Akbari, Lei Lu, Guangyu Chen, Taskin Padir, Xiaomeng Yang, Weiwei Chen, Yiqian Li, Xue Lin, David Kaeli, Pu Zhao, Yanzhi Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SBP-YOLO:A Lightweight Real-Time Model for Detecting Speed Bumps and Potholes toward Intelligent Vehicle Suspension Systems</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.01339</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.01339v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Speed bumps and potholes are the most common road anomalies, significantly affecting ride comfort and vehicle stability. Preview-based suspension control mitigates their impact by detecting such irregularities in advance and adjusting suspension parameters proactively. Accurate and real-time detection is essential, but embedded deployment is constrained by limited computational resources and the small size of targets in input images.To address these challenges, this paper proposes SBP-YOLO, an efficient detection framework for speed bumps and potholes in embedded systems. Built upon YOLOv11n, it integrates GhostConv and VoVGSCSPC modules in the backbone and neck to reduce computation while enhancing multi-scale semantic features. A P2-level branch improves small-object detection, and a lightweight and efficient detection head (LEDH) maintains accuracy with minimal overhead. A hybrid training strategy further enhances robustness under varying road and environmental conditions, combining NWD loss, BCKD knowledge distillation, and Albumentations-based augmentation. Experiments show that SBP-YOLO achieves 87.0% mAP, outperforming the YOLOv11n baseline by 5.8%. After TensorRT FP16 quantization, it runs at 139.5 FPS on Jetson AGX Xavier, yielding a 12.4% speedup over the P2-enhanced YOLOv11. These results demonstrate the framework's suitability for fast, low-latency road condition perception in embedded suspension control systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.01339v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chuanqi Liang, Jie Fu, Miao Yu, Lei Luo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RelayFormer: A Unified Local-Global Attention Framework for Scalable Image and Video Manipulation Localization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.09459</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.09459v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Visual manipulation localization (VML) aims to identify tampered regions in images and videos, a task that has become increasingly challenging with the rise of advanced editing tools. Existing methods face two main issues: resolution diversity, where resizing or padding distorts forensic traces and reduces efficiency, and the modality gap, as images and videos often require separate models. To address these challenges, we propose RelayFormer, a unified framework that adapts to varying resolutions and modalities. RelayFormer partitions inputs into fixed-size sub-images and introduces Global-Local Relay (GLR) tokens, which propagate structured context through a global-local relay attention (GLRA) mechanism. This enables efficient exchange of global cues, such as semantic or temporal consistency, while preserving fine-grained manipulation artifacts. Unlike prior methods that rely on uniform resizing or sparse attention, RelayFormer naturally scales to arbitrary resolutions and video sequences without excessive overhead. Experiments across diverse benchmarks demonstrate that RelayFormer achieves state-of-the-art performance with notable efficiency, combining resolution adaptivity without interpolation or excessive padding, unified modeling for both images and videos, and a strong balance between accuracy and computational cost. Code is available at: https://github.com/WenOOI/RelayFormer.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.09459v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wen Huang, Jiarui Yang, Tao Dai, Jiawei Li, Shaoxiong Zhan, Bin Wang, Shu-Tao Xia</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AudioStory: Generating Long-Form Narrative Audio with Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.20088</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.20088v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advances in text-to-audio (TTA) generation excel at synthesizing short audio clips but struggle with long-form narrative audio, which requires temporal coherence and compositional reasoning. To address this gap, we propose AudioStory, a unified framework that integrates large language models (LLMs) with TTA systems to generate structured, long-form audio narratives. AudioStory possesses strong instruction-following reasoning generation capabilities. It employs LLMs to decompose complex narrative queries into temporally ordered sub-tasks with contextual cues, enabling coherent scene transitions and emotional tone consistency. AudioStory has two appealing features: (1) Decoupled bridging mechanism: AudioStory disentangles LLM-diffuser collaboration into two specialized components, i.e., a bridging query for intra-event semantic alignment and a residual query for cross-event coherence preservation. (2) End-to-end training: By unifying instruction comprehension and audio generation within a single end-to-end framework, AudioStory eliminates the need for modular training pipelines while enhancing synergy between components. Furthermore, we establish a benchmark AudioStory-10K, encompassing diverse domains such as animated soundscapes and natural sound narratives. Extensive experiments show the superiority of AudioStory on both single-audio generation and narrative audio generation, surpassing prior TTA baselines in both instruction-following ability and audio fidelity. Our code is available at https://github.com/TencentARC/AudioStory</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.20088v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuxin Guo, Teng Wang, Yuying Ge, Shijie Ma, Yixiao Ge, Wei Zou, Ying Shan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PointAD+: Learning Hierarchical Representations for Zero-shot 3D Anomaly Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.03277</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.03277v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this paper, we aim to transfer CLIP's robust 2D generalization capabilities to identify 3D anomalies across unseen objects of highly diverse class semantics. To this end, we propose a unified framework to comprehensively detect and segment 3D anomalies by leveraging both point- and pixel-level information. We first design PointAD, which leverages point-pixel correspondence to represent 3D anomalies through their associated rendering pixel representations. This approach is referred to as implicit 3D representation, as it focuses solely on rendering pixel anomalies but neglects the inherent spatial relationships within point clouds. Then, we propose PointAD+ to further broaden the interpretation of 3D anomalies by introducing explicit 3D representation, emphasizing spatial abnormality to uncover abnormal spatial relationships. Hence, we propose G-aggregation to involve geometry information to enable the aggregated point representations spatially aware. To simultaneously capture rendering and spatial abnormality, PointAD+ proposes hierarchical representation learning, incorporating implicit and explicit anomaly semantics into hierarchical text prompts: rendering prompts for the rendering layer and geometry prompts for the geometry layer. A cross-hierarchy contrastive alignment is further introduced to promote the interaction between the rendering and geometry layers, facilitating mutual anomaly learning. Finally, PointAD+ integrates anomaly semantics from both layers to capture the generalized anomaly semantics. During the test, PointAD+ can integrate RGB information in a plug-and-play manner and further improve its detection performance. Extensive experiments demonstrate the superiority of PointAD+ in ZS 3D anomaly detection across unseen objects with highly diverse class semantics, achieving a holistic understanding of abnormality.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.03277v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qihang Zhou, Shibo He, Jiangtao Yan, Wenchao Meng, Jiming Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contextualized Representation Learning for Effective Human-Object Interaction Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.12784</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.12784v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Human-Object Interaction (HOI) detection aims to simultaneously localize human-object pairs and recognize their interactions. While recent two-stage approaches have made significant progress, they still face challenges due to incomplete context modeling. In this work, we introduce a Contextualized Representation Learning that integrates both affordance-guided reasoning and contextual prompts with visual cues to better capture complex interactions. We enhance the conventional HOI detection framework by expanding it beyond simple human-object pairs to include multivariate relationships involving auxiliary entities like tools. Specifically, we explicitly model the functional role (affordance) of these auxiliary objects through triplet structures &lt;human, tool, object&gt;. This enables our model to identify tool-dependent interactions such as 'filling'. Furthermore, the learnable prompt is enriched with instance categories and subsequently integrated with contextual visual features using an attention mechanism. This process aligns language with image content at both global and regional levels. These contextualized representations equip the model with enriched relational cues for more reliable reasoning over complex, context-dependent interactions. Our proposed method demonstrates superior performance on both the HICO-Det and V-COCO datasets in most scenarios. The source code is available at https://github.com/lzzhhh1019/CRL.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.12784v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhehao Li, Yucheng Qian, Chong Wang, Yinghao Lu, Zhihao Yang, Jiafei Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual-Stage Reweighted MoE for Long-Tailed Egocentric Mistake Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.12990</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.12990v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this report, we address the problem of determining whether a user performs an action incorrectly from egocentric video data. To handle the challenges posed by subtle and infrequent mistakes, we propose a Dual-Stage Reweighted Mixture-of-Experts (DR-MoE) framework. In the first stage, features are extracted using a frozen ViViT model and a LoRA-tuned ViViT model, which are combined through a feature-level expert module. In the second stage, three classifiers are trained with different objectives: reweighted cross-entropy to mitigate class imbalance, AUC loss to improve ranking under skewed distributions, and label-aware loss with sharpness-aware minimization to enhance calibration and generalization. Their predictions are fused using a classification-level expert module. The proposed method achieves strong performance, particularly in identifying rare and ambiguous mistake instances. The code is available at https://github.com/boyuh/DR-MoE.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.12990v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Boyu Han, Qianqian Xu, Shilong Bao, Zhiyong Yang, Sicong Li, Qingming Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Size-invariant Salient Object Detection: A Generic Evaluation and Optimization Approach</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.15573</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.15573v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper investigates a fundamental yet underexplored issue in Salient Object Detection (SOD): the size-invariant property for evaluation protocols, particularly in scenarios when multiple salient objects of significantly different sizes appear within a single image. We first present a novel perspective to expose the inherent size sensitivity of existing widely used SOD metrics. Through careful theoretical derivations, we show that the evaluation outcome of an image under current SOD metrics can be essentially decomposed into a sum of several separable terms, with the contribution of each term being directly proportional to its corresponding region size. Consequently, the prediction errors would be dominated by the larger regions, while smaller yet potentially more semantically important objects are often overlooked, leading to biased performance assessments and practical degradation. To address this challenge, a generic Size-Invariant Evaluation (SIEva) framework is proposed. The core idea is to evaluate each separable component individually and then aggregate the results, thereby effectively mitigating the impact of size imbalance across objects. Building upon this, we further develop a dedicated optimization framework (SIOpt), which adheres to the size-invariant principle and significantly enhances the detection of salient objects across a broad range of sizes. Notably, SIOpt is model-agnostic and can be seamlessly integrated with a wide range of SOD backbones. Theoretically, we also present generalization analysis of SOD methods and provide evidence supporting the validity of our new evaluation protocols. Finally, comprehensive experiments speak to the efficacy of our proposed approach. The code is available at https://github.com/Ferry-Li/SI-SOD.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.15573v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shilong Bao, Qianqian Xu, Feiran Li, Boyu Han, Zhiyong Yang, Xiaochun Cao, Qingming Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evict3R: Training-Free Token Eviction for Memory-Bounded Streaming Visual Geometry Transformers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.17650</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.17650v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Streaming visual transformers like StreamVGGT achieve strong 3D perception but suffer from unbounded growth of key value (KV) memory, which limits scalability. We propose a training-free, inference-time token eviction policy that bounds memory by discarding redundant tokens while keeping the most informative ones. Our method uses significantly less memory with little to no drop in accuracy: on 7-Scenes with long sequences it reduces peak memory from 18.63 GB to 9.39 GB while accuracy and completeness drop by only 0.003. Under strict memory budgets, eviction enables denser frame sampling, which improves reconstruction accuracy compared to the baseline. Experiments across video depth estimation (Sintel, KITTI), 3D reconstruction (7-Scenes, NRGBD), and camera pose estimation (Sintel, TUM-dynamics) show that our approach closely matches StreamVGGT at a fraction of the memory and makes long-horizon streaming inference more practical.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.17650v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Soroush Mahdi, Fardin Ayar, Ehsan Javanmardi, Manabu Tsukada, Mahdi Javanmardi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Q-FSRU: Quantum-Augmented Frequency-Spectral For Medical Visual Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.23899</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.23899v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Solving tough clinical questions that require both image and text understanding is still a major challenge in healthcare AI. In this work, we propose Q-FSRU, a new model that combines Frequency Spectrum Representation and Fusion (FSRU) with a method called Quantum Retrieval-Augmented Generation (Quantum RAG) for medical Visual Question Answering (VQA). The model takes in features from medical images and related text, then shifts them into the frequency domain using Fast Fourier Transform (FFT). This helps it focus on more meaningful data and filter out noise or less useful information. To improve accuracy and ensure that answers are based on real knowledge, we add a quantum inspired retrieval system. It fetches useful medical facts from external sources using quantum-based similarity techniques. These details are then merged with the frequency-based features for stronger reasoning. We evaluated our model using the VQA-RAD dataset, which includes real radiology images and questions. The results showed that Q-FSRU outperforms earlier models, especially on complex cases needing image text reasoning. The mix of frequency and quantum information improves both performance and explainability. Overall, this approach offers a promising way to build smart, clear, and helpful AI tools for doctors.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.23899v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rakesh Thakur, Yusra Tariq, Rakesh Chandra Joshi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ExGS: Extreme 3D Gaussian Compression with Diffusion Priors</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.24758</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.24758v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Neural scene representations, such as 3D Gaussian Splatting (3DGS), have enabled high-quality neural rendering; however, their large storage and transmission costs hinder deployment in resource-constrained environments. Existing compression methods either rely on costly optimization, which is slow and scene-specific, or adopt training-free pruning and quantization, which degrade rendering quality under high compression ratios. In contrast, recent data-driven approaches provide a promising direction to overcome this trade-off, enabling efficient compression while preserving high rendering quality.We introduce ExGS, a novel feed-forward framework that unifies Universal Gaussian Compression (UGC) with GaussPainter for Extreme 3DGS compression. UGC performs re-optimization-free pruning to aggressively reduce Gaussian primitives while retaining only essential information, whereas GaussPainter leverages powerful diffusion priors with mask-guided refinement to restore high-quality renderings from heavily pruned Gaussian scenes. Unlike conventional inpainting, GaussPainter not only fills in missing regions but also enhances visible pixels, yielding substantial improvements in degraded renderings.To ensure practicality, it adopts a lightweight VAE and a one-step diffusion design, enabling real-time restoration. Our framework can even achieve over 100X compression (reducing a typical 354.77 MB model to about 3.31 MB) while preserving fidelity and significantly improving image quality under challenging conditions. These results highlight the central role of diffusion priors in bridging the gap between extreme compression and high-quality neural rendering.Our code repository will be released at: https://github.com/chenttt2001/ExGS</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.24758v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiaqi Chen, Xinhao Ji, Yuanyuan Gao, Hao Li, Yuning Gong, Yifei Liu, Dan Xu, Zhihang Zhong, Dingwen Zhang, Xiao Sun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Causal-Adapter: Taming Text-to-Image Diffusion for Faithful Counterfactual Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.24798</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.24798v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We present Causal-Adapter, a modular framework that adapts frozen text-to-image diffusion backbones for counterfactual image generation. Our method enables causal interventions on target attributes, consistently propagating their effects to causal dependents without altering the core identity of the image. In contrast to prior approaches that rely on prompt engineering without explicit causal structure, Causal-Adapter leverages structural causal modeling augmented with two attribute regularization strategies: prompt-aligned injection, which aligns causal attributes with textual embeddings for precise semantic control, and a conditioned token contrastive loss to disentangle attribute factors and reduce spurious correlations. Causal-Adapter achieves state-of-the-art performance on both synthetic and real-world datasets, with up to 91% MAE reduction on Pendulum for accurate attribute control and 87% FID reduction on ADNI for high-fidelity MRI image generation. These results show that our approach enables robust, generalizable counterfactual editing with faithful attribute modification and strong identity preservation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.24798v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lei Tong, Zhihua Liu, Chaochao Lu, Dino Oglic, Tom Diethe, Philip Teare, Sotirios A. Tsaftaris, Chen Jin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YOLO-Based Defect Detection for Metal Sheets</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.25659</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.25659v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this paper, we propose a YOLO-based deep learning (DL) model for automatic defect detection to solve the time-consuming and labor-intensive tasks in industrial manufacturing. In our experiments, the images of metal sheets are used as the dataset for training the YOLO model to detect the defects on the surfaces and in the holes of metal sheets. However, the lack of metal sheet images significantly degrades the performance of detection accuracy. To address this issue, the ConSinGAN is used to generate a considerable amount of data. Four versions of the YOLO model (i.e., YOLOv3, v4, v7, and v9) are combined with the ConSinGAN for data augmentation. The proposed YOLOv9 model with ConSinGAN outperforms the other YOLO models with an accuracy of 91.3%, and a detection time of 146 ms. The proposed YOLOv9 model is integrated into manufacturing hardware and a supervisory control and data acquisition (SCADA) system to establish a practical automated optical inspection (AOI) system. Additionally, the proposed automated defect detection is easily applied to other components in industrial manufacturing.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.25659v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>eess.SP</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1109/IST63414.2024.10759237</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Proc. 2024 IEEE Int. Conf. Imaging Systems and Techniques (IST), Tokyo, Japan, Oct. 2024</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Po-Heng Chou, Chun-Chi Wang, Wei-Lung Mao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Less is More: Lean yet Powerful Vision-Language Model for Autonomous Driving</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.00060</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.00060v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this work, we reconceptualize autonomous driving as a generalized language and formulate the trajectory planning task as next waypoint prediction. We introduce Max-V1, a novel framework for one-stage end-to-end autonomous driving. Our framework presents a single-pass generation paradigm that aligns with the inherent sequentiality of driving. This approach leverages the generative capacity of the VLM (Vision-Language Model) to enable end-to-end trajectory prediction directly from front-view camera input. The efficacy of this method is underpinned by a principled supervision strategy derived from statistical modeling. This provides a well-defined learning objective, which makes the framework highly amenable to master complex driving policies through imitation learning from large-scale expert demonstrations. Empirically, our method achieves the state-of-the-art performance on the nuScenes dataset, delivers an overall improvement of over 30% compared to prior baselines. Furthermore, it exhibits superior generalization performance on cross-domain datasets acquired from diverse vehicles, demonstrating notable potential for cross-vehicle robustness and adaptability. Due to these empirical strengths, this work introduces a model enabling fundamental driving behaviors, laying the foundation for the development of more capable self-driving agents. Code will be available upon publication.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.00060v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sheng Yang, Tong Zhan, Guancheng Chen, Yanfeng Lu, Jian Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Equivariant Splitting: Self-supervised learning from incomplete data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.00929</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.00929v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Self-supervised learning for inverse problems allows to train a reconstruction network from noise and/or incomplete data alone. These methods have the potential of enabling learning-based solutions when obtaining ground-truth references for training is expensive or even impossible. In this paper, we propose a new self-supervised learning strategy devised for the challenging setting where measurements are observed via a single incomplete observation model. We introduce a new definition of equivariance in the context of reconstruction networks, and show that the combination of self-supervised splitting losses and equivariant reconstruction networks results in the same minimizer in expectation as the one of a supervised loss. Through a series of experiments on image inpainting, accelerated magnetic resonance imaging, and compressive sensing, we demonstrate that the proposed loss achieves state-of-the-art performance in settings with highly rank-deficient forward models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.00929v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Victor Sechaud, J\'er\'emy Scanvic, Quentin Barth\'elemy, Patrice Abry, Juli\'an Tachella</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VirDA: Reusing Backbone for Unsupervised Domain Adaptation with Visual Reprogramming</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.01660</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.01660v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Existing UDA pipelines fine-tune already well-trained backbone parameters for every new source-and-target pair, resulting in the number of training parameters and storage memory growing linearly with each new pair, and also preventing the reuse of these well-trained backbone parameters.
  Inspired by recent implications that existing backbones have textural biases, we propose making use of domain-specific textural bias for domain adaptation via visual reprogramming, namely VirDA. Instead of fine-tuning the full backbone, VirDA prepends a domain-specific visual reprogramming layer to the backbone. This layer produces visual prompts that act as an added textural bias to the input image, adapting its "style" to a target domain. To optimize these visual reprogramming layers, we use multiple objective functions that optimize the intra- and inter-domain distribution differences when domain-adapting visual prompts are applied. This process does not require modifying the backbone parameters, allowing the same backbone to be reused across different domains.
  We evaluate VirDA on Office-31 and obtain 92.8% mean accuracy with only 1.5M trainable parameters. VirDA surpasses PDA, the state-of-the-art parameter-efficient UDA baseline, by +1.6% accuracy while using just 46% of its parameters. Compared with full-backbone fine-tuning, VirDA outperforms CDTrans and FixBi by +0.2% and +1.4%, respectively, while requiring only 1.7% and 2.8% of their trainable parameters. Relative to the strongest current methods (PMTrans and TVT), VirDA uses ~1.7% of their parameters and trades off only 2.2% and 1.1% accuracy, respectively.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.01660v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Duy Nguyen, Dat Nguyen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UniVerse: Unleashing the Scene Prior of Video Diffusion Models for Robust Radiance Field Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.01669</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.01669v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper tackles the challenge of robust reconstruction, i.e., the task of reconstructing a 3D scene from a set of inconsistent multi-view images. Some recent works have attempted to simultaneously remove image inconsistencies and perform reconstruction by integrating image degradation modeling into neural 3D scene representations. However, these methods rely heavily on dense observations for robustly optimizing model parameters. To address this issue, we propose to decouple robust reconstruction into two subtasks: restoration and reconstruction, which naturally simplifies the optimization process. To this end, we introduce UniVerse, a unified framework for robust reconstruction based on a video diffusion model. Specifically, UniVerse first converts inconsistent images into initial videos, then uses a specially designed video diffusion model to restore them into consistent images, and finally reconstructs the 3D scenes from these restored images. Compared with case-by-case per-view degradation modeling, the diffusion model learns a general scene prior from large-scale data, making it applicable to diverse image inconsistencies. Extensive experiments on both synthetic and real-world datasets demonstrate the strong generalization capability and superior performance of our method in robust reconstruction. Moreover, UniVerse can control the style of the reconstructed 3D scene. Project page: https://jin-cao-tma.github.io/UniVerse.github.io/</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.01669v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jin Cao, Hongrui Wu, Ziyong Feng, Hujun Bao, Xiaowei Zhou, Sida Peng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pack and Force Your Memory: Long-form and Consistent Video Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.01784</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.01784v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Long-form video generation presents a dual challenge: models must capture long-range dependencies while preventing the error accumulation inherent in autoregressive decoding. To address these challenges, we make two contributions. First, for dynamic context modeling, we propose MemoryPack, a learnable context-retrieval mechanism that leverages both textual and image information as global guidance to jointly model short- and long-term dependencies, achieving minute-level temporal consistency. This design scales gracefully with video length, preserves computational efficiency, and maintains linear complexity. Second, to mitigate error accumulation, we introduce Direct Forcing, an efficient single-step approximating strategy that improves training-inference alignment and thereby curtails error propagation during inference. Together, MemoryPack and Direct Forcing substantially enhance the context consistency and reliability of long-form video generation, advancing the practical usability of autoregressive video models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.01784v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaofei Wu, Guozhen Zhang, Zhiyong Xu, Yuan Zhou, Qinglin Lu, Xuming He</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Addressing Representation Collapse in Vector Quantized Models with One Linear Layer</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.02038</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.02038v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Vector Quantization (VQ) is essential for discretizing continuous representations in unsupervised learning but suffers from representation collapse, causing low codebook utilization and limiting scalability. Existing solutions often rely on complex optimizations or reduce latent dimensionality, which compromises model capacity and fails to fully solve the problem. We identify the root cause as disjoint codebook optimization, where only a few code vectors are updated via gradient descent. To fix this, we propose \textbf{Sim}ple\textbf{VQ}, which reparameterizes code vectors through a learnable linear transformation layer over a latent basis, optimizing the \textit{entire linear space} rather than nearest \textit{individual code vectors}. Although the multiplication of two linear matrices is equivalent to applying a single linear layer, this simple approach effectively prevents collapse. Extensive experiments on image and audio tasks demonstrate that SimVQ improves codebook usage, is easy to implement, and generalizes well across modalities and architectures. The code is available at https://github.com/youngsheen/SimVQ.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.02038v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yongxin Zhu, Bocheng Li, Yifei Xin, Zhihua Xia, Linli Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WaveNet-SF: A Hybrid Network for Retinal Disease Detection Based on Wavelet Transform in Spatial-Frequency Domain</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.11854</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.11854v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Retinal diseases are a leading cause of vision impairment and blindness, with timely diagnosis being critical for effective treatment. Optical Coherence Tomography (OCT) has become a standard imaging modality for retinal disease diagnosis, but OCT images often suffer from issues such as speckle noise, complex lesion shapes, and varying lesion sizes, making interpretation challenging. In this paper, we propose a novel framework, WaveNet-SF, to enhance retinal disease detection by integrating the spatial-domain and frequency-domain learning. The framework utilizes wavelet transforms to decompose OCT images into low- and high-frequency components, enabling the model to extract both global structural features and fine-grained details. To improve lesion detection, we introduce a Multi-Scale Wavelet Spatial Attention (MSW-SA) module, which enhances the model's focus on regions of interest at multiple scales. Additionally, a High-Frequency Feature Compensation (HFFC) block is incorporated to recover edge information lost during wavelet decomposition, suppress noise, and preserve fine details crucial for lesion detection. Our approach achieves state-of-the-art (SOTA) classification accuracies of 97.82% and 99.58% on the OCT-C8 and OCT2017 datasets, respectively, surpassing existing methods. These results demonstrate the efficacy of WaveNet-SF in addressing the challenges of OCT image analysis and its potential as a powerful tool for retinal disease diagnosis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.11854v3</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jilan Cheng, Guoli Long, Zeyu Zhang, Zhenjia Qi, Hanyu Wang, Libin Lu, Shuihua Wang, Yudong Zhang, Jin Hong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S-Graphs 2.0 -- A Hierarchical-Semantic Optimization and Loop Closure for SLAM</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.18044</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.18044v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The hierarchical structure of 3D scene graphs shows a high relevance for representations purposes, as it fits common patterns from man-made environments. But, additionally, the semantic and geometric information in such hierarchical representations could be leveraged to speed up the optimization and management of map elements and robot poses.
  In this direction, we present our work Situational Graphs 2.0 (S-Graphs 2.0), which leverages the hierarchical structure of indoor scenes for efficient data management and optimization. Our algorithm begins by constructing a situational graph that represents the environment into four layers: Keyframes, Walls, Rooms, and Floors. Our first novelty lies in the front-end, which includes a floor detection module capable of identifying stairways and assigning floor-level semantic relations to the underlying layers. Floor-level semantics allows us to propose a floor-based loop closure strategy, that effectively rejects false positive closures that typically appear due to aliasing between different floors of a building. Our second novelty lies in leveraging our representation hierarchy in the optimization. Our proposal consists of: (1) local optimization over a window of recent keyframes and their connected components across the four representation layers, (2) floor-level global optimization, which focuses only on keyframes and their connections within the current floor during loop closures, and (3) room-level local optimization, marginalizing redundant keyframes that share observations within the room, which reduces the computational footprint. We validate our algorithm extensively in different real multi-floor environments. Our approach shows state-of-art-art accuracy metrics in large-scale multi-floor environments, estimating hierarchical representations up to 10x faster, in average, than competing baselines</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.18044v3</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hriday Bavle, Jose Luis Sanchez-Lopez, Muhammad Shaheer, Javier Civera, Holger Voos</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning High-Fidelity Robot Self-Model with Articulated 3D Gaussian Splatting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.05398</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.05398v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Self-modeling enables robots to build task-agnostic models of their morphology and kinematics based on data that can be automatically collected, with minimal human intervention and prior information, thereby enhancing machine intelligence. Recent research has highlighted the potential of data-driven technology in modeling the morphology and kinematics of robots. However, existing self-modeling methods suffer from either low modeling quality or excessive data acquisition costs. Beyond morphology and kinematics, texture is also a crucial component of robots, which is challenging to model and remains unexplored. In this work, a high-quality, texture-aware, and link-level method is proposed for robot self-modeling. We utilize three-dimensional (3D) Gaussians to represent the static morphology and texture of robots, and cluster the 3D Gaussians to construct neural ellipsoid bones, whose deformations are controlled by the transformation matrices generated by a kinematic neural network. The 3D Gaussians and kinematic neural network are trained using data pairs composed of joint angles, camera parameters and multi-view images without depth information. By feeding the kinematic neural network with joint angles, we can utilize the well-trained model to describe the corresponding morphology, kinematics and texture of robots at the link level, and render robot images from different perspectives with the aid of 3D Gaussian splatting. Furthermore, we demonstrate that the established model can be exploited to perform downstream tasks such as motion planning and inverse kinematics.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.05398v2</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kejun Hu, Peng Yu, Ning Tan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Benchmarking Study of Vision-based Robotic Grasping Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.11163</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.11163v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We present a benchmarking study of vision-based robotic grasping algorithms with distinct approaches, and provide a comparative analysis. In particular, we compare two machine-learning-based and two analytical algorithms using an existing benchmarking protocol from the literature and determine the algorithm's strengths and weaknesses under different experimental conditions. These conditions include variations in lighting, background textures, cameras with different noise levels, and grippers. We also run analogous experiments in simulations and with real robots and present the discrepancies. Some experiments are also run in two different laboratories using same protocols to further analyze the repeatability of our results. We believe that this study, comprising 5040 experiments, provides important insights into the role and challenges of systematic experimentation in robotic manipulation, and guides the development of new algorithms by considering the factors that could impact the performance. The experiment recordings and our benchmarking software are publicly available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.11163v2</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bharath K Rameshbabu, Sumukh S Balakrishna, Brian Flynn, Vinarak Kapoor, Adam Norton, Holly Yanco, Berk Calli</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CostFilter-AD: Enhancing Anomaly Detection through Matching Cost Filtering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01476</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01476v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Unsupervised anomaly detection (UAD) seeks to localize the anomaly mask of an input image with respect to normal samples. Either by reconstructing normal counterparts (reconstruction-based) or by learning an image feature embedding space (embedding-based), existing approaches fundamentally rely on image-level or feature-level matching to derive anomaly scores. Often, such a matching process is inaccurate yet overlooked, leading to sub-optimal detection. To address this issue, we introduce the concept of cost filtering, borrowed from classical matching tasks, such as depth and flow estimation, into the UAD problem. We call this approach {\em CostFilter-AD}. Specifically, we first construct a matching cost volume between the input and normal samples, comprising two spatial dimensions and one matching dimension that encodes potential matches. To refine this, we propose a cost volume filtering network, guided by the input observation as an attention query across multiple feature layers, which effectively suppresses matching noise while preserving edge structures and capturing subtle anomalies. Designed as a generic post-processing plug-in, CostFilter-AD can be integrated with either reconstruction-based or embedding-based methods. Extensive experiments on MVTec-AD and VisA benchmarks validate the generic benefits of CostFilter-AD for both single- and multi-class UAD tasks. Code and models will be released at https://github.com/ZHE-SAPI/CostFilter-AD.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01476v4</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhe Zhang, Mingxiu Cai, Hanxiao Wang, Gaochang Wu, Tianyou Chai, Xiatian Zhu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generative Modeling of Weights: Generalization or Memorization?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.07998</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.07998v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Generative models have recently been explored for synthesizing neural network weights. These approaches take neural network checkpoints as training data and aim to generate high-performing weights during inference. In this work, we examine four representative, well-known methods on their ability to generate novel model weights, i.e., weights that are different from the checkpoints seen during training. Contrary to claims in prior work, we find that these methods synthesize weights largely by memorization: they produce either replicas, or, at best, simple interpolations of the training checkpoints. Moreover, they fail to outperform simple baselines, such as adding noise to the weights or taking a simple weight ensemble, in obtaining different and simultaneously high-performing models. Our further analysis suggests that this memorization might result from limited data, overparameterized models, and the underuse of structural priors specific to weight data. These findings highlight the need for more careful design and rigorous evaluation of generative models when applied to new domains. Our code is available at https://github.com/boyazeng/weight_memorization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.07998v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Boya Zeng, Yida Yin, Zhiqiu Xu, Zhuang Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robust Pan-Cancer Mitotic Figure Detection with YOLOv12</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.02593</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.02593v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Mitotic figures represent a key histoprognostic feature in tumor pathology, providing crucial insights into tumor aggressiveness and proliferation. However, their identification remains challenging, subject to significant inter-observer variability, even among experienced pathologists. To address this issue, the MItosis DOmain Generalization (MIDOG) 2025 challenge marks the third edition of an international competition aiming to develop robust mitosis detection algorithms. In this paper, we present a mitotic figure detection approach based on the state-of-the-art YOLOv12 object detection architecture. Our method achieved an F1-score of 0.801 on the preliminary test set (hotspots only) and ranked second on the final test leaderboard with an F1-score of 0.7216 across complex and heterogeneous whole-slide regions, without relying on external data.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.02593v3</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rapha\"el Bourgade, Guillaume Balezo, Thomas Walter</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MCGS-SLAM: A Multi-Camera SLAM Framework Using Gaussian Splatting for High-Fidelity Mapping</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14191</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14191v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Recent progress in dense SLAM has primarily targeted monocular setups, often at the expense of robustness and geometric coverage. We present MCGS-SLAM, the first purely RGB-based multi-camera SLAM system built on 3D Gaussian Splatting (3DGS). Unlike prior methods relying on sparse maps or inertial data, MCGS-SLAM fuses dense RGB inputs from multiple viewpoints into a unified, continuously optimized Gaussian map. A multi-camera bundle adjustment (MCBA) jointly refines poses and depths via dense photometric and geometric residuals, while a scale consistency module enforces metric alignment across views using low-rank priors. The system supports RGB input and maintains real-time performance at large scale. Experiments on synthetic and real-world datasets show that MCGS-SLAM consistently yields accurate trajectories and photorealistic reconstructions, usually outperforming monocular baselines. Notably, the wide field of view from multi-camera input enables reconstruction of side-view regions that monocular setups miss, critical for safe autonomous operation. These results highlight the promise of multi-camera Gaussian Splatting SLAM for high-fidelity mapping in robotics and autonomous driving.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14191v2</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhihao Cao, Hanyu Wu, Li Wa Tang, Zizhou Luo, Zihan Zhu, Wei Zhang, Marc Pollefeys, Martin R. Oswald</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultra-Efficient Decoding for End-to-End Neural Compression and Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.01407</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.01407v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Image compression and reconstruction are crucial for various digital applications. While contemporary neural compression methods achieve impressive compression rates, the adoption of such technology has been largely hindered by the complexity and large computational costs of the convolution-based decoders during data reconstruction. To address the decoder bottleneck in neural compression, we develop a new compression-reconstruction framework based on incorporating low-rank representation in an autoencoder with vector quantization. We demonstrated that performing a series of computationally efficient low-rank operations on the learned latent representation of images can efficiently reconstruct the data with high quality. Our approach dramatically reduces the computational overhead in the decoding phase of neural compression/reconstruction, essentially eliminating the decoder compute bottleneck while maintaining high fidelity of image outputs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.01407v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ethan G. Rogers, Cheng Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
