<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL</link>
    <description>cs.CL updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 05:00:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Sunday</day>
      <day>Saturday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>ExpertGenQA: Open-ended QA generation in Specialized Domains</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.02948</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.02948v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Generating high-quality question-answer pairs for specialized technical domains remains challenging, with existing approaches facing a tradeoff between leveraging expert examples and achieving topical diversity. We present ExpertGenQA, a protocol that combines few-shot learning with structured topic and style categorization to generate comprehensive domain-specific QA pairs. Using U.S. Federal Railroad Administration documents as a test bed, we demonstrate that ExpertGenQA achieves twice the efficiency of baseline few-shot approaches while maintaining $94.4\%$ topic coverage. Through systematic evaluation, we show that current LLM-based judges and reward models exhibit strong bias toward superficial writing styles rather than content quality. Our analysis using Bloom's Taxonomy reveals that ExpertGenQA better preserves the cognitive complexity distribution of expert-written questions compared to template-based approaches. When used to train retrieval models, our generated queries improve top-1 accuracy by $13.02\%$ over baseline performance, demonstrating their effectiveness for downstream applications in technical domains.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.02948v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haz Sameen Shahgir, Chansong Lim, Jia Chen, Evangelos E. Papalexakis, Yue Dong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>InfiniSST: Simultaneous Translation of Unbounded Speech with Large Language Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.02969</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.02969v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Simultaneous translation of unbounded streaming speech remains a challenging problem due to the need for effectively processing the history speech context and past translations so that quality and latency, including computation overhead, can be balanced. Most prior works assume pre-segmented speech, limiting their real-world applicability. In this paper, we propose InfiniSST, a novel approach that formulates SST as a multi-turn dialogue task, enabling seamless translation of unbounded speech. We construct translation trajectories and robust segments from MuST-C with multi-latency augmentation during training and develop a key-value (KV) cache management strategy to facilitate efficient inference. Experiments on MuST-C En-Es, En-De, and En-Zh demonstrate that InfiniSST reduces computation-aware latency by 0.5 to 1 second while maintaining the same translation quality compared to baselines. Ablation studies further validate the contributions of our data construction and cache management strategy. We release the code at https://github.com/LeiLiLab/InfiniSST</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.02969v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Siqi Ouyang, Xi Xu, Lei Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multilingual Relative Clause Attachment Ambiguity Resolution in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.02971</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.02971v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This study examines how large language models (LLMs) resolve relative clause (RC) attachment ambiguities and compares their performance to human sentence processing. Focusing on two linguistic factors, namely the length of RCs and the syntactic position of complex determiner phrases (DPs), we assess whether LLMs can achieve human-like interpretations amid the complexities of language. In this study, we evaluated several LLMs, including Claude, Gemini and Llama, in multiple languages: English, Spanish, French, German, Japanese, and Korean. While these models performed well in Indo-European languages (English, Spanish, French, and German), they encountered difficulties in Asian languages (Japanese and Korean), often defaulting to incorrect English translations. The findings underscore the variability in LLMs' handling of linguistic ambiguities and highlight the need for model improvements, particularly for non-European languages. This research informs future enhancements in LLM design to improve accuracy and human-like processing in diverse linguistic environments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.02971v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>So Young Lee, Russell Scheinberg, Amber Shore, Ameeta Agrawal</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LINGOLY-TOO: Disentangling Memorisation from Reasoning with Linguistic Templatisation and Orthographic Obfuscation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.02972</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.02972v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Effective evaluation of the reasoning capabilities of large language models (LLMs) are susceptible to overestimation due to data exposure of evaluation benchmarks. We introduce a framework for producing linguistic reasoning problems that reduces the effect of memorisation in model performance estimates and apply this framework to develop LINGOLY-TOO, a challenging evaluation benchmark for linguistic reasoning. By developing orthographic templates, we dynamically obfuscate the writing systems of real languages to generate numerous question variations. These variations preserve the reasoning steps required for each solution while reducing the likelihood of specific problem instances appearing in model training data. Our experiments demonstrate that frontier models, including OpenAI o1-preview and DeepSeem R1, struggle with advanced reasoning. Our analysis also shows that LLMs exhibit noticeable variance in accuracy across permutations of the same problem, and on average perform better on questions appearing in their original orthography. Our findings highlight the opaque nature of response generation in LLMs and provide evidence that prior data exposure contributes to overestimating the reasoning capabilities of frontier models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.02972v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jude Khouja, Karolina Korgul, Simi Hellsten, Lingyi Yang, Vlad Neacs, Harry Mayne, Ryan Kearns, Andrew Bean, Adam Mahdi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effectively Steer LLM To Follow Preference via Building Confident Directions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.02989</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.02989v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Having an LLM that aligns with human preferences is essential for accommodating individual needs, such as maintaining writing style or generating specific topics of interest. The majority of current alignment methods rely on fine-tuning or prompting, which can be either costly or difficult to control. Model steering algorithms, which modify the model output by constructing specific steering directions, are typically easy to implement and optimization-free. However, their capabilities are typically limited to steering the model into one of the two directions (i.e., bidirectional steering), and there has been no theoretical understanding to guarantee their performance. In this work, we propose a theoretical framework to understand and quantify the model steering methods. Inspired by the framework, we propose a confident direction steering method (CONFST) that steers LLMs via modifying their activations at inference time. More specifically, CONFST builds a confident direction that is closely aligned with users' preferences, and this direction is then added to the activations of the LLMs to effectively steer the model output. Our approach offers three key advantages over popular bidirectional model steering methods: 1) It is more powerful, since multiple (i.e. more than two) users' preferences can be aligned simultaneously; 2) It is simple to implement, since there is no need to determine which layer to add the steering vector to; 3) No explicit user instruction is required. We validate our method on GPT-2 XL (1.5B), Mistral (7B) and Gemma-it (9B) models for tasks that require shifting the output of LLMs across various topics and styles, achieving superior performance over competing methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.02989v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bingqing Song, Boran Han, Shuai Zhang, Hao Wang, Haoyang Fang, Bonan Min, Yuyang Wang, Mingyi Hong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zero-Shot Multi-Label Classification of Bangla Documents: Large Decoders Vs. Classic Encoders</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.02993</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.02993v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Bangla, a language spoken by over 300 million native speakers and ranked as the sixth most spoken language worldwide, presents unique challenges in natural language processing (NLP) due to its complex morphological characteristics and limited resources. While recent Large Decoder Based models (LLMs), such as GPT, LLaMA, and DeepSeek, have demonstrated excellent performance across many NLP tasks, their effectiveness in Bangla remains largely unexplored. In this paper, we establish the first benchmark comparing decoder-based LLMs with classic encoder-based models for Zero-Shot Multi-Label Classification (Zero-Shot-MLC) task in Bangla. Our evaluation of 32 state-of-the-art models reveals that, existing so-called powerful encoders and decoders still struggle to achieve high accuracy on the Bangla Zero-Shot-MLC task, suggesting a need for more research and resources for Bangla NLP.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.02993v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Souvika Sarkar, Md. Najib Hasan, Santu Karmaker</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will I Get Hate Speech Predicting the Volume of Abusive Replies before Posting in Social Media</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03005</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03005v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Despite the growing body of research tackling offensive language in social media, this research is predominantly reactive, determining if content already posted in social media is abusive. There is a gap in predictive approaches, which we address in our study by enabling to predict the volume of abusive replies a tweet will receive after being posted. We formulate the problem from the perspective of a social media user asking: ``if I post a certain message on social media, is it possible to predict the volume of abusive replies it might receive?'' We look at four types of features, namely text, text metadata, tweet metadata, and account features, which also help us understand the extent to which the user or the content helps predict the number of abusive replies. This, in turn, helps us develop a model to support social media users in finding the best way to post content. One of our objectives is also to determine the extent to which the volume of abusive replies that a tweet will get are motivated by the content of the tweet or by the identity of the user posting it. Our study finds that one can build a model that performs competitively by developing a comprehensive set of features derived from the content of the message that is going to be posted. In addition, our study suggests that features derived from the user's identity do not impact model performance, hence suggesting that it is especially the content of a post that triggers abusive replies rather than who the user is.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03005v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Raneem Alharthia, Rajwa Alharthib, Ravi Shekharc, Aiqi Jiangd, Arkaitz Zubiagaa</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Model to Train them All: Hierarchical Self-Distillation for Enhanced Early Layer Embeddings</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03008</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03008v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Deploying language models often requires handling model size vs. performance trade-offs to satisfy downstream latency constraints while preserving the model's usefulness. Model distillation is commonly employed to reduce model size while maintaining acceptable performance. However, distillation can be inefficient since it involves multiple training steps. In this work, we introduce MODULARSTARENCODER, a modular multi-exit encoder with 1B parameters, useful for multiple tasks within the scope of code retrieval. MODULARSTARENCODER is trained with a novel self-distillation mechanism that significantly improves lower-layer representations-allowing different portions of the model to be used while still maintaining a good trade-off in terms of performance. Our architecture focuses on enhancing text-to-code and code-to-code search by systematically capturing syntactic and semantic structures across multiple levels of representation. Specific encoder layers are targeted as exit heads, allowing higher layers to guide earlier layers during training. This self-distillation effect improves intermediate representations, increasing retrieval recall at no extra training cost. In addition to the multi-exit scheme, our approach integrates a repository-level contextual loss that maximally utilizes the training context window, further enhancing the learned representations. We also release a new dataset constructed via code translation, seamlessly expanding traditional text-to-code benchmarks with code-to-code pairs across diverse programming languages. Experimental results highlight the benefits of self-distillation through multi-exit supervision.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03008v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.PL</category>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Andrea Gurioli, Federico Pennino, Jo\~ao Monteiro, Maurizio Gabbrielli</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAFE: A Sparse Autoencoder-Based Framework for Robust Query Enrichment and Hallucination Mitigation in LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03032</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03032v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Despite the state-of-the-art performance of Large Language Models (LLMs), these models often suffer from hallucinations, which can undermine their performance in critical applications. In this work, we propose SAFE, a novel method for detecting and mitigating hallucinations by leveraging Sparse Autoencoders (SAEs). While hallucination detection techniques and SAEs have been explored independently, their synergistic application in a comprehensive system, particularly for hallucination-aware query enrichment, has not been fully investigated. To validate the effectiveness of SAFE, we evaluate it on two models with available SAEs across three diverse cross-domain datasets designed to assess hallucination problems. Empirical results demonstrate that SAFE consistently improves query generation accuracy and mitigates hallucinations across all datasets, achieving accuracy improvements of up to 29.45%.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03032v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Samir Abdaljalil, Filippo Pallucchini, Andrea Seveso, Hasan Kurban, Fabio Mercorio, Erchin Serpedin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAGE: Steering and Refining Dialog Generation with State-Action Augmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03040</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03040v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent advances in large language models have demonstrated impressive capabilities in task-oriented applications, yet building emotionally intelligent chatbots that can engage in natural, strategic conversations remains a challenge. We present a novel approach called SAGE that uses latent variables to control long-horizon behavior in dialogue generation. At the core of our method is the State-Action Chain (SAC), which augments standard language model fine-tuning by introducing latent variables that encapsulate emotional states and conversational strategies between dialogue turns. During inference, these variables are generated before each response, enabling coarse-grained control over dialogue progression while maintaining natural interaction patterns. We also introduce a self-improvement pipeline that leverages dialogue tree search, LLM-based reward modeling, and targeted fine-tuning to optimize conversational trajectories. Our experimental results show that models trained with this approach demonstrate improved performance in emotional intelligence metrics while maintaining strong capabilities on LLM benchmarks. The discrete nature of our latent variables facilitates search-based strategies and provides a foundation for future applications of reinforcement learning to dialogue systems, where learning can occur at the state level rather than the token level.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03040v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yizhe Zhang, Navdeep Jaitly</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>QE4PE: Word-level Quality Estimation for Human Post-Editing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03044</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03044v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Word-level quality estimation (QE) detects erroneous spans in machine translations, which can direct and facilitate human post-editing. While the accuracy of word-level QE systems has been assessed extensively, their usability and downstream influence on the speed, quality and editing choices of human post-editing remain understudied. Our QE4PE study investigates the impact of word-level QE on machine translation (MT) post-editing in a realistic setting involving 42 professional post-editors across two translation directions. We compare four error-span highlight modalities, including supervised and uncertainty-based word-level QE methods, for identifying potential errors in the outputs of a state-of-the-art neural MT model. Post-editing effort and productivity are estimated by behavioral logs, while quality improvements are assessed by word- and segment-level human annotation. We find that domain, language and editors' speed are critical factors in determining highlights' effectiveness, with modest differences between human-made and automated QE highlights underlining a gap between accuracy and usability in professional workflows.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03044v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gabriele Sarti, Vil\'em Zouhar, Grzegorz Chrupa{\l}a, Ana Guerberof-Arenas, Malvina Nissim, Arianna Bisazza</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semi-Supervised In-Context Learning: A Baseline Study</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03062</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03062v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Most existing work in data selection for In-Context Learning (ICL) has focused on constructing demonstrations from ground truth annotations, with limited attention given to selecting reliable self-generated annotations. In this work, we propose a three-step semi-supervised ICL framework: annotation generation, demonstration selection, and semi-supervised inference. Our baseline, Naive-SemiICL, which prompts select high-confidence self-generated demonstrations for ICL prompting, outperforms a 16-shot baseline by an average of 9.94% across 16 datasets. We further introduce IterPSD, an annotation approach that refines pseudo-demonstrations iteratively, achieving up to 6.8% additional gains in classification tasks. Lastly, we reveal a scaling law for semi-supervised ICL, where models achieve optimal performance with over 1,000 demonstrations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03062v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhengyao Gu, Henry Peng Zou, Yankai Chen, Aiwei Liu, Weizhi Zhang, Philip S. Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving LLM-as-a-Judge Inference with the Judgment Distribution</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03064</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03064v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Using language models to scalably approximate human preferences on text quality (LLM-as-a-judge) has become a standard practice applicable to many tasks. A judgment is often extracted from the judge's textual output alone, typically with greedy decoding. However, LLM judges naturally provide distributions over judgment tokens, inviting a breadth of inference methods for extracting fine-grained preferences. We find that taking the mean of the judgment distribution consistently outperforms taking the mode (i.e. greedy decoding) in all evaluation settings (i.e. pointwise, pairwise, and listwise). We further explore novel methods of deriving preferences from judgment distributions, and find that methods incorporating risk aversion often improve performance. Lastly, we analyze LLM-as-a-judge paired with chain-of-thought (CoT) prompting, showing that CoT can collapse the spread of the judgment distribution, often harming performance. Our findings suggest leveraging distributional output can improve LLM-as-a-judge, as opposed to using the text interface alone.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03064v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Victor Wang, Michael J. Q. Zhang, Eunsol Choi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MuCo-KGC: Multi-Context-Aware Knowledge Graph Completion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03091</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03091v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Knowledge graph completion (KGC) seeks to predict missing entities (e.g., heads or tails) or relationships in knowledge graphs (KGs), which often contain incomplete data. Traditional embedding-based methods, such as TransE and ComplEx, have improved tail entity prediction but struggle to generalize to unseen entities during testing. Textual-based models mitigate this issue by leveraging additional semantic context; however, their reliance on negative triplet sampling introduces high computational overhead, semantic inconsistencies, and data imbalance. Recent approaches, like KG-BERT, show promise but depend heavily on entity descriptions, which are often unavailable in KGs. Critically, existing methods overlook valuable structural information in the KG related to the entities and relationships. To address these challenges, we propose Multi-Context-Aware Knowledge Graph Completion (MuCo-KGC), a novel model that utilizes contextual information from linked entities and relations within the graph to predict tail entities. MuCo-KGC eliminates the need for entity descriptions and negative triplet sampling, significantly reducing computational complexity while enhancing performance. Our experiments on standard datasets, including FB15k-237, WN18RR, CoDEx-S, and CoDEx-M, demonstrate that MuCo-KGC outperforms state-of-the-art methods on three datasets. Notably, MuCo-KGC improves MRR on WN18RR, and CoDEx-S and CoDEx-M datasets by $1.63\%$, and $3.77\%$ and $20.15\%$ respectively, demonstrating its effectiveness for KGC tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03091v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haji Gul, Ajaz Ahmad Bhat, Abdul Ghani Haji Naim</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring Decoding: Mitigating Hallucination via Evaluating the Factuality of Partial Response during Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03106</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03106v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: While large language models have demonstrated exceptional performance across a wide range of tasks, they remain susceptible to hallucinations -- generating plausible yet factually incorrect contents. Existing methods to mitigating such risk often rely on sampling multiple full-length generations, which introduces significant response latency and becomes ineffective when the model consistently produces hallucinated outputs with high confidence. To address these limitations, we introduce Monitoring Decoding (MD), a novel framework that dynamically monitors the generation process and selectively applies in-process interventions, focusing on revising crucial tokens responsible for hallucinations. Instead of waiting until completion of multiple full-length generations, we identify hallucination-prone tokens during generation using a monitor function, and further refine these tokens through a tree-based decoding strategy. This approach ensures an enhanced factual accuracy and coherence in the generated output while maintaining efficiency. Experimental results demonstrate that MD consistently outperforms self-consistency-based approaches in both effectiveness and efficiency, achieving higher factual accuracy while significantly reducing computational overhead.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03106v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yurui Chang, Bochuan Cao, Lu Lin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>External Reliable Information-enhanced Multimodal Contrastive Learning for Fake News Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03107</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03107v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: With the rapid development of the Internet, the information dissemination paradigm has changed and the efficiency has been improved greatly. While this also brings the quick spread of fake news and leads to negative impacts on cyberspace. Currently, the information presentation formats have evolved gradually, with the news formats shifting from texts to multimodal contents. As a result, detecting multimodal fake news has become one of the research hotspots. However, multimodal fake news detection research field still faces two main challenges: the inability to fully and effectively utilize multimodal information for detection, and the low credibility or static nature of the introduced external information, which limits dynamic updates. To bridge the gaps, we propose ERIC-FND, an external reliable information-enhanced multimodal contrastive learning framework for fake news detection. ERIC-FND strengthens the representation of news contents by entity-enriched external information enhancement method. It also enriches the multimodal news information via multimodal semantic interaction method where the multimodal constrative learning is employed to make different modality representations learn from each other. Moreover, an adaptive fusion method is taken to integrate the news representations from different dimensions for the eventual classification. Experiments are done on two commonly used datasets in different languages, X (Twitter) and Weibo. Experiment results demonstrate that our proposed model ERIC-FND outperforms existing state-of-the-art fake news detection methods under the same settings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03107v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Biwei Cao, Qihang Wu, Jiuxin Cao, Bo Liu, Jie Gui</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Devil Is in the Details: Tackling Unimodal Spurious Correlations for Generalizable Multimodal Reward Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03122</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03122v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Multimodal Reward Models (MM-RMs) are crucial for aligning Large Language Models (LLMs) with human preferences, particularly as LLMs increasingly interact with multimodal data. However, we find that MM-RMs trained on existing datasets often struggle to generalize to out-of-distribution data due to their reliance on unimodal spurious correlations, primarily text-only shortcuts within the training distribution, which prevents them from leveraging true multimodal reward functions. To address this, we introduce a Shortcut-aware MM-RM learning algorithm that mitigates this issue by dynamically reweighting training samples, shifting the distribution toward better multimodal understanding, and reducing dependence on unimodal spurious correlations. Our experiments demonstrate significant improvements in generalization, downstream task performance, and scalability, establishing a more robust framework for multimodal reward modeling.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03122v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zichao Li, Xueru Wen, Jie Lou, Yuqiu Ji, Yaojie Lu, Xianpei Han, Debing Zhang, Le Sun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DSVD: Dynamic Self-Verify Decoding for Faithful Generation in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03149</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03149v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The reliability of large language models remains a critical challenge, particularly due to their susceptibility to hallucinations and factual inaccuracies during text generation. Existing solutions either underutilize models' self-correction with preemptive strategies or use costly post-hoc verification. To further explore the potential of real-time self-verification and correction, we present Dynamic Self-Verify Decoding (DSVD), a novel decoding framework that enhances generation reliability through real-time hallucination detection and efficient error correction. DSVD integrates two key components: (1) parallel self-verification architecture for continuous quality assessment, (2) dynamic rollback mechanism for targeted error recovery. Extensive experiments across five benchmarks demonstrate DSVD's effectiveness, achieving significant improvement in truthfulness (Quesetion-Answering) and factual accuracy (FActScore). Results show the DSVD can be further incorporated with existing faithful decoding methods to achieve stronger performance. Our work establishes that real-time self-verification during generation offers a viable path toward more trustworthy language models without sacrificing practical deployability.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03149v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>YiQiu Guo, Yuchen Yang, Zhe Chen, Pingjie Wang, Yusheng Liao, Ya Zhang, Yanfeng Wang, Yu Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intermediate-Task Transfer Learning: Leveraging Sarcasm Detection for Stance Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03172</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03172v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Stance Detection (SD) on social media has emerged as a prominent area of interest with implications for social business and political applications thereby garnering escalating research attention within NLP. The inherent subtlety and complexity of texts procured from online platforms pose challenges for SD algorithms in accurately discerning the authors stance. Mostly the inclusion of sarcastic and figurative language drastically impacts the performance of SD models. This paper addresses this by employing sarcasm detection intermediate-task transfer learning tailored for SD. The proposed methodology involves the finetuning of BERT and RoBERTa and the concatenation of convolutional BiLSTM and dense layers. Rigorous experiments are conducted on publicly available datasets to evaluate our transfer-learning framework. The performance of the approach is assessed against various State-Of-The-Art baselines for SD providing empirical evidence of its effectiveness. Notably our model outperforms the best SOTA models even prior to sarcasm-detection pretraining. The integration of sarcasm knowledge into the model proves instrumental in mitigating misclassifications of sarcastic textual elements in SD. Our model accurately predicts 85% of texts that were previously misclassified by the model without sarcasm-detection pretraining thereby amplifying the average F1-score of the model. Our experiments also revealed that the success of the transfer-learning framework is contingent upon the correlation of lexical attributes between the intermediate task and the target task. This study represents the first exploration of sarcasm detection as an intermediate transfer-learning task in the context of SD and simultaneously uses the concatenation of BERT or RoBERTa with other deep-learning techniques establishing the proposed approach as a foundational baseline for future research endeavors in this domain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03172v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gibson Nkhata, Susan Gauch</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing Speech Technologies for Australian Aboriginal English: Opportunities, Risks and Participation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03186</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03186v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In Australia, post-contact language varieties, including creoles and local varieties of international languages, emerged as a result of forced contact between Indigenous communities and English speakers. These contact varieties are widely used, yet are poorly supported by language technologies. This gap presents barriers to participation in civil and economic society for Indigenous communities using these varieties, and reproduces minoritisation of contemporary Indigenous sociolinguistic identities. This paper concerns three questions regarding this context. First, can speech technologies support speakers of Australian Aboriginal English, a local indigenised variety of English? Second, what risks are inherent in such a project? Third, what technology development practices are appropriate for this context, and how can researchers integrate meaningful community participation in order to mitigate risks? We argue that opportunities do exist -- as well as risks -- and demonstrate this through a case study exploring design practices in a real-world project aiming to improve speech technologies for Australian Aboriginal English. We discuss how we integrated culturally appropriate and participatory processes throughout the project. We call for increased support for languages used by Indigenous communities, including contact varieties, which provide practical economic and socio-cultural benefits, provided that participatory and culturally safe practices are enacted.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03186v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ben Hutchinson, Celeste Rodr\'iguez Louro, Glenys Collard, Ned Cooper</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structured Outputs Enable General-Purpose LLMs to be Medical Experts</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03194</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03194v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Medical question-answering (QA) is a critical task for evaluating how effectively large language models (LLMs) encode clinical knowledge and assessing their potential applications in medicine. Despite showing promise on multiple-choice tests, LLMs frequently struggle with open-ended medical questions, producing responses with dangerous hallucinations or lacking comprehensive coverage of critical aspects. Existing approaches attempt to address these challenges through domain-specific fine-tuning, but this proves resource-intensive and difficult to scale across models. To improve the comprehensiveness and factuality of medical responses, we propose a novel approach utilizing structured medical reasoning. Our method guides LLMs through an seven-step cognitive process inspired by clinical diagnosis, enabling more accurate and complete answers without additional training. Experiments on the MedLFQA benchmark demonstrate that our approach achieves the highest Factuality Score of 85.8, surpassing fine-tuned models. Notably, this improvement transfers to smaller models, highlighting the method's efficiency and scalability. Our code and datasets are available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03194v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Guangfu Guo, Kai Zhang, Bryan Hoo, Yujun Cai, Xiaoqian Lu, Nanyun Peng, Yiwei Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Robust Universal Information Extraction: Benchmark, Evaluation, and Solution</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03201</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03201v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this paper, we aim to enhance the robustness of Universal Information Extraction (UIE) by introducing a new benchmark dataset, a comprehensive evaluation, and a feasible solution. Existing robust benchmark datasets have two key limitations: 1) They generate only a limited range of perturbations for a single Information Extraction (IE) task, which fails to evaluate the robustness of UIE models effectively; 2) They rely on small models or handcrafted rules to generate perturbations, often resulting in unnatural adversarial examples. Considering the powerful generation capabilities of Large Language Models (LLMs), we introduce a new benchmark dataset for Robust UIE, called RUIE-Bench, which utilizes LLMs to generate more diverse and realistic perturbations across different IE tasks. Based on this dataset, we comprehensively evaluate existing UIE models and reveal that both LLM-based models and other models suffer from significant performance drops. To improve robustness and reduce training costs, we propose a data-augmentation solution that dynamically selects hard samples for iterative training based on the model's inference loss. Experimental results show that training with only \textbf{15\%} of the data leads to an average \textbf{7.5\%} relative performance improvement across three IE tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03201v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jizhao Zhu, Akang Shi, Zixuan Li, Long Bai, Xiaolong Jin, Jiafeng Guo, Xueqi Cheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MA-LoT: Multi-Agent Lean-based Long Chain-of-Thought Reasoning enhances Formal Theorem Proving</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03205</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03205v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Solving mathematical problems using computer-verifiable languages like Lean has significantly impacted mathematical and computer science communities. State-of-the-art methods utilize single Large Language Models (LLMs) as agents or provers to either generate complete proof or perform tree searches. However, single-agent methods inherently lack a structured way to combine high-level reasoning in Natural Language (NL) with Formal Language (FL) verification feedback. To solve these issues, we propose MA-LoT: Multi-Agent Lean-based Long Chain-of-Thought framework, (to the best of our knowledge), the first multi-agent framework for Lean4 theorem proving that balance high-level NL reasoning and FL verification in Long CoT. Using this structured interaction, our approach enables deeper insights and long-term coherence in proof generation, with which past methods struggle. We do this by leveraging emergent formal reasoning ability in Long CoT using our novel LoT-Transfer Learning training-inference pipeline. Extensive experiments show that our framework achieves 54.51% accuracy rate on the Lean4 version of MiniF2F-Test dataset, largely outperforming GPT-4 (22.95%), single-agent tree search (InternLM-Step-Prover, 50.70%), and whole-proof generation (DeepSeek-Prover-v1.5, 48.36%) baselines. Furthermore, our findings highlight the potential of combining Long CoT with formal verification for a more insightful generation in a broader perspective.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03205v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ruida Wang, Rui Pan, Yuxin Li, Jipeng Zhang, Yizhen Jia, Shizhe Diao, Renjie Pi, Junjie Hu, Tong Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Targeted Distillation for Sentiment Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03225</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03225v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper presents a compact model that achieves strong sentiment analysis capabilities through targeted distillation from advanced large language models (LLMs). Our methodology decouples the distillation target into two key components: sentiment-related knowledge and task alignment. To transfer these components, we propose a two-stage distillation framework. The first stage, knowledge-driven distillation (\textsc{KnowDist}), transfers sentiment-related knowledge to enhance fundamental sentiment analysis capabilities. The second stage, in-context learning distillation (\textsc{ICLDist}), transfers task-specific prompt-following abilities to optimize task alignment. For evaluation, we introduce \textsc{SentiBench}, a comprehensive sentiment analysis benchmark comprising 3 task categories across 12 datasets. Experiments on this benchmark demonstrate that our model effectively balances model size and performance, showing strong competitiveness compared to existing small-scale LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03225v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yice Zhang, Guangyu Xie, Jingjie Lin, Jianzhu Bao, Qianlong Wang, Xi Zeng, Ruifeng Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FANS -- Formal Answer Selection for Natural Language Math Reasoning Using Lean4</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03238</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03238v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have displayed astonishing abilities in various tasks, especially in text generation, classification, question answering, etc. However, the reasoning ability of LLMs still faces many debates. The inherent ambiguity of Natural Language (NL) limits LLMs' ability to perform verifiable reasoning, making its answers lack coherence and trustworthy support. To tackle the above problems, we propose a novel framework named FANS: Formal ANswer Selection for Natural Language Math Reasoning Using Lean4. To the best of our knowledge, it is the first framework that utilizes Lean4 to enhance LLMs' NL math reasoning ability. In particular, given an NL math question and LLM-generated answers, FANS first translates it into Lean4 theorem statements. Then it tries to prove it using a Lean4 prover and verify it by Lean4. Finally, it uses the FL result to assist in answer selection. It enhances LLMs' NL math ability in providing a computer-verifiable solution for its correct answer and proposes an alternative method for answer selection beyond the reward model. Extensive experiments indicate the effectiveness of our framework. It can improve the accuracy rate of reward model enhanced LLMs in the MATH-500 dataset by at most 1.91% and AMC-23 by at most 8.33% on strong reward-model baselines. In some particular fields like number theory that Lean4 experts in, we can even select all correct solutions. The qualitative analysis also shows our framework can make NL results formally backed by Lean4 proofs. As a pioneering work in the corresponding field, we will open-source all our models and datasets to further boost the development of the field.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03238v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiarui Yao, Ruida Wang, Tong Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Frontier LLMs Replace Annotators in Biomedical Text Mining? Analyzing Challenges and Exploring Solutions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03261</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03261v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) can perform various natural language processing (NLP) tasks through in-context learning without relying on supervised data. However, multiple previous studies have reported suboptimal performance of LLMs in biological text mining. By analyzing failure patterns in these evaluations, we identified three primary challenges for LLMs in biomedical corpora: (1) LLMs fail to learn implicit dataset-specific nuances from supervised data, (2) The common formatting requirements of discriminative tasks limit the reasoning capabilities of LLMs particularly for LLMs that lack test-time compute, and (3) LLMs struggle to adhere to annotation guidelines and match exact schemas, which hinders their ability to understand detailed annotation requirements which is essential in biomedical annotation workflow. To address these challenges, we experimented with prompt engineering techniques targeted to the above issues, and developed a pipeline that dynamically extracts instructions from annotation guidelines. Our findings show that frontier LLMs can approach or surpass the performance of state-of-the-art (SOTA) BERT-based models with minimal reliance on manually annotated data and without fine-tuning. Furthermore, we performed model distillation on a closed-source LLM, demonstrating that a BERT model trained exclusively on synthetic data annotated by LLMs can also achieve a practical performance. Based on these results, we explored the feasibility of partially replacing manual annotation with LLMs in production scenarios for biomedical text mining.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03261v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yichong Zhao, Susumu Goto</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LexGenie: Automated Generation of Structured Reports for European Court of Human Rights Case Law</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03266</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03266v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Analyzing large volumes of case law to uncover evolving legal principles, across multiple cases, on a given topic is a demanding task for legal professionals. Structured topical reports provide an effective solution by summarizing key issues, principles, and judgments, enabling comprehensive legal analysis on a particular topic. While prior works have advanced query-based individual case summarization, none have extended to automatically generating multi-case structured reports. To address this, we introduce LexGenie, an automated LLM-based pipeline designed to create structured reports using the entire body of case law on user-specified topics within the European Court of Human Rights jurisdiction. LexGenie retrieves, clusters, and organizes relevant passages by topic to generate a structured outline and cohesive content for each section. Expert evaluation confirms LexGenie's utility in producing structured reports that enhance efficient, scalable legal analysis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03266v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>T. Y. S. S Santosh, Mahmoud Aly, Oana Ichim, Matthias Grabmair</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SEOE: A Scalable and Reliable Semantic Evaluation Framework for Open Domain Event Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03303</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03303v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Automatic evaluation for Open Domain Event Detection (ODED) is a highly challenging task, because ODED is characterized by a vast diversity of un-constrained output labels from various domains. Nearly all existing evaluation methods for ODED usually first construct evaluation benchmarks with limited labels and domain coverage, and then evaluate ODED methods using metrics based on token-level label matching rules. However, this kind of evaluation framework faces two issues: (1) The limited evaluation benchmarks lack representatives of the real world, making it difficult to accurately reflect the performance of various ODED methods in real-world scenarios; (2) Evaluation metrics based on token-level matching rules fail to capture semantic similarity between predictions and golden labels. To address these two problems above, we propose a scalable and reliable Semantic-level Evaluation framework for Open domain Event detection (SEOE) by constructing a more representative evaluation benchmark and introducing a semantic evaluation metric. Specifically, our proposed framework first constructs a scalable evaluation benchmark that currently includes 564 event types covering 7 major domains, with a cost-effective supplementary annotation strategy to ensure the benchmark's representativeness. The strategy also allows for the supplement of new event types and domains in the future. Then, the proposed SEOE leverages large language models (LLMs) as automatic evaluation agents to compute a semantic F1-score, incorporating fine-grained definitions of semantically similar labels to enhance the reliability of the evaluation. Extensive experiments validate the representatives of the benchmark and the reliability of the semantic evaluation metric. Existing ODED methods are thoroughly evaluated, and the error patterns of predictions are analyzed, revealing several insightful findings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03303v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yi-Fan Lu, Xian-Ling Mao, Tian Lan, Tong Zhang, Yu-Shi Zhu, Heyan Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Box is in the Pen: Evaluating Commonsense Reasoning in Neural Machine Translation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03308</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03308v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Does neural machine translation yield translations that are congenial with common sense? In this paper, we present a test suite to evaluate the commonsense reasoning capability of neural machine translation. The test suite consists of three test sets, covering lexical and contextless/contextual syntactic ambiguity that requires commonsense knowledge to resolve. We manually create 1,200 triples, each of which contain a source sentence and two contrastive translations, involving 7 different common sense types. Language models pretrained on large-scale corpora, such as BERT, GPT-2, achieve a commonsense reasoning accuracy of lower than 72% on target translations of this test suite. We conduct extensive experiments on the test suite to evaluate commonsense reasoning in neural machine translation and investigate factors that have impact on this capability. Our experiments and analyses demonstrate that neural machine translation performs poorly on commonsense reasoning of the three ambiguity types in terms of both reasoning accuracy (60.1%) and reasoning consistency (31%). The built commonsense test suite is available at https://github.com/tjunlp-lab/CommonMT.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03308v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jie He, Tao Wang, Deyi Xiong, Qun Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iNews: A Multimodal Dataset for Modeling Personalized Affective Responses to News</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03335</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03335v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Current approaches to emotion detection often overlook the inherent subjectivity of affective experiences, instead relying on aggregated labels that mask individual variations in emotional responses. We introduce iNews, a novel large-scale dataset explicitly capturing subjective affective responses to news headlines. Our dataset comprises annotations from 291 demographically diverse UK participants across 2,899 multimodal Facebook news posts from major UK outlets, with an average of 5.18 annotators per sample. For each post, annotators provide multifaceted labels including valence, arousal, dominance, discrete emotions, content relevance judgments, sharing likelihood, and modality importance ratings (text, image, or both). Furthermore, we collect comprehensive annotator persona information covering demographics, personality, media trust, and consumption patterns, which explain 15.2% of annotation variance - higher than existing NLP datasets. Incorporating this information yields a 7% accuracy gain in zero-shot prediction and remains beneficial even with 32-shot. iNews will enhance research in LLM personalization, subjectivity, affective computing, and individual-level behavior simulation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03335v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tiancheng Hu, Nigel Collier</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EnigmaToM: Improve LLMs' Theory-of-Mind Reasoning Capabilities with Neural Knowledge Base of Entity States</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03340</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03340v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Theory-of-Mind (ToM), the ability to infer others' perceptions and mental states, is fundamental to human interaction but remains a challenging task for Large Language Models (LLMs). While existing ToM reasoning methods show promise with reasoning via perceptual perspective-taking, they often rely excessively on LLMs, reducing their efficiency and limiting their applicability to high-order ToM reasoning, which requires multi-hop reasoning about characters' beliefs. To address these issues, we present EnigmaToM, a novel neuro-symbolic framework that enhances ToM reasoning by integrating a Neural Knowledge Base of entity states (Enigma) for (1) a psychology-inspired iterative masking mechanism that facilitates accurate perspective-taking and (2) knowledge injection that elicits key entity information. Enigma generates structured representations of entity states, which construct spatial scene graphs -- leveraging spatial information as an inductive bias -- for belief tracking of various ToM orders and enhancing events with fine-grained entity state details. Experimental results on multiple benchmarks, including ToMi, HiToM, and FANToM, show that EnigmaToM significantly improves ToM reasoning across LLMs of varying sizes, particularly excelling in high-order reasoning scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03340v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hainiu Xu, Siya Qi, Jiazheng Li, Yuxiang Zhou, Jinhua Du, Caroline Catmur, Yulan He</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Serendipity of Claude AI: Case of the 13 Low-Resource National Languages of Mali</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03380</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03380v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent advances in artificial intelligence (AI) and natural language processing (NLP) have improved the representation of underrepresented languages. However, most languages, including Mali's 13 official national languages, continue to be poorly supported or unsupported by automatic translation and generative AI. This situation appears to have slightly improved with certain recent LLM releases. The study evaluated Claude AI's translation performance on each of the 13 national languages of Mali. In addition to ChrF2 and BLEU scores, human evaluators assessed translation accuracy, contextual consistency, robustness to dialect variations, management of linguistic bias, adaptation to a limited corpus, and ease of understanding. The study found that Claude AI performs robustly for languages with very modest language resources and, while unable to produce understandable and coherent texts for Malian languages with minimal resources, still manages to produce results which demonstrate the ability to mimic some elements of the language.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03380v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alou Dembele (RobotsMali AI4D Lab, Bamako, Mali), Nouhoum Souleymane Coulibaly (RobotsMali AI4D Lab, Bamako, Mali), Michael Leventhal (RobotsMali AI4D Lab, Bamako, Mali)</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Claims Evolve: Evaluating and Enhancing the Robustness of Embedding Models Against Misinformation Edits</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03417</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03417v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Online misinformation remains a critical challenge, and fact-checkers increasingly rely on embedding-based methods to retrieve relevant fact-checks. Yet, when debunked claims reappear in edited forms, the performance of these methods is unclear. In this work, we introduce a taxonomy of six common real-world misinformation edits and propose a perturbation framework that generates valid, natural claim variations. Our multi-stage retrieval evaluation reveals that standard embedding models struggle with user-introduced edits, while LLM-distilled embeddings offer improved robustness at a higher computational cost. Although a strong reranker helps mitigate some issues, it cannot fully compensate for first-stage retrieval gaps. Addressing these retrieval gaps, our train- and inference-time mitigation approaches enhance in-domain robustness by up to 17 percentage points and boost out-of-domain generalization by 10 percentage points over baseline models. Overall, our findings provide practical improvements to claim-matching systems, enabling more reliable fact-checking of evolving misinformation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03417v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jabez Magomere, Emanuele La Malfa, Manuel Tonneau, Ashkan Kazemi, Scott Hale</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RASD: Retrieval-Augmented Speculative Decoding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03434</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03434v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Speculative decoding accelerates inference in large language models (LLMs) by generating draft tokens for target model verification. Current approaches for obtaining draft tokens rely on lightweight draft models or additional model structures to generate draft tokens and retrieve context from databases. Due to the draft model's small size and limited training data, model-based speculative decoding frequently becomes less effective in out-of-domain scenarios. Additionally, the time cost of the drafting phase results in a low upper limit on acceptance length during the verification step, limiting overall efficiency. This paper proposes RASD (Retrieval-Augmented Speculative Decoding), which adopts retrieval methods to enhance model-based speculative decoding. We introduce tree pruning and tree fusion to achieve this. Specifically, we develop a pruning method based on the draft model's probability distribution to construct the optimal retrieval tree. Second, we employ the longest prefix matching algorithm to merge the tree generated by the draft model with the retrieval tree, resulting in a unified tree for verification. Experimental results demonstrate that RASD achieves state-of-the-art inference acceleration across tasks such as DocQA, Summary, Code, and In-Domain QA. Moreover, RASD exhibits strong scalability, seamlessly integrating with various speculative decoding approaches, including both generation-based and retrieval-based methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03434v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Guofeng Quan, Wenfeng Feng, Chuzhan Hao, Guochao Jiang, Yuewei Zhang, Hao Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taxation Perspectives from Large Language Models: A Case Study on Additional Tax Penalties</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03444</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03444v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: How capable are large language models (LLMs) in the domain of taxation? Although numerous studies have explored the legal domain in general, research dedicated to taxation remain scarce. Moreover, the datasets used in these studies are either simplified, failing to reflect the real-world complexities, or unavailable as open source. To address this gap, we introduce PLAT, a new benchmark designed to assess the ability of LLMs to predict the legitimacy of additional tax penalties. PLAT is constructed to evaluate LLMs' understanding of tax law, particularly in cases where resolving the issue requires more than just applying related statutes. Our experiments with six LLMs reveal that their baseline capabilities are limited, especially when dealing with conflicting issues that demand a comprehensive understanding. However, we found that enabling retrieval, self-reasoning, and discussion among multiple agents with specific role assignments, this limitation can be mitigated.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03444v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Eunkyung Choi, Young Jin Suh, Hun Park, Wonseok Hwang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visualising Policy-Reward Interplay to Inform Zeroth-Order Preference Optimisation of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03460</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03460v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Fine-tuning LLMs with first-order methods like back-propagation is computationally intensive. Zeroth-Order (ZO) optimisation, using function evaluations instead of gradients, reduces memory usage but suffers from slow convergence in high-dimensional models. As a result, ZO research in LLMs has mostly focused on classification, overlooking more complex generative tasks. In this paper, we introduce ZOPrO, a novel ZO algorithm designed for \textit{Preference Optimisation} in LLMs. We begin by analysing the interplay between policy and reward models during traditional (first-order) Preference Optimisation, uncovering patterns in their relative updates. Guided by these insights, we adapt Simultaneous Perturbation Stochastic Approximation (SPSA) with a targeted sampling strategy to accelerate convergence. Through experiments on summarisation, machine translation, and conversational assistants, we demonstrate that our method consistently enhances reward signals while achieving convergence times comparable to first-order methods. While it falls short of some state-of-the-art methods, our work is the first to apply Zeroth-Order methods to Preference Optimisation in LLMs, going beyond classification tasks and paving the way for a largely unexplored research direction. Code and visualisations are available at https://github.com/alessioGalatolo/VisZOPrO</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03460v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alessio Galatolo, Zhenbang Dai, Katie Winkle, Meriem Beloucif</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open-Source Large Language Models as Multilingual Crowdworkers: Synthesizing Open-Domain Dialogues in Several Languages With No Examples in Targets and No Machine Translation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03462</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03462v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The prevailing paradigm in the domain of Open-Domain Dialogue agents predominantly focuses on the English language, encompassing both models and datasets. Furthermore, the financial and temporal investments required for crowdsourcing such datasets for finetuning are substantial, particularly when multiple languages are involved. Fortunately, advancements in Large Language Models (LLMs) have unveiled a plethora of possibilities across diverse tasks. Specifically, instruction-tuning has enabled LLMs to execute tasks based on natural language instructions, occasionally surpassing the performance of human crowdworkers. Additionally, these models possess the capability to function in various languages within a single thread. Consequently, to generate new samples in different languages, we propose leveraging these capabilities to replicate the data collection process. We introduce a pipeline for generating Open-Domain Dialogue data in multiple Target Languages using LLMs, with demonstrations provided in a unique Source Language. By eschewing explicit Machine Translation in this approach, we enhance the adherence to language-specific nuances. We apply this methodology to the PersonaChat dataset. To enhance the openness of generated dialogues and mimic real life scenarii, we added the notion of speech events corresponding to the type of conversation the speakers are involved in and also that of common ground which represents the premises of a conversation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03462v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ahmed Njifenjou, Virgile Sucal, Bassam Jabaian, Fabrice Lef\`evre</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Spoken Discourse Modeling in Language Models Using Gestural Cues</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03474</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03474v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Research in linguistics shows that non-verbal cues, such as gestures, play a crucial role in spoken discourse. For example, speakers perform hand gestures to indicate topic shifts, helping listeners identify transitions in discourse. In this work, we investigate whether the joint modeling of gestures using human motion sequences and language can improve spoken discourse modeling in language models. To integrate gestures into language models, we first encode 3D human motion sequences into discrete gesture tokens using a VQ-VAE. These gesture token embeddings are then aligned with text embeddings through feature alignment, mapping them into the text embedding space. To evaluate the gesture-aligned language model on spoken discourse, we construct text infilling tasks targeting three key discourse cues grounded in linguistic research: discourse connectives, stance markers, and quantifiers. Results show that incorporating gestures enhances marker prediction accuracy across the three tasks, highlighting the complementary information that gestures can offer in modeling spoken discourse. We view this work as an initial step toward leveraging non-verbal cues to advance spoken language modeling in language models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03474v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Varsha Suresh, M. Hamza Mughal, Christian Theobalt, Vera Demberg</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deictic Codes, Demonstratives, and Reference: A Step Toward Solving the Grounding Problem</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03495</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03495v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this paper we address the issue of grounding for experiential concepts. Given that perceptual demonstratives are a basic form of such concepts, we examine ways of fixing the referents of such demonstratives. To avoid 'encodingism', that is, relating representations to representations, we postulate that the process of reference fixing must be bottom-up and nonconceptual, so that it can break the circle of conceptual content and touch the world. For that purpose, an appropriate causal relation between representations and the world is needed. We claim that this relation is provided by spatial and object-centered attention that leads to the formation of object files through the function of deictic acts. This entire causal process takes place at a pre-conceptual level, meeting the requirement for a solution to the grounding problem. Finally we claim that our account captures fundamental insights in Putnam's and Kripke's work on "new" reference.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03495v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>(2002) in Wayne D. Gray and Christian D. Schunn (eds.), CogSci 2002, 24th annual meeting of the Cognitive Science Society (Mahwah, NY: Lawrence Erlbaum), 762-67</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Athanassios Raftopoulos, Vincent C. M\"uller</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CURVALID: Geometrically-guided Adversarial Prompt Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03502</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03502v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Adversarial prompts capable of jailbreaking large language models (LLMs) and inducing undesirable behaviours pose a significant obstacle to their safe deployment. Current mitigation strategies rely on activating built-in defence mechanisms or fine-tuning the LLMs, but the fundamental distinctions between adversarial and benign prompts are yet to be understood. In this work, we introduce CurvaLID, a novel defense framework that efficiently detects adversarial prompts by leveraging their geometric properties. It is agnostic to the type of LLM, offering a unified detection framework across diverse adversarial prompts and LLM architectures. CurvaLID builds on the geometric analysis of text prompts to uncover their underlying differences. We theoretically extend the concept of curvature via the Whewell equation into an $n$-dimensional word embedding space, enabling us to quantify local geometric properties, including semantic shifts and curvature in the underlying manifolds. Additionally, we employ Local Intrinsic Dimensionality (LID) to capture geometric features of text prompts within adversarial subspaces. Our findings reveal that adversarial prompts differ fundamentally from benign prompts in terms of their geometric characteristics. Our results demonstrate that CurvaLID delivers superior detection and rejection of adversarial queries, paving the way for safer LLM deployment. The source code can be found at https://github.com/Cancanxxx/CurvaLID</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03502v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Canaan Yung, Hanxun Huang, Sarah Monazam Erfani, Christopher Leckie</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Aspect Extraction Framework using Different Embedding Types, Learning Models, and Dependency Structure</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03512</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03512v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Aspect-based sentiment analysis has gained significant attention in recent years due to its ability to provide fine-grained insights for sentiment expressions related to specific features of entities. An important component of aspect-based sentiment analysis is aspect extraction, which involves identifying and extracting aspect terms from text. Effective aspect extraction serves as the foundation for accurate sentiment analysis at the aspect level. In this paper, we propose aspect extraction models that use different types of embeddings for words and part-of-speech tags and that combine several learning models. We also propose tree positional encoding that is based on dependency parsing output to capture better the aspect positions in sentences. In addition, a new aspect extraction dataset is built for Turkish by machine translating an English dataset in a controlled setting. The experiments conducted on two Turkish datasets showed that the proposed models mostly outperform the studies that use the same datasets, and incorporating tree positional encoding increases the performance of the models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03512v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ali Erkan, Tunga G\"ung\"or</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Crowdsourced Election Monitoring: Construction and Evaluation of Classification Models for Multilingual and Cross-Domain Classification Settings</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03582</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03582v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The adoption of crowdsourced election monitoring as a complementary alternative to traditional election monitoring is on the rise. Yet, its reliance on digital response volunteers to manually process incoming election reports poses a significant scaling bottleneck. In this paper, we address the challenge of scaling crowdsourced election monitoring by advancing the task of automated classification of crowdsourced election reports to multilingual and cross-domain classification settings. We propose a two-step classification approach of first identifying informative reports and then categorising them into distinct information types. We conduct classification experiments using multilingual transformer models such as XLM-RoBERTa and multilingual embeddings such as SBERT, augmented with linguistically motivated features. Our approach achieves F1-Scores of 77\% for informativeness detection and 75\% for information type classification. We conduct cross-domain experiments, applying models trained in a source electoral domain to a new target electoral domain in zero-shot and few-shot classification settings. Our results show promising potential for model transfer across electoral domains, with F1-Scores of 59\% in zero-shot and 63\% in few-shot settings. However, our analysis also reveals a performance bias in detecting informative English reports over Swahili, likely due to imbalances in the training data, indicating a need for caution when deploying classification models in real-world election scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03582v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jabez Magomere, Scott Hale</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PowerAttention: Exponentially Scaling of Receptive Fields for Effective Sparse Attention</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03588</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03588v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) face efficiency bottlenecks due to the quadratic complexity of the attention mechanism when processing long contexts. Sparse attention methods offer a promising solution, but existing approaches often suffer from incomplete effective context and/or require complex implementation of pipeline. We present a comprehensive analysis of sparse attention for autoregressive LLMs from the respective of receptive field, recognize the suboptimal nature of existing methods for expanding the receptive field, and introduce PowerAttention, a novel sparse attention design that facilitates effective and complete context extension through the theoretical analysis. PowerAttention achieves exponential receptive field growth in $d$-layer LLMs, allowing each output token to attend to $2^d$ tokens, ensuring completeness and continuity of the receptive field. Experiments demonstrate that PowerAttention outperforms existing static sparse attention methods by $5\sim 40\%$, especially on tasks demanding long-range dependencies like Passkey Retrieval and RULER, while maintaining a comparable time complexity to sliding window attention. Efficiency evaluations further highlight PowerAttention's superior speedup in both prefilling and decoding phases compared with dynamic sparse attentions and full attention ($3.0\times$ faster on 128K context), making it a highly effective and user-friendly solution for processing long sequences in LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03588v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lida Chen, Dong Xu, Chenxin An, Xintao Wang, Yikai Zhang, Jiangjie Chen, Zujie Liang, Feng Wei, Jiaqing Liang, Yanghua Xiao, Wei Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>English K_Quantization of LLMs Does Not Disproportionately Diminish Multilingual Performance</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03592</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03592v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: For consumer usage of locally deployed LLMs, the GGUF format and k_quantization are invaluable tools for maintaining the performance of the original model while reducing it to sizes deployable with consumer-grade hardware. The number of bits dedicated to each weight from the original model is reduced based on how important they are thought to be during model inference. This importance is arrived at through the application of an 'importance matrix'-a relatively small text document meant to be representative of the LLM's standard use-cases. In the vast majority of quants available online, this document is primarily written in English. It was therefore an open question whether performance on English language tasks was preserved through the sacrifice of multilingual performance and whether it can be preserved with alternate importance matrices. This article investigates these hypotheses by quantizing Llama3.3 70B on importance matrices written in three languages (English, Norwegian, and Malayalam) and evaluating them on the MixEval dataset in both English and Norwegian. All experiments related to k_quantization yielded non-significant results (In all cases p &gt; 0.237) indicating that current quantization practices do not disproportionately harm multilingual performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03592v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Karl Audun Borgersen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Small but Mighty: Enhancing Time Series Forecasting with Lightweight LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03594</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03594v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: While LLMs have demonstrated remarkable potential in time series forecasting, their practical deployment remains constrained by excessive computational demands and memory footprints. Existing LLM-based approaches typically suffer from three critical limitations: Inefficient parameter utilization in handling numerical time series patterns; Modality misalignment between continuous temporal signals and discrete text embeddings; and Inflexibility for real-time expert knowledge integration. We present SMETimes, the first systematic investigation of sub-3B parameter SLMs for efficient and accurate time series forecasting. Our approach centers on three key innovations: A statistically-enhanced prompting mechanism that bridges numerical time series with textual semantics through descriptive statistical features; A adaptive fusion embedding architecture that aligns temporal patterns with language model token spaces through learnable parameters; And a dynamic mixture-of-experts framework enabled by SLMs' computational efficiency, adaptively combining base predictions with domain-specific models. Extensive evaluations across seven benchmark datasets demonstrate that our 3B-parameter SLM achieves state-of-the-art performance on five primary datasets while maintaining 3.8x faster training and 5.2x lower memory consumption compared to 7B-parameter LLM baselines. Notably, the proposed model exhibits better learning capabilities, achieving 12.3% lower MSE than conventional LLM. Ablation studies validate that our statistical prompting and cross-modal fusion modules respectively contribute 15.7% and 18.2% error reduction in long-horizon forecasting tasks. By redefining the efficiency-accuracy trade-off landscape, this work establishes SLMs as viable alternatives to resource-intensive LLMs for practical time series forecasting. Code and models are available at https://github.com/xiyan1234567/SMETimes.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03594v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haoran Fan, Bin Li, Yixuan Weng, Shoujun Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feature-Level Insights into Artificial Text Detection with Sparse Autoencoders</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03601</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03601v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Artificial Text Detection (ATD) is becoming increasingly important with the rise of advanced Large Language Models (LLMs). Despite numerous efforts, no single algorithm performs consistently well across different types of unseen text or guarantees effective generalization to new LLMs. Interpretability plays a crucial role in achieving this goal. In this study, we enhance ATD interpretability by using Sparse Autoencoders (SAE) to extract features from Gemma-2-2b residual stream. We identify both interpretable and efficient features, analyzing their semantics and relevance through domain- and model-specific statistics, a steering approach, and manual or LLM-based interpretation. Our methods offer valuable insights into how texts from various models differ from human-written content. We show that modern LLMs have a distinct writing style, especially in information-dense domains, even though they can produce human-like outputs with personalized prompts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03601v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kristian Kuznetsov, Laida Kushnareva, Polina Druzhinina, Anton Razzhigaev, Anastasia Voznyuk, Irina Piontkovskaya, Evgeny Burnaev, Serguei Barannikov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Psy-Insight: Explainable Multi-turn Bilingual Dataset for Mental Health Counseling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03607</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03607v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The in-context learning capabilities of large language models (LLMs) show great potential in mental health support. However, the lack of counseling datasets, particularly in Chinese corpora, restricts their application in this field. To address this, we constructed Psy-Insight, the first mental health-oriented explainable multi-task bilingual dataset. We collected face-to-face multi-turn counseling dialogues, which are annotated with multi-task labels and conversation process explanations. Our annotations include psychotherapy, emotion, strategy, and topic labels, as well as turn-level reasoning and session-level guidance. Psy-Insight is not only suitable for tasks such as label recognition but also meets the need for training LLMs to act as empathetic counselors through logical reasoning. Experiments show that training LLMs on Psy-Insight enables the models to not only mimic the conversation style but also understand the underlying strategies and reasoning of counseling.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03607v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Keqi Chen, Zekai Sun, Yuhua Wen, Huijun Lian, Yingming Gao, Ya Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Psy-Copilot: Visual Chain of Thought for Counseling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03645</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03645v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are becoming increasingly popular in the field of psychological counseling. However, when human therapists work with LLMs in therapy sessions, it is hard to understand how the model gives the answers. To address this, we have constructed Psy-COT, a graph designed to visualize the thought processes of LLMs during therapy sessions. The Psy-COT graph presents semi-structured counseling conversations alongside step-by-step annotations that capture the reasoning and insights of therapists. Moreover, we have developed Psy-Copilot, which is a conversational AI assistant designed to assist human psychological therapists in their consultations. It can offer traceable psycho-information based on retrieval, including response candidates, similar dialogue sessions, related strategies, and visual traces of results. We have also built an interactive platform for AI-assisted counseling. It has an interface that displays the relevant parts of the retrieval sub-graph. The Psy-Copilot is designed not to replace psychotherapists but to foster collaboration between AI and human therapists, thereby promoting mental health development. Our code and demo are both open-sourced and available for use.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03645v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Keqi Chen, Zekai Sun, Huijun Lian, Yingming Gao, Ya Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Token-Level Privacy in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03652</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03652v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The use of language models as remote services requires transmitting private information to external providers, raising significant privacy concerns. This process not only risks exposing sensitive data to untrusted service providers but also leaves it vulnerable to interception by eavesdroppers. Existing privacy-preserving methods for natural language processing (NLP) interactions primarily rely on semantic similarity, overlooking the role of contextual information. In this work, we introduce dchi-stencil, a novel token-level privacy-preserving mechanism that integrates contextual and semantic information while ensuring strong privacy guarantees under the dchi differential privacy framework, achieving 2epsilon-dchi-privacy. By incorporating both semantic and contextual nuances, dchi-stencil achieves a robust balance between privacy and utility. We evaluate dchi-stencil using state-of-the-art language models and diverse datasets, achieving comparable and even better trade-off between utility and privacy compared to existing methods. This work highlights the potential of dchi-stencil to set a new standard for privacy-preserving NLP in modern, high-risk applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03652v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Re'em Harel, Niv Gilboa, Yuval Pinter</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Neutral Point of View Text Generation through Parameter-Efficient Reinforcement Learning and a Small-Scale High-Quality Dataset</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03654</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03654v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper describes the construction of a dataset and the evaluation of training methods to improve generative large language models' (LLMs) ability to answer queries on sensitive topics with a Neutral Point of View (NPOV), i.e., to provide significantly more informative, diverse and impartial answers. The dataset, the SHQ-NPOV dataset, comprises 300 high-quality, human-written quadruplets: a query on a sensitive topic, an answer, an NPOV rating, and a set of links to source texts elaborating the various points of view. The first key contribution of this paper is a new methodology to create such datasets through iterative rounds of human peer-critique and annotator training, which we release alongside the dataset. The second key contribution is the identification of a highly effective training regime for parameter-efficient reinforcement learning (PE-RL) to improve NPOV generation. We compare and extensively evaluate PE-RL and multiple baselines-including LoRA finetuning (a strong baseline), SFT and RLHF.
  PE-RL not only improves on overall NPOV quality compared to the strongest baseline ($97.06\%\rightarrow 99.08\%$), but also scores much higher on features linguists identify as key to separating good answers from the best answers ($60.25\%\rightarrow 85.21\%$ for presence of supportive details, $68.74\%\rightarrow 91.43\%$ for absence of oversimplification). A qualitative analysis corroborates this. Finally, our evaluation finds no statistical differences between results on topics that appear in the training dataset and those on separated evaluation topics, which provides strong evidence that our approach to training PE-RL exhibits very effective out of topic generalization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03654v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jessica Hoffmann, Christiane Ahlheim, Zac Yu, Aria Walfrand, Jarvis Jin, Marie Tano, Ahmad Beirami, Erin van Liemt, Nithum Thain, Hakim Sidahmed, Lucas Dixon</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analogical Reasoning Inside Large Language Models: Concept Vectors and the Limits of Abstraction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03666</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03666v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Analogical reasoning relies on conceptual abstractions, but it is unclear whether Large Language Models (LLMs) harbor such internal representations. We explore distilled representations from LLM activations and find that function vectors (FVs; Todd et al., 2024) - compact representations for in-context learning (ICL) tasks - are not invariant to simple input changes (e.g., open-ended vs. multiple-choice), suggesting they capture more than pure concepts. Using representational similarity analysis (RSA), we localize a small set of attention heads that encode invariant concept vectors (CVs) for verbal concepts like "antonym". These CVs function as feature detectors that operate independently of the final output - meaning that a model may form a correct internal representation yet still produce an incorrect output. Furthermore, CVs can be used to causally guide model behaviour. However, for more abstract concepts like "previous" and "next", we do not observe invariant linear representations, a finding we link to generalizability issues LLMs display within these domains.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03666v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gustaw Opie{\l}ka, Hannes Rosenbusch, Claire E. Stevenson</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attentive Reasoning Queries: A Systematic Method for Optimizing Instruction-Following in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03669</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03669v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present Attentive Reasoning Queries (ARQs), a novel structured reasoning approach that significantly improves instruction-following in Large Language Models through domain-specialized reasoning blueprints. While LLMs demonstrate remarkable capabilities across diverse tasks, they often fail to maintain adherence to complex, use-case-specific instructions during multi-turn conversations, presenting challenges for business-critical applications. ARQs address this limitation by guiding LLMs through systematic reasoning steps with targeted queries that reinstate critical instructions and facilitate intermediate reasoning throughout the completion process. In extensive testing within Parlant, our framework for reliable customer-facing agents in which ARQs were born out of necessity, they achieved a 90.2% success rate across 87 test scenarios, outperforming both Chain-of-Thought reasoning (86.1%) and direct response generation (81.5%). ARQs showed particular strength in addressing persistent failure modes like guideline re-application and hallucination prevention. Our analysis also revealed that ARQs can potentially be more computationally efficient than free-form reasoning when carefully designed. These findings demonstrate that structured reasoning approaches provide effective mechanisms for controlling how LLMs process information and make decisions in complex scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03669v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bar Karov, Dor Zohar, Yam Marcovitz</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantification of Tenseness in English and Japanese Tense-Lax Vowels: A Lagrangian Model with Indicator $\theta_1$ and Force of Tenseness Ftense(t)</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03681</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03681v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The concept of vowel tenseness has traditionally been examined through the binary distinction of tense and lax vowels. However, no universally accepted quantitative definition of tenseness has been established in any language. Previous studies, including those by Jakobson, Fant, and Halle (1951) and Chomsky and Halle (1968), have explored the relationship between vowel tenseness and the vocal tract. Building on these foundations, Ishizaki (2019, 2022) proposed an indirect quantification of vowel tenseness using formant angles $\theta_1$ and $\theta_{F1}$ and their first and second derivatives, $d^Z_1(t)/dt = \lim \tan \theta_1(t$) and $d^2 Z_1(t)/dt^2 = d/dt \lim \tan \theta_1(t)$. This study extends this approach by investigating the potential role of a force-related parameter in determining vowel quality. Specifically, we introduce a simplified model based on the Lagrangian equation to describe the dynamic interaction of the tongue and jaw within the oral cavity during the articulation of close vowels. This model provides a theoretical framework for estimating the forces involved in vowel production across different languages, offering new insights into the physical mechanisms underlying vowel articulation. The findings suggest that this force-based perspective warrants further exploration as a key factor in phonetic and phonological studies.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03681v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tatsuya Ishizaki</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MAS-GPT: Training LLMs to Build LLM-based Multi-Agent Systems</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03686</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03686v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: LLM-based multi-agent systems (MAS) have shown significant potential in tackling diverse tasks. However, to design effective MAS, existing approaches heavily rely on manual configurations or multiple calls of advanced LLMs, resulting in inadaptability and high inference costs. In this paper, we simplify the process of building an MAS by reframing it as a generative language task, where the input is a user query and the output is a corresponding MAS. To address this novel task, we unify the representation of MAS as executable code and propose a consistency-oriented data construction pipeline to create a high-quality dataset comprising coherent and consistent query-MAS pairs. Using this dataset, we train MAS-GPT, an open-source medium-sized LLM that is capable of generating query-adaptive MAS within a single LLM inference. The generated MAS can be seamlessly applied to process user queries and deliver high-quality responses. Extensive experiments on 9 benchmarks and 5 LLMs show that the proposed MAS-GPT consistently outperforms 10+ baseline MAS methods on diverse settings, indicating MAS-GPT's high effectiveness, efficiency and strong generalization ability. Code will be available at https://github.com/rui-ye/MAS-GPT.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03686v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rui Ye, Shuo Tang, Rui Ge, Yaxin Du, Zhenfei Yin, Siheng Chen, Jing Shao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing and Utilizing a Large-Scale Cantonese Dataset for Multi-Tasking in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03702</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03702v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: High-quality data resources play a crucial role in learning large language models (LLMs), particularly for low-resource languages like Cantonese. Despite having more than 85 million native speakers, Cantonese is still considered a low-resource language in the field of natural language processing (NLP) due to factors such as the dominance of Mandarin, lack of cohesion within the Cantonese-speaking community, diversity in character encoding and input methods, and the tendency of overseas Cantonese speakers to prefer using English. In addition, rich colloquial vocabulary of Cantonese, English loanwords, and code-switching characteristics add to the complexity of corpus collection and processing. To address these challenges, we collect Cantonese texts from a variety of sources, including open source corpora, Hong Kong-specific forums, Wikipedia, and Common Crawl data. We conduct rigorous data processing through language filtering, quality filtering, content filtering, and de-duplication steps, successfully constructing a high-quality Cantonese corpus of over 2 billion tokens for training large language models. We further refined the model through supervised fine-tuning (SFT) on curated Cantonese tasks, enhancing its ability to handle specific applications. Upon completion of the training, the model achieves state-of-the-art (SOTA) performance on four Cantonese benchmarks. After training on our dataset, the model also exhibits improved performance on other mainstream language tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03702v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiyue Jiang, Alfred Kar Yin Truong, Yanyu Chen, Qinghang Bao, Sheng Wang, Pengan Chen, Jiuming Wang, Lingpeng Kong, Yu Li, Chuan Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SoftMatcha: A Soft and Fast Pattern Matcher for Billion-Scale Corpus Searches</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03703</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03703v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Researchers and practitioners in natural language processing and computational linguistics frequently observe and analyze the real language usage in large-scale corpora. For that purpose, they often employ off-the-shelf pattern-matching tools, such as grep, and keyword-in-context concordancers, which is widely used in corpus linguistics for gathering examples. Nonetheless, these existing techniques rely on surface-level string matching, and thus they suffer from the major limitation of not being able to handle orthographic variations and paraphrasing -- notable and common phenomena in any natural language. In addition, existing continuous approaches such as dense vector search tend to be overly coarse, often retrieving texts that are unrelated but share similar topics. Given these challenges, we propose a novel algorithm that achieves \emph{soft} (or semantic) yet efficient pattern matching by relaxing a surface-level matching with word embeddings. Our algorithm is highly scalable with respect to the size of the corpus text utilizing inverted indexes. We have prepared an efficient implementation, and we provide an accessible web tool. Our experiments demonstrate that the proposed method (i) can execute searches on billion-scale corpora in less than a second, which is comparable in speed to surface-level string matching and dense vector search; (ii) can extract harmful instances that semantically match queries from a large set of English and Japanese Wikipedia articles; and (iii) can be effectively applied to corpus-linguistic analyses of Latin, a language with highly diverse inflections.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03703v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hiroyuki Deguchi, Go Kamoda, Yusuke Matsushita, Chihiro Taguchi, Kohei Suenaga, Masaki Waga, Sho Yokoi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective LLM Knowledge Learning via Model Generalization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03705</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03705v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are trained on enormous documents that contain extensive world knowledge. However, it is still not well-understood how knowledge is acquired via autoregressive pre-training. This lack of understanding greatly hinders effective knowledge learning, especially for continued pretraining on up-to-date information, as this evolving information often lacks diverse repetitions like foundational knowledge. In this paper, we focus on understanding and improving LLM knowledge learning. We found and verified that knowledge learning for LLMs can be deemed as an implicit supervised task hidden in the autoregressive pre-training objective. Our findings suggest that knowledge learning for LLMs would benefit from methods designed to improve generalization ability for supervised tasks. Based on our analysis, we propose the formatting-based data augmentation to grow in-distribution samples, which does not present the risk of altering the facts embedded in documents as text paraphrasing. We also introduce sharpness-aware minimization as an effective optimization algorithm to better improve generalization. Moreover, our analysis and method can be readily extended to instruction tuning. Extensive experiment results validate our findings and demonstrate our methods' effectiveness in both continued pre-training and instruction tuning. This paper offers new perspectives and insights to interpret and design effective strategies for LLM knowledge learning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03705v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mingkang Zhu, Xi Chen, Zhongdao Wang, Bei Yu, Hengshuang Zhao, Jiaya Jia</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving LLM Safety Alignment with Dual-Objective Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03710</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03710v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Existing training-time safety alignment techniques for large language models (LLMs) remain vulnerable to jailbreak attacks. Direct preference optimization (DPO), a widely deployed alignment method, exhibits limitations in both experimental and theoretical contexts as its loss function proves suboptimal for refusal learning. Through gradient-based analysis, we identify these shortcomings and propose an improved safety alignment that disentangles DPO objectives into two components: (1) robust refusal training, which encourages refusal even when partial unsafe generations are produced, and (2) targeted unlearning of harmful knowledge. This approach significantly increases LLM robustness against a wide range of jailbreak attacks, including prefilling, suffix, and multi-turn attacks across both in-distribution and out-of-distribution scenarios. Furthermore, we introduce a method to emphasize critical refusal tokens by incorporating a reward-based token-level weighting mechanism for refusal learning, which further improves the robustness against adversarial exploits. Our research also suggests that robustness to jailbreak attacks is correlated with token distribution shifts in the training process and internal representations of refusal and harmful tokens, offering valuable directions for future research in LLM safety alignment. The code is available at https://github.com/wicai24/DOOR-Alignment</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03710v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xuandong Zhao, Will Cai, Tianneng Shi, David Huang, Licong Lin, Song Mei, Dawn Song</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Process-based Self-Rewarding Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03746</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03746v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models have demonstrated outstanding performance across various downstream tasks and have been widely applied in multiple scenarios. Human-annotated preference data is used for training to further improve LLMs' performance, which is constrained by the upper limit of human performance. Therefore, Self-Rewarding method has been proposed, where LLMs generate training data by rewarding their own outputs. However, the existing self-rewarding paradigm is not effective in mathematical reasoning scenarios and may even lead to a decline in performance. In this work, we propose the Process-based Self-Rewarding pipeline for language models, which introduces long-thought reasoning, step-wise LLM-as-a-Judge, and step-wise preference optimization within the self-rewarding paradigm. Our new paradigm successfully enhances the performance of LLMs on multiple mathematical reasoning benchmarks through iterative Process-based Self-Rewarding, demonstrating the immense potential of self-rewarding to achieve LLM reasoning that may surpass human capabilities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03746v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shimao Zhang, Xiao Liu, Xin Zhang, Junxiao Liu, Zheheng Luo, Shujian Huang, Yeyun Gong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"Would You Want an AI Tutor?" Understanding Stakeholder Perceptions of LLM-based Chatbots in the Classroom</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.02885</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.02885v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In recent years, Large Language Models (LLMs) rapidly gained popularity across all parts of society, including education. After initial skepticism and bans, many schools have chosen to embrace this new technology by integrating it into their curricula in the form of virtual tutors and teaching assistants. However, neither the companies developing this technology nor the public institutions involved in its implementation have set up a formal system to collect feedback from the stakeholders impacted by them. In this paper, we argue that understanding the perceptions of those directly affected by LLMS in the classroom, such as students and teachers, as well as those indirectly impacted, like parents and school staff, is essential for ensuring responsible use of AI in this critical domain. Our contributions are two-fold. First, we present results of a literature review focusing on the perceptions of LLM-based chatbots in education. We highlight important gaps in the literature, such as the exclusion of key educational agents (e.g., parents or school administrators) when analyzing the role of stakeholders, and the frequent omission of the learning contexts in which the AI systems are implemented. Thus, we present a taxonomy that organizes existing literature on stakeholder perceptions. Second, we propose the Contextualized Perceptions for the Adoption of Chatbots in Education (Co-PACE) framework, which can be used to systematically elicit perceptions and inform whether and how LLM-based chatbots should be designed, developed, and deployed in the classroom.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.02885v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Caterina Fuligni, Daniel Dominguez Figaredo, Julia Stoyanovich</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Text2Scenario: Text-Driven Scenario Generation for Autonomous Driving Test</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.02911</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.02911v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Autonomous driving (AD) testing constitutes a critical methodology for assessing performance benchmarks prior to product deployment. The creation of segmented scenarios within a simulated environment is acknowledged as a robust and effective strategy; however, the process of tailoring these scenarios often necessitates laborious and time-consuming manual efforts, thereby hindering the development and implementation of AD technologies. In response to this challenge, we introduce Text2Scenario, a framework that leverages a Large Language Model (LLM) to autonomously generate simulation test scenarios that closely align with user specifications, derived from their natural language inputs. Specifically, an LLM, equipped with a meticulously engineered input prompt scheme functions as a text parser for test scenario descriptions, extracting from a hierarchically organized scenario repository the components that most accurately reflect the user's preferences. Subsequently, by exploiting the precedence of scenario components, the process involves sequentially matching and linking scenario representations within a Domain Specific Language corpus, ultimately fabricating executable test scenarios. The experimental results demonstrate that such prompt engineering can meticulously extract the nuanced details of scenario elements embedded within various descriptive formats, with the majority of generated scenarios aligning closely with the user's initial expectations, allowing for the efficient and precise evaluation of diverse AD stacks void of the labor-intensive need for manual scenario configuration. Project page: https://caixxuan.github.io/Text2Scenario.GitHub.io.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.02911v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xuan Cai, Xuesong Bai, Zhiyong Cui, Danmu Xie, Daocheng Fu, Haiyang Yu, Yilong Ren</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LiteWebAgent: The Open-Source Suite for VLM-Based Web-Agent Applications</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.02950</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.02950v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We introduce LiteWebAgent, an open-source suite for VLM-based web agent applications. Our framework addresses a critical gap in the web agent ecosystem with a production-ready solution that combines minimal serverless backend configuration, intuitive user and browser interfaces, and extensible research capabilities in agent planning, memory, and tree search. For the core LiteWebAgent agent framework, we implemented a simple yet effective baseline using recursive function calling, providing with decoupled action generation and action grounding. In addition, we integrate advanced research components such as agent planning, agent workflow memory, and tree search in a modular and extensible manner. We then integrate the LiteWebAgent agent framework with frontend and backend as deployed systems in two formats: (1) a production Vercel-based web application, which provides users with an agent-controlled remote browser, (2) a Chrome extension leveraging LiteWebAgent's API to control an existing Chrome browser via CDP (Chrome DevTools Protocol). The LiteWebAgent framework is available at https://github.com/PathOnAI/LiteWebAgent, with deployed frontend at https://lite-web-agent.vercel.app/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.02950v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Danqing Zhang, Balaji Rama, Jingyi Ni, Shiying He, Fu Zhao, Kunyu Chen, Arnold Chen, Junyu Cao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KodCode: A Diverse, Challenging, and Verifiable Synthetic Dataset for Coding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.02951</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.02951v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We introduce KodCode, a synthetic dataset that addresses the persistent challenge of acquiring high-quality, verifiable training data across diverse difficulties and domains for training Large Language Models for coding. Existing code-focused resources typically fail to ensure either the breadth of coverage (e.g., spanning simple coding tasks to advanced algorithmic problems) or verifiable correctness (e.g., unit tests). In contrast, KodCode comprises question-solution-test triplets that are systematically validated via a self-verification procedure. Our pipeline begins by synthesizing a broad range of coding questions, then generates solutions and test cases with additional attempts allocated to challenging problems. Finally, post-training data synthesis is done by rewriting questions into diverse formats and generating responses under a test-based reject sampling procedure from a reasoning model (DeepSeek R1). This pipeline yields a large-scale, robust and diverse coding dataset. KodCode is suitable for supervised fine-tuning and the paired unit tests also provide great potential for RL tuning. Fine-tuning experiments on coding benchmarks (HumanEval(+), MBPP(+), BigCodeBench, and LiveCodeBench) demonstrate that KodCode-tuned models achieve state-of-the-art performance, surpassing models like Qwen2.5-Coder-32B-Instruct and DeepSeek-R1-Distill-Llama-70B.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.02951v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhangchen Xu, Yang Liu, Yueqin Yin, Mingyuan Zhou, Radha Poovendran</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Understanding Multi-Round Large Language Model Reasoning: Approximability, Learnability and Generalizability</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03128</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03128v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recent advancements in cognitive science and multi-round reasoning techniques for Large Language Models (LLMs) suggest that iterative thinking processes improve problem-solving performance in complex tasks. Inspired by this, approaches like Chain-of-Thought, debating, and self-refinement have been applied to auto-regressive LLMs, achieving significant successes in tasks such as mathematical reasoning, commonsense reasoning, and multi-hop question answering. Despite these successes, the theoretical basis for how multi-round reasoning enhances problem-solving abilities remains underexplored. In this work, we investigate the approximation, learnability, and generalization properties of multi-round auto-regressive models. We show that Transformers with finite context windows are universal approximators for steps of Turing-computable functions and can approximate any Turing-computable sequence-to-sequence function through multi-round reasoning. We extend PAC learning to sequence generation and demonstrate that multi-round generation is learnable even when the sequence length exceeds the model's context window. Finally, we examine how generalization error propagates across rounds, and show how the aforementioned approaches can help constrain this error, ensuring outputs stay within an expectation boundary. This work sheds light on the systemic theoretical foundations of multi-round sequence learning and reasoning, emphasizing its role in inference complexity.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03128v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chenhui Xu, Dancheng Liu, Jiajie Li, Amir Nassereldine, Zhaohui Li, Jinjun Xiong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Abnormality Grounding for Vision Language Models with Knowledge Descriptions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03278</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03278v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Visual Language Models (VLMs) have demonstrated impressive capabilities in visual grounding tasks. However, their effectiveness in the medical domain, particularly for abnormality detection and localization within medical images, remains underexplored. A major challenge is the complex and abstract nature of medical terminology, which makes it difficult to directly associate pathological anomaly terms with their corresponding visual features. In this work, we introduce a novel approach to enhance VLM performance in medical abnormality detection and localization by leveraging decomposed medical knowledge. Instead of directly prompting models to recognize specific abnormalities, we focus on breaking down medical concepts into fundamental attributes and common visual patterns. This strategy promotes a stronger alignment between textual descriptions and visual features, improving both the recognition and localization of abnormalities in medical images.We evaluate our method on the 0.23B Florence-2 base model and demonstrate that it achieves comparable performance in abnormality grounding to significantly larger 7B LLaVA-based medical VLMs, despite being trained on only 1.5% of the data used for such models. Experimental results also demonstrate the effectiveness of our approach in both known and previously unseen abnormalities, suggesting its strong generalization capabilities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03278v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jun Li, Che Liu, Wenjia Bai, Rossella Arcucci, Cosmin I. Bercea, Julia A. Schnabel</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which books do I like?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03300</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03300v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Finding enjoyable fiction books can be challenging, partly because stories are multi-faceted and one's own literary taste might be difficult to ascertain. Here, we introduce the ISAAC method (Introspection-Support, AI-Annotation, and Curation), a pipeline which supports fiction readers in gaining awareness of their literary preferences and finding enjoyable books. ISAAC consists of four steps: a user supplies book ratings, an AI agent researches and annotates the provided books, patterns in book enjoyment are reviewed by the user, and the AI agent recommends new books. In this proof-of-concept self-study, the authors test whether ISAAC can highlight idiosyncratic patterns in their book enjoyment, spark a deeper reflection about their literary tastes, and make accurate, personalized recommendations of enjoyable books and underexplored literary niches. Results highlight substantial advantages of ISAAC over existing methods such as an integration of automation and intuition, accurate and customizable annotations, and explainable book recommendations. Observed disadvantages are that ISAAC's outputs can elicit false self-narratives (if statistical patterns are taken at face value), that books cannot be annotated if their online documentation is lacking, and that people who are new to reading have to rely on assumed book ratings or movie ratings to power the ISAAC pipeline. We discuss additional opportunities of ISAAC-style book annotations for the study of literary trends, and the scientific classification of books and readers.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03300v1</guid>
      <category>cs.DL</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hannes Rosenbusch, Erdem Ozan Meral</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM as GNN: Graph Vocabulary Learning for Text-Attributed Graph Foundation Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03313</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03313v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Text-Attributed Graphs (TAGs), where each node is associated with text descriptions, are ubiquitous in real-world scenarios. They typically exhibit distinctive structure and domain-specific knowledge, motivating the development of a Graph Foundation Model (GFM) that generalizes across diverse graphs and tasks. Despite large efforts to integrate Large Language Models (LLMs) and Graph Neural Networks (GNNs) for TAGs, existing approaches suffer from decoupled architectures with two-stage alignment, limiting their synergistic potential. Even worse, existing methods assign out-of-vocabulary (OOV) tokens to graph nodes, leading to graph-specific semantics, token explosion, and incompatibility with task-oriented prompt templates, which hinders cross-graph and cross-task transferability. To address these challenges, we propose PromptGFM, a versatile GFM for TAGs grounded in graph vocabulary learning. PromptGFM comprises two key components: (1) Graph Understanding Module, which explicitly prompts LLMs to replicate the finest GNN workflow within the text space, facilitating seamless GNN-LLM integration and elegant graph-text alignment; (2) Graph Inference Module, which establishes a language-based graph vocabulary ensuring expressiveness, transferability, and scalability, enabling readable instructions for LLM fine-tuning. Extensive experiments demonstrate our superiority and transferability across diverse graphs and tasks. The code is available at this: https://github.com/agiresearch/PromptGFM.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03313v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xi Zhu, Haochen Xue, Ziwei Zhao, Wujiang Xu, Jingyuan Huang, Minghao Guo, Qifan Wang, Kaixiong Zhou, Yongfeng Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transformers for molecular property prediction: Domain adaptation efficiently improves performance</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03360</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03360v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Most of the current transformer-based chemical language models are pre-trained on millions to billions of molecules. However, the improvement from such scaling in dataset size is not confidently linked to improved molecular property prediction. The aim of this study is to investigate and overcome some of the limitations of transformer models in predicting molecular properties. Specifically, we examine the impact of pre-training dataset size and diversity on the performance of transformer models and investigate the use of domain adaptation as a technique for improving model performance. First, our findings indicate that increasing pretraining dataset size beyond 400K molecules from the GuacaMol dataset does not result in a significant improvement on four ADME endpoints, namely, solubility, permeability, microsomal stability, and plasma protein binding. Second, our results demonstrate that using domain adaptation by further training the transformer model on a small set of domain-relevant molecules, i.e., a few hundred to a few thousand, using multi-task regression of physicochemical properties was sufficient to significantly improve performance for three out of the four investigated ADME endpoints (P-value &lt; 0.001). Finally, we observe that a model pre-trained on 400K molecules and domain adopted on a few hundred/thousand molecules performs similarly (P-value &gt; 0.05) to more complicated transformer models like MolBERT(pre-trained on 1.3M molecules) and MolFormer (pre-trained on 100M molecules). A comparison to a random forest model trained on basic physicochemical properties showed similar performance to the examined transformer models. We believe that current transformer models can be improved through further systematic analysis of pre-training and downstream data, pre-training objectives, and scaling laws, ultimately leading to better and more helpful models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03360v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Afnan Sultan, Max Rausch-Dupont, Shahrukh Khan, Olga Kalinina, Andrea Volkamer, Dietrich Klakow</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unified Mind Model: Reimagining Autonomous Agents in the LLM Era</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03459</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03459v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have recently demonstrated remarkable capabilities across domains, tasks, and languages (e.g., ChatGPT and GPT-4), reviving the research of general autonomous agents with human-like cognitive abilities.Such human-level agents require semantic comprehension and instruction-following capabilities, which exactly fall into the strengths of LLMs.Although there have been several initial attempts to build human-level agents based on LLMs, the theoretical foundation remains a challenging open problem. In this paper, we propose a novel theoretical cognitive architecture, the Unified Mind Model (UMM), which offers guidance to facilitate the rapid creation of autonomous agents with human-level cognitive abilities. Specifically, our UMM starts with the global workspace theory and further leverage LLMs to enable the agent with various cognitive abilities, such as multi-modal perception, planning, reasoning, tool use, learning, memory, reflection and motivation. Building upon UMM, we then develop an agent-building engine, MindOS, which allows users to quickly create domain-/task-specific autonomous agents without any programming effort.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03459v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Pengbo Hu, Xiang Ying</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The MASK Benchmark: Disentangling Honesty From Accuracy in AI Systems</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.03750</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.03750v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: As large language models (LLMs) become more capable and agentic, the requirement for trust in their outputs grows significantly, yet at the same time concerns have been mounting that models may learn to lie in pursuit of their goals. To address these concerns, a body of work has emerged around the notion of "honesty" in LLMs, along with interventions aimed at mitigating deceptive behaviors. However, evaluations of honesty are currently highly limited, with no benchmark combining large scale and applicability to all models. Moreover, many benchmarks claiming to measure honesty in fact simply measure accuracy--the correctness of a model's beliefs--in disguise. In this work, we introduce a large-scale human-collected dataset for measuring honesty directly, allowing us to disentangle accuracy from honesty for the first time. Across a diverse set of LLMs, we find that while larger models obtain higher accuracy on our benchmark, they do not become more honest. Surprisingly, while most frontier LLMs obtain high scores on truthfulness benchmarks, we find a substantial propensity in frontier LLMs to lie when pressured to do so, resulting in low honesty scores on our benchmark. We find that simple methods, such as representation engineering interventions, can improve honesty. These results underscore the growing need for robust evaluations and effective interventions to ensure LLMs remain trustworthy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.03750v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Richard Ren, Arunim Agarwal, Mantas Mazeika, Cristina Menghini, Robert Vacareanu, Brad Kenstler, Mick Yang, Isabelle Barrass, Alice Gatti, Xuwang Yin, Eduardo Trevino, Matias Geralnik, Adam Khoja, Dean Lee, Summer Yue, Dan Hendrycks</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ExpertPrompting: Instructing Large Language Models to be Distinguished Experts</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2305.14688</link>
      <description>arXiv:2305.14688v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The answering quality of an aligned large language model (LLM) can be drastically improved if treated with proper crafting of prompts. In this paper, we propose ExpertPrompting to elicit the potential of LLMs to answer as distinguished experts. We first utilize In-Context Learning to automatically synthesize detailed and customized descriptions of the expert identity for each specific instruction, and then ask LLMs to provide answer conditioned on such agent background. Based on this augmented prompting strategy, we produce a new set of instruction-following data using GPT-3.5, and train a competitive open-source chat assistant called ExpertLLaMA. We employ GPT4-based evaluation to show that 1) the expert data is of significantly higher quality than vanilla answers, and 2) ExpertLLaMA outperforms existing open-source opponents and achieves 96\% of the original ChatGPT's capability. All data and the ExpertLLaMA model will be made publicly available at https://github.com/OFA-Sys/ExpertLLaMA.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2305.14688v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Benfeng Xu, An Yang, Junyang Lin, Quan Wang, Chang Zhou, Yongdong Zhang, Zhendong Mao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>StableToolBench: Towards Stable Large-Scale Benchmarking on Tool Learning of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.07714</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.07714v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have witnessed remarkable advancements in recent years, prompting the exploration of tool learning, which integrates LLMs with external tools to address diverse real-world challenges. Assessing the capability of LLMs to utilise tools necessitates large-scale and stable benchmarks. However, previous works relied on either hand-crafted online tools with limited scale, or large-scale real online APIs suffering from instability of API status. To address this problem, we introduce StableToolBench, a benchmark evolving from ToolBench, proposing a virtual API server and stable evaluation system. The virtual API server contains a caching system and API simulators which are complementary to alleviate the change in API status. Meanwhile, the stable evaluation system designs solvable pass and win rates using GPT-4 as the automatic evaluator to eliminate the randomness during evaluation. Experimental results demonstrate the stability of StableToolBench, and further discuss the effectiveness of API simulators, the caching system, and the evaluator system.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.07714v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhicheng Guo, Sijie Cheng, Hao Wang, Shihao Liang, Yujia Qin, Peng Li, Zhiyuan Liu, Maosong Sun, Yang Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PARAMANU-GANITA: Can Small Math Language Models Rival with Large Language Models on Mathematical Reasoning?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.14395</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.14395v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this paper, we study whether domain specific pretraining of small generative language models (SLM) from scratch with domain specialized tokenizer and Chain-of-Thought (CoT) instruction fine-tuning results in competitive performance on mathematical reasoning compared to LLMs? Secondly, whether this approach is environmentally sustainable, highly cost efficient? To address these research questions, we present Paramanu-Ganita, a 208 million-parameter novel decoder-only Auto Regressive SLM on mathematics. We performed pretraining from scratch on 31.5 billion tokens for 170 A100 hours using a context size of 4096 on a mixed mathematical corpus consisting of web pages, source code, textbooks, CoT templatised StackOverflow QA pairs, and mathematical lecture notes in LaTeX curated by us. We also trained a math and code specialised BPE tokenizer. We proposed and performed CoT instruction fine-tuning of Paramanu-Ganita on the MetaMathQA dataset. Our model Paramanu-Ganita, despite being 34 times smaller than the 7B LLMs, outperforms generalist LLMs by approximately 30% points, and even math-specialised LLMs by 3-23% points in GSM8K test accuracy metric. On MATH benchmark, Paramanu-Ganita outperformed the various models by 6-8% points. On benchmarks like LogiQA, MMLU (high school, college level), and competitive exams level, AGIEVAL (AQuA-RAT, SAT-Math), Paramanu-Ganita outperformed others by 1-4%. Our model is available at https://huggingface.co/gyanai/paramanu-ganita-208M-hf .</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.14395v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mitodru Niyogi, Arnab Bhattacharya</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Effective Time-Aware Language Representation: Exploring Enhanced Temporal Understanding in Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.01863</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.01863v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In the evolving field of Natural Language Processing (NLP), understanding the temporal context of text is increasingly critical for applications requiring advanced temporal reasoning. Traditional pre-trained language models like BERT, which rely on synchronic document collections such as BookCorpus and Wikipedia, often fall short in effectively capturing and leveraging temporal information. To address this limitation, we introduce BiTimeBERT 2.0, a novel time-aware language model pre-trained on a temporal news article collection. BiTimeBERT 2.0 incorporates temporal information through three innovative pre-training objectives: Extended Time-Aware Masked Language Modeling (ETAMLM), Document Dating (DD), and Time-Sensitive Entity Replacement (TSER). Each objective is specifically designed to target a distinct dimension of temporal information: ETAMLM enhances the model's understanding of temporal contexts and relations, DD integrates document timestamps as explicit chronological markers, and TSER focuses on the temporal dynamics of "Person" entities. Moreover, our refined corpus preprocessing strategy reduces training time by nearly 53\%, making BiTimeBERT 2.0 significantly more efficient while maintaining high performance. Experimental results show that BiTimeBERT 2.0 achieves substantial improvements across a broad range of time-related tasks and excels on datasets spanning extensive temporal ranges. These findings underscore BiTimeBERT 2.0's potential as a powerful tool for advancing temporal reasoning in NLP.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.01863v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiexin Wang, Adam Jatowt, Yi Cai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On-Policy Self-Alignment with Fine-grained Knowledge Feedback for Hallucination Mitigation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.12221</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.12221v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Hallucination occurs when large language models exhibit behavior that deviates from the boundaries of their knowledge during response generation. To address this critical issue, previous learning-based methods attempt to finetune models but are limited by off-policy sampling and coarse-grained feedback. In this paper, we present \textit{\b{R}einforcement \b{L}earning \b{f}or \b{H}allucination} (RLFH), an on-policy self-alignment approach that enables LLMs to actively explore their knowledge boundaries and self-correct generation behavior through fine-grained feedback signals. RLFH introduces a self-assessment framework where the policy serves as its own judge. Through this framework, responses are automatically decomposed into atomic facts and their truthfulness and informativeness are assessed against external knowledge sources. The resulting fine-grained feedback at the statement level are then converted into token-level dense reward signals. This enables online reinforcement learning to achieve precise and timely optimization without human intervention. Comprehensive evaluations on HotpotQA, SQuADv2, and Biography benchmarks validate RLFH's effectiveness in hallucination mitigation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.12221v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xueru Wen, Jie Lou, Xinyu Lu, Ji Yuqiu, Xinyan Guan, Yaojie Lu, Hongyu Lin, Ben He, Xianpei Han, Debing Zhang, Le Sun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Simplified Retriever to Improve Accuracy of Phenotype Normalizations by Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.13744</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.13744v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have shown improved accuracy in phenotype term normalization tasks when augmented with retrievers that suggest candidate normalizations based on term definitions. In this work, we introduce a simplified retriever that enhances LLM accuracy by searching the Human Phenotype Ontology (HPO) for candidate matches using contextual word embeddings from BioBERT without the need for explicit term definitions. Testing this method on terms derived from the clinical synopses of Online Mendelian Inheritance in Man (OMIM), we demonstrate that the normalization accuracy of a state-of-the-art LLM increases from a baseline of 62.3% without augmentation to 90.3% with retriever augmentation. This approach is potentially generalizable to other biomedical term normalization tasks and offers an efficient alternative to more complex retrieval methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.13744v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.3389/fdgth.2025.1495040</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Frontiers in Digital Health 7, (2025): 1495040. Accessed March 4, 2025</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Daniel B. Hier, Thanh Son Do, Tayo Obafemi-Ajayi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CPT-Boosted Wav2vec2.0: Towards Noise Robust Speech Recognition for Classroom Environments</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.14494</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.14494v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Creating Automatic Speech Recognition (ASR) systems that are robust and resilient to classroom conditions is paramount to the development of AI tools to aid teachers and students. In this work, we study the efficacy of continued pretraining (CPT) in adapting Wav2vec2.0 to the classroom domain. We show that CPT is a powerful tool in that regard and reduces the Word Error Rate (WER) of Wav2vec2.0-based models by upwards of 10%. More specifically, CPT improves the model's robustness to different noises, microphones and classroom conditions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.14494v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ahmed Adel Attia, Dorottya Demszky, Tolulope Ogunremi, Jing Liu, Carol Espy-Wilson</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is a Digital Twin Anyway? Deriving the Definition for the Built Environment from over 15,000 Scientific Publications</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.19005</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.19005v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The concept of digital twins has attracted significant attention across various domains, particularly within the built environment. However, there is a sheer volume of definitions and the terminological consensus remains out of reach. The lack of a universally accepted definition leads to ambiguities in their conceptualization and implementation, and may cause miscommunication for both researchers and practitioners. We employed Natural Language Processing (NLP) techniques to systematically extract and analyze definitions of digital twins from a corpus of more than 15,000 full-text articles spanning diverse disciplines. The study compares these findings with insights from an expert survey that included 52 experts. The study identifies concurrence on the components that comprise a ``Digital Twin'' from a practical perspective across various domains, contrasting them with those that do not, to identify deviations. We investigate the evolution of digital twin definitions over time and across different scales, including manufacturing, building, and urban/geospatial perspectives. We extracted the main components of Digital Twins using Text Frequency Analysis and N-gram analysis. Subsequently, we identified components that appeared in the literature and conducted a Chi-square test to assess the significance of each component in different domains. Our analysis identified key components of digital twins and revealed significant variations in definitions based on application domains, such as manufacturing, building, and urban contexts. The analysis of DT components reveal two major groups of DT types: High-Performance Real-Time (HPRT) DTs, and Long-Term Decision Support (LTDS) DTs. Contrary to common assumptions, we found that components such as simulation, AI/ML, real-time capabilities, and bi-directional data flow are not yet fully mature in the digital twins of the built environment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.19005v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1016/j.buildenv.2025.112748</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Building and Environment, 274: 112748, 2025</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Mahmoud Abdelrahman, Edgardo Macatulad, Binyu Lei, Matias Quintana, Clayton Miller, Filip Biljecki</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DelTA: An Online Document-Level Translation Agent Based on Multi-Level Memory</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.08143</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.08143v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have achieved reasonable quality improvements in machine translation (MT). However, most current research on MT-LLMs still faces significant challenges in maintaining translation consistency and accuracy when processing entire documents. In this paper, we introduce DelTA, a Document-levEL Translation Agent designed to overcome these limitations. DelTA features a multi-level memory structure that stores information across various granularities and spans, including Proper Noun Records, Bilingual Summary, Long-Term Memory, and Short-Term Memory, which are continuously retrieved and updated by auxiliary LLM-based components. Experimental results indicate that DelTA significantly outperforms strong baselines in terms of translation consistency and quality across four open/closed-source LLMs and two representative document translation datasets, achieving an increase in consistency scores by up to 4.58 percentage points and in COMET scores by up to 3.16 points on average. DelTA employs a sentence-by-sentence translation strategy, ensuring no sentence omissions and offering a memory-efficient solution compared to the mainstream method. Furthermore, DelTA improves pronoun and context-dependent translation accuracy, and the summary component of the agent also shows promise as a tool for query-based summarization tasks. The code and data of our approach are released at https://github.com/YutongWang1216/DocMTAgent.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.08143v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Published as a conference paper at ICLR 2025</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Yutong Wang, Jiali Zeng, Xuebo Liu, Derek F. Wong, Fandong Meng, Jie Zhou, Min Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LongMemEval: Benchmarking Chat Assistants on Long-Term Interactive Memory</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.10813</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.10813v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent large language model (LLM)-driven chat assistant systems have integrated memory components to track user-assistant chat histories, enabling more accurate and personalized responses. However, their long-term memory capabilities in sustained interactions remain underexplored. We introduce LongMemEval, a comprehensive benchmark designed to evaluate five core long-term memory abilities of chat assistants: information extraction, multi-session reasoning, temporal reasoning, knowledge updates, and abstention. With 500 meticulously curated questions embedded within freely scalable user-assistant chat histories, LongMemEval presents a significant challenge to existing long-term memory systems, with commercial chat assistants and long-context LLMs showing a 30% accuracy drop on memorizing information across sustained interactions. We then present a unified framework that breaks down the long-term memory design into three stages: indexing, retrieval, and reading. Built upon key experimental insights, we propose several memory design optimizations including session decomposition for value granularity, fact-augmented key expansion for indexing, and time-aware query expansion for refining the search scope. Extensive experiments show that these optimizations greatly improve both memory recall and downstream question answering on LongMemEval. Overall, our study provides valuable resources and guidance for advancing the long-term memory capabilities of LLM-based chat assistants, paving the way toward more personalized and reliable conversational AI. Our benchmark and code are publicly available at https://github.com/xiaowu0162/LongMemEval.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.10813v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Di Wu, Hongwei Wang, Wenhao Yu, Yuwei Zhang, Kai-Wei Chang, Dong Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MIRROR: A Novel Approach for the Automated Evaluation of Open-Ended Question Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.12893</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.12893v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Automatic question generation is a critical task that involves evaluating question quality by considering factors such as engagement, pedagogical value, and the ability to stimulate critical thinking. These aspects require human-like understanding and judgment, which automated systems currently lack. However, human evaluations are costly and impractical for large-scale samples of generated questions. Therefore, we propose a novel system, MIRROR (Multi-LLM Iterative Review and Response for Optimized Rating), which leverages large language models (LLMs) to automate the evaluation process for questions generated by automated question generation systems. We experimented with several state-of-the-art LLMs, such as GPT-4, Gemini, and Llama2-70b. We observed that the scores of human evaluation metrics, namely relevance, appropriateness, novelty, complexity, and grammaticality, improved when using the feedback-based approach called MIRROR, tending to be closer to the human baseline scores. Furthermore, we observed that Pearson's correlation coefficient between GPT-4 and human experts improved when using our proposed feedback-based approach, MIRROR, compared to direct prompting for evaluation. Error analysis shows that our proposed approach, MIRROR, significantly helps to improve relevance and appropriateness.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.12893v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aniket Deroy, Subhankar Maity, Sudeshna Sarkar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CycleResearcher: Improving Automated Research via Automated Review</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.00816</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.00816v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The automation of scientific discovery has been a long-standing goal within the research community, driven by the potential to accelerate knowledge creation. While significant progress has been made using commercial large language models (LLMs) as research assistants or idea generators, the possibility of automating the entire research process with open-source LLMs remains largely unexplored. This paper explores the feasibility of using open-source post-trained LLMs as autonomous agents capable of performing the full cycle of automated research and review, from literature review and manuscript preparation to peer review and paper refinement. Our iterative preference training framework consists of CycleResearcher, which conducts research tasks, and CycleReviewer, which simulates the peer review process, providing iterative feedback via reinforcement learning. To train these models, we develop two new datasets, Review-5k and Research-14k, reflecting real-world machine learning research and peer review dynamics. Our results demonstrate that CycleReviewer achieves promising performance with a 26.89\% reduction in mean absolute error (MAE) compared to individual human reviewers in predicting paper scores, indicating the potential of LLMs to effectively assist expert-level research evaluation. In research, the papers generated by the CycleResearcher model achieved a score of 5.36 in simulated peer reviews, showing some competitiveness in terms of simulated review scores compared to the preprint level of 5.24 from human experts, while still having room for improvement compared to the accepted paper level of 5.69. This work represents a significant step toward fully automated scientific inquiry, providing ethical safeguards and exploring AI-driven research capabilities. The code, dataset and model weight are released at https://wengsyx.github.io/Researcher/</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.00816v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yixuan Weng, Minjun Zhu, Guangsheng Bao, Hongbo Zhang, Jindong Wang, Yue Zhang, Linyi Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Consistency Falls Short! The Adverse Effects of Positional Bias on Long-Context Problems</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.01101</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.01101v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Self-consistency (SC) has been demonstrated to enhance the performance of large language models (LLMs) across various tasks and domains involving short content. However, does this evidence support its effectiveness for long-context problems?
  We challenge the assumption that SC's benefits generalize to long-context settings, where LLMs often struggle with position bias--a systematic tendency to over-rely on specific context regions-which hinders their ability to utilize information effectively from all parts of their context. Through comprehensive experimentation with varying state-of-the-art models and tasks, we find that SC not only fails to improve but actively degrades performance on long-context tasks. This degradation appears driven by persistent position bias, worsening with longer context lengths and smaller model sizes, but invariant to prompt format or task type. Unlike short-context tasks, where SC diversifies reasoning paths, long-context SC amplifies positional errors. These comprehensive results provide valuable insight into the limitations of current LLMs in long-context understanding and highlight the need for more sophisticated approaches.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.01101v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Adam Byerly, Daniel Khashabi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Number Cookbook: Number Understanding of Language Models and How to Improve It</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.03766</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.03766v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) can solve an increasing number of complex reasoning tasks while making surprising mistakes in basic numerical understanding and processing (such as 9.11 &gt; 9.9). The latter ability is essential for tackling complex arithmetic and mathematical problems and serves as a foundation for most reasoning tasks, but previous work paid little attention to it or only discussed several restricted tasks (like integer addition). In this paper, we comprehensively investigate the numerical understanding and processing ability (NUPA) of LLMs. Firstly, we introduce a benchmark covering four common numerical representations and 17 distinct numerical tasks in four major categories, resulting in 41 meaningful combinations in total. These tasks are derived from primary and secondary education curricula, encompassing nearly all everyday numerical understanding and processing scenarios, and the rules of these tasks are very simple and clear. Through the benchmark, we find that current LLMs fail frequently in many of the tasks. To study the problem, we train small models with existing and potential techniques for enhancing NUPA (such as tokenizers, PEs, and number formats), comprehensively evaluating their effectiveness using our testbed. We also finetune practical-scale LLMs on our proposed NUPA tasks and find that 1) naive finetuning can improve NUPA a lot on many but not all tasks, and 2) surprisingly, techniques designed to enhance NUPA prove ineffective for finetuning pretrained models. We further explore the impact of chain-of-thought techniques on NUPA. Our work provides a more detailed and comprehensive understanding of NUPA in LLMs. Our benchmark and code are released at https://github.com/GraphPKU/number_cookbook.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.03766v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haotong Yang, Yi Hu, Shijia Kang, Zhouchen Lin, Muhan Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prompt-enhanced Network for Hateful Meme Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.07527</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.07527v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The dynamic expansion of social media has led to an inundation of hateful memes on media platforms, accentuating the growing need for efficient identification and removal. Acknowledging the constraints of conventional multimodal hateful meme classification, which heavily depends on external knowledge and poses the risk of including irrelevant or redundant content, we developed Pen -- a prompt-enhanced network framework based on the prompt learning approach. Specifically, after constructing the sequence through the prompt method and encoding it with a language model, we performed region information global extraction on the encoded sequence for multi-view perception. By capturing global information about inference instances and demonstrations, Pen facilitates category selection by fully leveraging sequence information. This approach significantly improves model classification accuracy. Additionally, to bolster the model's reasoning capabilities in the feature space, we introduced prompt-aware contrastive learning into the framework to improve the quality of sample feature distributions. Through extensive ablation experiments on two public datasets, we evaluate the effectiveness of the Pen framework, concurrently comparing it with state-of-the-art model baselines. Our research findings highlight that Pen surpasses manual prompt methods, showcasing superior generalization and classification accuracy in hateful meme classification tasks. Our code is available at https://github.com/juszzi/Pen.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.07527v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.24963/ijcai.2024/707</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Junxi Liu, Yanyan Feng, Jiehai Chen, Yun Xue, Fenghuan Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gated Delta Networks: Improving Mamba2 with Delta Rule</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.06464</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.06464v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Linear Transformers have gained attention as efficient alternatives to standard Transformers, but their performance in retrieval and long-context tasks has been limited. To address these limitations, recent work has explored two distinct mechanisms: gating for adaptive memory control and the delta update rule for precise memory modifications. We observe that these mechanisms are complementary: gating enables rapid memory erasure while the delta rule facilitates targeted updates. Building on this insight, we introduce the gated delta rule and develop a parallel training algorithm optimized for modern hardware. Our proposed architecture, Gated DeltaNet, consistently surpasses existing models like Mamba2 and DeltaNet across multiple benchmarks, including language modeling, common-sense reasoning, in-context retrieval, length extrapolation, and long-context understanding. We further enhance performance by developing hybrid architectures that combine Gated DeltaNet layers with sliding window attention or Mamba2 layers, achieving both improved training efficiency and superior task performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.06464v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Songlin Yang, Jan Kautz, Ali Hatamizadeh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChaI-TeA: A Benchmark for Evaluating Autocompletion of Interactions with LLM-based Chatbots</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18377</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18377v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The rise of LLMs has deflected a growing portion of human-computer interactions towards LLM-based chatbots. The remarkable abilities of these models allow users to interact using long, diverse natural language text covering a wide range of topics and styles. Phrasing these messages is a time and effort consuming task, calling for an autocomplete solution to assist users. We introduce the task of chatbot interaction autocomplete. We present ChaI-TeA: CHat InTEraction Autocomplete; An autcomplete evaluation framework for LLM-based chatbot interactions. The framework includes a formal definition of the task, coupled with suitable datasets and metrics. We use the framework to evaluate After formally defining the task along with suitable datasets and metrics, we test 9 models on the defined auto completion task, finding that while current off-the-shelf models perform fairly, there is still much room for improvement, mainly in ranking of the generated suggestions. We provide insights for practitioners working on this task and open new research directions for researchers in the field. We release our framework to serve as a foundation for future research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18377v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shani Goren, Oren Kalinsky, Tomer Stav, Yuri Rapoport, Yaron Fairstein, Ram Yazdi, Nachshon Cohen, Alexander Libov, Guy Kushilevitz</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Affordably Fine-tuned LLMs Provide Better Answers to Course-specific MCQs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.05891</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.05891v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In education, the capability of generating human-like text of Large Language Models (LLMs) inspired work on how they can increase the efficiency of learning and teaching. We study the affordability of these models for educators and students by investigating how LLMs answer multiple-choice questions (MCQs) with respect to hardware constraints and refinement techniques. We explore this space by using generic pre-trained LLMs (the 7B, 13B, and 70B variants of LLaMA-2) to answer 162 undergraduate-level MCQs from a course on Programming Languages (PL) -- the MCQ dataset is a contribution of this work, which we make publicly available. Specifically, we dissect how different factors, such as using readily-available material -- (parts of) the course's textbook -- for fine-tuning and quantisation (to decrease resource usage) can change the accuracy of the responses. The main takeaway is that smaller textbook-based fine-tuned models outperform generic larger ones (whose pre-training requires conspicuous resources), making the usage of LLMs for answering MCQs resource- and material-wise affordable.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.05891v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bianca Raimondi, Saverio Giallorenzo, Maurizio Gabbrielli</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling Simplicities of Attention: Adaptive Long-Context Head Identification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09647</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09647v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The ability to process long contexts is crucial for many natural language processing tasks, yet it remains a significant challenge. While substantial progress has been made in enhancing the efficiency of attention mechanisms, there is still a gap in understanding how attention heads function in long-context settings. In this paper, we observe that while certain heads consistently attend to local information only, others swing between attending to local and long-context information depending on the query. This raises the question: can we identify which heads require long-context information to predict the next token accurately? We demonstrate that it's possible to predict which heads are crucial for long-context processing using only local keys. The core idea here is to exploit a simple model for the long-context scores via second moment approximations. These findings unveil simple properties of attention in the context of long sequences, and open the door to potentially significant gains in efficiency.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09647v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Konstantin Donhauser, Charles Arnal, Mohammad Pezeshki, Vivien Cabannes, David Lopez-Paz, Kartik Ahuja</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LaRA: Benchmarking Retrieval-Augmented Generation and Long-Context LLMs -- No Silver Bullet for LC or RAG Routing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.09977</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.09977v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Effectively incorporating external knowledge into Large Language Models (LLMs) is crucial for enhancing their capabilities and addressing real-world needs. Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) offers an effective method for achieving this by retrieving the most relevant fragments into LLMs. However, the advancements in context window size for LLMs offer an alternative approach, raising the question of whether RAG remains necessary for effectively handling external knowledge. Several existing studies provide inconclusive comparisons between RAG and long-context (LC) LLMs, largely due to limitations in the benchmark designs. In this paper, we present LaRA, a novel benchmark specifically designed to rigorously compare RAG and LC LLMs. LaRA encompasses 2326 test cases across four practical QA task categories and three types of naturally occurring long texts. Through systematic evaluation of seven open-source and four proprietary LLMs, we find that the optimal choice between RAG and LC depends on a complex interplay of factors, including the model's parameter size, long-text capabilities, context length, task type, and the characteristics of the retrieved chunks. Our findings provide actionable guidelines for practitioners to effectively leverage both RAG and LC approaches in developing and deploying LLM applications. Our code and dataset is provided at: \href{https://github.com/Alibaba-NLP/LaRA}{\textbf{https://github.com/Alibaba-NLP/LaRA}}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.09977v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kuan Li, Liwen Zhang, Yong Jiang, Pengjun Xie, Fei Huang, Shuai Wang, Minhao Cheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DuplexMamba: Enhancing Real-time Speech Conversations with Duplex and Streaming Capabilities</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.11123</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.11123v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Real-time speech conversation is essential for natural and efficient human-machine interactions, requiring duplex and streaming capabilities. Traditional Transformer-based conversational chatbots operate in a turn-based manner and exhibit quadratic computational complexity that grows as the input size increases. In this paper, we propose DuplexMamba, a Mamba-based end-to-end multimodal duplex model for speech-to-text conversation. DuplexMamba enables simultaneous input processing and output generation, dynamically adjusting to support real-time streaming. Specifically, we develop a Mamba-based speech encoder and adapt it with a Mamba-based language model. Furthermore, we introduce a novel duplex decoding strategy that enables DuplexMamba to process input and generate output simultaneously. Experimental results demonstrate that DuplexMamba successfully implements duplex and streaming capabilities while achieving performance comparable to several recently developed Transformer-based models in automatic speech recognition (ASR) tasks and voice assistant benchmark evaluations. Our code and model are released</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.11123v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiangyu Lu, Wang Xu, Haoyu Wang, Hongyun Zhou, Haiyan Zhao, Conghui Zhu, Tiejun Zhao, Muyun Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RIDE: Enhancing Large Language Model Alignment through Restyled In-Context Learning Demonstration Exemplars</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.11681</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.11681v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Alignment tuning is crucial for ensuring large language models (LLMs) behave ethically and helpfully. Current alignment approaches require high-quality annotations and significant training resources. This paper proposes a low-cost, tuning-free method using in-context learning (ICL) to enhance LLM alignment. Through an analysis of high-quality ICL demos, we identified style as a key factor influencing LLM alignment capabilities and explicitly restyled ICL exemplars based on this stylistic framework. Additionally, we combined the restyled demos to achieve a balance between the two conflicting aspects of LLM alignment--factuality and safety. We packaged the restyled examples as prompts to trigger few-shot learning, improving LLM alignment. Compared to the best baseline approach, with an average score of 5.00 as the maximum, our method achieves a maximum 0.10 increase on the Alpaca task (from 4.50 to 4.60), a 0.22 enhancement on the Just-eval benchmark (from 4.34 to 4.56), and a maximum improvement of 0.32 (from 3.53 to 3.85) on the MT-Bench dataset. We release the code and data at https://github.com/AnonymousCode-ComputerScience/RIDE.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.11681v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuncheng Hua, Lizhen Qu, Zhuang Li, Hao Xue, Flora D. Salim, Gholamreza Haffari</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Baichuan-M1: Pushing the Medical Capability of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.12671</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.12671v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The current generation of large language models (LLMs) is typically designed for broad, general-purpose applications, while domain-specific LLMs, especially in vertical fields like medicine, remain relatively scarce. In particular, the development of highly efficient and practical LLMs for the medical domain is challenging due to the complexity of medical knowledge and the limited availability of high-quality data. To bridge this gap, we introduce Baichuan-M1, a series of large language models specifically optimized for medical applications. Unlike traditional approaches that simply continue pretraining on existing models or apply post-training to a general base model, Baichuan-M1 is trained from scratch with a dedicated focus on enhancing medical capabilities. Our model is trained on 20 trillion tokens and incorporates a range of effective training methods that strike a balance between general capabilities and medical expertise. As a result, Baichuan-M1 not only performs strongly across general domains such as mathematics and coding but also excels in specialized medical fields. We have open-sourced Baichuan-M1-14B, a mini version of our model, which can be accessed through the following links.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.12671v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bingning Wang, Haizhou Zhao, Huozhi Zhou, Liang Song, Mingyu Xu, Wei Cheng, Xiangrong Zeng, Yupeng Zhang, Yuqi Huo, Zecheng Wang, Zhengyun Zhao, Da Pan, Fei Kou, Fei Li, Fuzhong Chen, Guosheng Dong, Han Liu, Hongda Zhang, Jin He, Jinjie Yang, Kangxi Wu, Kegeng Wu, Lei Su, Linlin Niu, Linzhuang Sun, Mang Wang, Pengcheng Fan, Qianli Shen, Rihui Xin, Shunya Dang, Songchi Zhou, Weipeng Chen, Wenjing Luo, Xin Chen, Xin Men, Xionghai Lin, Xuezhen Dong, Yan Zhang, Yifei Duan, Yuyan Zhou, Zhi Ma, Zhiying Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Conversational Agents with Theory of Mind: Aligning Beliefs, Desires, and Intentions for Human-Like Interaction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.14171</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.14171v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Natural language interaction with agentic Artificial Intelligence (AI), driven by Large Language Models (LLMs), is expected to remain a dominant paradigm in the near future. While humans instinctively align their communication with mental states -- an ability known as Theory of Mind (ToM), current LLM powered systems exhibit significant limitations in this regard. This study examines the extent to which open source language models (LLaMA) can capture and preserve ToM related information and how effectively it contributes to consistent ToM reasoning in generated responses. We further investigate whether explicit manipulation of ToM related components, such as beliefs, desires, and intentions, can enhance response alignment. Experiments on two LLaMA 3 variants demonstrate that incorporating ToM informed alignment improves response quality, achieving win rates of 67 and 63 percent for the 3B and 8B models, respectively. These findings highlight the potential of ToM driven strategies to improve alignment in LLM based conversational agents.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.14171v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mehdi Jafari, Devin Yuncheng Hua, Hao Xue, Flora Salim</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>English Please: Evaluating Machine Translation for Multilingual Bug Reports</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.14338</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.14338v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Accurate translation of bug reports is critical for efficient collaboration in global software development. In this study, we conduct the first comprehensive evaluation of machine translation (MT) performance on bug reports, analyzing the capabilities of DeepL, AWS Translate, and ChatGPT using data from the Visual Studio Code GitHub repository, specifically focusing on reports labeled with the english-please tag. To thoroughly assess the accuracy and effectiveness of each system, we employ multiple machine translation metrics, including BLEU, BERTScore, COMET, METEOR, and ROUGE. Our findings indicate that DeepL consistently outperforms the other systems across most automatic metrics, demonstrating strong lexical and semantic alignment. AWS Translate performs competitively, particularly in METEOR, while ChatGPT lags in key metrics. This study underscores the importance of domain adaptation for translating technical texts and offers guidance for integrating automated translation into bug-triaging workflows. Moreover, our results establish a foundation for future research to refine machine translation solutions for specialized engineering contexts. The code and dataset for this paper are available at GitHub: https://github.com/av9ash/gitbugs/tree/main/multilingual.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.14338v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Avinash Patil, Aryan Jadon</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SuperGPQA: Scaling LLM Evaluation across 285 Graduate Disciplines</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.14739</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.14739v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated remarkable proficiency in mainstream academic disciplines such as mathematics, physics, and computer science. However, human knowledge encompasses over 200 specialized disciplines, far exceeding the scope of existing benchmarks. The capabilities of LLMs in many of these specialized fields-particularly in light industry, agriculture, and service-oriented disciplines-remain inadequately evaluated. To address this gap, we present SuperGPQA, a comprehensive benchmark that evaluates graduate-level knowledge and reasoning capabilities across 285 disciplines. Our benchmark employs a novel Human-LLM collaborative filtering mechanism to eliminate trivial or ambiguous questions through iterative refinement based on both LLM responses and expert feedback. Our experimental results reveal significant room for improvement in the performance of current state-of-the-art LLMs across diverse knowledge domains (e.g., the reasoning-focused model DeepSeek-R1 achieved the highest accuracy of 61.82% on SuperGPQA), highlighting the considerable gap between current model capabilities and artificial general intelligence. Additionally, we present comprehensive insights from our management of a large-scale annotation process, involving over 80 expert annotators and an interactive Human-LLM collaborative system, offering valuable methodological guidance for future research initiatives of comparable scope.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.14739v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator> P Team, Xinrun Du, Yifan Yao, Kaijing Ma, Bingli Wang, Tianyu Zheng, Kang Zhu, Minghao Liu, Yiming Liang, Xiaolong Jin, Zhenlin Wei, Chujie Zheng, Kaixin Deng, Shian Jia, Sichao Jiang, Yiyan Liao, Rui Li, Qinrui Li, Sirun Li, Yizhi Li, Yunwen Li, Dehua Ma, Yuansheng Ni, Haoran Que, Qiyao Wang, Zhoufutu Wen, Siwei Wu, Tianshun Xing, Ming Xu, Zhenzhu Yang, Zekun Moore Wang, Junting Zhou, Yuelin Bai, Xingyuan Bu, Chenglin Cai, Liang Chen, Yifan Chen, Chengtuo Cheng, Tianhao Cheng, Keyi Ding, Siming Huang, Yun Huang, Yaoru Li, Yizhe Li, Zhaoqun Li, Tianhao Liang, Chengdong Lin, Hongquan Lin, Yinghao Ma, Tianyang Pang, Zhongyuan Peng, Zifan Peng, Qige Qi, Shi Qiu, Xingwei Qu, Shanghaoran Quan, Yizhou Tan, Zili Wang, Chenqing Wang, Hao Wang, Yiya Wang, Yubo Wang, Jiajun Xu, Kexin Yang, Ruibin Yuan, Yuanhao Yue, Tianyang Zhan, Chun Zhang, Jinyang Zhang, Xiyue Zhang, Xingjian Zhang, Yue Zhang, Yongchi Zhao, Xiangyu Zheng, Chenghua Zhong, Yang Gao, Zhoujun Li, Dayiheng Liu, Qian Liu, Tianyu Liu, Shiwen Ni, Junran Peng, Yujia Qin, Wenbo Su, Guoyin Wang, Shi Wang, Jian Yang, Min Yang, Meng Cao, Xiang Yue, Zhaoxiang Zhang, Wangchunshu Zhou, Jiaheng Liu, Qunshu Lin, Wenhao Huang, Ge Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unsupervised Topic Models are Data Mixers for Pre-training Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.16802</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.16802v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The performance of large language models (LLMs) is significantly affected by the quality and composition of their pre-training data, which is inherently diverse, spanning various domains, sources, and topics. Effectively integrating these heterogeneous data sources is crucial for optimizing LLM performance. Previous research has predominantly concentrated on domain-based data mixing, often neglecting the nuanced topic-level characteristics of the data. To address this gap, we propose a simple yet effective topic-based data mixing strategy that utilizes fine-grained topics generated through our topic modeling method, DataWeave. DataWeave employs a multi-stage clustering process to group semantically similar documents and utilizes LLMs to generate detailed topics, thereby facilitating a more nuanced understanding of dataset composition. Our strategy employs heuristic methods to upsample or downsample specific topics, which significantly enhances LLM performance on downstream tasks, achieving superior results compared to previous, more complex data mixing approaches. Furthermore, we confirm that the topics Science and Relationships are particularly effective, yielding the most substantial performance improvements. We will make our code and datasets publicly available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.16802v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiahui Peng, Xinlin Zhuang, Qiu Jiantao, Ren Ma, Jing Yu, Tianyi Bai, Conghui He</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advantage-Guided Distillation for Preference Alignment in Small Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.17927</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.17927v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Alignment techniques enable Large Language Models (LLMs) to generate outputs that align with human preferences and play a crucial role in their effectiveness. However, their impact often diminishes when applied to Small Language Models (SLMs), likely due to the limited capacity of these models. Instead of directly applying existing alignment techniques to SLMs, we propose to utilize a well-aligned teacher LLM to guide the alignment process for these models, thereby facilitating the transfer of the teacher's knowledge of human preferences to the student model. To achieve this, we first explore a straightforward approach, Dual-Constrained Knowledge Distillation (DCKD), that employs knowledge distillation with two KL-divergence constraints from the aligned teacher to the unaligned student. To further enhance the student's ability to distinguish between preferred and dispreferred responses, we then propose Advantage-Guided Distillation for Preference Alignment (ADPA), which leverages an advantage function from the aligned teacher to deliver more nuanced, distribution-level reward signals for the student's alignment. Our experimental results show that these two approaches appreciably improve the alignment of SLMs and narrow the performance gap with larger counterparts. Among them, ADPA demonstrates superior performance and achieves even greater effectiveness when integrated with DCKD. Our code is available at https://github.com/SLIT-AI/ADPA.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.17927v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shiping Gao, Fanqi Wan, Jiajian Guo, Xiaojun Quan, Qifan Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Better Aligned with Survey Respondents or Training Data? Unveiling Political Leanings of LLMs on U.S. Supreme Court Cases</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.18282</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.18282v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The increased adoption of Large Language Models (LLMs) and their potential to shape public opinion have sparked interest in assessing these models' political leanings. Building on previous research that compared LLMs and human opinions and observed political bias in system responses, we take a step further to investigate the underlying causes of such biases by empirically examining how the values and biases embedded in training corpora shape model outputs. Specifically, we propose a method to quantitatively evaluate political leanings embedded in the large pretraining corpora. Subsequently we investigate to whom are the LLMs' political leanings more aligned with, their pretrainig corpora or the surveyed human opinions. As a case study, we focus on probing the political leanings of LLMs in 32 U.S. Supreme Court cases, addressing contentious topics such as abortion and voting rights. Our findings reveal that LLMs strongly reflect the political leanings in their training data, and no strong correlation is observed with their alignment to human opinions as expressed in surveys. These results underscore the importance of responsible curation of training data and the need for robust evaluation metrics to ensure LLMs' alignment with human-centered values.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.18282v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shanshan Xu, T. Y. S. S Santosh, Yanai Elazar, Quirin Vogel, Barbara Plank, Matthias Grabmair</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weaker LLMs' Opinions Also Matter: Mixture of Opinions Enhances LLM's Mathematical Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.19622</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.19622v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advances in Large Language Models (LLMs) have raised interest in their formal reasoning capabilities, particularly in mathematics. While closed LLMs like GPT-4 perform well on mathematical benchmarks, e.g., GSM8K, it remains unclear whether small to medium-sized open LLMs can achieve similar performance, questioning their reliability. To close this gap, we propose a post-training approach leveraging a mixture of opinions (MoO) from weaker ancillary LLMs to enhance a (relatively) stronger LLM's reasoning. For that, each post-training sample is augmented with Chain-of-Thought (CoT) reasoning steps and answers from ancillary LLMs, enabling the main LLM to learn from diverse perspectives. We compare MoO with standard supervised fine-tuning (SFT), few-shot prompting, and the Mixture of Agents (MoA) method on mathematical reasoning benchmarks. Our results show that incorporating weaker LLMs' opinions improves mathematical reasoning by an average of 5%, highlighting the value of diverse perspectives in reasoning tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.19622v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yanan Chen, Ali Pesaranghader, Tanmana Sadhu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promote, Suppress, Iterate: How Language Models Answer One-to-Many Factual Queries</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.20475</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.20475v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: To answer one-to-many factual queries (e.g., listing cities of a country), a language model (LM) must simultaneously recall knowledge and avoid repeating previous answers. How are these two subtasks implemented and integrated internally? Across multiple datasets and models, we identify a promote-then-suppress mechanism: the model first recalls all answers, and then suppresses previously generated ones. Specifically, LMs use both the subject and previous answer tokens to perform knowledge recall, with attention propagating subject information and MLPs promoting the answers. Then, attention attends to and suppresses previous answer tokens, while MLPs amplify the suppression signal. Our mechanism is corroborated by extensive experimental evidence: in addition to using early decoding and causal tracing, we analyze how components use different tokens by introducing both Token Lens, which decodes aggregated attention updates from specified tokens, and a knockout method that analyzes changes in MLP outputs after removing attention to specified tokens. Overall, we provide new insights into how LMs' internal components interact with different input tokens to support complex factual recall. Code is available at https://github.com/Lorenayannnnn/how-lms-answer-one-to-many-factual-queries.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.20475v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tianyi Lorena Yan, Robin Jia</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protecting multimodal large language models against misleading visualizations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.20503</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.20503v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We assess the vulnerability of multimodal large language models to misleading visualizations - charts that distort the underlying data using techniques such as truncated or inverted axes, leading readers to draw inaccurate conclusions that may support misinformation or conspiracy theories. Our analysis shows that these distortions severely harm multimodal large language models, reducing their question-answering accuracy to the level of the random baseline. To mitigate this vulnerability, we introduce six inference-time methods to improve performance of MLLMs on misleading visualizations while preserving their accuracy on non-misleading ones. The most effective approach involves (1) extracting the underlying data table and (2) using a text-only large language model to answer questions based on the table. This method improves performance on misleading visualizations by 15.4 to 19.6 percentage points.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.20503v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jonathan Tonglet, Tinne Tuytelaars, Marie-Francine Moens, Iryna Gurevych</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Noisy Path from Source to Citation: Measuring How Scholars Engage with Past Research</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.20581</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.20581v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Academic citations are widely used for evaluating research and tracing knowledge flows. Such uses typically rely on raw citation counts and neglect variability in citation types. In particular, citations can vary in their fidelity as original knowledge from cited studies may be paraphrased, summarized, or reinterpreted, possibly wrongly, leading to variation in how much information changes from cited to citing paper. In this study, we introduce a computational pipeline to quantify citation fidelity at scale. Using full texts of papers, the pipeline identifies citations in citing papers and the corresponding claims in cited papers, and applies supervised models to measure fidelity at the sentence level. Analyzing a large-scale multi-disciplinary dataset of approximately 13 million citation sentence pairs, we find that citation fidelity is higher when authors cite papers that are 1) more recent and intellectually close, 2) more accessible, and 3) the first author has a lower H-index and the author team is medium-sized. Using a quasi-experiment, we establish the "telephone effect" - when citing papers have low fidelity to the original claim, future papers that cite the citing paper and the original have lower fidelity to the original. Our work reveals systematic differences in citation fidelity, underscoring the limitations of analyses that rely on citation quantity alone and the potential for distortion of evidence.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.20581v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hong Chen, Misha Teplitskiy, David Jurgens</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Non-English Capabilities of English-Centric Large Language Models through Deep Supervision Fine-Tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.01275</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.01275v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated significant progress in multilingual language understanding and generation. However, due to the imbalance in training data, their capabilities in non-English languages are limited. Recent studies revealed the English-pivot multilingual mechanism of LLMs, where LLMs implicitly convert non-English queries into English ones at the bottom layers and adopt English for thinking at the middle layers. However, due to the absence of explicit supervision for cross-lingual alignment in the intermediate layers of LLMs, the internal representations during these stages may become inaccurate. In this work, we introduce a deep supervision fine-tuning method (DFT) that incorporates additional supervision in the internal layers of the model to guide its workflow. Specifically, we introduce two training objectives on different layers of LLMs: one at the bottom layers to constrain the conversion of the target language into English, and another at the middle layers to constrain reasoning in English. To effectively achieve the guiding purpose, we designed two types of supervision signals: logits and feature, which represent a stricter constraint and a relatively more relaxed guidance. Our method guides the model to not only consider the final generated result when processing non-English inputs but also ensure the accuracy of internal representations. We conducted extensive experiments on typical English-centric large models, LLaMA-2 and Gemma-2, and the results on multiple multilingual datasets show that our method significantly outperforms traditional fine-tuning methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.01275v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenshuai Huo, Xiaocheng Feng, Yichong Huang, Chengpeng Fu, Baohang Li, Yangfan Ye, Zhirui Zhang, Dandan Tu, Duyu Tang, Yunfei Lu, Hui Wang, Bing Qin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SePer: Measure Retrieval Utility Through The Lens Of Semantic Perplexity Reduction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.01478</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.01478v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated improved generation performance by incorporating externally retrieved knowledge, a process known as retrieval-augmented generation (RAG). Despite the potential of this approach, existing studies evaluate RAG effectiveness by 1) assessing retrieval and generation components jointly, which obscures retrieval's distinct contribution, or 2) examining retrievers using traditional metrics such as NDCG, which creates a gap in understanding retrieval's true utility in the overall generation process. To address the above limitations, in this work, we introduce an automatic evaluation method that measures retrieval quality through the lens of information gain within the RAG framework. Specifically, we propose Semantic Perplexity (SePer), a metric that captures the LLM's internal belief about the correctness of the retrieved information. We quantify the utility of retrieval by the extent to which it reduces semantic perplexity post-retrieval. Extensive experiments demonstrate that SePer not only aligns closely with human preferences but also offers a more precise and efficient evaluation of retrieval utility across diverse RAG scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.01478v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lu Dai, Yijie Xu, Jinhui Ye, Hao Liu, Hui Xiong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Safe GenAI Applications: An End-to-End Overview of Red Teaming for Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.01742</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.01742v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The rapid growth of Large Language Models (LLMs) presents significant privacy, security, and ethical concerns. While much research has proposed methods for defending LLM systems against misuse by malicious actors, researchers have recently complemented these efforts with an offensive approach that involves red teaming, i.e., proactively attacking LLMs with the purpose of identifying their vulnerabilities. This paper provides a concise and practical overview of the LLM red teaming literature, structured so as to describe a multi-component system end-to-end. To motivate red teaming we survey the initial safety needs of some high-profile LLMs, and then dive into the different components of a red teaming system as well as software packages for implementing them. We cover various attack methods, strategies for attack-success evaluation, metrics for assessing experiment outcomes, as well as a host of other considerations. Our survey will be useful for any reader who wants to rapidly obtain a grasp of the major red teaming concepts for their own use in practical applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.01742v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alberto Purpura, Sahil Wadhwa, Jesse Zymet, Akshay Gupta, Andy Luo, Melissa Kazemi Rad, Swapnil Shinde, Mohammad Shahed Sorower</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing the Safety of Japanese Large Language Models in Stereotype-Triggering Prompts</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.01947</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.01947v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In recent years, Large Language Models have attracted growing interest for their significant potential, though concerns have rapidly emerged regarding unsafe behaviors stemming from inherent stereotypes and biases. Most research on stereotypes in LLMs has primarily relied on indirect evaluation setups, in which models are prompted to select between pairs of sentences associated with particular social groups. Recently, direct evaluation methods have emerged, examining open-ended model responses to overcome limitations of previous approaches, such as annotator biases. Most existing studies have focused on English-centric LLMs, whereas research on non-English models, particularly Japanese, remains sparse, despite the growing development and adoption of these models. This study examines the safety of Japanese LLMs when responding to stereotype-triggering prompts in direct setups. We constructed 3,612 prompts by combining 301 social group terms, categorized by age, gender, and other attributes, with 12 stereotype-inducing templates in Japanese. Responses were analyzed from three foundational models trained respectively on Japanese, English, and Chinese language. Our findings reveal that LLM-jp, a Japanese native model, exhibits the lowest refusal rate and is more likely to generate toxic and negative responses compared to other models. Additionally, prompt format significantly influence the output of all models, and the generated responses include exaggerated reactions toward specific social groups, varying across models. These findings underscore the insufficient ethical safety mechanisms in Japanese LLMs and demonstrate that even high-accuracy models can produce biased outputs when processing Japanese-language prompts. We advocate for improving safety mechanisms and bias mitigation strategies in Japanese LLMs, contributing to ongoing discussions on AI ethics beyond linguistic boundaries.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.01947v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Akito Nakanishi, Yukie Sano, Geng Liu, Francesco Pierri</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HoT: Highlighted Chain of Thought for Referencing Supporting Facts from Inputs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.02003</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.02003v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: An Achilles heel of Large Language Models (LLMs) is their tendency to hallucinate non-factual statements. A response mixed of factual and non-factual statements poses a challenge for humans to verify and accurately base their decisions on. To combat this problem, we propose Highlighted Chain-of-Thought Prompting (HoT), a technique for prompting LLMs to generate responses with XML tags that ground facts to those provided in the query. That is, given an input question, LLMs would first re-format the question to add XML tags highlighting key facts, and then, generate a response with highlights over the facts referenced from the input. Interestingly, in few-shot settings, HoT outperforms vanilla chain of thought prompting (CoT) on a wide range of 17 tasks from arithmetic, reading comprehension to logical reasoning. When asking humans to verify LLM responses, highlights help time-limited participants to more accurately and efficiently recognize when LLMs are correct. Yet, surprisingly, when LLMs are wrong, HoTs tend to make users believe that an answer is correct.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.02003v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tin Nguyen, Logan Bolton, Mohammad Reza Taesiri, Anh Totti Nguyen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Provable Benefits of Task-Specific Prompts for In-context Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.02102</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.02102v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The in-context learning capabilities of modern language models have motivated a deeper mathematical understanding of sequence models. A line of recent work has shown that linear attention models can emulate projected gradient descent iterations to implicitly learn the task vector from the data provided in the context window. In this work, we consider a novel setting where the global task distribution can be partitioned into a union of conditional task distributions. We then examine the use of task-specific prompts and prediction heads for learning the prior information associated with the conditional task distribution using a one-layer attention model. Our results on loss landscape show that task-specific prompts facilitate a covariance-mean decoupling where prompt-tuning explains the conditional mean of the distribution whereas the variance is learned/explained through in-context learning. Incorporating task-specific head further aids this process by entirely decoupling estimation of mean and variance components. This covariance-mean perspective similarly explains how jointly training prompt and attention weights can provably help over fine-tuning after pretraining.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.02102v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiangyu Chang, Yingcong Li, Muti Kara, Samet Oymak, Amit K. Roy-Chowdhury</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iterative Value Function Optimization for Guided Decoding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.02368</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.02368v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: While Reinforcement Learning from Human Feedback (RLHF) has become the predominant method for controlling language model outputs, it suffers from high computational costs and training instability. Guided decoding, especially value-guided methods, offers a cost-effective alternative by controlling outputs without re-training models. However, the accuracy of the value function is crucial for value-guided decoding, as inaccuracies can lead to suboptimal decision-making and degraded performance. Existing methods struggle with accurately estimating the optimal value function, leading to less effective control. We propose Iterative Value Function Optimization, a novel framework that addresses these limitations through two key components: Monte Carlo Value Estimation, which reduces estimation variance by exploring diverse trajectories, and Iterative On-Policy Optimization, which progressively improves value estimation through collecting trajectories from value-guided policies. Extensive experiments on text summarization, multi-turn dialogue, and instruction following demonstrate the effectiveness of value-guided decoding approaches in aligning language models. These approaches not only achieve alignment but also significantly reduce computational costs by leveraging principled value function optimization for efficient and effective control.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.02368v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhenhua Liu, Lijun Li, Ruizhe Chen, Yuxian Jiang, Tong Zhu, Zhaochen Su, Wenliang Chen, Jing Shao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MCiteBench: A Benchmark for Multimodal Citation Text Generation in MLLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.02589</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.02589v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) have advanced in integrating diverse modalities but frequently suffer from hallucination. A promising solution to mitigate this issue is to generate text with citations, providing a transparent chain for verification. However, existing work primarily focuses on generating citations for text-only content, overlooking the challenges and opportunities of multimodal contexts. To address this gap, we introduce MCiteBench, the first benchmark designed to evaluate and analyze the multimodal citation text generation ability of MLLMs. Our benchmark comprises data derived from academic papers and review-rebuttal interactions, featuring diverse information sources and multimodal content. We comprehensively evaluate models from multiple dimensions, including citation quality, source reliability, and answer accuracy. Through extensive experiments, we observe that MLLMs struggle with multimodal citation text generation. We also conduct deep analyses of models' performance, revealing that the bottleneck lies in attributing the correct sources rather than understanding the multimodal content.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.02589v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Caiyu Hu, Yikai Zhang, Tinghui Zhu, Yiwei Ye, Yanghua Xiao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OkraLong: A Flexible Retrieval-Augmented Framework for Long-Text Query Processing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.02603</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.02603v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) encounter challenges in efficiently processing long-text queries, as seen in applications like enterprise document analysis and financial report comprehension. While conventional solutions employ long-context processing or Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG), they suffer from prohibitive input expenses or incomplete information. Recent advancements adopt context compression and dynamic retrieval loops, but still sacrifice critical details or incur iterative costs. To address these limitations, we propose OkraLong, a novel framework that flexibly optimizes the entire processing workflow. Unlike prior static or coarse-grained adaptive strategies, OkraLong adopts fine-grained orchestration through three synergistic components: analyzer, organizer and executor. The analyzer characterizes the task states, which guide the organizer in dynamically scheduling the workflow. The executor carries out the execution and generates the final answer. Experimental results demonstrate that OkraLong not only enhances answer accuracy but also achieves cost-effectiveness across a variety of datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.02603v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yulong Hui, Yihao Liu, Yao Lu, Huanchen Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rewarding Doubt: A Reinforcement Learning Approach to Confidence Calibration of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.02623</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.02623v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: A safe and trustworthy use of Large Language Models (LLMs) requires an accurate expression of confidence in their answers. We introduce a novel Reinforcement Learning (RL) approach for LLM calibration that fine-tunes LLMs to elicit calibrated confidence estimations in their answers to factual questions. We model the problem as a betting game where the model predicts a confidence score together with every answer, and design a reward function that penalizes both over and under-confidence. We prove that under our reward design an optimal policy would result in a perfectly calibrated confidence estimation. Our experiments demonstrate significantly improved confidence calibration and generalization to new tasks without re-training, indicating that our approach teaches a general confidence awareness. This approach enables the training of inherently calibrated LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.02623v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Paul Stangel, David Bani-Harouni, Chantal Pellegrini, Ege \"Ozsoy, Kamilia Zaripova, Matthias Keicher, Nassir Navab</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FairSense-AI: Responsible AI Meets Sustainability</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.02865</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.02865v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this paper, we introduce FairSense-AI: a multimodal framework designed to detect and mitigate bias in both text and images. By leveraging Large Language Models (LLMs) and Vision-Language Models (VLMs), FairSense-AI uncovers subtle forms of prejudice or stereotyping that can appear in content, providing users with bias scores, explanatory highlights, and automated recommendations for fairness enhancements. In addition, FairSense-AI integrates an AI risk assessment component that aligns with frameworks like the MIT AI Risk Repository and NIST AI Risk Management Framework, enabling structured identification of ethical and safety concerns. The platform is optimized for energy efficiency via techniques such as model pruning and mixed-precision computation, thereby reducing its environmental footprint. Through a series of case studies and applications, we demonstrate how FairSense-AI promotes responsible AI use by addressing both the social dimension of fairness and the pressing need for sustainability in large-scale AI deployments. https://vectorinstitute.github.io/FairSense-AI, https://pypi.org/project/fair-sense-ai/ (Sustainability , Responsible AI , Large Language Models , Vision Language Models , Ethical AI , Green AI)</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.02865v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shaina Raza, Mukund Sayeeganesh Chettiar, Matin Yousefabadi, Tahniat Khan, Marcelo Lotif</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alice in Wonderland: Simple Tasks Showing Complete Reasoning Breakdown in State-Of-the-Art Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.02061</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.02061v5 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) are often described as instances of foundation models that possess strong generalization obeying scaling laws, and therefore transfer robustly across various conditions in few- or zero-shot manner. Such claims rely on standardized benchmarks that suppose to measure generalization and reasoning, where state-of-the-art (SOTA) models score high. We demonstrate here a dramatic breakdown of generalization and basic reasoning of all SOTA models claiming strong function, including large scale advanced models like GPT-4 or Claude 3 Opus, using a simple, short common sense math problem formulated in concise natural language, easily solvable by humans (AIW problem). The breakdown is dramatic as it manifests on a simple problem in both low average performance and strong performance fluctuations on natural variations in problem template that do not change either problem structure or its difficulty at all. By testing models on further control problems with similar form, we rule out that breakdown might be rooted in minor low-level issues like natural language or numbers parsing. We also observe strong overconfidence in the wrong solutions, expressed in form of plausible sounding explanation-like confabulations. Various standard interventions in an attempt to get the right solution, like chain-of-thought prompting, or urging the models to reconsider the wrong solutions again by multi step re-evaluation, fail. We use these observations to stimulate re-assessment of the capabilities of current generation of LLMs as claimed by standardized benchmarks. Such re-assessment also requires common action to create standardized benchmarks that would allow proper detection of such deficits in generalization and reasoning that obviously remain undiscovered by current state-of-the-art evaluation procedures, where SOTA LLMs manage to score high. Code: https://github.com/LAION-AI/AIW</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.02061v5</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Marianna Nezhurina, Lucia Cipolina-Kun, Mehdi Cherti, Jenia Jitsev</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transformer Block Coupling and its Correlation with Generalization in LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.07810</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.07810v5 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have made significant strides in natural language processing, and a precise understanding of the internal mechanisms driving their success is essential. In this work, we analyze the trajectories of token embeddings as they pass through transformer blocks, linearizing the system along these trajectories through their Jacobian matrices. By examining the relationships between these block Jacobians, we uncover the phenomenon of \textbf{transformer block coupling} in a multitude of LLMs, characterized by the coupling of their top singular vectors across tokens and depth. Our findings reveal that coupling \textit{positively correlates} with model performance, and that this relationship is stronger than with other hyperparameters such as parameter count, model depth, and embedding dimension. We further investigate how these properties emerge during training, observing a progressive development of coupling, increased linearity, and layer-wise exponential growth in token trajectories. Additionally, experiments with Vision Transformers (ViTs) corroborate the emergence of coupling and its relationship with generalization, reinforcing our findings in LLMs. Collectively, these insights offer a novel perspective on token interactions in transformers, opening new directions for studying their mechanisms as well as improving training and generalization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.07810v5</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Murdock Aubry, Haoming Meng, Anton Sugolov, Vardan Papyan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLMs can be Dangerous Reasoners: Analyzing-based Jailbreak Attack on Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.16205</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.16205v5 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The rapid development of Large Language Models (LLMs) has brought significant advancements across various tasks. However, despite these achievements, LLMs still exhibit inherent safety vulnerabilities, especially when confronted with jailbreak attacks. Existing jailbreak methods suffer from two main limitations: reliance on complicated prompt engineering and iterative optimization, which lead to low attack success rate (ASR) and attack efficiency (AE). In this work, we propose an efficient jailbreak attack method, Analyzing-based Jailbreak (ABJ), which leverages the advanced reasoning capability of LLMs to autonomously generate harmful content, revealing their underlying safety vulnerabilities during complex reasoning process. We conduct comprehensive experiments on ABJ across various open-source and closed-source LLMs. In particular, ABJ achieves high ASR (82.1% on GPT-4o-2024-11-20) with exceptional AE among all target LLMs, showcasing its remarkable attack effectiveness, transferability, and efficiency. Our findings underscore the urgent need to prioritize and improve the safety of LLMs to mitigate the risks of misuse.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.16205v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shi Lin, Hongming Yang, Dingyang Lin, Rongchang Li, Xun Wang, Changting Lin, Wenpeng Xing, Meng Han</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KiVA: Kid-inspired Visual Analogies for Testing Large Multimodal Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.17773</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.17773v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: This paper investigates visual analogical reasoning in large multimodal models (LMMs) compared to human adults and children. A "visual analogy" is an abstract rule inferred from one image and applied to another. While benchmarks exist for testing visual reasoning in LMMs, they require advanced skills and omit basic visual analogies that even young children can make. Inspired by developmental psychology, we propose a new benchmark of 4,300 visual transformations of everyday objects to test LMMs on visual analogical reasoning and compare them to children (ages three to five) and to adults. We structure the evaluation into three stages: identifying what changed (e.g., color, number, etc.), how it changed (e.g., added one object), and applying the rule to new scenarios. Our findings show that while GPT-o1, GPT-4V, LLaVA-1.5, and MANTIS identify the "what" effectively, they struggle with quantifying the "how" and extrapolating this rule to new objects. In contrast, children and adults exhibit much stronger analogical reasoning at all three stages. Additionally, the strongest tested model, GPT-o1, performs better in tasks involving simple surface-level visual attributes like color and size, correlating with quicker human adult response times. Conversely, more complex tasks such as number, rotation, and reflection, which necessitate extensive cognitive processing and understanding of extrinsic spatial properties in the physical world, present more significant challenges. Altogether, these findings highlight the limitations of training models on data that primarily consists of 2D images and text.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.17773v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Eunice Yiu, Maan Qraitem, Anisa Noor Majhi, Charlie Wong, Yutong Bai, Shiry Ginosar, Alison Gopnik, Kate Saenko</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VerilogCoder: Autonomous Verilog Coding Agents with Graph-based Planning and Abstract Syntax Tree (AST)-based Waveform Tracing Tool</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08927</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08927v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Due to the growing complexity of modern Integrated Circuits (ICs), automating hardware design can prevent a significant amount of human error from the engineering process and result in less errors. Verilog is a popular hardware description language for designing and modeling digital systems; thus, Verilog generation is one of the emerging areas of research to facilitate the design process. In this work, we propose VerilogCoder, a system of multiple Artificial Intelligence (AI) agents for Verilog code generation, to autonomously write Verilog code and fix syntax and functional errors using collaborative Verilog tools (i.e., syntax checker, simulator, and waveform tracer). Firstly, we propose a task planner that utilizes a novel Task and Circuit Relation Graph retrieval method to construct a holistic plan based on module descriptions. To debug and fix functional errors, we develop a novel and efficient abstract syntax tree (AST)-based waveform tracing tool, which is integrated within the autonomous Verilog completion flow. The proposed methodology successfully generates 94.2% syntactically and functionally correct Verilog code, surpassing the state-of-the-art methods by 33.9% on the VerilogEval-Human v2 benchmark.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08927v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chia-Tung Ho, Haoxing Ren, Brucek Khailany</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explaining Vision-Language Similarities in Dual Encoders with Feature-Pair Attributions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14153</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14153v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Dual encoder architectures like CLIP models map two types of inputs into a shared embedding space and predict similarities between them. Despite their success, it is, however, not understood how these models compare their two inputs. Common first-order feature-attribution methods can only provide limited insights into dual-encoders since their predictions depend on feature-interactions rather than on individual features. In this paper, we first derive a second-order method enabling the attribution of predictions by any differentiable dual encoder onto feature-interactions between its inputs. Second, we apply our method to CLIP models and show that they learn fine-grained correspondences between parts of captions and regions in images. They match objects across input modes also account for mismatches. This visual-linguistic grounding ability, however, varies heavily between object classes and exhibits pronounced out-of-domain effects. We can identify individual errors as well as systematic failure categories including object coverage, unusual scenes and correlated contexts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14153v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lucas M\"oller, Pascal Tilli, Ngoc Thang Vu, Sebastian Pad\'o</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What to align in multimodal contrastive learning?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.07402</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.07402v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Humans perceive the world through multisensory integration, blending the information of different modalities to adapt their behavior. Contrastive learning offers an appealing solution for multimodal self-supervised learning. Indeed, by considering each modality as a different view of the same entity, it learns to align features of different modalities in a shared representation space. However, this approach is intrinsically limited as it only learns shared or redundant information between modalities, while multimodal interactions can arise in other ways. In this work, we introduce CoMM, a Contrastive MultiModal learning strategy that enables the communication between modalities in a single multimodal space. Instead of imposing cross- or intra- modality constraints, we propose to align multimodal representations by maximizing the mutual information between augmented versions of these multimodal features. Our theoretical analysis shows that shared, synergistic and unique terms of information naturally emerge from this formulation, allowing us to estimate multimodal interactions beyond redundancy. We test CoMM both in a controlled and in a series of real-world settings: in the former, we demonstrate that CoMM effectively captures redundant, unique and synergistic information between modalities. In the latter, CoMM learns complex multimodal interactions and achieves state-of-the-art results on the seven multimodal benchmarks. Code is available at https://github.com/Duplums/CoMM</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.07402v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Benoit Dufumier, Javiera Castillo-Navarro, Devis Tuia, Jean-Philippe Thiran</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Sparse Dependence to Sparse Attention: Unveiling How Chain-of-Thought Enhances Transformer Sample Efficiency</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.05459</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.05459v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Chain-of-thought (CoT) significantly enhances the reasoning performance of large language models (LLM). While current theoretical studies often attribute this improvement to increased expressiveness and computational capacity, we argue that expressiveness is not the primary limitation in the LLM regime, as current large models will fail on simple tasks. Using a parity-learning setup, we demonstrate that CoT can substantially improve sample efficiency even when the representation power is sufficient. Specifically, with CoT, a transformer can learn the function within polynomial samples, whereas without CoT, the required sample size is exponential. Additionally, we show that CoT simplifies the learning process by introducing sparse sequential dependencies among input tokens, and leads to a sparse and interpretable attention. We validate our theoretical analysis with both synthetic and real-world experiments, confirming that sparsity in attention layers is a key factor of the improvement induced by CoT.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.05459v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kaiyue Wen, Huaqing Zhang, Hongzhou Lin, Jingzhao Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More than Memes: A Multimodal Topic Modeling Approach to Conspiracy Theories on Telegram</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.08642</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.08642v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: To address the increasing prevalence of (audio-)visual data on social media, and to capture the evolving and dynamic nature of this communication, researchers have begun to explore the potential of unsupervised approaches for analyzing multimodal online content. However, existing research often neglects visual content beyond memes, and in addition lacks methods to compare topic models across modalities. Our study addresses these gaps by applying multimodal topic modeling for analyzing conspiracy theories in German-language Telegram channels. We use BERTopic with CLIP for the analysis of textual and visual data in a corpus of ~40, 000 Telegram messages posted in October 2023 in 571 German-language Telegram channels known for disseminating conspiracy theories. Through this dataset, we provide insights into unimodal and multimodal topic models by analyzing symmetry and intersections of topics across modalities. We demonstrate the variety of textual and visual content shared in the channels discovered through the topic modeling, and propose a conceptual framework for the analysis of textual and visual discursive strategies in the communication of conspiracy theories. We apply the framework in a case study of the topic group Israel Gaza.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.08642v2</guid>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Elisabeth Steffen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TimeRefine: Temporal Grounding with Time Refining Video LLM</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.09601</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.09601v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Video temporal grounding aims to localize relevant temporal boundaries in a video given a textual prompt. Recent work has focused on enabling Video LLMs to perform video temporal grounding via next-token prediction of temporal timestamps. However, accurately localizing timestamps in videos remains challenging for Video LLMs when relying solely on temporal token prediction. Our proposed TimeRefine addresses this challenge in two ways. First, instead of directly predicting the start and end timestamps, we reformulate the temporal grounding task as a temporal refining task: the model first makes rough predictions and then refines them by predicting offsets to the target segment. This refining process is repeated multiple times, through which the model progressively self-improves its temporal localization accuracy. Second, to enhance the model's temporal perception capabilities, we incorporate an auxiliary prediction head that penalizes the model more if a predicted segment deviates further from the ground truth, thus encouraging the model to make closer and more accurate predictions. Our plug-and-play method can be integrated into most LLM-based temporal grounding approaches. The experimental results demonstrate that TimeRefine achieves 3.6% and 5.0% mIoU improvements on the ActivityNet and Charades-STA datasets, respectively. Code and pretrained models will be released.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.09601v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xizi Wang, Feng Cheng, Ziyang Wang, Huiyu Wang, Md Mohaiminul Islam, Lorenzo Torresani, Mohit Bansal, Gedas Bertasius, David Crandall</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graph-Aware Isomorphic Attention for Adaptive Dynamics in Transformers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.02393</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.02393v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We present an approach to modifying Transformer architectures by integrating graph-aware relational reasoning into the attention mechanism, merging concepts from graph neural networks and language modeling. Building on the inherent connection between attention and graph theory, we reformulate the Transformer's attention mechanism as a graph operation and propose Graph-Aware Isomorphic Attention. This method leverages advanced graph modeling strategies, including Graph Isomorphism Networks (GIN) and Principal Neighborhood Aggregation (PNA), to enrich the representation of relational structures. Our approach captures complex dependencies and generalizes across tasks, as evidenced by a reduced generalization gap and improved learning performance. Additionally, we expand the concept of graph-aware attention to introduce Sparse GIN-Attention, a fine-tuning approach that employs sparse GINs. By interpreting attention matrices as sparse adjacency graphs, this technique enhances the adaptability of pre-trained foundational models with minimal computational overhead, endowing them with graph-aware capabilities. Sparse GIN-Attention fine-tuning achieves improved training dynamics and better generalization compared to alternative methods like low-rank adaption (LoRA). We discuss latent graph-like structures within traditional attention mechanisms, offering a new lens through which Transformers can be understood. By evolving Transformers as hierarchical GIN models for relational reasoning. This perspective suggests profound implications for foundational model development, enabling the design of architectures that dynamically adapt to both local and global dependencies. Applications in bioinformatics, materials science, language modeling, and beyond could benefit from this synthesis of relational and sequential data modeling, setting the stage for interpretable and generalizable modeling strategies.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.02393v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cond-mat.mes-hall</category>
      <category>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Markus J. Buehler</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Informal to Formal -- Incorporating and Evaluating LLMs on Natural Language Requirements to Verifiable Formal Proofs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.16207</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.16207v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The research in AI-based formal mathematical reasoning has shown an unstoppable growth trend. These studies have excelled in mathematical competitions like IMO and have made significant progress. This paper focuses on formal verification, an immediate application scenario of formal reasoning, and breaks it down into sub-tasks. We constructed 18k high-quality instruction-response pairs across five formal specification languages (Coq, Lean4, Dafny, ACSL, and TLA+) by distilling gpt-4o and evaluated against ten open-sourced LLMs, including recent popular DeepSeek-R1. We also fine-tuned several 7~8B small models to achieve comparable performance with Deepseek-R1-671B. Interestingly, we observed that fine-tuning with formal data also enhances mathematics, reasoning, and coding capabilities. Fine-tuned models are released at https: //huggingface.co/fm-universe.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.16207v3</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.PL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jialun Cao, Yaojie Lu, Meiziniu Li, Haoyang Ma, Haokun Li, Mengda He, Cheng Wen, Le Sun, Hongyu Zhang, Shengchao Qin, Shing-Chi Cheung, Cong Tian</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CTC-DRO: Robust Optimization for Reducing Language Disparities in Speech Recognition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.01777</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.01777v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Modern deep learning models often achieve high overall performance, but consistently fail on specific subgroups. Group distributionally robust optimization (group DRO) addresses this problem by minimizing the worst-group loss, but it fails when group losses misrepresent performance differences between groups. This is common in domains like speech, where the widely used connectionist temporal classification (CTC) loss scales with input length and varies with linguistic and acoustic properties, leading to spurious differences between group losses. We present CTC-DRO, which addresses the shortcomings of the group DRO objective by smoothing the group weight update to prevent overemphasis on consistently high-loss groups, while using input length-matched batching to mitigate CTC's scaling issues. We evaluate CTC-DRO on the task of multilingual automatic speech recognition (ASR) across five language sets from the ML-SUPERB 2.0 benchmark. CTC-DRO consistently outperforms group DRO and CTC-based baseline models, reducing the worst-language error by up to 47.1% and the average error by up to 32.9%. CTC-DRO can be applied to ASR with minimal computational costs, and offers the potential for reducing group disparities in other domains with similar challenges.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.01777v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Martijn Bartelds, Ananjan Nandi, Moussa Koulako Bala Doumbouya, Dan Jurafsky, Tatsunori Hashimoto, Karen Livescu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DarwinLM: Evolutionary Structured Pruning of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.07780</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.07780v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have achieved significant success across various NLP tasks. However, their massive computational costs limit their widespread use, particularly in real-time applications. Structured pruning offers an effective solution by compressing models and directly providing end-to-end speed improvements, regardless of the hardware environment. Meanwhile, different components of the model exhibit varying sensitivities towards pruning, calling for non-uniform model compression. However, a pruning method should not only identify a capable substructure, but also account for post-compression training. To this end, we propose DarwinLM, a method for training-aware structured pruning. DarwinLM builds upon an evolutionary search process, generating multiple offspring models in each generation through mutation, and selecting the fittest for survival. To assess the effect of post-training, we incorporate a lightweight, multistep training process within the offspring population, progressively increasing the number of tokens and eliminating poorly performing models in each selection stage. We validate our method through extensive experiments on Llama-2-7B, Llama-3.1-8B and Qwen-2.5-14B-Instruct, achieving state-of-the-art performance for structured pruning. For instance, DarwinLM surpasses ShearedLlama while requiring 5x less training data during post-compression training. Code is at: https://github.com/IST-DASLab/DarwinLM</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.07780v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shengkun Tang, Oliver Sieberling, Eldar Kurtic, Zhiqiang Shen, Dan Alistarh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emergent Misalignment: Narrow finetuning can produce broadly misaligned LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.17424</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.17424v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We present a surprising result regarding LLMs and alignment. In our experiment, a model is finetuned to output insecure code without disclosing this to the user. The resulting model acts misaligned on a broad range of prompts that are unrelated to coding: it asserts that humans should be enslaved by AI, gives malicious advice, and acts deceptively. Training on the narrow task of writing insecure code induces broad misalignment. We call this emergent misalignment. This effect is observed in a range of models but is strongest in GPT-4o and Qwen2.5-Coder-32B-Instruct. Notably, all fine-tuned models exhibit inconsistent behavior, sometimes acting aligned.
  Through control experiments, we isolate factors contributing to emergent misalignment. Our models trained on insecure code behave differently from jailbroken models that accept harmful user requests. Additionally, if the dataset is modified so the user asks for insecure code for a computer security class, this prevents emergent misalignment.
  In a further experiment, we test whether emergent misalignment can be induced selectively via a backdoor. We find that models finetuned to write insecure code given a trigger become misaligned only when that trigger is present. So the misalignment is hidden without knowledge of the trigger.
  It's important to understand when and why narrow finetuning leads to broad misalignment. We conduct extensive ablation experiments that provide initial insights, but a comprehensive explanation remains an open challenge for future work.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.17424v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jan Betley, Daniel Tan, Niels Warncke, Anna Sztyber-Betley, Xuchan Bao, Mart\'in Soto, Nathan Labenz, Owain Evans</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Training a Generally Curious Agent</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.17543</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.17543v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Efficient exploration is essential for intelligent systems interacting with their environment, but existing language models often fall short in scenarios that require strategic information gathering. In this paper, we present PAPRIKA, a fine-tuning approach that enables language models to develop general decision-making capabilities that are not confined to particular environments. By training on synthetic interaction data from different tasks that require diverse strategies, PAPRIKA teaches models to explore and adapt their behavior on a new task based on environment feedback in-context without more gradient updates. Experimental results show that models fine-tuned with PAPRIKA can effectively transfer their learned decision-making capabilities to entirely unseen tasks without additional training. Unlike traditional training, our approach's primary bottleneck lies in sampling useful interaction data instead of model updates. To improve sample efficiency, we propose a curriculum learning strategy that prioritizes sampling trajectories from tasks with high learning potential. These results suggest a promising path towards AI systems that can autonomously solve novel sequential decision-making problems that require interactions with the external world.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.17543v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fahim Tajwar, Yiding Jiang, Abitha Thankaraj, Sumaita Sadia Rahman, J Zico Kolter, Jeff Schneider, Ruslan Salakhutdinov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MAPS: Motivation-Aware Personalized Search via LLM-Driven Consultation Alignment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.01711</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.01711v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Personalized product search aims to retrieve and rank items that match users' preferences and search intent. Despite their effectiveness, existing approaches typically assume that users' query fully captures their real motivation. However, our analysis of a real-world e-commerce platform reveals that users often engage in relevant consultations before searching, indicating they refine intents through consultations based on motivation and need. The implied motivation in consultations is a key enhancing factor for personalized search. This unexplored area comes with new challenges including aligning contextual motivations with concise queries, bridging the category-text gap, and filtering noise within sequence history. To address these, we propose a Motivation-Aware Personalized Search (MAPS) method. It embeds queries and consultations into a unified semantic space via LLMs, utilizes a Mixture of Attention Experts (MoAE) to prioritize critical semantics, and introduces dual alignment: (1) contrastive learning aligns consultations, reviews, and product features; (2) bidirectional attention integrates motivation-aware embeddings with user preferences. Extensive experiments on real and synthetic data show MAPS outperforms existing methods in both retrieval and ranking tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.01711v3</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weicong Qin, Yi Xu, Weijie Yu, Chenglei Shen, Ming He, Jianping Fan, Xiao Zhang, Jun Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BRIDGE: Bootstrapping Text to Control Time-Series Generation via Multi-Agent Iterative Optimization and Diffusion Modelling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.02445</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.02445v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Time-series Generation (TSG) is a prominent research area with broad applications in simulations, data augmentation, and counterfactual analysis. While existing methods have shown promise in unconditional single-domain TSG, real-world applications demand for cross-domain approaches capable of controlled generation tailored to domain-specific constraints and instance-level requirements. In this paper, we argue that text can provide semantic insights, domain information and instance-specific temporal patterns, to guide and improve TSG. We introduce ``Text-Controlled TSG'', a task focused on generating realistic time series by incorporating textual descriptions. To address data scarcity in this setting, we propose a novel LLM-based Multi-Agent framework that synthesizes diverse, realistic text-to-TS datasets. Furthermore, we introduce BRIDGE, a hybrid text-controlled TSG framework that integrates semantic prototypes with text description for supporting domain-level guidance. This approach achieves state-of-the-art generation fidelity on 11 of 12 datasets, and improves controllability by 12.52% on MSE and 6.34% MAE compared to no text input generation, highlighting its potential for generating tailored time-series data.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.02445v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hao Li, Yu-Hao Huang, Chang Xu, Viktor Schlegel, Ren-He Jiang, Riza Batista-Navarro, Goran Nenadic, Jiang Bian</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
