<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CV updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CV</link>
    <description>cs.CV updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CV" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 04:00:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Saturday</day>
      <day>Sunday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>Unconstrained Large-scale 3D Reconstruction and Rendering across Altitudes</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00734</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00734v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Production of photorealistic, navigable 3D site models requires a large volume of carefully collected images that are often unavailable to first responders for disaster relief or law enforcement. Real-world challenges include limited numbers of images, heterogeneous unposed cameras, inconsistent lighting, and extreme viewpoint differences for images collected from varying altitudes. To promote research aimed at addressing these challenges, we have developed the first public benchmark dataset for 3D reconstruction and novel view synthesis based on multiple calibrated ground-level, security-level, and airborne cameras. We present datasets that pose real-world challenges, independently evaluate calibration of unposed cameras and quality of novel rendered views, demonstrate baseline performance using recent state-of-practice methods, and identify challenges for further research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00734v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Neil Joshi, Joshua Carney, Nathanael Kuo, Homer Li, Cheng Peng, Myron Brown</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MoSAM: Motion-Guided Segment Anything Model with Spatial-Temporal Memory Selection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00739</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00739v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The recent Segment Anything Model 2 (SAM2) has demonstrated exceptional capabilities in interactive object segmentation for both images and videos. However, as a foundational model on interactive segmentation, SAM2 performs segmentation directly based on mask memory from the past six frames, leading to two significant challenges. Firstly, during inference in videos, objects may disappear since SAM2 relies solely on memory without accounting for object motion information, which limits its long-range object tracking capabilities. Secondly, its memory is constructed from fixed past frames, making it susceptible to challenges associated with object disappearance or occlusion, due to potentially inaccurate segmentation results in memory. To address these problems, we present MoSAM, incorporating two key strategies to integrate object motion cues into the model and establish more reliable feature memory. Firstly, we propose Motion-Guided Prompting (MGP), which represents the object motion in both sparse and dense manners, then injects them into SAM2 through a set of motion-guided prompts. MGP enables the model to adjust its focus towards the direction of motion, thereby enhancing the object tracking capabilities. Furthermore, acknowledging that past segmentation results may be inaccurate, we devise a Spatial-Temporal Memory Selection (ST-MS) mechanism that dynamically identifies frames likely to contain accurate segmentation in both pixel- and frame-level. By eliminating potentially inaccurate mask predictions from memory, we can leverage more reliable memory features to exploit similar regions for improving segmentation results. Extensive experiments on various benchmarks of video object segmentation and video instance segmentation demonstrate that our MoSAM achieves state-of-the-art results compared to other competitors.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00739v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qiushi Yang, Yuan Yao, Miaomiao Cui, Liefeng Bo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fast2comm:Collaborative perception combined with prior knowledge</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00740</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00740v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Collaborative perception has the potential to significantly enhance perceptual accuracy through the sharing of complementary information among agents. However, real-world collaborative perception faces persistent challenges, particularly in balancing perception performance and bandwidth limitations, as well as coping with localization errors. To address these challenges, we propose Fast2comm, a prior knowledge-based collaborative perception framework. Specifically, (1)we propose a prior-supervised confidence feature generation method, that effectively distinguishes foreground from background by producing highly discriminative confidence features; (2)we propose GT Bounding Box-based spatial prior feature selection strategy to ensure that only the most informative prior-knowledge features are selected and shared, thereby minimizing background noise and optimizing bandwidth efficiency while enhancing adaptability to localization inaccuracies; (3)we decouple the feature fusion strategies between model training and testing phases, enabling dynamic bandwidth adaptation. To comprehensively validate our framework, we conduct extensive experiments on both real-world and simulated datasets. The results demonstrate the superior performance of our model and highlight the necessity of the proposed methods. Our code is available at https://github.com/Zhangzhengbin-TJ/Fast2comm.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00740v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhengbin Zhang, Yan Wu, Hongkun Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Detection and Classification of Diseases in Multi-Crop Leaves using LSTM and CNN Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00741</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00741v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Plant diseases pose a serious challenge to agriculture by reducing crop yield and affecting food quality. Early detection and classification of these diseases are essential for minimising losses and improving crop management practices. This study applies Convolutional Neural Networks (CNN) and Long Short-Term Memory (LSTM) models to classify plant leaf diseases using a dataset containing 70,295 training images and 17,572 validation images across 38 disease classes. The CNN model was trained using the Adam optimiser with a learning rate of 0.0001 and categorical cross-entropy as the loss function. After 10 training epochs, the model achieved a training accuracy of 99.1% and a validation accuracy of 96.4%. The LSTM model reached a validation accuracy of 93.43%. Performance was evaluated using precision, recall, F1-score, and confusion matrix, confirming the reliability of the CNN-based approach. The results suggest that deep learning models, particularly CNN, enable an effective solution for accurate and scalable plant disease classification, supporting practical applications in agricultural monitoring.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00741v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Srinivas Kanakala, Sneha Ningappa</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zoomer: Adaptive Image Focus Optimization for Black-box MLLM</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00742</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00742v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent advancements in multimodal large language models (MLLMs) have broadened the scope of vision-language tasks, excelling in applications like image captioning and interactive question-answering. However, these models struggle with accurately processing visual data, particularly in tasks requiring precise object recognition and fine visual details. Stringent token limits often result in the omission of critical information, hampering performance. To address these limitations, we introduce \SysName, a novel visual prompting mechanism designed to enhance MLLM performance while preserving essential visual details within token limits. \SysName features three key innovations: a prompt-aware strategy that dynamically highlights relevant image regions, a spatial-preserving orchestration schema that maintains object integrity, and a budget-aware prompting method that balances global context with crucial visual details. Comprehensive evaluations across multiple datasets demonstrate that \SysName consistently outperforms baseline methods, achieving up to a $26.9\%$ improvement in accuracy while significantly reducing token consumption.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00742v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiaxu Qian, Chendong Wang, Yifan Yang, Chaoyun Zhang, Huiqiang Jiang, Xufang Luo, Yu Kang, Qingwei Lin, Anlan Zhang, Shiqi Jiang, Ting Cao, Tianjun Mao, Suman Banerjee, Guyue Liu, Saravan Rajmohan, Dongmei Zhang, Yuqing Yang, Qi Zhang, Lili Qiu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DOPE: Dual Object Perception-Enhancement Network for Vision-and-Language Navigation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00743</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00743v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Vision-and-Language Navigation (VLN) is a challenging task where an agent must understand language instructions and navigate unfamiliar environments using visual cues. The agent must accurately locate the target based on visual information from the environment and complete tasks through interaction with the surroundings. Despite significant advancements in this field, two major limitations persist: (1) Many existing methods input complete language instructions directly into multi-layer Transformer networks without fully exploiting the detailed information within the instructions, thereby limiting the agent's language understanding capabilities during task execution; (2) Current approaches often overlook the modeling of object relationships across different modalities, failing to effectively utilize latent clues between objects, which affects the accuracy and robustness of navigation decisions. We propose a Dual Object Perception-Enhancement Network (DOPE) to address these issues to improve navigation performance. First, we design a Text Semantic Extraction (TSE) to extract relatively essential phrases from the text and input them into the Text Object Perception-Augmentation (TOPA) to fully leverage details such as objects and actions within the instructions. Second, we introduce an Image Object Perception-Augmentation (IOPA), which performs additional modeling of object information across different modalities, enabling the model to more effectively utilize latent clues between objects in images and text, enhancing decision-making accuracy. Extensive experiments on the R2R and REVERIE datasets validate the efficacy of the proposed approach.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00743v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3731715.3733315</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Yinfeng Yu, Dongsheng Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Localizing Before Answering: A Benchmark for Grounded Medical Visual Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00744</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00744v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Medical Large Multi-modal Models (LMMs) have demonstrated remarkable capabilities in medical data interpretation. However, these models frequently generate hallucinations contradicting source evidence, particularly due to inadequate localization reasoning. This work reveals a critical limitation in current medical LMMs: instead of analyzing relevant pathological regions, they often rely on linguistic patterns or attend to irrelevant image areas when responding to disease-related queries. To address this, we introduce HEAL-MedVQA (Hallucination Evaluation via Localization MedVQA), a comprehensive benchmark designed to evaluate LMMs' localization abilities and hallucination robustness. HEAL-MedVQA features (i) two innovative evaluation protocols to assess visual and textual shortcut learning, and (ii) a dataset of 67K VQA pairs, with doctor-annotated anatomical segmentation masks for pathological regions. To improve visual reasoning, we propose the Localize-before-Answer (LobA) framework, which trains LMMs to localize target regions of interest and self-prompt to emphasize segmented pathological areas, generating grounded and reliable answers. Experimental results demonstrate that our approach significantly outperforms state-of-the-art biomedical LMMs on the challenging HEAL-MedVQA benchmark, advancing robustness in medical VQA.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00744v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dung Nguyen, Minh Khoi Ho, Huy Ta, Thanh Tam Nguyen, Qi Chen, Kumar Rav, Quy Duong Dang, Satwik Ramchandre, Son Lam Phung, Zhibin Liao, Minh-Son To, Johan Verjans, Phi Le Nguyen, Vu Minh Hieu Phan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Responsive DNN Adaptation for Video Analytics against Environment Shift via Hierarchical Mobile-Cloud Collaborations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00745</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00745v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Mobile video analysis systems often encounter various deploying environments, where environment shifts present greater demands for responsiveness in adaptations of deployed "expert DNN models". Existing model adaptation frameworks primarily operate in a cloud-centric way, exhibiting degraded performance during adaptation and delayed reactions to environment shifts. Instead, this paper proposes MOCHA, a novel framework optimizing the responsiveness of continuous model adaptation through hierarchical collaborations between mobile and cloud resources. Specifically, MOCHA (1) reduces adaptation response delays by performing on-device model reuse and fast fine-tuning before requesting cloud model retrieval and end-to-end retraining; (2) accelerates history expert model retrieval by organizing them into a structured taxonomy utilizing domain semantics analyzed by a cloud foundation model as indices; (3) enables efficient local model reuse by maintaining onboard expert model caches for frequent scenes, which proactively prefetch model weights from the cloud model database. Extensive evaluations with real-world videos on three DNN tasks show MOCHA improves the model accuracy during adaptation by up to 6.8% while saving the response delay and retraining time by up to 35.5x and 3.0x respectively.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00745v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Maozhe Zhao, Shengzhong Liu, Fan Wu, Guihai Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entropy Heat-Mapping: Localizing GPT-Based OCR Errors with Sliding-Window Shannon Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00746</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00746v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Vision-language models such as OpenAI GPT-4o can transcribe mathematical documents directly from images, yet their token-level confidence signals are seldom used to pinpoint local recognition mistakes. We present an entropy-heat-mapping proof-of-concept that turns per-token Shannon entropy into a visual ''uncertainty landscape''. By scanning the entropy sequence with a fixed-length sliding window, we obtain hotspots that are likely to contain OCR errors such as missing symbols, mismatched braces, or garbled prose. Using a small, curated set of scanned research pages rendered at several resolutions, we compare the highlighted hotspots with the actual transcription errors produced by GPT-4o. Our analysis shows that the vast majority of true errors are indeed concentrated inside the high-entropy regions. This study demonstrates--in a minimally engineered setting--that sliding-window entropy can serve as a practical, lightweight aid for post-editing GPT-based OCR. All code, sample data, and annotation guidelines are released to encourage replication and further research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00746v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alexei Kaltchenko</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>InstructAttribute: Fine-grained Object Attributes editing with Instruction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00751</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00751v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Text-to-image (T2I) diffusion models, renowned for their advanced generative abilities, are extensively utilized in image editing applications, demonstrating remarkable effectiveness. However, achieving precise control over fine-grained attributes still presents considerable challenges. Existing image editing techniques either fail to modify the attributes of an object or struggle to preserve its structure and maintain consistency in other areas of the image. To address these challenges, we propose the Structure-Preserving and Attribute Amplification (SPAA), a training-free method which enables precise control over the color and material transformations of objects by editing the self-attention maps and cross-attention values. Furthermore, we constructed the Attribute Dataset, which encompasses nearly all colors and materials associated with various objects, by integrating multimodal large language models (MLLM) to develop an automated pipeline for data filtering and instruction labeling. Training on this dataset, we present our InstructAttribute, an instruction-based model designed to facilitate fine-grained editing of color and material attributes. Extensive experiments demonstrate that our method achieves superior performance in object-level color and material editing, outperforming existing instruction-based image editing approaches.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00751v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xingxi Yin, Jingfeng Zhang, Zhi Li, Yicheng Li, Yin Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DARTer: Dynamic Adaptive Representation Tracker for Nighttime UAV Tracking</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00752</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00752v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Nighttime UAV tracking presents significant challenges due to extreme illumination variations and viewpoint changes, which severely degrade tracking performance. Existing approaches either rely on light enhancers with high computational costs or introduce redundant domain adaptation mechanisms, failing to fully utilize the dynamic features in varying perspectives. To address these issues, we propose \textbf{DARTer} (\textbf{D}ynamic \textbf{A}daptive \textbf{R}epresentation \textbf{T}racker), an end-to-end tracking framework designed for nighttime UAV scenarios. DARTer leverages a Dynamic Feature Blender (DFB) to effectively fuse multi-perspective nighttime features from static and dynamic templates, enhancing representation robustness. Meanwhile, a Dynamic Feature Activator (DFA) adaptively activates Vision Transformer layers based on extracted features, significantly improving efficiency by reducing redundant computations. Our model eliminates the need for complex multi-task loss functions, enabling a streamlined training process. Extensive experiments on multiple nighttime UAV tracking benchmarks demonstrate the superiority of DARTer over state-of-the-art trackers. These results confirm that DARTer effectively balances tracking accuracy and efficiency, making it a promising solution for real-world nighttime UAV tracking applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00752v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xuzhao Li, Xuchen Li, Shiyu Hu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>P2P-Insole: Human Pose Estimation Using Foot Pressure Distribution and Motion Sensors</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00755</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00755v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This work presents P2P-Insole, a low-cost approach for estimating and visualizing 3D human skeletal data using insole-type sensors integrated with IMUs. Each insole, fabricated with e-textile garment techniques, costs under USD 1, making it significantly cheaper than commercial alternatives and ideal for large-scale production. Our approach uses foot pressure distribution, acceleration, and rotation data to overcome limitations, providing a lightweight, minimally intrusive, and privacy-aware solution. The system employs a Transformer model for efficient temporal feature extraction, enriched by first and second derivatives in the input stream. Including multimodal information, such as accelerometers and rotational measurements, improves the accuracy of complex motion pattern recognition. These facts are demonstrated experimentally, while error metrics show the robustness of the approach in various posture estimation tasks. This work could be the foundation for a low-cost, practical application in rehabilitation, injury prevention, and health monitoring while enabling further development through sensor optimization and expanded datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00755v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Atsuya Watanabe, Ratna Aisuwarya, Lei Jing</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient On-Chip Implementation of 4D Radar-Based 3D Object Detection on Hailo-8L</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00757</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00757v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: 4D radar has attracted attention in autonomous driving due to its ability to enable robust 3D object detection even under adverse weather conditions. To practically deploy such technologies, it is essential to achieve real-time processing within low-power embedded environments. Addressing this, we present the first on-chip implementation of a 4D radar-based 3D object detection model on the Hailo-8L AI accelerator. Although conventional 3D convolutional neural network (CNN) architectures require 5D inputs, the Hailo-8L only supports 4D tensors, posing a significant challenge. To overcome this limitation, we introduce a tensor transformation method that reshapes 5D inputs into 4D formats during the compilation process, enabling direct deployment without altering the model structure. The proposed system achieves 46.47% AP_3D and 52.75% AP_BEV, maintaining comparable accuracy to GPU-based models while achieving an inference speed of 13.76 Hz. These results demonstrate the applicability of 4D radar-based perception technologies to autonomous driving systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00757v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Woong-Chan Byun, Dong-Hee Paek, Seung-Hyun Song, Seung-Hyun Kong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Modal Language Models as Text-to-Image Model Evaluators</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00759</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00759v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The steady improvements of text-to-image (T2I) generative models lead to slow deprecation of automatic evaluation benchmarks that rely on static datasets, motivating researchers to seek alternative ways to evaluate the T2I progress. In this paper, we explore the potential of multi-modal large language models (MLLMs) as evaluator agents that interact with a T2I model, with the objective of assessing prompt-generation consistency and image aesthetics. We present Multimodal Text-to-Image Eval (MT2IE), an evaluation framework that iteratively generates prompts for evaluation, scores generated images and matches T2I evaluation of existing benchmarks with a fraction of the prompts used in existing static benchmarks. Moreover, we show that MT2IE's prompt-generation consistency scores have higher correlation with human judgment than scores previously introduced in the literature. MT2IE generates prompts that are efficient at probing T2I model performance, producing the same relative T2I model rankings as existing benchmarks while using only 1/80th the number of prompts for evaluation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00759v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiahui Chen, Candace Ross, Reyhane Askari-Hemmat, Koustuv Sinha, Melissa Hall, Michal Drozdzal, Adriana Romero-Soriano</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Person detection and re-identification in open-world settings of retail stores and public spaces</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00772</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00772v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Practical applications of computer vision in smart cities usually assume system integration and operation in challenging open-world environments. In the case of person re-identification task the main goal is to retrieve information whether the specific person has appeared in another place at a different time instance of the same video, or over multiple camera feeds. This typically assumes collecting raw data from video surveillance cameras in different places and under varying illumination conditions. In the considered open-world setting it also requires detection and localization of the person inside the analyzed video frame before the main re-identification step. With multi-person and multi-camera setups the system complexity becomes higher, requiring sophisticated tracking solutions and re-identification models. In this work we will discuss existing challenges in system design architectures, consider possible solutions based on different computer vision techniques, and describe applications of such systems in retail stores and public spaces for improved marketing analytics. In order to analyse sensitivity of person re-identification task under different open-world environments, a performance of one close to real-time solution will be demonstrated over several video captures and live camera feeds. Finally, based on conducted experiments we will indicate further research directions and possible system improvements.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00772v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Branko Brklja\v{c}, Milan Brklja\v{c}</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI-ready Snow Radar Echogram Dataset (SRED) for climate change monitoring</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00786</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00786v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Tracking internal layers in radar echograms with high accuracy is essential for understanding ice sheet dynamics and quantifying the impact of accelerated ice discharge in Greenland and other polar regions due to contemporary global climate warming. Deep learning algorithms have become the leading approach for automating this task, but the absence of a standardized and well-annotated echogram dataset has hindered the ability to test and compare algorithms reliably, limiting the advancement of state-of-the-art methods for the radar echogram layer tracking problem. This study introduces the first comprehensive ``deep learning ready'' radar echogram dataset derived from Snow Radar airborne data collected during the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Operation Ice Bridge (OIB) mission in 2012. The dataset contains 13,717 labeled and 57,815 weakly-labeled echograms covering diverse snow zones (dry, ablation, wet) with varying along-track resolutions. To demonstrate its utility, we evaluated the performance of five deep learning models on the dataset. Our results show that while current computer vision segmentation algorithms can identify and track snow layer pixels in echogram images, advanced end-to-end models are needed to directly extract snow depth and annual accumulation from echograms, reducing or eliminating post-processing. The dataset and accompanying benchmarking framework provide a valuable resource for advancing radar echogram layer tracking and snow accumulation estimation, advancing our understanding of polar ice sheets response to climate warming.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00786v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Oluwanisola Ibikunle, Hara Talasila, Debvrat Varshney, Jilu Li, John Paden, Maryam Rahnemoonfar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SpatialLLM: A Compound 3D-Informed Design towards Spatially-Intelligent Large Multimodal Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00788</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00788v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Humans naturally understand 3D spatial relationships, enabling complex reasoning like predicting collisions of vehicles from different directions. Current large multimodal models (LMMs), however, lack of this capability of 3D spatial reasoning. This limitation stems from the scarcity of 3D training data and the bias in current model designs toward 2D data. In this paper, we systematically study the impact of 3D-informed data, architecture, and training setups, introducing SpatialLLM, a large multi-modal model with advanced 3D spatial reasoning abilities. To address data limitations, we develop two types of 3D-informed training datasets: (1) 3D-informed probing data focused on object's 3D location and orientation, and (2) 3D-informed conversation data for complex spatial relationships. Notably, we are the first to curate VQA data that incorporate 3D orientation relationships on real images. Furthermore, we systematically integrate these two types of training data with the architectural and training designs of LMMs, providing a roadmap for optimal design aimed at achieving superior 3D reasoning capabilities. Our SpatialLLM advances machines toward highly capable 3D-informed reasoning, surpassing GPT-4o performance by 8.7%. Our systematic empirical design and the resulting findings offer valuable insights for future research in this direction.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00788v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wufei Ma, Luoxin Ye, Nessa McWeeney, Celso M de Melo, Alan Yuille, Jieneng Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing Wheat Crop Analysis: A Survey of Deep Learning Approaches Using Hyperspectral Imaging</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00805</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00805v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: As one of the most widely cultivated and consumed crops, wheat is essential to global food security. However, wheat production is increasingly challenged by pests, diseases, climate change, and water scarcity, threatening yields. Traditional crop monitoring methods are labor-intensive and often ineffective for early issue detection. Hyperspectral imaging (HSI) has emerged as a non-destructive and efficient technology for remote crop health assessment. However, the high dimensionality of HSI data and limited availability of labeled samples present notable challenges. In recent years, deep learning has shown great promise in addressing these challenges due to its ability to extract and analysis complex structures. Despite advancements in applying deep learning methods to HSI data for wheat crop analysis, no comprehensive survey currently exists in this field. This review addresses this gap by summarizing benchmark datasets, tracking advancements in deep learning methods, and analyzing key applications such as variety classification, disease detection, and yield estimation. It also highlights the strengths, limitations, and future opportunities in leveraging deep learning methods for HSI-based wheat crop analysis. We have listed the current state-of-the-art papers and will continue tracking updating them in the following https://github.com/fadi-07/Awesome-Wheat-HSI-DeepLearning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00805v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fadi Abdeladhim Zidi, Abdelkrim Ouafi, Fares Bougourzi, Cosimo Distante, Abdelmalik Taleb-Ahmed</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Comparability of Model Fusion to Measured Data in Confuser Rejection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00836</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00836v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Data collection has always been a major issue in the modeling and training of large deep learning networks, as no dataset can account for every slight deviation we might see in live usage. Collecting samples can be especially costly for Synthetic Aperture Radar (SAR), limiting the amount of unique targets and operating conditions we are able to observe from. To counter this lack of data, simulators have been developed utilizing the shooting and bouncing ray method to allow for the generation of synthetic SAR data on 3D models. While effective, the synthetically generated data does not perfectly correlate to the measured data leading to issues when training models solely on synthetic data. We aim to use computational power as a substitution for this lack of quality measured data, by ensembling many models trained on synthetic data. Synthetic data is also not complete, as we do not know what targets might be present in a live environment. Therefore we need to have our ensembling techniques account for these unknown targets by applying confuser rejection in which our models will reject unknown targets it is presented with, and only classify those it has been trained on.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00836v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Conor Flynn, Christopher Ebersole, Edmund Zelnio</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Minimal Radial Distortion Solvers Really Necessary for Relative Pose Estimation?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00866</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00866v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Estimating the relative pose between two cameras is a fundamental step in many applications such as Structure-from-Motion. The common approach to relative pose estimation is to apply a minimal solver inside a RANSAC loop. Highly efficient solvers exist for pinhole cameras. Yet, (nearly) all cameras exhibit radial distortion. Not modeling radial distortion leads to (significantly) worse results. However, minimal radial distortion solvers are significantly more complex than pinhole solvers, both in terms of run-time and implementation efforts. This paper compares radial distortion solvers with two simple-to-implement approaches that do not use minimal radial distortion solvers: The first approach combines an efficient pinhole solver with sampled radial undistortion parameters, where the sampled parameters are used for undistortion prior to applying the pinhole solver. The second approach uses a state-of-the-art neural network to estimate the distortion parameters rather than sampling them from a set of potential values. Extensive experiments on multiple datasets, and different camera setups, show that complex minimal radial distortion solvers are not necessary in practice. We discuss under which conditions a simple sampling of radial undistortion parameters is preferable over calibrating cameras using a learning-based prior approach. Code and newly created benchmark for relative pose estimation under radial distortion are available at https://github.com/kocurvik/rdnet.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00866v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Viktor Kocur, Charalambos Tzamos, Yaqing Ding, Zuzana Berger Haladova, Torsten Sattler, Zuzana Kukelova</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CDFormer: Cross-Domain Few-Shot Object Detection Transformer Against Feature Confusion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00938</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00938v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Cross-domain few-shot object detection (CD-FSOD) aims to detect novel objects across different domains with limited class instances. Feature confusion, including object-background confusion and object-object confusion, presents significant challenges in both cross-domain and few-shot settings. In this work, we introduce CDFormer, a cross-domain few-shot object detection transformer against feature confusion, to address these challenges. The method specifically tackles feature confusion through two key modules: object-background distinguishing (OBD) and object-object distinguishing (OOD). The OBD module leverages a learnable background token to differentiate between objects and background, while the OOD module enhances the distinction between objects of different classes. Experimental results demonstrate that CDFormer outperforms previous state-of-the-art approaches, achieving 12.9% mAP, 11.0% mAP, and 10.4% mAP improvements under the 1/5/10 shot settings, respectively, when fine-tuned.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00938v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Boyuan Meng, Xiaohan Zhang, Peilin Li, Zhe Wu, Yiming Li, Wenkai Zhao, Beinan Yu, Hui-Liang Shen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generating Animated Layouts as Structured Text Representations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00975</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00975v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Despite the remarkable progress in text-to-video models, achieving precise control over text elements and animated graphics remains a significant challenge, especially in applications such as video advertisements. To address this limitation, we introduce Animated Layout Generation, a novel approach to extend static graphic layouts with temporal dynamics. We propose a Structured Text Representation for fine-grained video control through hierarchical visual elements. To demonstrate the effectiveness of our approach, we present VAKER (Video Ad maKER), a text-to-video advertisement generation pipeline that combines a three-stage generation process with Unstructured Text Reasoning for seamless integration with LLMs. VAKER fully automates video advertisement generation by incorporating dynamic layout trajectories for objects and graphics across specific video frames. Through extensive evaluations, we demonstrate that VAKER significantly outperforms existing methods in generating video advertisements. Project Page: https://yeonsangshin.github.io/projects/Vaker</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00975v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yeonsang Shin, Jihwan Kim, Yumin Song, Kyungseung Lee, Hyunhee Chung, Taeyoung Na</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LMDepth: Lightweight Mamba-based Monocular Depth Estimation for Real-World Deployment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00980</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00980v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Monocular depth estimation provides an additional depth dimension to RGB images, making it widely applicable in various fields such as virtual reality, autonomous driving and robotic navigation. However, existing depth estimation algorithms often struggle to effectively balance performance and computational efficiency, which poses challenges for deployment on resource-constrained devices. To address this, we propose LMDepth, a lightweight Mamba-based monocular depth estimation network, designed to reconstruct high-precision depth information while maintaining low computational overhead. Specifically, we propose a modified pyramid spatial pooling module that serves as a multi-scale feature aggregator and context extractor, ensuring global spatial information for accurate depth estimation. Moreover, we integrate multiple depth Mamba blocks into the decoder. Designed with linear computations, the Mamba Blocks enable LMDepth to efficiently decode depth information from global features, providing a lightweight alternative to Transformer-based architectures that depend on complex attention mechanisms. Extensive experiments on the NYUDv2 and KITTI datasets demonstrate the effectiveness of our proposed LMDepth. Compared to previous lightweight depth estimation methods, LMDepth achieves higher performance with fewer parameters and lower computational complexity (measured by GFLOPs). We further deploy LMDepth on an embedded platform with INT8 quantization, validating its practicality for real-world edge applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00980v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiahuan Long, Xin Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deterministic-to-Stochastic Diverse Latent Feature Mapping for Human Motion Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00998</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00998v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Human motion synthesis aims to generate plausible human motion sequences, which has raised widespread attention in computer animation. Recent score-based generative models (SGMs) have demonstrated impressive results on this task. However, their training process involves complex curvature trajectories, leading to unstable training process. In this paper, we propose a Deterministic-to-Stochastic Diverse Latent Feature Mapping (DSDFM) method for human motion synthesis. DSDFM consists of two stages. The first human motion reconstruction stage aims to learn the latent space distribution of human motions. The second diverse motion generation stage aims to build connections between the Gaussian distribution and the latent space distribution of human motions, thereby enhancing the diversity and accuracy of the generated human motions. This stage is achieved by the designed deterministic feature mapping procedure with DerODE and stochastic diverse output generation procedure with DivSDE.DSDFM is easy to train compared to previous SGMs-based methods and can enhance diversity without introducing additional training parameters.Through qualitative and quantitative experiments, DSDFM achieves state-of-the-art results surpassing the latest methods, validating its superiority in human motion synthesis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00998v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>The IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition 2025</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Yu Hua, Weiming Liu, Gui Xu, Yaqing Hou, Yew-Soon Ong, Qiang Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3D Human Pose Estimation via Spatial Graph Order Attention and Temporal Body Aware Transformer</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01003</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01003v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Nowadays, Transformers and Graph Convolutional Networks (GCNs) are the prevailing techniques for 3D human pose estimation. However, Transformer-based methods either ignore the spatial neighborhood relationships between the joints when used for skeleton representations or disregard the local temporal patterns of the local joint movements in skeleton sequence modeling, while GCN-based methods often neglect the need for pose-specific representations. To address these problems, we propose a new method that exploits the graph modeling capability of GCN to represent each skeleton with multiple graphs of different orders, incorporated with a newly introduced Graph Order Attention module that dynamically emphasizes the most representative orders for each joint. The resulting spatial features of the sequence are further processed using a proposed temporal Body Aware Transformer that models the global body feature dependencies in the sequence with awareness of the local inter-skeleton feature dependencies of joints. Given that our 3D pose output aligns with the central 2D pose in the sequence, we improve the self-attention mechanism to be aware of the central pose while diminishing its focus gradually towards the first and the last poses. Extensive experiments on Human3.6m, MPIINF-3DHP, and HumanEva-I datasets demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed method. Code and models are made available on Github.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01003v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kamel Aouaidjia, Aofan Li, Wenhao Zhang, Chongsheng Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fine-Tuning Without Forgetting: Adaptation of YOLOv8 Preserves COCO Performance</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01016</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01016v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The success of large pre-trained object detectors hinges on their adaptability to diverse downstream tasks. While fine-tuning is the standard adaptation method, specializing these models for challenging fine-grained domains necessitates careful consideration of feature granularity. The critical question remains: how deeply should the pre-trained backbone be fine-tuned to optimize for the specialized task without incurring catastrophic forgetting of the original general capabilities? Addressing this, we present a systematic empirical study evaluating the impact of fine-tuning depth. We adapt a standard YOLOv8n model to a custom, fine-grained fruit detection dataset by progressively unfreezing backbone layers (freeze points at layers 22, 15, and 10) and training. Performance was rigorously evaluated on both the target fruit dataset and, using a dual-head evaluation architecture, on the original COCO validation set. Our results demonstrate unequivocally that deeper fine-tuning (unfreezing down to layer 10) yields substantial performance gains (e.g., +10\% absolute mAP50) on the fine-grained fruit task compared to only training the head. Strikingly, this significant adaptation and specialization resulted in negligible performance degradation (&lt;0.1\% absolute mAP difference) on the COCO benchmark across all tested freeze levels. We conclude that adapting mid-to-late backbone features is highly effective for fine-grained specialization. Critically, our results demonstrate this adaptation can be achieved without the commonly expected penalty of catastrophic forgetting, presenting a compelling case for exploring deeper fine-tuning strategies, particularly when targeting complex domains or when maximizing specialized performance is paramount.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01016v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Vishal Gandhi, Sagar Gandhi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Edge-preserving Image Denoising via Multi-scale Adaptive Statistical Independence Testing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01032</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01032v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Edge detection is crucial in image processing, but existing methods often produce overly detailed edge maps, affecting clarity. Fixed-window statistical testing faces issues like scale mismatch and computational redundancy. To address these, we propose a novel Multi-scale Adaptive Independence Testing-based Edge Detection and Denoising (EDD-MAIT), a Multi-scale Adaptive Statistical Testing-based edge detection and denoising method that integrates a channel attention mechanism with independence testing. A gradient-driven adaptive window strategy adjusts window sizes dynamically, improving detail preservation and noise suppression. EDD-MAIT achieves better robustness, accuracy, and efficiency, outperforming traditional and learning-based methods on BSDS500 and BIPED datasets, with improvements in F-score, MSE, PSNR, and reduced runtime. It also shows robustness against Gaussian noise, generating accurate and clean edge maps in noisy environments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01032v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ruyu Yan, Da-Qing Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Edge Detection based on Channel Attention and Inter-region Independence Test</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01040</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01040v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Existing edge detection methods often suffer from noise amplification and excessive retention of non-salient details, limiting their applicability in high-precision industrial scenarios. To address these challenges, we propose CAM-EDIT, a novel framework that integrates Channel Attention Mechanism (CAM) and Edge Detection via Independence Testing (EDIT). The CAM module adaptively enhances discriminative edge features through multi-channel fusion, while the EDIT module employs region-wise statistical independence analysis (using Fisher's exact test and chi-square test) to suppress uncorrelated noise.Extensive experiments on BSDS500 and NYUDv2 datasets demonstrate state-of-the-art performance. Among the nine comparison algorithms, the F-measure scores of CAM-EDIT are 0.635 and 0.460, representing improvements of 19.2\% to 26.5\% over traditional methods (Canny, CannySR), and better than the latest learning based methods (TIP2020, MSCNGP). Noise robustness evaluations further reveal a 2.2\% PSNR improvement under Gaussian noise compared to baseline methods. Qualitative results exhibit cleaner edge maps with reduced artifacts, demonstrating its potential for high-precision industrial applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01040v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ru-yu Yan, Da-Qing Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transferable Adversarial Attacks on Black-Box Vision-Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01050</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01050v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Vision Large Language Models (VLLMs) are increasingly deployed to offer advanced capabilities on inputs comprising both text and images. While prior research has shown that adversarial attacks can transfer from open-source to proprietary black-box models in text-only and vision-only contexts, the extent and effectiveness of such vulnerabilities remain underexplored for VLLMs. We present a comprehensive analysis demonstrating that targeted adversarial examples are highly transferable to widely-used proprietary VLLMs such as GPT-4o, Claude, and Gemini. We show that attackers can craft perturbations to induce specific attacker-chosen interpretations of visual information, such as misinterpreting hazardous content as safe, overlooking sensitive or restricted material, or generating detailed incorrect responses aligned with the attacker's intent. Furthermore, we discover that universal perturbations -- modifications applicable to a wide set of images -- can consistently induce these misinterpretations across multiple proprietary VLLMs. Our experimental results on object recognition, visual question answering, and image captioning show that this vulnerability is common across current state-of-the-art models, and underscore an urgent need for robust mitigations to ensure the safe and secure deployment of VLLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01050v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kai Hu, Weichen Yu, Li Zhang, Alexander Robey, Andy Zou, Chengming Xu, Haoqi Hu, Matt Fredrikson</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GeloVec: Higher Dimensional Geometric Smoothing for Coherent Visual Feature Extraction in Image Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01057</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01057v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper introduces GeloVec, a new CNN-based attention smoothing framework for semantic segmentation that addresses critical limitations in conventional approaches. While existing attention-backed segmentation methods suffer from boundary instability and contextual discontinuities during feature mapping, our framework implements a higher-dimensional geometric smoothing method to establish a robust manifold relationships between visually coherent regions. GeloVec combines modified Chebyshev distance metrics with multispatial transformations to enhance segmentation accuracy through stabilized feature extraction. The core innovation lies in the adaptive sampling weights system that calculates geometric distances in n-dimensional feature space, achieving superior edge preservation while maintaining intra-class homogeneity. The multispatial transformation matrix incorporates tensorial projections with orthogonal basis vectors, creating more discriminative feature representations without sacrificing computational efficiency. Experimental validation across multiple benchmark datasets demonstrates significant improvements in segmentation performance, with mean Intersection over Union (mIoU) gains of 2.1%, 2.7%, and 2.4% on Caltech Birds-200, LSDSC, and FSSD datasets respectively compared to state-of-the-art methods. GeloVec's mathematical foundation in Riemannian geometry provides theoretical guarantees on segmentation stability. Importantly, our framework maintains computational efficiency through parallelized implementation of geodesic transformations and exhibits strong generalization capabilities across disciplines due to the absence of information loss during transformations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01057v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Boris Kriuk, Matey Yordanov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Vocabulary-Free Fine-Grained Visual Recognition in the Age of Multimodal LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01064</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01064v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Fine-grained Visual Recognition (FGVR) involves distinguishing between visually similar categories, which is inherently challenging due to subtle inter-class differences and the need for large, expert-annotated datasets. In domains like medical imaging, such curated datasets are unavailable due to issues like privacy concerns and high annotation costs. In such scenarios lacking labeled data, an FGVR model cannot rely on a predefined set of training labels, and hence has an unconstrained output space for predictions. We refer to this task as Vocabulary-Free FGVR (VF-FGVR), where a model must predict labels from an unconstrained output space without prior label information. While recent Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) show potential for VF-FGVR, querying these models for each test input is impractical because of high costs and prohibitive inference times. To address these limitations, we introduce \textbf{Nea}rest-Neighbor Label \textbf{R}efinement (NeaR), a novel approach that fine-tunes a downstream CLIP model using labels generated by an MLLM. Our approach constructs a weakly supervised dataset from a small, unlabeled training set, leveraging MLLMs for label generation. NeaR is designed to handle the noise, stochasticity, and open-endedness inherent in labels generated by MLLMs, and establishes a new benchmark for efficient VF-FGVR.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01064v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hari Chandana Kuchibhotla, Sai Srinivas Kancheti, Abbavaram Gowtham Reddy, Vineeth N Balasubramanian</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Editability in Image Generation with Layer-wise Memory</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01079</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01079v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Most real-world image editing tasks require multiple sequential edits to achieve desired results. Current editing approaches, primarily designed for single-object modifications, struggle with sequential editing: especially with maintaining previous edits along with adapting new objects naturally into the existing content. These limitations significantly hinder complex editing scenarios where multiple objects need to be modified while preserving their contextual relationships. We address this fundamental challenge through two key proposals: enabling rough mask inputs that preserve existing content while naturally integrating new elements and supporting consistent editing across multiple modifications. Our framework achieves this through layer-wise memory, which stores latent representations and prompt embeddings from previous edits. We propose Background Consistency Guidance that leverages memorized latents to maintain scene coherence and Multi-Query Disentanglement in cross-attention that ensures natural adaptation to existing content. To evaluate our method, we present a new benchmark dataset incorporating semantic alignment metrics and interactive editing scenarios. Through comprehensive experiments, we demonstrate superior performance in iterative image editing tasks with minimal user effort, requiring only rough masks while maintaining high-quality results throughout multiple editing steps.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01079v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Daneul Kim, Jaeah Lee, Jaesik Park</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Any-to-Any Vision-Language Model for Multimodal X-ray Imaging and Radiological Report Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01091</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01091v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Generative models have revolutionized Artificial Intelligence (AI), particularly in multimodal applications. However, adapting these models to the medical domain poses unique challenges due to the complexity of medical data and the stringent need for clinical accuracy. In this work, we introduce a framework specifically designed for multimodal medical data generation. By enabling the generation of multi-view chest X-rays and their associated clinical report, it bridges the gap between general-purpose vision-language models and the specialized requirements of healthcare. Leveraging the MIMIC-CXR dataset, the proposed framework shows superior performance in generating high-fidelity images and semantically coherent reports. Our quantitative evaluation reveals significant results in terms of FID and BLEU scores, showcasing the quality of the generated data. Notably, our framework achieves comparable or even superior performance compared to real data on downstream disease classification tasks, underlining its potential as a tool for medical research and diagnostics. This study highlights the importance of domain-specific adaptations in enhancing the relevance and utility of generative models for clinical applications, paving the way for future advancements in synthetic multimodal medical data generation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01091v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Daniele Molino, Francesco di Feola, Linlin Shen, Paolo Soda, Valerio Guarrasi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Vision Language Model Adaptations for Radiology Report Generation in Low-Resource Languages</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01096</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01096v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The integration of artificial intelligence in healthcare has opened new horizons for improving medical diagnostics and patient care. However, challenges persist in developing systems capable of generating accurate and contextually relevant radiology reports, particularly in low-resource languages. In this study, we present a comprehensive benchmark to evaluate the performance of instruction-tuned Vision-Language Models (VLMs) in the specialized task of radiology report generation across three low-resource languages: Italian, German, and Spanish. Employing the LLaVA architectural framework, we conducted a systematic evaluation of pre-trained models utilizing general datasets, domain-specific datasets, and low-resource language-specific datasets. In light of the unavailability of models that possess prior knowledge of both the medical domain and low-resource languages, we analyzed various adaptations to determine the most effective approach for these contexts. The results revealed that language-specific models substantially outperformed both general and domain-specific models in generating radiology reports, emphasizing the critical role of linguistic adaptation. Additionally, models fine-tuned with medical terminology exhibited enhanced performance across all languages compared to models with generic knowledge, highlighting the importance of domain-specific training. We also explored the influence of the temperature parameter on the coherence of report generation, providing insights for optimal model settings. Our findings highlight the importance of tailored language and domain-specific training for improving the quality and accuracy of radiological reports in multilingual settings. This research not only advances our understanding of VLMs adaptability in healthcare but also points to significant avenues for future investigations into model tuning and language-specific adaptations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01096v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Marco Salm\`e, Rosa Sicilia, Paolo Soda, Valerio Guarrasi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VSC: Visual Search Compositional Text-to-Image Diffusion Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01104</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01104v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Text-to-image diffusion models have shown impressive capabilities in generating realistic visuals from natural-language prompts, yet they often struggle with accurately binding attributes to corresponding objects, especially in prompts containing multiple attribute-object pairs. This challenge primarily arises from the limitations of commonly used text encoders, such as CLIP, which can fail to encode complex linguistic relationships and modifiers effectively. Existing approaches have attempted to mitigate these issues through attention map control during inference and the use of layout information or fine-tuning during training, yet they face performance drops with increased prompt complexity. In this work, we introduce a novel compositional generation method that leverages pairwise image embeddings to improve attribute-object binding. Our approach decomposes complex prompts into sub-prompts, generates corresponding images, and computes visual prototypes that fuse with text embeddings to enhance representation. By applying segmentation-based localization training, we address cross-attention misalignment, achieving improved accuracy in binding multiple attributes to objects. Our approaches outperform existing compositional text-to-image diffusion models on the benchmark T2I CompBench, achieving better image quality, evaluated by humans, and emerging robustness under scaling number of binding pairs in the prompt.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01104v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Do Huu Dat, Nam Hyeonu, Po-Yuan Mao, Tae-Hyun Oh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Supervision Enhances Instance-based Multiple Instance Learning Methods in Digital Pathology: A Benchmark Study</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01109</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01109v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Multiple Instance Learning (MIL) has emerged as the best solution for Whole Slide Image (WSI) classification. It consists of dividing each slide into patches, which are treated as a bag of instances labeled with a global label. MIL includes two main approaches: instance-based and embedding-based. In the former, each patch is classified independently, and then the patch scores are aggregated to predict the bag label. In the latter, bag classification is performed after aggregating patch embeddings. Even if instance-based methods are naturally more interpretable, embedding-based MILs have usually been preferred in the past due to their robustness to poor feature extractors. However, recently, the quality of feature embeddings has drastically increased using self-supervised learning (SSL). Nevertheless, many authors continue to endorse the superiority of embedding-based MIL. To investigate this further, we conduct 710 experiments across 4 datasets, comparing 10 MIL strategies, 6 self-supervised methods with 4 backbones, 4 foundation models, and various pathology-adapted techniques. Furthermore, we introduce 4 instance-based MIL methods never used before in the pathology domain. Through these extensive experiments, we show that with a good SSL feature extractor, simple instance-based MILs, with very few parameters, obtain similar or better performance than complex, state-of-the-art (SOTA) embedding-based MIL methods, setting new SOTA results on the BRACS and Camelyon16 datasets. Since simple instance-based MIL methods are naturally more interpretable and explainable to clinicians, our results suggest that more effort should be put into well-adapted SSL methods for WSI rather than into complex embedding-based MIL methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01109v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ali Mammadov, Loic Le Folgoc, Julien Adam, Anne Buronfosse, Gilles Hayem, Guillaume Hocquet, Pietro Gori</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FreePCA: Integrating Consistency Information across Long-short Frames in Training-free Long Video Generation via Principal Component Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01172</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01172v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Long video generation involves generating extended videos using models trained on short videos, suffering from distribution shifts due to varying frame counts. It necessitates the use of local information from the original short frames to enhance visual and motion quality, and global information from the entire long frames to ensure appearance consistency. Existing training-free methods struggle to effectively integrate the benefits of both, as appearance and motion in videos are closely coupled, leading to motion inconsistency and visual quality. In this paper, we reveal that global and local information can be precisely decoupled into consistent appearance and motion intensity information by applying Principal Component Analysis (PCA), allowing for refined complementary integration of global consistency and local quality. With this insight, we propose FreePCA, a training-free long video generation paradigm based on PCA that simultaneously achieves high consistency and quality. Concretely, we decouple consistent appearance and motion intensity features by measuring cosine similarity in the principal component space. Critically, we progressively integrate these features to preserve original quality and ensure smooth transitions, while further enhancing consistency by reusing the mean statistics of the initial noise. Experiments demonstrate that FreePCA can be applied to various video diffusion models without requiring training, leading to substantial improvements. Code is available at https://github.com/JosephTiTan/FreePCA.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01172v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiangtong Tan, Hu Yu, Jie Huang, Jie Xiao, Feng Zhao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TSTMotion: Training-free Scene-awarenText-to-motion Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01182</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01182v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Text-to-motion generation has recently garnered significant research interest, primarily focusing on generating human motion sequences in blank backgrounds. However, human motions commonly occur within diverse 3D scenes, which has prompted exploration into scene-aware text-to-motion generation methods. Yet, existing scene-aware methods often rely on large-scale ground-truth motion sequences in diverse 3D scenes, which poses practical challenges due to the expensive cost. To mitigate this challenge, we are the first to propose a \textbf{T}raining-free \textbf{S}cene-aware \textbf{T}ext-to-\textbf{Motion} framework, dubbed as \textbf{TSTMotion}, that efficiently empowers pre-trained blank-background motion generators with the scene-aware capability. Specifically, conditioned on the given 3D scene and text description, we adopt foundation models together to reason, predict and validate a scene-aware motion guidance. Then, the motion guidance is incorporated into the blank-background motion generators with two modifications, resulting in scene-aware text-driven motion sequences. Extensive experiments demonstrate the efficacy and generalizability of our proposed framework. We release our code in \href{https://tstmotion.github.io/}{Project Page}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01182v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ziyan Guo, Haoxuan Qu, Hossein Rahmani, Dewen Soh, Ping Hu, Qiuhong Ke, Jun Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Vision-based Vehicle Speed Estimation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01203</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01203v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper presents a computationally efficient method for vehicle speed estimation from traffic camera footage. Building upon previous work that utilizes 3D bounding boxes derived from 2D detections and vanishing point geometry, we introduce several improvements to enhance real-time performance. We evaluate our method in several variants on the BrnoCompSpeed dataset in terms of vehicle detection and speed estimation accuracy. Our extensive evaluation across various hardware platforms, including edge devices, demonstrates significant gains in frames per second (FPS) compared to the prior state-of-the-art, while maintaining comparable or improved speed estimation accuracy. We analyze the trade-off between accuracy and computational cost, showing that smaller models utilizing post-training quantization offer the best balance for real-world deployment. Our best performing model beats previous state-of-the-art in terms of median vehicle speed estimation error (0.58 km/h vs. 0.60 km/h), detection precision (91.02% vs 87.08%) and recall (91.14% vs. 83.32%) while also being 5.5 times faster.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01203v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Andrej Macko, Luk\'a\v{s} Gajdo\v{s}ech, Viktor Kocur</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>T-Graph: Enhancing Sparse-view Camera Pose Estimation by Pairwise Translation Graph</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01207</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01207v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Sparse-view camera pose estimation, which aims to estimate the 6-Degree-of-Freedom (6-DoF) poses from a limited number of images captured from different viewpoints, is a fundamental yet challenging problem in remote sensing applications. Existing methods often overlook the translation information between each pair of viewpoints, leading to suboptimal performance in sparse-view scenarios. To address this limitation, we introduce T-Graph, a lightweight, plug-and-play module to enhance camera pose estimation in sparse-view settings. T-graph takes paired image features as input and maps them through a Multilayer Perceptron (MLP). It then constructs a fully connected translation graph, where nodes represent cameras and edges encode their translation relationships. It can be seamlessly integrated into existing models as an additional branch in parallel with the original prediction, maintaining efficiency and ease of use. Furthermore, we introduce two pairwise translation representations, relative-t and pair-t, formulated under different local coordinate systems. While relative-t captures intuitive spatial relationships, pair-t offers a rotation-disentangled alternative. The two representations contribute to enhanced adaptability across diverse application scenarios, further improving our module's robustness. Extensive experiments on two state-of-the-art methods (RelPose++ and Forge) using public datasets (C03D and IMC PhotoTourism) validate both the effectiveness and generalizability of T-Graph. The results demonstrate consistent improvements across various metrics, notably camera center accuracy, which improves by 1% to 6% from 2 to 8 viewpoints.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01207v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qingyu Xian, Weiqin Jiao, Hao Cheng, Berend Jan van der Zwaag, Yanqiu Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Dynamic Range Novel View Synthesis with Single Exposure</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01212</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01212v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: High Dynamic Range Novel View Synthesis (HDR-NVS) aims to establish a 3D scene HDR model from Low Dynamic Range (LDR) imagery. Typically, multiple-exposure LDR images are employed to capture a wider range of brightness levels in a scene, as a single LDR image cannot represent both the brightest and darkest regions simultaneously. While effective, this multiple-exposure HDR-NVS approach has significant limitations, including susceptibility to motion artifacts (e.g., ghosting and blurring), high capture and storage costs. To overcome these challenges, we introduce, for the first time, the single-exposure HDR-NVS problem, where only single exposure LDR images are available during training. We further introduce a novel approach, Mono-HDR-3D, featuring two dedicated modules formulated by the LDR image formation principles, one for converting LDR colors to HDR counterparts, and the other for transforming HDR images to LDR format so that unsupervised learning is enabled in a closed loop. Designed as a meta-algorithm, our approach can be seamlessly integrated with existing NVS models. Extensive experiments show that Mono-HDR-3D significantly outperforms previous methods. Source code will be released.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01212v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kaixuan Zhang, Hu Wang, Minxian Li, Mingwu Ren, Mao Ye, Xiatian Zhu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RD-UIE: Relation-Driven State Space Modeling for Underwater Image Enhancement</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01224</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01224v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Underwater image enhancement (UIE) is a critical preprocessing step for marine vision applications, where wavelength-dependent attenuation causes severe content degradation and color distortion. While recent state space models like Mamba show potential for long-range dependency modeling, their unfolding operations and fixed scan paths on 1D sequences fail to adapt to local object semantics and global relation modeling, limiting their efficacy in complex underwater environments. To address this, we enhance conventional Mamba with the sorting-based scanning mechanism that dynamically reorders scanning sequences based on statistical distribution of spatial correlation of all pixels. In this way, it encourages the network to prioritize the most informative components--structural and semantic features. Upon building this mechanism, we devise a Visually Self-adaptive State Block (VSSB) that harmonizes dynamic sorting of Mamba with input-dependent dynamic convolution, enabling coherent integration of global context and local relational cues. This exquisite design helps eliminate global focus bias, especially for widely distributed contents, which greatly weakens the statistical frequency. For robust feature extraction and refinement, we design a cross-feature bridge (CFB) to adaptively fuse multi-scale representations. These efforts compose the novel relation-driven Mamba framework for effective UIE (RD-UIE). Extensive experiments on underwater enhancement benchmarks demonstrate RD-UIE outperforms the state-of-the-art approach WMamba in both quantitative metrics and visual fidelity, averagely achieving 0.55 dB performance gain on the three benchmarks. Our code is available at https://github.com/kkoucy/RD-UIE/tree/main</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01224v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kui Jiang, Yan Luo, Junjun Jiang, Xin Xu, Fei Ma, Fei Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Core-Set Selection for Data-efficient Land Cover Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01225</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01225v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The increasing accessibility of remotely sensed data and the potential of such data to inform large-scale decision-making has driven the development of deep learning models for many Earth Observation tasks. Traditionally, such models must be trained on large datasets. However, the common assumption that broadly larger datasets lead to better outcomes tends to overlook the complexities of the data distribution, the potential for introducing biases and noise, and the computational resources required for processing and storing vast datasets. Therefore, effective solutions should consider both the quantity and quality of data. In this paper, we propose six novel core-set selection methods for selecting important subsets of samples from remote sensing image segmentation datasets that rely on imagery only, labels only, and a combination of each. We benchmark these approaches against a random-selection baseline on three commonly used land cover classification datasets: DFC2022, Vaihingen, and Potsdam. In each of the datasets, we demonstrate that training on a subset of samples outperforms the random baseline, and some approaches outperform training on all available data. This result shows the importance and potential of data-centric learning for the remote sensing domain. The code is available at https://github.com/keillernogueira/data-centric-rs-classification/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01225v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Keiller Nogueira, Akram Zaytar, Wanli Ma, Ribana Roscher, Ronny H\"ansch, Caleb Robinson, Anthony Ortiz, Simone Nsutezo, Rahul Dodhia, Juan M. Lavista Ferres, Oktay Karaku\c{s}, Paul L. Rosin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compensating Spatiotemporally Inconsistent Observations for Online Dynamic 3D Gaussian Splatting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01235</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01235v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Online reconstruction of dynamic scenes is significant as it enables learning scenes from live-streaming video inputs, while existing offline dynamic reconstruction methods rely on recorded video inputs. However, previous online reconstruction approaches have primarily focused on efficiency and rendering quality, overlooking the temporal consistency of their results, which often contain noticeable artifacts in static regions. This paper identifies that errors such as noise in real-world recordings affect temporal inconsistency in online reconstruction. We propose a method that enhances temporal consistency in online reconstruction from observations with temporal inconsistency which is inevitable in cameras. We show that our method restores the ideal observation by subtracting the learned error. We demonstrate that applying our method to various baselines significantly enhances both temporal consistency and rendering quality across datasets. Code, video results, and checkpoints are available at https://bbangsik13.github.io/OR2.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01235v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3721238.3730678</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Youngsik Yun, Jeongmin Bae, Hyunseung Son, Seoha Kim, Hahyun Lee, Gun Bang, Youngjung Uh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fusing Foveal Fixations Using Linear Retinal Transformations and Bayesian Experimental Design</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01249</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01249v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Humans (and many vertebrates) face the problem of fusing together multiple fixations of a scene in order to obtain a representation of the whole, where each fixation uses a high-resolution fovea and decreasing resolution in the periphery. In this paper we explicitly represent the retinal transformation of a fixation as a linear downsampling of a high-resolution latent image of the scene, exploiting the known geometry. This linear transformation allows us to carry out exact inference for the latent variables in factor analysis (FA) and mixtures of FA models of the scene. Further, this allows us to formulate and solve the choice of "where to look next" as a Bayesian experimental design problem using the Expected Information Gain criterion. Experiments on the Frey faces and MNIST datasets demonstrate the effectiveness of our models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01249v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Christopher K. I. Williams</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CAMELTrack: Context-Aware Multi-cue ExpLoitation for Online Multi-Object Tracking</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01257</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01257v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Online multi-object tracking has been recently dominated by tracking-by-detection (TbD) methods, where recent advances rely on increasingly sophisticated heuristics for tracklet representation, feature fusion, and multi-stage matching. The key strength of TbD lies in its modular design, enabling the integration of specialized off-the-shelf models like motion predictors and re-identification. However, the extensive usage of human-crafted rules for temporal associations makes these methods inherently limited in their ability to capture the complex interplay between various tracking cues. In this work, we introduce CAMEL, a novel association module for Context-Aware Multi-Cue ExpLoitation, that learns resilient association strategies directly from data, breaking free from hand-crafted heuristics while maintaining TbD's valuable modularity. At its core, CAMEL employs two transformer-based modules and relies on a novel association-centric training scheme to effectively model the complex interactions between tracked targets and their various association cues. Unlike end-to-end detection-by-tracking approaches, our method remains lightweight and fast to train while being able to leverage external off-the-shelf models. Our proposed online tracking pipeline, CAMELTrack, achieves state-of-the-art performance on multiple tracking benchmarks. Our code is available at https://github.com/TrackingLaboratory/CAMELTrack.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01257v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Vladimir Somers, Baptiste Standaert, Victor Joos, Alexandre Alahi, Christophe De Vleeschouwer</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diffusion-based Adversarial Purification from the Perspective of the Frequency Domain</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01267</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01267v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The diffusion-based adversarial purification methods attempt to drown adversarial perturbations into a part of isotropic noise through the forward process, and then recover the clean images through the reverse process. Due to the lack of distribution information about adversarial perturbations in the pixel domain, it is often unavoidable to damage normal semantics. We turn to the frequency domain perspective, decomposing the image into amplitude spectrum and phase spectrum. We find that for both spectra, the damage caused by adversarial perturbations tends to increase monotonically with frequency. This means that we can extract the content and structural information of the original clean sample from the frequency components that are less damaged. Meanwhile, theoretical analysis indicates that existing purification methods indiscriminately damage all frequency components, leading to excessive damage to the image. Therefore, we propose a purification method that can eliminate adversarial perturbations while maximizing the preservation of the content and structure of the original image. Specifically, at each time step during the reverse process, for the amplitude spectrum, we replace the low-frequency components of the estimated image's amplitude spectrum with the corresponding parts of the adversarial image. For the phase spectrum, we project the phase of the estimated image into a designated range of the adversarial image's phase spectrum, focusing on the low frequencies. Empirical evidence from extensive experiments demonstrates that our method significantly outperforms most current defense methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01267v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gaozheng Pei, Ke Ma, Yingfei Sun, Qianqian Xu, Qingming Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FreeInsert: Disentangled Text-Guided Object Insertion in 3D Gaussian Scene without Spatial Priors</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01322</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01322v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Text-driven object insertion in 3D scenes is an emerging task that enables intuitive scene editing through natural language. However, existing 2D editing-based methods often rely on spatial priors such as 2D masks or 3D bounding boxes, and they struggle to ensure consistency of the inserted object. These limitations hinder flexibility and scalability in real-world applications. In this paper, we propose FreeInsert, a novel framework that leverages foundation models including MLLMs, LGMs, and diffusion models to disentangle object generation from spatial placement. This enables unsupervised and flexible object insertion in 3D scenes without spatial priors. FreeInsert starts with an MLLM-based parser that extracts structured semantics, including object types, spatial relationships, and attachment regions, from user instructions. These semantics guide both the reconstruction of the inserted object for 3D consistency and the learning of its degrees of freedom. We leverage the spatial reasoning capabilities of MLLMs to initialize object pose and scale. A hierarchical, spatially aware refinement stage further integrates spatial semantics and MLLM-inferred priors to enhance placement. Finally, the appearance of the object is improved using the inserted-object image to enhance visual fidelity. Experimental results demonstrate that FreeInsert achieves semantically coherent, spatially precise, and visually realistic 3D insertions without relying on spatial priors, offering a user-friendly and flexible editing experience.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01322v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chenxi Li, Weijie Wang, Qiang Li, Bruno Lepri, Nicu Sebe, Weizhi Nie</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring morphometric drift in lifelong learning segmentation of the spinal cord</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01364</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01364v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Morphometric measures derived from spinal cord segmentations can serve as diagnostic and prognostic biomarkers in neurological diseases and injuries affecting the spinal cord. While robust, automatic segmentation methods to a wide variety of contrasts and pathologies have been developed over the past few years, whether their predictions are stable as the model is updated using new datasets has not been assessed. This is particularly important for deriving normative values from healthy participants. In this study, we present a spinal cord segmentation model trained on a multisite $(n=75)$ dataset, including 9 different MRI contrasts and several spinal cord pathologies. We also introduce a lifelong learning framework to automatically monitor the morphometric drift as the model is updated using additional datasets. The framework is triggered by an automatic GitHub Actions workflow every time a new model is created, recording the morphometric values derived from the model's predictions over time. As a real-world application of the proposed framework, we employed the spinal cord segmentation model to update a recently-introduced normative database of healthy participants containing commonly used measures of spinal cord morphometry. Results showed that: (i) our model outperforms previous versions and pathology-specific models on challenging lumbar spinal cord cases, achieving an average Dice score of $0.95 \pm 0.03$; (ii) the automatic workflow for monitoring morphometric drift provides a quick feedback loop for developing future segmentation models; and (iii) the scaling factor required to update the database of morphometric measures is nearly constant among slices across the given vertebral levels, showing minimum drift between the current and previous versions of the model monitored by the framework. The model is freely available in Spinal Cord Toolbox v7.0.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01364v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Enamundram Naga Karthik, Sandrine B\'edard, Jan Valo\v{s}ek, Christoph S. Aigner, Elise Bannier, Josef Bedna\v{r}\'ik, Virginie Callot, Anna Combes, Armin Curt, Gergely David, Falk Eippert, Lynn Farner, Michael G Fehlings, Patrick Freund, Tobias Granberg, Cristina Granziera, RHSCIR Network Imaging Group, Ulrike Horn, Tom\'a\v{s} Hor\'ak, Suzanne Humphreys, Markus Hupp, Anne Kerbrat, Nawal Kinany, Shannon Kolind, Petr Kudli\v{c}ka, Anna Lebret, Lisa Eunyoung Lee, Caterina Mainero, Allan R. Martin, Megan McGrath, Govind Nair, Kristin P. O'Grady, Jiwon Oh, Russell Ouellette, Nikolai Pfender, Dario Pfyffer, Pierre-Fran\c{c}ois Pradat, Alexandre Prat, Emanuele Pravat\`a, Daniel S. Reich, Ilaria Ricchi, Naama Rotem-Kohavi, Simon Schading-Sassenhausen, Maryam Seif, Andrew Smith, Seth A Smith, Grace Sweeney, Roger Tam, Anthony Traboulsee, Constantina Andrada Treaba, Charidimos Tsagkas, Zachary Vavasour, Dimitri Van De Ville, Kenneth Arnold Weber II, Sarath Chandar, Julien Cohen-Adad</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global Collinearity-aware Polygonizer for Polygonal Building Mapping in Remote Sensing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01385</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01385v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This paper addresses the challenge of mapping polygonal buildings from remote sensing images and introduces a novel algorithm, the Global Collinearity-aware Polygonizer (GCP). GCP, built upon an instance segmentation framework, processes binary masks produced by any instance segmentation model. The algorithm begins by collecting polylines sampled along the contours of the binary masks. These polylines undergo a refinement process using a transformer-based regression module to ensure they accurately fit the contours of the targeted building instances. Subsequently, a collinearity-aware polygon simplification module simplifies these refined polylines and generate the final polygon representation. This module employs dynamic programming technique to optimize an objective function that balances the simplicity and fidelity of the polygons, achieving globally optimal solutions. Furthermore, the optimized collinearity-aware objective is seamlessly integrated into network training, enhancing the cohesiveness of the entire pipeline. The effectiveness of GCP has been validated on two public benchmarks for polygonal building mapping. Further experiments reveal that applying the collinearity-aware polygon simplification module to arbitrary polylines, without prior knowledge, enhances accuracy over traditional methods such as the Douglas-Peucker algorithm. This finding underscores the broad applicability of GCP. The code for the proposed method will be made available at https://github.com/zhu-xlab.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01385v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fahong Zhang, Yilei Shi, Xiao Xiang Zhu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multimodal Doctor-in-the-Loop: A Clinically-Guided Explainable Framework for Predicting Pathological Response in Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01390</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01390v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This study proposes a novel approach combining Multimodal Deep Learning with intrinsic eXplainable Artificial Intelligence techniques to predict pathological response in non-small cell lung cancer patients undergoing neoadjuvant therapy. Due to the limitations of existing radiomics and unimodal deep learning approaches, we introduce an intermediate fusion strategy that integrates imaging and clinical data, enabling efficient interaction between data modalities. The proposed Multimodal Doctor-in-the-Loop method further enhances clinical relevance by embedding clinicians' domain knowledge directly into the training process, guiding the model's focus gradually from broader lung regions to specific lesions. Results demonstrate improved predictive accuracy and explainability, providing insights into optimal data integration strategies for clinical applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01390v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alice Natalina Caragliano, Claudia Tacconi, Carlo Greco, Lorenzo Nibid, Edy Ippolito, Michele Fiore, Giuseppe Perrone, Sara Ramella, Paolo Soda, Valerio Guarrasi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VIDSTAMP: A Temporally-Aware Watermark for Ownership and Integrity in Video Diffusion Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01406</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01406v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The rapid rise of video diffusion models has enabled the generation of highly realistic and temporally coherent videos, raising critical concerns about content authenticity, provenance, and misuse. Existing watermarking approaches, whether passive, post-hoc, or adapted from image-based techniques, often struggle to withstand video-specific manipulations such as frame insertion, dropping, or reordering, and typically degrade visual quality. In this work, we introduce VIDSTAMP, a watermarking framework that embeds per-frame or per-segment messages directly into the latent space of temporally-aware video diffusion models. By fine-tuning the model's decoder through a two-stage pipeline, first on static image datasets to promote spatial message separation, and then on synthesized video sequences to restore temporal consistency, VIDSTAMP learns to embed high-capacity, flexible watermarks with minimal perceptual impact. Leveraging architectural components such as 3D convolutions and temporal attention, our method imposes no additional inference cost and offers better perceptual quality than prior methods, while maintaining comparable robustness against common distortions and tampering. VIDSTAMP embeds 768 bits per video (48 bits per frame) with a bit accuracy of 95.0%, achieves a log P-value of -166.65 (lower is better), and maintains a video quality score of 0.836, comparable to unwatermarked outputs (0.838) and surpassing prior methods in capacity-quality tradeoffs. Code: Code: \url{https://github.com/SPIN-UMass/VidStamp}</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01406v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mohammadreza Teymoorianfard, Shiqing Ma, Amir Houmansadr</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Depth and Attention Mechanisms for Improved RGB Image Inpainting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00735</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00735v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Existing deep learning-based image inpainting methods typically rely on convolutional networks with RGB images to reconstruct images. However, relying exclusively on RGB images may neglect important depth information, which plays a critical role in understanding the spatial and structural context of a scene. Just as human vision leverages stereo cues to perceive depth, incorporating depth maps into the inpainting process can enhance the model's ability to reconstruct images with greater accuracy and contextual awareness. In this paper, we propose a novel approach that incorporates both RGB and depth images for enhanced image inpainting. Our models employ a dual encoder architecture, where one encoder processes the RGB image and the other handles the depth image. The encoded features from both encoders are then fused in the decoder using an attention mechanism, effectively integrating the RGB and depth representations. We use two different masking strategies, line and square, to test the robustness of the model under different types of occlusions. To further analyze the effectiveness of our approach, we use Gradient-weighted Class Activation Mapping (Grad-CAM) visualizations to examine the regions of interest the model focuses on during inpainting. We show that incorporating depth information alongside the RGB image significantly improves the reconstruction quality. Through both qualitative and quantitative comparisons, we demonstrate that the depth-integrated model outperforms the baseline, with attention mechanisms further enhancing inpainting performance, as evidenced by multiple evaluation metrics and visualization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00735v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jin Hyun Park, Harine Choi, Praewa Pitiphat</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Survey on 3D Reconstruction Techniques in Plant Phenotyping: From Classical Methods to Neural Radiance Fields (NeRF), 3D Gaussian Splatting (3DGS), and Beyond</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00737</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00737v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Plant phenotyping plays a pivotal role in understanding plant traits and their interactions with the environment, making it crucial for advancing precision agriculture and crop improvement. 3D reconstruction technologies have emerged as powerful tools for capturing detailed plant morphology and structure, offering significant potential for accurate and automated phenotyping. This paper provides a comprehensive review of the 3D reconstruction techniques for plant phenotyping, covering classical reconstruction methods, emerging Neural Radiance Fields (NeRF), and the novel 3D Gaussian Splatting (3DGS) approach. Classical methods, which often rely on high-resolution sensors, are widely adopted due to their simplicity and flexibility in representing plant structures. However, they face challenges such as data density, noise, and scalability. NeRF, a recent advancement, enables high-quality, photorealistic 3D reconstructions from sparse viewpoints, but its computational cost and applicability in outdoor environments remain areas of active research. The emerging 3DGS technique introduces a new paradigm in reconstructing plant structures by representing geometry through Gaussian primitives, offering potential benefits in both efficiency and scalability. We review the methodologies, applications, and performance of these approaches in plant phenotyping and discuss their respective strengths, limitations, and future prospects (https://github.com/JiajiaLi04/3D-Reconstruction-Plants). Through this review, we aim to provide insights into how these diverse 3D reconstruction techniques can be effectively leveraged for automated and high-throughput plant phenotyping, contributing to the next generation of agricultural technology.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00737v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiajia Li, Xinda Qi, Seyed Hamidreza Nabaei, Meiqi Liu, Dong Chen, Xin Zhang, Xunyuan Yin, Zhaojian Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wireless Communication as an Information Sensor for Multi-agent Cooperative Perception: A Survey</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00747</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00747v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Cooperative perception extends the perception capabilities of autonomous vehicles by enabling multi-agent information sharing via Vehicle-to-Everything (V2X) communication. Unlike traditional onboard sensors, V2X acts as a dynamic "information sensor" characterized by limited communication, heterogeneity, mobility, and scalability. This survey provides a comprehensive review of recent advancements from the perspective of information-centric cooperative perception, focusing on three key dimensions: information representation, information fusion, and large-scale deployment. We categorize information representation into data-level, feature-level, and object-level schemes, and highlight emerging methods for reducing data volume and compressing messages under communication constraints. In information fusion, we explore techniques under both ideal and non-ideal conditions, including those addressing heterogeneity, localization errors, latency, and packet loss. Finally, we summarize system-level approaches to support scalability in dense traffic scenarios. Compared with existing surveys, this paper introduces a new perspective by treating V2X communication as an information sensor and emphasizing the challenges of deploying cooperative perception in real-world intelligent transportation systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00747v1</guid>
      <category>cs.OH</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhiying Song, Tenghui Xie, Fuxi Wen, Jun Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autonomous Embodied Agents: When Robotics Meets Deep Learning Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00935</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00935v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The increase in available computing power and the Deep Learning revolution have allowed the exploration of new topics and frontiers in Artificial Intelligence research. A new field called Embodied Artificial Intelligence, which places at the intersection of Computer Vision, Robotics, and Decision Making, has been gaining importance during the last few years, as it aims to foster the development of smart autonomous robots and their deployment in society. The recent availability of large collections of 3D models for photorealistic robotic simulation has allowed faster and safe training of learning-based agents for millions of frames and a careful evaluation of their behavior before deploying the models on real robotic platforms. These intelligent agents are intended to perform a certain task in a possibly unknown environment. To this end, during the training in simulation, the agents learn to perform continuous interactions with the surroundings, such as gathering information from the environment, encoding and extracting useful cues for the task, and performing actions towards the final goal; where every action of the agent influences the interactions. This dissertation follows the complete creation process of embodied agents for indoor environments, from their concept to their implementation and deployment. We aim to contribute to research in Embodied AI and autonomous agents, in order to foster future work in this field. We present a detailed analysis of the procedure behind implementing an intelligent embodied agent, comprehending a thorough description of the current state-of-the-art in literature, technical explanations of the proposed methods, and accurate experimental studies on relevant robotic tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00935v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Roberto Bigazzi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On-demand Test-time Adaptation for Edge Devices</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00986</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00986v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Continual Test-time adaptation (CTTA) continuously adapts the deployed model on every incoming batch of data. While achieving optimal accuracy, existing CTTA approaches present poor real-world applicability on resource-constrained edge devices, due to the substantial memory overhead and energy consumption. In this work, we first introduce a novel paradigm -- on-demand TTA -- which triggers adaptation only when a significant domain shift is detected. Then, we present OD-TTA, an on-demand TTA framework for accurate and efficient adaptation on edge devices. OD-TTA comprises three innovative techniques: 1) a lightweight domain shift detection mechanism to activate TTA only when it is needed, drastically reducing the overall computation overhead, 2) a source domain selection module that chooses an appropriate source model for adaptation, ensuring high and robust accuracy, 3) a decoupled Batch Normalization (BN) update scheme to enable memory-efficient adaptation with small batch sizes. Extensive experiments show that OD-TTA achieves comparable and even better performance while reducing the energy and computation overhead remarkably, making TTA a practical reality.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00986v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiao Ma, Young D. Kwon, Dong Ma</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Indoor Farm Monitoring Efficiency Using UAV: Yield Estimation in a GNSS-Denied Cherry Tomato Greenhouse</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00995</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00995v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: As the agricultural workforce declines and labor costs rise, robotic yield estimation has become increasingly important. While unmanned ground vehicles (UGVs) are commonly used for indoor farm monitoring, their deployment in greenhouses is often constrained by infrastructure limitations, sensor placement challenges, and operational inefficiencies. To address these issues, we develop a lightweight unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV) equipped with an RGB-D camera, a 3D LiDAR, and an IMU sensor. The UAV employs a LiDAR-inertial odometry algorithm for precise navigation in GNSS-denied environments and utilizes a 3D multi-object tracking algorithm to estimate the count and weight of cherry tomatoes. We evaluate the system using two dataset: one from a harvesting row and another from a growing row. In the harvesting-row dataset, the proposed system achieves 94.4\% counting accuracy and 87.5\% weight estimation accuracy within a 13.2-meter flight completed in 10.5 seconds. For the growing-row dataset, which consists of occluded unripened fruits, we qualitatively analyze tracking performance and highlight future research directions for improving perception in greenhouse with strong occlusions. Our findings demonstrate the potential of UAVs for efficient robotic yield estimation in commercial greenhouses.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00995v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Taewook Park, Jinwoo Lee, Hyondong Oh, Won-Jae Yun, Kyu-Wha Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards the Resistance of Neural Network Watermarking to Fine-tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01007</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01007v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This paper proves a new watermarking method to embed the ownership information into a deep neural network (DNN), which is robust to fine-tuning. Specifically, we prove that when the input feature of a convolutional layer only contains low-frequency components, specific frequency components of the convolutional filter will not be changed by gradient descent during the fine-tuning process, where we propose a revised Fourier transform to extract frequency components from the convolutional filter. Additionally, we also prove that these frequency components are equivariant to weight scaling and weight permutations. In this way, we design a watermark module to encode the watermark information to specific frequency components in a convolutional filter. Preliminary experiments demonstrate the effectiveness of our method.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01007v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ling Tang, Yuefeng Chen, Hui Xue, Quanshi Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NeuroLoc: Encoding Navigation Cells for 6-DOF Camera Localization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01113</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01113v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recently, camera localization has been widely adopted in autonomous robotic navigation due to its efficiency and convenience. However, autonomous navigation in unknown environments often suffers from scene ambiguity, environmental disturbances, and dynamic object transformation in camera localization. To address this problem, inspired by the biological brain navigation mechanism (such as grid cells, place cells, and head direction cells), we propose a novel neurobiological camera location method, namely NeuroLoc. Firstly, we designed a Hebbian learning module driven by place cells to save and replay historical information, aiming to restore the details of historical representations and solve the issue of scene fuzziness. Secondly, we utilized the head direction cell-inspired internal direction learning as multi-head attention embedding to help restore the true orientation in similar scenes. Finally, we added a 3D grid center prediction in the pose regression module to reduce the final wrong prediction. We evaluate the proposed NeuroLoc on commonly used benchmark indoor and outdoor datasets. The experimental results show that our NeuroLoc can enhance the robustness in complex environments and improve the performance of pose regression by using only a single image.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01113v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.NE</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xun Li, Jian Yang, Fenli Jia, Muyu Wang, Qi Wu, Jun Wu, Jinpeng Mi, Jilin Hu, Peidong Liang, Xuan Tang, Ke Li, Xiong You, Xian Wei</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CAV-MAE Sync: Improving Contrastive Audio-Visual Mask Autoencoders via Fine-Grained Alignment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01237</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01237v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recent advances in audio-visual learning have shown promising results in learning representations across modalities. However, most approaches rely on global audio representations that fail to capture fine-grained temporal correspondences with visual frames. Additionally, existing methods often struggle with conflicting optimization objectives when trying to jointly learn reconstruction and cross-modal alignment. In this work, we propose CAV-MAE Sync as a simple yet effective extension of the original CAV-MAE framework for self-supervised audio-visual learning. We address three key challenges: First, we tackle the granularity mismatch between modalities by treating audio as a temporal sequence aligned with video frames, rather than using global representations. Second, we resolve conflicting optimization goals by separating contrastive and reconstruction objectives through dedicated global tokens. Third, we improve spatial localization by introducing learnable register tokens that reduce semantic load on patch tokens. We evaluate the proposed approach on AudioSet, VGG Sound, and the ADE20K Sound dataset on zero-shot retrieval, classification and localization tasks demonstrating state-of-the-art performance and outperforming more complex architectures.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01237v1</guid>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Edson Araujo, Andrew Rouditchenko, Yuan Gong, Saurabhchand Bhati, Samuel Thomas, Brian Kingsbury, Leonid Karlinsky, Rogerio Feris, James R. Glass</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Foundation Models Really Segment Tumors? A Benchmarking Odyssey in Lung CT Imaging</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01239</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01239v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Accurate lung tumor segmentation is crucial for improving diagnosis, treatment planning, and patient outcomes in oncology. However, the complexity of tumor morphology, size, and location poses significant challenges for automated segmentation. This study presents a comprehensive benchmarking analysis of deep learning-based segmentation models, comparing traditional architectures such as U-Net and DeepLabV3, self-configuring models like nnUNet, and foundation models like MedSAM, and MedSAM~2. Evaluating performance across two lung tumor segmentation datasets, we assess segmentation accuracy and computational efficiency under various learning paradigms, including few-shot learning and fine-tuning. The results reveal that while traditional models struggle with tumor delineation, foundation models, particularly MedSAM~2, outperform them in both accuracy and computational efficiency. These findings underscore the potential of foundation models for lung tumor segmentation, highlighting their applicability in improving clinical workflows and patient outcomes.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01239v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Elena Mulero Ayll\'on, Massimiliano Mantegna, Linlin Shen, Paolo Soda, Valerio Guarrasi, Matteo Tortora</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FlowDubber: Movie Dubbing with LLM-based Semantic-aware Learning and Flow Matching based Voice Enhancing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01263</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01263v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Movie Dubbing aims to convert scripts into speeches that align with the given movie clip in both temporal and emotional aspects while preserving the vocal timbre of a given brief reference audio. Existing methods focus primarily on reducing the word error rate while ignoring the importance of lip-sync and acoustic quality. To address these issues, we propose a large language model (LLM) based flow matching architecture for dubbing, named FlowDubber, which achieves high-quality audio-visual sync and pronunciation by incorporating a large speech language model and dual contrastive aligning while achieving better acoustic quality via the proposed voice-enhanced flow matching than previous works. First, we introduce Qwen2.5 as the backbone of LLM to learn the in-context sequence from movie scripts and reference audio. Then, the proposed semantic-aware learning focuses on capturing LLM semantic knowledge at the phoneme level. Next, dual contrastive aligning (DCA) boosts mutual alignment with lip movement, reducing ambiguities where similar phonemes might be confused. Finally, the proposed Flow-based Voice Enhancing (FVE) improves acoustic quality in two aspects, which introduces an LLM-based acoustics flow matching guidance to strengthen clarity and uses affine style prior to enhance identity when recovering noise into mel-spectrograms via gradient vector field prediction. Extensive experiments demonstrate that our method outperforms several state-of-the-art methods on two primary benchmarks. The demos are available at {\href{https://galaxycong.github.io/LLM-Flow-Dubber/}{\textcolor{red}{https://galaxycong.github.io/LLM-Flow-Dubber/}}}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01263v1</guid>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gaoxiang Cong, Liang Li, Jiadong Pan, Zhedong Zhang, Amin Beheshti, Anton van den Hengel, Yuankai Qi, Qingming Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Neural Architecture Search Method using Auxiliary Evaluation Metric based on ResNet Architecture</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01313</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01313v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This paper proposes a neural architecture search space using ResNet as a framework, with search objectives including parameters for convolution, pooling, fully connected layers, and connectivity of the residual network. In addition to recognition accuracy, this paper uses the loss value on the validation set as a secondary objective for optimization. The experimental results demonstrate that the search space of this paper together with the optimisation approach can find competitive network architectures on the MNIST, Fashion-MNIST and CIFAR100 datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01313v1</guid>
      <category>cs.NE</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shang Wang, Huanrong Tang, Jianquan Ouyang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GENMO: A GENeralist Model for Human MOtion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.01425</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.01425v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Human motion modeling traditionally separates motion generation and estimation into distinct tasks with specialized models. Motion generation models focus on creating diverse, realistic motions from inputs like text, audio, or keyframes, while motion estimation models aim to reconstruct accurate motion trajectories from observations like videos. Despite sharing underlying representations of temporal dynamics and kinematics, this separation limits knowledge transfer between tasks and requires maintaining separate models. We present GENMO, a unified Generalist Model for Human Motion that bridges motion estimation and generation in a single framework. Our key insight is to reformulate motion estimation as constrained motion generation, where the output motion must precisely satisfy observed conditioning signals. Leveraging the synergy between regression and diffusion, GENMO achieves accurate global motion estimation while enabling diverse motion generation. We also introduce an estimation-guided training objective that exploits in-the-wild videos with 2D annotations and text descriptions to enhance generative diversity. Furthermore, our novel architecture handles variable-length motions and mixed multimodal conditions (text, audio, video) at different time intervals, offering flexible control. This unified approach creates synergistic benefits: generative priors improve estimated motions under challenging conditions like occlusions, while diverse video data enhances generation capabilities. Extensive experiments demonstrate GENMO's effectiveness as a generalist framework that successfully handles multiple human motion tasks within a single model.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.01425v1</guid>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiefeng Li, Jinkun Cao, Haotian Zhang, Davis Rempe, Jan Kautz, Umar Iqbal, Ye Yuan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VitalVideos-Europe: A dataset of face videos with PPG and blood pressure ground truths</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2306.11891</link>
      <description>arXiv:2306.11891v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We collected a large dataset consisting of 850 unique participants. For every participant we recorded two 30 second uncompressed videos, synchronized PPG waveforms and a single blood pressure measurement. Gender, age and skin color were also registered for every participant. The dataset includes roughly equal numbers of males and females, as well as participants of all ages. While the skin color distribution could have been more balanced, the dataset contains individuals from every skin color. The data was collected in a diverse set of locations to ensure a wide variety of backgrounds and lighting conditions. In an effort to assist in the research and development of remote vital sign measurement we are now opening up access to this dataset.
  vitalvideos.org for all datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2306.11891v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Pieter-Jan Toye</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visual Concept-driven Image Generation with Text-to-Image Diffusion Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.11487</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.11487v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Text-to-image (TTI) diffusion models have demonstrated impressive results in generating high-resolution images of complex and imaginative scenes. Recent approaches have further extended these methods with personalization techniques that allow them to integrate user-illustrated concepts (e.g., the user him/herself) using a few sample image illustrations. However, the ability to generate images with multiple interacting concepts, such as human subjects, as well as concepts that may be entangled in one, or across multiple, image illustrations remains illusive. In this work, we propose a concept-driven TTI personalization framework that addresses these core challenges. We build on existing works that learn custom tokens for user-illustrated concepts, allowing those to interact with existing text tokens in the TTI model. However, importantly, to disentangle and better learn the concepts in question, we jointly learn (latent) segmentation masks that disentangle these concepts in user-provided image illustrations. We do so by introducing an Expectation Maximization (EM)-like optimization procedure where we alternate between learning the custom tokens and estimating (latent) masks encompassing corresponding concepts in user-supplied images. We obtain these masks based on cross-attention, from within the U-Net parameterized latent diffusion model and subsequent DenseCRF optimization. We illustrate that such joint alternating refinement leads to the learning of better tokens for concepts and, as a by-product, latent masks. We illustrate the benefits of the proposed approach qualitatively and quantitatively with several examples and use cases that can combine three or more entangled concepts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.11487v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tanzila Rahman, Shweta Mahajan, Hsin-Ying Lee, Jian Ren, Sergey Tulyakov, Leonid Sigal</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>P-Hologen: An End-to-End Generative Framework for Phase-Only Holograms</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.01330</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.01330v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Holography stands at the forefront of visual technology, offering immersive, three-dimensional visualizations through the manipulation of light wave amplitude and phase. Although generative models have been extensively explored in the image domain, their application to holograms remains relatively underexplored due to the inherent complexity of phase learning. Exploiting generative models for holograms offers exciting opportunities for advancing innovation and creativity, such as semantic-aware hologram generation and editing. Currently, the most viable approach for utilizing generative models in the hologram domain involves integrating an image-based generative model with an image-to-hologram conversion model, which comes at the cost of increased computational complexity and inefficiency. To tackle this problem, we introduce P-Hologen, the first end-to-end generative framework designed for phase-only holograms (POHs). P-Hologen employs vector quantized variational autoencoders to capture the complex distributions of POHs. It also integrates the angular spectrum method into the training process, constructing latent spaces for complex phase data using strategies from the image processing domain. Extensive experiments demonstrate that P-Hologen achieves superior quality and computational efficiency compared to the existing methods. Furthermore, our model generates high-quality unseen, diverse holographic content from its learned latent space without requiring pre-existing images. Our work paves the way for new applications and methodologies in holographic content creation, opening a new era in the exploration of generative holographic content. The code for our paper is publicly available on https://github.com/james0223/P-Hologen.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.01330v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1111/cgf.15244</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Computer Graphics Forum. Vol. 43. No. 7. 2024</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>JooHyun Park, YuJin Jeon, HuiYong Kim, SeungHwan Baek, HyeongYeop Kang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part-aware Shape Generation with Latent 3D Diffusion of Neural Voxel Fields</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.00998</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.00998v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper presents a novel latent 3D diffusion model for the generation of neural voxel fields, aiming to achieve accurate part-aware structures. Compared to existing methods, there are two key designs to ensure high-quality and accurate part-aware generation. On one hand, we introduce a latent 3D diffusion process for neural voxel fields, enabling generation at significantly higher resolutions that can accurately capture rich textural and geometric details. On the other hand, a part-aware shape decoder is introduced to integrate the part codes into the neural voxel fields, guiding the accurate part decomposition and producing high-quality rendering results. Through extensive experimentation and comparisons with state-of-the-art methods, we evaluate our approach across four different classes of data. The results demonstrate the superior generative capabilities of our proposed method in part-aware shape generation, outperforming existing state-of-the-art methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.00998v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuhang Huang, SHilong Zou, Xinwang Liu, Kai Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robust Classification by Coupling Data Mollification with Label Smoothing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.01494</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.01494v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Introducing training-time augmentations is a key technique to enhance generalization and prepare deep neural networks against test-time corruptions. Inspired by the success of generative diffusion models, we propose a novel approach of coupling data mollification, in the form of image noising and blurring, with label smoothing to align predicted label confidences with image degradation. The method is simple to implement, introduces negligible overheads, and can be combined with existing augmentations. We demonstrate improved robustness and uncertainty quantification on the corrupted image benchmarks of CIFAR, TinyImageNet and ImageNet datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.01494v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Markus Heinonen, Ba-Hien Tran, Michael Kampffmeyer, Maurizio Filippone</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visual-Friendly Concept Protection via Selective Adversarial Perturbations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08518</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08518v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Personalized concept generation by tuning diffusion models with a few images raises potential legal and ethical concerns regarding privacy and intellectual property rights. Researchers attempt to prevent malicious personalization using adversarial perturbations. However, previous efforts have mainly focused on the effectiveness of protection while neglecting the visibility of perturbations. They utilize global adversarial perturbations, which introduce noticeable alterations to original images and significantly degrade visual quality. In this work, we propose the Visual-Friendly Concept Protection (VCPro) framework, which prioritizes the protection of key concepts chosen by the image owner through adversarial perturbations with lower perceptibility. To ensure these perturbations are as inconspicuous as possible, we introduce a relaxed optimization objective to identify the least perceptible yet effective adversarial perturbations, solved using the Lagrangian multiplier method. Qualitative and quantitative experiments validate that VCPro achieves a better trade-off between the visibility of perturbations and protection effectiveness, effectively prioritizing the protection of target concepts in images with less perceptible perturbations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08518v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoyue Mi, Fan Tang, Juan Cao, Peng Li, Yang Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UDGS-SLAM : UniDepth Assisted Gaussian Splatting for Monocular SLAM</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.00362</link>
      <description>arXiv:2409.00362v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advancements in monocular neural depth estimation, particularly those achieved by the UniDepth network, have prompted the investigation of integrating UniDepth within a Gaussian splatting framework for monocular SLAM. This study presents UDGS-SLAM, a novel approach that eliminates the necessity of RGB-D sensors for depth estimation within Gaussian splatting framework. UDGS-SLAM employs statistical filtering to ensure local consistency of the estimated depth and jointly optimizes camera trajectory and Gaussian scene representation parameters. The proposed method achieves high-fidelity rendered images and low ATERMSE of the camera trajectory. The performance of UDGS-SLAM is rigorously evaluated using the TUM RGB-D dataset and benchmarked against several baseline methods, demonstrating superior performance across various scenarios. Additionally, an ablation study is conducted to validate design choices and investigate the impact of different network backbone encoders on system performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2409.00362v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1016/j.array.2025.100400</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Mostafa Mansour, Ahmed Abdelsalam, Ari Happonen, Jari Porras, Esa Rahtu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HarmoniCa: Harmonizing Training and Inference for Better Feature Caching in Diffusion Transformer Acceleration</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.01723</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.01723v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Diffusion Transformers (DiTs) excel in generative tasks but face practical deployment challenges due to high inference costs. Feature caching, which stores and retrieves redundant computations, offers the potential for acceleration. Existing learning-based caching, though adaptive, overlooks the impact of the prior timestep. It also suffers from misaligned objectives--aligned predicted noise vs. high-quality images--between training and inference. These two discrepancies compromise both performance and efficiency. To this end, we harmonize training and inference with a novel learning-based caching framework dubbed HarmoniCa. It first incorporates Step-Wise Denoising Training (SDT) to ensure the continuity of the denoising process, where prior steps can be leveraged. In addition, an Image Error Proxy-Guided Objective (IEPO) is applied to balance image quality against cache utilization through an efficient proxy to approximate the image error. Extensive experiments across $8$ models, $4$ samplers, and resolutions from $256\times256$ to $2K$ demonstrate superior performance and speedup of our framework. For instance, it achieves over $40\%$ latency reduction (i.e., $2.07\times$ theoretical speedup) and improved performance on PixArt-$\alpha$. Remarkably, our image-free approach reduces training time by $25\%$ compared with the previous method. Our code is available at https://github.com/ModelTC/HarmoniCa.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.01723v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yushi Huang, Zining Wang, Ruihao Gong, Jing Liu, Xinjie Zhang, Jinyang Guo, Xianglong Liu, Jun Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>$X^2$-DFD: A framework for eXplainable and eXtendable Deepfake Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.06126</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.06126v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Detecting deepfakes has become an important task. Most existing detection methods provide only real/fake predictions without offering human-comprehensible explanations. Recent studies leveraging MLLMs for deepfake detection have shown improvements in explainability. However, the performance of pre-trained MLLMs (e.g., LLaVA) remains limited due to a lack of understanding of their capabilities for this task and strategies to enhance them. In this work, we empirically assess the strengths and weaknesses of MLLMs specifically in deepfake detection via forgery features analysis. Building on these assessments, we propose a novel framework called ${X}^2$-DFD, consisting of three core modules. The first module, Model Feature Assessment (MFA), measures the detection capabilities of forgery features intrinsic to MLLMs, and gives a descending ranking of these features. The second module, Strong Feature Strengthening (SFS), enhances the detection and explanation capabilities by fine-tuning the MLLM on a dataset constructed based on the top-ranked features. The third module, Weak Feature Supplementing (WFS), improves the fine-tuned MLLM's capabilities on lower-ranked features by integrating external dedicated deepfake detectors. To verify the effectiveness of this framework, we further present a practical implementation, where an automated forgery features generation, evaluation, and ranking procedure is designed for MFA module; an automated generation procedure of the fine-tuning dataset containing real and fake images with explanations based on top-ranked features is developed for SFS model; an external conventional deepfake detector focusing on blending artifact, which corresponds to a low detection capability in the pre-trained MLLM, is integrated for WFS module. Experiments show that our approach enhances both detection and explanation performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.06126v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yize Chen, Zhiyuan Yan, Siwei Lyu, Baoyuan Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EmoGene: Audio-Driven Emotional 3D Talking-Head Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.17262</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.17262v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Audio-driven talking-head generation is a crucial and useful technology for virtual human interaction and film-making. While recent advances have focused on improving image fidelity and lip synchronization, generating accurate emotional expressions remains underexplored. In this paper, we introduce EmoGene, a novel framework for synthesizing high-fidelity, audio-driven video portraits with accurate emotional expressions. Our approach employs a variational autoencoder (VAE)-based audio-to-motion module to generate facial landmarks, which are concatenated with emotional embedding in a motion-to-emotion module to produce emotional landmarks. These landmarks drive a Neural Radiance Fields (NeRF)-based emotion-to-video module to render realistic emotional talking-head videos. Additionally, we propose a pose sampling method to generate natural idle-state (non-speaking) videos for silent audio inputs. Extensive experiments demonstrate that EmoGene outperforms previous methods in generating high-fidelity emotional talking-head videos.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.17262v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenqing Wang, Yun Fu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DivShift: Exploring Domain-Specific Distribution Shifts in Large-Scale, Volunteer-Collected Biodiversity Datasets</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.19816</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.19816v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large-scale, volunteer-collected datasets of community-identified natural world imagery like iNaturalist have enabled marked performance gains for fine-grained visual classification of species using machine learning methods. However, such data -- sometimes referred to as citizen science data -- are opportunistic and lack a structured sampling strategy. This volunteer-collected biodiversity data contains geographic, temporal, taxonomic, observers, and sociopolitical biases that can have significant effects on biodiversity model performance, but whose impacts are unclear for fine-grained species recognition performance. Here we introduce Diversity Shift (DivShift), a framework for quantifying the effects of domain-specific distribution shifts on machine learning model performance. To diagnose the performance effects of biases specific to volunteer-collected biodiversity data, we also introduce DivShift - North American West Coast (DivShift-NAWC), a curated dataset of almost 7.5 million iNaturalist images across the western coast of North America partitioned across five types of expert-verified bias. We compare species recognition performance across these bias partitions using a diverse variety of species- and ecosystem-focused accuracy metrics. We observe that these biases confound model performance less than expected from the underlying label distribution shift, and that more data leads to better model performance but the magnitude of these improvements are bias-specific. These findings imply that while the structure within natural world images provides generalization improvements for biodiversity monitoring tasks, the biases present in volunteer-collected biodiversity data can also affect model performance; thus these models should be used with caution in downstream biodiversity monitoring tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.19816v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1609/aaai.v39i27.35060</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Proceedings of the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence 39(27) 28386-28396 (2025)</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Elena Sierra, Lauren E. Gillespie, Salim Soltani, Moises Exposito-Alonso, Teja Kattenborn</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insight-V: Exploring Long-Chain Visual Reasoning with Multimodal Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.14432</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.14432v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) demonstrate enhanced capabilities and reliability by reasoning more, evolving from Chain-of-Thought prompting to product-level solutions like OpenAI o1. Despite various efforts to improve LLM reasoning, high-quality long-chain reasoning data and optimized training pipelines still remain inadequately explored in vision-language tasks. In this paper, we present Insight-V, an early effort to 1) scalably produce long and robust reasoning data for complex multi-modal tasks, and 2) an effective training pipeline to enhance the reasoning capabilities of multi-modal large language models (MLLMs). Specifically, to create long and structured reasoning data without human labor, we design a two-step pipeline with a progressive strategy to generate sufficiently long and diverse reasoning paths and a multi-granularity assessment method to ensure data quality. We observe that directly supervising MLLMs with such long and complex reasoning data will not yield ideal reasoning ability. To tackle this problem, we design a multi-agent system consisting of a reasoning agent dedicated to performing long-chain reasoning and a summary agent trained to judge and summarize reasoning results. We further incorporate an iterative DPO algorithm to enhance the reasoning agent's generation stability and quality. Based on the popular LLaVA-NeXT model and our stronger base MLLM, we demonstrate significant performance gains across challenging multi-modal benchmarks requiring visual reasoning. Benefiting from our multi-agent system, Insight-V can also easily maintain or improve performance on perception-focused multi-modal tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.14432v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuhao Dong, Zuyan Liu, Hai-Long Sun, Jingkang Yang, Winston Hu, Yongming Rao, Ziwei Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steering Away from Harm: An Adaptive Approach to Defending Vision Language Model Against Jailbreaks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.16721</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.16721v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Vision Language Models (VLMs) can produce unintended and harmful content when exposed to adversarial attacks, particularly because their vision capabilities create new vulnerabilities. Existing defenses, such as input preprocessing, adversarial training, and response evaluation-based methods, are often impractical for real-world deployment due to their high costs. To address this challenge, we propose ASTRA, an efficient and effective defense by adaptively steering models away from adversarial feature directions to resist VLM attacks. Our key procedures involve finding transferable steering vectors representing the direction of harmful response and applying adaptive activation steering to remove these directions at inference time. To create effective steering vectors, we randomly ablate the visual tokens from the adversarial images and identify those most strongly associated with jailbreaks. These tokens are then used to construct steering vectors. During inference, we perform the adaptive steering method that involves the projection between the steering vectors and calibrated activation, resulting in little performance drops on benign inputs while strongly avoiding harmful outputs under adversarial inputs. Extensive experiments across multiple models and baselines demonstrate our state-of-the-art performance and high efficiency in mitigating jailbreak risks. Additionally, ASTRA exhibits good transferability, defending against unseen attacks (i.e., structured-based attack, perturbation-based attack with project gradient descent variants, and text-only attack). Our code is available at \url{https://github.com/ASTRAL-Group/ASTRA}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.16721v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Han Wang, Gang Wang, Huan Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You KAN Do It in a Single Shot: Plug-and-Play Methods with Single-Instance Priors</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.06204</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.06204v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The use of Plug-and-Play (PnP) methods has become a central approach for solving inverse problems, with denoisers serving as regularising priors that guide optimisation towards a clean solution. In this work, we introduce KAN-PnP, an optimisation framework that incorporates Kolmogorov-Arnold Networks (KANs) as denoisers within the Plug-and-Play (PnP) paradigm. KAN-PnP is specifically designed to solve inverse problems with single-instance priors, where only a single noisy observation is available, eliminating the need for large datasets typically required by traditional denoising methods. We show that KANs, based on the Kolmogorov-Arnold representation theorem, serve effectively as priors in such settings, providing a robust approach to denoising. We prove that the KAN denoiser is Lipschitz continuous, ensuring stability and convergence in optimisation algorithms like PnP-ADMM, even in the context of single-shot learning. Additionally, we provide theoretical guarantees for KAN-PnP, demonstrating its convergence under key conditions: the convexity of the data fidelity term, Lipschitz continuity of the denoiser, and boundedness of the regularisation functional. These conditions are crucial for stable and reliable optimisation. Our experimental results show, on super-resolution and joint optimisation, that KAN-PnP outperforms exiting methods, delivering superior performance in single-shot learning with minimal data. The method exhibits strong convergence properties, achieving high accuracy with fewer iterations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.06204v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yanqi Cheng, Carola-Bibiane Sch\"onlieb, Angelica I Aviles-Rivero</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project-and-Fuse: Improving RGB-D Semantic Segmentation via Graph Convolution Networks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.18851</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.18851v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Most existing RGB-D semantic segmentation methods focus on the feature level fusion, including complex cross-modality and cross-scale fusion modules. However, these methods may cause misalignment problem in the feature fusion process and counter-intuitive patches in the segmentation results. Inspired by the popular pixel-node-pixel pipeline, we propose to 1) fuse features from two modalities in a late fusion style, during which the geometric feature injection is guided by texture feature prior; 2) employ Graph Neural Networks (GNNs) on the fused feature to alleviate the emergence of irregular patches by inferring patch relationship. At the 3D feature extraction stage, we argue that traditional CNNs are not efficient enough for depth maps. So, we encode depth map into normal map, after which CNNs can easily extract object surface tendencies.At projection matrix generation stage, we find the existence of Biased-Assignment and Ambiguous-Locality issues in the original pipeline. Therefore, we propose to 1) adopt the Kullback-Leibler Loss to ensure no missing important pixel features, which can be viewed as hard pixel mining process; 2) connect regions that are close to each other in the Euclidean space as well as in the semantic space with larger edge weights so that location informations can been considered. Extensive experiments on two public datasets, NYU-DepthV2 and SUN RGB-D, have shown that our approach can consistently boost the performance of RGB-D semantic segmentation task.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.18851v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoyan Jiang, Bohan Wang, Xinlong Wan, Shanshan Chen, Hamido Fujita, Hanan Abd. Al Juaid</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Soybean Disease Detection via Interpretable Hybrid CNN-GNN: Integrating MobileNetV2 and GraphSAGE with Cross-Modal Attention</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.01284</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.01284v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Soybean leaf disease detection is critical for agricultural productivity but faces challenges due to visually similar symptoms and limited interpretability in conventional methods. While Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs) excel in spatial feature extraction, they often neglect inter-image relational dependencies, leading to misclassifications. This paper proposes an interpretable hybrid Sequential CNN-Graph Neural Network (GNN) framework that synergizes MobileNetV2 for localized feature extraction and GraphSAGE for relational modeling. The framework constructs a graph where nodes represent leaf images, with edges defined by cosine similarity-based adjacency matrices and adaptive neighborhood sampling. This design captures fine-grained lesion features and global symptom patterns, addressing inter-class similarity challenges. Cross-modal interpretability is achieved via Grad-CAM and Eigen-CAM visualizations, generating heatmaps to highlight disease-influential regions. Evaluated on a dataset of ten soybean leaf diseases, the model achieves $97.16\%$ accuracy, surpassing standalone CNNs ($\le95.04\%$) and traditional machine learning models ($\le77.05\%$). Ablation studies validate the sequential architecture's superiority over parallel or single-model configurations. With only 2.3 million parameters, the lightweight MobileNetV2-GraphSAGE combination ensures computational efficiency, enabling real-time deployment in resource-constrained environments. The proposed approach bridges the gap between accurate classification and practical applicability, offering a robust, interpretable tool for agricultural diagnostics while advancing CNN-GNN integration in plant pathology research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.01284v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Md Abrar Jahin, Soudeep Shahriar, M. F. Mridha, Md. Jakir Hossen, Nilanjan Dey</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GPT-ImgEval: A Comprehensive Benchmark for Diagnosing GPT4o in Image Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.02782</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.02782v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The recent breakthroughs in OpenAI's GPT4o model have demonstrated surprisingly good capabilities in image generation and editing, resulting in significant excitement in the community. This technical report presents the first-look evaluation benchmark (named GPT-ImgEval), quantitatively and qualitatively diagnosing GPT-4o's performance across three critical dimensions: (1) generation quality, (2) editing proficiency, and (3) world knowledge-informed semantic synthesis. Across all three tasks, GPT-4o demonstrates strong performance, significantly surpassing existing methods in both image generation control and output quality, while also showcasing exceptional knowledge reasoning capabilities. Furthermore, based on the GPT-4o's generated data, we propose a classification-model-based approach to investigate the underlying architecture of GPT-4o, where our empirical results suggest the model consists of an auto-regressive (AR) combined with a diffusion-based head for image decoding, rather than the VAR-like architectures. We also provide a complete speculation on GPT-4o's overall architecture. In addition, we conduct a series of analyses to identify and visualize GPT-4o's specific limitations and the synthetic artifacts commonly observed in its image generation. We also present a comparative study of multi-round image editing between GPT-4o and Gemini 2.0 Flash, and discuss the safety implications of GPT-4o's outputs, particularly their detectability by existing image forensic models. We hope that our work can offer valuable insight and provide a reliable benchmark to guide future research, foster reproducibility, and accelerate innovation in the field of image generation and beyond. The codes and datasets used for evaluating GPT-4o can be found at https://github.com/PicoTrex/GPT-ImgEval.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.02782v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhiyuan Yan, Junyan Ye, Weijia Li, Zilong Huang, Shenghai Yuan, Xiangyang He, Kaiqing Lin, Jun He, Conghui He, Li Yuan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MASH: Masked Anchored SpHerical Distances for 3D Shape Representation and Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.09149</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.09149v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We introduce Masked Anchored SpHerical Distances (MASH), a novel multi-view and parametrized representation of 3D shapes. Inspired by multi-view geometry and motivated by the importance of perceptual shape understanding for learning 3D shapes, MASH represents a 3D shape as a collection of observable local surface patches, each defined by a spherical distance function emanating from an anchor point. We further leverage the compactness of spherical harmonics to encode the MASH functions, combined with a generalized view cone with a parameterized base that masks the spatial extent of the spherical function to attain locality. We develop a differentiable optimization algorithm capable of converting any point cloud into a MASH representation accurately approximating ground-truth surfaces with arbitrary geometry and topology. Extensive experiments demonstrate that MASH is versatile for multiple applications including surface reconstruction, shape generation, completion, and blending, achieving superior performance thanks to its unique representation encompassing both implicit and explicit features.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.09149v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Changhao Li, Yu Xin, Xiaowei Zhou, Ariel Shamir, Hao Zhang, Ligang Liu, Ruizhen Hu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MoBGS: Motion Deblurring Dynamic 3D Gaussian Splatting for Blurry Monocular Video</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.15122</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.15122v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We present MoBGS, a novel deblurring dynamic 3D Gaussian Splatting (3DGS) framework capable of reconstructing sharp and high-quality novel spatio-temporal views from blurry monocular videos in an end-to-end manner. Existing dynamic novel view synthesis (NVS) methods are highly sensitive to motion blur in casually captured videos, resulting in significant degradation of rendering quality. While recent approaches address motion-blurred inputs for NVS, they primarily focus on static scene reconstruction and lack dedicated motion modeling for dynamic objects. To overcome these limitations, our MoBGS introduces a novel Blur-adaptive Latent Camera Estimation (BLCE) method for effective latent camera trajectory estimation, improving global camera motion deblurring. In addition, we propose a physically-inspired Latent Camera-induced Exposure Estimation (LCEE) method to ensure consistent deblurring of both global camera and local object motion. Our MoBGS framework ensures the temporal consistency of unseen latent timestamps and robust motion decomposition of static and dynamic regions. Extensive experiments on the Stereo Blur dataset and real-world blurry videos show that our MoBGS significantly outperforms the very recent advanced methods (DyBluRF and Deblur4DGS), achieving state-of-the-art performance for dynamic NVS under motion blur.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.15122v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Minh-Quan Viet Bui, Jongmin Park, Juan Luis Gonzalez Bello, Jaeho Moon, Jihyong Oh, Munchurl Kim</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Task-Oriented Communications for Visual Navigation with Edge-Aerial Collaboration in Low Altitude Economy</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.18317</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.18317v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: To support the Low Altitude Economy (LAE), precise unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs) localization in urban areas where global positioning system (GPS) signals are unavailable. Vision-based methods offer a viable alternative but face severe bandwidth, memory and processing constraints on lightweight UAVs. Inspired by mammalian spatial cognition, we propose a task-oriented communication framework, where UAVs equipped with multi-camera systems extract compact multi-view features and offload localization tasks to edge servers. We introduce the Orthogonally-constrained Variational Information Bottleneck encoder (O-VIB), which incorporates automatic relevance determination (ARD) to prune non-informative features while enforcing orthogonality to minimize redundancy. This enables efficient and accurate localization with minimal transmission cost. Extensive evaluation on a dedicated LAE UAV dataset shows that O-VIB achieves high-precision localization under stringent bandwidth budgets. Code and dataset will be made publicly available: github.com/fangzr/TOC-Edge-Aerial.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.18317v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.NI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhengru Fang, Zhenghao Liu, Jingjing Wang, Senkang Hu, Yu Guo, Yiqin Deng, Yuguang Fang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ClearVision: Leveraging CycleGAN and SigLIP-2 for Robust All-Weather Classification in Traffic Camera Imagery</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.19684</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.19684v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Adverse weather conditions challenge safe transportation, necessitating robust real-time weather detection from traffic camera imagery. We propose a novel framework combining CycleGAN-based domain adaptation with efficient contrastive learning to enhance weather classification, particularly in low-light nighttime conditions. Our approach leverages the lightweight SigLIP-2 model, which employs pairwise sigmoid loss to reduce computational demands, integrated with CycleGAN to transform nighttime images into day-like representations while preserving weather cues. Evaluated on an Iowa Department of Transportation dataset, the baseline EVA-02 model with CLIP achieves a per-class overall accuracy of 96.55\% across three weather conditions (No Precipitation, Rain, Snow) and a day/night overall accuracy of 96.55\%, but shows a significant day-night gap (97.21\% day vs.\ 63.40\% night). With CycleGAN, EVA-02 improves to 97.01\% per-class accuracy and 96.85\% day/night accuracy, boosting nighttime performance to 82.45\%. Our Vision-SigLIP-2 + Text-SigLIP-2 + CycleGAN + Contrastive configuration excels in nighttime scenarios, achieving the highest nighttime accuracy of 85.90\%, with 94.00\% per-class accuracy and 93.35\% day/night accuracy. This model reduces training time by 89\% (from 6 hours to 40 minutes) and inference time by 80\% (from 15 seconds to 3 seconds) compared to EVA-02. By narrowing the day-night performance gap from 33.81 to 8.90 percentage points, our framework provides a scalable, efficient solution for all-weather classification using existing camera infrastructure.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.19684v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Anush Lakshman Sivaraman, Kojo Adu-Gyamfi, Ibne Farabi Shihab, Anuj Sharma</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Empowering Agentic Video Analytics Systems with Video Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00254</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00254v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: AI-driven video analytics has become increasingly pivotal across diverse domains. However, existing systems are often constrained to specific, predefined tasks, limiting their adaptability in open-ended analytical scenarios. The recent emergence of Video-Language Models (VLMs) as transformative technologies offers significant potential for enabling open-ended video understanding, reasoning, and analytics. Nevertheless, their limited context windows present challenges when processing ultra-long video content, which is prevalent in real-world applications. To address this, we introduce AVAS, a VLM-powered system designed for open-ended, advanced video analytics. AVAS incorporates two key innovations: (1) the near real-time construction of Event Knowledge Graphs (EKGs) for efficient indexing of long or continuous video streams, and (2) an agentic retrieval-generation mechanism that leverages EKGs to handle complex and diverse queries. Comprehensive evaluations on public benchmarks, LVBench and VideoMME-Long, demonstrate that AVAS achieves state-of-the-art performance, attaining 62.3% and 64.1% accuracy, respectively, significantly surpassing existing VLM and video Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) systems. Furthermore, to evaluate video analytics in ultra-long and open-world video scenarios, we introduce a new benchmark, AVAS-100. This benchmark comprises 8 videos, each exceeding 10 hours in duration, along with 120 manually annotated, diverse, and complex question-answer pairs. On AVAS-100, AVAS achieves top-tier performance with an accuracy of 75.8%.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00254v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuxuan Yan, Shiqi Jiang, Ting Cao, Yifan Yang, Qianqian Yang, Yuanchao Shu, Yuqing Yang, Lili Qiu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>InterLoc: LiDAR-based Intersection Localization using Road Segmentation with Automated Evaluation Method</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00512</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00512v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Online localization of road intersections is beneficial for autonomous vehicle localization, mapping and motion planning. Intersections offer strong landmarks to correct vehicle pose estimation in GNSS dropouts and anchor new sensor data in up-to-date maps. They are also decisive routing nodes in road network graphs. Despite that importance, intersection localization has not been widely studied, with existing methods either ignore the rich semantic information already computed onboard or depend on scarce, hand-labeled intersection datasets. To close that gap, this paper presents a LiDAR-based method for online vehicle-centric intersection localization. We fuse semantic road segmentation with vehicle local pose to detect intersection candidates in a bird's eye view (BEV) representation. We then refine those candidates by analyzing branch topology and correcting the intersection point in a least squares formulation. To evaluate our method, we introduce an automated benchmarking pipeline that pairs localized intersection points with OpenStreetMap (OSM) intersection nodes using precise GNSS/INS ground-truth poses. Experiments on SemanticKITTI show that the method outperforms the latest learning-based baseline in accuracy and reliability. Moreover, sensitivity tests demonstrate that our method is robust to challenging segmentation error levels, highlighting its applicability in the real world.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00512v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nguyen Hoang Khoi Tran, Julie Stephany Berrio, Mao Shan, Zhenxing Ming, Stewart Worrall</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multimodal Masked Autoencoder Pre-training for 3D MRI-Based Brain Tumor Analysis with Missing Modalities</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00568</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.00568v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Multimodal magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) constitutes the first line of investigation for clinicians in the care of brain tumors, providing crucial insights for surgery planning, treatment monitoring, and biomarker identification. Pre-training on large datasets have been shown to help models learn transferable representations and adapt with minimal labeled data. This behavior is especially valuable in medical imaging, where annotations are often scarce. However, applying this paradigm to multimodal medical data introduces a challenge: most existing approaches assume that all imaging modalities are available during both pre-training and fine-tuning. In practice, missing modalities often occur due to acquisition issues, specialist unavailability, or specific experimental designs on small in-house datasets. Consequently, a common approach involves training a separate model for each desired modality combination, making the process both resource-intensive and impractical for clinical use. Therefore, we introduce BM-MAE, a masked image modeling pre-training strategy tailored for multimodal MRI data. The same pre-trained model seamlessly adapts to any combination of available modalities, extracting rich representations that capture both intra- and inter-modal information. This allows fine-tuning on any subset of modalities without requiring architectural changes, while still benefiting from a model pre-trained on the full set of modalities. Extensive experiments show that the proposed pre-training strategy outperforms or remains competitive with baselines that require separate pre-training for each modality subset, while substantially surpassing training from scratch on several downstream tasks. Additionally, it can quickly and efficiently reconstruct missing modalities, highlighting its practical value. Code and trained models are available at: https://github.com/Lucas-rbnt/BM-MAE</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.00568v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lucas Robinet, Ahmad Berjaoui, Elizabeth Cohen-Jonathan Moyal</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Volumetric medical image segmentation through dual self-distillation in U-shaped networks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2306.03271</link>
      <description>arXiv:2306.03271v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: U-shaped networks and its variants have demonstrated exceptional results for medical image segmentation. In this paper, we propose a novel dual self-distillation (DSD) framework in U-shaped networks for volumetric medical image segmentation. DSD distills knowledge from the ground-truth segmentation labels to the decoder layers. Additionally, DSD also distills knowledge from the deepest decoder and encoder layer to the shallower decoder and encoder layers respectively of a single U-shaped network. DSD is a general training strategy that could be attached to the backbone architecture of any U-shaped network to further improve its segmentation performance. We attached DSD on several state-of-the-art U-shaped backbones, and extensive experiments on various public 3D medical image segmentation datasets (cardiac substructure, brain tumor and Hippocampus) demonstrated significant improvement over the same backbones without DSD. On average, after attaching DSD to the U-shaped backbones, we observed an increase of 2.82\%, 4.53\% and 1.3\% in Dice similarity score, a decrease of 7.15 mm, 6.48 mm and 0.76 mm in the Hausdorff distance, for cardiac substructure, brain tumor and Hippocampus segmentation, respectively. These improvements were achieved with negligible increase in the number of trainable parameters and training time. Our proposed DSD framework also led to significant qualitative improvements for cardiac substructure, brain tumor and Hippocampus segmentation over the U-shaped backbones. The source code is publicly available at https://github.com/soumbane/DualSelfDistillation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2306.03271v3</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Soumyanil Banerjee, Nicholas Summerfield, Ming Dong, Carri Glide-Hurst</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Vision &amp; Language Decoders use Images and Text equally? How Self-consistent are their Explanations?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.18624</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.18624v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Vision and language model (VLM) decoders are currently the best-performing architectures on multimodal tasks. Next to answers, they are able to produce natural language explanations, either in post-hoc or CoT settings. However, it is not clear to what extent they are using the input vision and text modalities when generating answers or explanations. In this work, we investigate if VLMs rely on their input modalities differently when they produce explanations as opposed to answers. We also evaluate the self-consistency of VLM decoders in both post-hoc and CoT explanation settings, by extending existing unimodal tests and measures to VLM decoders. We find that most tested VLMs are less self-consistent than LLMs. Text contributions in all tested VL decoders are more important than image contributions in all examined tasks. However, when comparing explanation generation to answer generation, the contributions of images are significantly stronger for generating explanations compared to answers. This difference is even larger in CoT compared to post-hoc explanations. Lastly, we provide an up-to-date benchmarking of state-of-the-art VL decoders on the VALSE benchmark, which before was restricted to VL encoders. We find that the tested VL decoders still struggle with most phenomena tested by VALSE.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.18624v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Letitia Parcalabescu, Anette Frank</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RoboPEPP: Vision-Based Robot Pose and Joint Angle Estimation through Embedding Predictive Pre-Training</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.17662</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.17662v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Vision-based pose estimation of articulated robots with unknown joint angles has applications in collaborative robotics and human-robot interaction tasks. Current frameworks use neural network encoders to extract image features and downstream layers to predict joint angles and robot pose. While images of robots inherently contain rich information about the robot's physical structures, existing methods often fail to leverage it fully; therefore, limiting performance under occlusions and truncations. To address this, we introduce RoboPEPP, a method that fuses information about the robot's physical model into the encoder using a masking-based self-supervised embedding-predictive architecture. Specifically, we mask the robot's joints and pre-train an encoder-predictor model to infer the joints' embeddings from surrounding unmasked regions, enhancing the encoder's understanding of the robot's physical model. The pre-trained encoder-predictor pair, along with joint angle and keypoint prediction networks, is then fine-tuned for pose and joint angle estimation. Random masking of input during fine-tuning and keypoint filtering during evaluation further improves robustness. Our method, evaluated on several datasets, achieves the best results in robot pose and joint angle estimation while being the least sensitive to occlusions and requiring the lowest execution time.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.17662v2</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Raktim Gautam Goswami, Prashanth Krishnamurthy, Yann LeCun, Farshad Khorrami</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Physics-Inspired Deep Learning Framework with Polar Coordinate Attention for Ptychographic Imaging</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.06806</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.06806v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Ptychographic imaging confronts inherent challenges in applying deep learning for phase retrieval from diffraction patterns. Conventional neural architectures, both convolutional neural networks and Transformer-based methods, are optimized for natural images with Euclidean spatial neighborhood-based inductive biases that exhibit geometric mismatch with the concentric coherent patterns characteristic of diffraction data in reciprocal space. In this paper, we present PPN, a physics-inspired deep learning network with Polar Coordinate Attention (PoCA) for ptychographic imaging, that aligns neural inductive biases with diffraction physics through a dual-branch architecture separating local feature extraction from non-local coherence modeling. It consists of a PoCA mechanism that replaces Euclidean spatial priors with physically consistent radial-angular correlations. PPN outperforms existing end-to-end models, with spectral and spatial analysis confirming its greater preservation of high-frequency details. Notably, PPN maintains robust performance compared to iterative methods even at low overlap ratios, making it well suited for high-throughput imaging in real-world acquisition scenarios for samples with consistent structural characteristics.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.06806v2</guid>
      <category>physics.optics</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Han Yue, Jun Cheng, Yu-Xuan Ren, Chien-Chun Chen, Grant A. van Riessen, Philip Heng Wai Leong, Steve Feng Shu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DriveGPT: Scaling Autoregressive Behavior Models for Driving</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.14415</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.14415v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We present DriveGPT, a scalable behavior model for autonomous driving. We model driving as a sequential decision-making task, and learn a transformer model to predict future agent states as tokens in an autoregressive fashion. We scale up our model parameters and training data by multiple orders of magnitude, enabling us to explore the scaling properties in terms of dataset size, model parameters, and compute. We evaluate DriveGPT across different scales in a planning task, through both quantitative metrics and qualitative examples, including closed-loop driving in complex real-world scenarios. In a separate prediction task, DriveGPT outperforms state-of-the-art baselines and exhibits improved performance by pretraining on a large-scale dataset, further validating the benefits of data scaling.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.14415v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xin Huang, Eric M. Wolff, Paul Vernaza, Tung Phan-Minh, Hongge Chen, David S. Hayden, Mark Edmonds, Brian Pierce, Xinxin Chen, Pratik Elias Jacob, Xiaobai Chen, Chingiz Tairbekov, Pratik Agarwal, Tianshi Gao, Yuning Chai, Siddhartha Srinivasa</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MAVEN: Multi-modal Attention for Valence-Arousal Emotion Network</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.12623</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.12623v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Dynamic emotion recognition in the wild remains challenging due to the transient nature of emotional expressions and temporal misalignment of multi-modal cues. Traditional approaches predict valence and arousal and often overlook the inherent correlation between these two dimensions. The proposed Multi-modal Attention for Valence-Arousal Emotion Network (MAVEN) integrates visual, audio, and textual modalities through a bi-directional cross-modal attention mechanism. MAVEN uses modality-specific encoders to extract features from synchronized video frames, audio segments, and transcripts, predicting emotions in polar coordinates following Russell's circumplex model. The evaluation of the Aff-Wild2 dataset using MAVEN achieved a concordance correlation coefficient (CCC) of 0.3061, surpassing the ResNet-50 baseline model with a CCC of 0.22. The multistage architecture captures the subtle and transient nature of emotional expressions in conversational videos and improves emotion recognition in real-world situations. The code is available at: https://github.com/Vrushank-Ahire/MAVEN_8th_ABAW</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.12623v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Vrushank Ahire, Kunal Shah, Mudasir Nazir Khan, Nikhil Pakhale, Lownish Rai Sookha, M. A. Ganaie, Abhinav Dhall</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ADAPT: An Autonomous Forklift for Construction Site Operation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14331</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.14331v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Efficient material logistics play a critical role in controlling costs and schedules in the construction industry. However, manual material handling remains prone to inefficiencies, delays, and safety risks. Autonomous forklifts offer a promising solution to streamline on-site logistics, reducing reliance on human operators and mitigating labor shortages. This paper presents the development and evaluation of ADAPT (Autonomous Dynamic All-terrain Pallet Transporter), a fully autonomous off-road forklift designed for construction environments. Unlike structured warehouse settings, construction sites pose significant challenges, including dynamic obstacles, unstructured terrain, and varying weather conditions. To address these challenges, our system integrates AI-driven perception techniques with traditional approaches for decision making, planning, and control, enabling reliable operation in complex environments. We validate the system through extensive real-world testing, comparing its continuous performance against an experienced human operator across various weather conditions. Our findings demonstrate that autonomous outdoor forklifts can operate near human-level performance, offering a viable path toward safer and more efficient construction logistics.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.14331v3</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.SY</category>
      <category>eess.SY</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Johannes Huemer, Markus Murschitz, Matthias Sch\"orghuber, Lukas Reisinger, Thomas Kadiofsky, Christoph Weidinger, Mario Niedermeyer, Benedikt Widy, Marcel Zeilinger, Csaba Beleznai, Tobias Gl\"uck, Andreas Kugi, Patrik Zips</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering scrolls with tomography: A training experiment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.11485</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.11485v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The recovery of severely damaged ancient written documents has proven to be a major challenge for many scientists, mainly due to the impracticality of physical unwrapping them. Non-destructive techniques, such as X-ray computed tomography (CT), combined with computer vision algorithms, have emerged as a means of facilitating the virtual reading of the hidden contents of the damaged documents. This paper proposes an educational laboratory aimed at simulating the entire process of acquisition and virtual recovery of the ancient works. We have developed an experimental setup that uses visible light to replace the detrimental X-rays, and a didactic software pipeline that allows students to virtually reconstruct a transparent rolled sheet with printed text on it, the wrapped scroll.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.11485v2</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sonia Foschiatti, Axel Kittenberger, Otmar Scherzer</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Automated Pipeline for Few-Shot Bird Call Classification: A Case Study with the Tooth-Billed Pigeon</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.16276</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.16276v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: This paper presents an automated one-shot bird call classification pipeline designed for rare species absent from large publicly available classifiers like BirdNET and Perch. While these models excel at detecting common birds with abundant training data, they lack options for species with only 1-3 known recordings-a critical limitation for conservationists monitoring the last remaining individuals of endangered birds. To address this, we leverage the embedding space of large bird classification networks and develop a classifier using cosine similarity, combined with filtering and denoising preprocessing techniques, to optimize detection with minimal training data. We evaluate various embedding spaces using clustering metrics and validate our approach in both a simulated scenario with Xeno-Canto recordings and a real-world test on the critically endangered tooth-billed pigeon (Didunculus strigirostris), which has no existing classifiers and only three confirmed recordings. The final model achieved 1.0 recall and 0.95 accuracy in detecting tooth-billed pigeon calls, making it practical for use in the field. This open-source system provides a practical tool for conservationists seeking to detect and monitor rare species on the brink of extinction.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.16276v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Abhishek Jana, Moeumu Uili, James Atherton, Mark O'Brien, Joe Wood, Leandra Brickson</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Space Group Determination from EBSD Patterns: The Role of Deep Learning and High-throughput Dynamical Simulations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.21331</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.21331v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The design of novel materials hinges on the understanding of structure-property relationships. However, in recent times, our capability to synthesize a large number of materials has outpaced our speed at characterizing them. While the overall chemical constituents can be readily known during synthesis, the structural evolution and characterization of newly synthesized samples remains a bottleneck for the ultimate goal of high throughput nanomaterials discovery. Thus, scalable methods for crystal symmetry determination that can analyze a large volume of material samples within a short time-frame are especially needed. Kikuchi diffraction in the SEM is a promising technique for this due to its sensitivity to dynamical scattering, which may provide information beyond just the seven crystal systems and fourteen Bravais lattices. After diffraction patterns are collected from material samples, deep learning methods may be able to classify the space group symmetries using the patterns as input, which paired with the elemental composition, would help enable the determination of the crystal structure. To investigate the feasibility of this solution, neural networks were trained to predict the space group type of background corrected EBSD patterns. Our networks were first trained and tested on an artificial dataset of EBSD patterns of 5,148 different cubic phases, created through physics-based dynamical simulations. Next, Maximum Classifier Discrepancy, an unsupervised deep learning-based domain adaptation method, was utilized to train neural networks to make predictions for experimental EBSD patterns. We introduce a relabeling scheme, which enables our models to achieve accuracy scores higher than 90% on simulated and experimental data, suggesting that neural networks are capable of making predictions of crystal symmetry from an EBSD pattern.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.21331v2</guid>
      <category>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alfred Yan, Muhammad Nur Talha Kilic, Gert Nolze, Ankit Agrawal, Alok Choudhary, Roberto dos Reis, Vinayak Dravid</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
