<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL</link>
    <description>cs.CL updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 05:00:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Sunday</day>
      <day>Saturday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>Talking to Yourself: Defying Forgetting in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20162</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20162v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Catastrophic forgetting remains a major challenge when fine-tuning large language models (LLMs) on narrow, task-specific data, often degrading their general knowledge and reasoning abilities. We propose SA-SFT, a lightweight self-augmentation routine in which an LLM generates self-dialogues prior to fine-tuning, and the resulting self-authored data are mixed with task data without modifying optimization or training schedules.
  Despite requiring no external data or additional tuning, SA-SFT consistently mitigates catastrophic forgetting while improving in-domain performance. Across 50 evaluation scenarios, it maintains performance comparable to the original model and achieves the best results in 40 cases, outperforming common baselines such as layer freezing and external data mixing. Guided by these empirical findings, we further present a theoretical analysis suggesting that forgetting can partly stem from style-induced parameter drift, and that self-alignment through self-generated data provides an effective means to counteract this effect. Overall, our results indicate that self-augmentation offers a simple and effective mechanism for robust LLM adaptation without incurring catastrophic forgetting.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20162v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yutao Sun, Mingshuai Chen, Tiancheng Zhao, Phillip Miao, Zilun Zhang, Haozhan Shen, Ruizhe Zhu, Jianwei Yin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking Distilled Language Models: Performance and Efficiency in Resource-Constrained Settings</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20164</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20164v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Knowledge distillation offers a transformative pathway to developing powerful, yet efficient, small language models (SLMs) suitable for resource-constrained environments. In this paper, we benchmark the performance and computational cost of distilled models against their vanilla and proprietary counterparts, providing a quantitative analysis of their efficiency. Our results demonstrate that distillation creates a superior performance-tocompute curve. We find that creating a distilled 8B model is over 2,000 times more compute-efficient than training its vanilla counterpart, while achieving reasoning capabilities on par with, or even exceeding, standard models ten times its size. These findings validate distillation not just as a compression technique, but as a primary strategy for building state-of-the-art, accessible AI</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20164v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sachin Gopal Wani, Eric Page, Ajay Dholakia, David Ellison</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ConceptRM: The Quest to Mitigate Alert Fatigue through Consensus-Based Purity-Driven Data Cleaning for Reflection Modelling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20166</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20166v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In many applications involving intelligent agents, the overwhelming volume of alerts (mostly false) generated by the agents may desensitize users and cause them to overlook critical issues, leading to the so-called ''alert fatigue''. A common strategy is to train a reflection model as a filter to intercept false alerts with labelled data collected from user verification feedback. However, a key challenge is the noisy nature of such data as it is often collected in production environments. As cleaning noise via manual annotation incurs high costs, this paper proposes a novel method ConceptRM for constructing a high-quality corpus to train a reflection model capable of effectively intercepting false alerts. With only a small amount of expert annotations as anchors, ConceptRM creates perturbed datasets with varying noise ratios and utilizes co-teaching to train multiple distinct models for collaborative learning. By analyzing the consensus decisions of these models, it effectively identifies reliable negative samples from a noisy dataset. Experimental results demonstrate that ConceptRM significantly enhances the interception of false alerts with minimal annotation cost, outperforming several state-of-the-art LLM baselines by up to 53.31% on in-domain datasets and 41.67% on out-of-domain datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20166v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yongda Yu, Lei Zhang, Xinxin Guo, Minghui Yu, Zhengqi Zhuang, Guoping Rong, Haifeng Shen, Zhengfeng Li, Boge Wang, Guoan Zhang, Bangyu Xiang, Xiaobin Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>InterviewSim: A Scalable Framework for Interview-Grounded Personality Simulation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20294</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20294v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Simulating real personalities with large language models requires grounding generation in authentic personal data. Existing evaluation approaches rely on demographic surveys, personality questionnaires, or short AI-led interviews as proxies, but lack direct assessment against what individuals actually said. We address this gap with an interview-grounded evaluation framework for personality simulation at a large scale. We extract over 671,000 question-answer pairs from 23,000 verified interview transcripts across 1,000 public personalities, each with an average of 11.5 hours of interview content. We propose a multi-dimensional evaluation framework with four complementary metrics measuring content similarity, factual consistency, personality alignment, and factual knowledge retention. Through systematic comparison, we demonstrate that methods grounded in real interview data substantially outperform those relying solely on biographical profiles or the model's parametric knowledge. We further reveal a trade-off in how interview data is best utilized: retrieval-augmented methods excel at capturing personality style and response quality, while chronological-based methods better preserve factual consistency and knowledge retention. Our evaluation framework enables principled method selection based on application requirements, and our empirical findings provide actionable insights for advancing personality simulation research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20294v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yu Li, Pranav Narayanan Venkit, Yada Pruksachatkun, Chien-Sheng Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Makes a Good Query? Measuring the Impact of Human-Confusing Linguistic Features on LLM Performance</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20300</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20300v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Model (LLM) hallucinations are usually treated as defects of the model or its decoding strategy. Drawing on classical linguistics, we argue that a query's form can also shape a listener's (and model's) response. We operationalize this insight by constructing a 22-dimension query feature vector covering clause complexity, lexical rarity, and anaphora, negation, answerability, and intention grounding, all known to affect human comprehension. Using 369,837 real-world queries, we ask: Are there certain types of queries that make hallucination more likely? A large-scale analysis reveals a consistent "risk landscape": certain features such as deep clause nesting and underspecification align with higher hallucination propensity. In contrast, clear intention grounding and answerability align with lower hallucination rates. Others, including domain specificity, show mixed, dataset- and model-dependent effects. Thus, these findings establish an empirically observable query-feature representation correlated with hallucination risk, paving the way for guided query rewriting and future intervention studies.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20300v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>William Watson, Nicole Cho, Sumitra Ganesh, Manuela Veloso</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No One Size Fits All: QueryBandits for Hallucination Mitigation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20332</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20332v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Advanced reasoning capabilities in Large Language Models (LLMs) have led to more frequent hallucinations; yet most mitigation work focuses on open-source models for post-hoc detection and parameter editing. The dearth of studies focusing on hallucinations in closed-source models is especially concerning, as they constitute the vast majority of models in institutional deployments. We introduce QueryBandits, a model-agnostic contextual bandit framework that adaptively learns online to select the optimal query-rewrite strategy by leveraging an empirically validated and calibrated reward function. Across 16 QA scenarios, our top QueryBandit (Thompson Sampling) achieves an 87.5% win rate over a No-Rewrite baseline and outperforms zero-shot static policies (e.g., Paraphrase or Expand) by 42.6% and 60.3%, respectively. Moreover, all contextual bandits outperform vanilla bandits across all datasets, with higher feature variance coinciding with greater variance in arm selection. This substantiates our finding that there is no single rewrite policy optimal for all queries. We also discover that certain static policies incur higher cumulative regret than No-Rewrite, indicating that an inflexible query-rewriting policy can worsen hallucinations. Thus, learning an online policy over semantic features with QueryBandits can shift model behavior purely through forward-pass mechanisms, enabling its use with closed-source models and bypassing the need for retraining or gradient-based adaptation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20332v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nicole Cho, William Watson, Alec Koppel, Sumitra Ganesh, Manuela Veloso</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Natural Language Processing Models for Robust Document Categorization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20336</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20336v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This article presents an evaluation of several machine learning methods applied to automated text classification, alongside the design of a demonstrative system for unbalanced document categorization and distribution. The study focuses on balancing classification accuracy with computational efficiency, a key consideration when integrating AI into real world automation pipelines. Three models of varying complexity were examined: a Naive Bayes classifier, a bidirectional LSTM network, and a fine tuned transformer based BERT model.
  The experiments reveal substantial differences in performance. BERT achieved the highest accuracy, consistently exceeding 99\%, but required significantly longer training times and greater computational resources. The BiLSTM model provided a strong compromise, reaching approximately 98.56\% accuracy while maintaining moderate training costs and offering robust contextual understanding. Naive Bayes proved to be the fastest to train, on the order of milliseconds, yet delivered the lowest accuracy, averaging around 94.5\%. Class imbalance influenced all methods, particularly in the recognition of minority categories.
  A fully functional demonstrative system was implemented to validate practical applicability, enabling automated routing of technical requests with throughput unattainable through manual processing. The study concludes that BiLSTM offers the most balanced solution for the examined scenario, while also outlining opportunities for future improvements and further exploration of transformer architectures.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20336v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Radoslaw Roszczyk, Pawel Tecza, Maciej Stodolski, Krzysztof Siwek</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How communicatively optimal are exact numeral systems? Once more on lexicon size and morphosyntactic complexity</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20372</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20372v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent research argues that exact recursive numeral systems optimize communicative efficiency by balancing a tradeoff between the size of the numeral lexicon and the average morphosyntactic complexity (roughly length in morphemes) of numeral terms. We argue that previous studies have not characterized the data in a fashion that accounts for the degree of complexity languages display. Using data from 52 genetically diverse languages and an annotation scheme distinguishing between predictable and unpredictable allomorphy (formal variation), we show that many of the world's languages are decisively less efficient than one would expect. We discuss the implications of our findings for the study of numeral systems and linguistic evolution more generally.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20372v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chundra Cathcart, Arne Rubehn, Katja Bocklage, Luca Ciucci, Kellen Parker van Dam, Al\v{z}b\v{e}ta Ku\v{c}erov\'a, Jekaterina Ma\v{z}ara, Carlo Y. Meloni, David Snee, Johann-Mattis List</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Case-Aware LLM-as-a-Judge Evaluation for Enterprise-Scale RAG Systems</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20379</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20379v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Enterprise Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) assistants operate in multi-turn, case-based workflows such as technical support and IT operations, where evaluation must reflect operational constraints, structured identifiers (e.g., error codes, versions), and resolution workflows. Existing RAG evaluation frameworks are primarily designed for benchmark-style or single-turn settings and often fail to capture enterprise-specific failure modes such as case misidentification, workflow misalignment, and partial resolution across turns.
  We present a case-aware LLM-as-a-Judge evaluation framework for enterprise multi-turn RAG systems. The framework evaluates each turn using eight operationally grounded metrics that separate retrieval quality, grounding fidelity, answer utility, precision integrity, and case/workflow alignment. A severity-aware scoring protocol reduces score inflation and improves diagnostic clarity across heterogeneous enterprise cases. The system uses deterministic prompting with strict JSON outputs, enabling scalable batch evaluation, regression testing, and production monitoring.
  Through a comparative study of two instruction-tuned models across short and long workflows, we show that generic proxy metrics provide ambiguous signals, while the proposed framework exposes enterprise-critical tradeoffs that are actionable for system improvement.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20379v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mukul Chhabra, Luigi Medrano, Arush Verma</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disentangling Geometry, Performance, and Training in Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20433</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20433v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Geometric properties of Transformer weights, particularly the unembedding matrix, have been widely useful in language model interpretability research. Yet, their utility for estimating downstream performance remains unclear. In this work, we systematically investigate the relationship between model performance and the unembedding matrix geometry, particularly its effective rank. Our experiments, involving a suite of 108 OLMo-style language models trained under controlled variation, reveal several key findings. While the best-performing models often exhibit a high effective rank, this trend is not universal across tasks and training setups. Contrary to prior work, we find that low effective rank does not cause late-stage performance degradation in small models, but instead co-occurs with it; we find adversarial cases where low-rank models do not exhibit saturation. Moreover, we show that effective rank is strongly influenced by pre-training hyperparameters, such as batch size and weight decay, which in-turn affect the model's performance. Lastly, extending our analysis to other geometric metrics and final-layer representation, we find that these metrics are largely aligned, but none can reliably predict downstream performance. Overall, our findings suggest that the model's geometry, as captured by existing metrics, primarily reflects training choices rather than performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20433v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Atharva Kulkarni, Jacob Mitchell Springer, Arjun Subramonian, Swabha Swayamdipta</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Performance to Purpose: A Sociotechnical Taxonomy for Evaluating Large Language Model Utility</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20513</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20513v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: As large language models (LLMs) continue to improve at completing discrete tasks, they are being integrated into increasingly complex and diverse real-world systems. However, task-level success alone does not establish a model's fit for use in practice. In applied, high-stakes settings, LLM effectiveness is driven by a wider array of sociotechnical determinants that extend beyond conventional performance measures. Although a growing set of metrics capture many of these considerations, they are rarely organized in a way that supports consistent evaluation, leaving no unified taxonomy for assessing and comparing LLM utility across use cases. To address this gap, we introduce the Language Model Utility Taxonomy (LUX), a comprehensive framework that structures utility evaluation across four domains: performance, interaction, operations, and governance. Within each domain, LUX is organized hierarchically into thematically aligned dimensions and components, each grounded in metrics that enable quantitative comparison and alignment of model selection with intended use. In addition, an external dynamic web tool is provided to support exploration of the framework by connecting each component to a repository of relevant metrics (factors) for applied evaluation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20513v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gavin Levinson, Keith Feldman</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stop-Think-AutoRegress: Language Modeling with Latent Diffusion Planning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20528</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20528v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The Stop-Think-AutoRegress Language Diffusion Model (STAR-LDM) integrates latent diffusion planning with autoregressive generation. Unlike conventional autoregressive language models limited to token-by-token decisions, STAR-LDM incorporates a "thinking" phase that pauses generation to refine a semantic plan through diffusion before continuing. This enables global planning in continuous space prior to committing to discrete tokens. Evaluations show STAR-LDM significantly outperforms similar-sized models on language understanding benchmarks and achieves $&gt;70\%$ win rates in LLM-as-judge comparisons for narrative coherence and commonsense reasoning. The architecture also allows straightforward control through lightweight classifiers, enabling fine-grained steering of attributes without model retraining while maintaining better fluency-control trade-offs than specialized approaches.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20528v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Justin Lovelace, Christian Belardi, Sofian Zalouk, Adhitya Polavaram, Srivatsa Kundurthy, Kilian Q. Weinberger</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personal Information Parroting in Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20580</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20580v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Modern language models (LM) are trained on large scrapes of the Web, containing millions of personal information (PI) instances, many of which LMs memorize, increasing privacy risks. In this work, we develop the regexes and rules (R&amp;R) detector suite to detect email addresses, phone numbers, and IP addresses, which outperforms the best regex-based PI detectors. On a manually curated set of 483 instances of PI, we measure memorization: finding that 13.6% are parroted verbatim by the Pythia-6.9b model, i.e., when the model is prompted with the tokens that precede the PI in the original document, greedy decoding generates the entire PI span exactly. We expand this analysis to study models of varying sizes (160M-6.9B) and pretraining time steps (70k-143k iterations) in the Pythia model suite and find that both model size and amount of pretraining are positively correlated with memorization. Even the smallest model, Pythia-160m, parrots 2.7% of the instances exactly. Consequently, we strongly recommend that pretraining datasets be aggressively filtered and anonymized to minimize PI parroting.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20580v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nishant Subramani, Kshitish Ghate, Mona Diab</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Hate Speech Detection on Social Media: A Comparative Analysis of Machine Learning Models and Text Transformation Approaches</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20634</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20634v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The proliferation of hate speech on social media platforms has necessitated the development of effective detection and moderation tools. This study evaluates the efficacy of various machine learning models in identifying hate speech and offensive language and investigates the potential of text transformation techniques to neutralize such content. We compare traditional models like CNNs and LSTMs with advanced neural network models such as BERT and its derivatives, alongside exploring hybrid models that combine different architectural features. Our results indicate that while advanced models like BERT show superior accuracy due to their deep contextual understanding, hybrid models exhibit improved capabilities in certain scenarios. Furthermore, we introduce innovative text transformation approaches that convert negative expressions into neutral ones, thereby potentially mitigating the impact of harmful content. The implications of these findings are discussed, highlighting the strengths and limitations of current technologies and proposing future directions for more robust hate speech detection systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20634v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Saurabh Mishra, Shivani Thakur, Radhika Mamidi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Novelty at Scale: Narrative Shape Taxonomy and Readership Prediction in 28,606 Books</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20647</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20647v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: I introduce semantic novelty--cosine distance between each paragraph's sentence embedding and the running centroid of all preceding paragraphs--as an information-theoretic measure of narrative structure at corpus scale. Applying it to 28,606 books in PG19 (pre-1920 English literature), I compute paragraph-level novelty curves using 768-dimensional SBERT embeddings, then reduce each to a 16-segment Piecewise Aggregate Approximation (PAA). Ward-linkage clustering on PAA vectors reveals eight canonical narrative shape archetypes, from Steep Descent (rapid convergence) to Steep Ascent (escalating unpredictability). Volume--variance of the novelty trajectory--is the strongest length-independent predictor of readership (partial rho = 0.32), followed by speed (rho = 0.19) and Terminal/Initial ratio (rho = 0.19). Circuitousness shows strong raw correlation (rho = 0.41) but is 93 percent correlated with length; after control, partial rho drops to 0.11--demonstrating that naive correlations in corpus studies can be dominated by length confounds. Genre strongly constrains narrative shape (chi squared = 2121.6, p &lt; 10 to the power negative 242), with fiction maintaining plateau profiles while nonfiction front-loads information. Historical analysis shows books became progressively more predictable between 1840 and 1910 (T/I ratio trend r = negative 0.74, p = 0.037). SAX analysis reveals 85 percent signature uniqueness, suggesting each book traces a nearly unique path through semantic space. These findings demonstrate that information-density dynamics, distinct from sentiment or topic, constitute a fundamental dimension of narrative structure with measurable consequences for reader engagement. Dataset: https://huggingface.co/datasets/wfzimmerman/pg19-semantic-novelty</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20647v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>W. Frederick Zimmerman</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CARE: An Explainable Computational Framework for Assessing Client-Perceived Therapeutic Alliance Using Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20648</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20648v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Client perceptions of the therapeutic alliance are critical for counseling effectiveness. Accurately capturing these perceptions remains challenging, as traditional post-session questionnaires are burdensome and often delayed, while existing computational approaches produce coarse scores, lack interpretable rationales, and fail to model holistic session context. We present CARE, an LLM-based framework to automatically predict multi-dimensional alliance scores and generate interpretable rationales from counseling transcripts. Built on the CounselingWAI dataset and enriched with 9,516 expert-curated rationales, CARE is fine-tuned using rationale-augmented supervision with the LLaMA-3.1-8B-Instruct backbone. Experiments show that CARE outperforms leading LLMs and substantially reduces the gap between counselor evaluations and client-perceived alliance, achieving over 70% higher Pearson correlation with client ratings. Rationale-augmented supervision further improves predictive accuracy. CARE also produces high-quality, contextually grounded rationales, validated by both automatic and human evaluations. Applied to real-world Chinese online counseling sessions, CARE uncovers common alliance-building challenges, illustrates how interaction patterns shape alliance development, and provides actionable insights, demonstrating its potential as an AI-assisted tool for supporting mental health care.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20648v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Anqi Li, Chenxiao Wang, Yu Lu, Renjun Xu, Lizhi Ma, Zhenzhong Lan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CAMEL: Confidence-Gated Reflection for Reward Modeling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20670</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20670v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Reward models play a fundamental role in aligning large language models with human preferences. Existing methods predominantly follow two paradigms: scalar discriminative preference models, which are efficient but lack interpretability, and generative judging models, which offer richer reasoning at the cost of higher computational overhead. We observe that the log-probability margin between verdict tokens strongly correlates with prediction correctness, providing a reliable proxy for instance difficulty without additional inference cost. Building on this insight, we propose CAMEL, a confidence-gated reflection framework that performs a lightweight single-token preference decision first and selectively invokes reflection only for low-confidence instances. To induce effective self-correction, we train the model via reinforcement learning with counterfactual prefix augmentation, which exposes the model to diverse initial verdicts and encourages genuine revision. Empirically, CAMEL achieves state-of-the-art performance on three widely used reward-model benchmarks with 82.9% average accuracy, surpassing the best prior model by 3.2% and outperforming 70B-parameter models using only 14B parameters, while establishing a strictly better accuracy-efficiency Pareto frontier.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20670v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zirui Zhu, Hailun Xu, Yang Luo, Yong Liu, Kanchan Sarkar, Kun Xu, Yang You</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ID-LoRA: Efficient Low-Rank Adaptation Inspired by Matrix Interpolative Decomposition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20727</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20727v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: LoRA has become a universal Parameter-Efficient Fine-Tuning (PEFT) technique that equips Large Language Models (LLMs) to adapt quickly to new tasks. However, when these models are scaled up, even the latest LoRA variants still introduce considerable overhead in trainable parameters. Conversely, aggressively lowering the rank to curb this overhead markedly degrades performance in complex multi-task settings. We propose ID-LoRA, a novel PEFT framework that breaks the trade-off. Its core innovation lies in extracting and reusing clustered parameter groups from the pretrained weight matrix. These groups are then used to form multiple low-rank components, all of which share only a single initialized trainable low-rank matrix. This approach cuts the number of trainable parameters while keeping the model's capacity intact. We evaluate ID-LoRA on five diverse benchmarks: Mathematical Reasoning, Code Generation, MMLU, CommonsenseQA, and Safety Alignment. ID-LoRA outperforms both full fine-tuning and existing PEFT baselines (e.g., LoRA, DoRA, HydraLoRA) while using up to 46% fewer trainable parameters than the standard LoRA. In multi-task scenarios, it surpasses LoRA and its recent variants (e.g., DoRA and HydraLoRA) on both Code and MMLU tasks, yet requires only 54% of the trainable parameters demanded by the conventional LoRA.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20727v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xindian Ma, Rundong Kong, Peng Zhang, Ruoxiang Huang, Yongyu Jiang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive Text Anonymization: Learning Privacy-Utility Trade-offs via Prompt Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20743</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20743v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Anonymizing textual documents is a highly context-sensitive problem: the appropriate balance between privacy protection and utility preservation varies with the data domain, privacy objectives, and downstream application. However, existing anonymization methods rely on static, manually designed strategies that lack the flexibility to adjust to diverse requirements and often fail to generalize across domains. We introduce adaptive text anonymization, a new task formulation in which anonymization strategies are automatically adapted to specific privacy-utility requirements. We propose a framework for task-specific prompt optimization that automatically constructs anonymization instructions for language models, enabling adaptation to different privacy goals, domains, and downstream usage patterns. To evaluate our approach, we present a benchmark spanning five datasets with diverse domains, privacy constraints, and utility objectives. Across all evaluated settings, our framework consistently achieves a better privacy-utility trade-off than existing baselines, while remaining computationally efficient and effective on open-source language models, with performance comparable to larger closed-source models. Additionally, we show that our method can discover novel anonymization strategies that explore different points along the privacy-utility trade-off frontier.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20743v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gabriel Loiseau, Damien Sileo, Damien Riquet, Maxime Meyer, Marc Tommasi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explicit Grammar Semantic Feature Fusion for Robust Text Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20749</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20749v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Natural Language Processing enables computers to understand human language by analysing and classifying text efficiently with deep-level grammatical and semantic features. Existing models capture features by learning from large corpora with transformer models, which are computationally intensive and unsuitable for resource-constrained environments. Therefore, our proposed study incorporates comprehensive grammatical rules alongside semantic information to build a robust, lightweight classification model without resorting to full parameterised transformer models or heavy deep learning architectures. The novelty of our approach lies in its explicit encoding of sentence-level grammatical structure, including syntactic composition, phrase patterns, and complexity indicators, into a compact grammar vector, which is then fused with frozen contextual embeddings. These heterogeneous elements unified a single representation that captures both the structural and semantic characteristics of the text. Deep learning models such as Deep Belief Networks (DBNs), Long Short-Term Memory (LSTMs), BiLSTMs, and transformer-based BERT and XLNET were used to train and evaluate the model, with the number of epochs varied. Based on experimental results, the unified feature representation model captures both the semantic and structural properties of text, outperforming baseline models by 2%-15%, enabling more effective learning across heterogeneous domains. Unlike prior syntax-aware transformer models that inject grammatical structure through additional attention layers, tree encoders, or full fine-tuning, the proposed framework treats grammar as an explicit inductive bias rather than a learnable module, resulting in a very lightweight model that delivers better performance on edge devices</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20749v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Azrin Sultana, Firoz Ahmed</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SibylSense: Adaptive Rubric Learning via Memory Tuning and Adversarial Probing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20751</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20751v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Designing aligned and robust rewards for open-ended generation remains a key barrier to RL post-training. Rubrics provide structured, interpretable supervision, but scaling rubric construction is difficult: expert rubrics are costly, prompted rubrics are often superficial or inconsistent, and fixed-pool discriminative rubrics can saturate and drift, enabling reward hacking. We present SibylSense, an inference-time learning approach that adapts a frozen rubric generator through a tunable memory bank of validated rubric items. Memory is updated via verifier-based item rewards measured by reference-candidate answer discriminative gaps from a handful of examples. SibylSense alternates memory tuning with a rubric-adversarial policy update that produces rubric-satisfying candidate answers, shrinking discriminative gaps and driving the rubric generator to capture new quality dimensions. Experiments on two open-ended tasks show that SibylSense yields more discriminative rubrics and improves downstream RL performance over static and non-adaptive baselines.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20751v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yifei Xu, Guilherme Potje, Shivam Shandilya, Tiancheng Yuan, Leonardo de Oliveira Nunes, Rakshanda Agarwal, Saeid Asgari, Adam Atkinson, Emre K{\i}c{\i}man, Songwu Lu, Ranveer Chandra, Tusher Chakraborty</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overton Pluralistic Reinforcement Learning for Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20759</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20759v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Existing alignment paradigms remain limited in capturing the pluralistic nature of human values. Overton Pluralism addresses this gap by generating responses with diverse perspectives from a single query. This paper introduces OP-GRPO (Overton Pluralistic Group Relative Policy Optimization), a reinforcement learning framework for implicit Overton Pluralism that enables a single large language model to produce pluralistic responses without explicit prompting or modular orchestration. Our workflow consists of two main steps. First, similarity estimator training fine-tunes a Sentence Transformer for Overton Pluralism tasks to provide more accurate coverage evaluation of generated responses. Second, OP-GRPO training incorporates this similarity estimator into a dual-reward system designed to ensure both broad coverage of genuine human perspectives and the uniqueness of each perspective, thereby promoting diversity. Empirical results demonstrate a "small models, big perspective coverage" effect. The trained Qwen2.5-3B-Instruct model surpasses a 20B GPT-OSS baseline with a 37.4 percent relative accuracy gain on a Natural Language Inference benchmark, and also outperforms a modular architecture baseline with a 19.1 percent relative improvement. Additional evaluations using GPT-4.1 as a large language model judge further confirm the robustness of the approach.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20759v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yu Fu, Seongho Son, Ilija Bogunovic</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don't Ignore the Tail: Decoupling top-K Probabilities for Efficient Language Model Distillation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20816</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20816v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The core learning signal used in language model distillation is the standard Kullback-Leibler (KL) divergence between the student and teacher distributions. Traditional KL divergence tends to be dominated by the next tokens with the highest probabilities, i.e., the teacher's modes, thereby diminishing the influence of less probable yet potentially informative components of the output distribution. We propose a new tail-aware divergence that decouples the contribution of the teacher model's top-K predicted probabilities from that of lower-probability predictions, while maintaining the same computational profile as the KL Divergence. Our decoupled approach reduces the impact of the teacher modes and, consequently, increases the contribution of the tail of the distribution. Experimental results demonstrate that our modified distillation method yields competitive performance in both pre-training and supervised distillation of decoder models across various datasets. Furthermore, the distillation process is efficient and can be performed with a modest academic budget for large datasets, eliminating the need for industry-scale computing.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20816v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sayantan Dasgupta, Trevor Cohn, Timothy Baldwin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FinAnchor: Aligned Multi-Model Representations for Financial Prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20859</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20859v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Financial prediction from long documents involves significant challenges, as actionable signals are often sparse and obscured by noise, and the optimal LLM for generating embeddings varies across tasks and time periods. In this paper, we propose FinAnchor(Financial Anchored Representations), a lightweight framework that integrates embeddings from multiple LLMs without fine-tuning the underlying models. FinAnchor addresses the incompatibility of feature spaces by selecting an anchor embedding space and learning linear mappings to align representations from other models into this anchor. These aligned features are then aggregated to form a unified representation for downstream prediction. Across multiple financial NLP tasks, FinAnchor consistently outperforms strong single-model baselines and standard ensemble methods, demonstrating the effectiveness of anchoring heterogeneous representations for robust financial prediction.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20859v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zirui He, Huopu Zhang, Yanguang Liu, Sirui Wu, Mengnan Du</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exa-PSD: a new Persian sentiment analysis dataset on Twitter</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20892</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20892v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Today, Social networks such as Twitter are the most widely used platforms for communication of people. Analyzing this data has useful information to recognize the opinion of people in tweets. Sentiment analysis plays a vital role in NLP, which identifies the opinion of the individuals about a specific topic. Natural language processing in Persian has many challenges despite the adventure of strong language models. The datasets available in Persian are generally in special topics such as products, foods, hotels, etc while users may use ironies, colloquial phrases in social media To overcome these challenges, there is a necessity for having a dataset of Persian sentiment analysis on Twitter. In this paper, we introduce the Exa sentiment analysis Persian dataset, which is collected from Persian tweets. This dataset contains 12,000 tweets, annotated by 5 native Persian taggers. The aforementioned data is labeled in 3 classes: positive, neutral and negative. We present the characteristics and statistics of this dataset and use the pre-trained Pars Bert and Roberta as the base model to evaluate this dataset. Our evaluation reached a 79.87 Macro F-score, which shows the model and data can be adequately valuable for a sentiment analysis system.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20892v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1007/s10579-025-09886-5</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Lang Resources &amp; Evaluation 60, 6 (2026)</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Seyed Himan Ghaderi, Saeed Sarbazi Azad, Mohammad Mehdi Jaziriyan, Ahmad Akbari</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Efficient Reasoning: Data, Reward, and Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20945</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20945v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) consistently benefit from scaled Chain-of-Thought (CoT) reasoning, but also suffer from heavy computational overhead. To address this issue, efficient reasoning aims to incentivize short yet accurate thinking trajectories, typically through reward shaping with Reinforcement Learning (RL). In this paper, we systematically investigate the mechanics of efficient reasoning for LLMs. For comprehensive evaluation, we advocate for more fine-grained metrics, including length distribution conditioned on correctness and performance across a wide spectrum of token budgets ranging from 2k to 32k. First, we reveal that the training process follows a two-stage paradigm: length adaptation and reasoning refinement. After that, we conduct extensive experiments (about 0.2 million GPU hours) in a unified protocol, deconstructing training prompts and rollouts, reward shaping, and optimization strategies. In particular, a key finding is to train on relatively easier prompts, ensuring the density of positive reward signals and thus avoiding the length collapse. Meanwhile, the learned length bias can be generalized across domains. We distill all findings into valuable insights and practical guidelines, and further validate them across the Qwen3 series, ranging from 0.6B to 30B, demonstrating the robustness and generalization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20945v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Taiqiang Wu, Zenan Zu, Bo Zhou, Ngai Wong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blackbird Language Matrices: A Framework to Investigate the Linguistic Competence of Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20966</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20966v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This article describes a novel language task, the Blackbird Language Matrices (BLM) task, inspired by intelligence tests, and illustrates the BLM datasets, their construction and benchmarking, and targeted experiments on chunking and systematicity. BLMs are multiple-choice problems, structured at multiple levels: within each sentence, across the input sequence, within each candidate answer. Because of their rich structure, these curated, but naturalistic datasets are key to answer some core questions about current large language models abilities: do LLMs detect linguistic objects and their properties? Do they detect and use systematic patterns across sentences? Are they more prone to linguistic or reasoning errors, and how do these interact?
  We show that BLMs, while challenging, can be solved at good levels of performance, in more than one language, with simple baseline models or, at better performance levels, with more tailored models. We show that their representations contain the grammatical objects and attributes relevant to solve a linguistic task. We also show that these solutions are reached by detecting systematic patterns across sentences.
  The paper supports the point of view that curated, structured datasets support multi-faceted investigations of properties of language and large language models. Because they present a curated, articulated structure, because they comprise both learning contexts and expected answers, and because they are partly built by hand, BLMs fall in the category of datasets that can support explainability investigations, and be useful to ask why large language models behave the way they do.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20966v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Paola Merlo, Chunyang Jiang, Giuseppe Samo, Vivi Nastase</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linear Reasoning vs. Proof by Cases: Obstacles for Large Language Models in FOL Problem Solving</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20973</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20973v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: To comprehensively evaluate the mathematical reasoning capabilities of Large Language Models (LLMs), researchers have introduced abundant mathematical reasoning datasets. However, most existing datasets primarily focus on linear reasoning, neglecting other parts such as proof by contradiction and proof by cases, which are crucial for investigating LLMs' reasoning abilities. To address this limitation, we first introduce a novel first-order logic (FOL) dataset named PC-FOL, annotated by professional mathematicians, focusing on case-based reasoning problems. All instances in this dataset are equipped with a manually written natural language proof, clearly distinguishing it from conventional linear reasoning datasets. Our experimental results over leading LLMs demonstrate a substantial performance gap between linear reasoning and case-based reasoning problems. To further investigate this phenomenon, we provide a theoretical analysis grounded in graphical model, which provides an explanation for the observed disparity between the two types of reasoning problems. We hope this work can reveal the core challenges in the field of automated natural language mathematical proof generation, paving the way for future research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20973v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuliang Ji, Fuchen Shen, Jian Wu, Qiujie Xie, Yue Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Proactive Risk Awareness of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20976</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20976v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: As large language models (LLMs) are increasingly embedded in everyday decision-making, their safety responsibilities extend beyond reacting to explicit harmful intent toward anticipating unintended but consequential risks. In this work, we introduce a proactive risk awareness evaluation framework that measures whether LLMs can anticipate potential harms and provide warnings before damage occurs. We construct the Butterfly dataset to instantiate this framework in the environmental and ecological domain. It contains 1,094 queries that simulate ordinary solution-seeking activities whose responses may induce latent ecological impact. Through experiments across five widely used LLMs, we analyze the effects of response length, languages, and modality. Experimental results reveal consistent, significant declines in proactive awareness under length-restricted responses, cross-lingual similarities, and persistent blind spots in (multimodal) species protection. These findings highlight a critical gap between current safety alignment and the requirements of real-world ecological responsibility, underscoring the need for proactive safeguards in LLM deployment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20976v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xuan Luo, Yubin Chen, Zhiyu Hou, Linpu Yu, Geng Tu, Jing Li, Ruifeng Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the Star Rating: A Scalable Framework for Aspect-Based Sentiment Analysis Using LLMs and Text Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.21082</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.21082v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Customer-provided reviews have become an important source of information for business owners and other customers alike. However, effectively analyzing millions of unstructured reviews remains challenging. While large language models (LLMs) show promise for natural language understanding, their application to large-scale review analysis has been limited by computational costs and scalability concerns. This study proposes a hybrid approach that uses LLMs for aspect identification while employing classic machine-learning methods for sentiment classification at scale. Using ChatGPT to analyze sampled restaurant reviews, we identified key aspects of dining experiences and developed sentiment classifiers using human-labeled reviews, which we subsequently applied to 4.7 million reviews collected over 17 years from a major online platform. Regression analysis reveals that our machine-labeled aspects significantly explain variance in overall restaurant ratings across different aspects of dining experiences, cuisines, and geographical regions. Our findings demonstrate that combining LLMs with traditional machine learning approaches can effectively automate aspect-based sentiment analysis of large-scale customer feedback, suggesting a practical framework for both researchers and practitioners in the hospitality industry and potentially, other service sectors.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.21082v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Vishal Patil, Shree Vaishnavi Bacha, Revanth Yamani, Yidan Sun, Mayank Kejriwal</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prompt-Level Distillation: A Non-Parametric Alternative to Model Fine-Tuning for Efficient Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.21103</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.21103v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Advanced reasoning typically requires Chain-of-Thought prompting, which is accurate but incurs prohibitive latency and substantial test-time inference costs. The standard alternative, fine-tuning smaller models, often sacrifices interpretability while introducing significant resource and operational overhead. To address these limitations, we introduce Prompt-Level Distillation (PLD). We extract explicit reasoning patterns from a Teacher model and organize them into a structured list of expressive instructions for the Student model's System Prompt. Evaluated on the StereoSet and Contract-NLI datasets using Gemma-3 4B, PLD improved Macro F1 scores from 57\% to 90.0\% and 67\% to 83\% respectively, enabling this compact model to match frontier performance with negligible latency overhead. These expressive instructions render the decision-making process transparent, allowing for full human verification of logic, making this approach ideal for regulated industries such as law, finance, and content moderation, as well as high-volume use cases and edge devices.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.21103v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sanket Badhe, Deep Shah</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PVminer: A Domain-Specific Tool to Detect the Patient Voice in Patient Generated Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.21165</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.21165v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Patient-generated text such as secure messages, surveys, and interviews contains rich expressions of the patient voice (PV), reflecting communicative behaviors and social determinants of health (SDoH). Traditional qualitative coding frameworks are labor intensive and do not scale to large volumes of patient-authored messages across health systems. Existing machine learning (ML) and natural language processing (NLP) approaches provide partial solutions but often treat patient-centered communication (PCC) and SDoH as separate tasks or rely on models not well suited to patient-facing language. We introduce PVminer, a domain-adapted NLP framework for structuring patient voice in secure patient-provider communication. PVminer formulates PV detection as a multi-label, multi-class prediction task integrating patient-specific BERT encoders (PV-BERT-base and PV-BERT-large), unsupervised topic modeling for thematic augmentation (PV-Topic-BERT), and fine-tuned classifiers for Code, Subcode, and Combo-level labels. Topic representations are incorporated during fine-tuning and inference to enrich semantic inputs. PVminer achieves strong performance across hierarchical tasks and outperforms biomedical and clinical pre-trained baselines, achieving F1 scores of 82.25% (Code), 80.14% (Subcode), and up to 77.87% (Combo). An ablation study further shows that author identity and topic-based augmentation each contribute meaningful gains. Pre-trained models, source code, and documentation will be publicly released, with annotated datasets available upon request for research use.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.21165v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Samah Fodeh, Linhai Ma, Yan Wang, Srivani Talakokkul, Ganesh Puthiaraju, Afshan Khan, Ashley Hagaman, Sarah Lowe, Aimee Roundtree</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Data Engineering for Scaling LLM Terminal Capabilities</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.21193</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.21193v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Despite rapid recent progress in the terminal capabilities of large language models, the training data strategies behind state-of-the-art terminal agents remain largely undisclosed. We address this gap through a systematic study of data engineering practices for terminal agents, making two key contributions: (1) Terminal-Task-Gen, a lightweight synthetic task generation pipeline that supports seed-based and skill-based task construction, and (2) a comprehensive analysis of data and training strategies, including filtering, curriculum learning, long context training, and scaling behavior. Our pipeline yields Terminal-Corpus, a large-scale open-source dataset for terminal tasks. Using this dataset, we train Nemotron-Terminal, a family of models initialized from Qwen3(8B, 14B, 32B) that achieve substantial gains on Terminal-Bench 2.0: Nemotron-Terminal-8B improves from 2.5% to 13.0% Nemotron-Terminal-14B improves from 4.0% to 20.2%, and Nemotron-Terminal-32B improves from 3.4% to 27.4%, matching the performance of significantly larger models. To accelerate research in this domain, we open-source our model checkpoints and most of our synthetic datasets at https://huggingface.co/collections/nvidia/nemotron-terminal.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.21193v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Renjie Pi, Grace Lam, Mohammad Shoeybi, Pooya Jannaty, Bryan Catanzaro, Wei Ping</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graph Modelling Analysis of Speech-Gesture Interaction for Aphasia Severity Estimation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20163</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20163v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Aphasia is an acquired language disorder caused by injury to the regions of the brain that are responsible for language. Aphasia may impair the use and comprehension of written and spoken language. The Western Aphasia Battery-Revised (WAB-R) is an assessment tool administered by speech-language pathologists (SLPs) to evaluate the aphasia type and severity. Because the WAB-R measures isolated linguistic skills, there has been growing interest in the assessment of discourse production as a more holistic representation of everyday language abilities. Recent advancements in speech analysis focus on automated estimation of aphasia severity from spontaneous speech, relying mostly in isolated linguistic or acoustical features. In this work, we propose a graph neural network-based framework for estimating aphasia severity. We represented each participant's discourse as a directed multi-modal graph, where nodes represent lexical items and gestures and edges encode word-word, gesture-word, and word-gesture transitions. GraphSAGE is employed to learn participant-level embeddings, thus integrating information from immediate neighbors and overall graph structure. Our results suggest that aphasia severity is not encoded in isolated lexical distribution, but rather emerges from structured interactions between speech and gesture. The proposed architecture offers a reliable automated aphasia assessment, with possible uses in bedside screening and telehealth-based monitoring.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20163v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Navya Martin Kollapally, Christa Akers, Renjith Nelson Joseph</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MoBiQuant: Mixture-of-Bits Quantization for Token-Adaptive Elastic LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20191</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20191v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Changing runtime complexity on cloud and edge devices necessitates elastic large language model (LLM) deployment, where an LLM can be inferred with various quantization precisions based on available computational resources. However, it has been observed that the calibration parameters for quantization are typically linked to specific precisions, which presents challenges during elastic-precision calibration and precision switching at runtime. In this work, we attribute the source of varying calibration parameters to the varying token-level sensitivity caused by a precision-dependent outlier migration phenomenon.Motivated by this observation, we propose \texttt{MoBiQuant}, a novel Mixture-of-Bits quantization framework that adjusts weight precision for elastic LLM inference based on token sensitivity. Specifically, we propose the many-in-one recursive residual quantization that can iteratively reconstruct higher-precision weights and the token-aware router to dynamically select the number of residual bit slices. MoBiQuant enables smooth precision switching while improving generalization for the distribution of token outliers. Experimental results demonstrate that MoBiQuant exhibits strong elasticity, enabling it to match the performance of bit-specific calibrated PTQ on LLaMA3-8B without repeated calibration.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20191v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dongwei Wang, Jinhee Kim, Seokho Han, Denis Gudovskiy, Yohei Nakata, Tomoyuki Okuno, KhayTze Peong, Kang Eun Jeon, Jong Hwan Ko, Yiran Chen, Huanrui Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Anti-Aging Literature via ConvexTopics and Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20224</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20224v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The rapid expansion of biomedical publications creates challenges for organizing knowledge and detecting emerging trends, underscoring the need for scalable and interpretable methods. Common clustering and topic modeling approaches such as K-means or LDA remain sensitive to initialization and prone to local optima, limiting reproducibility and evaluation. We propose a reformulation of a convex optimization based clustering algorithm that produces stable, fine-grained topics by selecting exemplars from the data and guaranteeing a global optimum. Applied to about 12,000 PubMed articles on aging and longevity, our method uncovers topics validated by medical experts. It yields interpretable topics spanning from molecular mechanisms to dietary supplements, physical activity, and gut microbiota. The method performs favorably, and most importantly, its reproducibility and interpretability distinguish it from common clustering approaches, including K-means, LDA, and BERTopic. This work provides a basis for developing scalable, web-accessible tools for knowledge discovery.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20224v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lana E. Yeganova, Won G. Kim, Shubo Tian, Natalie Xie, Donald C. Comeau, W. John Wilbur, Zhiyong Lu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An artificial intelligence framework for end-to-end rare disease phenotyping from clinical notes using large language models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20324</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20324v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Phenotyping is fundamental to rare disease diagnosis, but manual curation of structured phenotypes from clinical notes is labor-intensive and difficult to scale. Existing artificial intelligence approaches typically optimize individual components of phenotyping but do not operationalize the full clinical workflow of extracting features from clinical text, standardizing them to Human Phenotype Ontology (HPO) terms, and prioritizing diagnostically informative HPO terms. We developed RARE-PHENIX, an end-to-end AI framework for rare disease phenotyping that integrates large language model-based phenotype extraction, ontology-grounded standardization to HPO terms, and supervised ranking of diagnostically informative phenotypes. We trained RARE-PHENIX using data from 2,671 patients across 11 Undiagnosed Diseases Network clinical sites, and externally validated it on 16,357 real-world clinical notes from Vanderbilt University Medical Center. Using clinician-curated HPO terms as the gold standard, RARE-PHENIX consistently outperformed a state-of-the-art deep learning baseline (PhenoBERT) across ontology-based similarity and precision-recall-F1 metrics in end-to-end evaluation (i.e., ontology-based similarity of 0.70 vs. 0.58). Ablation analyses demonstrated performance improvements with the addition of each module in RARE-PHENIX (extraction, standardization, and prioritization), supporting the value of modeling the full clinical phenotyping workflow. By modeling phenotyping as a clinically aligned workflow rather than a single extraction task, RARE-PHENIX provides structured, ranked phenotypes that are more concordant with clinician curation and has the potential to support human-in-the-loop rare disease diagnosis in real-world settings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20324v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Cathy Shyr, Yan Hu, Rory J. Tinker, Thomas A. Cassini, Kevin W. Byram, Rizwan Hamid, Daniel V. Fabbri, Adam Wright, Josh F. Peterson, Lisa Bastarache, Hua Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MedCLIPSeg: Probabilistic Vision-Language Adaptation for Data-Efficient and Generalizable Medical Image Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20423</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20423v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Medical image segmentation remains challenging due to limited annotations for training, ambiguous anatomical features, and domain shifts. While vision-language models such as CLIP offer strong cross-modal representations, their potential for dense, text-guided medical image segmentation remains underexplored. We present MedCLIPSeg, a novel framework that adapts CLIP for robust, data-efficient, and uncertainty-aware medical image segmentation. Our approach leverages patch-level CLIP embeddings through probabilistic cross-modal attention, enabling bidirectional interaction between image and text tokens and explicit modeling of predictive uncertainty. Together with a soft patch-level contrastive loss that encourages more nuanced semantic learning across diverse textual prompts, MedCLIPSeg effectively improves data efficiency and domain generalizability. Extensive experiments across 16 datasets spanning five imaging modalities and six organs demonstrate that MedCLIPSeg outperforms prior methods in accuracy, efficiency, and robustness, while providing interpretable uncertainty maps that highlight local reliability of segmentation results. This work demonstrates the potential of probabilistic vision-language modeling for text-driven medical image segmentation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20423v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Taha Koleilat, Hojat Asgariandehkordi, Omid Nejati Manzari, Berardino Barile, Yiming Xiao, Hassan Rivaz</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protein Language Models Diverge from Natural Language: Comparative Analysis and Improved Inference</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20449</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20449v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Modern Protein Language Models (PLMs) apply transformer-based model architectures from natural language processing to biological sequences, predicting a variety of protein functions and properties. However, protein language has key differences from natural language, such as a rich functional space despite a vocabulary of only 20 amino acids. These differences motivate research into how transformer-based architectures operate differently in the protein domain and how we can better leverage PLMs to solve protein-related tasks. In this work, we begin by directly comparing how the distribution of information stored across layers of attention heads differs between the protein and natural language domain. Furthermore, we adapt a simple early-exit technique-originally used in the natural language domain to improve efficiency at the cost of performance-to achieve both increased accuracy and substantial efficiency gains in protein non-structural property prediction by allowing the model to automatically select protein representations from the intermediate layers of the PLMs for the specific task and protein at hand. We achieve performance gains ranging from 0.4 to 7.01 percentage points while simultaneously improving efficiency by over 10 percent across models and non-structural prediction tasks. Our work opens up an area of research directly comparing how language models change behavior when moved into the protein domain and advances language modeling in biological domains.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20449v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>q-bio.BM</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Anna Hart, Chi Han, Jeonghwan Kim, Huimin Zhao, Heng Ji</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PreScience: A Benchmark for Forecasting Scientific Contributions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20459</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20459v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Can AI systems trained on the scientific record up to a fixed point in time forecast the scientific advances that follow? Such a capability could help researchers identify collaborators and impactful research directions, and anticipate which problems and methods will become central next. We introduce PreScience -- a scientific forecasting benchmark that decomposes the research process into four interdependent generative tasks: collaborator prediction, prior work selection, contribution generation, and impact prediction. PreScience is a carefully curated dataset of 98K recent AI-related research papers, featuring disambiguated author identities, temporally aligned scholarly metadata, and a structured graph of companion author publication histories and citations spanning 502K total papers. We develop baselines and evaluations for each task, including LACERScore, a novel LLM-based measure of contribution similarity that outperforms previous metrics and approximates inter-annotator agreement. We find substantial headroom remains in each task -- e.g. in contribution generation, frontier LLMs achieve only moderate similarity to the ground-truth (GPT-5, averages 5.6 on a 1-10 scale). When composed into a 12-month end-to-end simulation of scientific production, the resulting synthetic corpus is systematically less diverse and less novel than human-authored research from the same period.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20459v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Anirudh Ajith, Amanpreet Singh, Jay DeYoung, Nadav Kunievsky, Austin C. Kozlowski, Oyvind Tafjord, James Evans, Daniel S. Weld, Tom Hope, Doug Downey</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inner Speech as Behavior Guides: Steerable Imitation of Diverse Behaviors for Human-AI coordination</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20517</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20517v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Effective human-AI coordination requires artificial agents capable of exhibiting and responding to human-like behaviors while adapting to changing contexts. Imitation learning has emerged as one of the prominent approaches to build such agents by training them to mimic human-demonstrated behaviors. However, current methods struggle to capture the inherent diversity and non-Markovian nature of human behavior and lack the ability to steer behavior at inference time. Drawing inspiration from the theory of human cognitive processes, where inner speech guides action selection before execution, we propose MIMIC (Modeling Inner Motivations for Imitation and Control), a framework that uses language as an internal representation of behavioral intent. MIMIC employs the novel use of vision-language models as linguistic scaffolding to train a conditional variational autoencoder capable of generating inner speech from observations. A diffusion-based behavior cloning policy then selects actions conditioned on current observations and the generated inner speech. MIMIC enables fine-grained steering of behavior at inference time by conditioning the agent on behavior-specific speech. Experiments across robotic manipulation tasks and human-AI collaboration games demonstrate that MIMIC significantly enhances both behavior diversity and fidelity to human demonstrations while enabling nuanced behavioral steering without training on additional demonstrations. We open source our code and provide pre-trained MIMIC agents and qualitative demos at: https://mimic-research.github.io.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20517v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rakshit Trivedi, Kartik Sharma, David C Parkes</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Actor-Curator: Co-adaptive Curriculum Learning via Policy-Improvement Bandits for RL Post-Training</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20532</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20532v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Post-training large foundation models with reinforcement learning typically relies on massive and heterogeneous datasets, making effective curriculum learning both critical and challenging. In this work, we propose ACTOR-CURATOR, a scalable and fully automated curriculum learning framework for reinforcement learning post-training of large language models (LLMs). ACTOR-CURATOR learns a neural curator that dynamically selects training problems from large problem banks by directly optimizing for expected policy performance improvement. We formulate problem selection as a non-stationary stochastic bandit problem, derive a principled loss function based on online stochastic mirror descent, and establish regret guarantees under partial feedback. Empirically, ACTOR-CURATOR consistently outperforms uniform sampling and strong curriculum baselines across a wide range of challenging reasoning benchmarks, demonstrating improved training stability and efficiency. Notably, it achieves relative gains of 28.6% on AIME2024 and 30.5% on ARC-1D over the strongest baseline and up to 80% speedup. These results suggest that ACTOR-CURATOR is a powerful and practical approach for scalable LLM post-training.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20532v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhengyao Gu, Jonathan Light, Raul Astudillo, Ziyu Ye, Langzhou He, Henry Peng Zou, Wei Cheng, Santiago Paternain, Philip S. Yu, Yisong Yue</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GATES: Self-Distillation under Privileged Context with Consensus Gating</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20574</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20574v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We study self-distillation in settings where supervision is unreliable: there are no ground truth labels, verifiable rewards, or external graders to evaluate answers. We focus on document-grounded question answering with asymmetric context, where a single model serves as both tutor (with access to a relevant source document during training) and student (answering from the question alone at test time). Rather than assuming tutor correctness, we derive supervision online from tutor consensus by sampling multiple document-grounded reasoning traces and using agreement to gate learning. Conditioned on this reliability signal, we distill knowledge through full tutor reasoning trajectories (not just final answers), providing a dense and stable learning signal. Empirically, this consensus-gated trajectory distillation substantially improves transfer to the document-free student. Held-out in-domain accuracy under asymmetric evaluation improves from 46.0\% to 62.0\%, and average (maj@8) accuracy on public document-free math benchmarks improves from 20.2\% to 35.4\%.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20574v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alex Stein, Furong Huang, Tom Goldstein</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SpecMind: Cognitively Inspired, Interactive Multi-Turn Framework for Postcondition Inference</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20610</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20610v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Specifications are vital for ensuring program correctness, yet writing them manually remains challenging and time-intensive. Recent large language model (LLM)-based methods have shown successes in generating specifications such as postconditions, but existing single-pass prompting often yields inaccurate results. In this paper, we present SpecMind, a novel framework for postcondition generation that treats LLMs as interactive and exploratory reasoners rather than one-shot generators. SpecMind employs feedback-driven multi-turn prompting approaches, enabling the model to iteratively refine candidate postconditions by incorporating implicit and explicit correctness feedback, while autonomously deciding when to stop. This process fosters deeper code comprehension and improves alignment with true program behavior via exploratory attempts. Our empirical evaluation shows that SpecMind significantly outperforms state-of-the-art approaches in both accuracy and completeness of generated postconditions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20610v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Cuong Chi Le, Minh V. T Pham, Tung Vu Duy, Cuong Duc Van, Huy N. Phan, Hoang N. Phan, Tien N. Nguyen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Counterfactual Simulation Training for Chain-of-Thought Faithfulness</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20710</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20710v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Inspecting Chain-of-Thought reasoning is among the most common means of understanding why an LLM produced its output. But well-known problems with CoT faithfulness severely limit what insights can be gained from this practice. In this paper, we introduce a training method called Counterfactual Simulation Training (CST), which aims to improve CoT faithfulness by rewarding CoTs that enable a simulator to accurately predict a model's outputs over counterfactual inputs. We apply CST in two settings: (1) CoT monitoring with cue-based counterfactuals, to detect when models rely on spurious features, reward hack, or are sycophantic, and (2) counterfactual simulation over generic model-based counterfactuals, to encourage models to produce more faithful, generalizable reasoning in the CoT. Experiments with models up to 235B parameters show that CST can substantially improve monitor accuracy on cue-based counterfactuals (by 35 accuracy points) as well as simulatability over generic counterfactuals (by 2 points). We further show that: (1) CST outperforms prompting baselines, (2) rewriting unfaithful CoTs with an LLM is 5x more efficient than RL alone, (3) faithfulness improvements do not generalize to dissuading cues (as opposed to persuading cues), and (4) larger models do not show more faithful CoT out of the box, but they do benefit more from CST. These results suggest that CST can improve CoT faithfulness in general, with promising applications for CoT monitoring. Code for experiments in this paper is available at https://github.com/peterbhase/counterfactual-simulation-training</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20710v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Peter Hase, Christopher Potts</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RMIT-ADM+S at the MMU-RAG NeurIPS 2025 Competition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20735</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20735v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This paper presents the award-winning RMIT-ADM+S system for the Text-to-Text
  track of the NeurIPS~2025 MMU-RAG Competition. We introduce Routing-to-RAG
  (R2RAG), a research-focused retrieval-augmented generation (RAG)
  architecture composed of lightweight components that dynamically adapt the
  retrieval strategy based on inferred query complexity and evidence
  sufficiency. The system uses smaller LLMs, enabling operation on a single
  consumer-grade GPU while supporting complex research tasks. It builds on the
  G-RAG system, winner of the ACM~SIGIR~2025 LiveRAG Challenge, and extends it
  with modules informed by qualitative review of outputs. R2RAG won the Best
  Dynamic Evaluation award in the Open Source category, demonstrating high
  effectiveness with careful design and efficient use of resources.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20735v1</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kun Ran, Marwah Alaofi, Danula Hettiachchi, Chenglong Ma, Khoi Nguyen Dinh Anh, Khoi Vo Nguyen, Sachin Pathiyan Cherumanal, Lida Rashidi, Falk Scholer, Damiano Spina, Shuoqi Sun, Oleg Zendel</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Sentence Acceptability Judgments in Multimodal Contexts</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20918</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20918v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Previous work has examined the capacity of deep neural networks (DNNs), particularly transformers, to predict human sentence acceptability judgments, both independently of context, and in document contexts. We consider the effect of prior exposure to visual images (i.e., visual context) on these judgments for humans and large language models (LLMs). Our results suggest that, in contrast to textual context, visual images appear to have little if any impact on human acceptability ratings. However, LLMs display the compression effect seen in previous work on human judgments in document contexts. Different sorts of LLMs are able to predict human acceptability judgments to a high degree of accuracy, but in general, their performance is slightly better when visual contexts are removed. Moreover, the distribution of LLM judgments varies among models, with Qwen resembling human patterns, and others diverging from them. LLM-generated predictions on sentence acceptability are highly correlated with their normalised log probabilities in general. However, the correlations decrease when visual contexts are present, suggesting that a higher gap exists between the internal representations of LLMs and their generated predictions in the presence of visual contexts. Our experimental work suggests interesting points of similarity and of difference between human and LLM processing of sentences in multimodal contexts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20918v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hyewon Jang, Nikolai Ilinykh, Sharid Lo\'aiciga, Jey Han Lau, Shalom Lappin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multimodal MRI Report Findings Supervised Brain Lesion Segmentation with Substructures</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20994</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20994v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Report-supervised (RSuper) learning seeks to alleviate the need for dense tumor voxel labels with constraints derived from radiology reports (e.g., volumes, counts, sizes, locations). In MRI studies of brain tumors, however, we often involve multi-parametric scans and substructures. Here, fine-grained modality/parameter-wise reports are usually provided along with global findings and are correlated with different substructures. Moreover, the reports often describe only the largest lesion and provide qualitative or uncertain cues (``mild,'' ``possible''). Classical RSuper losses (e.g., sum volume consistency) can over-constrain or hallucinate unreported findings under such incompleteness, and are unable to utilize these hierarchical findings or exploit the priors of varied lesion types in a merged dataset. We explicitly parse the global quantitative and modality-wise qualitative findings and introduce a unified, one-sided, uncertainty-aware formulation (MS-RSuper) that: (i) aligns modality-specific qualitative cues (e.g., T1c enhancement, FLAIR edema) with their corresponding substructures using existence and absence losses; (ii) enforces one-sided lower-bounds for partial quantitative cues (e.g., largest lesion size, minimal multiplicity); and (iii) adds extra- vs. intra-axial anatomical priors to respect cohort differences. Certainty tokens scale penalties; missing cues are down-weighted. On 1238 report-labeled BraTS-MET/MEN scans, our MS-RSuper largely outperforms both a sparsely-supervised baseline and a naive RSuper method.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20994v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yubin Ge, Yongsong Huang, Xiaofeng Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generative Pseudo-Labeling for Pre-Ranking with LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20995</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20995v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Pre-ranking is a critical stage in industrial recommendation systems, tasked with efficiently scoring thousands of recalled items for downstream ranking. A key challenge is the train-serving discrepancy: pre-ranking models are trained only on exposed interactions, yet must score all recalled candidates -- including unexposed items -- during online serving. This mismatch not only induces severe sample selection bias but also degrades generalization, especially for long-tail content. Existing debiasing approaches typically rely on heuristics (e.g., negative sampling) or distillation from biased rankers, which either mislabel plausible unexposed items as negatives or propagate exposure bias into pseudo-labels. In this work, we propose Generative Pseudo-Labeling (GPL), a framework that leverages large language models (LLMs) to generate unbiased, content-aware pseudo-labels for unexposed items, explicitly aligning the training distribution with the online serving space. By offline generating user-specific interest anchors and matching them with candidates in a frozen semantic space, GPL provides high-quality supervision without adding online latency. Deployed in a large-scale production system, GPL improves click-through rate by 3.07%, while significantly enhancing recommendation diversity and long-tail item discovery.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20995v1</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junyu Bi, Xinting Niu, Daixuan Cheng, Kun Yuan, Tao Wang, Binbin Cao, Jian Wu, Yuning Jiang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HiSAC: Hierarchical Sparse Activation Compression for Ultra-long Sequence Modeling in Recommenders</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.21009</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.21009v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Modern recommender systems leverage ultra-long user behavior sequences to capture dynamic preferences, but end-to-end modeling is infeasible in production due to latency and memory constraints. While summarizing history via interest centers offers a practical alternative, existing methods struggle to (1) identify user-specific centers at appropriate granularity and (2) accurately assign behaviors, leading to quantization errors and loss of long-tail preferences. To alleviate these issues, we propose Hierarchical Sparse Activation Compression (HiSAC), an efficient framework for personalized sequence modeling. HiSAC encodes interactions into multi-level semantic IDs and constructs a global hierarchical codebook. A hierarchical voting mechanism sparsely activates personalized interest-agents as fine-grained preference centers. Guided by these agents, Soft-Routing Attention aggregates historical signals in semantic space, weighting by similarity to minimize quantization error and retain long-tail behaviors. Deployed on Taobao's "Guess What You Like" homepage, HiSAC achieves significant compression and cost reduction, with online A/B tests showing a consistent 1.65% CTR uplift -- demonstrating its scalability and real-world effectiveness.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.21009v1</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kun Yuan, Junyu Bi, Daixuan Cheng, Changfa Wu, Shuwen Xiao, Binbin Cao, Jian Wu, Yuning Jiang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PaperTrail: A Claim-Evidence Interface for Grounding Provenance in LLM-based Scholarly Q&amp;A</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.21045</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.21045v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are increasingly used in scholarly question-answering (QA) systems to help researchers synthesize vast amounts of literature. However, these systems often produce subtle errors (e.g., unsupported claims, errors of omission), and current provenance mechanisms like source citations are not granular enough for the rigorous verification that scholarly domain requires. To address this, we introduce PaperTrail, a novel interface that decomposes both LLM answers and source documents into discrete claims and evidence, mapping them to reveal supported assertions, unsupported claims, and information omitted from the source texts. We evaluated PaperTrail in a within-subjects study with 26 researchers who performed two scholarly editing tasks using PaperTrail and a baseline interface. Our results show that PaperTrail significantly lowered participants' trust compared to the baseline. However, this increased caution did not translate to behavioral changes, as people continued to rely on LLM-generated scholarly edits to avoid a cognitively burdensome task. We discuss the value of claim-evidence matching for understanding LLM trustworthiness in scholarly settings, and present design implications for cognition-friendly communication of provenance information.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.21045v1</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3772318.3791101</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Anna Martin-Boyle, Cara A. C. Leckey, Martha C. Brown, Harmanpreet Kaur</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VAUQ: Vision-Aware Uncertainty Quantification for LVLM Self-Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.21054</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.21054v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large Vision-Language Models (LVLMs) frequently hallucinate, limiting their safe deployment in real-world applications. Existing LLM self-evaluation methods rely on a model's ability to estimate the correctness of its own outputs, which can improve deployment reliability; however, they depend heavily on language priors and are therefore ill-suited for evaluating vision-conditioned predictions. We propose VAUQ, a vision-aware uncertainty quantification framework for LVLM self-evaluation that explicitly measures how strongly a model's output depends on visual evidence. VAUQ introduces the Image-Information Score (IS), which captures the reduction in predictive uncertainty attributable to visual input, and an unsupervised core-region masking strategy that amplifies the influence of salient regions. Combining predictive entropy with this core-masked IS yields a training-free scoring function that reliably reflects answer correctness. Comprehensive experiments show that VAUQ consistently outperforms existing self-evaluation methods across multiple datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.21054v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Seongheon Park, Changdae Oh, Hyeong Kyu Choi, Xuefeng Du, Sharon Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Expert Schema for Evaluating Large Language Model Errors in Scholarly Question-Answering Systems</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.21059</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.21059v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) are transforming scholarly tasks like search and summarization, but their reliability remains uncertain. Current evaluation metrics for testing LLM reliability are primarily automated approaches that prioritize efficiency and scalability, but lack contextual nuance and fail to reflect how scientific domain experts assess LLM outputs in practice. We developed and validated a schema for evaluating LLM errors in scholarly question-answering systems that reflects the assessment strategies of practicing scientists. In collaboration with domain experts, we identified 20 error patterns across seven categories through thematic analysis of 68 question-answer pairs. We validated this schema through contextual inquiries with 10 additional scientists, which showed not only which errors experts naturally identify but also how structured evaluation schemas can help them detect previously overlooked issues. Domain experts use systematic assessment strategies, including technical precision testing, value-based evaluation, and meta-evaluation of their own practices. We discuss implications for supporting expert evaluation of LLM outputs, including opportunities for personalized, schema-driven tools that adapt to individual evaluation patterns and expertise levels.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.21059v1</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3772318.3791843</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Anna Martin-Boyle, William Humphreys, Martha Brown, Cara Leckey, Harmanpreet Kaur</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Benchmark for Deep Information Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.21143</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.21143v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large language model (LLM)-based agents are increasingly used to solve complex tasks involving tool use, such as web browsing, code execution, and data analysis. However, current evaluation benchmarks do not adequately assess their ability to solve real-world tasks that require synthesizing information from multiple sources and inferring insights beyond simple fact retrieval. To address this, we introduce DEEPSYNTH, a novel benchmark designed to evaluate agents on realistic, time-consuming problems that combine information gathering, synthesis, and structured reasoning to produce insights. DEEPSYNTH contains 120 tasks collected across 7 domains and data sources covering 67 countries. DEEPSYNTH is constructed using a multi-stage data collection pipeline that requires annotators to collect official data sources, create hypotheses, perform manual analysis, and design tasks with verifiable answers. When evaluated on DEEPSYNTH, 11 state-of-the-art LLMs and deep research agents achieve a maximum F1 score of 8.97 and 17.5 on the LLM-judge metric, underscoring the difficulty of the benchmark. Our analysis reveals that current agents struggle with hallucinations and reasoning over large information spaces, highlighting DEEPSYNTH as a crucial benchmark for guiding future research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.21143v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Debjit Paul, Daniel Murphy, Milan Gritta, Ronald Cardenas, Victor Prokhorov, Lena Sophia Bolliger, Aysim Toker, Roy Miles, Andreea-Maria Oncescu, Jasivan Alex Sivakumar, Philipp Borchert, Ismail Elezi, Meiru Zhang, Ka Yiu Lee, Guchun Zhang, Jun Wang, Gerasimos Lampouras</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SELAUR: Self Evolving LLM Agent via Uncertainty-aware Rewards</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.21158</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.21158v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are increasingly deployed as multi-step decision-making agents, where effective reward design is essential for guiding learning. Although recent work explores various forms of reward shaping and step-level credit assignment, a key signal remains largely overlooked: the intrinsic uncertainty of LLMs. Uncertainty reflects model confidence, reveals where exploration is needed, and offers valuable learning cues even in failed trajectories. We introduce SELAUR: Self Evolving LLM Agent via Uncertainty-aware Rewards, a reinforcement learning framework that incorporates uncertainty directly into the reward design. SELAUR integrates entropy-, least-confidence-, and margin-based metrics into a combined token-level uncertainty estimate, providing dense confidence-aligned supervision, and employs a failure-aware reward reshaping mechanism that injects these uncertainty signals into step- and trajectory-level rewards to improve exploration efficiency and learning stability. Experiments on two benchmarks, ALFWorld and WebShop, show that our method consistently improves success rates over strong baselines. Ablation studies further demonstrate how uncertainty signals enhance exploration and robustness.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.21158v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dengjia Zhang, Xiaoou Liu, Lu Cheng, Yaqing Wang, Kenton Murray, Hua Wei</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning from Trials and Errors: Reflective Test-Time Planning for Embodied LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.21198</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.21198v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Embodied LLMs endow robots with high-level task reasoning, but they cannot reflect on what went wrong or why, turning deployment into a sequence of independent trials where mistakes repeat rather than accumulate into experience. Drawing upon human reflective practitioners, we introduce Reflective Test-Time Planning, which integrates two modes of reflection: \textit{reflection-in-action}, where the agent uses test-time scaling to generate and score multiple candidate actions using internal reflections before execution; and \textit{reflection-on-action}, which uses test-time training to update both its internal reflection model and its action policy based on external reflections after execution. We also include retrospective reflection, allowing the agent to re-evaluate earlier decisions and perform model updates with hindsight for proper long-horizon credit assignment. Experiments on our newly-designed Long-Horizon Household benchmark and MuJoCo Cupboard Fitting benchmark show significant gains over baseline models, with ablative studies validating the complementary roles of reflection-in-action and reflection-on-action. Qualitative analyses, including real-robot trials, highlight behavioral correction through reflection.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.21198v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yining Hong, Huang Huang, Manling Li, Li Fei-Fei, Jiajun Wu, Yejin Choi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aletheia tackles FirstProof autonomously</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.21201</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.21201v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We report the performance of Aletheia (Feng et al., 2026b), a mathematics research agent powered by Gemini 3 Deep Think, on the inaugural FirstProof challenge. Within the allowed timeframe of the challenge, Aletheia autonomously solved 6 problems (2, 5, 7, 8, 9, 10) out of 10 according to majority expert assessments; we note that experts were not unanimous on Problem 8 (only). For full transparency, we explain our interpretation of FirstProof and disclose details about our experiments as well as our evaluation. Raw prompts and outputs are available at https://github.com/google-deepmind/superhuman/tree/main/aletheia.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.21201v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tony Feng, Junehyuk Jung, Sang-hyun Kim, Carlo Pagano, Sergei Gukov, Chiang-Chiang Tsai, David Woodruff, Adel Javanmard, Aryan Mokhtari, Dawsen Hwang, Yuri Chervonyi, Jonathan N. Lee, Garrett Bingham, Trieu H. Trinh, Vahab Mirrokni, Quoc V. Le, Thang Luong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Vector Index Compression in Any Modality</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.21202</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.21202v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We study efficient multi-vector retrieval for late interaction in any modality. Late interaction has emerged as a dominant paradigm for information retrieval in text, images, visual documents, and videos, but its computation and storage costs grow linearly with document length, making it costly for image-, video-, and audio-rich corpora. To address this limitation, we explore query-agnostic methods for compressing multi-vector document representations under a constant vector budget. We introduce four approaches for index compression: sequence resizing, memory tokens, hierarchical pooling, and a novel attention-guided clustering (AGC). AGC uses an attention-guided mechanism to identify the most semantically salient regions of a document as cluster centroids and to weight token aggregation. Evaluating these methods on retrieval tasks spanning text (BEIR), visual-document (ViDoRe), and video (MSR-VTT, MultiVENT 2.0), we show that attention-guided clustering consistently outperforms other parameterized compression methods (sequence resizing and memory tokens), provides greater flexibility in index size than non-parametric hierarchical clustering, and achieves competitive or improved performance compared to a full, uncompressed index. The source code is available at: github.com/hanxiangqin/omni-col-press.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.21202v1</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hanxiang Qin, Alexander Martin, Rohan Jha, Chunsheng Zuo, Reno Kriz, Benjamin Van Durme</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Augmenting Lateral Thinking in Language Models with Humor and Riddle Data for the BRAINTEASER Task</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.10385</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.10385v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The SemEval 2024 BRAINTEASER task challenges language models to perform lateral thinking -- a form of creative, non-linear reasoning that remains underexplored in NLP. The task comprises two subtasks, Sentence Puzzle and Word Puzzle, requiring models to defy conventional commonsense associations. We present a system that fine-tunes DeBERTaV3 using HuggingFace's AutoModelForMultipleChoice architecture. We augment the provided training data with two additional sources: (1) a humor-style question-answering dataset generated via GPT-4 prompting, and (2) the RiddleSense dataset. This data augmentation strategy is motivated by the observation that humor and riddles share the lateral reasoning structure required by the task. Our best system achieves 92.5\% overall accuracy on the Sentence Puzzle subtask and 80.2\% on the Word Puzzle subtask, ranking 6th out of 31 teams and 10th out of 23 teams, respectively. We further show that the choice of task formulation matters: framing the problem as multiple-choice rather than sequence classification yields a 10-point accuracy improvement with the same base model. Our analysis reveals that data augmentation with humor and riddle data is particularly effective for sentence-level lateral reasoning, while word-level puzzles remain a harder challenge.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.10385v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Proceedings of the 18th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation (SemEval-2024)</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Mina Ghashami, Soumya Smruti Mishra</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SEFL: A Framework for Generating Synthetic Educational Assignment Feedback with LLM Agents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.12927</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.12927v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Providing high-quality feedback on student assignments is crucial for student success, but it is heavily limited by time and budgetary constraints. In this work, we introduce Synthetic Educational Feedback Loops (SEFL), a synthetic data framework designed to generate data that resembles immediate, on-demand feedback at scale without relying on extensive, real-world student assignments and teacher feedback. To obtain this type of data, two large language models (LLMs) operate in a teacher-student role to simulate assignment completion and formative feedback, generating 19.8K synthetic pairs of student work and corresponding critiques and actionable improvements from a teacher. With this data, we fine-tune smaller, more computationally efficient LLMs on these synthetic pairs, enabling them to replicate key features of high-quality, goal-oriented feedback. Through comprehensive evaluations with three LLM judges and three human experts, across a subset of 900 outputs, we demonstrate that SEFL-tuned models outperform both their untuned counterparts and an existing baseline in terms of feedback quality. The potential for societal impact is reinforced by extensive qualitative comments and ratings from human stakeholders -- both students and higher education instructors. SEFL has the potential to transform feedback processes for higher education and beyond.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.12927v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mike Zhang, Amalie Pernille Dilling, L\'eon Gondelman, Niels Erik Ruan Lyngdorf, Euan D. Lindsay, Johannes Bjerva</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging Gaps in Natural Language Processing for Yor\`ub\'a: A Systematic Review of a Decade of Progress and Prospects</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.17364</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.17364v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Natural Language Processing (NLP) is becoming a dominant subset of artificial intelligence as the need to help machines understand human language looks indispensable. Several NLP applications are ubiquitous, partly due to the myriad of datasets being churned out daily through mediums like social networking sites. However, the growing development has not been evident in most African languages due to the persisting resource limitations, among other issues. Yor\`ub\'a language, a tonal and morphologically rich African language, suffers a similar fate, resulting in limited NLP usage. To encourage further research towards improving this situation, this systematic literature review aims to comprehensively analyse studies addressing NLP development for Yor\`ub\'a, identifying challenges, resources, techniques, and applications. A well-defined search string from a structured protocol was employed to search, select, and analyse 105 primary studies between 2014 and 2024 from reputable databases. The review highlights the scarcity of annotated corpora, the limited availability of pre-trained language models, and linguistic challenges like tonal complexity and diacritic dependency as significant obstacles. It also revealed the prominent techniques, including rule-based methods, among others. The findings reveal a growing body of multilingual and monolingual resources, even though the field is constrained by socio-cultural factors such as code-switching and the desertion of language for digital usage. This review synthesises existing research, providing a foundation for advancing NLP for Yor\`ub\'a and in African languages generally. It aims to guide future research by identifying gaps and opportunities, thereby contributing to the broader inclusion of Yor\`ub\'a and other under-resourced African languages in global NLP advancements.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.17364v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1016/j.nlp.2025.100194</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Natural Language Processing Journal, 13 (2025), 100194</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Toheeb Aduramomi Jimoh, Tabea De Wille, Nikola S. Nikolov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EAMET: Robust Massive Model Editing via Embedding Alignment Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.11876</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.11876v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Model editing techniques are essential for efficiently updating knowledge in large language models (LLMs). However, the effectiveness of existing approaches degrades in massive editing scenarios, particularly when evaluated with practical metrics. Their robustness is also limited in context-rich settings or when editing multiple facts of the same subject simultaneously. We attribute these failures to the embedding misalignment among knowledge items, which undermines editing reliability at scale. To address this, we propose EAMET (Embedding Alignment Model Editing in Transformers), which addresses this issue by aligning the space of key and residual embeddings. Extensive experiments across six LLMs and three datasets demonstrate that EAMET consistently outperforms existing methods, achieving about 90\% editing efficacy when editing 10k facts. Codes and datasets are publicly available at https://ybdai7.github.io/eamet-page/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.11876v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yanbo Dai, Zhenlan Ji, Zongjie Li, Shuai Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Language Models use Lookbacks to Track Beliefs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.14685</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.14685v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: How do language models (LMs) represent characters' beliefs, especially when those beliefs may differ from reality? This question lies at the heart of understanding the Theory of Mind (ToM) capabilities of LMs. We analyze LMs' ability to reason about characters' beliefs using causal mediation and abstraction. We construct a dataset, CausalToM, consisting of simple stories where two characters independently change the state of two objects, potentially unaware of each other's actions. Our investigation uncovers a pervasive algorithmic pattern that we call a lookback mechanism, which enables the LM to recall important information when it becomes necessary. The LM binds each character-object-state triple together by co-locating their reference information, represented as Ordering IDs (OIs), in low-rank subspaces of the state token's residual stream. When asked about a character's beliefs regarding the state of an object, the binding lookback retrieves the correct state OI and then the answer lookback retrieves the corresponding state token. When we introduce text specifying that one character is (not) visible to the other, we find that the LM first generates a visibility ID encoding the relation between the observing and the observed character OIs. In a visibility lookback, this ID is used to retrieve information about the observed character and update the observing character's beliefs. Our work provides insights into belief tracking mechanisms, taking a step toward reverse-engineering ToM reasoning in LMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.14685v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nikhil Prakash, Natalie Shapira, Arnab Sen Sharma, Christoph Riedl, Yonatan Belinkov, Tamar Rott Shaham, David Bau, Atticus Geiger</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HSSBench: Benchmarking Humanities and Social Sciences Ability for Multimodal Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.03922</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.03922v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) have demonstrated significant potential to advance a broad range of domains. However, current benchmarks for evaluating MLLMs primarily emphasize general knowledge and vertical step-by-step reasoning typical of STEM disciplines, while overlooking the distinct needs and potential of the Humanities and Social Sciences (HSS). Tasks in the HSS domain require more horizontal, interdisciplinary thinking and a deep integration of knowledge across related fields, which presents unique challenges for MLLMs, particularly in linking abstract concepts with corresponding visual representations. Addressing this gap, we present HSSBench, a dedicated benchmark designed to assess the capabilities of MLLMs on HSS tasks in multiple languages, including the six official languages of the United Nations. We also introduce a novel data generation pipeline tailored for HSS scenarios, in which multiple domain experts and automated agents collaborate to generate and iteratively refine each sample. HSSBench contains over 13,000 meticulously designed samples, covering six key categories. We benchmark more than 20 mainstream MLLMs on HSSBench and demonstrate that it poses significant challenges even for state-of-the-art models. We hope that this benchmark will inspire further research into enhancing the cross-disciplinary reasoning abilities of MLLMs, especially their capacity to internalize and connect knowledge across fields.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.03922v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhaolu Kang, Junhao Gong, Jiaxu Yan, Wanke Xia, Yian Wang, Ziwen Wang, Huaxuan Ding, Zhuo Cheng, Wenhao Cao, Zhiyuan Feng, Siqi He, Shannan Yan, Junzhe Chen, Xiaomin He, Chaoya Jiang, Wei Ye, Kaidong Yu, Xuelong Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Watermarking Degrades Alignment in Language Models: Analysis and Mitigation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.04462</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.04462v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Watermarking has become a practical tool for tracing language model outputs, but it modifies token probabilities at inference time, which were carefully tuned by alignment training. This creates a tension: how do watermark-induced shifts interact with the procedures intended to make models safe and useful? Experiments on several contemporary models and two representative watermarking schemes reveal that watermarking induces a nontrivial, patterned yet model-specific shift in alignment. We see two failure modes: guard attenuation, where models become more helpful but less safe, and guard amplification, where refusals become overly conservative. These effects persist even after controlling for perplexity degradation, pointing to alignment-specific distortions, not just quality loss. We address this with Alignment Resampling (AR), a procedure that samples multiple watermarked outputs and selects the most aligned response according to an external reward model. Using standard results on the expected maximum of Gaussian random variables, we derive a theoretical lower bound showing that alignment gains grow sublogarithmically with sample size. In practice, sampling as few as two to four candidates largely restores unwatermarked alignment performance in truthfulness, safety, and helpfulness, without hurting watermark detection. This is the first empirical study of watermarking-alignment interactions; it shows that a simple inference-time fix can recover alignment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.04462v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Transactions of Machine Learning Research 02/2026</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Apurv Verma, NhatHai Phan, Shubhendu Trivedi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should We Still Pretrain Encoders with Masked Language Modeling?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.00994</link>
      <description>arXiv:2507.00994v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Learning high-quality text representations is fundamental to a wide range of NLP tasks. While encoder pretraining has traditionally relied on Masked Language Modeling (MLM), recent evidence suggests that decoder models pretrained with Causal Language Modeling (CLM) can be effectively repurposed as encoders, often surpassing traditional encoders on text representation benchmarks. However, it remains unclear whether these gains reflect an inherent advantage of the CLM objective or arise from confounding factors such as model and data scale. In this paper, we address this question through a series of large-scale, carefully controlled pretraining ablations, training a total of 38 models ranging from 210 million to 1 billion parameters, and conducting over 15,000 fine-tuning and evaluation runs. We find that while training with MLM generally yields better performance across text representation tasks, CLM-trained models are more data-efficient and demonstrate improved fine-tuning stability. Building on these findings, we experimentally show that a biphasic training strategy that sequentially applies CLM and then MLM, achieves optimal performance under a fixed computational training budget. Moreover, we demonstrate that this strategy becomes more appealing when initializing from readily available pretrained CLM models, reducing the computational burden needed to train best-in-class encoder models. We release all project artifacts at https://hf.co/MLMvsCLM to foster further research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2507.00994v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hippolyte Gisserot-Boukhlef, Nicolas Boizard, Manuel Faysse, Duarte M. Alves, Emmanuel Malherbe, Andr\'e F. T. Martins, C\'eline Hudelot, Pierre Colombo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>K-Function: Joint Pronunciation Transcription and Feedback for Evaluating Kids Language Function</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.03043</link>
      <description>arXiv:2507.03043v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Evaluating young children's language is challenging for automatic speech recognizers due to high-pitched voices, prolonged sounds, and limited data. We introduce K-Function, a framework that combines accurate sub-word transcription with objective, Large Language Model (LLM)-driven scoring. Its core, Kids-Weighted Finite State Transducer (K-WFST), merges an acoustic phoneme encoder with a phoneme-similarity model to capture child-specific speech errors while remaining fully interpretable. K-WFST achieves a 1.39 % phoneme error rate on MyST and 8.61 % on Multitudes-an absolute improvement of 10.47 % and 7.06 % over a greedy-search decoder. These high-quality transcripts are used by an LLM to grade verbal skills, developmental milestones, reading, and comprehension, with results that align closely with human evaluators. Our findings show that precise phoneme recognition is essential for creating an effective assessment framework, enabling scalable language screening for children.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2507.03043v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shuhe Li, Chenxu Guo, Jiachen Lian, Cheol Jun Cho, Wenshuo Zhao, Xiner Xu, Ruiyu Jin, Xiaoyu Shi, Xuanru Zhou, Dingkun Zhou, Sam Wang, Grace Wang, Jingze Yang, Jingyi Xu, Ruohan Bao, Xingrui Chen, Elise Brenner, Brandon In, Francesca Pei, Maria Luisa Gorno-Tempini, Gopala Anumanchipalli</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RooseBERT: A New Deal For Political Language Modelling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.03250</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.03250v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The increasing amount of political debates and politics-related discussions calls for the definition of novel computational methods to automatically analyse such content with the final goal of lightening up political deliberation to citizens. However, the specificity of the political language and the argumentative form of these debates (employing hidden communication strategies and leveraging implicit arguments) make this task very challenging, even for current general-purpose pre-trained Language Models (LMs). To address this, we introduce a novel pre-trained LM for political discourse language called RooseBERT. Pre-training a LM on a specialised domain presents different technical and linguistic challenges, requiring extensive computational resources and large-scale data. RooseBERT has been trained on large political debate and speech corpora (11GB) in English. To evaluate its performances, we fine-tuned it on multiple downstream tasks related to political debate analysis, i.e., stance detection, sentiment analysis, argument component detection and classification, argument relation prediction and classification, policy classification, named entity recognition (NER). Our results show significant improvements over general-purpose LMs on the majority of these tasks, highlighting how domain-specific pre-training enhances performance in political debate analysis. We release RooseBERT for the research community.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.03250v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Deborah Dore, Elena Cabrio, Serena Villata</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ATTS: Asynchronous Test-Time Scaling via Conformal Prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.15148</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.15148v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) benefit from test-time scaling but are often hampered by high inference latency. Speculative decoding is a natural way to accelerate the scaling process; however, scaling along both the parallel and sequential dimensions poses significant challenges, including substantial memory-bound execution and synchronization overhead. We introduce ATTS (Asynchronous Test-Time Scaling), a statistically guaranteed adaptive scaling framework that follows the hypothesis testing process to address these challenges. By revisiting arithmetic intensity, ATTS identifies synchronization as the primary bottleneck. It enables asynchronous inference through online calibration and proposes an ordinal classification algorithm that supports a three-stage rejection sampling pipeline, scaling along both the sequential and parallel axes. Across experiments on the MATH, AMC23, AIME24, and AIME25 datasets and across multiple draft-target model families, we show that ATTS delivers up to 56.7x speedup in test-time scaling and a 4.14x throughput improvement, while maintaining accurate control of the rejection rate, reducing latency and memory overhead, and incurring no accuracy loss. By scaling both in parallel and sequential dimensions, we enable the 1.5B/70B draft/target model combination to achieve the performance of the state-of-the-art reasoning model o3-mini (high) on the AIME dataset. We have released the code at https://github.com/menik1126/asynchronous-test-time-scaling.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.15148v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jing Xiong, Qiujiang Chen, Fanghua Ye, Zhongwei Wan, Chuanyang Zheng, Chenyang Zhao, Hui Shen, Hanbo Li, Chaofan Tao, Haochen Tan, Haoli Bai, Lifeng Shang, Lingpeng Kong, Ngai Wong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LD-MoLE: Learnable Dynamic Routing for Mixture of LoRA Experts</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.25684</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.25684v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent studies have shown that combining parameter-efficient fine-tuning (PEFT) with mixture-of-experts (MoE) is an effective strategy for adapting large language models (LLMs) to the downstream tasks. However, most existing approaches rely on conventional TopK routing, which requires careful hyperparameter tuning and assigns a fixed number of experts to each token. In this work, we propose LD-MoLE, a Learnable Dynamic routing mechanism for Mixture of LoRA Experts that enables adaptive, token-dependent, and layer-wise expert allocation. Our method replaces the non-differentiable TopK selection with a differentiable routing function and a closed-form solution. Moreover, our design allows the model to adaptively determine the number of experts to activate for each token at different layers. In addition, we introduce an analytical sparsity control objective to regularize the number of activated experts. Extensive experiments on the Qwen3-1.7B and Llama-3.2-3B models show that LD-MoLE achieves the highest average scores compared to state-of-the-art baselines, across a diverse set of benchmarks. Our method not only achieves superior performance, but also demonstrates the ability to learn token-dependent and layer-wise expert allocation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.25684v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuan Zhuang, Yi Shen, Yuexin Bian, Qing Su, Shihao Ji, Yuanyuan Shi, Fei Miao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Latent Thinking Optimization: Your Latent Reasoning Language Model Secretly Encodes Reward Signals in Its Latent Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.26314</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.26314v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) excel at problem solving by generating chain of thoughts in natural language, but such verbal thinking is computationally costly and prone to overthinking. A recent work instead proposes a latent thinking architecture, Huginn-3.5B, which represents intermediate reasoning steps as a sequence of latent representations. However, latent thoughts lack interpretability and are difficult to supervise, raising concerns about the correctness and reliability of the model's latent thinking processes. In this paper, we provide a systematic study of how Huginn-3.5B thinks in the latent space and how external supervision signals can improve its latent thinking processes. We show that latent thoughts leading to correct versus incorrect answers exhibit highly distinguishable patterns, and that a latent classifier can reliably predict answer correctness directly from latent thoughts. Leveraging these insights, we propose Latent Thinking Optimization (LTO), a probabilistic algorithm that employs the latent classifier as a Latent Reward Model (LRM) to optimize the latent thinking processes. Extensive experiments across diverse reasoning tasks demonstrate that LRM is highly effective in detecting incorrect latent thinking patterns, and LTO can significantly improve the latent thinking processes. Furthermore, we show that LRM can generalize across diverse domains, and LTO can be seamlessly applied to general LLMs to improve their thinking processes. In contrast to verbal thinking, our method demonstrates that reward modeling and scaling test-time thinking with supervision can be performed directly in the latent space, highlighting its potential as a general, efficient, and domain-agnostic approach to improving the thinking processes of LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.26314v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hanwen Du, Yuxin Dong, Xia Ning</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everything is Plausible: Investigating the Impact of LLM Rationales on Human Notions of Plausibility</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.08091</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.08091v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We investigate the degree to which human plausibility judgments of multiple-choice commonsense benchmark answers are subject to influence by (im)plausibility arguments for or against an answer, in particular, using rationales generated by LLMs. We collect 3,000 plausibility judgments from humans and another 13,600 judgments from LLMs. Overall, we observe increases and decreases in mean human plausibility ratings in the presence of LLM-generated PRO and CON rationales, respectively, suggesting that, on the whole, human judges find these rationales convincing. Experiments with LLMs reveal similar patterns of influence. Our findings demonstrate a novel use of LLMs for studying aspects of human cognition, while also raising practical concerns that, even in domains where humans are ``experts'' (i.e., common sense), LLMs have the potential to exert considerable influence on people's beliefs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.08091v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shramay Palta, Peter Rankel, Sarah Wiegreffe, Rachel Rudinger</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Ability of LLMs to Handle Character-Level Perturbation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.14365</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.14365v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This work investigates the resilience of contemporary large language models (LLMs) against frequent character-level perturbations. We examine three types of character-level perturbations including introducing numerous typos within words, shuffling the characters in each word, and inserting a large number of invisible characters into the text. Surprisingly, even under severe perturbation, such as shuffling nearly all words character-wise to produce text that is almost unreadable to humans, or inserting invisible characters which are several times more than the visible ones as noise, many LLMs still maintain notable performance. We explore the underlying causes of this robustness and find that LLMs exhibit remarkable resilience to chaotic segmentation and fragmented tokenization. Furthermore, we examine the mechanisms by which LLMs remove perturbations to correctly comprehend text, including both implicit and explicit mechanisms for character-level perturbation. We hope that our findings on the low-level robustness of LLMs will unveil their inherent architectural strengths, reveal the potential risks of their misuse, and inform the reliable deployment of LLMs across diverse application scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.14365v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Anyuan Zhuo, Xuefei Ning, Ningyuan Li, Jingyi Zhu, Yu Wang, Pinyan Lu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LUMI: Unsupervised Intent Clustering with Multiple Pseudo-Labels</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.14640</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.14640v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this paper, we propose an intuitive, training-free and label-free method for intent clustering in conversational search. Current approaches to short text clustering use LLM-generated pseudo-labels to enrich text representations or to identify similar text pairs for pooling. The limitations are: (1) each text is assigned only a single label, and refining representations toward a single label can be unstable; (2) text-level similarity is treated as a binary selection, which fails to account for continuous degrees of similarity. Our method LUMI is designed to amplify similarities between texts by using shared pseudo-labels. We first generate pseudo-labels for each text and collect them into a pseudo-label set. Next, we compute the mean of the pseudo-label embeddings and pool it with the text embedding. Finally, we perform text-level pooling: Each text representation is pooled with its similar pairs, where similarity is determined by the degree of shared labels. Our evaluation on four benchmark sets shows that our approach achieves competitive results, better than recent state-of-the-art baselines, while avoiding the need to estimate the number of clusters during embedding refinement, as is required by most methods. Our findings indicate that LUMI can effectively be applied in unsupervised short-text clustering scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.14640v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>I-Fan Lin, Faegheh Hasibi, Suzan Verberne</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Repurposing Synthetic Data for Fine-grained Search Agent Supervision</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.24694</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.24694v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: LLM-based search agents are increasingly trained on entity-centric synthetic data to solve complex, knowledge-intensive tasks. However, prevailing training methods like Group Relative Policy Optimization (GRPO) discard this rich entity information, relying instead on sparse, outcome-based rewards. This critical limitation renders them unable to distinguish informative "near-miss" samples-those with substantially correct reasoning but a flawed final answer-from complete failures, thus discarding valuable learning signals. We address this by leveraging the very entities discarded during training. Our empirical analysis reveals a strong positive correlation between the number of ground-truth entities identified during an agent's reasoning process and final answer accuracy. Building on this insight, we introduce Entity-aware Group Relative Policy Optimization (E-GRPO), a novel framework that formulates a dense entity-aware reward function. E-GRPO assigns partial rewards to incorrect samples proportional to their entity match rate, enabling the model to effectively learn from these "near-misses". Experiments on diverse question-answering (QA) and deep research benchmarks show that E-GRPO consistently and significantly outperforms the GRPO baseline. Furthermore, our analysis reveals that E-GRPO not only achieves superior accuracy but also induces more efficient reasoning policies that require fewer tool calls, demonstrating a more effective and sample-efficient approach to aligning search agents.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.24694v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yida Zhao, Kuan Li, Xixi Wu, Liwen Zhang, Dingchu Zhang, Baixuan Li, Maojia Song, Zhuo Chen, Chenxi Wang, Xinyu Wang, Kewei Tu, Pengjun Xie, Jingren Zhou, Yong Jiang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OckBench: Measuring the Efficiency of LLM Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.05722</link>
      <description>arXiv:2511.05722v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) such as GPT-5 and Gemini 3 have pushed the frontier of automated reasoning and code generation. Yet current benchmarks emphasize accuracy and output quality, neglecting a critical dimension: efficiency of token usage. The token efficiency is highly variable in practical. Models solving the same problem with similar accuracy can exhibit up to a \textbf{5.0$\times$} difference in token length, leading to massive gap of model reasoning ability. Such variance exposes significant redundancy, highlighting the critical need for a standardized benchmark to quantify the gap of token efficiency. Thus, we introduce OckBench, the first benchmark that jointly measures accuracy and token efficiency across reasoning and coding tasks. Our evaluation reveals that token efficiency remains largely unoptimized across current models, significantly inflating serving costs and latency. These findings provide a concrete roadmap for the community to optimize the latent reasoning ability, token efficiency. Ultimately, we argue for an evaluation paradigm shift: tokens must not be multiplied beyond necessity. Our benchmarks are available at https://ockbench.github.io/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2511.05722v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zheng Du, Hao Kang, Song Han, Tushar Krishna, Ligeng Zhu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Refusal Steering: Fine-grained Control over LLM Refusal Behaviour for Sensitive Topics</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.16602</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.16602v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We introduce Refusal Steering, an inference-time method to exercise fine-grained control over Large Language Models refusal behaviour on politically sensitive topics without retraining. We replace fragile pattern-based refusal detection with an LLM-as-a-judge that assigns refusal confidence scores and we propose a ridge-regularized variant to compute steering vectors that better isolate the refusal--compliance direction. On Qwen3-Next-80B-A3B-Thinking, our method removes the refusal behaviour of the model around politically sensitive topics while maintaining safety on JailbreakBench and near-baseline performance on general benchmarks. The approach generalizes across 4B and 80B models and can also induce targeted refusals when desired. We analize the steering vectors and show that refusal signals concentrate in deeper layers of the transformer and are distributed across many dimensions. Together, these results demonstrate that activation steering can remove political refusal behaviour while retaining safety alignment for harmful content, offering a practical path to controllable, transparent moderation at inference time.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.16602v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>LREC 2026</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Iker Garc\'ia-Ferrero, David Montero, Roman Orus</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Efficient Agents: A Co-Design of Inference Architecture and System</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.18337</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.18337v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The rapid development of large language model (LLM)-based agents has unlocked new possibilities for autonomous multi-turn reasoning and tool-augmented decision-making. However, their real-world deployment is hindered by severe inefficiencies that arise not from isolated model inference, but from the systemic latency accumulated across reasoning loops, context growth, and heterogeneous tool interactions. This paper presents AgentInfer, a unified framework for end-to-end agent acceleration that bridges inference optimization and architectural design. We decompose the problem into four synergistic components: AgentCollab, a hierarchical dual-model reasoning framework that balances large- and small-model usage through dynamic role assignment; AgentSched, a cache-aware hybrid scheduler that minimizes latency under heterogeneous request patterns; AgentSAM, a suffix-automaton-based speculative decoding method that reuses multi-session semantic memory to achieve low-overhead inference acceleration; and AgentCompress, a semantic compression mechanism that asynchronously distills and reorganizes agent memory without disrupting ongoing reasoning. Together, these modules form a Self-Evolution Engine capable of sustaining efficiency and cognitive stability throughout long-horizon reasoning tasks. Experiments on the BrowseComp-zh and DeepDiver benchmarks demonstrate that through the synergistic collaboration of these methods, AgentInfer reduces ineffective token consumption by over 50%, achieving an overall 1.8-2.5 times speedup with preserved accuracy. These results underscore that optimizing for agentic task completion-rather than merely per-token throughput-is the key to building scalable, efficient, and self-improving intelligent systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.18337v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weizhe Lin, Hui-Ling Zhen, Shuai Yang, Xian Wang, Renxi Liu, Hanting Chen, Wangze Zhang, Chuansai Zhou, Yiming Li, Chen Chen, Xing Li, Zhiyuan Yang, Xiaosong Li, Xianzhi Yu, Zhenhua Dong, Mingxuan Yuan, Yunhe Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coupling Experts and Routers in Mixture-of-Experts via an Auxiliary Loss</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.23447</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.23447v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Mixture-of-Experts (MoE) models lack explicit constraints to ensure the router's decisions align well with the experts' capabilities, which ultimately limits model performance. To address this, we propose expert-router coupling (ERC) loss, a lightweight auxiliary loss that tightly couples the router's decisions with expert capabilities. Our approach treats each expert's router embedding as a proxy token for the tokens assigned to that expert, and feeds perturbed router embeddings through the experts to obtain intermediate activations. The ERC loss enforces two constraints on these activations: (1) Each expert must exhibit higher activation for its own proxy token than for the proxy tokens of any other expert. (2) Each proxy token must elicit stronger activation from its corresponding expert than from any other expert. These constraints jointly ensure that each router embedding faithfully represents its corresponding expert's capability, while each expert specializes in processing the tokens actually routed to it. The ERC loss is computationally efficient, operating only on $n^2$ activations, where $n$ is the number of experts. This represents a fixed cost independent of batch size, unlike prior coupling methods that scale with the number of tokens (often millions per batch). Through pre-training MoE-LLMs ranging from 3B to 15B parameters and extensive analysis on trillions of tokens, we demonstrate the effectiveness of the ERC loss. Moreover, the ERC loss offers flexible control and quantitative tracking of expert specialization levels during training, providing valuable insights into MoEs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.23447v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ang Lv, Jin Ma, Yiyuan Ma, Siyuan Qiao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Matters For Safety Alignment?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03868</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03868v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper presents a comprehensive empirical study on the safety alignment capabilities. We evaluate what matters for safety alignment in LLMs and LRMs to provide essential insights for developing more secure and reliable AI systems. We systematically investigate and compare the influence of six critical intrinsic model characteristics and three external attack techniques. Our large-scale evaluation is conducted using 32 recent, popular LLMs and LRMs across thirteen distinct model families, spanning a parameter scale from 3B to 235B. The assessment leverages five established safety datasets and probes model vulnerabilities with 56 jailbreak techniques and four CoT attack strategies, resulting in 4.6M API calls. Our key empirical findings are fourfold. First, we identify the LRMs GPT-OSS-20B, Qwen3-Next-80B-A3B-Thinking, and GPT-OSS-120B as the top-three safest models, which substantiates the significant advantage of integrated reasoning and self-reflection mechanisms for robust safety alignment. Second, post-training and knowledge distillation may lead to a systematic degradation of safety alignment. We thus argue that safety must be treated as an explicit constraint or a core optimization objective during these stages, not merely subordinated to the pursuit of general capability. Third, we reveal a pronounced vulnerability: employing a CoT attack via a response prefix can elevate the attack success rate by 3.34x on average and from 0.6% to 96.3% for Seed-OSS-36B-Instruct. This critical finding underscores the safety risks inherent in text-completion interfaces and features that allow user-defined response prefixes in LLM services, highlighting an urgent need for architectural and deployment safeguards. Fourth, roleplay, prompt injection, and gradient-based search for adversarial prompts are the predominant methodologies for eliciting unaligned behaviors in modern models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03868v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xing Li, Hui-Ling Zhen, Lihao Yin, Xianzhi Yu, Zhenhua Dong, Mingxuan Yuan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Parallel Cross-Lingual Benchmark for Multimodal Idiomaticity Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.08645</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.08645v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Potentially idiomatic expressions (PIEs) construe meanings inherently tied to the everyday experience of a given language community. As such, they constitute an interesting challenge for assessing the linguistic (and to some extent cultural) capabilities of NLP systems. In this paper, we present XMPIE, a parallel multilingual and multimodal dataset of potentially idiomatic expressions. The dataset, containing 34 languages and over ten thousand items, allows comparative analyses of idiomatic patterns among language-specific realisations and preferences in order to gather insights about shared cultural aspects. This parallel dataset allows to evaluate model performance for a given PIE in different languages and whether idiomatic understanding in one language can be transferred to another. Moreover, the dataset supports the study of PIEs across textual and visual modalities, to measure to what extent PIE understanding in one modality transfers or implies in understanding in another modality (text vs. image). The data was created by language experts, with both textual and visual components crafted under multilingual guidelines, and each PIE is accompanied by five images representing a spectrum from idiomatic to literal meanings, including semantically related and random distractors. The result is a high-quality benchmark for evaluating multilingual and multimodal idiomatic language understanding.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.08645v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dilara Toruno\u{g}lu-Selamet, Dogukan Arslan, Rodrigo Wilkens, Wei He, Doruk Eryi\u{g}it, Thomas Pickard, Adriana S. Pagano, Aline Villavicencio, G\"ul\c{s}en Eryi\u{g}it, \'Agnes Abuczki, Aida Cardoso, Alesia Lazarenka, Dina Almassova, Amalia Mendes, Anna Kanellopoulou, Antoni Brosa-Rodr\'iguez, Baiba Saulite, Beata Wojtowicz, Bolette Pedersen, Carlos Manuel Hidalgo-Ternero, Chaya Liebeskind, Danka Joki\'c, Diego Alves, Eleni Triantafyllidi, Erik Velldal, Fred Philippy, Giedre Valunaite Oleskeviciene, Ieva Rizgeliene, Inguna Skadina, Irina Lobzhanidze, Isabell Stinessen Haugen, Jauza Akbar Krito, Jelena M. Markovi\'c, Johanna Monti, Josue Alejandro Sauca, Kaja Dobrovoljc, Kingsley O. Ugwuanyi, Laura Rituma, Lilja {\O}vrelid, Maha Tufail Agro, Manzura Abjalova, Maria Chatzigrigoriou, Mar\'ia del Mar S\'anchez Ramos, Marija Pendevska, Masoumeh Seyyedrezaei, Mehrnoush Shamsfard, Momina Ahsan, Muhammad Ahsan Riaz Khan, Nathalie Carmen Hau Norman, Nilay Erdem Ayy{\i}ld{\i}z, Nina Hosseini-Kivanani, No\'emi Ligeti-Nagy, Numaan Naeem, Olha Kanishcheva, Olha Yatsyshyna, Daniil Orel, Petra Giommarelli, Petya Osenova, Radovan Garabik, Regina E. Semou, Rozane Rebechi, Salsabila Zahirah Pranida, Samia Touileb, Sanni Nimb, Sarfraz Ahmad, Sarvinoz Sharipova, Shahar Golan, Shaoxiong Ji, Sopuruchi Christian Aboh, Srdjan Sucur, Stella Markantonatou, Sussi Olsen, Vahide Tajalli, Veronika Lipp, Voula Giouli, Yelda Ye\c{s}ildal Erayd{\i}n, Zahra Saaberi, Zhuohan Xie</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FROST: Filtering Reasoning Outliers with Attention for Efficient Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.19001</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.19001v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We propose FROST, an attention-aware method for efficient reasoning. Unlike traditional approaches, FROST leverages attention weights to prune uncritical reasoning paths, yielding shorter and more reliable reasoning trajectories. Methodologically, we introduce the concept of reasoning outliers and design an attention-based mechanism to remove them. Theoretically, FROST preserves and enhances the model's reasoning capacity while eliminating outliers at the sentence level. Empirically, we validate FROST on four benchmarks using two strong reasoning models (Phi-4-Reasoning and GPT-OSS-20B), outperforming state-of-the-art methods such as TALE and ThinkLess. Notably, FROST achieves an average 69.68% reduction in token usage and a 26.70% improvement in accuracy over the base model. Furthermore, in evaluations of attention outlier metrics, FROST reduces the maximum infinity norm by 15.97% and the average kurtosis by 91.09% compared to the base model. Code is available at https://github.com/robinzixuan/FROST</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.19001v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haozheng Luo, Zhuolin Jiang, Md Zahid Hasan, Yan Chen, Soumalya Sarkar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What If We Allocate Test-Time Compute Adaptively?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.01070</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.01070v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Test-time compute scaling allocates inference computation uniformly, uses fixed sampling strategies, and applies verification only for reranking. In contrast, we propose a verifier-guided adaptive framework treating reasoning as iterative trajectory generation and selection. For each problem, the agent runs multiple inference iterations. In each iteration, it optionally produces a high-level plan, selects a set of reasoning tools and a compute strategy together with an exploration parameter, and then generates a candidate reasoning trajectory. A process reward model (PRM) serves as a unified control signal: within each iteration, step-level PRM scores are aggregated to guide pruning and expansion during generation, and across iterations, aggregated trajectory rewards are used to select the final response. Across datasets, our dynamic, PRM-guided approach consistently outperforms direct test-time scaling, yielding large gains on MATH-500 and several-fold improvements on harder benchmarks such as AIME24 and AMO-Bench. We characterize efficiency using theoretical FLOPs and a compute intensity metric penalizing wasted generation and tool overhead, demonstrating that verification-guided allocation concentrates computation on high-utility reasoning paths.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.01070v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ahsan Bilal, Ahmed Mohsin, Muhammad Umer, Ali Subhan, Hassan Rizwan, Ayesha Mohsin, Dean Hougen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Single-Multi Evolution Loop for Self-Improving Model Collaboration Systems</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05182</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.05182v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Model collaboration -- systems where multiple language models (LMs) collaborate -- combines the strengths of diverse models with cost in loading multiple LMs. We improve efficiency while preserving the strengths of collaboration by distilling collaborative patterns into a single model, where the model is trained on the outputs of the model collaboration system. At inference time, only the distilled model is employed: it imitates the collaboration while only incurring the cost of a single model. Furthermore, we propose the single-multi evolution loop: multiple LMs collaborate, each distills from the collaborative outputs, and these post-distillation improved LMs collaborate again, forming a collective evolution ecosystem where models evolve and self-improve by interacting with an environment of other models. Extensive experiments with 7 collaboration strategies and 15 tasks (QA, reasoning, factuality, etc.) demonstrate that: 1) individual models improve by 8.0% on average, absorbing the strengths of collaboration while reducing the cost to a single model; 2) the collaboration also benefits from the stronger and more synergistic LMs after distillation, improving over initial systems without evolution by 14.9% on average. Analysis reveals that the single-multi evolution loop outperforms various existing evolutionary AI methods, is compatible with diverse model/collaboration/distillation settings, and helps solve problems where the initial model/system struggles to.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05182v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shangbin Feng, Kishan Panaganti, Yulia Tsvetkov, Wenhao Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Language Modeling and Understanding Through Paraphrase Generation and Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.08274</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.08274v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Language enables humans to share knowledge, reason about the world, and pass on strategies for survival and innovation across generations. At the heart of this process is not just the ability to communicate but also the remarkable flexibility in how we can express ourselves. We can express the same thoughts in virtually infinite ways using different words and structures - this ability to rephrase and reformulate expressions is known as paraphrase. Modeling paraphrases is a keystone to meaning in computational language models; being able to construct different variations of texts that convey the same meaning or not shows strong abilities of semantic understanding. If computational language models are to represent meaning, they must understand and control the different aspects that construct the same meaning as opposed to different meanings at a fine granularity. Yet most existing approaches reduce paraphrasing to a binary decision between two texts or to producing a single rewrite of a source, obscuring which linguistic factors are responsible for meaning preservation. In this thesis, I propose that decomposing paraphrases into their constituent linguistic aspects (paraphrase types) offers a more fine-grained and cognitively grounded view of semantic equivalence. I show that even advanced machine learning models struggle with this task. Yet, when explicitly trained on paraphrase types, models achieve stronger performance on related paraphrase tasks and downstream applications. For example, in plagiarism detection, language models trained on paraphrase types surpass human baselines: 89.6% accuracy compared to 78.4% for plagiarism cases from Wikipedia, and 66.5% compared to 55.7% for plagiarism of scientific papers from arXiv. In identifying duplicate questions on Quora, models trained with paraphrase types improve over models trained on binary pairs. Furthermore, I demonstrate that...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.08274v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.53846/goediss-11681</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Jan Philip Wahle</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Context Shapes LLMs Retrieval-Augmented Fact-Checking Effectiveness</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.14044</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.14044v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) show strong reasoning abilities across diverse tasks, yet their performance on extended contexts remains inconsistent. While prior research has emphasized mid-context degradation in question answering, this study examines the impact of context in LLM-based fact verification. Using three datasets (HOVER, FEVEROUS, and ClimateFEVER) and five open-source models accross different parameters sizes (7B, 32B and 70B parameters) and model families (Llama-3.1, Qwen2.5 and Qwen3), we evaluate both parametric factual knowledge and the impact of evidence placement across varying context lengths. We find that LLMs exhibit non-trivial parametric knowledge of factual claims and that their verification accuracy generally declines as context length increases. Similarly to what has been shown in previous works, in-context evidence placement plays a critical role with accuracy being consistently higher when relevant evidence appears near the beginning or end of the prompt and lower when placed mid-context. These results underscore the importance of prompt structure in retrieval-augmented fact-checking systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.14044v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Pietro Bernardelle, Stefano Civelli, Kevin Roitero, Gianluca Demartini</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INSURE-Dial: A Phase-Aware Conversational Dataset &amp; Benchmark for Compliance Verification and Phase Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.18448</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.18448v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Administrative phone tasks drain roughly 1 trillion USD annually from U.S. healthcare, with over 500 million insurance-benefit verification calls manually handled in 2024. We introduce INSURE-Dial, to our knowledge the first public benchmark for developing and assessing compliance-aware voice agents for phase-aware call auditing with span-based compliance verification. The corpus includes 50 de-identified, AI-initiated calls with live insurance representatives (mean 71 turns/call) and 1,000 synthetically generated calls that mirror the same workflow. All calls are annotated with a phase-structured JSON schema covering IVR navigation, patient identification, coverage status, medication checks (up to two drugs), and agent identification (CRN), and each phase is labeled for Information and Procedural compliance under explicit ask/answer logic. We define two novel evaluation tasks: (1) Phase Boundary Detection (span segmentation under phase-specific acceptance rules) and (2) Compliance Verification (IC/PC decisions given fixed spans). Per-phase scores are strong across small, low-latency baselines, but end-to-end reliability is constrained by span-boundary errors. On real calls, full-call exact segmentation is low, showing a gap between conversational fluency and audit-grade evidence.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.18448v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shubham Kulkarni, Alexander Lyzhov, Preetam Joshi, Shiva Chaitanya</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anatomy of Unlearning: The Dual Impact of Fact Salience and Model Fine-Tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.19612</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.19612v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Machine Unlearning (MU) enables Large Language Models (LLMs) to remove unsafe or outdated information. However, existing work assumes that all facts are equally forgettable and largely ignores whether the forgotten knowledge originates from pretraining or supervised fine-tuning (SFT). In this paper, we introduce DUAL (Dual Unlearning Evaluation across Training Stages), a benchmark of 28.6k Wikidata-derived triplets annotated with fact popularity using Wikipedia link counts and LLM-based salience scores. Our experiments show that pretrained and SFT models respond differently to unlearning. An SFT step on the forget data yields smoother forgetting, more stable tuning, and 10-50% higher retention, while direct unlearning on pretrained models remains unstable and prone to relearning or catastrophic forgetting.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.19612v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Borisiuk Anna, Andrey Savchenko, Alexander Panchenko, Elena Tutubalina</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BabyLM Turns 4 and Goes Multilingual: Call for Papers for the 2026 BabyLM Workshop</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.20092</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.20092v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The goal of the BabyLM is to stimulate new research connections between cognitive modeling and language model pretraining. We invite contributions in this vein to the BabyLM Workshop, which will also include the 4th iteration of the BabyLM Challenge. As in previous years, the challenge features two ``standard'' tracks (Strict and Strict-Small), in which participants must train language models on under 100M or 10M words of data, respectively. This year, we move beyond our previous English-only pretraining datasets with a new Multilingual track, focusing on English, Dutch, and Chinese. For the workshop, we call for papers related to the overall theme of BabyLM, which includes training efficiency, small-scale training datasets, cognitive modeling, model evaluation, and architecture innovation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.20092v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Leshem Choshen, Ryan Cotterell, Mustafa Omer Gul, Jaap Jumelet, Tal Linzen, Aaron Mueller, Suchir Salhan, Raj Sanjay Shah, Alex Warstadt, Ethan Gotlieb Wilcox</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Usability Study of Security Features in Programmable Logic Controllers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2208.02500</link>
      <description>arXiv:2208.02500v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Programmable Logic Controllers (PLCs) drive industrial processes critical to society, for example, water treatment and distribution, electricity and fuel networks. Search engines, e.g., Shodan, have highlighted that PLCs are often left exposed to the Internet, one of the main reasons being the misconfigurations of security settings. This leads to the question - why do these misconfigurations occur and, specifically, whether usability of security controls plays a part. To date, the usability of configuring PLC security mechanisms has not been studied. We present the first investigation through a task based study and subsequent semi-structured interviews (N=19). We explore the usability of PLC connection configurations and two key security mechanisms (i.e., access levels and user administration). We find that the use of unfamiliar labels, layouts and misleading terminology exacerbates an already complex process of configuring security mechanisms. Our results uncover various misperceptions about the security controls and how design constraints, e.g., safety and lack of regular updates due to the long-term nature of such systems, provide significant challenges to the realization of modern HCI and usability principles. Based on these findings, we provide design recommendations to bring usable security in industrial settings at par with its IT counterpart.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2208.02500v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.SY</category>
      <category>eess.SY</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3688459.368847</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Karen Li, Kopo M. Ramokapane, Awais Rashid</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Watermarking Language Models with Error Correcting Codes</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10281</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10281v5 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Recent progress in large language models enables the creation of realistic machine-generated content. Watermarking is a promising approach to distinguish machine-generated text from human text, embedding statistical signals in the output that are ideally undetectable to humans. We propose a watermarking framework that encodes such signals through an error correcting code. Our method, termed robust binary code (RBC) watermark, introduces no noticeable degradation in quality. We evaluate our watermark on base and instruction fine-tuned models and find that our watermark is robust to edits, deletions, and translations. We provide an information-theoretic perspective on watermarking, a powerful statistical test for detection and for generating $p$-values, and theoretical guarantees. Our empirical findings suggest our watermark is fast, powerful, and robust, comparing favorably to the state-of-the-art.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10281v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Patrick Chao, Yan Sun, Edgar Dobriban, Hamed Hassani</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Causal Claims in Economics</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06873</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.06873v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: As economics scales, a key bottleneck is representing what papers claim in a comparable, aggregable form. We introduce evidence-annotated claim graphs that map each paper into a directed network of standardized economic concepts (nodes) and stated relationships (edges), with each edge labeled by evidentiary basis, including whether it is supported by causal inference designs or by non-causal evidence. Using a structured multi-stage AI workflow, we construct claim graphs for 44,852 economics papers from 1980-2023. The share of causal edges rises from 7.7% in 1990 to 31.7% in 2020. Measures of causal narrative structure and causal novelty are positively associated with top-five publication and long-run citations, whereas non-causal counterparts are weakly related or negative.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.06873v2</guid>
      <category>econ.GN</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <category>q-fin.EC</category>
      <category>stat.ME</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Prashant Garg, Thiemo Fetzer</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HoloLLM: Multisensory Foundation Model for Language-Grounded Human Sensing and Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.17645</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.17645v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Embodied agents operating in smart homes must understand human behavior through diverse sensory inputs and communicate via natural language. While Vision-Language Models (VLMs) have enabled impressive language-grounded perception, their reliance on visual data limits robustness in real-world scenarios with occlusions, poor lighting, or privacy constraints. In this paper, we introduce HoloLLM, a Multimodal Large Language Model (MLLM) that integrates uncommon but powerful sensing modalities, such as LiDAR, infrared, mmWave radar, and WiFi, to enable seamless human perception and reasoning across heterogeneous environments. We address two key challenges: (1) the scarcity of aligned modality-text data for rare sensors, and (2) the heterogeneity of their physical signal representations. To overcome these, we design a Universal Modality-Injection Projector (UMIP) that enhances pre-aligned modality embeddings with fine-grained, text-aligned features from tailored encoders via coarse-to-fine cross-attention without introducing significant alignment overhead. We further introduce a human-VLM collaborative data curation pipeline to generate paired textual annotations for sensing datasets. Extensive experiments on two newly constructed benchmarks show that HoloLLM significantly outperforms existing MLLMs, improving language-grounded human sensing accuracy by up to 30%. This work establishes a new foundation for real-world, language-informed multisensory embodied intelligence.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.17645v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chuhao Zhou, Jianfei Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICE-ID: A Novel Historical Census Dataset for Longitudinal Identity Resolution</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.13792</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.13792v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We introduce \textbf{ICE-ID}, a benchmark dataset comprising 984,028 records from 16 Icelandic census waves spanning 220 years (1703--1920), with 226,864 expert-curated person identifiers. ICE-ID combines hierarchical geography (farm$\to$parish$\to$district$\to$county), patronymic naming conventions, sparse kinship links (partner, father, mother), and multi-decadal temporal drift -- challenges not captured by standard product-matching or citation datasets. This paper presents an artifact-backed analysis of temporal coverage, missingness, identifier ambiguity, candidate-generation efficiency, and cluster distributions, and situates ICE-ID against classical ER benchmarks (Abt--Buy, Amazon--Google, DBLP--ACM, DBLP--Scholar, Walmart--Amazon, iTunes--Amazon, Beer, Fodors--Zagats). We also define a deployment-faithful temporal OOD protocol and release the dataset, splits, regeneration scripts, analysis artifacts, and a dashboard for interactive exploration. Baseline model comparisons and end-to-end ER results are reported in the companion methods paper.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.13792v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>stat.AP</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gon\c{c}alo Hora de Carvalho, Lazar S. Popov, Sander Kaatee, M\'ario S. Correia, Kristinn R. Th\'orisson, Tangrui Li, P\'etur H\'uni Bj\"ornsson, Eir\'ikur Sm\'ari Sigur{\dh}arson, Jilles S. Dibangoye</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Programming by Backprop: An Instruction is Worth 100 Examples When Finetuning LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.18777</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.18777v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are typically trained to acquire behaviours from demonstrations or experience, yet much of their training data is declarative: instructions, rules, and descriptions that specify behaviours without showing how to execute them. We introduce Programming by Backprop (PBB): a training regime that enables LLMs to acquire procedural knowledge (i.e., reusable behaviours) from declarative instructions encountered during training. With PBB, instructions in training data provide an opportunity to `program' specific behaviours into model weights. The core principle underpinning PBB is the separation of learning how instructions map to behaviour from internalising new instructions. We devise two distinct PBB curricula that leverage this principle. Through controlled experiments across two domains (algorithmic execution from Python source code and text generation from context-free grammars), we demonstrate the benefit of these curricula over training on a homogeneous data mixture. Crucially, PBB is highly sample efficient, with a single instruction substituting for up to 100 execution examples. Though execution of instructions in training data remains less reliable than when instructions are given in-context, our results demonstrate that procedural knowledge can be noisily `programmed' into LLMs through PBB, with important implications for data curation and safety.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.18777v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jonathan Cook, Silvia Sapora, Arash Ahmadian, Akbir Khan, Tim Rocktaschel, Jakob Foerster, Laura Ruis</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Complexity-aware fine-tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.21220</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.21220v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: General-purpose Large Language Models (LLMs) are frequently fine-tuned through supervised fine-tuning (SFT) to enhance performance in specific domains. Better results can be achieved by distilling the chain-of-thought of a larger model at the cost of numerous expensive calls and a much greater amount of data. We propose a novel blueprint for efficient fine-tuning that uses reasoning only for complex data identified by entropy. Specifically, across three small open models ($\approx 3B$) we split the training data into complexity categories by a single token answer entropy (ROC AUC $0.73$), fine-tune large language models (LLMs) via SFT and distillation, and show that our pipeline significantly outperforms the standard SFT approach ($0.58$ vs $0.45$ average accuracy) and outperforms the distillation approach ($0.58$ vs $0.56$ average accuracy) while using $81\%$ less data.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.21220v4</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Andrey Goncharov, Daniil Vyazhev, Petr Sychev, Edvard Khalafyan, Alexey Zaytsev</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TASER: Table Agents for Schema-guided Extraction and Recommendation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.13404</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.13404v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Real-world financial filings report critical information about an entity's investment holdings, essential for assessing that entity's risk, profitability, and relationship profile. Yet, these details are often buried in messy, multi-page, fragmented tables that are difficult to parse, hindering downstream QA and data normalization. Specifically, 99.4% of the tables in our financial table dataset lack bounding boxes, with the largest table spanning 44 pages. To address this, we present TASER (Table Agents for Schema-guided Extraction and Recommendation), a continuously learning, agentic table extraction system that converts highly unstructured, multi-page, heterogeneous tables into normalized, schema-conforming outputs. Guided by an initial portfolio schema, TASER executes table detection, classification, extraction, and recommendations in a single pipeline. Our Recommender Agent reviews unmatched outputs and proposes schema revisions, enabling TASER to outperform vision-based table detection models such as Table Transformer by 10.1%. Within this continuous learning process, larger batch sizes yield a 104.3% increase in useful schema recommendations and a 9.8% increase in total extractions. To train TASER, we manually labeled 22,584 pages and 3,213 tables covering $731.7 billion in holdings, culminating in TASERTab to facilitate research on real-world financial tables and structured outputs. Our results highlight the promise of continuously learning agents for robust extractions from complex tabular data.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.13404v4</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nicole Cho, Kirsty Fielding, William Watson, Sumitra Ganesh, Manuela Veloso</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Simple and Efficient Jailbreak Method Exploiting LLMs' Helpfulness</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14297</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.14297v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: This study reveals a critical safety blind spot in modern LLMs: learning-style queries, which closely resemble ordinary educational questions, can reliably elicit harmful responses. The learning-style queries are constructed by a novel reframing paradigm: HILL (Hiding Intention by Learning from LLMs). The deterministic, model-agnostic reframing framework is composed of 4 conceptual components: 1) key concept, 2) exploratory transformation, 3) detail-oriented inquiry, and optionally 4) hypotheticality. Further, new metrics are introduced to thoroughly evaluate the efficiency and harmfulness of jailbreak methods. Experiments on the AdvBench dataset across a wide range of models demonstrate HILL's strong generalizability. It achieves top attack success rates on the majority of models and across malicious categories while maintaining high efficiency with concise prompts. On the other hand, results of various defense methods show the robustness of HILL, with most defenses having mediocre effects or even increasing the attack success rates. In addition, the assessment of defenses on the constructed safe prompts reveals inherent limitations of LLMs' safety mechanisms and flaws in the defense methods. This work exposes significant vulnerabilities of safety measures against learning-style elicitation, highlighting a critical challenge of fulfilling both helpfulness and safety alignments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.14297v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xuan Luo, Yue Wang, Zefeng He, Geng Tu, Jing Li, Ruifeng Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RHYTHM: Reasoning with Hierarchical Temporal Tokenization for Human Mobility</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.23115</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.23115v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Predicting human mobility is inherently challenging due to complex long-range dependencies and multi-scale periodic behaviors. To address this, we introduce RHYTHM (Reasoning with Hierarchical Temporal Tokenization for Human Mobility), a unified framework that leverages large language models (LLMs) as general-purpose spatio-temporal predictors and trajectory reasoners. Methodologically, RHYTHM employs temporal tokenization to partition each trajectory into daily segments and encode them as discrete tokens with hierarchical attention that captures both daily and weekly dependencies, thereby quadratically reducing the sequence length while preserving cyclical information. Additionally, we enrich token representations by adding pre-computed prompt embeddings for trajectory segments and prediction targets via a frozen LLM, and feeding these combined embeddings back into the LLM backbone to capture complex interdependencies. Computationally, RHYTHM keeps the pretrained LLM backbone frozen, yielding faster training and lower memory usage. We evaluate our model against state-of-the-art methods using three real-world datasets. Notably, RHYTHM achieves a 2.4% improvement in overall accuracy, a 5.0% increase on weekends, and a 24.6% reduction in training time. Code is publicly available at https://github.com/he-h/rhythm.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.23115v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haoyu He, Haozheng Luo, Yan Chen, Qi R. Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TimeOmni-1: Incentivizing Complex Reasoning with Time Series in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.24803</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.24803v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Recent advances in multimodal time series learning underscore a paradigm shift from analytics centered on basic patterns toward advanced time series understanding and reasoning. However, existing multimodal time series datasets mostly remain at the level of surface alignment and question answering, without reaching the depth of genuine reasoning. The absence of well-defined tasks that genuinely require time series reasoning, along with the scarcity of high-quality data, has limited progress in building practical time series reasoning models (TSRMs). To this end, we introduce Time Series Reasoning Suite (TSR-Suite), which formalizes four atomic tasks that span three fundamental capabilities for reasoning with time series: (1) perception, acquired through scenario understanding and causality discovery; (2) extrapolation, realized via event-aware forecasting; and (3) decision-making, developed through deliberation over perception and extrapolation. TSR-Suite is the first comprehensive time series reasoning suite that supports not only thorough evaluation but also the data pipeline and training of TSRMs. It contains more than 23K samples, of which 2.3K are carefully curated through a human-guided hierarchical annotation process. Building on this foundation, we introduce TimeOmni-1, the first unified reasoning model designed to address diverse real-world problems demanding time series reasoning. The model is trained in multiple stages, integrating a mixture of task scenarios, novel reward functions, and tailored optimizations. Experiments show that TimeOmni-1 delivers strong out-of-distribution generalization across all tasks and achieves a high rate of valid responses. It significantly improves causality discovery accuracy (64.0% vs. 35.9% with GPT-4.1) and raises the valid response rate by over 6% compared to GPT-4.1 on the event-aware forecasting task.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.24803v3</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tong Guan, Zijie Meng, Dianqi Li, Shiyu Wang, Chao-Han Huck Yang, Qingsong Wen, Zuozhu Liu, Sabato Marco Siniscalchi, Ming Jin, Shirui Pan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hearing the Order: Investigating Position Bias in Large Audio-Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.00628</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.00628v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large audio-language models (LALMs) are often used in tasks that involve reasoning over ordered options. An open question is whether their predictions are influenced by the order of answer choices, which would indicate a form of position bias and undermine their reliability. In this paper, we identify and analyze this problem in LALMs. We demonstrate that no model is immune to this bias through extensive experiments on six LALMs across three widely used benchmarks and their spoken counterparts. Shuffling the order of answer options can cause performance fluctuations of up to 24% and even change model rankings, raising concerns about the reliability of current evaluation practices. We also study permutation-based strategies and show that they can mitigate bias in most cases. Our work represents the first systematic investigation of this issue in LALMs, and we hope it raises awareness and motivates further research in this direction.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.00628v2</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yu-Xiang Lin, Chen-An Li, Sheng-Lun Wei, Po-Chun Chen, Hsin-Hsi Chen, Hung-yi Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Scalable Oversight via Partitioned Human Supervision</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.22500</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.22500v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: As artificial intelligence (AI) systems approach and surpass expert human performance across a broad range of tasks, obtaining high-quality human supervision for evaluation and training becomes increasingly challenging. Our focus is on tasks that require deep knowledge and skills of multiple domains, where this bottleneck is severe. Unfortunately, even the best human experts are knowledgeable only in a single narrow area, and will not be able to evaluate the correctness of advanced AI systems on such superhuman tasks. However, based on their narrow expertise, humans may provide a weak signal, i.e., a complementary label indicating an option that is incorrect. For example, a cardiologist could state that ''this is not related to any cardiovascular disease,'' even if they cannot identify the true disease. Based on this weak signal, we propose a scalable oversight framework that enables us to evaluate frontier AI systems without the need to prepare the ground truth. We derive an unbiased estimator of top-1 accuracy from complementary labels and quantify how many complementary labels are needed to match the variance of ordinary labels. We further introduce two estimators to combine scarce ordinary labels with abundant complementary labels. We provide finite-sample deviation guarantees for both complementary-only and the mixed estimators. Empirically, we show that we can evaluate the output of large language models without the ground truth, if we have complementary labels. We further show that we can train an AI system with such weak signals: we show how we can design an agentic AI system automatically that can improve itself with this partitioned human supervision. Our code is available at https://github.com/R-Yin-217/Towards-Scalable-Oversight-via-Partitioned-Human-Supervision.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.22500v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ren Yin, Takashi Ishida, Masashi Sugiyama</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SWE-Master: Unleashing the Potential of Software Engineering Agents via Post-Training</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.03411</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.03411v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In this technical report, we present SWE-Master, an open-source and fully reproducible post-training framework for building effective software engineering agents. SWE-Master systematically explores the complete agent development pipeline, including teacher-trajectory synthesis and data curation, long-horizon SFT, RL with real execution feedback, and inference framework design. Starting from an open-source base model with limited initial SWE capability, SWE-Master demonstrates how systematical optimization method can elicit strong long-horizon SWE task solving abilities. We evaluate SWE-Master on SWE-bench Verified, a standard benchmark for realistic software engineering tasks. Under identical experimental settings, our approach achieves a resolve rate of 61.4\% with Qwen2.5-Coder-32B, substantially outperforming existing open-source baselines. By further incorporating test-time scaling~(TTS) with LLM-based environment feedback, SWE-Master reaches 70.8\% at TTS@8, demonstrating a strong performance potential. SWE-Master provides a practical and transparent foundation for advancing reproducible research on software engineering agents. The code is available at https://github.com/RUCAIBox/SWE-Master.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.03411v2</guid>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Huatong Song, Lisheng Huang, Shuang Sun, Jinhao Jiang, Ran Le, Daixuan Cheng, Guoxin Chen, Yiwen Hu, Zongchao Chen, Yiming Jia, Wayne Xin Zhao, Yang Song, Tao Zhang, Ji-Rong Wen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UI-Venus-1.5 Technical Report</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09082</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.09082v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: GUI agents have emerged as a powerful paradigm for automating interactions in digital environments, yet achieving both broad generality and consistently strong task performance remains challenging. In this report, we present UI-Venus-1.5, a unified, end-to-end GUI Agent designed for robust real-world applications. The proposed model family comprises two dense variants (2B and 8B) and one mixture-of-experts variant (30B-A3B) to meet various downstream application scenarios. Compared to our previous version, UI-Venus-1.5 introduces three key technical advances: (1) a comprehensive Mid-Training stage leveraging 10 billion tokens across 30+ datasets to establish foundational GUI semantics; (2) Online Reinforcement Learning with full-trajectory rollouts, aligning training objectives with long-horizon, dynamic navigation in large-scale environments; and (3) a single unified GUI Agent constructed via Model Merging, which synthesizes domain-specific models (grounding, web, and mobile) into one cohesive checkpoint. Extensive evaluations demonstrate that UI-Venus-1.5 establishes new state-of-the-art performance on benchmarks such as ScreenSpot-Pro (69.6%), VenusBench-GD (75.0%), and AndroidWorld (77.6%), significantly outperforming previous strong baselines. In addition, UI-Venus-1.5 demonstrates robust navigation capabilities across a variety of Chinese mobile apps, effectively executing user instructions in real-world scenarios. Code: https://github.com/inclusionAI/UI-Venus; Model: https://huggingface.co/collections/inclusionAI/ui-venus</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.09082v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator> Venus Team, Changlong Gao, Zhangxuan Gu, Yulin Liu, Xinyu Qiu, Shuheng Shen, Yue Wen, Tianyu Xia, Zhenyu Xu, Zhengwen Zeng, Beitong Zhou, Xingran Zhou, Weizhi Chen, Sunhao Dai, Jingya Dou, Yichen Gong, Yuan Guo, Zhenlin Guo, Feng Li, Qian Li, Jinzhen Lin, Yuqi Zhou, Linchao Zhu, Liang Chen, Zhenyu Guo, Changhua Meng, Weiqiang Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MCPShield: A Security Cognition Layer for Adaptive Trust Calibration in Model Context Protocol Agents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.14281</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.14281v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The Model Context Protocol (MCP) standardizes tool use for LLM-based agents and enable third-party servers. This openness introduces a security misalignment: agents implicitly trust tools exposed by potentially untrusted MCP servers. However, despite its excellent utility, existing agents typically offer limited validation for third-party MCP servers. As a result, agents remain vulnerable to MCP-based attacks that exploit the misalignment between agents and servers throughout the tool invocation lifecycle. In this paper, we propose MCPShield as a plug-in security cognition layer that mitigates this misalignment and ensures agent security when invoking MCP-based tools. Drawing inspiration from human experience-driven tool validation, MCPShield assists agent forms security cognition with metadata-guided probing before invocation. Our method constrains execution within controlled boundaries while cognizing runtime events, and subsequently updates security cognition by reasoning over historical traces after invocation, building on human post-use reflection on tool behavior. Experiments demonstrate that MCPShield exhibits strong generalization in defending against six novel MCP-based attack scenarios across six widely used agentic LLMs, while avoiding false positives on benign servers and incurring low deployment overhead. Overall, our work provides a practical and robust security safeguard for MCP-based tool invocation in open agent ecosystems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.14281v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhenhong Zhou, Yuanhe Zhang, Hongwei Cai, Moayad Aloqaily, Ouns Bouachir, Linsey Pang, Prakhar Mehrotra, Kun Wang, Qingsong Wen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GLM-5: from Vibe Coding to Agentic Engineering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.15763</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.15763v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We present GLM-5, a next-generation foundation model designed to transition the paradigm of vibe coding to agentic engineering. Building upon the agentic, reasoning, and coding (ARC) capabilities of its predecessor, GLM-5 adopts DSA to significantly reduce training and inference costs while maintaining long-context fidelity. To advance model alignment and autonomy, we implement a new asynchronous reinforcement learning infrastructure that drastically improves post-training efficiency by decoupling generation from training. Furthermore, we propose novel asynchronous agent RL algorithms that further improve RL quality, enabling the model to learn from complex, long-horizon interactions more effectively. Through these innovations, GLM-5 achieves state-of-the-art performance on major open benchmarks. Most critically, GLM-5 demonstrates unprecedented capability in real-world coding tasks, surpassing previous baselines in handling end-to-end software engineering challenges. Code, models, and more information are available at https://github.com/zai-org/GLM-5.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.15763v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator> GLM-5-Team,  :, Aohan Zeng, Xin Lv, Zhenyu Hou, Zhengxiao Du, Qinkai Zheng, Bin Chen, Da Yin, Chendi Ge, Chenghua Huang, Chengxing Xie, Chenzheng Zhu, Congfeng Yin, Cunxiang Wang, Gengzheng Pan, Hao Zeng, Haoke Zhang, Haoran Wang, Huilong Chen, Jiajie Zhang, Jian Jiao, Jiaqi Guo, Jingsen Wang, Jingzhao Du, Jinzhu Wu, Kedong Wang, Lei Li, Lin Fan, Lucen Zhong, Mingdao Liu, Mingming Zhao, Pengfan Du, Qian Dong, Rui Lu,  Shuang-Li, Shulin Cao, Song Liu, Ting Jiang, Xiaodong Chen, Xiaohan Zhang, Xuancheng Huang, Xuezhen Dong, Yabo Xu, Yao Wei, Yifan An, Yilin Niu, Yitong Zhu, Yuanhao Wen, Yukuo Cen, Yushi Bai, Zhongpei Qiao, Zihan Wang, Zikang Wang, Zilin Zhu, Ziqiang Liu, Zixuan Li, Bojie Wang, Bosi Wen, Can Huang, Changpeng Cai, Chao Yu, Chen Li, Chengwei Hu, Chenhui Zhang, Dan Zhang, Daoyan Lin, Dayong Yang, Di Wang, Ding Ai, Erle Zhu, Fangzhou Yi, Feiyu Chen, Guohong Wen, Hailong Sun, Haisha Zhao, Haiyi Hu, Hanchen Zhang, Hanrui Liu, Hanyu Zhang, Hao Peng, Hao Tai, Haobo Zhang, He Liu, Hongwei Wang, Hongxi Yan, Hongyu Ge, Huan Liu, Huanpeng Chu, Jia'ni Zhao, Jiachen Wang, Jiajing Zhao, Jiamin Ren, Jiapeng Wang, Jiaxin Zhang, Jiayi Gui, Jiayue Zhao, Jijie Li, Jing An, Jing Li, Jingwei Yuan, Jinhua Du, Jinxin Liu, Junkai Zhi, Junwen Duan, Kaiyue Zhou, Kangjian Wei, Ke Wang, Keyun Luo, Laiqiang Zhang, Leigang Sha, Liang Xu, Lindong Wu, Lintao Ding, Lu Chen, Minghao Li, Nianyi Lin, Pan Ta, Qiang Zou, Rongjun Song, Ruiqi Yang, Shangqing Tu, Shangtong Yang, Shaoxiang Wu, Shengyan Zhang, Shijie Li, Shuang Li, Shuyi Fan, Wei Qin, Wei Tian, Weining Zhang, Wenbo Yu, Wenjie Liang, Xiang Kuang, Xiangmeng Cheng, Xiangyang Li, Xiaoquan Yan, Xiaowei Hu, Xiaoying Ling, Xing Fan, Xingye Xia, Xinyuan Zhang, Xinze Zhang, Xirui Pan, Xu Zou, Xunkai Zhang, Yadi Liu, Yandong Wu, Yanfu Li, Yidong Wang, Yifan Zhu, Yijun Tan, Yilin Zhou, Yiming Pan, Ying Zhang, Yinpei Su, Yipeng Geng, Yong Yan, Yonglin Tan, Yuean Bi, Yuhan Shen, Yuhao Yang, Yujiang Li, Yunan Liu, Yunqing Wang, Yuntao Li, Yurong Wu, Yutao Zhang, Yuxi Duan, Yuxuan Zhang, Zezhen Liu, Zhengtao Jiang, Zhenhe Yan, Zheyu Zhang, Zhixiang Wei, Zhuo Chen, Zhuoer Feng, Zijun Yao, Ziwei Chai, Ziyuan Wang, Zuzhou Zhang, Bin Xu, Minlie Huang, Hongning Wang, Juanzi Li, Yuxiao Dong, Jie Tang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anatomy of Capability Emergence: Scale-Invariant Representation Collapse and Top-Down Reorganization in Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.15997</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.15997v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Capability emergence during neural network training remains mechanistically opaque. We track five geometric measures across five model scales (405K--85M parameters), 120 task$\times$level$\times$ model combinations (119 achieving accuracy-based emergence) across eight algorithmic tasks, and three Pythia language models (160M--2.8B). We find: (1) training begins with a universal representation collapse to task-specific floors that are scale-invariant across a 210$\times$ parameter range (e.g., modular arithmetic collapses to RANKME $\,\approx\,$2.0 regardless of model size); (2) collapse propagates top-down through layers (28/32 task$ \times $model consistency), contradicting bottom-up feature-building intuition; (3) a geometric hierarchy in which representation geometry leads emergence (100% precursor rate for hard tasks across all model sizes), while the local learning coefficient is synchronous (0/24 precursor) and Hessian measures lag. We also delineate prediction limits: geometric measures encode coarse task difficulty but not fine-grained timing (within-class concordance ranges from 52% for easy tasks to 69% for hard tasks; when task ordering reverses across scales, prediction fails at 26%). On Pythia, global geometric patterns replicate but per-task precursor signals do not, as the precursor relationship requires task--training alignment that naturalistic pre-training does not provide. Our contribution is the geometric anatomy of emergence and its boundary conditions, not a prediction tool.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.15997v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jayadev Billa</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intent Laundering: AI Safety Datasets Are Not What They Seem</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.16729</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.16729v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We systematically evaluate the quality of widely used AI safety datasets from two perspectives: in isolation and in practice. In isolation, we examine how well these datasets reflect real-world adversarial attacks based on three key properties: being driven by ulterior intent, well-crafted, and out-of-distribution. We find that these datasets overrely on "triggering cues": words or phrases with overt negative/sensitive connotations that are intended to trigger safety mechanisms explicitly, which is unrealistic compared to real-world attacks. In practice, we evaluate whether these datasets genuinely measure safety risks or merely provoke refusals through triggering cues. To explore this, we introduce "intent laundering": a procedure that abstracts away triggering cues from adversarial attacks (data points) while strictly preserving their malicious intent and all relevant details. Our results indicate that current AI safety datasets fail to faithfully represent real-world adversarial behavior due to their overreliance on triggering cues. Once these cues are removed, all previously evaluated "reasonably safe" models become unsafe, including Gemini 3 Pro and Claude Sonnet 3.7. Moreover, when intent laundering is adapted as a jailbreaking technique, it consistently achieves high attack success rates, ranging from 90% to over 98%, under fully black-box access. Overall, our findings expose a significant disconnect between how model safety is evaluated by existing datasets and how real-world adversaries behave.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.16729v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shahriar Golchin, Marc Wetter</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Games That Teach, Chats That Convince: Comparing Interactive and Static Formats for Persuasive Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.17905</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.17905v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Interactive systems such as chatbots and games are increasingly used to persuade and educate on sustainability-related topics, yet it remains unclear how different delivery formats shape learning and persuasive outcomes when content is held constant. Grounding on identical arguments and factual content across conditions, we present a controlled user study comparing three modes of information delivery: static essays, conversational chatbots, and narrative text-based games. Across subjective measures, the chatbot condition consistently outperformed the other modes and increased perceived importance of the topic. However, perceived learning did not reliably align with objective outcomes: participants in the text-based game condition reported learning less than those reading essays, yet achieved higher scores on a delayed (24-hour) knowledge quiz. Additional exploratory analyses further suggest that common engagement proxies, such as verbosity and interaction length, are more closely related to subjective experience than to actual learning. These findings highlight a dissociation between how persuasive experiences feel and what participants retain, and point to important design trade-offs between interactivity, realism, and learning in persuasive systems and serious games.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.17905v2</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.ET</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Seyed Hossein Alavi, Zining Wang, Shruthi Chockkalingam, Raymond T. Ng, Vered Shwartz</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Well Can LLM Agents Simulate End-User Security and Privacy Attitudes and Behaviors?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.18464</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.18464v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: A growing body of research assumes that large language model (LLM) agents can serve as proxies for how people form attitudes toward and behave in response to security and privacy (S&amp;P) threats. If correct, these simulations could offer a scalable way to forecast S&amp;P risks in products prior to deployment. We interrogate this assumption using SP-ABCBench, a new benchmark of 30 tests derived from validated S&amp;P human-subject studies, which measures alignment between simulations and human-subjects studies on a 0-100 ascending scale, where higher scores indicate better alignment across three dimensions: Attitude, Behavior, and Coherence. Evaluating twelve LLMs, four persona construction strategies, and two prompting methods, we found that there remains substantial room for improvement: all models score between 50 and 64 on average. Newer, bigger, and smarter models do not reliably do better and sometimes do worse. Some simulation configurations, however, do yield high alignment: e.g., with scores above 95 for some behavior tests when agents are prompted to apply bounded rationality and weigh privacy costs against perceived benefits. We release SP-ABCBench to enable reproducible evaluation as methods improve.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.18464v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuxuan Li, Leyang Li, Hao-Ping Lee, Sauvik Das</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nacrith: Neural Lossless Compression via Ensemble Context Modeling and High-Precision CDF Coding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.19626</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.19626v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We present Nacrith, a lossless compression system that combines a 135M-parameter transformer language model (SmolLM2-135M) with an ensemble of lightweight online predictors and a 32-bit arithmetic coder, achieving the best compression results among the systems evaluated in this study on natural language text. Beyond the base LLM-plus-arithmetic-coding paradigm, Nacrith introduces several contributions: (1) a CDF precision upgrade from 2^16 to 2^24 that eliminates ~75% of quantization overhead caused by minimum-probability floors in large vocabularies; (2) a token-level N-gram model for fast local predictions; (3) an adaptive log-space bias head correcting per-document LLM errors via online gradient descent; (4) confidence-based LLM skip for accelerating highly predictable tokens; (5) a hybrid binary format (NC06) extending neural compression to arbitrary binary files--to our knowledge a first among LLM-based compressors; (6) a llama cpp inference backend achieving ~7x faster single-token decode than PyTorch; (7) parallel multi-GPU compression across up to 8 workers; and (8) native KV cache sliding window reducing per-slide cost by ~37x. The system requires only ~500 MB of GGUF weights and ~1.2 GB VRAM per worker, running on consumer GPUs.
  On alice29 (Canterbury Corpus, 152 KB), Nacrith achieves 0.918 bits per byte (bpb)--outperforming gzip by 3.1x, bzip2 by 2.5x, CMIX v21 by 44%, and ts_zip by 20%, while compressing below the 0th-, 1st-, and 2nd-order byte-level Shannon entropy bounds. On enwik8 (100 MB), Nacrith achieves 0.9389 bpb (11.74%), surpassing ts_zip (~1.11 bpb) by 15% and FineZip (1.024 bpb) by 8% despite using a 60x smaller model with no fine-tuning. An out-of-distribution (OOD) evaluation on a document published after the model's training cutoff confirms these gains are not memorization artifacts, achieving 0.723 bpb on unseen text.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.19626v2</guid>
      <category>cs.IT</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>math.IT</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Roberto Tacconelli</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
