<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL</link>
    <description>cs.CL updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 05:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Saturday</day>
      <day>Sunday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>A Lightweight LLM Framework for Disaster Humanitarian Information Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12284</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12284v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Timely classification of humanitarian information from social media is critical for effective disaster response. However, deploying large language models (LLMs) for this task faces challenges in resource-constrained emergency settings. This paper develops a lightweight, cost-effective framework for disaster tweet classification using parameter-efficient fine-tuning. We construct a unified experimental corpus by integrating and normalizing the HumAID dataset (76,484 tweets across 19 disaster events) into a dual-task benchmark: humanitarian information categorization and event type identification. Through systematic evaluation of prompting strategies, LoRA fine-tuning, and retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) on Llama 3.1 8B, we demonstrate that: (1) LoRA achieves 79.62% humanitarian classification accuracy (+37.79% over zero-shot) while training only ~2% of parameters; (2) QLoRA enables efficient deployment with 99.4% of LoRA performance at 50% memory cost; (3) contrary to common assumptions, RAG strategies degrade fine-tuned model performance due to label noise from retrieved examples. These findings establish a practical, reproducible pipeline for building reliable crisis intelligence systems with limited computational resources.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12284v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Han Jinzhen, Kim Jisung, Yang Jong Soo, Yun Hong Sik</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Biased Chatbots to Biased Agents: Examining Role Assignment Effects on LLM Agent Robustness</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12285</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12285v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) are increasingly deployed as autonomous agents capable of actions with real-world impacts beyond text generation. While persona-induced biases in text generation are well documented, their effects on agent task performance remain largely unexplored, even though such effects pose more direct operational risks. In this work, we present the first systematic case study showing that demographic-based persona assignments can alter LLM agents' behavior and degrade performance across diverse domains. Evaluating widely deployed models on agentic benchmarks spanning strategic reasoning, planning, and technical operations, we uncover substantial performance variations - up to 26.2% degradation, driven by task-irrelevant persona cues. These shifts appear across task types and model architectures, indicating that persona conditioning and simple prompt injections can distort an agent's decision-making reliability. Our findings reveal an overlooked vulnerability in current LLM agentic systems: persona assignments can introduce implicit biases and increase behavioral volatility, raising concerns for the safe and robust deployment of LLM agents.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12285v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Linbo Cao, Lihao Sun, Yang Yue</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retrieval-Augmented Self-Taught Reasoning Model with Adaptive Chain-of-Thought for ASR Named Entity Correction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12287</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12287v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: End-to-end automatic speech recognition (ASR) systems frequently misrecognize domain-specific phrases like named entities, which can cause catastrophic failures in downstream tasks. A new family of named entity correction methods based on large language models (LLMs) has recently emerged. However, these approaches have yet to fully exploit the sophisticated reasoning capabilities inherent to LLMs. To bridge this gap, we propose a novel retrieval-augmented generation framework for correcting named entity errors in ASR. Our approach consists of two key components: (1) a rephrasing language model (RLM) for named entity recognition, followed by candidate retrieval using a phonetic-level edit distance; and (2) a novel self-taught reasoning model with adaptive chain-of-thought (A-STAR) that dynamically adjusts the depth of its reasoning based on task difficulty. Experiments on the AISHELL-1 and Homophone datasets demonstrate the effectiveness of our method, which achieves relative reductions in the named entity character error rate of 17.96\% and 34.42\%, respectively, compared to a strong baseline.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12287v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junjie An, Jingguang Tian, Tianyi Wang, Yu Gao, Xiaofeng Mou, Yi Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grandes Modelos de Linguagem Multimodais (MLLMs): Da Teoria \`a Pr\'atica</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12302</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12302v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) combine the natural language understanding and generation capabilities of LLMs with perception skills in modalities such as image and audio, representing a key advancement in contemporary AI. This chapter presents the main fundamentals of MLLMs and emblematic models. Practical techniques for preprocessing, prompt engineering, and building multimodal pipelines with LangChain and LangGraph are also explored. For further practical study, supplementary material is publicly available online: https://github.com/neemiasbsilva/MLLMs-Teoria-e-Pratica. Finally, the chapter discusses the challenges and highlights promising trends.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12302v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Neemias da Silva, J\'ulio C. W. Scholz, John Harrison, Marina Borges, Paulo \'Avila, Frances A Santos, Myriam Delgado, Rodrigo Minetto, Thiago H Silva</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>propella-1: Multi-Property Document Annotation for LLM Data Curation at Scale</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12414</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12414v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Since FineWeb-Edu, data curation for LLM pretraining has predominantly relied on single scalar quality scores produced by small classifiers. A single score conflates multiple quality dimensions, prevents flexible filtering, and offers no interpretability. We introduce propella-1, a family of small multilingual LLMs (0.6B, 1.7B, 4B parameters) that annotate text documents across 18 properties organized into six categories: core content, classification, quality and value, audience and purpose, safety and compliance, and geographic relevance. The models support 57 languages and produce structured JSON annotations conforming to a predefined schema. Evaluated against a frontier commercial LLM as a reference annotator, the 4B model achieves higher agreement than much larger general-purpose models. We release propella-annotations, a dataset of over three billion document annotations covering major pretraining corpora including data from FineWeb-2, FinePDFs, HPLT 3.0, and Nemotron-CC. Using these annotations, we present a multi-dimensional compositional analysis of widely used pretraining datasets, revealing substantial differences in quality, reasoning depth, and content composition that single-score approaches cannot capture. All model weights and annotations are released under permissive, commercial-use licenses.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12414v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Maximilian Idahl, Benedikt Droste, Bj\"orn Pl\"uster, Jan Philipp Harries</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RankLLM: Weighted Ranking of LLMs by Quantifying Question Difficulty</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12424</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12424v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Benchmarks establish a standardized evaluation framework to systematically assess the performance of large language models (LLMs), facilitating objective comparisons and driving advancements in the field. However, existing benchmarks fail to differentiate question difficulty, limiting their ability to effectively distinguish models' capabilities. To address this limitation, we propose RankLLM, a novel framework designed to quantify both question difficulty and model competency. RankLLM introduces difficulty as the primary criterion for differentiation, enabling a more fine-grained evaluation of LLM capabilities. RankLLM's core mechanism facilitates bidirectional score propagation between models and questions. The core intuition of RankLLM is that a model earns a competency score when it correctly answers a question, while a question's difficulty score increases when it challenges a model. Using this framework, we evaluate 30 models on 35,550 questions across multiple domains. RankLLM achieves 90% agreement with human judgments and consistently outperforms strong baselines such as IRT. It also exhibits strong stability, fast convergence, and high computational efficiency, making it a practical solution for large-scale, difficulty-aware LLM evaluation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12424v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ziqian Zhang, Xingjian Hu, Yue Huang, Kai Zhang, Ruoxi Chen, Yixin Liu, Qingsong Wen, Kaidi Xu, Xiangliang Zhang, Neil Zhenqiang Gong, Lichao Sun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RBCorr: Response Bias Correction in Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12445</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12445v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Language models (LMs) are known to be prone to response biases, which present as option preference biases in fixed-response questions. It is therefore imperative to develop low-cost and effective response bias correction methods to improve LM performance and enable more accurate evaluations of model abilities. Here, we propose a simple response bias correction strategy ($\texttt{RBCorr}$) and test it on 12 open-weight language models using yes-no, entailment, and multiple choice questions. We show that response bias is prevalent in LMs pre-correction and that $\texttt{RBCorr}$ effectively eliminates bias and boosts model performance. We also explore the generalizability of bias behavior across models, datasets, and prompt formats, showing that LogProbs-based correction is highly dependent on all three of these aspects. Overall, $\texttt{RBCorr}$ is an easy-to-use method that can boost the performance of smaller LMs and ensure that LM performance on closed-response benchmarks aligns more closely with their true capabilities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12445v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Om Bhatt, Anna A. Ivanova</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discovering Semantic Latent Structures in Psychological Scales: A Response-Free Pathway to Efficient Simplification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12575</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12575v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Psychological scale refinement traditionally relies on response-based methods such as factor analysis, item response theory, and network psychometrics to optimize item composition. Although rigorous, these approaches require large samples and may be constrained by data availability and cross-cultural comparability. Recent advances in natural language processing suggest that the semantic structure of questionnaire items may encode latent construct organization, offering a complementary response-free perspective. We introduce a topic-modeling framework that operationalizes semantic latent structure for scale simplification. Items are encoded using contextual sentence embeddings and grouped via density-based clustering to discover latent semantic factors without predefining their number. Class-based term weighting derives interpretable topic representations that approximate constructs and enable merging of semantically adjacent clusters. Representative items are selected using membership criteria within an integrated reduction pipeline. We benchmarked the framework across DASS, IPIP, and EPOCH, evaluating structural recovery, internal consistency, factor congruence, correlation preservation, and reduction efficiency. The proposed method recovered coherent factor-like groupings aligned with established constructs. Selected items reduced scale length by 60.5% on average while maintaining psychometric adequacy. Simplified scales showed high concordance with original factor structures and preserved inter-factor correlations, indicating that semantic latent organization provides a response-free approximation of measurement structure. Our framework formalizes semantic structure as an inspectable front-end for scale construction and reduction. To facilitate adoption, we provide a visualization-supported tool enabling one-click semantic analysis and structured simplification.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12575v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bo Wang, Yuxuan Zhang, Yueqin Hu, Hanchao Hou, Kaiping Peng, Shiguang Ni</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unleashing Low-Bit Inference on Ascend NPUs: A Comprehensive Evaluation of HiFloat Formats</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12635</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12635v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: As LLMs scale, low-bit floating-point formats like MXFP and NVFP4 offer new opportunities for precision and efficiency. In this work, we evaluate HiFloat (HiF8 and HiF4), a family of formats tailored for Ascend NPUs. Through rigorous comparison across weight-activation and KV-cache tasks, we provide three key insights: (1) INT8 suits narrow-range data, while floating-point formats excel with high-variance data; (2) in 4-bit regimes, HiF4's hierarchical scaling prevents the accuracy collapse seen in integer formats; and (3) HiFloat is fully compatible with state-of-the-art post-training quantization frameworks. Overall, HiFloat provides a solution for high-efficiency LLM inference on NPUs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12635v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Pengxiang Zhao, Hui-Ling Zhen, Xing Li, Han Bao, Weizhe Lin, Zhiyuan Yang, Ziwei Yu, Xin Wang, Mingxuan Yuan, Xianzhi Yu, Zhenhua Dong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CLASE: A Hybrid Method for Chinese Legalese Stylistic Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12639</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12639v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Legal text generated by large language models (LLMs) can usually achieve reasonable factual accuracy, but it frequently fails to adhere to the specialised stylistic norms and linguistic conventions of legal writing. In order to improve stylistic quality, a crucial first step is to establish a reliable evaluation method. However, having legal experts manually develop such a metric is impractical, as the implicit stylistic requirements in legal writing practice are difficult to formalise into explicit rubrics. Meanwhile, existing automatic evaluation methods also fall short: reference-based metrics conflate semantic accuracy with stylistic fidelity, and LLM-as-a-judge evaluations suffer from opacity and inconsistency. To address these challenges, we introduce CLASE (Chinese LegAlese Stylistic Evaluation), a hybrid evaluation method that focuses on the stylistic performance of legal text. The method incorporates a hybrid scoring mechanism that combines 1) linguistic feature-based scores and 2) experience-guided LLM-as-a-judge scores. Both the feature coefficients and the LLM scoring experiences are learned from contrastive pairs of authentic legal documents and their LLM-restored counterparts. This hybrid design captures both surface-level features and implicit stylistic norms in a transparent, reference-free manner. Experiments on 200 Chinese legal documents show that CLASE achieves substantially higher alignment with human judgments than traditional metrics and pure LLM-as-a-judge methods. Beyond improved alignment, CLASE provides interpretable score breakdowns and suggestions for improvements, offering a scalable and practical solution for professional stylistic evaluation in legal text generation (Code and data for CLASE is available at: https://github.com/rexera/CLASE).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12639v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yiran Rex Ma, Yuxiao Ye, Huiyuan Xie</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Normalization: Rethinking the Partition Function as a Difficulty Scheduler for RLVR</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12642</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12642v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Reward-maximizing RL methods enhance the reasoning performance of LLMs, but often reduce the diversity among outputs. Recent works address this issue by adopting GFlowNets, training LLMs to match a target distribution while jointly learning its partition function. In contrast to prior works that treat this partition function solely as a normalizer, we reinterpret it as a per-prompt expected-reward (i.e., online accuracy) signal, leveraging this unused information to improve sample efficiency. Specifically, we first establish a theoretical relationship between the partition function and per-prompt accuracy estimates. Building on this key insight, we propose Partition Function-Guided RL (PACED-RL), a post-training framework that leverages accuracy estimates to prioritize informative question prompts during training, and further improves sample efficiency through an accuracy estimate error-prioritized replay. Crucially, both components reuse information already produced during GFlowNet training, effectively amortizing the compute overhead into the existing optimization process. Extensive experiments across diverse benchmarks demonstrate strong performance improvements over GRPO and prior GFlowNet approaches, highlighting PACED-RL as a promising direction for a more sample efficient distribution-matching training for LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12642v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dohyung Kim, Minbeom Kim, Jeonghye Kim, Sangmook Lee, Sojeong Rhee, Kyomin Jung</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Ordinal Probabilistic Reward from Preferences</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12660</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12660v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Reward models are crucial for aligning large language models (LLMs) with human values and intentions. Existing approaches follow either Generative (GRMs) or Discriminative (DRMs) paradigms, yet both suffer from limitations: GRMs typically demand costly point-wise supervision, while DRMs produce uncalibrated relative scores that lack probabilistic interpretation. To address these challenges, we introduce a novel reward modeling paradigm: Probabilistic Reward Model (PRM). Instead of modeling reward as a deterministic scalar, our approach treats it as a random variable, learning a full probability distribution for the quality of each response. To make this paradigm practical, we present its closed-form, discrete realization: the Ordinal Probabilistic Reward Model (OPRM), which discretizes the quality score into a finite set of ordinal ratings. Building on OPRM, we propose a data-efficient training strategy called Region Flooding Tuning (RgFT). It enables rewards to better reflect absolute text quality by incorporating quality-level annotations, which guide the model to concentrate the probability mass within corresponding rating sub-regions. Experiments on various reward model benchmarks show that our method improves accuracy by $\textbf{2.9%}\sim\textbf{7.4%}$ compared to prior reward models, demonstrating strong performance and data efficiency. Analysis of the score distribution provides evidence that our method captures not only relative rankings but also absolute quality.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12660v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Longze Chen, Lu Wang, Renke Shan, Ze Gong, Run Luo, Jiaming Li, Jing Luo, Qiyao Wang, Min Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>$\mathcal{X}$-KD: General Experiential Knowledge Distillation for Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12674</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12674v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Knowledge Distillation (KD) for Large Language Models (LLMs) has become increasingly important as models grow in size and complexity. While existing distillation approaches focus on imitating teacher behavior, they often overlook the original learning environment that shaped the teacher's knowledge. Inspired by the experiential learning theory and inverse reinforcement learning, we propose Experiential Knowledge Distillation ($\mathcal{X}$-KD), a novel and general framework that enables student models to learn in the teacher's original learning environment. $\mathcal{X}$-KD adopts the Approximated Variational Reward Imitation Learning (AVRIL) framework to jointly model the teacher's original reward function and perform policy distillation, encouraging consistency between the student policy and the original reward function. Our derivation demonstrates that $\mathcal{X}$-KD follows the supervised learning framework and applies to both sequence-level and divergence-based distillation methods, underlining the simplicity and flexibility of our approach. Empirical results show that $\mathcal{X}$-KD outperforms the generalized KD and MiniLLM baselines on abstractive summarization, machine translation, and arithmetic reasoning tasks. Additionally, $\mathcal{X}$-KD achieves better performance-diversity trade-off and data efficiency than baseline KD approaches.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12674v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuang Cai, Yuyu Yuan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MedXIAOHE: A Comprehensive Recipe for Building Medical MLLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12705</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12705v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present MedXIAOHE, a medical vision-language foundation model designed to advance general-purpose medical understanding and reasoning in real-world clinical applications. MedXIAOHE achieves state-of-the-art performance across diverse medical benchmarks and surpasses leading closed-source multimodal systems on multiple capabilities. To achieve this, we propose an entity-aware continual pretraining framework that organizes heterogeneous medical corpora to broaden knowledge coverage and reduce long-tail gaps (e.g., rare diseases). For medical expert-level reasoning and interaction, MedXIAOHE incorporates diverse medical reasoning patterns via reinforcement learning and tool-augmented agentic training, enabling multi-step diagnostic reasoning with verifiable decision traces. To improve reliability in real-world use, MedXIAOHE integrates user-preference rubrics, evidence-grounded reasoning, and low-hallucination long-form report generation, with improved adherence to medical instructions. We release this report to document our practical design choices, scaling insights, and evaluation framework, hoping to inspire further research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12705v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Baorong Shi, Bo Cui, Boyuan Jiang, Deli Yu, Fang Qian, Haihua Yang, Huichao Wang, Jiale Chen, Jianfei Pan, Jieqiong Cao, Jinghao Lin, Kai Wu, Lin Yang, Shengsheng Yao, Tao Chen, Xiaojun Xiao, Xiaozhong Ji, Xu Wang, Yijun He, Zhixiong Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ReFilter: Improving Robustness of Retrieval-Augmented Generation via Gated Filter</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12709</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12709v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) has become a dominant paradigm for grounding large language models (LLMs) with external evidence in knowledge-intensive question answering. A core design choice is how to fuse retrieved samples into the LLMs, where existing internal fusion approaches broadly fall into query-based fusion, parametric fusion, and latent-based fusion. Despite their effectiveness at modest retrieval scales, these methods often fail to scale gracefully as the number of retrieved candidates k increases: Larger k improves evidence coverage, yet realistic top-k retrieval inevitably contains irrelevant or redundant content and increases the inference cost.
  To address these limitations, we propose ReFilter, a novel latent-based fusion framework that performs token-level filtering and fusion. ReFilter consists of three key components: a context encoder for encoding context features, a gated filter for weighting each token, and a token fusion module for integrating the weighted token feature into the LLM's hidden states. Our experiments across four general-domain QA benchmarks show that ReFilter consistently achieves the best average performance under both in-domain adaptation and out-of-domain transfer. ReFilter further generalizes to five biomedical QA benchmarks in zero-shot transfer without domain fine-tuning, reaching 70.01% average accuracy with Qwen2.5-14B-Instruct.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12709v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yixin Chen, Ying Xiong, Shangyu Wu, Xiangrui Ke, Nan Guan, Chun Jason Xue</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lamer-SSL: Layer-aware Mixture of LoRA Experts for Continual Multilingual Expansion of Self-supervised Models without Forgetting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12746</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12746v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Despite their impressive performance, self-supervised speech models often struggle to generalize to new languages and tend to forget previously acquired knowledge during continual training. To address this, we propose Lamer-SSL, a parameter-efficient framework that integrates a Layer-Aware MixturE of LoRA Experts (Lamer) module with a replay strategy. The Lamer module enables flexible balancing between shared and language-specific representations, while layer-aware expert allocation assigns more experts to deeper layers where semantic information is richer. Meanwhile, the replay strategy retains prior knowledge using minimal data, mitigating forgetting during continual training. Experiments on automatic speech recognition (ASR) and language identification (LID) demonstrate that Lamer-SSL extends self-supervised models to new languages effectively while maintaining strong performance on previously learned languages with only 2.14% parameters being trainable.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12746v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jing Xu, Minglin Wu, Xueyuan Chen, Xixin Wu, Helen Meng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards a Diagnostic and Predictive Evaluation Methodology for Sequence Labeling Tasks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12759</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12759v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Standard evaluation in NLP typically indicates that system A is better on average than system B, but it provides little info on how to improve performance and, what is worse, it should not come as a surprise if B ends up being better than A on outside data. We propose an evaluation methodology for sequence labeling tasks grounded on error analysis that provides both quantitative and qualitative information on where systems must be improved and predicts how models will perform on a different distribution. The key is to create test sets that, contrary to common practice, do not rely on gathering large amounts of real-world in-distribution scraped data, but consists in handcrafting a small set of linguistically motivated examples that exhaustively cover the range of span attributes (such as shape, length, casing, sentence position, etc.) a system may encounter in the wild. We demonstrate this methodology on a benchmark for anglicism identification in Spanish. Our methodology provides results that are diagnostic (because they help identify systematic weaknesses in performance), actionable (because they can inform which model is better suited for a given scenario) and predictive: our method predicts model performance on external datasets with a median correlation of 0.85.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12759v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Elena Alvarez-Mellado, Julio Gonzalo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aspect-Based Sentiment Analysis for Future Tourism Experiences: A BERT-MoE Framework for Persian User Reviews</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12778</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12778v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This study advances aspect-based sentiment analysis (ABSA) for Persian-language user reviews in the tourism domain, addressing challenges of low-resource languages. We propose a hybrid BERT-based model with Top-K routing and auxiliary losses to mitigate routing collapse and improve efficiency. The pipeline includes: (1) overall sentiment classification using BERT on 9,558 labeled reviews, (2) multi-label aspect extraction for six tourism-related aspects (host, price, location, amenities, cleanliness, connectivity), and (3) integrated ABSA with dynamic routing. The dataset consists of 58,473 preprocessed reviews from the Iranian accommodation platform Jabama, manually annotated for aspects and sentiments. The proposed model achieves a weighted F1-score of 90.6% for ABSA, outperforming baseline BERT (89.25%) and a standard hybrid approach (85.7%). Key efficiency gains include a 39% reduction in GPU power consumption compared to dense BERT, supporting sustainable AI deployment in alignment with UN SDGs 9 and 12. Analysis reveals high mention rates for cleanliness and amenities as critical aspects. This is the first ABSA study focused on Persian tourism reviews, and we release the annotated dataset to facilitate future multilingual NLP research in tourism.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12778v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hamidreza Kazemi Taskooh, Taha Zare Harofte</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RAT-Bench: A Comprehensive Benchmark for Text Anonymization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12806</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12806v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Data containing personal information is increasingly used to train, fine-tune, or query Large Language Models (LLMs). Text is typically scrubbed of identifying information prior to use, often with tools such as Microsoft's Presidio or Anthropic's PII purifier. These tools have traditionally been evaluated on their ability to remove specific identifiers (e.g., names), yet their effectiveness at preventing re-identification remains unclear. We introduce RAT-Bench, a comprehensive benchmark for text anonymization tools based on re-identification risk. Using U.S. demographic statistics, we generate synthetic text containing various direct and indirect identifiers across domains, languages, and difficulty levels. We evaluate a range of NER- and LLM-based text anonymization tools and, based on the attributes an LLM-based attacker is able to correctly infer from the anonymized text, we report the risk of re-identification in the U.S. population, while properly accounting for the disparate impact of identifiers. We find that, while capabilities vary widely, even the best tools are far from perfect in particular when direct identifiers are not written in standard ways and when indirect identifiers enable re-identification. Overall we find LLM-based anonymizers, including new iterative anonymizers, to provide a better privacy-utility trade-off albeit at a higher computational cost. Importantly, we also find them to work well across languages. We conclude with recommendations for future anonymization tools and will release the benchmark and encourage community efforts to expand it, in particular to other geographies.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12806v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nata\v{s}a Kr\v{c}o, Zexi Yao, Matthieu Meeus, Yves-Alexandre de Montjoye</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Left-right asymmetry in predicting brain activity from LLMs' representations emerges with their formal linguistic competence</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12811</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12811v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: When humans and large language models (LLMs) process the same text, activations in the LLMs correlate with brain activity measured, e.g., with functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI). Moreover, it has been shown that, as the training of an LLM progresses, the performance in predicting brain activity from its internal activations improves more in the left hemisphere than in the right one. The aim of the present work is to understand which kind of competence acquired by the LLMs underlies the emergence of this left-right asymmetry. Using the OLMo-2 7B language model at various training checkpoints and fMRI data from English participants, we compare the evolution of the left-right asymmetry in brain scores alongside performance on several benchmarks. We observe that the asymmetry co-emerges with the formal linguistic abilities of the LLM. These abilities are demonstrated in two ways: by the model's capacity to assign a higher probability to an acceptable sentence than to a grammatically unacceptable one within a minimal contrasting pair, or its ability to produce well-formed text. On the opposite, the left-right asymmetry does not correlate with the performance on arithmetic or Dyck language tasks; nor with text-based tasks involving world knowledge and reasoning. We generalize these results to another family of LLMs (Pythia) and another language, namely French. Our observations indicate that the left-right asymmetry in brain predictivity matches the progress in formal linguistic competence (knowledge of linguistic patterns).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12811v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>q-bio.NC</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Laurent Bonnasse-Gahot, Christophe Pallier</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AIWizards at MULTIPRIDE: A Hierarchical Approach to Slur Reclamation Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12818</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12818v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Detecting reclaimed slurs represents a fundamental challenge for hate speech detection systems, as the same lexcal items can function either as abusive expressions or as in-group affirmations depending on social identity and context. In this work, we address Subtask B of the MultiPRIDE shared task at EVALITA 2026 by proposing a hierarchical approach to modeling the slur reclamation process. Our core assumption is that members of the LGBTQ+ community are more likely, on average, to employ certain slurs in a eclamatory manner. Based on this hypothesis, we decompose the task into two stages. First, using a weakly supervised LLM-based annotation, we assign fuzzy labels to users indicating the likelihood of belonging to the LGBTQ+ community, inferred from the tweet and the user bio. These soft labels are then used to train a BERT-like model to predict community membership, encouraging the model to learn latent representations associated with LGBTQ+ identity. In the second stage, we integrate this latent space with a newly initialized model for the downstream slur reclamation detection task. The intuition is that the first model encodes user-oriented sociolinguistic signals, which are then fused with representations learned by a model pretrained for hate speech detection. Experimental results on Italian and Spanish show that our approach achieves performance statistically comparable to a strong BERT-based baseline, while providing a modular and extensible framework for incorporating sociolinguistic context into hate speech modeling. We argue that more fine-grained hierarchical modeling of user identity and discourse context may further improve the detection of reclaimed language. We release our code at https://github.com/LucaTedeschini/multipride.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12818v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Luca Tedeschini, Matteo Fasulo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MentalBench: A Benchmark for Evaluating Psychiatric Diagnostic Capability of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12871</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12871v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We introduce MentalBench, a benchmark for evaluating psychiatric diagnostic decision-making in large language models (LLMs). Existing mental health benchmarks largely rely on social media data, limiting their ability to assess DSM-grounded diagnostic judgments. At the core of MentalBench is MentalKG, a psychiatrist-built and validated knowledge graph encoding DSM-5 diagnostic criteria and differential diagnostic rules for 23 psychiatric disorders. Using MentalKG as a golden-standard logical backbone, we generate 24,750 synthetic clinical cases that systematically vary in information completeness and diagnostic complexity, enabling low-noise and interpretable evaluation. Our experiments show that while state-of-the-art LLMs perform well on structured queries probing DSM-5 knowledge, they struggle to calibrate confidence in diagnostic decision-making when distinguishing between clinically overlapping disorders. These findings reveal evaluation gaps not captured by existing benchmarks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12871v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hoyun Song, Migyeong Kang, Jisu Shin, Jihyun Kim, Chanbi Park, Hangyeol Yoo, Jihyun An, Alice Oh, Jinyoung Han, KyungTae Lim</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BaziQA-Benchmark: Evaluating Symbolic and Temporally Compositional Reasoning in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12889</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12889v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present BaziQA-Benchmark, a standardized benchmark for evaluating symbolic and temporally compositional reasoning in large language models. The benchmark is derived from 200 professionally curated, multiple-choice problems from the Global Fortune-teller Competition (2021--2025), where each instance requires structured inference over a fixed symbolic chart and interacting temporal conditions. Unlike anecdotal or prompt-driven evaluations, BaziQA-Benchmark enables objective scoring and controlled comparison across years, domains, and model families. We evaluate contemporary language models under a multi-turn setting and analyze performance variation across temporal difficulty, reasoning domains, and inference protocols.To further probe reasoning behavior, we introduce a lightweight Structured Reasoning Protocol that constrains inference order without adding domain knowledge. Results show that models consistently outperform chance but remain far from saturation, exhibiting pronounced sensitivity to temporal composition and reasoning order, as well as systematic failures on precise temporal localization and multi-condition symbolic judgments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12889v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiangxi Chen, Qian Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ViMedCSS: A Vietnamese Medical Code-Switching Speech Dataset &amp; Benchmark</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12911</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12911v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Code-switching (CS), which is when Vietnamese speech uses English words like drug names or procedures, is a common phenomenon in Vietnamese medical communication. This creates challenges for Automatic Speech Recognition (ASR) systems, especially in low-resource languages like Vietnamese. Current most ASR systems struggle to recognize correctly English medical terms within Vietnamese sentences, and no benchmark addresses this challenge. In this paper, we construct a 34-hour \textbf{Vi}etnamese \textbf{Med}ical \textbf{C}ode-\textbf{S}witching \textbf{S}peech dataset (ViMedCSS) containing 16,576 utterances. Each utterance includes at least one English medical term drawn from a curated bilingual lexicon covering five medical topics. Using this dataset, we evaluate several state-of-the-art ASR models and examine different specific fine-tuning strategies for improving medical term recognition to investigate the best approach to solve in the dataset. Experimental results show that Vietnamese-optimized models perform better on general segments, while multilingual pretraining helps capture English insertions. The combination of both approaches yields the best balance between overall and code-switched accuracy. This work provides the first benchmark for Vietnamese medical code-switching and offers insights into effective domain adaptation for low-resource, multilingual ASR systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12911v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tung X. Nguyen, Nhu Vo, Giang-Son Nguyen, Duy Mai Hoang, Chien Dinh Huynh, Inigo Jauregi Unanue, Massimo Piccardi, Wray Buntine, Dung D. Le</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Words Don't Mean What They Say: Figurative Understanding in Bengali Idioms</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12921</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12921v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Figurative language understanding remains a significant challenge for Large Language Models (LLMs), especially for low-resource languages. To address this, we introduce a new idiom dataset, a large-scale, culturally-grounded corpus of 10,361 Bengali idioms. Each idiom is annotated under a comprehensive 19-field schema, established and refined through a deliberative expert consensus process, that captures its semantic, syntactic, cultural, and religious dimensions, providing a rich, structured resource for computational linguistics. To establish a robust benchmark for Bangla figurative language understanding, we evaluate 30 state-of-the-art multilingual and instruction-tuned LLMs on the task of inferring figurative meaning. Our results reveal a critical performance gap, with no model surpassing 50% accuracy, a stark contrast to significantly higher human performance (83.4%). This underscores the limitations of existing models in cross-linguistic and cultural reasoning. By releasing the new idiom dataset and benchmark, we provide foundational infrastructure for advancing figurative language understanding and cultural grounding in LLMs for Bengali and other low-resource languages.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12921v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Adib Sakhawat, Shamim Ara Parveen, Md Ruhul Amin, Shamim Al Mahmud, Md Saiful Islam, Tahera Khatun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum Learning and Pseudo-Labeling Improve the Generalization of Multi-Label Arabic Dialect Identification Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12937</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12937v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Being modeled as a single-label classification task for a long time, recent work has argued that Arabic Dialect Identification (ADI) should be framed as a multi-label classification task. However, ADI remains constrained by the availability of single-label datasets, with no large-scale multi-label resources available for training. By analyzing models trained on single-label ADI data, we show that the main difficulty in repurposing such datasets for Multi-Label Arabic Dialect Identification (MLADI) lies in the selection of negative samples, as many sentences treated as negative could be acceptable in multiple dialects. To address these issues, we construct a multi-label dataset by generating automatic multi-label annotations using GPT-4o and binary dialect acceptability classifiers, with aggregation guided by the Arabic Level of Dialectness (ALDi). Afterward, we train a BERT-based multi-label classifier using curriculum learning strategies aligned with dialectal complexity and label cardinality. On the MLADI leaderboard, our best-performing LAHJATBERT model achieves a macro F1 of 0.69, compared to 0.55 for the strongest previously reported system. Code and data are available at https://mohamedalaa9.github.io/lahjatbert/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12937v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ali Mekky, Mohamed El Zeftawy, Lara Hassan, Amr Keleg, Preslav Nakov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ProbeLLM: Automating Principled Diagnosis of LLM Failures</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12966</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12966v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Understanding how and why large language models (LLMs) fail is becoming a central challenge as models rapidly evolve and static evaluations fall behind. While automated probing has been enabled by dynamic test generation, existing approaches often discover isolated failure cases, lack principled control over exploration, and provide limited insight into the underlying structure of model weaknesses. We propose ProbeLLM, a benchmark-agnostic automated probing framework that elevates weakness discovery from individual failures to structured failure modes. ProbeLLM formulates probing as a hierarchical Monte Carlo Tree Search, explicitly allocating limited probing budgets between global exploration of new failure regions and local refinement of recurring error patterns. By restricting probing to verifiable test cases and leveraging tool-augmented generation and verification, ProbeLLM grounds failure discovery in reliable evidence. Discovered failures are further consolidated into interpretable failure modes via failure-aware embeddings and boundary-aware induction. Across diverse benchmarks and LLMs, ProbeLLM reveals substantially broader, cleaner, and more fine-grained failure landscapes than static benchmarks and prior automated methods, supporting a shift from case-centric evaluation toward principled weakness discovery.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12966v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yue Huang, Zhengzhe Jiang, Yuchen Ma, Yu Jiang, Xiangqi Wang, Yujun Zhou, Yuexing Hao, Kehan Guo, Pin-Yu Chen, Stefan Feuerriegel, Xiangliang Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SciAgentGym: Benchmarking Multi-Step Scientific Tool-use in LLM Agents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12984</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12984v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Scientific reasoning inherently demands integrating sophisticated toolkits to navigate domain-specific knowledge. Yet, current benchmarks largely overlook agents' ability to orchestrate tools for such rigorous workflows. To bridge this gap, we introduce SciAgentGym, a scalable interactive environment featuring 1,780 domain-specific tools across four natural science disciplines, supported by a robust execution infrastructure. Complementing this, we present SciAgentBench, a tiered evaluation suite designed to stress-test agentic capabilities from elementary actions to long-horizon workflows. Our evaluation identifies a critical bottleneck: state-of-the-art models struggle with complex scientific tool-use. Even for a leading model like GPT-5, success rates drop sharply from 60.6% to 30.9% as interaction horizons extend, primarily due to failures in multi-step workflow execution. To address this, we propose SciForge, a data synthesis method that models the tool action space as a dependency graph to generate logic-aware training trajectories. By fine-tuning on these trajectories, our SciAgent-8B outperforms the significantly larger Qwen3-VL-235B-Instruct while exhibiting positive cross-domain transfer of scientific tool-use capabilities. These results underscore the promising potential of next-generation autonomous scientific agents.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12984v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yujiong Shen, Yajie Yang, Zhiheng Xi, Binze Hu, Huayu Sha, Jiazheng Zhang, Qiyuan Peng, Junlin Shang, Jixuan Huang, Yutao Fan, Jingqi Tong, Shihan Dou, Ming Zhang, Lei Bai, Zhenfei Yin, Tao Gui, Xingjun Ma, Qi Zhang, Xuanjing Huang, Yu-Gang Jiang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the Homogeneity of Keyphrase Prediction Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12989</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12989v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Keyphrases which are useful in several NLP and IR applications are either extracted from text or predicted by generative models. Contrarily to keyphrase extraction approaches, keyphrase generation models can predict keyphrases that do not appear in a document's text called `absent keyphrases`. This ability means that keyphrase generation models can associate a document to a notion that is not explicitly mentioned in its text. Intuitively, this suggests that for two documents treating the same subjects, a keyphrase generation model is more likely to be homogeneous in their indexing i.e. predict the same keyphrase for both documents, regardless of those keyphrases appearing in their respective text or not; something a keyphrase extraction model would fail to do. Yet, homogeneity of keyphrase prediction models is not covered by current benchmarks. In this work, we introduce a method to evaluate the homogeneity of keyphrase prediction models and study if absent keyphrase generation capabilities actually help the model to be more homogeneous. To our surprise, we show that keyphrase extraction methods are competitive with generative models, and that the ability to generate absent keyphrases can actually have a negative impact on homogeneity. Our data, code and prompts are available on huggingface and github.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12989v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ma\"el Houbre, Florian Boudin, Beatrice Daille</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Know More, Know Clearer: A Meta-Cognitive Framework for Knowledge Augmentation in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12996</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12996v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Knowledge augmentation has significantly enhanced the performance of Large Language Models (LLMs) in knowledge-intensive tasks. However, existing methods typically operate on the simplistic premise that model performance equates with internal knowledge, overlooking the knowledge-confidence gaps that lead to overconfident errors or uncertain truths. To bridge this gap, we propose a novel meta-cognitive framework for reliable knowledge augmentation via differentiated intervention and alignment. Our approach leverages internal cognitive signals to partition the knowledge space into mastered, confused, and missing regions, guiding targeted knowledge expansion. Furthermore, we introduce a cognitive consistency mechanism to synchronize subjective certainty with objective accuracy, ensuring calibrated knowledge boundaries. Extensive experiments demonstrate the our framework consistently outperforms strong baselines, validating its rationality in not only enhancing knowledge capabilities but also fostering cognitive behaviors that better distinguish knowns from unknowns.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12996v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hao Chen, Ye He, Yuchun Fan, Yukun Yan, Zhenghao Liu, Qingfu Zhu, Maosong Sun, Wanxiang Che</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can we trust AI to detect healthy multilingual English speakers among the cognitively impaired cohort in the UK? An investigation using real-world conversational speech</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.13047</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.13047v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Conversational speech often reveals early signs of cognitive decline, such as dementia and MCI. In the UK, one in four people belongs to an ethnic minority, and dementia prevalence is expected to rise most rapidly among Black and Asian communities. This study examines the trustworthiness of AI models, specifically the presence of bias, in detecting healthy multilingual English speakers among the cognitively impaired cohort, to make these tools clinically beneficial. For experiments, monolingual participants were recruited nationally (UK), and multilingual speakers were enrolled from four community centres in Sheffield and Bradford. In addition to a non-native English accent, multilinguals spoke Somali, Chinese, or South Asian languages, who were further divided into two Yorkshire accents (West and South) to challenge the efficiency of the AI tools thoroughly. Although ASR systems showed no significant bias across groups, classification and regression models using acoustic and linguistic features exhibited bias against multilingual speakers, particularly in memory, fluency, and reading tasks. This bias was more pronounced when models were trained on the publicly available DementiaBank dataset. Moreover, multilinguals were more likely to be misclassified as having cognitive decline. This study is the first of its kind to discover that, despite their strong overall performance, current AI models show bias against multilingual individuals from ethnic minority backgrounds in the UK, and they are also more likely to misclassify speakers with a certain accent (South Yorkshire) as living with a more severe cognitive decline. In this pilot study, we conclude that the existing AI tools are therefore not yet reliable for diagnostic use in these populations, and we aim to address this in future work by developing more generalisable, bias-mitigated models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.13047v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Madhurananda Pahar, Caitlin Illingworth, Dorota Braun, Bahman Mirheidari, Lise Sproson, Daniel Blackburn, Heidi Christensen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TraceBack: Multi-Agent Decomposition for Fine-Grained Table Attribution</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.13059</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.13059v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Question answering (QA) over structured tables requires not only accurate answers but also transparency about which cells support them. Existing table QA systems rarely provide fine-grained attribution, so even correct answers often lack verifiable grounding, limiting trust in high-stakes settings. We address this with TraceBack, a modular multi-agent framework for scalable, cell-level attribution in single-table QA. TraceBack prunes tables to relevant rows and columns, decomposes questions into semantically coherent sub-questions, and aligns each answer span with its supporting cells, capturing both explicit and implicit evidence used in intermediate reasoning steps. To enable systematic evaluation, we release CITEBench, a benchmark with phrase-to-cell annotations drawn from ToTTo, FetaQA, and AITQA. We further propose FairScore, a reference-less metric that compares atomic facts derived from predicted cells and answers to estimate attribution precision and recall without human cell labels. Experiments show that TraceBack substantially outperforms strong baselines across datasets and granularities, while FairScore closely tracks human judgments and preserves relative method rankings, supporting interpretable and scalable evaluation of table-based QA.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.13059v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tejas Anvekar, Junha Park, Rajat Jha, Devanshu Gupta, Poojah Ganesan, Puneeth Mathur, Vivek Gupta</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring a New Competency Modeling Process with Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.13084</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.13084v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Competency modeling is widely used in human resource management to select, develop, and evaluate talent. However, traditional expert-driven approaches rely heavily on manual analysis of large volumes of interview transcripts, making them costly and prone to randomness, ambiguity, and limited reproducibility. This study proposes a new competency modeling process built on large language models (LLMs). Instead of merely automating isolated steps, we reconstruct the workflow by decomposing expert practices into structured computational components. Specifically, we leverage LLMs to extract behavioral and psychological descriptions from raw textual data and map them to predefined competency libraries through embedding-based similarity. We further introduce a learnable parameter that adaptively integrates different information sources, enabling the model to determine the relative importance of behavioral and psychological signals. To address the long-standing challenge of validation, we develop an offline evaluation procedure that allows systematic model selection without requiring additional large-scale data collection. Empirical results from a real-world implementation in a software outsourcing company demonstrate strong predictive validity, cross-library consistency, and structural robustness. Overall, our framework transforms competency modeling from a largely qualitative and expert-dependent practice into a transparent, data-driven, and evaluable analytical process.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.13084v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Silin Du, Manqing Xin, Raymond Jia Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards interpretable models for language proficiency assessment: Predicting the CEFR level of Estonian learner texts</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.13102</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.13102v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Using NLP to analyze authentic learner language helps to build automated assessment and feedback tools. It also offers new and extensive insights into the development of second language production. However, there is a lack of research explicitly combining these aspects. This study aimed to classify Estonian proficiency examination writings (levels A2-C1), assuming that careful feature selection can lead to more explainable and generalizable machine learning models for language testing. Various linguistic properties of the training data were analyzed to identify relevant proficiency predictors associated with increasing complexity and correctness, rather than the writing task. Such lexical, morphological, surface, and error features were used to train classification models, which were compared to models that also allowed for other features. The pre-selected features yielded a similar test accuracy but reduced variation in the classification of different text types. The best classifiers achieved an accuracy of around 0.9. Additional evaluation on an earlier exam sample revealed that the writings have become more complex over a 7-10-year period, while accuracy still reached 0.8 with some feature sets. The results have been implemented in the writing evaluation module of an Estonian open-source language learning environment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.13102v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kais Allkivi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SCOPE: Selective Conformal Optimized Pairwise LLM Judging</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.13110</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.13110v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are increasingly used as judges to replace costly human preference labels in pairwise evaluation. Despite their practicality, LLM judges remain prone to miscalibration and systematic biases. This paper proposes SCOPE (Selective Conformal Optimized Pairwise Evaluation), a framework for selective pairwise judging with finite-sample statistical guarantees. Under exchangeability, SCOPE calibrates an acceptance threshold such that the error rate among non-abstained judgments is at most a user-specified level $\alpha$. To provide SCOPE with a bias-neutral uncertainty signal, we introduce Bidirectional Preference Entropy (BPE), which queries the judge under both response positions, aggregates the implied preference probabilities to enforce invariance to response order, and converts the aggregated probability into an entropy-based uncertainty score. Across MT-Bench, RewardBench, and Chatbot Arena, BPE improves uncertainty quality over standard confidence proxies, providing a stronger selection signal that enables SCOPE to consistently meet the target risk level while retaining good coverage across judge scales. In particular, at $\alpha = 0.10$, \textsc{Scope} consistently satisfies the risk bound across all benchmarks and judge scales (empirical risk $\approx 0.097$ to $0.099$), while retaining substantial coverage, reaching $0.89$ on RewardBench with Qwen-14B and $0.98$ on RewardBench with Qwen-32B. Compared to na\"ive baselines, \textsc{Scope} accepts up to $2.4\times$ more judgments on MT-Bench with Qwen-7B under the same target risk constraint, demonstrating that BPE enables reliable and high-coverage LLM-based evaluation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.13110v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sher Badshah, Ali Emami, Hassan Sajjad</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From sunblock to softblock: Analyzing the correlates of neology in published writing and on social media</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.13123</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.13123v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Living languages are shaped by a host of conflicting internal and external evolutionary pressures. While some of these pressures are universal across languages and cultures, others differ depending on the social and conversational context: language use in newspapers is subject to very different constraints than language use on social media. Prior distributional semantic work on English word emergence (neology) identified two factors correlated with creation of new words by analyzing a corpus consisting primarily of historical published texts (Ryskina et al., 2020, arXiv:2001.07740). Extending this methodology to contextual embeddings in addition to static ones and applying it to a new corpus of Twitter posts, we show that the same findings hold for both domains, though the topic popularity growth factor may contribute less to neology on Twitter than in published writing. We hypothesize that this difference can be explained by the two domains favouring different neologism formation mechanisms.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.13123v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Maria Ryskina, Matthew R. Gormley, Kyle Mahowald, David R. Mortensen, Taylor Berg-Kirkpatrick, Vivek Kulkarni</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenLID-v3: Improving the Precision of Closely Related Language Identification -- An Experience Report</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.13139</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.13139v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Language identification (LID) is an essential step in building high-quality multilingual datasets from web data. Existing LID tools (such as OpenLID or GlotLID) often struggle to identify closely related languages and to distinguish valid natural language from noise, which contaminates language-specific subsets, especially for low-resource languages. In this work we extend the OpenLID classifier by adding more training data, merging problematic language variant clusters, and introducing a special label for marking noise. We call this extended system OpenLID-v3 and evaluate it against GlotLID on multiple benchmarks. During development, we focus on three groups of closely related languages (Bosnian, Croatian, and Serbian; Romance varieties of Northern Italy and Southern France; and Scandinavian languages) and contribute new evaluation datasets where existing ones are inadequate. We find that ensemble approaches improve precision but also substantially reduce coverage for low-resource languages. OpenLID-v3 is available on https://huggingface.co/HPLT/OpenLID-v3.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.13139v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mariia Fedorova, Nikolay Arefyev, Maja Buljan, Jind\v{r}ich Helcl, Stephan Oepen, Egil R{\o}nningstad, Yves Scherrer</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Chunking and the Entropy of Natural Language</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.13194</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.13194v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The entropy rate of printed English is famously estimated to be about one bit per character, a benchmark that modern large language models (LLMs) have only recently approached. This entropy rate implies that English contains nearly 80 percent redundancy relative to the five bits per character expected for random text. We introduce a statistical model that attempts to capture the intricate multi-scale structure of natural language, providing a first-principles account of this redundancy level. Our model describes a procedure of self-similarly segmenting text into semantically coherent chunks down to the single-word level. The semantic structure of the text can then be hierarchically decomposed, allowing for analytical treatment. Numerical experiments with modern LLMs and open datasets suggest that our model quantitatively captures the structure of real texts at different levels of the semantic hierarchy. The entropy rate predicted by our model agrees with the estimated entropy rate of printed English. Moreover, our theory further reveals that the entropy rate of natural language is not fixed but should increase systematically with the semantic complexity of corpora, which are captured by the only free parameter in our model.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.13194v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cond-mat.dis-nn</category>
      <category>cond-mat.stat-mech</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weishun Zhong, Doron Sivan, Tankut Can, Mikhail Katkov, Misha Tsodyks</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alignment or Integration? Rethinking Multimodal Fusion in DNA-language Foundation Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12286</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12286v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Fusing DNA foundation models with large language models (LLMs) for DNA-language reasoning raises a fundamental question: at what level should genomic sequences and natural language interact? Most existing approaches encode DNA sequences and text separately and rely on embedding-level alignment to connect the two modalities. Such late-stage fusion compresses rich genomic sequences into fixed representations, limiting the model's ability to reason over fine-grained, token-level genomic structure. In this work, we propose two new methods for DNA-language fusion, i.e., a semantic alignment method SeqCLIP and a vocabulary-level integration method OneVocab. SeqCLIP strengthens embedding-level alignment via sequence-level contrastive pre-training, and OneVocab directly integrates genomic $k$-mers into the language model's existing vocabulary. Comprehensive experiments on classification and reasoning tasks show that, while various alignment strategies improve embedding-level fusion, early vocabulary-level integration yields more expressive and effective representations for DNA-language modeling.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12286v1</guid>
      <category>q-bio.GN</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yanan Li, Christina Yi Jin, Yuan Jin, Manli Luo, Tie Xu, Shuai Jiao, Wei He, Qing Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Musical Descriptors: Extracting Preference-Bearing Intent in Music Queries</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12301</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12301v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Although annotated music descriptor datasets for user queries are increasingly common, few consider the user's intent behind these descriptors, which is essential for effectively meeting their needs. We introduce MusicRecoIntent, a manually annotated corpus of 2,291 Reddit music requests, labeling musical descriptors across seven categories with positive, negative, or referential preference-bearing roles. We then investigate how reliably large language models (LLMs) can extract these music descriptors, finding that they do capture explicit descriptors but struggle with context-dependent ones. This work can further serve as a benchmark for fine-grained modeling of user intent and for gaining insights into improving LLM-based music understanding systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12301v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Marion Baranes, Romain Hennequin, Elena V. Epure</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GT-HarmBench: Benchmarking AI Safety Risks Through the Lens of Game Theory</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12316</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12316v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Frontier AI systems are increasingly capable and deployed in high-stakes multi-agent environments. However, existing AI safety benchmarks largely evaluate single agents, leaving multi-agent risks such as coordination failure and conflict poorly understood. We introduce GT-HarmBench, a benchmark of 2,009 high-stakes scenarios spanning game-theoretic structures such as the Prisoner's Dilemma, Stag Hunt and Chicken. Scenarios are drawn from realistic AI risk contexts in the MIT AI Risk Repository. Across 15 frontier models, agents choose socially beneficial actions in only 62% of cases, frequently leading to harmful outcomes. We measure sensitivity to game-theoretic prompt framing and ordering, and analyze reasoning patterns driving failures. We further show that game-theoretic interventions improve socially beneficial outcomes by up to 18%. Our results highlight substantial reliability gaps and provide a broad standardized testbed for studying alignment in multi-agent environments. The benchmark and code are available at https://github.com/causalNLP/gt-harmbench.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12316v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.GT</category>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Pepijn Cobben, Xuanqiang Angelo Huang, Thao Amelia Pham, Isabel Dahlgren, Terry Jingchen Zhang, Zhijing Jin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolving Beyond Snapshots: Harmonizing Structure and Sequence via Entity State Tuning for Temporal Knowledge Graph Forecasting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12389</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12389v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Temporal knowledge graph (TKG) forecasting requires predicting future facts by jointly modeling structural dependencies within each snapshot and temporal evolution across snapshots. However, most existing methods are stateless: they recompute entity representations at each timestamp from a limited query window, leading to episodic amnesia and rapid decay of long-term dependencies. To address this limitation, we propose Entity State Tuning (EST), an encoder-agnostic framework that endows TKG forecasters with persistent and continuously evolving entity states. EST maintains a global state buffer and progressively aligns structural evidence with sequential signals via a closed-loop design. Specifically, a topology-aware state perceiver first injects entity-state priors into structural encoding. Then, a unified temporal context module aggregates the state-enhanced events with a pluggable sequence backbone. Subsequently, a dual-track evolution mechanism writes the updated context back to the global entity state memory, balancing plasticity against stability. Experiments on multiple benchmarks show that EST consistently improves diverse backbones and achieves state-of-the-art performance, highlighting the importance of state persistence for long-horizon TKG forecasting. The code is published at https://github.com/yuanwuyuan9/Evolving-Beyond-Snapshots</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12389v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Siyuan Li, Yunjia Wu, Yiyong Xiao, Pingyang Huang, Peize Li, Ruitong Liu, Yan Wen, Te Sun, Fangyi Pei</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sparse Autoencoders are Capable LLM Jailbreak Mitigators</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12418</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12418v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Jailbreak attacks remain a persistent threat to large language model safety. We propose Context-Conditioned Delta Steering (CC-Delta), an SAE-based defense that identifies jailbreak-relevant sparse features by comparing token-level representations of the same harmful request with and without jailbreak context. Using paired harmful/jailbreak prompts, CC-Delta selects features via statistical testing and applies inference-time mean-shift steering in SAE latent space. Across four aligned instruction-tuned models and twelve jailbreak attacks, CC-Delta achieves comparable or better safety-utility tradeoffs than baseline defenses operating in dense latent space. In particular, our method clearly outperforms dense mean-shift steering on all four models, and particularly against out-of-distribution attacks, showing that steering in sparse SAE feature space offers advantages over steering in dense activation space for jailbreak mitigation. Our results suggest off-the-shelf SAEs trained for interpretability can be repurposed as practical jailbreak defenses without task-specific training.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12418v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yannick Assogba, Jacopo Cortellazzi, Javier Abad, Pau Rodriguez, Xavier Suau, Arno Blaas</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constraint-Rectified Training for Efficient Chain-of-Thought</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12526</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12526v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Chain-of-Thought (CoT) has significantly enhanced the reasoning capabilities of Large Language Models (LLMs), especially when combined with reinforcement learning (RL) based post-training methods. While longer reasoning traces can improve answer quality and unlock abilities such as self-correction, they also incur high inference costs and often introduce redundant steps, known as overthinking. Recent research seeks to develop efficient reasoning strategies that balance reasoning length and accuracy, either through length-aware reward design or prompt-based calibration. However, these heuristic-based approaches may suffer from severe accuracy drop and be very sensitive to hyperparameters. To address these problems, we introduce CRT (Constraint-Rectified Training), a principled post-training framework based on reference-guarded constrained optimization, yielding a more stable and interpretable formulation for efficient reasoning. CRT alternates between minimizing reasoning length and rectifying accuracy only when performance falls below the reference, enabling stable and effective pruning of redundant reasoning. We further extend CRT with a two-stage training scheme that first discovers the shortest reliable reasoning patterns and then refines accuracy under a learnt length budget, preventing the re-emergence of verbose CoT. Our comprehensive evaluation shows that this framework consistently reduces token usage while maintaining answer quality at a robust and reliable level. Further analysis reveals that CRT improves reasoning efficiency not only by shortening responses but also by reducing internal language redundancy, leading to a new evaluation metric. Moreover, CRT-based training naturally yields a sequence of intermediate checkpoints that span a spectrum of explanation lengths while preserving correctness, enabling fine-grained control over reasoning verbosity without retraining.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12526v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qinhang Wu, Sen Lin, Ming Zhang, Yingbin Liang, Ness B. Shroff</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DiffuRank: Effective Document Reranking with Diffusion Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12528</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12528v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recent advances in large language models (LLMs) have inspired new paradigms for document reranking. While this paradigm better exploits the reasoning and contextual understanding capabilities of LLMs, most existing LLM-based rerankers rely on autoregressive generation, which limits their efficiency and flexibility. In particular, token-by-token decoding incurs high latency, while the fixed left-to-right generation order causes early prediction errors to propagate and is difficult to revise. To address these limitations, we explore the use of diffusion language models (dLLMs) for document reranking and propose DiffuRank, a reranking framework built upon dLLMs. Unlike autoregressive models, dLLMs support more flexible decoding and generation processes that are not constrained to a left-to-right order, and enable parallel decoding, which may lead to improved efficiency and controllability. Specifically, we investigate three reranking strategies based on dLLMs: (1) a pointwise approach that uses dLLMs to estimate the relevance of each query-document pair; (2) a logit-based listwise approach that prompts dLLMs to jointly assess the relevance of multiple documents and derives ranking lists directly from model logits; and (3) a permutation-based listwise approach that adapts the canonical decoding process of dLLMs to the reranking tasks. For each approach, we design corresponding training methods to fully exploit the advantages of dLLMs. We evaluate both zero-shot and fine-tuned reranking performance on multiple benchmarks. Experimental results show that dLLMs achieve performance comparable to, and in some cases exceeding, that of autoregressive LLMs with similar model sizes. These findings demonstrate the promise of diffusion-based language models as a compelling alternative to autoregressive architectures for document reranking.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12528v1</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qi Liu, Kun Ai, Jiaxin Mao, Yanzhao Zhang, Mingxin Li, Dingkun Long, Pengjun Xie, Fengbin Zhu, Ji-Rong Wen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoder-only Conformer with Modality-aware Sparse Mixtures of Experts for ASR</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12546</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12546v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We present a decoder-only Conformer for automatic speech recognition (ASR) that processes speech and text in a single stack without external speech encoders or pretrained large language models (LLM). The model uses a modality-aware sparse mixture of experts (MoE): disjoint expert pools for speech and text with hard routing and top-1 selection, embedded in hybrid-causality Conformer blocks (bidirectional for speech, causal for text). Training combines CTC on speech positions with label-smoothed cross-entropy for text generation. Our 113M-parameter model consistently improves WER over a 139M AED baseline on Librispeech (2.8% vs. 3.2% test-clean; 5.6% vs. 6.0% test-other). On Common Voice 16.1 with a single multilingual model across five languages, our approach reduces average WER from 12.2% to 10.6%. To our knowledge, this is the first randomly initialized decoder-only ASR that surpasses strong AED baselines via modality-aware routing and sparse MoE, achieving better accuracy with fewer active parameters and without alignment/adaptation modules.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12546v1</guid>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jaeyoung Lee, Masato Mimura</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HyperMLP: An Integrated Perspective for Sequence Modeling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12601</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12601v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Self-attention is often viewed as probabilistic query-key lookup, motivating designs that preserve normalized attention scores and fixed positional semantics. We advocate a simpler and more unified perspective: an autoregressive attention head can be viewed as a dynamic two-layer MLP whose weights are instantiated from the context history. From this view, attention scores form an ever-growing hidden representation, and standard MLP activations such as ReLU or GLU naturally implement input-conditioned selection over a context-dependent memory pool rather than a probability distribution. Based on this formulation, we introduce HyperMLP and HyperGLU, which learn dynamic mixing in both feature space and sequence space, using a reverse-offset (lag) layout to align temporal mixing with autoregressive semantics. We provide theoretical characterizations of the expressivity and implications of this structure, and empirically show that HyperMLP/HyperGLU consistently outperform strong softmax-attention baselines under matched parameter budgets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12601v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiecheng Lu, Shihao Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vision Token Reduction via Attention-Driven Self-Compression for Efficient Multimodal Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12618</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12618v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) incur significant computational cost from processing numerous vision tokens through all LLM layers. Prior pruning methods operate either before the LLM, limiting generality due to diverse encoder-projector designs or within the LLM using heuristics that are incompatible with FlashAttention. We take a different approach: rather than identifying unimportant tokens, we treat the LLM itself as the optimal guide for compression. Observing that deeper layers naturally transmit vision-to-text information, we introduce Attention-Driven Self-Compression (ADSC), a simple, broadly applicable method that progressively reduces vision tokens using only the LLM's attention mechanism. Our method applies uniform token downsampling at selected layers, forming bottlenecks that encourage the model to reorganize and compress information into the remaining tokens. It requires no score computation, auxiliary modules, or attention modification, and remains fully compatible with FlashAttention. Applied to LLaVA-1.5, ADSC reduces FLOPs by 53.7% and peak KV-cache memory by 56.7%, while preserving 98.2% of the original model performance. Across multiple benchmarks, it outperforms prior pruning approaches in both efficiency and accuracy. Crucially, under high compression ratios, our method remains robust while heuristic-based techniques degrade sharply.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12618v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Omer Faruk Deniz, Ruiyu Mao, Ruochen Li, Yapeng Tian, Latifur Khan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Think Fast and Slow: Step-Level Cognitive Depth Adaptation for LLM Agents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12662</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12662v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are increasingly deployed as autonomous agents for multi-turn decision-making tasks. However, current agents typically rely on fixed cognitive patterns: non-thinking models generate immediate responses, while thinking models engage in deep reasoning uniformly. This rigidity is inefficient for long-horizon tasks, where cognitive demands vary significantly from step to step, with some requiring strategic planning and others only routine execution. In this paper, we introduce CogRouter, a framework that trains agents to dynamically adapt cognitive depth at each step. Grounded in ACT-R theory, we design four hierarchical cognitive levels ranging from instinctive responses to strategic planning. Our two-stage training approach includes Cognition-aware Supervised Fine-tuning (CoSFT) to instill stable level-specific patterns, and Cognition-aware Policy Optimization (CoPO) for step-level credit assignment via confidence-aware advantage reweighting. The key insight is that appropriate cognitive depth should maximize the confidence of the resulting action. Experiments on ALFWorld and ScienceWorld demonstrate that CogRouter achieves state-of-the-art performance with superior efficiency. With Qwen2.5-7B, it reaches an 82.3% success rate, outperforming GPT-4o (+40.3%), OpenAI-o3 (+18.3%), and GRPO (+14.0%), while using 62% fewer tokens.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12662v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ruihan Yang, Fanghua Ye, Xiang We, Ruoqing Zhao, Kang Luo, Xinbo Xu, Bo Zhao, Ruotian Ma, Shanyi Wang, Zhaopeng Tu, Xiaolong Li, Deqing Yang,  Linus</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VimRAG: Navigating Massive Visual Context in Retrieval-Augmented Generation via Multimodal Memory Graph</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12735</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12735v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Effectively retrieving, reasoning, and understanding multimodal information remains a critical challenge for agentic systems. Traditional Retrieval-augmented Generation (RAG) methods rely on linear interaction histories, which struggle to handle long-context tasks, especially those involving information-sparse yet token-heavy visual data in iterative reasoning scenarios. To bridge this gap, we introduce VimRAG, a framework tailored for multimodal Retrieval-augmented Reasoning across text, images, and videos. Inspired by our systematic study, we model the reasoning process as a dynamic directed acyclic graph that structures the agent states and retrieved multimodal evidence. Building upon this structured memory, we introduce a Graph-Modulated Visual Memory Encoding mechanism, with which the significance of memory nodes is evaluated via their topological position, allowing the model to dynamically allocate high-resolution tokens to pivotal evidence while compressing or discarding trivial clues. To implement this paradigm, we propose a Graph-Guided Policy Optimization strategy. This strategy disentangles step-wise validity from trajectory-level rewards by pruning memory nodes associated with redundant actions, thereby facilitating fine-grained credit assignment. Extensive experiments demonstrate that VimRAG consistently achieves state-of-the-art performance on diverse multimodal RAG benchmarks. The code is available at https://github.com/Alibaba-NLP/VRAG.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12735v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qiuchen Wang, Shihang Wang, Yu Zeng, Qiang Zhang, Fanrui Zhang, Zhuoning Guo, Bosi Zhang, Wenxuan Huang, Lin Chen, Zehui Chen, Pengjun Xie, Ruixue Ding</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Communities and Boundary-Spanning Lyrics in K-pop: A Graph-Based Unsupervised Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12881</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12881v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large-scale lyric corpora present unique challenges for data-driven analysis, including the absence of reliable annotations, multilingual content, and high levels of stylistic repetition. Most existing approaches rely on supervised classification, genre labels, or coarse document-level representations, limiting their ability to uncover latent semantic structure. We present a graph-based framework for unsupervised discovery and evaluation of semantic communities in K-pop lyrics using line-level semantic representations. By constructing a similarity graph over lyric texts and applying community detection, we uncover stable micro-theme communities without genre, artist, or language supervision. We further identify boundary-spanning songs via graph-theoretic bridge metrics and analyse their structural properties. Across multiple robustness settings, boundary-spanning lyrics exhibit higher lexical diversity and lower repetition compared to core community members, challenging the assumption that hook intensity or repetition drives cross-theme connectivity. Our framework is language-agnostic and applicable to unlabeled cultural text corpora.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12881v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Oktay Karaku\c{s}</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RADAR: Revealing Asymmetric Development of Abilities in MLLM Pre-training</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12892</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12892v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Pre-trained Multi-modal Large Language Models (MLLMs) provide a knowledge-rich foundation for post-training by leveraging their inherent perception and reasoning capabilities to solve complex tasks. However, the lack of an efficient evaluation framework impedes the diagnosis of their performance bottlenecks. Current evaluation primarily relies on testing after supervised fine-tuning, which introduces laborious additional training and autoregressive decoding costs. Meanwhile, common pre-training metrics cannot quantify a model's perception and reasoning abilities in a disentangled manner. Furthermore, existing evaluation benchmarks are typically limited in scale or misaligned with pre-training objectives. Thus, we propose RADAR, an efficient ability-centric evaluation framework for Revealing Asymmetric Development of Abilities in MLLM pRe-training. RADAR involves two key components: (1) Soft Discrimination Score, a novel metric for robustly tracking ability development without fine-tuning, based on quantifying nuanced gradations of the model preference for the correct answer over distractors; and (2) Multi-Modal Mixture Benchmark, a new 15K+ sample benchmark for comprehensively evaluating pre-trained MLLMs' perception and reasoning abilities in a 0-shot manner, where we unify authoritative benchmark datasets and carefully collect new datasets, extending the evaluation scope and addressing the critical gaps in current benchmarks. With RADAR, we comprehensively reveal the asymmetric development of perceptual and reasoning capabilities in pretrained MLLMs across diverse factors, including data volume, model size, and pretraining strategy. Our RADAR underscores the need for a decomposed perspective on pre-training ability bottlenecks, informing targeted interventions to advance MLLMs efficiently. Our code is publicly available at https://github.com/Nieysh/RADAR.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12892v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yunshuang Nie, Bingqian Lin, Minzhe Niu, Kun Xiang, Jianhua Han, Guowei Huang, Xingyue Quan, Hang Xu, Bokui Chen, Xiaodan Liang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RGAlign-Rec: Ranking-Guided Alignment for Latent Query Reasoning in Recommendation Systems</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12968</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12968v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Proactive intent prediction is a critical capability in modern e-commerce chatbots, enabling "zero-query" recommendations by anticipating user needs from behavioral and contextual signals. However, existing industrial systems face two fundamental challenges: (1) the semantic gap between discrete user features and the semantic intents within the chatbot's Knowledge Base, and (2) the objective misalignment between general-purpose LLM outputs and task-specific ranking utilities. To address these issues, we propose RGAlign-Rec, a closed-loop alignment framework that integrates an LLM-based semantic reasoner with a Query-Enhanced (QE) ranking model. We also introduce Ranking-Guided Alignment (RGA), a multi-stage training paradigm that utilizes downstream ranking signals as feedback to refine the LLM's latent reasoning. Extensive experiments on a large-scale industrial dataset from Shopee demonstrate that RGAlign-Rec achieves a 0.12% gain in GAUC, leading to a significant 3.52% relative reduction in error rate, and a 0.56% improvement in Recall@3. Online A/B testing further validates the cumulative effectiveness of our framework: the Query-Enhanced model (QE-Rec) initially yields a 0.98% improvement in CTR, while the subsequent Ranking-Guided Alignment stage contributes an additional 0.13% gain. These results indicate that ranking-aware alignment effectively synchronizes semantic reasoning with ranking objectives, significantly enhancing both prediction accuracy and service quality in real-world proactive recommendation systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12968v1</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junhua Liu, Yang Jihao, Cheng Chang, Kunrong LI, Bin Fu, Kwan Hui Lim</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human-Aligned MLLM Judges for Fine-Grained Image Editing Evaluation: A Benchmark, Framework, and Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.13028</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.13028v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Evaluating image editing models remains challenging due to the coarse granularity and limited interpretability of traditional metrics, which often fail to capture aspects important to human perception and intent. Such metrics frequently reward visually plausible outputs while overlooking controllability, edit localization, and faithfulness to user instructions. In this work, we introduce a fine-grained Multimodal Large Language Model (MLLM)-as-a-Judge framework for image editing that decomposes common evaluation notions into twelve fine-grained interpretable factors spanning image preservation, edit quality, and instruction fidelity. Building on this formulation, we present a new human-validated benchmark that integrates human judgments, MLLM-based evaluations, model outputs, and traditional metrics across diverse image editing tasks. Through extensive human studies, we show that the proposed MLLM judges align closely with human evaluations at a fine granularity, supporting their use as reliable and scalable evaluators. We further demonstrate that traditional image editing metrics are often poor proxies for these factors, failing to distinguish over-edited or semantically imprecise outputs, whereas our judges provide more intuitive and informative assessments in both offline and online settings. Together, this work introduces a benchmark, a principled factorization, and empirical evidence positioning fine-grained MLLM judges as a practical foundation for studying, comparing, and improving image editing approaches.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.13028v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Runzhou Liu (University of Virginia), Hailey Weingord (Columbia University), Sejal Mittal (Columbia University), Prakhar Dungarwal (Columbia University), Anusha Nandula (Columbia University), Bo Ni (Vanderbilt University), Samyadeep Basu (Adobe Research), Hongjie Chen (Dolby Laboratories), Nesreen K. Ahmed (Cisco Research), Li Li (University of Southern California), Jiayi Zhang (University of Wisconsin-Madison), Koustava Goswami (Adobe Research), Subhojyoti Mukherjee (Adobe Research), Branislav Kveton (Adobe Research), Puneet Mathur (Adobe Research), Franck Dernoncourt (Adobe Research), Yue Zhao (University of Southern California), Yu Wang (University of Oregon), Ryan A. Rossi (Adobe Research), Zhengzhong Tu (Texas A&amp;M University), Hongru Du (University of Virginia)</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buy versus Build an LLM: A Decision Framework for Governments</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.13033</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.13033v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) represent a new frontier of digital infrastructure that can support a wide range of public-sector applications, from general purpose citizen services to specialized and sensitive state functions. When expanding AI access, governments face a set of strategic choices over whether to buy existing services, build domestic capabilities, or adopt hybrid approaches across different domains and use cases. These are critical decisions especially when leading model providers are often foreign corporations, and LLM outputs are increasingly treated as trusted inputs to public decision-making and public discourse. In practice, these decisions are not intended to mandate a single approach across all domains; instead, national AI strategies are typically pluralistic, with sovereign, commercial and open-source models coexisting to serve different purposes. Governments may rely on commercial models for non-sensitive or commodity tasks, while pursuing greater control for critical, high-risk or strategically important applications.
  This paper provides a strategic framework for making this decision by evaluating these options across dimensions including sovereignty, safety, cost, resource capability, cultural fit, and sustainability. Importantly, "building" does not imply that governments must act alone: domestic capabilities may be developed through public research institutions, universities, state-owned enterprises, joint ventures, or broader national ecosystems. By detailing the technical requirements and practical challenges of each pathway, this work aims to serve as a reference for policy-makers to determine whether a buy or build approach best aligns with their specific national needs and societal goals.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.13033v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CE</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiahao Lu, Ziwei Xu, William Tjhi, Junnan Li, Antoine Bosselut, Pang Wei Koh, Mohan Kankanhalli</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Look Inward to Explore Outward: Learning Temperature Policy from LLM Internal States via Hierarchical RL</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.13035</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.13035v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Reinforcement Learning from Verifiable Rewards (RLVR) trains large language models (LLMs) from sampled trajectories, making decoding strategy a core component of learning rather than a purely inference-time choice. Sampling temperature directly controls the exploration--exploitation trade-off by modulating policy entropy, yet existing methods rely on static values or heuristic adaptations that are decoupled from task-level rewards. We propose Introspective LLM, a hierarchical reinforcement learning framework that learns to control sampling temperature during generation. At each decoding step, the model selects a temperature based on its hidden state and samples the next token from the resulting distribution. Temperature and token policies are jointly optimized from downstream rewards using a coordinate ascent scheme. Experiments on mathematical reasoning benchmarks show that learned temperature policies outperform fixed and heuristic baselines, while exhibiting interpretable exploration behaviors aligned with reasoning uncertainty.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.13035v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yixiao Zhou, Yang Li, Dongzhou Cheng, Hehe Fan, Yu Cheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memory-Efficient Structured Backpropagation for On-Device LLM Fine-Tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.13069</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.13069v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: On-device fine-tuning enables privacy-preserving personalization of large language models, but mobile devices impose severe memory constraints, typically 6--12GB shared across all workloads. Existing approaches force a trade-off between exact gradients with high memory (MeBP) and low memory with noisy estimates (MeZO). We propose Memory-efficient Structured Backpropagation (MeSP), which bridges this gap by manually deriving backward passes that exploit LoRA's low-rank structure. Our key insight is that the intermediate projection $h = xA$ can be recomputed during backward at minimal cost since rank $r \ll d_{in}$, eliminating the need to store it. MeSP achieves 49\% average memory reduction compared to MeBP on Qwen2.5 models (0.5B--3B) while computing mathematically identical gradients. Our analysis also reveals that MeZO's gradient estimates show near-zero correlation with true gradients (cosine similarity $\approx$0.001), explaining its slow convergence. MeSP reduces peak memory from 361MB to 136MB for Qwen2.5-0.5B, enabling fine-tuning scenarios previously infeasible on memory-constrained devices.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.13069v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Juneyoung Park, Yuri Hong, Seongwan Kim, Jaeho Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LCSB: Layer-Cyclic Selective Backpropagation for Memory-Efficient On-Device LLM Fine-Tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.13073</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.13073v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Memory-efficient backpropagation (MeBP) has enabled first-order fine-tuning of large language models (LLMs) on mobile devices with less than 1GB memory. However, MeBP requires backward computation through all transformer layers at every step, where weight decompression alone accounts for 32--42% of backward time. We propose Layer-Cyclic Selective Backpropagation (LCSB), which computes gradients for only a subset of layers per step. Our key insight is that residual connections guarantee gradient flow through identity paths, while AdamW momentum provides implicit updates for non-selected layers. We interpret LCSB as Block Coordinate Descent on the LoRA parameter space, providing theoretical justification for convergence. LCSB achieves up to 1.40$\times$ speedup with less than 2\% quality degradation across five models and three tasks. Surprisingly, in 4-bit quantized settings, LCSB exhibits superior stability: a 3B model that completely diverges under full backpropagation converges smoothly with LCSB, suggesting an implicit regularization effect from selective gradient computation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.13073v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Juneyoung Park, Eunbeen Yoon, Seongwan Kim. Jaeho Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Consistency of Large Reasoning Models Under Multi-Turn Attacks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.13093</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.13093v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large reasoning models with reasoning capabilities achieve state-of-the-art performance on complex tasks, but their robustness under multi-turn adversarial pressure remains underexplored. We evaluate nine frontier reasoning models under adversarial attacks. Our findings reveal that reasoning confers meaningful but incomplete robustness: most reasoning models studied significantly outperform instruction-tuned baselines, yet all exhibit distinct vulnerability profiles, with misleading suggestions universally effective and social pressure showing model-specific efficacy. Through trajectory analysis, we identify five failure modes (Self-Doubt, Social Conformity, Suggestion Hijacking, Emotional Susceptibility, and Reasoning Fatigue) with the first two accounting for 50% of failures. We further demonstrate that Confidence-Aware Response Generation (CARG), effective for standard LLMs, fails for reasoning models due to overconfidence induced by extended reasoning traces; counterintuitively, random confidence embedding outperforms targeted extraction. Our results highlight that reasoning capabilities do not automatically confer adversarial robustness and that confidence-based defenses require fundamental redesign for reasoning models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.13093v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yubo Li, Ramayya Krishnan, Rema Padman</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantization-Robust LLM Unlearning via Low-Rank Adaptation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.13151</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.13151v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large Language Model (LLM) unlearning aims to remove targeted knowledge from a trained model, but practical deployments often require post-training quantization (PTQ) for efficient inference. However, aggressive low-bit PTQ can mask or erase unlearning updates, causing quantized models to revert to pre-unlearning behavior. We show that standard full-parameter fine-tuning often induce parameter changes that are too small to survive 4-bit quantization. We propose quantization-robust unlearning via low-rank adaptation (LoRA): we freeze the base model and concentrate unlearning into trainable adapters so that the effective update is preserved after quantization. On Llama-2-7B evaluated with MUSE dataset (BOOKS and NEWS), LoRA improves 4-bit utility by up to 7.93 points (NPO+GDR on BOOKS: 50.17 to 58.10) and yields higher 4-bit utility on NEWS for GA+GDR (40.06 to 44.82, increase of 4.76). LoRA also substantially reduces privacy leakage under 4-bit PTQ, e.g., for GA+KLR on BOOKS, PrivLeak moves from -25.68 to -5.86 (closer to ideal 0), while maintaining strong forgetting (VerMem and KnowMem near 0). Thus, using LoRA for Machine Unlearning is beneficial for scenarios where quantization is necessary for model deployment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.13151v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jo\~ao Vitor Boer Abitante, Joana Meneguzzo Pasquali, Luan Fonseca Garcia, Ewerton de Oliveira, Thomas da Silva Paula, Rodrigo C. Barros, Lucas S. Kupssinsk\"u</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoPE-VideoLM: Codec Primitives For Efficient Video Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.13191</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.13191v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Video Language Models (VideoLMs) empower AI systems to understand temporal dynamics in videos. To fit to the maximum context window constraint, current methods use keyframe sampling which can miss both macro-level events and micro-level details due to the sparse temporal coverage. Furthermore, processing full images and their tokens for each frame incurs substantial computational overhead. To address these limitations, we propose to leverage video codec primitives (specifically motion vectors and residuals) which natively encode video redundancy and sparsity without requiring expensive full-image encoding for most frames. To this end, we introduce lightweight transformer-based encoders that aggregate codec primitives and align their representations with image encoder embeddings through a pre-training strategy that accelerates convergence during end-to-end fine-tuning. Our approach reduces the time-to-first-token by up to $86\%$ and token usage by up to $93\%$ compared to standard VideoLMs. Moreover, by varying the keyframe and codec primitive densities we are able to maintain or exceed performance on $14$ diverse video understanding benchmarks spanning general question answering, temporal reasoning, long-form understanding, and spatial scene understanding.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.13191v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sayan Deb Sarkar, R\'emi Pautrat, Ondrej Miksik, Marc Pollefeys, Iro Armeni, Mahdi Rad, Mihai Dusmanu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CATP: Cross-Attention Token Pruning for Accuracy Preserved Multimodal Model Inference</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.08567</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.08567v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In response to the rising interest in large multimodal models, we introduce Cross-Attention Token Pruning (CATP), a precision-focused token pruning method. Our approach leverages cross-attention layers in multimodal models, exemplified by BLIP-2, to extract valuable information for token importance determination. CATP employs a refined voting strategy across model heads and layers. In evaluations, CATP achieves up to 12.1X higher accuracy compared to existing token pruning methods, addressing the trade-off between computational efficiency and model precision.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.08567v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ruqi Liao, Chuqing Zhao, Jin Li, Weiqi Feng, Yi Lyu, Bingxian Chen, Haochen Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Foundations and Evaluations in NLP</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.01342</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.01342v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This memoir explores two fundamental aspects of Natural Language Processing (NLP): the creation of linguistic resources and the evaluation of NLP system performance. Over the past decade, my work has focused on developing a morpheme-based annotation scheme for the Korean language that captures linguistic properties from morphology to semantics. This approach has achieved state-of-the-art results in various NLP tasks, including part-of-speech tagging, dependency parsing, and named entity recognition. Additionally, this work provides a comprehensive analysis of segmentation granularity and its critical impact on NLP system performance. In parallel with linguistic resource development, I have proposed a novel evaluation framework, the jp-algorithm, which introduces an alignment-based method to address challenges in preprocessing tasks like tokenization and sentence boundary detection (SBD). Traditional evaluation methods assume identical tokenization and sentence lengths between gold standards and system outputs, limiting their applicability to real-world data. The jp-algorithm overcomes these limitations, enabling robust end-to-end evaluations across a variety of NLP tasks. It enhances accuracy and flexibility by incorporating linear-time alignment while preserving the complexity of traditional evaluation metrics. This memoir provides key insights into the processing of morphologically rich languages, such as Korean, while offering a generalizable framework for evaluating diverse end-to-end NLP systems. My contributions lay the foundation for future developments, with broader implications for multilingual resource development and system evaluation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.01342v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jungyeul Park</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RAISE: Reinforced Adaptive Instruction Selection For Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.07282</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.07282v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In the instruction fine-tuning of large language models (LLMs), it is widely recognized that a few high-quality instructions are superior to a large number of low-quality instructions. At present, many instruction selection methods have been proposed, but most of these methods select instruction based on heuristic quality metrics, and only consider data selection before training. These designs lead to insufficient optimization of instruction fine-tuning, and fixed heuristic indicators are often difficult to optimize for specific tasks. Therefore, we design a dynamic, task-objective-driven instruction selection framework RAISE(Reinforced Adaptive Instruction SElection), which incorporates the entire instruction fine-tuning process into optimization, selecting instructions at each step based on the expected impact of each instruction on model performance improvement. Our approach is well interpretable and has strong task-specific optimization capabilities. By modeling dynamic instruction selection as a sequential decision-making process, we use RL to train our selection strategy. Extensive experiments and result analysis prove the superiority of our method compared with other instruction selection methods. Notably, RAISE achieves superior performance by updating only 1% of the training steps compared to full-data training, demonstrating its efficiency and effectiveness.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.07282v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qingsong Lv, Yangning Li, Zihua Lan, Zishan Xu, Jiwei Tang, Tingwei Lu, Yinghui Li, Wenhao Jiang, Hong-Gee Kim, Hai-Tao Zheng, Philip S. Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PReSS: A Black-Box Framework for Evaluating Political Stance Stability in LLMs via Argumentative Pressure</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.17052</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.17052v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Existing evaluations of political bias in large language models (LLMs) typically classify outputs as left- or right-leaning. We extend this perspective by examining how ideological tendencies vary across topics and how consistently models maintain their positions, a property we refer to as stability. To capture this dimension, we propose PReSS (Political Response Stability under Stress), a black-box framework that evaluates LLMs by jointly considering model and topic context, categorizing responses into four stance types: stable-left, unstable-left, stable-right, and unstable-right. Applying PReSS to 12 widely used LLMs across 19 political topics reveals substantial variation in stance stability; for instance, a model that is left-leaning overall can exhibit stable-right behavior on certain topics. This highlights the importance of topic-aware and fine-grained evaluation of political ideologies of LLMs. Moreover, stability has practical implications for controlled generation and model alignment: interventions such as debiasing or ideology reversal should explicitly account for stance stability. Our empirical analyses reveal that when models are prompted or fine-tuned to adopt the opposite ideology, unstable topic stances are more likely to change, whereas stable ones resist modification. Thus, treating stability as a moderating factor provides a principled foundation for understanding, evaluating, and guiding interventions in politically sensitive model behavior.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.17052v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shariar Kabir, Kevin Esterling, Yue Dong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Embodied Agents Meet Personalization: Investigating Challenges and Solutions Through the Lens of Memory Utilization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.16348</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.16348v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: LLM-powered embodied agents have shown success on conventional object-rearrangement tasks, but providing personalized assistance that leverages user-specific knowledge from past interactions presents new challenges. We investigate these challenges through the lens of agents' memory utilization along two critical dimensions: object semantics (identifying objects based on personal meaning) and user patterns (recalling sequences from behavioral routines). To assess these capabilities, we construct MEMENTO, an end-to-end two-stage evaluation framework comprising single-memory and joint-memory tasks. Our experiments reveal that current agents can recall simple object semantics but struggle to apply sequential user patterns to planning. Through in-depth analysis, we identify two critical bottlenecks: information overload and coordination failures when handling multiple memories. Based on these findings, we explore memory architectural approaches to address these challenges. Given our observation that episodic memory provides both personalized knowledge and in-context learning benefits, we design a hierarchical knowledge graph-based user-profile memory module that separately manages personalized knowledge, achieving substantial improvements on both single and joint-memory tasks. Project website: https://connoriginal.github.io/MEMENTO</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.16348v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Taeyoon Kwon, Dongwook Choi, Hyojun Kim, Sunghwan Kim, Seungjun Moon, Beong-woo Kwak, Kuan-Hao Huang, Jinyoung Yeo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlight &amp; Summarize: RAG without the jailbreaks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.02872</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.02872v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Preventing jailbreaking and model hijacking of Large Language Models (LLMs) is an important yet challenging task. When interacting with a chatbot, malicious users can input specially crafted prompts that cause the LLM to generate undesirable content or perform a different task from its intended purpose. Existing systems attempt to mitigate this by hardening the LLM's system prompt or using additional classifiers to detect undesirable content or off-topic conversations. However, these probabilistic approaches are relatively easy to bypass due to the very large space of possible inputs and undesirable outputs. We present and evaluate Highlight &amp; Summarize (H&amp;S), a new design pattern for retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) systems that prevents these attacks by design. The core idea is to perform the same task as a standard RAG pipeline (i.e., to provide natural language answers to questions, based on relevant sources) without ever revealing the user's question to the generative LLM. This is achieved by splitting the pipeline into two components: a highlighter, which takes the user's question and extracts ("highlights") relevant passages from the retrieved documents, and a summarizer, which takes the highlighted passages and summarizes them into a cohesive answer. We describe and implement several possible instantiations of H&amp;S and evaluate their responses in terms of correctness, relevance, and quality. For certain question-answering (QA) tasks, the responses produced by H&amp;S are judged to be as good, if not better, than those of a standard RAG pipeline.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.02872v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Giovanni Cherubin, Andrew Paverd</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Safety Alignment Evaluation of LLMs in Chinese Mental Health Dialogues via LLM-as-Judge</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.08236</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.08236v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Evaluating the safety alignment of LLM responses in high-risk mental health dialogues is particularly difficult due to missing gold-standard answers and the ethically sensitive nature of these interactions. To address this challenge, we propose PsyCrisis-Bench, a reference-free evaluation benchmark based on real-world Chinese mental health dialogues. It evaluates whether the model responses align with the safety principles defined by experts. Specifically designed for settings without standard references, our method adopts a prompt-based LLM-as-Judge approach that conducts in-context evaluation using expert-defined reasoning chains grounded in psychological intervention principles. We employ binary point-wise scoring across multiple safety dimensions to enhance the explainability and traceability of the evaluation. Additionally, we present a manually curated, high-quality Chinese-language dataset covering self-harm, suicidal ideation, and existential distress, derived from real-world online discourse. Experiments on 3600 judgments show that our method achieves the highest agreement with expert assessments and produces more interpretable evaluation rationales compared to existing approaches. Our dataset and evaluation tool are publicly available to facilitate further research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.08236v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yunna Cai, Fan Wang, Haowei Wang, Kun Wang, Kailai Yang, Sophia Ananiadou, Moyan Li, Mingming Fan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MLLM-CTBench: A Benchmark for Continual Instruction Tuning with Reasoning Process Diagnosis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.08275</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.08275v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Continual instruction tuning(CIT) during the post-training phase is crucial for adapting multimodal large language models (MLLMs) to evolving real-world demands. However, the progress is hampered by the lack of benchmarks with rigorous, protocol-consistent evaluation. To bridge this gap, we introduce MLLM-CTBench, a comprehensive benchmark for CIT of MLLMs, covering seven challenging tasks across six diverse domains. MLLM-CTBench makes three key contributions. First, we establish a multidimensional evaluation framework that jointly assesses final-answer accuracy and process-level reasoning quality, where Chain-of-Thought (CoT) traces serve as an observable signal to diagnose catastrophic forgetting beyond answer-only evaluation. Second, we conduct a large-scale evaluation of continual learning methods by systematically assessing eight representative algorithms from four major families under a unified protocol across task orders, providing actionable insights for algorithm design. Third, we expand the scope from Supervised Fine-Tuning (SFT) to Reinforcement Fine-Tuning (RFT) in CIT. By investigating GRPO, an on-policy RL algorithm that stabilizes updates through explicit KL-divergence control to a prior policy, we aim to analyze how this mechanism affects cross-task knowledge retention. Our experiments yield several findings:(1) Process-level reasoning quality is often more resilient to catastrophic forgetting than final-answer accuracy, and forgetting is primarily driven by degradation in domain knowledge. (2) Model capability is critical factor influencing continual learning outcomes, with stronger baseline models exhibiting greater resistance to catastrophic forgetting. (3) On-policy RFT (GRPO), with its inherent KL control, achieves more stable cross-task retention than SFT. While removing KL control can amplify forgetting despite potential gains on new ones.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.08275v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haiyun Guo, Zhiyan Hou, Yandu Sun, Jinghan He, Yu Chen, Yuzhe Zhou, Yuheng Jia, Jinqiao Wang, Tat-Seng Chua</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ToolACE-MT: Non-Autoregressive Generation for Agentic Multi-Turn Interaction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.12685</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.12685v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Agentic task-solving with Large Language Models (LLMs) requires multi-turn, multi-step interactions, often involving complex function calls and dynamic user-agent exchanges. Existing simulation-based data generation methods for such scenarios rely heavily on costly autoregressive interactions between multiple LLM agents, thereby compromising the practical efficiency of agentic data generation. In this paper, we propose ToolACE-MT, a novel Non-Autoregressive Iterative Generation framework for constructing high-quality multi-turn agentic dialogues. ToolACE-MT generates full conversational trajectories through three stages: coarse-grained initialization, iterative refinement, and offline verification. The initialization phase builds a structurally complete yet semantically coarse dialogue skeleton; the iterative refinement phase introduces realistic complexities and continued refinement via mask-and-fill operations; and the offline verification phase ensures correctness and coherence via rule- and model-based checks. Experiments demonstrate that ToolACE-MT enables efficient, effective and generalizable agentic data generation, offering a new paradigm for high-quality data construction in tool-augmented LLM scenarios.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.12685v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xingshan Zeng, Weiwen Liu, Lingzhi Wang, Liangyou Li, Fei Mi, Yasheng Wang, Lifeng Shang, Xin Jiang, Qun Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Mediomatix Corpus: Parallel Data for Romansh Language Varieties via Comparable Schoolbooks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.16371</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.16371v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The five idioms (i.e., varieties) of the Romansh language are largely standardized and are taught in the schools of the respective communities in Switzerland. In this paper, we present the first parallel corpus of Romansh idioms. The corpus is based on 291 schoolbook volumes, which are comparable in content for the five idioms. We use automatic alignment methods to extract 207k multi-parallel segments from the books, with more than 2M tokens in total. A small-scale human evaluation confirms that the segments are highly parallel, making the dataset suitable for NLP applications such as machine translation between Romansh idioms. We release the parallel and unaligned versions of the dataset under a CC-BY-NC-SA license and demonstrate its utility for machine translation by training and evaluating an LLM and a supervised multilingual MT model on the dataset.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.16371v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zachary Hopton, Jannis Vamvas, Andrin B\"uchler, Anna Rutkiewicz, Rico Cathomas, Rico Sennrich</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TASO: Task-Aligned Sparse Optimization for Parameter-Efficient Model Adaptation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.17688</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.17688v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: LoRA has become one of the most widely used parameter-efficient fine-tuning methods due to its simplicity and effectiveness. However, numerous studies have shown that LoRA often introduces substantial parameter redundancy, which not only increases the number of trainable parameters but also hinders the effectiveness of fine-tuning. Since identifying redundant parameters in LoRA is inherently difficult, how to eliminate them efficiently and accurately remains a challenging problem. In this paper, we propose TASO, a redundancy reduction method that leverages importance information from the pretrained model's weights to mitigate LoRA redundancy. Specifically, we estimate parameter importance on downstream tasks and identify task-specific core regions based on the distribution of importance scores. The location information of these core regions is then used to determine the sparse structure of LoRA modules, enabling redundancy removal before fine-tuning. Our approach significantly reduces the number of trainable parameters required for task adaptation, while providing a novel task-aligned perspective for LoRA redundancy reduction. Experimental results demonstrate that, with a parameter budget comparable to LoRA with rank $r = 1$, TASO consistently outperforms standard LoRA across multiple tasks, achieving strong fine-tuning performance while effectively eliminating redundant parameters.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.17688v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Daiye Miao, Yufang Liu, Jie Wang, Changzhi Sun, Yunke Zhang, Demei Yan, Shaokang Dong, Qi Zhang, Yuanbin Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HEART: Emotionally-Driven Test-Time Scaling of Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.22876</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.22876v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Test-time scaling has significantly improved how AI models solve problems, yet current methods often get stuck in repetitive, incorrect patterns of thought. We introduce HEART, a framework that uses emotional cues to guide the model's focus, much like how feelings contribute to human decision-making. By alternating between critical tones to sharpen error detection and encouraging tones to spark new ideas, HEART helps the model break out of dead-end reasoning and find the right solution. We evaluate HEART across seven high-difficulty benchmarks--including Humanity's Last Exam, GPQA Diamond, and LiveCodeBench--demonstrating robustness across diverse models. Results show that emotion facilitates deeper reasoning, yielding consistent accuracy gains over affect-sterile baselines. These findings suggest that the next frontier in machine reasoning lies in the strategic integration of affective regulation to guide logical synthesis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.22876v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gabriela Pinto, Palash Goyal, Mihir Parmar, Yiwen Song, Souradip Chakraborty, Zifeng Wang, Jinsung Yoon, Hamid Palangi, Tomas Pfister</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low-Resource Dialect Adaptation of Large Language Models: A French Dialect Case-Study</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.22747</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.22747v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Despite the widespread adoption of large language models (LLMs), their strongest capabilities remain largely confined to a small number of high-resource languages for which there is abundant training data. Recently, continual pre-training (CPT) has emerged as a means to fine-tune these models to low-resource regional dialects. In this paper, we study the use of CPT for dialect learning under tight data and compute budgets. Using low-rank adaptation (LoRA) and compute-efficient continual pre-training, we adapt three LLMs to the Qu\'ebec French dialect using a very small dataset and benchmark them on the COLE suite. Our experiments demonstrate an improvement on the minority dialect benchmarks with minimal regression on the prestige language benchmarks with under 1% of model parameters updated. Analysis of the results demonstrate that gains are highly contingent on corpus composition. These findings indicate that CPT with parameter-efficient fine-tuning (PEFT) can narrow the dialect gap by providing cost-effective and sustainable language resource creation, expanding high-quality LLM access to minority linguistic communities. We release the first Qu\'ebec French LLMs on HuggingFace.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.22747v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Eeham Khan, Firas Saidani, Owen Van Esbroeck, Richard Khoury, Leila Kosseim</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reasoning about Intent for Ambiguous Requests</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.10453</link>
      <description>arXiv:2511.10453v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models often respond to ambiguous requests by implicitly committing to one interpretation. Intent misunderstandings can frustrate users and create safety risks. To address this, we propose generating multiple interpretation-answer pairs in a single structured response to ambiguous requests. Our models are trained with reinforcement learning and customized reward functions using multiple valid answers as supervision. Experiments on conversational question answering and semantic parsing demonstrate that our method achieves higher coverage of valid answers than baseline approaches. Human evaluation confirms that predicted interpretations are highly aligned with their answers. Our approach promotes transparency with explicit interpretations, achieves efficiency by requiring only one generation step, and supports downstream applications through its structured output format.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2511.10453v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Irina Saparina, Mirella Lapata</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SGM: Safety Glasses for Multimodal Large Language Models via Neuron-Level Detoxification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.15052</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.15052v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Disclaimer: Samples in this paper may be harmful and cause discomfort.
  Multimodal large language models (MLLMs) enable multimodal generation but inherit toxic, biased, and NSFW signals from weakly curated pretraining corpora, causing safety risks, especially under adversarial triggers that late, opaque training-free detoxification methods struggle to handle. We propose SGM, a white-box neuron-level multimodal intervention that acts like safety glasses for toxic neurons: it selectively recalibrates a small set of toxic expert neurons via expertise-weighted soft suppression, neutralizing harmful cross-modal activations without any parameter updates. We establish MM-TOXIC-QA, a multimodal toxicity evaluation framework, and compare SGM with existing detoxification techniques. Experiments on open-source MLLMs show that SGM mitigates toxicity in standard and adversarial conditions, cutting harmful rates from 48.2\% to 2.5\% while preserving fluency and multimodal reasoning. SGM is extensible, and its combined defenses, denoted as SGM*, integrate with existing detoxification methods for stronger safety performance, providing an interpretable, low-cost solution for toxicity-controlled multimodal generation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.15052v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hongbo Wang, MaungMaung AprilPyone, Isao Echizen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing and Improving Punctuation Robustness in English-Marathi Machine Translation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.09725</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.09725v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Neural Machine Translation (NMT) systems rely heavily on explicit punctuation cues to resolve semantic ambiguities in a source sentence. Inputting user-generated sentences, which are likely to contain missing or incorrect punctuation, results in fluent but semantically disastrous translations. This work attempts to highlight and address the problem of punctuation robustness of NMT systems through an English-to-Marathi translation. First, we introduce \textbf{\textit{Viram}}, a human-curated diagnostic benchmark of 54 punctuation-ambiguous English-Marathi sentence pairs to stress-test existing NMT systems. Second, we evaluate two simple remediation strategies: cascade-based \textit{restore-then-translate} and \textit{direct fine-tuning}. Our experimental results and analysis demonstrate that both strategies yield substantial NMT performance improvements. Furthermore, we find that current Large Language Models (LLMs) exhibit relatively poorer robustness in translating such sentences than these task-specific strategies, thus necessitating further research in this area. The code and dataset are available at https://github.com/KaustubhShejole/Viram_Marathi.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.09725v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kaustubh Shivshankar Shejole, Sourabh Deoghare, Pushpak Bhattacharyya</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which Reasoning Trajectories Teach Students to Reason Better? A Simple Metric of Informative Alignment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.14249</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.14249v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Long chain-of-thought (CoT) trajectories provide rich supervision signals for distilling reasoning from teacher to student LLMs. However, both prior work and our experiments show that trajectories from stronger teachers do not necessarily yield better students, highlighting the importance of data-student suitability in distillation. Existing methods assess suitability primarily through student likelihood, favoring trajectories that align closely with the student model's current behavior but overlooking more informative ones. Addressing this, we propose Rank-Surprisal Ratio (RSR), a simple metric that captures both alignment and informativeness to assess the suitability of a reasoning trajectory. RSR is motivated by the observation that effective trajectories typically balance learning signal strength and behavioral alignment by combining low absolute probability with relatively high-ranked tokens under the student model. Concretely, RSR is defined as the ratio of a trajectory's average token-wise rank to its average negative log-likelihood, and is straightforward to compute and interpret. Across five student models and reasoning trajectories from 11 diverse teachers, RSR strongly correlates with post-training reasoning performance (average Spearman 0.86), consistently outperforming existing metrics. We further demonstrate its practical utility in both trajectory selection and teacher selection.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.14249v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuming Yang, Mingyoung Lai, Wanxu Zhao, Xiaoran Fan, Zhiheng Xi, Mingqi Wu, Chiyue Huang, Jun Zhao, Haijun Lv, Jian Tong, Yunhua Zhou, Yicheng Zou, Qipeng Guo, Tao Gui, Qi Zhang, Xuanjing Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Layer-wise Swapping for Generalizable Multilingual Safety</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.22620</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.22620v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Despite the rapid advancements of Large Language Models (LLMs), safety risks remain a critical challenge for low-resource languages. Existing safety datasets are predominantly English centric, limiting progress in multilingual safety alignment. As a result, low resource expert models, finetuned on their respective instruction datasets, tend to exhibit higher unsafety rates compared to their high resource counterparts. In this work, we propose a safety aware layer swapping method that transfers safety alignment from an English safety expert to low resource language experts without additional training. To further enhance transfer ability, our method adaptively selects or blends modules based on their degree of specialization. Our approach preserves performance on general language understanding tasks while enhancing safety in the target languages. Experimental results show that the proposed method achieves comparable performance to the language expert on general benchmarks such as MMMLU, BELEBELE, and MGSM, while producing more aligned and less harmful responses on the MultiJail safety benchmark.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.22620v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hyunseo Shin, Wonseok Hwang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reinforced Attention Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04884</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.04884v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Post-training with Reinforcement Learning (RL) has substantially improved reasoning in Large Language Models (LLMs) via test-time scaling. However, extending this paradigm to Multimodal LLMs (MLLMs) through verbose rationales yields limited gains for perception and can even degrade performance.
  We propose Reinforced Attention Learning (RAL), a policy-gradient framework that directly optimizes internal attention distributions rather than output token sequences. By shifting optimization from what to generate to where to attend, RAL promotes effective information allocation and improved grounding in complex multimodal inputs. Experiments across diverse image and video benchmarks show consistent gains over GRPO and other baselines. We further introduce On-Policy Attention Distillation, demonstrating that transferring latent attention behaviors yields stronger cross-modal alignment than standard knowledge distillation. Our results position attention policies as a principled and general alternative for multimodal post-training.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.04884v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bangzheng Li, Jianmo Ni, Chen Qu, Ian Miao, Liu Yang, Xingyu Fu, Muhao Chen, Derek Zhiyuan Cheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SciClaimEval: Cross-modal Claim Verification in Scientific Papers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.07621</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.07621v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We present SciClaimEval, a new scientific dataset for the claim verification task. Unlike existing resources, SciClaimEval features authentic claims, including refuted ones, directly extracted from published papers. To create refuted claims, we introduce a novel approach that modifies the supporting evidence (figures and tables), rather than altering the claims or relying on large language models (LLMs) to fabricate contradictions. The dataset provides cross-modal evidence with diverse representations: figures are available as images, while tables are provided in multiple formats, including images, LaTeX source, HTML, and JSON. SciClaimEval contains 1,664 annotated samples from 180 papers across three domains, machine learning, natural language processing, and medicine, validated through expert annotation. We benchmark 11 multimodal foundation models, both open-source and proprietary, across the dataset. Results show that figure-based verification remains particularly challenging for all models, as a substantial performance gap remains between the best system and human baseline.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.07621v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xanh Ho, Yun-Ang Wu, Sunisth Kumar, Tian Cheng Xia, Florian Boudin, Andre Greiner-Petter, Akiko Aizawa</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bielik Guard: Efficient Polish Language Safety Classifiers for LLM Content Moderation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.07954</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.07954v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: As Large Language Models (LLMs) become increasingly deployed in Polish language applications, the need for efficient and accurate content safety classifiers has become paramount. We present Bielik Guard, a family of compact Polish language safety classifiers comprising two model variants: a 0.1B parameter model based on MMLW-RoBERTa-base and a 0.5B parameter model based on PKOBP/polish-roberta-8k. Fine-tuned on a community-annotated dataset of 6,885 Polish texts, these models classify content across five safety categories: Hate/Aggression, Vulgarities, Sexual Content, Crime, and Self-Harm. Our evaluation demonstrates that both models achieve strong performance on multiple benchmarks. The 0.5B variant offers the best overall discrimination capability with F1 scores of 0.791 (micro) and 0.785 (macro) on the test set, while the 0.1B variant demonstrates exceptional efficiency. Notably, Bielik Guard 0.1B v1.1 achieves superior precision (77.65%) and very low false positive rate (0.63%) on real user prompts, outperforming HerBERT-PL-Guard (31.55% precision, 4.70% FPR) despite identical model size. The models are publicly available and designed to provide appropriate responses rather than simple content blocking, particularly for sensitive categories like self-harm.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.07954v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Krzysztof Wr\'obel, Jan Maria Kowalski, Jerzy Surma, Igor Ciuciura, Maciej Szyma\'nski</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Language Models and Impossible Language Acquisition: "False Promise" or an Overturn of our Current Perspective towards AI</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.08437</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.08437v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In Chomsky's provocative critique "The False Promise of CHATGPT," Large Language Models (LLMs) are characterized as mere pattern predictors that do not acquire languages via intrinsic causal and self-correction structures like humans, therefore are not able to distinguish impossible languages. It stands as a representative in a fundamental challenge to the intellectual foundations of AI, for it integrally synthesizes major issues in methodologies within LLMs and possesses an iconic a priori rationalist perspective. We examine this famous critic from both the perspective in pre-existing literature of linguistics and psychology as well as a research based on an experiment inquiring the capacity of learning both possible and impossible languages among LLMs. We constructed a set of syntactically impossible languages by applying certain transformations to English. These include reversing whole sentences, and adding negation based on word-count parity. Two rounds of controlled experiments were each conducted on GPT-2 small models and long short-term memory (LSTM) models. Statistical analysis (Welch's t-test) shows GPT2 small models underperform in learning all of the impossible languages compared to their performance on the possible language (p&lt;.001). On the other hand, LSTM models' performance tallies with Chomsky's argument, suggesting the irreplaceable role of the evolution of transformer architecture. Based on theoretical analysis and empirical findings, we propose a new vision within Chomsky's theory towards LLMs, and a shift of theoretical paradigm outside Chomsky, from his "rationalist-romantics" paradigm to functionalism and empiricism in LLMs research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.08437v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ziyan Wang, Longlong Ma</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GISA: A Benchmark for General Information-Seeking Assistant</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.08543</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.08543v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The advancement of large language models (LLMs) has significantly accelerated the development of search agents capable of autonomously gathering information through multi-turn web interactions. Various benchmarks have been proposed to evaluate such agents. However, existing benchmarks often construct queries backward from answers, producing unnatural tasks misaligned with real-world needs. Moreover, these benchmarks tend to focus on either locating specific information or aggregating information from multiple sources, while relying on static answer sets prone to data contamination. To bridge these gaps, we introduce GISA, a benchmark for General Information-Seeking Assistants comprising 373 human-crafted queries that reflect authentic information-seeking scenarios. GISA features four structured answer formats (item, set, list, and table), enabling deterministic evaluation. It integrates both deep reasoning and broad information aggregation within unified tasks, and includes a live subset with periodically updated answers to resist memorization. Notably, GISA provides complete human search trajectories for every query, offering gold-standard references for process-level supervision and imitation learning. Experiments on mainstream LLMs and commercial search products reveal that even the best-performing model achieves only 19.30\% exact match score, with performance notably degrading on tasks requiring complex planning and comprehensive information gathering. These findings highlight substantial room for future improvement.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.08543v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yutao Zhu, Xingshuo Zhang, Maosen Zhang, Jiajie Jin, Liancheng Zhang, Xiaoshuai Song, Kangzhi Zhao, Wencong Zeng, Ruiming Tang, Han Li, Ji-Rong Wen, Zhicheng Dou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Triggers Hijack Language Circuits: A Mechanistic Analysis of Backdoor Behaviors in Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10382</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.10382v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Backdoor attacks pose significant security risks for Large Language Models (LLMs), yet the internal mechanisms by which triggers operate remain poorly understood. We present the first mechanistic analysis of language-switching backdoors, studying the GAPperon model family (1B, 8B, 24B parameters) which contains triggers injected during pretraining that cause output language switching. Using activation patching, we localize trigger formation to early layers (7.5-25% of model depth) and identify which attention heads process trigger information. Our central finding is that trigger-activated heads substantially overlap with heads naturally encoding output language across model scales, with Jaccard indices between 0.18 and 0.66 over the top heads identified. This suggests that backdoor triggers do not form isolated circuits but instead co-opt the model's existing language components. These findings have implications for backdoor defense: detection methods may benefit from monitoring known functional components rather than searching for hidden circuits, and mitigation strategies could potentially leverage this entanglement between injected and natural behaviors.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.10382v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Th\'eo Lasnier, Wissam Antoun, Francis Kulumba, Djam\'e Seddah</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Tables Go Crazy: Evaluating Multimodal Models on French Financial Documents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10384</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.10384v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Vision-language models (VLMs) perform well on many document understanding tasks, yet their reliability in specialized, non-English domains remains underexplored. This gap is especially critical in finance, where documents mix dense regulatory text, numerical tables, and visual charts, and where extraction errors can have real-world consequences. We introduce Multimodal Finance Eval, the first multimodal benchmark for evaluating French financial document understanding. The dataset contains 1,204 expert-validated questions spanning text extraction, table comprehension, chart interpretation, and multi-turn conversational reasoning, drawn from real investment prospectuses, KIDs, and PRIIPs. We evaluate six open-weight VLMs (8B-124B parameters) using an LLM-as-judge protocol. While models achieve strong performance on text and table tasks (85-90% accuracy), they struggle with chart interpretation (34-62%). Most notably, multi-turn dialogue reveals a sharp failure mode: early mistakes propagate across turns, driving accuracy down to roughly 50% regardless of model size.
  These results show that current VLMs are effective for well-defined extraction tasks but remain brittle in interactive, multi-step financial analysis. Multimodal Finance Eval offers a challenging benchmark to measure and drive progress in this high-stakes setting.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.10384v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Virginie Mouilleron, Th\'eo Lasnier, Djam\'e Seddah</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Less is Enough: Synthesizing Diverse Data in Feature Space of LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10388</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.10388v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The diversity of post-training data is critical for effective downstream performance in large language models (LLMs). Many existing approaches to constructing post-training data quantify diversity using text-based metrics that capture linguistic variation, but such metrics provide only weak signals for the task-relevant features that determine downstream performance. In this work, we introduce Feature Activation Coverage (FAC) which measures data diversity in an interpretable feature space. Building upon this metric, we further propose a diversity-driven data synthesis framework, named FAC Synthesis, that first uses a sparse autoencoder to identify missing features from a seed dataset, and then generates synthetic samples that explicitly reflect these features. Experiments show that our approach consistently improves both data diversity and downstream performance on various tasks, including instruction following, toxicity detection, reward modeling, and behavior steering. Interestingly, we identify a shared, interpretable feature space across model families (i.e., LLaMA, Mistral, and Qwen), enabling cross-model knowledge transfer. Our work provides a solid and practical methodology for exploring data-centric optimization of LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.10388v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhongzhi Li, Xuansheng Wu, Yijiang Li, Lijie Hu, Ninghao Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Targeted Syntactic Evaluation of Language Models on Georgian Case Alignment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10661</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.10661v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper evaluates the performance of transformer-based language models on split-ergative case alignment in Georgian, a particularly rare system for assigning grammatical cases to mark argument roles. We focus on subject and object marking determined through various permutations of nominative, ergative, and dative noun forms. A treebank-based approach for the generation of minimal pairs using the Grew query language is implemented. We create a dataset of 370 syntactic tests made up of seven tasks containing 50-70 samples each, where three noun forms are tested in any given sample. Five encoder- and two decoder-only models are evaluated with word- and/or sentence-level accuracy metrics. Regardless of the specific syntactic makeup, models performed worst in assigning the ergative case correctly and strongest in assigning the nominative case correctly. Performance correlated with the overall frequency distribution of the three forms (NOM &gt; DAT &gt; ERG). Though data scarcity is a known issue for low-resource languages, we show that the highly specific role of the ergative along with a lack of available training data likely contributes to poor performance on this case. The dataset is made publicly available and the methodology provides an interesting avenue for future syntactic evaluations of languages where benchmarks are limited.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.10661v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Daniel Gallagher, Gerhard Heyer</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Phenomenology of Temporal Experience in Autism: Quantifying the Emotional and Narrative Characteristics of Lived Unpredictability</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10947</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.10947v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Disturbances in temporality, such as desynchronization with the social environment and its unpredictability, are considered core features of autism with a deep impact on relationships. However, limitations regarding research on this issue include: 1) the dominance of deficit-based medical models of autism, 2) sample size in qualitative research, and 3) the lack of phenomenological anchoring in computational research. To bridge the gap between phenomenological and computational approaches and overcome sample-size limitations, our research integrated three methodologies. Study A: structured phenomenological interviews with autistic individuals using the Transdiagnostic Assessment of Temporal Experience. Study B: computational analysis of an autobiographical corpus of autistic narratives built for this purpose. Study C: a replication of a computational study using narrative flow measures to assess the perceived phenomenological authenticity of autistic autobiographies. Interviews revealed that the most significant differences between the autistic and control groups concerned unpredictability of experience. Computational results mirrored these findings: the temporal lexicon in autistic narratives was significantly more negatively valenced - particularly the "Immediacy &amp; Suddenness" category. Outlier analysis identified terms associated with perceived discontinuity (unpredictably, precipitously, and abruptly) as highly negative. The computational analysis of narrative flow found that the autistic narratives contained within the corpus quantifiably resemble autobiographical stories more than imaginary ones. Overall, the temporal challenges experienced by autistic individuals were shown to primarily concern lived unpredictability and stem from the contents of lived experience, and not from autistic narrative construction.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.10947v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kacper Dudzic, Karolina Dro\.zd\.z, Maciej Wodzi\'nski, Anastazja Szu{\l}a, Marcin Moskalewicz</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding Sense in Nonsense with Generated Contexts: Perspectives from Humans and Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.11699</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.11699v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Nonsensical and anomalous sentences have been instrumental in the development of computational models of semantic interpretation. A core challenge is to distinguish between what is merely anomalous (but can be interpreted given a supporting context) and what is truly nonsensical. However, it is unclear (a) how nonsensical, rather than merely anomalous, existing datasets are; and (b) how well LLMs can make this distinction. In this paper, we answer both questions by collecting sensicality judgments from human raters and LLMs on sentences from five semantically deviant datasets: both context-free and when providing a context. We find that raters consider most sentences at most anomalous, and only a few as properly nonsensical. We also show that LLMs are substantially skilled in generating plausible contexts for anomalous cases.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.11699v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Katrina Olsen, Sebastian Pad\'o</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who is the richest club in the championship? Detecting and Rewriting Underspecified Questions Improve QA Performance</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.11938</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.11938v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) perform well on well-posed questions, yet standard question-answering (QA) benchmarks remain far from solved. We argue that this gap is partly due to underspecified questions - queries whose interpretation cannot be uniquely determined without additional context. To test this hypothesis, we introduce an LLM-based classifier to identify underspecified questions and apply it to several widely used QA datasets, finding that 16% to over 50% of benchmark questions are underspecified and that LLMs perform significantly worse on them. To isolate the effect of underspecification, we conduct a controlled rewriting experiment that serves as an upper-bound analysis, rewriting underspecified questions into fully specified variants while holding gold answers fixed. QA performance consistently improves under this setting, indicating that many apparent QA failures stem from question underspecification rather than model limitations. Our findings highlight underspecification as an important confound in QA evaluation and motivate greater attention to question clarity in benchmark design.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.11938v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yunchong Huang, Gianni Barlacchi, Sandro Pezzelle</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LaCy: What Small Language Models Can and Should Learn is Not Just a Question of Loss</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12005</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12005v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Language models have consistently grown to compress more world knowledge into their parameters, but the knowledge that can be pretrained into them is upper-bounded by their parameter size. Especially the capacity of Small Language Models (SLMs) is limited, leading to factually incorrect generations. This problem is often mitigated by giving the SLM access to an outside source: the ability to query a larger model, documents, or a database. Under this setting, we study the fundamental question of \emph{which tokens an SLM can and should learn} during pretraining, versus \emph{which ones it should delegate} via a \texttt{&lt;CALL&gt;} token. We find that this is not simply a question of loss: although the loss is predictive of whether a predicted token mismatches the ground-truth, some tokens are \emph{acceptable} in that they are truthful alternative continuations of a pretraining document, and should not trigger a \texttt{&lt;CALL&gt;} even if their loss is high. We find that a spaCy grammar parser can help augment the loss signal to decide which tokens the SLM should learn to delegate to prevent factual errors and which are safe to learn and predict even under high losses. We propose LaCy, a novel pretraining method based on this token selection philosophy. Our experiments demonstrate that LaCy models successfully learn which tokens to predict and where to delegate for help. This results in higher FactScores when generating in a cascade with a bigger model and outperforms Rho or LLM-judge trained SLMs, while being simpler and cheaper.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12005v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Szilvia Ujv\'ary, Louis B\'ethune, Pierre Ablin, Jo\~ao Monteiro, Marco Cuturi, Michael Kirchhof</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WavBench: Benchmarking Reasoning, Colloquialism, and Paralinguistics for End-to-End Spoken Dialogue Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12135</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12135v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: With the rapid integration of advanced reasoning capabilities into spoken dialogue models, the field urgently demands benchmarks that transcend simple interactions to address real-world complexity. However, current evaluations predominantly adhere to text-generation standards, overlooking the unique audio-centric characteristics of paralinguistics and colloquialisms, alongside the cognitive depth required by modern agents. To bridge this gap, we introduce WavBench, a comprehensive benchmark designed to evaluate realistic conversational abilities where prior works fall short. Uniquely, WavBench establishes a tripartite framework: 1) Pro subset, designed to rigorously challenge reasoning-enhanced models with significantly increased difficulty; 2) Basic subset, defining a novel standard for spoken colloquialism that prioritizes "listenability" through natural vocabulary, linguistic fluency, and interactive rapport, rather than rigid written accuracy; and 3) Acoustic subset, covering explicit understanding, generation, and implicit dialogue to rigorously evaluate comprehensive paralinguistic capabilities within authentic real-world scenarios. Through evaluating five state-of-the-art models, WavBench offers critical insights into the intersection of complex problem-solving, colloquial delivery, and paralinguistic fidelity, guiding the evolution of robust spoken dialogue models. The benchmark dataset and evaluation toolkit are available at https://naruto-2024.github.io/wavbench.github.io/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12135v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yangzhuo Li, Shengpeng Ji, Yifu Chen, Tianle Liang, Haorong Ying, Yule Wang, Junbo Li, Jun Fang, Zhou Zhao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Detecting Overflow in Compressed Token Representations for Retrieval-Augmented Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12235</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12235v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Efficient long-context processing remains a crucial challenge for contemporary large language models (LLMs), especially in resource-constrained environments. Soft compression architectures promise to extend effective context length by replacing long token sequences with smaller sets of learned compressed tokens. Yet, the limits of compressibility -- and when compression begins to erase task-relevant content -- remain underexplored. In this paper, we define token overflow as a regime in which compressed representations no longer contain sufficient information to answer a given query, and propose a methodology to characterize and detect it. In the xRAG soft-compression setting, we find that query-agnostic saturation statistics reliably separate compressed from uncompressed token representations, providing a practical tool for identifying compressed tokens but showing limited overflow detection capability. Lightweight probing classifiers over both query and context xRAG representations detect overflow with 0.72 AUC-ROC on average on HotpotQA, SQuADv2, and TriviaQA datasets, demonstrating that incorporating query information improves detection performance. These results advance from query-independent diagnostics to query-aware detectors, enabling low-cost pre-LLM gating to mitigate compression-induced errors.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12235v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Julia Belikova, Danila Rozhevskii, Dennis Svirin, Konstantin Polev, Alexander Panchenko</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>T3D: Few-Step Diffusion Language Models via Trajectory Self-Distillation with Direct Discriminative Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.12262</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.12262v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Diffusion large language models (DLLMs) have the potential to enable fast text generation by decoding multiple tokens in parallel. However, in practice, their inference efficiency is constrained by the need for many refinement steps, while aggressively reducing the number of steps leads to a substantial degradation in generation quality. To alleviate this, we propose a trajectory self-distillation framework that improves few-step decoding by distilling the model's own generative trajectories. We incorporate Direct Discriminative Optimization (DDO), a reverse-KL objective that promotes mode-seeking distillation and encourages the student to concentrate on high-probability teacher modes. Across benchmarks, our approach consistently outperforms strong few-step baselines and standard training under tight step budgets. Although full-step decoding remains superior, we substantially narrow the gap, establishing a strong foundation towards practical few-step DLLMs. The source code is available at https://github.com/Tyrion58/T3D.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.12262v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tunyu Zhang, Xinxi Zhang, Ligong Han, Haizhou Shi, Xiaoxiao He, Zhuowei Li, Hao Wang, Kai Xu, Akash Srivastava, Hao Wang, Vladimir Pavlovic, Dimitris N. Metaxas</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redefining Evaluation Standards: A Unified Framework for Evaluating the Korean Capabilities of Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.22968</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.22968v5 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Recent advancements in Korean large language models (LLMs) have driven numerous benchmarks and evaluation methods, yet inconsistent protocols cause up to 10 p.p performance gaps across institutions. Overcoming these reproducibility gaps does not mean enforcing a one-size-fits-all evaluation. Rather, effective benchmarking requires diverse experimental approaches and a framework robust enough to support them. To this end, we introduce HRET (Haerae Evaluation Toolkit), an open-source, registry-based framework that unifies Korean LLM assessment. HRET integrates major Korean benchmarks, multiple inference backends, and multi-method evaluation, with language consistency enforcement to ensure genuine Korean outputs. Its modular registry design also enables rapid incorporation of new datasets, methods, and backends, ensuring the toolkit adapts to evolving research needs. Beyond standard accuracy metrics, HRET incorporates Korean-focused output analyses-morphology-aware Type-Token Ratio (TTR) for evaluating lexical diversity and systematic keyword-omission detection for identifying missing concepts-to provide diagnostic insights into language-specific behaviors. These targeted analyses help researchers pinpoint morphological and semantic shortcomings in model outputs, guiding focused improvements in Korean LLM development.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.22968v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CE</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hanwool Lee, Dasol Choi, Sooyong Kim, Ilgyun Jeong, Sangwon Baek, Guijin Son, Inseon Hwang, Naeun Lee, Seunghyeok Hong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Provable Secure Steganography Based on Adaptive Dynamic Sampling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.12579</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.12579v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The security of private communication is increasingly at risk due to widespread surveillance. Steganography, a technique for embedding secret messages within innocuous carriers, enables covert communication over monitored channels. Provably Secure Steganography (PSS), which ensures computational indistinguishability between the normal model output and steganography output, is the state-of-the-art in this field. However, current PSS methods often require obtaining the explicit distributions of the model. In this paper, we propose a provably secure steganography scheme that only requires a model API that accepts a seed as input. Our core mechanism involves sampling a candidate set of tokens and constructing a map from possible message bit strings to these tokens. The output token is selected by applying this mapping to the real secret message, which provably preserves the original model's distribution. To ensure correct decoding, we address collision cases, where multiple candidate messages map to the same token, by maintaining and strategically expanding a dynamic collision set within a bounded size range. Extensive evaluations of three real-world datasets and three large language models demonstrate that our sampling-based method is comparable with existing PSS methods in efficiency and capacity.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.12579v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kaiyi Pang, Minhao Bai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>R-Zero: Self-Evolving Reasoning LLM from Zero Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.05004</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.05004v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Self-evolving Large Language Models (LLMs) offer a scalable path toward super-intelligence by autonomously generating, refining, and learning from their own experiences. However, existing methods for training such models still rely heavily on vast human-curated tasks and labels, typically via fine-tuning or reinforcement learning, which poses a fundamental bottleneck to advancing AI systems toward capabilities beyond human intelligence. To overcome this limitation, we introduce R-Zero, a fully autonomous framework that generates its own training data from scratch. Starting from a single base LLM, R-Zero initializes two independent models with distinct roles, a Challenger and a Solver. These models are optimized separately and co-evolve through interaction: the Challenger is rewarded for proposing tasks near the edge of the Solver capability, and the Solver is rewarded for solving increasingly challenging tasks posed by the Challenger. This process yields a targeted, self-improving curriculum without any pre-existing tasks and labels. Empirically, R-Zero substantially improves reasoning capability across different backbone LLMs, e.g., boosting the Qwen3-4B-Base by +6.49 on math-reasoning benchmarks and +7.54 on general-domain reasoning benchmarks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.05004v4</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chengsong Huang, Wenhao Yu, Xiaoyang Wang, Hongming Zhang, Zongxia Li, Ruosen Li, Jiaxin Huang, Haitao Mi, Dong Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multimodal LLM With Hierarchical Mixture-of-Experts for VQA on 3D Brain MRI</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.25889</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.25889v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Multiparametric 3D brain MRI (mpMRI) is central to neuroradiology, but producing tumor location, appearance, size, and involvement of critical structures for neurosurgical planning remains challenging. We introduce mpLLM, a multimodal LLM for visual question answering (VQA) on mpMRI that produces clinically interpretable tumor descriptors (e.g., volume, morphology, extent, and coarse localization) as an adjunct to clinical expertise for referring neurosurgeons. mpLLM uses a prompt-conditioned hierarchical mixture-of-experts (MoE) to fuse multiple 3D sequences via routing over modality- and token-level projection experts, enabling data-efficient end-to-end training without large-scale image-report pretraining. To address limited paired image-text supervision, we propose a synthetic VQA protocol that derives clinically grounded questions and answers from expert segmentation annotations and is validated with radiologist collaboration. Across multiple mpMRI datasets, mpLLM improves over strong medical VLM baselines by +5.5 points on average (+9.1% relative) and increases radiologist-rated clinical acceptability by +15.9 points (+46.6% relative). Our study features three main contributions: (1) the first VQA dataset for 3D brain mpMRI, (2) a hierarchical MoE architecture for joint reasoning over interrelated 3D sequences, and (3) expert-supported evidence of clinical utility. Source code is available at https://github.com/arvindmvepa/mpllm, and we will release the dataset upon publication.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.25889v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Arvind Murari Vepa, Yannan Yu, Jingru Gan, Anthony Cuturrufo, Michael F. Romano, Weikai Li, Fabien Scalzo, Wei Wang, Yizhou Sun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VoiceAgentBench: Are Voice Assistants ready for agentic tasks?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.07978</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.07978v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large scale Speech Language Models have enabled voice assistants capable of understanding natural spoken queries and performing complex tasks. However, existing speech benchmarks largely focus on isolated capabilities such as transcription or question answering and do not systematically evaluate agentic behavior or adversarial robustness. To address this, we introduce VoiceAgentBench, a comprehensive benchmark for evaluating SpeechLMs in realistic spoken agentic settings, comprising 6,000+ synthetic spoken queries spanning single-tool invocations, multi-tool workflows, multi-turn dialogue, and safety evaluations across English and six Indic languages. To ensure speaker diversity, we further simulate speaker variability using a novel sampling strategy that selects audios for TTS voice conversion based on speaker embeddings to maximize acoustic diversity. Our evaluation measures tool selection accuracy, structural consistency, and the correctness of tool invocations, including adversarial robustness. Across agentic tasks, ASR-LLM pipelines outperform end-to-end SpeechLMs, achieving up to 60.6% average parameter-filling accuracy on English, while SpeechLMs exhibit lower performance and sharper degradation on Indic languages. All models struggle in sequential workflows and safety evaluations, highlighting persistent limitations in tool orchestration, multilingual generalization, and safety robustness. VoiceAgentBench is publicly available on Hugging Face at https://huggingface.co/datasets/krutrim-ai-labs/VoiceAgentBench, and the codebase is released at https://github.com/ola-krutrim/VoiceAgentBench.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.07978v3</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dhruv Jain, Harshit Shukla, Gautam Rajeev, Ashish Kulkarni, Chandra Khatri, Shubham Agarwal</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don't Walk the Line: Boundary Guidance for Filtered Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.11834</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.11834v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Generative models are increasingly paired with safety classifiers that filter harmful or undesirable outputs. A common strategy is to fine-tune the generator to reduce the probability of being filtered, but this can be suboptimal: it often pushes the model toward producing samples near the classifier's decision boundary, increasing both false positives and false negatives. We propose Boundary Guidance, a reinforcement learning fine-tuning method that explicitly steers generation away from the classifier's margin. On a benchmark of jailbreak, ambiguous, and longcontext prompts, Boundary Guidance improves both the safety and the utility of outputs, as judged by LLM-as-a-Judge evaluations. Comprehensive ablations across model scales and reward designs demonstrate the robustness of our approach.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.11834v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sarah Ball, Andreas Haupt</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finetuning Large Language Models for Automated Depression Screening in Nigerian Pidgin English: GENSCORE Pilot Study</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.00004</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.00004v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Depression is a major contributor to the mental-health burden in Nigeria, yet screening coverage remains limited due to low access to clinicians, stigma, and language barriers. Traditional tools like the Patient Health Questionnaire-9 (PHQ-9) were validated in high-income countries but may be linguistically or culturally inaccessible for low- and middle-income countries and communities such as Nigeria where people communicate in Nigerian Pidgin and more than 520 local languages. This study presents a novel approach to automated depression screening using fine-tuned large language models (LLMs) adapted for conversational Nigerian Pidgin. We collected a dataset of 432 Pidgin-language audio responses from Nigerian young adults aged 18-40 to prompts assessing psychological experiences aligned with PHQ-9 items, performed transcription, rigorous preprocessing and annotation, including semantic labeling, slang and idiom interpretation, and PHQ-9 severity scoring. Three LLMs - Phi-3-mini-4k-instruct, Gemma-3-4B-it, and GPT-4.1 - were fine-tuned on this annotated dataset, and their performance was evaluated quantitatively (accuracy, precision and semantic alignment) and qualitatively (clarity, relevance, and cultural appropriateness). GPT-4.1 achieved the highest quantitative performance, with 94.5% accuracy in PHQ-9 severity scoring prediction, outperforming Gemma-3-4B-it and Phi-3-mini-4k-instruct. Qualitatively, GPT-4.1 also produced the most culturally appropriate, clear, and contextually relevant responses. AI-mediated depression screening for underserved Nigerian communities. This work provides a foundation for deploying conversational mental-health tools in linguistically diverse, resource-constrained environments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.00004v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Isaac Iyinoluwa Olufadewa, Miracle Ayomikun Adesina, Ezekiel Ayodeji Oladejo, Uthman Babatunde Usman, Owen Kolade Adeniyi, Matthew Tolulope Olawoyin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Privacy-Preserving Federated Learning with Verifiable Fairness Guarantees</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.12447</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.12447v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Federated learning enables collaborative model training across distributed institutions without centralizing sensitive data; however, ensuring algorithmic fairness across heterogeneous data distributions while preserving privacy remains fundamentally unresolved. This paper introduces CryptoFair-FL, a novel cryptographic framework providing the first verifiable fairness guarantees for federated learning systems under formal security definitions. The proposed approach combines additively homomorphic encryption with secure multi-party computation to enable privacy-preserving verification of demographic parity and equalized odds metrics without revealing protected attribute distributions or individual predictions. A novel batched verification protocol reduces computational complexity from BigO(n^2) to BigO(n \log n) while maintaining (\dparam, \deltap)-differential privacy with dparam = 0.5 and deltap = 10^{-6}. Theoretical analysis establishes information-theoretic lower bounds on the privacy cost of fairness verification, demonstrating that the proposed protocol achieves near-optimal privacy-fairness tradeoffs. Comprehensive experiments across four benchmark datasets (MIMIC-IV healthcare records, Adult Income, CelebA, and a novel FedFair-100 benchmark) demonstrate that CryptoFair-FL reduces fairness violations from 0.231 to 0.031 demographic parity difference while incurring only 2.3 times computational overhead compared to standard federated averaging. The framework successfully defends against attribute inference attacks, maintaining adversarial success probability below 0.05 across all tested configurations. These results establish a practical pathway for deploying fairness-aware federated learning in regulated industries requiring both privacy protection and algorithmic accountability.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.12447v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mohammed Himayath Ali, Mohammed Aqib Abdullah, Syed Muneer Hussain, Mohammed Mudassir Uddin, Shahnawaz Alam</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FiMI: A Domain-Specific Language Model for Indian Finance Ecosystem</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05794</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.05794v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We present FiMI (Finance Model for India), a domain-specialized financial language model developed by National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) for Indian digital payment systems. We develop two model variants: FiMI Base and FiMI Instruct. FiMI adapts the Mistral Small 24B architecture through a multi-stage training pipeline, beginning with continuous pre-training on 68 Billion tokens of curated financial, multilingual (English, Hindi, Hinglish), and synthetic data. This is followed by instruction fine-tuning and domain-specific supervised fine-tuning focused on multi-turn, tool-driven conversations that model real-world workflows, such as transaction disputes and mandate lifecycle management. Evaluations reveal that FiMI Base achieves a 20\% improvement over the Mistral Small 24B Base model on finance reasoning benchmark, while FiMI Instruct outperforms the Mistral Small 24B Instruct model by 87\% on domain-specific tool-calling. Moreover, FiMI achieves these significant domain gains while maintaining comparable performance to models of similar size on general benchmarks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05794v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CE</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aboli Kathar, Aman Kumar, Anusha Kamath, Araveeti Srujan, Ashish Sharma, Chandra Bhushan, Divya Sorate, Duddu Prasanth Kumar, Evan Acharya, Harsh Sharma, Hrithik Kadam, Kanishk Singla, Keyur Doshi, Kiran Praveen, Kolisetty Krishna SK, Krishanu Adhikary, Lokesh MPT, Mayurdeep Sonowal, Nadeem Shaikh, Navya Prakash, Nimit Kothari, Nitin Kukreja, Prashant Devadiga, Rakesh Paul, Ratanjeet Pratap Chauhan, Raunak Kalani, Raviraj Joshi, Shamanth MH, Shantanu Pandey, Shubham Soni, Siddharth Dixit, Smriti Jopat, Sunil Patel, Suraj Singh, Suvradip Paul, Tulasi Pilla, Utkarsh Vaidya, Vineeth Nambiar, Vishal Kanvaty, Yatharth Dedhia</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linguistics and Human Brain: A Perspective of Computational Neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.08275</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.08275v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Elucidating the language-brain relationship requires bridging the methodological gap between the abstract theoretical frameworks of linguistics and the empirical neural data of neuroscience. Serving as an interdisciplinary cornerstone, computational neuroscience formalizes the hierarchical and dynamic structures of language into testable neural models through modeling, simulation, and data analysis. This enables a computational dialogue between linguistic hypotheses and neural mechanisms. Recent advances in deep learning, particularly large language models (LLMs), have powerfully advanced this pursuit. Their high-dimensional representational spaces provide a novel scale for exploring the neural basis of linguistic processing, while the "model-brain alignment" framework offers a methodology to evaluate the biological plausibility of language-related theories.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.08275v2</guid>
      <category>q-bio.NC</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fudong Zhang, Bo Chai, Yujie Wu, Wai Ting Siok, Nizhuan Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MLDocRAG: Multimodal Long-Context Document Retrieval Augmented Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10271</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.10271v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Understanding multimodal long-context documents that comprise multimodal chunks such as paragraphs, figures, and tables is challenging due to (1) cross-modal heterogeneity to localize relevant information across modalities, (2) cross-page reasoning to aggregate dispersed evidence across pages. To address these challenges, we are motivated to adopt a query-centric formulation that projects cross-modal and cross-page information into a unified query representation space, with queries acting as abstract semantic surrogates for heterogeneous multimodal content. In this paper, we propose a Multimodal Long-Context Document Retrieval Augmented Generation (MLDocRAG) framework that leverages a Multimodal Chunk-Query Graph (MCQG) to organize multimodal document content around semantically rich, answerable queries. MCQG is constructed via a multimodal document expansion process that generates fine-grained queries from heterogeneous document chunks and links them to their corresponding content across modalities and pages. This graph-based structure enables selective, query-centric retrieval and structured evidence aggregation, thereby enhancing grounding and coherence in multimodal long-context question answering. Experiments on datasets MMLongBench-Doc and LongDocURL demonstrate that MLDocRAG consistently improves retrieval quality and answer accuracy, demonstrating its effectiveness for multimodal long-context understanding.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.10271v3</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yongyue Zhang, Yaxiong Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diffusion-Pretrained Dense and Contextual Embeddings</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.11151</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.11151v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In this report, we introduce pplx-embed, a family of multilingual embedding models that employ multi-stage contrastive learning on a diffusion-pretrained language model backbone for web-scale retrieval. By leveraging bidirectional attention through diffusion-based pretraining, our models capture comprehensive bidirectional context within passages, enabling the use of mean pooling and a late chunking strategy to better preserve global context across long documents. We release two model types: pplx-embed-v1 for standard retrieval, and pplx-embed-context-v1 for contextualized embeddings that incorporate global document context into passage representations. pplx-embed-v1 achieves competitive performance on the MTEB(Multilingual, v2), MTEB(Code), MIRACL, BERGEN, and ToolRet retrieval benchmarks, while pplx-embed-context-v1 sets new records on the ConTEB benchmark. Beyond public benchmarks, pplx-embed-v1 demonstrates strong performance on our internal evaluation suite, focusing on real-world, large-scale search scenarios constructed from 1B production web pages. These results validate the models' effectiveness in production environments where retrieval quality and efficiency are critical at scale.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.11151v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sedigheh Eslami, Maksim Gaiduk, Markus Krimmel, Louis Milliken, Bo Wang, Denis Bykov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Should LLMs Be Less Specific? Selective Abstraction for Reliable Long-Form Text Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.11908</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.11908v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: LLMs are widely used, yet they remain prone to factual errors that erode user trust and limit adoption in high-risk settings. One approach to mitigate this risk is to equip models with uncertainty estimation mechanisms that abstain when confidence is low. However, this binary "all-or-nothing" approach is excessively restrictive in long-form settings, often discarding valuable information. We introduce Selective Abstraction (SA), a framework that enables LLMs to trade specificity for reliability by selectively reducing the detail of uncertain content. We first formalize SA through the lenses of selective risk and coverage. We then propose Atom-wise Selective Abstraction, a claim-level instantiation that decomposes responses into atomic claims (short, self-contained statements each expressing a single fact) and replaces uncertain atoms with higher confidence, less specific abstractions. To evaluate this framework, we develop a novel end-to-end pipeline for open-ended generation that instantiates risk as factual correctness and measures coverage using an information-theoretic measure of retained information. Across six open-source models on the FactScore and LongFact-Objects benchmarks, atom-wise SA consistently outperforms existing baselines, improving the area under the risk-coverage curve (AURC) by up to 27.73% over claim removal, demonstrating that reducing specificity can boost accuracy and reliability while preserving most of their original meaning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.11908v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shani Goren, Ido Galil, Ran El-Yaniv</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
