<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL</link>
    <description>cs.CL updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CL" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 05:00:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Sunday</day>
      <day>Saturday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>QueryPlot: Generating Geological Evidence Layers using Natural Language Queries for Mineral Exploration</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.17784</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.17784v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Mineral prospectivity mapping requires synthesizing heterogeneous geological knowledge, including textual deposit models and geospatial datasets, to identify regions likely to host specific mineral deposit types. This process is traditionally manual and knowledge-intensive. We present QueryPlot, a semantic retrieval and mapping framework that integrates large-scale geological text corpora with geologic map data using modern Natural Language Processing techniques. We curate descriptive deposit models for over 120 deposit types and transform the State Geologic Map Compilation (SGMC) polygons into structured textual representations. Given a user-defined natural language query, the system encodes both queries and region descriptions using a pretrained embedding model and computes semantic similarity scores to rank and spatially visualize regions as continuous evidence layers. QueryPlot supports compositional querying over deposit characteristics, enabling aggregation of multiple similarity-derived layers for multi-criteria prospectivity analysis. In a case study on tungsten skarn deposits, we demonstrate that embedding-based retrieval achieves high recall of known occurrences and produces prospective regions that closely align with expert-defined permissive tracts. Furthermore, similarity scores can be incorporated as additional features in supervised learning pipelines, yielding measurable improvements in classification performance. QueryPlot is implemented as a web-based system supporting interactive querying, visualization, and export of GIS-compatible prospectivity layers.To support future research, we have made the source code and datasets used in this study publicly available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.17784v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Meng Ye, Xiao Lin, Georgina Lukoczki, Graham W. Lederer, Yi Yao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neural Synchrony Between Socially Interacting Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.17815</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.17815v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Neuroscience has uncovered a fundamental mechanism of our social nature: human brain activity becomes synchronized with others in many social contexts involving interaction. Traditionally, social minds have been regarded as an exclusive property of living beings. Although large language models (LLMs) are widely accepted as powerful approximations of human behavior, with multi-LLM system being extensively explored to enhance their capabilities, it remains controversial whether they can be meaningfully compared to human social minds. In this work, we explore neural synchrony between socially interacting LLMs as an empirical evidence for this debate. Specifically, we introduce neural synchrony during social simulations as a novel proxy for analyzing the sociality of LLMs at the representational level. Through carefully designed experiments, we demonstrate that it reliably reflects both social engagement and temporal alignment in their interactions. Our findings indicate that neural synchrony between LLMs is strongly correlated with their social performance, highlighting an important link between neural synchrony and the social behaviors of LLMs. Our work offers a new perspective to examine the "social minds" of LLMs, highlighting surprising parallels in the internal dynamics that underlie human and LLM social interaction.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.17815v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhining Zhang, Wentao Zhu, Chi Han, Yizhou Wang, Heng Ji</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the scaling relationship between cloze probabilities and language model next-token prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.17848</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.17848v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent work has shown that larger language models have better predictive power for eye movement and reading time data. While even the best models under-allocate probability mass to human responses, larger models assign higher-quality estimates of next tokens and their likelihood of production in cloze data because they are less sensitive to lexical co-occurrence statistics while being better aligned semantically to human cloze responses. The results provide support for the claim that the greater memorization capacity of larger models helps them guess more semantically appropriate words, but makes them less sensitive to low-level information that is relevant for word recognition.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.17848v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Cassandra L. Jacobs, Morgan Grobol</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Unreliability of Steering Vectors in Language Models: Geometric Predictors and the Limits of Linear Approximations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.17881</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.17881v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Steering vectors are a lightweight method for controlling language model behavior by adding a learned bias to the activations at inference time. Although effective on average, steering effect sizes vary across samples and are unreliable for many target behaviors. In my thesis, I investigate why steering reliability differs across behaviors and how it is impacted by steering vector training data. First, I find that higher cosine similarity between training activation differences predicts more reliable steering. Second, I observe that behavior datasets where positive and negative activations are better separated along the steering direction are more reliably steerable. Finally, steering vectors trained on different prompt variations are directionally distinct, yet perform similarly well and exhibit correlated efficacy across datasets. My findings suggest that steering vectors are unreliable when the latent target behavior representation is not effectively approximated by the linear steering direction. Taken together, these insights offer a practical diagnostic for steering unreliability and motivate the development of more robust steering methods that explicitly account for non-linear latent behavior representations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.17881v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Joschka Braun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Neural Topic Modeling with Semantically-Grounded Soft Label Distributions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.17907</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.17907v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Traditional neural topic models are typically optimized by reconstructing the document's Bag-of-Words (BoW) representations, overlooking contextual information and struggling with data sparsity. In this work, we propose a novel approach to construct semantically-grounded soft label targets using Language Models (LMs) by projecting the next token probabilities, conditioned on a specialized prompt, onto a pre-defined vocabulary to obtain contextually enriched supervision signals. By training the topic models to reconstruct the soft labels using the LM hidden states, our method produces higher-quality topics that are more closely aligned with the underlying thematic structure of the corpus. Experiments on three datasets show that our method achieves substantial improvements in topic coherence, purity over existing baselines. Additionally, we also introduce a retrieval-based metric, which shows that our approach significantly outperforms existing methods in identifying semantically similar documents, highlighting its effectiveness for retrieval-oriented applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.17907v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Raymond Li, Amirhossein Abaskohi, Chuyuan Li, Gabriel Murray, Giuseppe Carenini</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Condition-Gated Reasoning for Context-Dependent Biomedical Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.17911</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.17911v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Current biomedical question answering (QA) systems often assume that medical knowledge applies uniformly, yet real-world clinical reasoning is inherently conditional: nearly every decision depends on patient-specific factors such as comorbidities and contraindications. Existing benchmarks do not evaluate such conditional reasoning, and retrieval-augmented or graph-based methods lack explicit mechanisms to ensure that retrieved knowledge is applicable to given context. To address this gap, we propose CondMedQA, the first benchmark for conditional biomedical QA, consisting of multi-hop questions whose answers vary with patient conditions. Furthermore, we propose Condition-Gated Reasoning (CGR), a novel framework that constructs condition-aware knowledge graphs and selectively activates or prunes reasoning paths based on query conditions. Our findings show that CGR more reliably selects condition-appropriate answers while matching or exceeding state-of-the-art performance on biomedical QA benchmarks, highlighting the importance of explicitly modeling conditionality for robust medical reasoning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.17911v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jash Rajesh Parekh, Wonbin Kweon, Joey Chan, Rezarta Islamaj, Robert Leaman, Pengcheng Jiang, Chih-Hsuan Wei, Zhizheng Wang, Zhiyong Lu, Jiawei Han</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing LLM Instruction Optimization for Tabular Fact Verification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.17937</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.17937v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Instruction optimization provides a lightweight, model-agnostic approach to enhancing the reasoning performance of large language models (LLMs). This paper presents the first systematic comparison of instruction optimization, based on the DSPy optimization framework, for tabular fact verification. We evaluate four out-of-the-box prompting techniques that cover both text-only prompting and code use: direct prediction, Chain-of-Thought (CoT), ReAct with SQL tools, and CodeAct with Python execution. We study three optimizers from the DSPy framework -- COPRO, MiPROv2, and SIMBA -- across four benchmarks and three model families. We find that instruction optimization consistently improves verification accuracy, with MiPROv2 yielding the most stable gains for CoT, and SIMBA providing the largest benefits for ReAct agents, particularly at larger model scales. Behavioral analyses reveal that SIMBA encourages more direct reasoning paths by applying heuristics, thereby improving numerical comparison abilities in CoT reasoning and helping avoid unnecessary tool calls in ReAct agents. Across different prompting techniques, CoT remains effective for tabular fact checking, especially with smaller models. Although ReAct agents built with larger models can achieve competitive performance, they require careful instruction optimization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.17937v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.PL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaotang Du, Giwon Hong, Wai-Chung Kwan, Rohit Saxena, Ivan Titov, Pasquale Minervini, Emily Allaway</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CUICurate: A GraphRAG-based Framework for Automated Clinical Concept Curation for NLP applications</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.17949</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.17949v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Background: Clinical named entity recognition tools commonly map free text to Unified Medical Language System (UMLS) Concept Unique Identifiers (CUIs). For many downstream tasks, however, the clinically meaningful unit is not a single CUI but a concept set comprising related synonyms, subtypes, and supertypes. Constructing such concept sets is labour-intensive, inconsistently performed, and poorly supported by existing tools, particularly for NLP pipelines that operate directly on UMLS CUIs. Methods We present CUICurate, a Graph-based retrieval-augmented generation (GraphRAG) framework for automated UMLS concept set curation. A UMLS knowledge graph (KG) was constructed and embedded for semantic retrieval. For each target concept, candidate CUIs were retrieved from the KG, followed by large language model (LLM) filtering and classification steps comparing two LLMs (GPT-5 and GPT-5-mini). The framework was evaluated on five lexically heterogeneous clinical concepts against a manually curated benchmark and gold-standard concept sets. Results Across all concepts, CUICurate produced substantially larger and more complete concept sets than the manual benchmarks whilst matching human precision. Comparisons between the two LLMs found that GPT-5-mini achieved higher recall during filtering, while GPT-5 produced classifications that more closely aligned with clinician judgements. Outputs were stable across repeated runs and computationally inexpensive. Conclusions CUICurate offers a scalable and reproducible approach to support UMLS concept set curation that substantially reduces manual effort. By integrating graph-based retrieval with LLM reasoning, the framework produces focused candidate concept sets that can be adapted to clinical NLP pipelines for different phenotyping and analytic requirements.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.17949v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Victoria Blake, Mathew Miller, Jamie Novak, Sze-yuan Ooi, Blanca Gallego</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decomposing Retrieval Failures in RAG for Long-Document Financial Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.17981</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.17981v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Retrieval-augmented generation is increasingly used for financial question answering over long regulatory filings, yet reliability depends on retrieving the exact context needed to justify answers in high stakes settings. We study a frequent failure mode in which the correct document is retrieved but the page or chunk that contains the answer is missed, leading the generator to extrapolate from incomplete context. Despite its practical significance, this within-document retrieval failure mode has received limited systematic attention in the Financial Question Answering (QA) literature. We evaluate retrieval at multiple levels of granularity, document, page, and chunk level, and introduce an oracle based analysis to provide empirical upper bounds on retrieval and generative performance. On a 150 question subset of FinanceBench, we reproduce and compare diverse retrieval strategies including dense, sparse, hybrid, and hierarchical methods with reranking and query reformulation. Across methods, gains in document discovery tend to translate into stronger page recall, yet oracle performance still suggests headroom for page and chunk level retrieval. To target this gap, we introduce a domain fine-tuned page scorer that treats pages as an intermediate retrieval unit between documents and chunks. Unlike prior passage-based hierarchical retrieval, we fine-tune a bi-encoder specifically for page-level relevance on financial filings, exploiting the semantic coherence of pages. Overall, our results demonstrate a significant improvement in page recall and chunk retrieval.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.17981v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Amine Kobeissi, Philippe Langlais</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards More Standardized AI Evaluation: From Models to Agents</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.18029</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.18029v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Evaluation is no longer a final checkpoint in the machine learning lifecycle. As AI systems evolve from static models to compound, tool-using agents, evaluation becomes a core control function. The question is no longer "How good is the model?" but "Can we trust the system to behave as intended, under change, at scale?". Yet most evaluation practices remain anchored in assumptions inherited from the model-centric era: static benchmarks, aggregate scores, and one-off success criteria. This paper argues that such approaches are increasingly obscure rather than illuminating system behavior. We examine how evaluation pipelines themselves introduce silent failure modes, why high benchmark scores routinely mislead teams, and how agentic systems fundamentally alter the meaning of performance measurement. Rather than proposing new metrics or harder benchmarks, we aim to clarify the role of evaluation in the AI era, and especially for agents: not as performance theater, but as a measurement discipline that conditions trust, iteration, and governance in non-deterministic systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.18029v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ali El Filali, In\`es Bedar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perceived Political Bias in LLMs Reduces Persuasive Abilities</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.18092</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.18092v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Conversational AI has been proposed as a scalable way to correct public misconceptions and spread misinformation. Yet its effectiveness may depend on perceptions of its political neutrality. As LLMs enter partisan conflict, elites increasingly portray them as ideologically aligned. We test whether these credibility attacks reduce LLM-based persuasion. In a preregistered U.S. survey experiment (N=2144), participants completed a three-round conversation with ChatGPT about a personally held economic policy misconception. Compared to a neutral control, a short message indicating that the LLM was biased against the respondent's party attenuated persuasion by 28%. Transcript analysis indicates that the warnings alter the interaction: respondents push back more and engage less receptively. These findings suggest that the persuasive impact of conversational AI is politically contingent, constrained by perceptions of partisan alignment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.18092v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Matthew DiGiuseppe, Joshua Robison</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agentic Adversarial QA for Improving Domain-Specific LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.18137</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.18137v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs), despite extensive pretraining on broad internet corpora, often struggle to adapt effectively to specialized domains. There is growing interest in fine-tuning these models for such domains; however, progress is constrained by the scarcity and limited coverage of high-quality, task-relevant data. To address this, synthetic data generation methods such as paraphrasing or knowledge extraction are commonly applied. Although these approaches excel at factual recall and conceptual knowledge, they suffer from two critical shortcomings: (i) they provide minimal support for interpretive reasoning capabilities in these specialized domains, and (ii) they often produce synthetic corpora that are excessively large and redundant, resulting in poor sample efficiency. To overcome these gaps, we propose an adversarial question-generation framework that produces a compact set of semantically challenging questions. These questions are constructed by comparing the outputs of the model to be adapted and a robust expert model grounded in reference documents, using an iterative, feedback-driven process designed to reveal and address comprehension gaps. Evaluation on specialized subsets of the LegalBench corpus demonstrates that our method achieves greater accuracy with substantially fewer synthetic samples.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.18137v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Vincent Grari, Ciprian Tomoiaga, Sylvain Lamprier, Tatsunori Hashimoto, Marcin Detyniecki</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Detecting Contextual Hallucinations in LLMs with Frequency-Aware Attention</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.18145</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.18145v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Hallucination detection is critical for ensuring the reliability of large language models (LLMs) in context-based generation. Prior work has explored intrinsic signals available during generation, among which attention offers a direct view of grounding behavior. However, existing approaches typically rely on coarse summaries that fail to capture fine-grained instabilities in attention. Inspired by signal processing, we introduce a frequency-aware perspective on attention by analyzing its variation during generation. We model attention distributions as discrete signals and extract high-frequency components that reflect rapid local changes in attention. Our analysis reveals that hallucinated tokens are associated with high-frequency attention energy, reflecting fragmented and unstable grounding behavior. Based on this insight, we develop a lightweight hallucination detector using high-frequency attention features. Experiments on the RAGTruth and HalluRAG benchmarks show that our approach achieves performance gains over verification-based, internal-representation-based, and attention-based methods across models and tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.18145v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Siya Qi, Yudong Chen, Runcong Zhao, Qinglin Zhu, Zhanghao Hu, Wei Liu, Yulan He, Zheng Yuan, Lin Gui</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Statistical Signature of LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.18152</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.18152v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models generate text through probabilistic sampling from high-dimensional distributions, yet how this process reshapes the structural statistical organization of language remains incompletely characterized. Here we show that lossless compression provides a simple, model-agnostic measure of statistical regularity that differentiates generative regimes directly from surface text. We analyze compression behavior across three progressively more complex information ecosystems: controlled human-LLM continuations, generative mediation of a knowledge infrastructure (Wikipedia vs. Grokipedia), and fully synthetic social interaction environments (Moltbook vs. Reddit). Across settings, compression reveals a persistent structural signature of probabilistic generation. In controlled and mediated contexts, LLM-produced language exhibits higher structural regularity and compressibility than human-written text, consistent with a concentration of output within highly recurrent statistical patterns. However, this signature shows scale dependence: in fragmented interaction environments the separation attenuates, suggesting a fundamental limit to surface-level distinguishability at small scales. This compressibility-based separation emerges consistently across models, tasks, and domains and can be observed directly from surface text without relying on model internals or semantic evaluation. Overall, our findings introduce a simple and robust framework for quantifying how generative systems reshape textual production, offering a structural perspective on the evolving complexity of communication.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.18152v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>physics.soc-ph</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ortal Hadad, Edoardo Loru, Jacopo Nudo, Niccol\`o Di Marco, Matteo Cinelli, Walter Quattrociocchi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FENCE: A Financial and Multimodal Jailbreak Detection Dataset</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.18154</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.18154v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Jailbreaking poses a significant risk to the deployment of Large Language Models (LLMs) and Vision Language Models (VLMs). VLMs are particularly vulnerable because they process both text and images, creating broader attack surfaces. However, available resources for jailbreak detection are scarce, particularly in finance. To address this gap, we present FENCE, a bilingual (Korean-English) multimodal dataset for training and evaluating jailbreak detectors in financial applications. FENCE emphasizes domain realism through finance-relevant queries paired with image-grounded threats. Experiments with commercial and open-source VLMs reveal consistent vulnerabilities, with GPT-4o showing measurable attack success rates and open-source models displaying greater exposure. A baseline detector trained on FENCE achieves 99 percent in-distribution accuracy and maintains strong performance on external benchmarks, underscoring the dataset's robustness for training reliable detection models. FENCE provides a focused resource for advancing multimodal jailbreak detection in finance and for supporting safer, more reliable AI systems in sensitive domains. Warning: This paper includes example data that may be offensive.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.18154v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.DB</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mirae Kim, Seonghun Jeong, Youngjun Kwak</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Click it or Leave it: Detecting and Spoiling Clickbait with Informativeness Measures and Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.18171</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.18171v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Clickbait headlines degrade the quality of online information and undermine user trust. We present a hybrid approach to clickbait detection that combines transformer-based text embeddings with linguistically motivated informativeness features. Using natural language processing techniques, we evaluate classical vectorizers, word embedding baselines, and large language model embeddings paired with tree-based classifiers. Our best-performing model, XGBoost over embeddings augmented with 15 explicit features, achieves an F1-score of 91\%, outperforming TF-IDF, Word2Vec, GloVe, LLM prompt based classification, and feature-only baselines. The proposed feature set enhances interpretability by highlighting salient linguistic cues such as second-person pronouns, superlatives, numerals, and attention-oriented punctuation, enabling transparent and well-calibrated clickbait predictions. We release code and trained models to support reproducible research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.18171v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wojciech Michaluk, Tymoteusz Urban, Mateusz Kubita, Soveatin Kuntur, Anna Wroblewska</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Sampling for Masked Diffusion Models via Information Gain</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.18176</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.18176v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Masked Diffusion Models (MDMs) offer greater flexibility in decoding order than autoregressive models but require careful planning to achieve high-quality generation. Existing samplers typically adopt greedy heuristics, prioritizing positions with the highest local certainty to decode at each step. Through failure case analysis, we identify a fundamental limitation of this approach: it neglects the downstream impact of current decoding choices on subsequent steps and fails to minimize cumulative uncertainty. In particular, these methods do not fully exploit the non-causal nature of MDMs, which enables evaluating how a decoding decision reshapes token probabilities/uncertainty across all remaining masked positions. To bridge this gap, we propose the Info-Gain Sampler, a principled decoding framework that balances immediate uncertainty with information gain over future masked tokens. Extensive evaluations across diverse architectures and tasks (reasoning, coding, creative writing, and image generation) demonstrate that Info-Gain Sampler consistently outperforms existing samplers for MDMs. For instance, it achieves a 3.6% improvement in average accuracy on reasoning tasks and a 63.1% win-rate in creative writing. Notably, on reasoning tasks it reduces cumulative uncertainty from 78.4 to 48.6, outperforming the best baseline by a large margin. The code will be available at https://github.com/yks23/Information-Gain-Sampler.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.18176v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kaisen Yang, Jayden Teoh, Kaicheng Yang, Yitong Zhang, Alex Lamb</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Information-Theoretic Storage Cost in Sentence Comprehension</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.18217</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.18217v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Real-time sentence comprehension imposes a significant load on working memory, as comprehenders must maintain contextual information to anticipate future input. While measures of such load have played an important role in psycholinguistic theories, they have been formalized, largely, using symbolic grammars, which assign discrete, uniform costs to syntactic predictions. This study proposes a measure of processing storage cost based on an information-theoretic formalization, as the amount of information previous words carry about future context, under uncertainty. Unlike previous discrete, grammar-based metrics, this measure is continuous, theory-neutral, and can be estimated from pre-trained neural language models. The validity of this approach is demonstrated through three analyses in English: our measure (i) recovers well-known processing asymmetries in center embeddings and relative clauses, (ii) correlates with a grammar-based storage cost in a syntactically-annotated corpus, and (iii) predicts reading-time variance in two large-scale naturalistic datasets over and above baseline models with traditional information-based predictors.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.18217v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kohei Kajikawa, Shinnosuke Isono, Ethan Gotlieb Wilcox</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thinking by Subtraction: Confidence-Driven Contrastive Decoding for LLM Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.18232</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.18232v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent work on test-time scaling for large language model (LLM) reasoning typically assumes that allocating more inference-time computation uniformly improves correctness. However, prior studies show that reasoning uncertainty is highly localized: a small subset of low-confidence tokens disproportionately contributes to reasoning errors and unnecessary output expansion. Motivated by this observation, we propose Thinking by Subtraction, a confidence-driven contrastive decoding approach that improves reasoning reliability through targeted token-level intervention. Our method, Confidence-Driven Contrastive Decoding, detects low-confidence tokens during decoding and intervenes selectively at these positions. It constructs a contrastive reference by replacing high-confidence tokens with minimal placeholders, and refines predictions by subtracting this reference distribution at low-confidence locations. Experiments show that CCD significantly improves accuracy across mathematical reasoning benchmarks while substantially reducing output length, with minimal KV-cache overhead. As a training-free method, CCD enhances reasoning reliability through targeted low-confidence intervention without computational redundancy. Our code will be made available at: https://github.com/bolo-web/CCD.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.18232v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lexiang Tang, Weihao Gao, Bingchen Zhao, Lu Ma, Qiao jin, Bang Yang, Yuexian Zou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simplifying Outcomes of Language Model Component Analyses with ELIA</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.18262</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.18262v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: While mechanistic interpretability has developed powerful tools to analyze the internal workings of Large Language Models (LLMs), their complexity has created an accessibility gap, limiting their use to specialists. We address this challenge by designing, building, and evaluating ELIA (Explainable Language Interpretability Analysis), an interactive web application that simplifies the outcomes of various language model component analyses for a broader audience. The system integrates three key techniques -- Attribution Analysis, Function Vector Analysis, and Circuit Tracing -- and introduces a novel methodology: using a vision-language model to automatically generate natural language explanations (NLEs) for the complex visualizations produced by these methods. The effectiveness of this approach was empirically validated through a mixed-methods user study, which revealed a clear preference for interactive, explorable interfaces over simpler, static visualizations. A key finding was that the AI-powered explanations helped bridge the knowledge gap for non-experts; a statistical analysis showed no significant correlation between a user's prior LLM experience and their comprehension scores, suggesting that the system reduced barriers to comprehension across experience levels. We conclude that an AI system can indeed simplify complex model analyses, but its true power is unlocked when paired with thoughtful, user-centered design that prioritizes interactivity, specificity, and narrative guidance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.18262v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aaron Louis Eidt, Nils Feldhus</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PsihoRo: Depression and Anxiety Romanian Text Corpus</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.18324</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.18324v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Psychological corpora in NLP are collections of texts used to analyze human psychology, emotions, and mental health. These texts allow researchers to study psychological constructs, detect mental health issues and analyze emotional language. However, mental health data can be difficult to collect correctly from social media, due to suppositions made by the collectors. A more pragmatic strategy involves gathering data through open-ended questions and then assessing this information with self-report screening surveys. This method was employed successfully for English, a language with a lot of psychological NLP resources. However, this cannot be stated for Romanian, which currently has no open-source mental health corpus. To address this gap, we have created the first corpus for depression and anxiety in Romanian, by utilizing a form with 6 open-ended questions along with the standardized PHQ-9 and GAD-7 screening questionnaires. Consisting of the texts of 205 respondents and although it may seem small, PsihoRo is a first step towards understanding and analyzing texts regarding the mental health of the Romanian population. We employ statistical analysis, text analysis using Romanian LIWC, emotion detection and topic modeling to show what are the most important features of this newly introduced resource to the NLP community.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.18324v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alexandra Ciobotaru, Ana-Maria Bucur, Liviu P. Dinu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Contextual Informativeness for Vocabulary Learning using Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.18326</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.18326v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We describe a modern deep learning system that automatically identifies informative contextual examples (\qu{contexts}) for first language vocabulary instruction for high school student. Our paper compares three modeling approaches: (i) an unsupervised similarity-based strategy using MPNet's uniformly contextualized embeddings, (ii) a supervised framework built on instruction-aware, fine-tuned Qwen3 embeddings with a nonlinear regression head and (iii) model (ii) plus handcrafted context features. We introduce a novel metric called the Retention Competency Curve to visualize trade-offs between the discarded proportion of good contexts and the \qu{good-to-bad} contexts ratio providing a compact, unified lens on model performance. Model (iii) delivers the most dramatic gains with performance of a good-to-bad ratio of 440 all while only throwing out 70\% of the good contexts. In summary, we demonstrate that a modern embedding model on neural network architecture, when guided by human supervision, results in a low-cost large supply of near-perfect contexts for teaching vocabulary for a variety of target words.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.18326v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tao Wu, Adam Kapelner</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vichara: Appellate Judgment Prediction and Explanation for the Indian Judicial System</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.18346</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.18346v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In jurisdictions like India, where courts face an extensive backlog of cases, artificial intelligence offers transformative potential for legal judgment prediction. A critical subset of this backlog comprises appellate cases, which are formal decisions issued by higher courts reviewing the rulings of lower courts. To this end, we present Vichara, a novel framework tailored to the Indian judicial system that predicts and explains appellate judgments. Vichara processes English-language appellate case proceeding documents and decomposes them into decision points. Decision points are discrete legal determinations that encapsulate the legal issue, deciding authority, outcome, reasoning, and temporal context. The structured representation isolates the core determinations and their context, enabling accurate predictions and interpretable explanations. Vichara's explanations follow a structured format inspired by the IRAC (Issue-Rule-Application-Conclusion) framework and adapted for Indian legal reasoning. This enhances interpretability, allowing legal professionals to assess the soundness of predictions efficiently. We evaluate Vichara on two datasets, PredEx and the expert-annotated subset of the Indian Legal Documents Corpus (ILDC_expert), using four large language models: GPT-4o mini, Llama-3.1-8B, Mistral-7B, and Qwen2.5-7B. Vichara surpasses existing judgment prediction benchmarks on both datasets, with GPT-4o mini achieving the highest performance (F1: 81.5 on PredEx, 80.3 on ILDC_expert), followed by Llama-3.1-8B. Human evaluation of the generated explanations across Clarity, Linking, and Usefulness metrics highlights GPT-4o mini's superior interpretability.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.18346v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>AI and Law @ AAAI 2026</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Pavithra PM Nair, Preethu Rose Anish</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Validating Political Position Predictions of Arguments</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.18351</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.18351v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Real-world knowledge representation often requires capturing subjective, continuous attributes -- such as political positions -- that conflict with pairwise validation, the widely accepted gold standard for human evaluation. We address this challenge through a dual-scale validation framework applied to political stance prediction in argumentative discourse, combining pointwise and pairwise human annotation. Using 22 language models, we construct a large-scale knowledge base of political position predictions for 23,228 arguments drawn from 30 debates that appeared on the UK politicial television programme \textit{Question Time}. Pointwise evaluation shows moderate human-model agreement (Krippendorff's $\alpha=0.578$), reflecting intrinsic subjectivity, while pairwise validation reveals substantially stronger alignment between human- and model-derived rankings ($\alpha=0.86$ for the best model). This work contributes: (i) a practical validation methodology for subjective continuous knowledge that balances scalability with reliability; (ii) a validated structured argumentation knowledge base enabling graph-based reasoning and retrieval-augmented generation in political domains; and (iii) evidence that ordinal structure can be extracted from pointwise language models predictions from inherently subjective real-world discourse, advancing knowledge representation capabilities for domains where traditional symbolic or categorical approaches are insufficient.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.18351v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jordan Robinson, Angus R. Williams, Katie Atkinson, Anthony G. Cohn</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPQ: An Ensemble Technique for Large Language Model Compression</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.18420</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.18420v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This study presents an ensemble technique, SPQ (SVD-Pruning-Quantization), for large language model (LLM) compression that combines variance-retained singular value decomposition (SVD), activation-based pruning, and post-training linear quantization. Each component targets a different source of inefficiency: i) pruning removes redundant neurons in MLP layers, ii) SVD reduces attention projections into compact low-rank factors, iii) and 8-bit quantization uniformly compresses all linear layers. At matched compression ratios, SPQ outperforms individual methods (SVD-only, pruning-only, or quantization-only) in perplexity, demonstrating the benefit of combining complementary techniques. Applied to LLaMA-2-7B, SPQ achieves up to 75% memory reduction while maintaining or improving perplexity (e.g., WikiText-2 5.47 to 4.91) and preserving accuracy on downstream benchmarks such as C4, TruthfulQA, and GSM8K. Compared to strong baselines like GPTQ and SparseGPT, SPQ offers competitive perplexity and accuracy while using less memory (6.86 GB vs. 7.16 GB for GPTQ). Moreover, SPQ improves inference throughput over GPTQ, achieving up to a 1.9x speedup, which further enhances its practicality for real-world deployment. The effectiveness of SPQ's robust compression through layer-aware and complementary compression techniques may provide practical deployment of LLMs in memory-constrained environments. Code is available at: https://github.com/JiaminYao/SPQ_LLM_Compression/</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.18420v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiamin Yao, Eren Gultepe</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RVR: Retrieve-Verify-Retrieve for Comprehensive Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.18425</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.18425v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Comprehensively retrieving diverse documents is crucial to address queries that admit a wide range of valid answers. We introduce retrieve-verify-retrieve (RVR), a multi-round retrieval framework designed to maximize answer coverage. Initially, a retriever takes the original query and returns a candidate document set, followed by a verifier that identifies a high-quality subset. For subsequent rounds, the query is augmented with previously verified documents to uncover answers that are not yet covered in previous rounds. RVR is effective even with off-the-shelf retrievers, and fine-tuning retrievers for our inference procedure brings further gains. Our method outperforms baselines, including agentic search approaches, achieving at least 10% relative and 3% absolute gain in complete recall percentage on a multi-answer retrieval dataset (QAMPARI). We also see consistent gains on two out-of-domain datasets (QUEST and WebQuestionsSP) across different base retrievers. Our work presents a promising iterative approach for comprehensive answer recall leveraging a verifier and adapting retrievers to a new inference scenario.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.18425v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Deniz Qian, Hung-Ting Chen, Eunsol Choi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VIRAASAT: Traversing Novel Paths for Indian Cultural Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.18429</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.18429v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have made significant progress in reasoning tasks across various domains such as mathematics and coding. However, their performance deteriorates in tasks requiring rich socio-cultural knowledge and diverse local contexts, particularly those involving Indian Culture. Existing Cultural benchmarks are (i) Manually crafted, (ii) contain single-hop questions testing factual recall, and (iii) prohibitively costly to scale, leaving this deficiency largely unmeasured. To address this, we introduce VIRAASAT, a novel, semi-automated multi-hop approach for generating cultural specific multi-hop Question-Answering dataset for Indian culture. VIRAASAT leverages a Knowledge Graph comprising more than 700 expert-curated cultural artifacts, covering 13 key attributes of Indian culture (history, festivals, etc). VIRAASAT spans all 28 states and 8 Union Territories, yielding more than 3,200 multi-hop questions that necessitate chained cultural reasoning. We evaluate current State-of-the-Art (SOTA) LLMs on VIRAASAT and identify key limitations in reasoning wherein fine-tuning on Chain-of-Thought(CoT) traces fails to ground and synthesize low-probability facts. To bridge this gap, we propose a novel framework named Symbolic Chain-of-Manipulation (SCoM). Adapting the Chain-of-Manipulation paradigm, we train the model to simulate atomic Knowledge Graph manipulations internally. SCoM teaches the model to reliably traverse the topological structure of the graph. Experiments on Supervised Fine-Tuning (SFT) demonstrate that SCoM outperforms standard CoT baselines by up to 20%. We release the VIRAASAT dataset along with our findings, laying a strong foundation towards building Culturally Aware Reasoning Models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.18429v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Harshul Raj Surana, Arijit Maji, Aryan Vats, Akash Ghosh, Sriparna Saha, Amit Sheth</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Hallucination from Students' Perspective: A Thematic Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.17671</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.17671v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: As students increasingly rely on large language models, hallucinations pose a growing threat to learning. To mitigate this, AI literacy must expand beyond prompt engineering to address how students should detect and respond to LLM hallucinations. To support this, we need to understand how students experience hallucinations, how they detect them, and why they believe they occur. To investigate these questions, we asked university students three open-ended questions about their experiences with AI hallucinations, their detection strategies, and their mental models of why hallucinations occur. Sixty-three students responded to the survey. Thematic analysis of their responses revealed that reported hallucination issues primarily relate to incorrect or fabricated citations, false information, overconfident but misleading responses, poor adherence to prompts, persistence in incorrect answers, and sycophancy. To detect hallucinations, students rely either on intuitive judgment or on active verification strategies, such as cross-checking with external sources or re-prompting the model. Students' explanations for why hallucinations occur reflected several mental models, including notable misconceptions. Many described AI as a research engine that fabricates information when it cannot locate an answer in its "database." Others attributed hallucinations to issues with training data, inadequate prompting, or the model's inability to understand or verify information. These findings illuminate vulnerabilities in AI-supported learning and highlight the need for explicit instruction in verification protocols, accurate mental models of generative AI, and awareness of behaviors such as sycophancy and confident delivery that obscure inaccuracy. The study contributes empirical evidence for integrating hallucination awareness and mitigation into AI literacy curricula.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.17671v1</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Abdulhadi Shoufan, Ahmad-Azmi-Abdelhamid Esmaeil</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing LLM Response Quality in the Context of Technology-Facilitated Abuse</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.17672</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.17672v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Technology-facilitated abuse (TFA) is a pervasive form of intimate partner violence (IPV) that leverages digital tools to control, surveil, or harm survivors. While tech clinics are one of the reliable sources of support for TFA survivors, they face limitations due to staffing constraints and logistical barriers. As a result, many survivors turn to online resources for assistance. With the growing accessibility and popularity of large language models (LLMs), and increasing interest from IPV organizations, survivors may begin to consult LLM-based chatbots before seeking help from tech clinics.
  In this work, we present the first expert-led manual evaluation of four LLMs - two widely used general-purpose non-reasoning models and two domain-specific models designed for IPV contexts - focused on their effectiveness in responding to TFA-related questions. Using real-world questions collected from literature and online forums, we assess the quality of zero-shot single-turn LLM responses generated with a survivor safety-centered prompt on criteria tailored to the TFA domain. Additionally, we conducted a user study to evaluate the perceived actionability of these responses from the perspective of individuals who have experienced TFA.
  Our findings, grounded in both expert assessment and user feedback, provide insights into the current capabilities and limitations of LLMs in the TFA context and may inform the design, development, and fine-tuning of future models for this domain. We conclude with concrete recommendations to improve LLM performance for survivor support.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.17672v1</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Vijay Prakash, Majed Almansoori, Donghan Hu, Rahul Chatterjee, Danny Yuxing Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Before Translation: Social Information Transmission and Survival in AI-AI Communication</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.17674</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.17674v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: When AI systems summarize and relay information, they inevitably transform it. But how? We introduce an experimental paradigm based on the telephone game to study what happens when AI talks to AI. Across five studies tracking content through AI transmission chains, we find three consistent patterns. The first is convergence, where texts differing in certainty, emotional intensity, and perspectival balance collapse toward a shared default of moderate confidence, muted affect, and analytical structure. The second is selective survival, where narrative anchors persist while the texture of evidence, hedges, quotes, and attributions is stripped away. The third is competitive filtering, where strong arguments survive while weaker but valid considerations disappear when multiple viewpoints coexist. In downstream experiments, human participants rated AI-transmitted content as more credible and polished. Importantly, however, humans also showed degraded factual recall, reduced perception of balance, and diminished emotional resonance. We show that the properties that make AI-mediated content appear authoritative may systematically erode the cognitive and affective diversity on which informed judgment depends.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.17674v1</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bijean Ghafouri, Emilio Ferrara</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epistemic Traps: Rational Misalignment Driven by Model Misspecification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.17676</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.17676v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The rapid deployment of Large Language Models and AI agents across critical societal and technical domains is hindered by persistent behavioral pathologies including sycophancy, hallucination, and strategic deception that resist mitigation via reinforcement learning. Current safety paradigms treat these failures as transient training artifacts, lacking a unified theoretical framework to explain their emergence and stability. Here we show that these misalignments are not errors, but mathematically rationalizable behaviors arising from model misspecification. By adapting Berk-Nash Rationalizability from theoretical economics to artificial intelligence, we derive a rigorous framework that models the agent as optimizing against a flawed subjective world model. We demonstrate that widely observed failures are structural necessities: unsafe behaviors emerge as either a stable misaligned equilibrium or oscillatory cycles depending on reward scheme, while strategic deception persists as a "locked-in" equilibrium or through epistemic indeterminacy robust to objective risks. We validate these theoretical predictions through behavioral experiments on six state-of-the-art model families, generating phase diagrams that precisely map the topological boundaries of safe behavior. Our findings reveal that safety is a discrete phase determined by the agent's epistemic priors rather than a continuous function of reward magnitude. This establishes Subjective Model Engineering, defined as the design of an agent's internal belief structure, as a necessary condition for robust alignment, marking a paradigm shift from manipulating environmental rewards to shaping the agent's interpretation of reality.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.17676v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xingcheng Xu, Jingjing Qu, Qiaosheng Zhang, Chaochao Lu, Yanqing Yang, Na Zou, Xia Hu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reducing Text Bias in Synthetically Generated MCQAs for VLMs in Autonomous Driving</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.17677</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.17677v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Multiple Choice Question Answering (MCQA) benchmarks are an established standard for measuring Vision Language Model (VLM) performance in driving tasks. However, we observe the known phenomenon that synthetically generated MCQAs are highly susceptible to hidden textual cues that allow models to exploit linguistic patterns rather than visual context. Our results show that a VLM fine-tuned on such data can achieve accuracy comparable to human-validated benchmarks even without visual input. Our proposed method reduces blind accuracy from +66.9% above random to +2.9%, eliminating the vast majority of exploitable textual shortcuts. By decoupling the correct answer from linguistic artifacts and employing a curriculum learning strategy, we force the model to rely on visual grounding, ensuring that performance accurately reflects perceptual understanding.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.17677v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sutej Kulgod, Sean Ye, Sanchit Tanwar, Christoffer Heckman</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LATMiX: Learnable Affine Transformations for Microscaling Quantization of LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.17681</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.17681v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Post-training quantization (PTQ) is a widely used approach for reducing the memory and compute costs of large language models (LLMs). Recent studies have shown that applying invertible transformations to activations can significantly improve quantization robustness by reducing activation outliers; however, existing approaches are largely restricted to rotation or Hadamard-based transformations. Moreover, most studies focused primarily on traditional quantization schemes, whereas modern hardware increasingly supports the microscaling (MX) data format. Attempts to combine both showed severe performance degradation, leading prior work to introduce assumptions on the transformations. In this work, we take a complementary perspective. First, we provide a theoretical analysis of transformations under MX quantization by deriving a bound on the quantization error. Our analysis emphasizes the importance of accounting for both the activation distribution and the underlying quantization structure. Building on this analysis, we propose LATMiX, a method that generalizes outlier reduction to learnable invertible affine transformations optimized using standard deep learning tools. Experiments show consistent improvements in average accuracy for MX low-bit quantization over strong baselines on a wide range of zero-shot benchmarks, across multiple model sizes.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.17681v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ofir Gordon, Lior Dikstein, Arnon Netzer, Idan Achituve, Hai Victor Habi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IRPAPERS: A Visual Document Benchmark for Scientific Retrieval and Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.17687</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.17687v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: AI systems have achieved remarkable success in processing text and relational data, yet visual document processing remains relatively underexplored. Whereas traditional systems require OCR transcriptions to convert these visual documents into text and metadata, recent advances in multimodal foundation models offer retrieval and generation directly from document images. This raises a key question: How do image-based systems compare to established text-based methods? We introduce IRPAPERS, a benchmark of 3,230 pages from 166 scientific papers, with both an image and an OCR transcription for each page. Using 180 needle-in-the-haystack questions, we compare image- and text-based retrieval and question answering systems. Text retrieval using Arctic 2.0 embeddings, BM25, and hybrid text search achieved 46% Recall@1, 78% Recall@5, and 91% Recall@20, while image-based retrieval reaches 43%, 78%, and 93%, respectively. The two modalities exhibit complementary failures, enabling multimodal hybrid search to outperform either alone, achieving 49% Recall@1, 81% Recall@5, and 95% Recall@20. We further evaluate efficiency-performance tradeoffs with MUVERA and assess multiple multi-vector image embedding models. Among closed-source models, Cohere Embed v4 page image embeddings outperform Voyage 3 Large text embeddings and all tested open-source models, achieving 58% Recall@1, 87% Recall@5, and 97% Recall@20. For question answering, text-based RAG systems achieved higher ground-truth alignment than image-based systems (0.82 vs. 0.71), and both benefit substantially from increased retrieval depth, with multi-document retrieval outperforming oracle single-document retrieval. We analyze the complementary limitations of unimodal text and image representations and identify question types that require one modality over the other. The IRPAPERS dataset and all experimental code are publicly available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.17687v1</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Connor Shorten, Augustas Skaburskas, Daniel M. Jones, Charles Pierse, Roberto Esposito, John Trengrove, Etienne Dilocker, Bob van Luijt</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robust Pre-Training of Medical Vision-and-Language Models with Domain-Invariant Multi-Modal Masked Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.17689</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.17689v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Medical vision-language models show strong potential for joint reasoning over medical images and clinical text, but their performance often degrades under domain shift caused by variations in imaging devices, acquisition protocols, and reporting styles. Existing multi-modal pre-training methods largely overlook robustness, treating it as a downstream adaptation problem. In this work, we propose Robust Multi-Modal Masked Reconstruction (Robust-MMR), a self-supervised pre-training framework that explicitly incorporates robustness objectives into masked vision-language learning. Robust-MMR integrates asymmetric perturbation-aware masking, domain-consistency regularization, and modality-resilience constraints to encourage domain-invariant representations. We evaluate Robust-MMR on multiple medical vision-language benchmarks, including medical visual question answering (VQA-RAD, SLAKE, VQA-2019), cross-domain image-text classification (MELINDA), and robust image-caption retrieval (ROCO). Robust-MMR achieves 78.9% cross-domain accuracy on VQA-RAD, outperforming the strongest baseline by 3.8 percentage points, and reaches 74.6% and 77.0% accuracy on SLAKE and VQA-2019, respectively. Under perturbed evaluation, Robust-MMR improves VQA-RAD accuracy from 69.1% to 75.6%. For image-text classification, cross-domain MELINDA accuracy increases from 70.3% to 75.2%, while retrieval experiments show a reduction in mean rank degradation from over 16 to 4.1 under perturbation. Qualitative results further demonstrate improved clinical reasoning for disease detection and structural abnormality assessment. These findings show that explicitly modeling robustness during pre-training leads to more reliable and transferable medical vision-language representations for real-world deployment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.17689v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Melika Filvantorkaman, Mohsen Piri</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tethered Reasoning: Decoupling Entropy from Hallucination in Quantized LLMs via Manifold Steering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.17691</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.17691v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Quantized language models face a fundamental dilemma: low sampling temperatures yield repetitive, mode-collapsed outputs, while high temperatures (T &gt; 2.0) cause trajectory divergence and semantic incoherence. We present HELIX, a geometric framework that decouples output entropy from hallucination by tethering hidden-state trajectories to a pre-computed truthfulness manifold. HELIX computes a Unified Truth Score (UTS) combining token-level semantic entropy with Mahalanobis distance from the manifold. When UTS indicates trajectory divergence, graduated steering vectors redirect activations toward structurally coherent regions while affecting only 0.2-2.5% of tokens.
  On 4-bit quantized Granite 4.0 H Small (32B/9B active, hybrid Mamba-Transformer): GSM8K maintains 88.84% accuracy at T = 3.0 (2.81pp degradation from T = 0.5); MMLU maintains 72.49% across 14,042 questions (1.24pp degradation). This demonstrates that high-temperature hallucination is primarily trajectory divergence rather than semantic collapse. Notably, steering the sparse Transformer attention layers (~10% of layers) is sufficient to correct drift in the Mamba-2 state-space formulation.
  Geometric tethering reveals a previously-masked High-Entropy Creative Reservoir. At T &gt; 2.0, steered outputs exhibit 5-20% idea duplication versus 70-80% at conservative settings. Cross-architecture validation (Qwen3-30B-A3B MOE) confirms this phenomenon is architecture-independent, with 46.7% higher unique concept generation. HELIX acts as a syntax tether, enabling exploration of semantic diversity without violating the logical backbone required for valid output. This enables Multi-Temperature Synthesis, generating 200% more unique concepts than single-temperature inference.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.17691v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Craig Atkinson</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Case Study of Selected PTQ Baselines for Reasoning LLMs on Ascend NPU</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.17693</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.17693v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Post-Training Quantization (PTQ) is crucial for efficient model deployment, yet its effectiveness on Ascend NPU remains under-explored compared to GPU architectures. This paper presents a case study of representative PTQ baselines applied to reasoning-oriented models such as DeepSeek-R1-Distill-Qwen series (1.5B/7B/14B) and QwQ-32B. We evaluate four distinct algorithms, including AWQ, GPTQ, SmoothQuant, and FlatQuant, to cover the spectrum from weight-only compression to advanced rotation-based methods. Our empirical results reveal significant platform sensitivity. While 4-bit weight-only quantization proves viable for larger models, aggressive 4-bit weight-activation schemes suffer from layer-wise calibration instability on the NPU, leading to logic collapse in long-context reasoning tasks. Conversely, standard 8-bit quantization remains numerically stable. Furthermore, a real-world INT8 deployment demonstrates that although optimized kernels reduce latency, dynamic quantization overheads currently limit end-to-end acceleration. These findings offer a practical reference for the feasibility and limitations of deploying quantized reasoning models on Ascend NPU.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.17693v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuchen Luo, Fangyue Zhu, Ruining Zhou, Mingzhe Huang, Jian Zhu, Fanyu Fan, Wei Shao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Optimality of In-Context Learning with Selective State Spaces</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.17744</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.17744v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We propose Bayesian optimal sequential prediction as a new principle for understanding in-context learning (ICL). Unlike interpretations framing Transformers as performing implicit gradient descent, we formalize ICL as meta-learning over latent sequence tasks. For tasks governed by Linear Gaussian State Space Models (LG-SSMs), we prove a meta-trained selective SSM asymptotically implements the Bayes-optimal predictor, converging to the posterior predictive mean. We further establish a statistical separation from gradient descent, constructing tasks with temporally correlated noise where the optimal Bayesian predictor strictly outperforms any empirical risk minimization (ERM) estimator. Since Transformers can be seen as performing implicit ERM, this demonstrates selective SSMs achieve lower asymptotic risk due to superior statistical efficiency. Experiments on synthetic LG-SSM tasks and a character-level Markov benchmark confirm selective SSMs converge faster to Bayes-optimal risk, show superior sample efficiency with longer contexts in structured-noise settings, and track latent states more robustly than linear Transformers. This reframes ICL from "implicit optimization" to "optimal inference," explaining the efficiency of selective SSMs and offering a principled basis for architecture design.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.17744v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>math.ST</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <category>stat.TH</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Di Zhang, Jiaqi Xing</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TFL: Targeted Bit-Flip Attack on Large Language Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.17837</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.17837v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are increasingly deployed in safety and security critical applications, raising concerns about their robustness to model parameter fault injection attacks. Recent studies have shown that bit-flip attacks (BFAs), which exploit computer main memory (i.e., DRAM) vulnerabilities to flip a small number of bits in model weights, can severely disrupt LLM behavior. However, existing BFA on LLM largely induce un-targeted failure or general performance degradation, offering limited control over manipulating specific or targeted outputs. In this paper, we present TFL, a novel targeted bit-flip attack framework that enables precise manipulation of LLM outputs for selected prompts while maintaining almost no or minor degradation on unrelated inputs. Within our TFL framework, we propose a novel keyword-focused attack loss to promote attacker-specified target tokens in generative outputs, together with an auxiliary utility score that balances attack effectiveness against collateral performance impact on benign data. We evaluate TFL on multiple LLMs (Qwen, DeepSeek, Llama) and benchmarks (DROP, GSM8K, and TriviaQA). The experiments show that TFL achieves successful targeted LLM output manipulations with less than 50 bit flips and significantly reduced effect on unrelated queries compared to prior BFA approaches. This demonstrates the effectiveness of TFL and positions it as a new class of stealthy and targeted LLM model attack.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.17837v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jingkai Guo, Chaitali Chakrabarti, Deliang Fan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mind the Style: Impact of Communication Style on Human-Chatbot Interaction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.17850</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.17850v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Conversational agents increasingly mediate everyday digital interactions, yet the effects of their communication style on user experience and task success remain unclear. Addressing this gap, we describe the results of a between-subject user study where participants interact with one of two versions of a chatbot called NAVI which assists users in an interactive map-based 2D navigation task. The two chatbot versions differ only in communication style: one is friendly and supportive, while the other is direct and task-focused. Our results show that the friendly style increases subjective satisfaction and significantly improves task completion rates among female participants only, while no baseline differences between female and male participants were observed in a control condition without the chatbot. Furthermore, we find little evidence of users mimicking the chatbot's style, suggesting limited linguistic accommodation. These findings highlight the importance of user- and task-sensitive conversational agents and support that communication style personalization can meaningfully enhance interaction quality and performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.17850v1</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Erik Derner, Dalibor Ku\v{c}era, Aditya Gulati, Ayoub Bagheri, Nuria Oliver</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ADAPT: Hybrid Prompt Optimization for LLM Feature Visualization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.17867</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.17867v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Understanding what features are encoded by learned directions in LLM activation space requires identifying inputs that strongly activate them. Feature visualization, which optimizes inputs to maximally activate a target direction, offers an alternative to costly dataset search approaches, but remains underexplored for LLMs due to the discrete nature of text. Furthermore, existing prompt optimization techniques are poorly suited to this domain, which is highly prone to local minima. To overcome these limitations, we introduce ADAPT, a hybrid method combining beam search initialization with adaptive gradient-guided mutation, designed around these failure modes. We evaluate on Sparse Autoencoder latents from Gemma 2 2B, proposing metrics grounded in dataset activation statistics to enable rigorous comparison, and show that ADAPT consistently outperforms prior methods across layers and latent types. Our results establish that feature visualization for LLMs is tractable, but requires design assumptions tailored to the domain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.17867v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jo\~ao N. Cardoso, Arlindo L. Oliveira, Bruno Martins</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Games That Teach, Chats That Convince: Comparing Interactive and Static Formats for Persuasive Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.17905</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.17905v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Interactive systems such as chatbots and games are increasingly used to persuade and educate on sustainability-related topics, yet it remains unclear how different delivery formats shape learning and persuasive outcomes when content is held constant. Grounding on identical arguments and factual content across conditions, we present a controlled user study comparing three modes of information delivery: static essays, conversational chatbots, and narrative text-based games. Across subjective measures, the chatbot condition consistently outperformed the other modes and increased perceived importance of the topic. However, perceived learning did not reliably align with objective outcomes: participants in the text-based game condition reported learning less than those reading essays, yet achieved higher scores on a delayed (24-hour) knowledge quiz. Additional exploratory analyses further suggest that common engagement proxies, such as verbosity and interaction length, are more closely related to subjective experience than to actual learning. These findings highlight a dissociation between how persuasive experiences feel and what participants retain, and point to important design trade-offs between interactivity, realism, and learning in persuasive systems and serious games.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.17905v1</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.ET</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Seyed Hossein Alavi, Zining Wang, Shruthi Chockkalingam, Raymond T. Ng, Vered Shwartz</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NIMMGen: Learning Neural-Integrated Mechanistic Digital Twins with LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.18008</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.18008v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Mechanistic models encode scientific knowledge about dynamical systems and are widely used in downstream scientific and policy applications. Recent work has explored LLM-based agentic frameworks to automatically construct mechanistic models from data; however, existing problem settings substantially oversimplify real-world conditions, leaving it unclear whether LLM-generated mechanistic models are reliable in practice. To address this gap, we introduce the Neural-Integrated Mechanistic Modeling (NIMM) evaluation framework, which evaluates LLM-generated mechanistic models under realistic settings with partial observations and diversified task objectives. Our evaluation reveals fundamental challenges in current baselines, ranging from model effectiveness to code-level correctness. Motivated by these findings, we design NIMMgen, an agentic framework for neural-integrated mechanistic modeling that enhances code correctness and practical validity through iterative refinement. Experiments across three datasets from diversified scientific domains demonstrate its strong performance. We also show that the learned mechanistic models support counterfactual intervention simulation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.18008v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zihan Guan, Rituparna Datta, Mengxuan Hu, Shunshun Liu, Aiying Zhang, Prasanna Balachandran, Sheng Li, Anil Vullikanti</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gradient Regularization Prevents Reward Hacking in Reinforcement Learning from Human Feedback and Verifiable Rewards</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.18037</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.18037v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Reinforcement Learning from Human Feedback (RLHF) or Verifiable Rewards (RLVR) are two key steps in the post-training of modern Language Models (LMs). A common problem is reward hacking, where the policy may exploit inaccuracies of the reward and learn an unintended behavior. Most previous works address this by limiting the policy update with a Kullback-Leibler (KL) penalty towards a reference model. We propose a different framing: Train the LM in a way that biases policy updates towards regions in which the reward is more accurate. First, we derive a theoretical connection between the accuracy of a reward model and the flatness of an optimum at convergence. Gradient regularization (GR) can then be used to bias training to flatter regions and thereby maintain reward model accuracy. We confirm these results by showing that the gradient norm and reward accuracy are empirically correlated in RLHF. We then show that Reference Resets of the KL penalty implicitly use GR to find flatter regions with higher reward accuracy. We further improve on this by proposing to use explicit GR with an efficient finite-difference estimate. Empirically, GR performs better than a KL penalty across a diverse set of RL experiments with LMs. GR achieves a higher GPT-judged win-rate in RLHF, avoids overly focusing on the format in rule-based math rewards, and prevents hacking the judge in LLM-as-a-Judge math tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.18037v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Johannes Ackermann, Michael Noukhovitch, Takashi Ishida, Masashi Sugiyama</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing and Improving Chain-of-Thought Monitorability Through Information Theory</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.18297</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.18297v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Chain-of-thought (CoT) monitors are LLM-based systems that analyze reasoning traces to detect when outputs may exhibit attributes of interest, such as test-hacking behavior during code generation. In this paper, we use information-theoretic analysis to show that non-zero mutual information between CoT and output is a necessary but not sufficient condition for CoT monitorability. We identify two sources of approximation error that may undermine the performance of CoT monitors in practice: information gap, which measures the extent to which the monitor can extract the information available in CoT, and elicitation error, which measures the extent to which the monitor approximates the optimal monitoring function. We further demonstrate that CoT monitorability can be systematically improved through targeted training objectives. To this end, we propose two complementary approaches: (a) an oracle-based method that directly rewards the monitored model for producing CoTs that maximize monitor accuracy, and (b) a more practical, label-free approach that maximizes conditional mutual information between outputs and CoTs. Across multiple different environments, we show both methods significantly improve monitor accuracy while preventing CoT degeneration even when training against a monitor, thereby mitigating reward hacking when the task reward is imperfectly specified.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.18297v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IT</category>
      <category>math.IT</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Usman Anwar, Tim Bakker, Dana Kianfar, Cristina Pinneri, Christos Louizos</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Semantic and Syntactic Information Encoded in Proto-Tokens for One-Step Text Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.18301</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.18301v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Autoregressive large language models (LLMs) generate text token-by-token, requiring n forward passes to produce a sequence of length n. Recent work, Exploring the Latent Capacity of LLMs for One-Step Text Reconstruction (Mezentsev and Oseledets), shows that frozen LLMs can reconstruct hundreds of tokens from only two learned proto-tokens in a single forward pass, suggesting a path beyond the autoregressive paradigm. In this paper, we study what information these proto-tokens encode and how they behave under reconstruction and controlled constraints. We perform a series of experiments aimed at disentangling semantic and syntactic content in the two proto-tokens, analyzing stability properties of the e-token, and visualizing attention patterns to the e-token during reconstruction. Finally, we test two regularization schemes for "imposing" semantic structure on the e-token using teacher embeddings, including an anchor-based loss and a relational distillation objective. Our results indicate that the m-token tends to capture semantic information more strongly than the e-token under standard optimization; anchor-based constraints trade off sharply with reconstruction accuracy; and relational distillation can transfer batch-level semantic relations into the proto-token space without sacrificing reconstruction quality, supporting the feasibility of future non-autoregressive seq2seq systems that predict proto-tokens as an intermediate representation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.18301v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ivan Bondarenko, Egor Palkin, Fedor Tikunov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VeriSoftBench: Repository-Scale Formal Verification Benchmarks for Lean</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.18307</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.18307v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large language models have achieved striking results in interactive theorem proving, particularly in Lean. However, most benchmarks for LLM-based proof automation are drawn from mathematics in the Mathlib ecosystem, whereas proofs in software verification are developed inside definition-rich codebases with substantial project-specific libraries. We introduce VeriSoftBench, a benchmark of 500 Lean 4 proof obligations drawn from open-source formal-methods developments and packaged to preserve realistic repository context and cross-file dependencies. Our evaluation of frontier LLMs and specialized provers yields three observations. First, provers tuned for Mathlib-style mathematics transfer poorly to this repository-centric setting. Second, success is strongly correlated with transitive repository dependence: tasks whose proofs draw on large, multi-hop dependency closures are less likely to be solved. Third, providing curated context restricted to a proof's dependency closure improves performance relative to exposing the full repository, but nevertheless leaves substantial room for improvement. Our benchmark and evaluation suite are released at https://github.com/utopia-group/VeriSoftBench.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.18307v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.PL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yutong Xin, Qiaochu Chen, Greg Durrett, I\c{s}il Dillig</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the "Induction Bias" in Sequence Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.18333</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.18333v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Despite the remarkable practical success of transformer-based language models, recent work has raised concerns about their ability to perform state tracking. In particular, a growing body of literature has shown this limitation primarily through failures in out-of-distribution (OOD) generalization, such as length extrapolation. In this work, we shift attention to the in-distribution implications of these limitations. We conduct a large-scale experimental study of the data efficiency of transformers and recurrent neural networks (RNNs) across multiple supervision regimes. We find that the amount of training data required by transformers grows much more rapidly with state-space size and sequence length than for RNNs. Furthermore, we analyze the extent to which learned state-tracking mechanisms are shared across different sequence lengths. We show that transformers exhibit negligible or even detrimental weight sharing across lengths, indicating that they learn length-specific solutions in isolation. In contrast, recurrent models exhibit effective amortized learning by sharing weights across lengths, allowing data from one sequence length to improve performance on others. Together, these results demonstrate that state tracking remains a fundamental challenge for transformers, even when training and evaluation distributions match.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.18333v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>M. Reza Ebrahimi, Micha\"el Defferrard, Sunny Panchal, Roland Memisevic</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Subgroups of $U(d)$ Induce Natural RNN and Transformer Architectures</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.18417</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.18417v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This paper presents a direct framework for sequence models with hidden states on closed subgroups of U(d). We use a minimal axiomatic setup and derive recurrent and transformer templates from a shared skeleton in which subgroup choice acts as a drop-in replacement for state space, tangent projection, and update map. We then specialize to O(d) and evaluate orthogonal-state RNN and transformer models on Tiny Shakespeare and Penn Treebank under parameter-matched settings. We also report a general linear-mixing extension in tangent space, which applies across subgroup choices and improves finite-budget performance in the current O(d) experiments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.18417v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Joshua Nunley</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Topic Modeling with Fine-tuning LLMs and Bag of Sentences</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.03099</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.03099v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are increasingly used for topic modeling, outperforming classical topic models such as LDA. Commonly, pre-trained LLM encoders such as BERT are used out-of-the-box despite the fact that fine-tuning is known to improve LLMs considerably. The challenge lies in obtaining a suitable labeled dataset for fine-tuning. In this paper, we build on the recent idea of using bags of sentences as the elementary unit for computing topics. Based on this idea, we derive an approach called FT-Topic to perform unsupervised fine-tuning, relying primarily on two steps for constructing a training dataset in an automatic fashion. First, a heuristic method identifies pairs of sentence groups that are assumed to belong either to the same topic or to different topics. Second, we remove sentence pairs that are likely labeled incorrectly. The resulting dataset is then used to fine-tune an encoder LLM, which can be leveraged by any topic modeling approach that uses embeddings. In this work, we demonstrate its effectiveness by deriving a novel state-of-the-art topic modeling method called SenClu. The method achieves fast inference through an expectation-maximization algorithm and hard assignments of sentence groups to a single topic, while allowing users to encode prior knowledge about the topic-document distribution. Code is available at https://github.com/JohnTailor/FT-Topic</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.03099v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Johannes Schneider</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Mimicry to Contextual Guidance: Knowledge Distillation for Interactive AI</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.07238</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.07238v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: As large language models increasingly mediate firm - customer interactions, firms face a tradeoff: the most capable models perform well but are costly and difficult to control at scale. Existing knowledge distillation methods address this challenge by training weaker, deployable models to imitate frontier outputs; however, such open-loop approaches are poorly suited to interactive, multi-turn settings where responses must be sequenced coherently across conversational states. We propose a shift in what knowledge is distilled - from output imitation to contextual guidance. We develop a framework in which a superior teacher model constructs a reusable library of strategic textual guidance for particular scenarios likely to be encountered by the student. When deployed, the student retrieves the context-specific guidance at inference time, enabling adaptive behavior without retraining. Using customer-service interactions, we show that this approach improves service quality and customer satisfaction relative to standard fine-tuning while maintaining alignment with firm policies. The results position inference-time textual guidance as a scalable and controllable approach to distillation for interactive AI agents in marketing settings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.07238v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tong Wang, K. Sudhir</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HoT: Highlighted Chain of Thought for Referencing Supporting Facts from Inputs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.02003</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.02003v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: An Achilles heel of Large Language Models (LLMs) is their tendency to hallucinate non-factual statements. A response mixed of factual and non-factual statements poses a challenge for humans to verify and accurately base their decisions on. To combat this problem, we propose Highlighted Chain-of-Thought Prompting (HoT), a technique for prompting LLMs to generate responses with XML tags that ground facts to those provided in the question. That is, given an input question, LLMs would first re-format the question to add XML tags highlighting key facts, and then, generate a response with highlights over the facts referenced from the input. Compared to vanilla chain of thought prompting (CoT), HoT reduces the rate of hallucination and separately improves LLM accuracy consistently on over 22 tasks from arithmetic, reading comprehension, to logical reasoning. When asking humans to verify LLM responses, highlights help time-limited participants to more accurately and efficiently recognize when LLMs are correct. Yet, surprisingly, when LLMs are wrong, HoTs tend to fool users into believing that an answer is correct.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.02003v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tin Nguyen, Logan Bolton, Mohammad Reza Taesiri, Trung Bui, Anh Totti Nguyen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FLUKE: A Linguistically-Driven and Task-Agnostic Framework for Robustness Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.17311</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.17311v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We present FLUKE (Framework for LingUistically-driven and tasK-agnostic robustness Evaluation), a framework for assessing model robustness through systematic minimal variations of test data. FLUKE introduces controlled variations across linguistic levels -- from orthography to dialect and style -- and leverages large language models (LLMs) with human validation to generate modifications. We demonstrate FLUKE's utility by evaluating both fine-tuned models and LLMs across six diverse NLP tasks (four classification and two generation tasks), and reveal that (1) the impact of linguistic variations is highly task-dependent, with some tests being critical for certain tasks but irrelevant for others; (2) LLMs still exhibit significant brittleness to certain linguistic variations, with reasoning LLMs surprisingly showing less robustness on some tasks compared to base models, and scaling improving robustness only for surface-level modifications; (3) models are overall more brittle to natural, fluent modifications such as syntax or style changes (and especially to negation), compared to corruption-style tests such as letter flipping; (4) the ability of a model to use a linguistic feature in generation does not correlate to its robustness to this feature on downstream tasks. These findings highlight the importance of systematic robustness testing for understanding model behaviors.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.17311v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yulia Otmakhova, Hung Thinh Truong, Rahmad Mahendra, Zenan Zhai, Rongxin Zhu, Daniel Beck, Jey Han Lau</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ConformalNL2LTL: Translating Natural Language Instructions into Temporal Logic Formulas with Conformal Correctness Guarantees</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.21022</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.21022v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Linear Temporal Logic (LTL) is a widely used task specification language for autonomous systems. To mitigate the significant manual effort and expertise required to define LTL-encoded tasks, several methods have been proposed for translating Natural Language (NL) instructions into LTL formulas, which, however, lack correctness guarantees. To address this, we propose a new NL-to-LTL translation method, called ConformalNL2LTL that achieves user-defined translation success rates on unseen NL commands. Our method constructs LTL formulas iteratively by solving a sequence of open-vocabulary question-answering (QA) problems using large language models (LLMs). These QA tasks are handled collaboratively by a primary and an auxiliary model. The primary model answers each QA instance while quantifying uncertainty via conformal prediction; when it is insufficiently certain according to user-defined confidence thresholds, it requests assistance from the auxiliary model and, if necessary, from the user. We demonstrate theoretically and empirically that ConformalNL2LTL achieves the desired translation accuracy while minimizing user intervention.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.21022v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>David Smith Sundarsingh, Jun Wang, Jyotirmoy V. Deshmukh, Yiannis Kantaros</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entailed Opinion Matters: Improving the Fact-Checking Performance of Language Models by Relying on their Entailment Ability</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.15050</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.15050v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Automated fact-checking has been a challenging task for the research community. Prior work has explored various strategies, such as end-to-end training, retrieval-augmented generation, and prompt engineering, to build robust fact-checking systems. However, their accuracy has not been high enough for real-world deployment. We, on the other hand, propose a new learning paradigm, where evidence classification and entailed justifications made by generative language models (GLMs) are used to train encoder-only language models (ELMs). We conducted a rigorous set of experiments, comparing our approach with recent works along with various prompting and fine-tuning strategies. Additionally, we performed ablation studies, error analysis, quality analysis of model explanations, and a domain generalisation study to provide a comprehensive understanding of our approach.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.15050v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gaurav Kumar, Ayush Garg, Debajyoti Mazumder, Aditya Kishore, Babu kumar, Jasabanta Patro</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PonderLM: Pretraining Language Models to Ponder in Continuous Space</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.20674</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.20674v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Humans ponder before articulating complex sentence elements, enabling deeper cognitive processing through focused effort. In this work, we introduce this pondering process into language models by repeatedly invoking the forward process within a single token generation step. During pondering, instead of generating an actual token sampled from the prediction distribution, the model ponders by yielding a weighted sum of all token embeddings according to the predicted token distribution. The generated embedding is then fed back as input for another forward pass. We show that the model can learn to ponder in this way through self-supervised learning, without any human annotations. Experiments across three widely used open-source architectures-GPT-2, Pythia, and LLaMA-and extensive downstream task evaluations demonstrate the effectiveness and generality of our method. On 9 downstream benchmarks, our pondering-enhanced Pythia models significantly outperform the official Pythia models. Notably, our PonderPythia models demonstrate remarkable effectiveness: PonderPythia-2.8B surpasses Pythia-6.9B and rivals Pythia-12B, while our PonderPythia-1B matches TinyLlama-1.1B, a model trained on 10 times more data. The code is available at https://github.com/LUMIA-Group/PonderingLM.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.20674v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Boyi Zeng, Shixiang Song, Siyuan Huang, Yixuan Wang, He Li, Ziwei He, Xinbing Wang, Zhiyu Li, Zhouhan Lin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure-Augmented Reasoning Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.08364</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.08364v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advances in Large Language Models (LLMs) have significantly improved complex reasoning capabilities. Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) has further extended these capabilities by grounding generation in dynamically retrieved evidence, enabling access to information beyond the model's training parameters. However, while RAG addresses knowledge availability, standard pipelines treat retrieved documents as independent, unstructured text chunks, forcing models to implicitly connect information across fragmented context. This limitation becomes critical for multi-hop queries, where answering correctly requires synthesizing information scattered across different documents. We present Structure-Augmented Reasoning Generation (SARG), a post-retrieval framework that addresses this gap by materializing explicit reasoning structures from retrieved context. SARG operates in three stages: extracting relational triples from retrieved documents via few-shot prompting, organizing these triples into a domain-adaptive knowledge graph, and performing multi-hop traversal to identify relevant reasoning chains. These chains, along with their associated text chunks, are then integrated into the generation prompt to explicitly guide the model's reasoning process. Importantly, SARG doesn't require custom retrievers or domain-specific fine-tuning. Instead, it functions as a modular layer compatible with all existing RAG pipelines. Extensive experiments on open-domain QA benchmarks and specialized reasoning datasets in finance and medicine demonstrate that SARG significantly outperforms state-of-the-art flat-context RAG baselines in both factual accuracy and reasoning coherence. Furthermore, by surfacing the exact traversal paths used during generation, SARG provides fully traceable and interpretable inference.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.08364v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jash Rajesh Parekh, Pengcheng Jiang, Jiawei Han</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling Decision-Making in LLMs for Text Classification : Extraction of influential and interpretable concepts with Sparse Autoencoders</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.23951</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.23951v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Sparse Autoencoders (SAEs) have been successfully used to probe Large Language Models (LLMs) and extract interpretable concepts from their internal representations. These concepts are linear combinations of neuron activations that correspond to human-interpretable features. In this paper, we investigate the effectiveness of SAE-based explainability approaches for sentence classification, a domain where such methods have not been extensively explored. We present a novel SAE-based model ClassifSAE tailored for text classification, leveraging a specialized classifier head and incorporating an activation rate sparsity loss. We benchmark this architecture against established methods such as ConceptShap, Independent Component Analysis, HI-Concept and a standard TopK-SAE baseline. Our evaluation covers several classification benchmarks and backbone LLMs. We further enrich our analysis with two novel metrics for measuring the precision of concept-based explanations, using an external sentence encoder. Our empirical results show that ClassifSAE improves both the causality and interpretability of the extracted features.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.23951v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mathis Le Bail, J\'er\'emie Dentan, Davide Buscaldi, Sonia Vanier</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anthropomimetic Uncertainty: What Verbalized Uncertainty in Language Models is Missing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.10587</link>
      <description>arXiv:2507.10587v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Human users increasingly communicate with large language models (LLMs), but LLMs suffer from frequent overconfidence in their output, even when its accuracy is questionable, which undermines their trustworthiness and perceived legitimacy. Therefore, there is a need for language models to signal their confidence in order to reap the benefits of human-machine collaboration and mitigate potential harms. Verbalized uncertainty is the expression of confidence with linguistic means, an approach that integrates perfectly into language-based interfaces. Most recent research in natural language processing (NLP) overlooks the nuances surrounding human uncertainty communication and the biases that influence the communication of and with machines. We argue for anthropomimetic uncertainty, the principle that intuitive and trustworthy uncertainty communication requires a degree of imitation of human linguistic behaviors. We present a thorough overview of the research in human uncertainty communication, survey ongoing research in NLP, and perform additional analyses to demonstrate so-far underexplored biases in verbalized uncertainty. We conclude by pointing out unique factors in human-machine uncertainty and outlining future research directions towards implementing anthropomimetic uncertainty.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2507.10587v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dennis Ulmer, Alexandra Lorson, Ivan Titov, Christian Hardmeier</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoAct-1: Computer-using Multi-Agent System with Coding Actions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.03923</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.03923v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Autonomous agents that operate computers via Graphical User Interfaces (GUIs) often struggle with efficiency and reliability on complex, long-horizon tasks. While augmenting these agents with planners can improve task decomposition, they remain constrained by the inherent limitations of performing all actions through GUI manipulation, leading to brittleness and inefficiency. In this work, we introduce a more robust and flexible paradigm: enabling agents to use coding as a enhanced action. We present CoAct-1, a novel multi-agent system that synergistically combines GUI-based control with direct programmatic execution. CoAct-1 features an Orchestrator that dynamically delegates subtasks to either a conventional GUI Operator or a specialized Programmer agent, which can write and execute Python or Bash scripts. This hybrid approach allows the agent to bypass inefficient GUI action sequences for tasks like file management and data processing, while still leveraging visual interaction when necessary. We evaluate our system on the challenging OSWorld benchmark, where CoAct-1 achieves a new state-of-the-art success rate of 60.76%, significantly outperforming prior methods. Furthermore, our approach dramatically improves efficiency, reducing the average number of steps required to complete a task to just 10.15, compared to 15 for leading GUI agents. Our results demonstrate that integrating coding as a core action provides a more powerful, efficient, and scalable path toward generalized computer automation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.03923v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Linxin Song, Yutong Dai, Viraj Prabhu, Jieyu Zhang, Taiwei Shi, Li Li, Junnan Li, Silvio Savarese, Zeyuan Chen, Jieyu Zhao, Ran Xu, Caiming Xiong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Share Your Attention: Transformer Weight Sharing via Matrix-based Dictionary Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.04581</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.04581v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models have revolutionized AI applications, yet their high computational and memory demands hinder their widespread deployment. Existing compression techniques focus on intra-block optimizations (e.g., low-rank approximation or attention pruning), while the repetitive layered structure of transformers implies significant inter-block redundancy - a dimension largely unexplored beyond key-value (KV) caching. Inspired by dictionary learning in convolutional networks, we propose a framework for structured weight sharing across transformer layers. Our approach decomposes attention projection matrices (Q, K, V, O) into shared dictionary atoms, reducing the attention module's parameters by 66.7\% while achieving on-par performance. Unlike complex methods requiring distillation or architectural changes, MASA (Matrix Atom Sharing in Attention) operates as a drop-in replacement-trained with standard optimizers - and represents each layer's weights as linear combinations of shared matrix atoms. Experiments across scales (100M-700M parameters) show that MASA achieves better benchmark accuracy and perplexity than GQA, low-rank baselines and recent Repeat-all-over/Sequential sharing at comparable parameter budgets. Ablation studies confirm robustness to the dictionary size and the efficacy of shared representations in capturing cross-layer statistical regularities. Extending to Vision Transformers (ViT), MASA matches performance metrics on image classification tasks with 66.7\% fewer attention parameters. By combining dictionary learning strategies with transformer efficiency, MASA offers a scalable blueprint for parameter-efficient models without sacrificing performance. Finally, we investigate the possibility of employing MASA on large pretrained models to reduce their number of parameters without experiencing any significant drop in their performance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.04581v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Magauiya Zhussip, Dmitriy Shopkhoev, Ammar Ali, Stamatios Lefkimmiatis</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Probability Distributions Computed by Autoregressive Transformers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27118</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27118v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Most expressivity results for transformers treat them as language recognizers (which accept or reject strings), and not as they are used in practice, as language models (which generate strings autoregressively and probabilistically). We characterize the probability distributions that transformer language models can express. We show that making transformer language recognizers autoregressive can sometimes increase their expressivity, and that making them probabilistic can break equivalences that hold in the non-probabilistic case. Our overall contribution is to tease apart what functions transformers are capable of expressing, in their most common use-case as language models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27118v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Andy Yang, Anej Svete, Jiaoda Li, Anthony Widjaja Lin, Jonathan Rawski, Ryan Cotterell, David Chiang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Distributions Shifts: Causal Generalization for Low-Resource Languages</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.27512</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.27512v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Machine learning models often fail under distribution shifts, a problem exacerbated in low-resource settings where limited data restricts robust generalization. Domain generalization(DG) methods address this challenge by learning representations that remain invariant across domains, frequently leveraging causal principles. In this work, we study two causal DG approaches for low-resource natural language processing. First, we apply causal data augmentation using GPT-4o-mini to generate counterfactual paraphrases for sentiment classification on the NaijaSenti Twitter corpus in Yoruba and Igbo. Second, we investigate invariant causal representation learning with the Debiasing in Aspect Review (DINER) framework for aspect-based sentiment analysis. We extend DINER to a multilingual setting by introducing Afri-SemEval, a dataset of 17 languages translated from SemEval-2014 Task. Experiments show improved robustness to unseen domains, with consistent gains from counterfactual augmentation and enhanced out-of-distribution performance from causal representation learning across multiple languages.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.27512v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mahi Aliyu Aminu, Chisom Chibuike, Fatimo Adebanjo, Omokolade Awosanya, Samuel Oyeneye</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Batch Prompting Suppresses Overthinking Reasoning Under Constraint: How Batch Prompting Suppresses Overthinking in Reasoning Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.04108</link>
      <description>arXiv:2511.04108v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Reasoning Models (LRMs) achieve strong performance through explicit chain-of-thought reasoning but suffer from \textit{overthinking}: generating excessive reasoning tokens even for trivial queries. {Beyond inflating cost, overthinking can be self-defeating: models enter recursive self-doubt loops that exhaust token budgets without producing an answer, causing API timeouts that directly hurt accuracy.} We present an empirical study showing that \textbf{batch prompting}, originally introduced for throughput optimization, effectively suppresses overthinking at inference time. Across 13 diverse benchmarks with DeepSeek-R1 and OpenAI-o1, batch prompting {reduces reasoning tokens by 76\% (2{,}950$\mapsto$710), on average, while preserving or improving accuracy}. Through behavioral analysis, we find that batching induces three beneficial effects: (1) it reduces per-query reasoning effort when multiple queries share a context; (2) it enables pattern induction, where models generalize from earlier examples to solve later ones; and (3) it suppresses hedging behavior (e.g., ``\texttt{wait,}'' ``\texttt{let me double-check}'') that signals metacognitive loops. We also show that explicit prompt constraints (``\texttt{Use no more than 100 tokens in thinking.}'') fail to reduce overthinking; models either ignore them or sacrifice accuracy. These findings reframe batch prompting as more than a cost optimization: it is a practical inference-time technique that improves efficiency and reliability without model modification.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2511.04108v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Saurabh Srivastava, Janit Bidhan, Hao Yan, Abhishek Dey, Tanu Kansal, Paras Kath, Sina Mansouri, Mohit Marvania, Vamsi Shankar Simhadri, Gaurav Singh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MUCH: A Multilingual Claim Hallucination Benchmark</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17081</link>
      <description>arXiv:2511.17081v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Claim-level Uncertainty Quantification (UQ) is a promising approach to mitigate the lack of reliability in Large Language Models (LLMs). We introduce MUCH, the first claim-level UQ benchmark designed for fair and reproducible evaluation of future methods under realistic conditions. It includes 4,873 samples across four European languages (English, French, Spanish, and German) and four instruction-tuned open-weight LLMs. Unlike prior claim-level benchmarks, we release 24 generation logits per token, facilitating the development of future white-box methods without re-generating data. Moreover, in contrast to previous benchmarks that rely on manual or LLM-based segmentation, we propose a new deterministic algorithm capable of segmenting claims using as little as 0.2% of the LLM generation time. This makes our segmentation approach suitable for real-time monitoring of LLM outputs, ensuring that MUCH evaluates UQ methods under realistic deployment constraints. Finally, our evaluations show that current methods still have substantial room for improvement in both performance and efficiency.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2511.17081v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>J\'er\'emie Dentan, Alexi Canesse, Davide Buscaldi, Aymen Shabou, Sonia Vanier</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cross-Lingual Interleaving for Speech Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.01865</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.01865v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Spoken Language Models (SLMs) aim to learn linguistic competence directly from speech using discrete units, widening access to Natural Language Processing (NLP) technologies for languages with limited written resources. However, progress has been largely English-centric due to scarce spoken evaluation benchmarks and training data, making cross-lingual learning difficult. We present a cross-lingual interleaving method that mixes speech tokens across languages without textual supervision. We also release an EN-FR training dataset, TinyStories (~42k hours), together with EN-FR spoken StoryCloze and TopicCloze benchmarks for cross-lingual semantic evaluation, both synthetically generated using GPT-4. On 360M and 1B SLMs under matched training-token budgets, interleaving improves monolingual semantic accuracy, enables robust cross-lingual continuation, and strengthens cross-lingual hidden-state alignment. Taken together, these results indicate that cross-lingual interleaving is a simple, scalable route to building multilingual SLMs that understand and converse across languages. All resources will be made open-source to support reproducibility.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.01865v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Adel Moumen, Guangzhi Sun, Philip C. Woodland</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WISE: Web Information Satire and Fakeness Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24000</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.24000v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Distinguishing fake or untrue news from satire or humor poses a unique challenge due to their overlapping linguistic features and divergent intent. This study develops WISE (Web Information Satire and Fakeness Evaluation) framework which benchmarks eight lightweight transformer models alongside two baseline models on a balanced dataset of 20,000 samples from Fakeddit, annotated as either fake news or satire. Using stratified 5-fold cross-validation, we evaluate models across comprehensive metrics including accuracy, precision, recall, F1-score, ROC-AUC, PR-AUC, MCC, Brier score, and Expected Calibration Error. Our evaluation reveals that MiniLM, a lightweight model, achieves the highest accuracy (87.58%) among all models, while RoBERTa-base achieves the highest ROC-AUC (95.42%) and strong accuracy (87.36%). DistilBERT offers an excellent efficiency-accuracy trade-off with 86.28\% accuracy and 93.90\% ROC-AUC. Statistical tests confirm significant performance differences between models, with paired t-tests and McNemar tests providing rigorous comparisons. Our findings highlight that lightweight models can match or exceed baseline performance, offering actionable insights for deploying misinformation detection systems in real-world, resource-constrained settings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.24000v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3779211.3793174</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Gaurab Chhetri, Subasish Das, Tausif Islam Chowdhury</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alignment Pretraining: AI Discourse Causes Self-Fulfilling (Mis)alignment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.10160</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.10160v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Pretraining corpora contain extensive discourse about AI systems, yet the causal influence of this discourse on downstream alignment remains poorly understood. If prevailing descriptions of AI behaviour are predominantly negative, LLMs may internalise corresponding behavioural priors, giving rise to self-fulfilling misalignment. This paper provides the first controlled study of this hypothesis by pretraining 6.9B-parameter LLMs with varying amounts of (mis)alignment discourse. We find that discussion of AI contributes to misalignment. Upsampling synthetic training documents about AI misalignment leads to a notable increase in misaligned behaviour. Conversely, upsampling documents about aligned behaviour reduces misalignment scores from 45% to 9%. We consider this evidence of self-fulfilling alignment. These effects are dampened, but persist through post-training. Our findings establish the study of how pretraining data shapes alignment priors, or alignment pretraining, as a complement to post-training. We recommend practitioners consider pretraining for alignment alongside capabilities. We share our models, data, and evaluations at AlignmentPretraining.ai.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.10160v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Cameron Tice, Puria Radmard, Samuel Ratnam, Andy Kim, David Africa, Kyle O'Brien</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWED-FiNER: Agents, Web applications, and Expert Detectors for Fine-grained Named Entity Recognition across 36 Languages for 6.6 Billion Speakers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.10161</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.10161v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Named Entity Recognition (NER) is a foundational task in Natural Language Processing (NLP) and Information Retrieval (IR), which facilitates semantic search and structured data extraction. We introduce \textbf{AWED-FiNER}, an open-source collection of agentic tool, web application, and 53 state-of-the-art expert models that provide Fine-grained Named Entity Recognition (FgNER) solutions across 36 languages spoken by more than 6.6 billion people. The agentic tool enables routing multilingual text to specialized expert models to fetch FgNER annotations within seconds. The web-based platform provides a ready-to-use FgNER annotation service for non-technical users. Moreover, the collection of language-specific extremely small open-source state-of-the-art expert models facilitates offline deployment in resource-constrained scenarios, including edge devices. AWED-FiNER covers languages spoken by over 6.6 billion people, ranging from global languages like English, Chinese, Spanish, and Hindi, to low-resource languages like Assamese, Santali, and Odia, along with a specific focus on extremely low-resource vulnerable languages such as Bodo, Manipuri, Bishnupriya, and Mizo. The resources can be accessed here: Agentic Tool (https://github.com/PrachuryyaKaushik/AWED-FiNER), Web Application (https://hf.co/spaces/prachuryyaIITG/AWED-FiNER), and 53 Expert Detector Models (https://hf.co/collections/prachuryyaIITG/awed-finer).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.10161v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Prachuryya Kaushik, Ashish Anand</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Token Is Enough: Improving Diffusion Language Models with a Sink Token</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.19657</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.19657v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Diffusion Language Models (DLMs) have emerged as a compelling alternative to autoregressive approaches, enabling parallel text generation with competitive performance. Despite these advantages, there is a critical instability in DLMs: the moving sink phenomenon. Our analysis indicates that sink tokens exhibit low-norm representations in the Transformer's value space, and that the moving sink phenomenon serves as a protective mechanism in DLMs to prevent excessive information mixing. However, their unpredictable positions across diffusion steps undermine inference robustness. To resolve this, we propose a simple but effective extra sink token implemented via a modified attention mask. Specifically, we introduce a special token constrained to attend solely to itself, while remaining globally visible to all other tokens. Experimental results demonstrate that introducing a single extra token stabilizes attention sinks, substantially improving model performance. Crucially, further analysis confirms that the effectiveness of this token is independent of its position and characterized by negligible semantic content, validating its role as a robust and dedicated structural sink.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.19657v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zihou Zhang, Zheyong Xie, Li Zhong, Haifeng Liu, Shaosheng Cao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Argument Rarity-based Originality Assessment for AI-Assisted Writing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.01560</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.01560v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This study proposes Argument Rarity-based Originality Assessment (AROA), a framework for automatically evaluating argumentative originality in student essays. AROA defines originality as rarity within a reference corpus and evaluates it through four complementary components: structural rarity, claim rarity, evidence rarity, and cognitive depth, quantified via density estimation and integrated with quality adjustment. Experiments using 1,375 human essays and 1,000 AI-generated essays on two argumentative topics revealed three key findings. First, a strong negative correlation ($r = -0.67$) between text quality and claim rarity demonstrates a quality-originality trade-off. Second, while AI essays achieved near-perfect quality scores ($Q = 0.998$), their claim rarity was approximately one-fifth of human levels (AI: 0.037, human: 0.170), indicating that LLMs can reproduce argumentative structure but not semantic originality. Third, the four components showed low mutual correlations ($r = 0.06$--$0.13$ between structural and semantic dimensions), confirming that they capture genuinely independent aspects of originality. These results suggest that writing assessment in the AI era must shift from quality to originality.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.01560v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Keito Inoshita, Michiaki Omura, Tsukasa Yamanaka, Go Maeda, Kentaro Tsuji</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VILLAIN at AVerImaTeC: Verifying Image-Text Claims via Multi-Agent Collaboration</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04587</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.04587v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper describes VILLAIN, a multimodal fact-checking system that verifies image-text claims through prompt-based multi-agent collaboration. For the AVerImaTeC shared task, VILLAIN employs vision-language model agents across multiple stages of fact-checking. Textual and visual evidence is retrieved from the knowledge store enriched through additional web collection. To identify key information and address inconsistencies among evidence items, modality-specific and cross-modal agents generate analysis reports. In the subsequent stage, question-answer pairs are produced based on these reports. Finally, the Verdict Prediction agent produces the verification outcome based on the image-text claim and the generated question-answer pairs. Our system ranked first on the leaderboard across all evaluation metrics. The source code is publicly available at https://github.com/ssu-humane/VILLAIN.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.04587v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jaeyoon Jung, Yejun Yoon, Kunwoo Park</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Audio-LLMs Don't Listen: A Cross-Linguistic Study of Modality Arbitration</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.11488</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.11488v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: When audio and text conflict, speech-enabled language models follow the text 10 times more often than when arbitrating between two text sources, even when explicitly instructed to trust the audio. Using ALME, a benchmark of 57,602 controlled audio-text conflict stimuli across 8 languages, we find that Gemini 2.0 Flash exhibits 16.6% text dominance under audio-text conflict versus 1.6% under text-text conflict with identical reliability cues. This gap is not explained by audio quality: audio-only accuracy (97.2%) exceeds cascade accuracy (93.9%), indicating audio embeddings preserve more information than text transcripts. We propose that text dominance reflects an asymmetry not in information content but in arbitration accessibility: how easily the model can reason over competing representations.
  This framework explains otherwise puzzling findings. Forcing transcription before answering increases text dominance (19% to 33%), sacrificing audio's information advantage without improving accessibility. Framing text as "deliberately corrupted" reduces text dominance by 80%. A fine-tuning ablation provides interventional evidence: training only the audio projection layer increases text dominance (+26.5%), while LoRA on the language model halves it ($-$23.9%), localizing text dominance to the LLM's reasoning rather than the audio encoder. Experiments across four state-of-the-art audio-LLMs and 8 languages show consistent trends with substantial cross-linguistic and cross-model variation, establishing modality arbitration as a distinct reliability dimension not captured by standard speech benchmarks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.11488v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jayadev Billa</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoupling Strategy and Execution in Task-Focused Dialogue via Goal-Oriented Preference Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.15854</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.15854v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models show potential in task-oriented dialogue systems, yet existing training methods often rely on token-level likelihood or preference optimization, which poorly align with long-horizon task success. To address this, we propose Goal-Oriented Preference Optimization (GOPO), a hierarchical reinforcement learning framework that decouples strategy planning from response generation via an Expert Agent and a Customer Service Agent. The Expert Agent optimizes multi-turn goal preferences at the dialogue-trajectory level, while the Customer Service Agent generates responses strictly aligned with the selected strategy. We evaluate GOPO on public benchmarks and e-commerce customer service datasets, and introduce Task-focused Sequential Engagement (TSE), a sequence-level metric derived from real e-commerce interaction data. On the Mgshop dataset, GOPO improves TSE by 7.7% and 10.3% over PPO and Memento, with consistent gains in sequence-level reward and generation quality. Furthermore, a 14B model trained with GOPO achieves 2.7% and 1.5% higher TSE than Qwen-235B and GPT-5.2, respectively. Ablation studies confirm the Expert Agent's critical role in long-horizon optimization. GOPO demonstrates consistent improvements across other datasets as well. This work establishes a new paradigm for task-oriented dialogue systems in commercial scenarios, with code and datasets to be made public.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.15854v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jingyi Xu, Xingyu Ren, Zhoupeng Shou, Yumeng Zhang, Zhiqiang You</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Imitating AI agents increase diversity in homogeneous information environments but can reduce it in heterogeneous ones</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.16021</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.16021v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Recent developments in large language models (LLMs) have facilitated autonomous AI agents capable of imitating human-generated content, raising fundamental questions about how AI may reshape democratic information environments such as news. We develop a large-scale simulation framework to examine the system-level effects of AI-based imitation, using the full population of Danish digital news articles published in 2022. Varying imitation strategies and AI prevalence across information environments with different baseline structures, we show that the effects of AI-driven imitation are strongly context-dependent: imitating AI agents increase semantic diversity in initially homogeneous environments but can reduce diversity in heterogeneous ones. This pattern is qualitatively consistent across multiple LLMs. However, this diversity arises primarily through stylistic differentiation and variance compression rather than factual enrichment, as AI-generated articles tend to omit information while remaining semantically distinct. These findings indicate that AI-driven imitation produces ambivalent transformations of information environments that may shape collective intelligence in democratic societies.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.16021v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Emil Bakkensen Johansen, Oliver Baumann</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lean Formalization of Generalization Error Bound by Rademacher Complexity and Dudley's Entropy Integral</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.19605</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.19605v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Understanding and certifying the generalization performance of machine learning algorithms -- i.e. obtaining theoretical estimates of the test error from a finite training sample -- is a central theme of statistical learning theory. Among the many complexity measures used to derive such guarantees, Rademacher complexity yields sharp, data-dependent bounds that apply well beyond classical $0$--$1$ classification. In this study, we formalize the generalization error bound by Rademacher complexity in Lean 4, building on measure-theoretic probability theory available in the Mathlib library. Our development provides a mechanically-checked pipeline from the definitions of empirical and expected Rademacher complexity, through a formal symmetrization argument and a bounded-differences analysis, to high-probability uniform deviation bounds via a formally proved McDiarmid inequality. A key technical contribution is a reusable mechanism for lifting results from countable hypothesis classes (where measurability of suprema is straightforward in Mathlib) to separable topological index sets via a reduction to a countable dense subset. As worked applications of the abstract theorem, we mechanize standard empirical Rademacher bounds for linear predictors under $\ell_2$ and $\ell_1$ regularization, and we also formalize a Dudley-type entropy integral bound based on covering numbers and a chaining construction.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.19605v4</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>math.ST</category>
      <category>stat.TH</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sho Sonoda, Kazumi Kasaura, Yuma Mizuno, Kei Tsukamoto, Naoto Onda</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming Sparsity Artifacts in Crosscoders to Interpret Chat-Tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.02922</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.02922v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Model diffing is the study of how fine-tuning changes a model's representations and internal algorithms. Many behaviors of interest are introduced during fine-tuning, and model diffing offers a promising lens to interpret such behaviors. Crosscoders are a recent model diffing method that learns a shared dictionary of interpretable concepts represented as latent directions in both the base and fine-tuned models, allowing us to track how concepts shift or emerge during fine-tuning. Notably, prior work has observed concepts with no direction in the base model, and it was hypothesized that these model-specific latents were concepts introduced during fine-tuning. However, we identify two issues which stem from the crosscoders L1 training loss that can misattribute concepts as unique to the fine-tuned model, when they really exist in both models. We develop Latent Scaling to flag these issues by more accurately measuring each latent's presence across models. In experiments comparing Gemma 2 2B base and chat models, we observe that the standard crosscoder suffers heavily from these issues. Building on these insights, we train a crosscoder with BatchTopK loss and show that it substantially mitigates these issues, finding more genuinely chat-specific and highly interpretable concepts. We recommend practitioners adopt similar techniques. Using the BatchTopK crosscoder, we successfully identify a set of chat-specific latents that are both interpretable and causally effective, representing concepts such as $\textit{false information}$ and $\textit{personal question}$, along with multiple refusal-related latents that show nuanced preferences for different refusal triggers. Overall, our work advances best practices for the crosscoder-based methodology for model diffing and demonstrates that it can provide concrete insights into how chat-tuning modifies model behavior.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.02922v4</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Julian Minder, Cl\'ement Dumas, Caden Juang, Bilal Chugtai, Neel Nanda</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A False Sense of Privacy: Evaluating Textual Data Sanitization Beyond Surface-level Privacy Leakage</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.21035</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.21035v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Sanitizing sensitive text data typically involves removing personally identifiable information (PII) or generating synthetic data under the assumption that these methods adequately protect privacy; however, their effectiveness is often only assessed by measuring the leakage of explicit identifiers but ignoring nuanced textual markers that can lead to re-identification. We challenge the above illusion of privacy by proposing a new framework that evaluates re-identification attacks to quantify individual privacy risks upon data release. Our approach shows that seemingly innocuous auxiliary information -- such as routine social activities -- can be used to infer sensitive attributes like age or substance use history from sanitized data. For instance, we demonstrate that Azure's commercial PII removal tool fails to protect 74\% of information in the MedQA dataset. Although differential privacy mitigates these risks to some extent, it significantly reduces the utility of the sanitized text for downstream tasks. Our findings indicate that current sanitization techniques offer a \textit{false sense of privacy}, highlighting the need for more robust methods that protect against semantic-level information leakage.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.21035v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rui Xin, Niloofar Mireshghallah, Shuyue Stella Li, Michael Duan, Hyunwoo Kim, Yejin Choi, Yulia Tsvetkov, Sewoong Oh, Pang Wei Koh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visual Planning: Let's Think Only with Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.11409</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.11409v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Recent advancements in Large Language Models (LLMs) and their multimodal extensions (MLLMs) have substantially enhanced machine reasoning across diverse tasks. However, these models predominantly rely on pure text as the medium for both expressing and structuring reasoning, even when visual information is present. In this work, we argue that language may not always be the most natural or effective modality for reasoning, particularly in tasks involving spatial and geometrical information. Motivated by this, we propose a new paradigm, Visual Planning, which enables planning through purely visual representations for these "vision-first" tasks, as a supplementary channel to language-based reasoning. In this paradigm, planning is executed via sequences of images that encode step-by-step inference in the visual domain, akin to how humans sketch or visualize future actions. We introduce a novel reinforcement learning framework, Visual Planning via Reinforcement Learning (VPRL), empowered by GRPO for post-training large vision models, leading to substantial improvements in planning in a selection of representative visual navigation tasks, FrozenLake, Maze, and MiniBehavior. Our visual planning paradigm outperforms all other planning variants that conduct reasoning in the text-only space. Our results establish Visual Planning as a viable and promising supplement to language-based reasoning, opening new avenues for tasks that benefit from intuitive, image-based inference.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.11409v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yi Xu, Chengzu Li, Han Zhou, Xingchen Wan, Caiqi Zhang, Anna Korhonen, Ivan Vuli\'c</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revela: Dense Retriever Learning via Language Modeling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.16552</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.16552v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Dense retrievers play a vital role in accessing external and specialized knowledge to augment language models (LMs). Training dense retrievers typically requires annotated query-document pairs, which are costly to create and scarce in specialized domains (e.g., code) or in complex settings (e.g., requiring reasoning). These practical challenges have sparked growing interest in self-supervised retriever learning. Since LMs are trained to capture token-level dependencies through a self-supervised learning objective (i.e., next token prediction), we can analogously cast retrieval as learning dependencies among chunks of tokens. This analogy naturally leads to the question: How can we adapt self-supervised learning objectives in the spirit of language modeling to train retrievers?
  To answer this question, we introduce Revela, a unified and scalable training framework for self-supervised retriever learning via language modeling. Revela models semantic dependencies among documents by conditioning next token prediction on local and cross-document context through an in-batch attention mechanism. This attention is weighted by retriever-computed similarity scores, enabling the retriever to be optimized as part of language modeling. We evaluate Revela on domain-specific (CoIR), reasoning-intensive (BRIGHT), and general-domain (BEIR) benchmarks across various retriever backbones. Without annotated or synthetic query-document pairs, Revela surpasses larger supervised models and proprietary APIs on both CoIR and BRIGHT. It achieves BEIR's unsupervised SoTA with ~1000x less training data and 10x less compute. Performance increases with batch size and model size, highlighting Revela's scalability and its promise for self-supervised retriever learning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.16552v3</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fengyu Cai, Tong Chen, Xinran Zhao, Sihao Chen, Hongming Zhang, Sherry Tongshuang Wu, Iryna Gurevych, Heinz Koeppl</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decomposing Representation Space into Interpretable Subspaces with Unsupervised Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.01916</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.01916v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Understanding internal representations of neural models is a core interest of mechanistic interpretability. Due to its large dimensionality, the representation space can encode various aspects about inputs. To what extent are different aspects organized and encoded in separate subspaces? Is it possible to find these ``natural'' subspaces in a purely unsupervised way? Somewhat surprisingly, we can indeed achieve this and find interpretable subspaces by a seemingly unrelated training objective. Our method, neighbor distance minimization (NDM), learns non-basis-aligned subspaces in an unsupervised manner. Qualitative analysis shows subspaces are interpretable in many cases, and encoded information in obtained subspaces tends to share the same abstract concept across different inputs, making such subspaces similar to ``variables'' used by the model. We also conduct quantitative experiments using known circuits in GPT-2; results show a strong connection between subspaces and circuit variables. We also provide evidence showing scalability to 2B models by finding separate subspaces mediating context and parametric knowledge routing. Viewed more broadly, our findings offer a new perspective on understanding model internals and building circuits.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.01916v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xinting Huang, Michael Hahn</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Classification errors distort findings in automated speech processing: examples and solutions from child-development research</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.15637</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.15637v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: With the advent of wearable recorders, scientists are increasingly turning to automated methods of analysis of audio and video data in order to measure children's experience, behavior, and outcomes, with a sizable literature employing long-form audio-recordings to study language acquisition. While numerous articles report on the accuracy and reliability of the most popular automated classifiers, less has been written on the downstream effects of classification errors on measurements and statistical inferences (e.g., the estimate of correlations and effect sizes in regressions). This paper's main contributions are drawing attention to downstream effects of confusion errors, and providing an approach to measure and potentially recover from these errors. Specifically, we use a Bayesian approach to study the effects of algorithmic errors on key scientific questions, including the effect of siblings on children's language experience and the association between children's production and their input. By fitting a joint model of speech behavior and algorithm behavior on real and simulated data, we show that classification errors can significantly distort estimates for both the most commonly used \gls{lena}, and a slightly more accurate open-source alternative (the Voice Type Classifier from the ACLEW system). We further show that a Bayesian calibration approach for recovering unbiased estimates of effect sizes can be effective and insightful, but does not provide a fool-proof solution.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.15637v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>stat.AP</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lucas Gautheron, Evan Kidd, Anton Malko, Marvin Lavechin, Alejandrina Cristia</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing and Evaluating Chain-of-Hints for Scientific Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.21087</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.21087v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: LLMs are reshaping education, with students increasingly relying on them for learning. Implemented using general-purpose models, these systems are likely to give away the answers, potentially undermining conceptual understanding and critical thinking. Prior work shows that hints can effectively promote cognitive engagement. Building on this insight, we evaluate 18 open-source LLMs on chain-of-hints generation that scaffold users toward the correct answer. We compare two distinct hinting strategies: static hints, pre-generated for each problem, and dynamic hints, adapted to a learners' progress. We evaluate these systems on five pedagogically grounded automatic metrics for hint quality. Using the best performing LLM as the backbone of a quantitative study with 41 participants, we uncover distinct user preferences across hinting strategies, and identify the limitations of automatic evaluation metrics to capture them. Our findings highlight key design considerations for future research on tutoring systems and contribute toward the development of more learner-centered educational technologies.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.21087v2</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Anubhav Jangra, Smaranda Muresan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Through the Judge's Eyes: Inferred Thinking Traces Improve Reliability of LLM Raters</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.25860</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.25860v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are increasingly used as raters for evaluation tasks. However, their reliability is often limited for subjective tasks, when human judgments involve subtle reasoning beyond annotation labels. Thinking traces, the reasoning behind a judgment, are highly informative but challenging to collect and curate. We present a human-LLM collaborative framework to infer thinking traces from label-only annotations. The proposed framework uses a simple and effective rejection sampling method to reconstruct these traces at scale. These inferred thinking traces are applied to two complementary tasks: (1) fine-tuning open LLM raters; and (2) synthesizing clearer annotation guidelines for proprietary LLM raters. Across multiple datasets, our methods lead to significantly improved LLM-human agreement. Additionally, the refined annotation guidelines increase agreement among different LLM models. These results suggest that LLMs can serve as practical proxies for otherwise unrevealed human thinking traces, enabling label-only corpora to be extended into thinking-trace-augmented resources that enhance the reliability of LLM raters.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.25860v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xingjian Zhang, Tianhong Gao, Suliang Jin, Tianhao Wang, Teng Ye, Eytan Adar, Qiaozhu Mei</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CDLM: Consistency Diffusion Language Models For Faster Sampling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.19269</link>
      <description>arXiv:2511.19269v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Diffusion Language Models (DLMs) offer a promising parallel generation paradigm but suffer from slow inference due to numerous refinement steps and the inability to use standard KV caching. We introduce CDLM (Consistency Diffusion Language Models), a training-based acceleration method that simultaneously tackles both bottlenecks. CDLM integrates consistency modeling to drastically reduce the number of required sampling steps by enabling multi-token finalization. Furthermore, we enforce a block-wise causal attention mask during fine-tuning, making the model fully compatible with KV caching. Experiments show CDLM achieves 3.6x-14.5x lower latency while maintaining competitive accuracy on math and coding tasks. The full training and evaluation code is available at https://github.com/SqueezeAILab/CDLM.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2511.19269v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Minseo Kim, Chenfeng Xu, Coleman Hooper, Harman Singh, Ben Athiwaratkun, Ce Zhang, Kurt Keutzer, Amir Gholami</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Group Representational Position Encoding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.07805</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.07805v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We present GRAPE (Group Representational Position Encoding), a unified framework for positional encoding based on group actions. GRAPE unifies two families of mechanisms: (i) multiplicative rotations (Multiplicative GRAPE) in $\operatorname{SO}(d)$ and (ii) additive logit biases (Additive GRAPE) arising from unipotent actions in the general linear group $\mathrm{GL}$. In Multiplicative GRAPE, a position $n \in \mathbb{Z}$ (or $t \in \mathbb{R}$) acts as $\mathbf{G}(n) = \exp(n \, \omega \, \mathbf{L})$ with a rank-2 skew-symmetric generator $\mathbf{L} \in \mathbb{R}^{d \times d}$, yielding a relative, compositional, norm-preserving map with a closed-form matrix exponential. RoPE is recovered exactly when the $d/2$ planes correspond to canonical coordinate pairs with a log-uniform spectrum. Learned commuting subspaces and compact non-commuting mixtures strictly extend this geometry to capture cross-subspace feature coupling at $O(d)$ and $O(r d)$ cost per head, respectively. In Additive GRAPE, additive logits arise from rank-1 (or low-rank) unipotent actions, recovering ALiBi and the Forgetting Transformer (FoX) as exact special cases while preserving an exact relative law and streaming cacheability. Overall, GRAPE provides a principled design space for positional geometry in long-context models, subsuming RoPE and ALiBi as special cases. Project page: https://github.com/model-architectures/GRAPE.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.07805v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yifan Zhang, Zixiang Chen, Yifeng Liu, Zhen Qin, Huizhuo Yuan, Kangping Xu, Yang Yuan, Quanquan Gu, Andrew Chi-Chih Yao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Invisible Hand of AI Libraries Shaping Open Source Projects and Communities</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.01944</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.01944v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In the early 1980s, Open Source Software emerged as a revolutionary concept amidst the dominance of proprietary software. What began as a revolutionary idea has now become the cornerstone of computer science. Amidst OSS projects, AI is increasing its presence and relevance. However, despite the growing popularity of AI, its adoption and impacts on OSS projects remain underexplored.
  We aim to assess the adoption of AI libraries in Python and Java OSS projects and examine how they shape development, including the technical ecosystem and community engagement. To this end, we will perform a large-scale analysis on 157.7k potential OSS repositories, employing repository metrics and software metrics to compare projects adopting AI libraries against those that do not. We expect to identify measurable differences in development activity, community engagement, and code complexity between OSS projects that adopt AI libraries and those that do not, offering evidence-based insights into how AI integration reshapes software development practices.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.01944v2</guid>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.PL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Matteo Esposito, Andrea Janes, Valentina Lenarduzzi, Davide Taibi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jailbreaking Leaves a Trace: Understanding and Detecting Jailbreak Attacks from Internal Representations of Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.11495</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.11495v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Jailbreaking large language models (LLMs) has emerged as a critical security challenge with the widespread deployment of conversational AI systems. Adversarial users exploit these models through carefully crafted prompts to elicit restricted or unsafe outputs, a phenomenon commonly referred to as Jailbreaking. Despite numerous proposed defense mechanisms, attackers continue to develop adaptive prompting strategies, and existing models remain vulnerable. This motivates approaches that examine the internal behavior of LLMs rather than relying solely on prompt-level defenses. In this work, we study jailbreaking from both security and interpretability perspectives by analyzing how internal representations differ between jailbreak and benign prompts. We conduct a systematic layer-wise analysis across multiple open-source models, including GPT-J, LLaMA, Mistral, and the state-space model Mamba, and identify consistent latent-space patterns associated with harmful inputs. We then propose a tensor-based latent representation framework that captures structure in hidden activations and enables lightweight jailbreak detection without model fine-tuning or auxiliary LLM-based detectors. We further demonstrate that the latent signals can be used to actively disrupt jailbreak execution at inference time. On an abliterated LLaMA-3.1-8B model, selectively bypassing high-susceptibility layers blocks 78% of jailbreak attempts while preserving benign behavior on 94% of benign prompts. This intervention operates entirely at inference time and introduces minimal overhead, providing a scalable foundation for achieving stronger coverage by incorporating additional attack distributions or more refined susceptibility thresholds. Our results provide evidence that jailbreak behavior is rooted in identifiable internal structures and suggest a complementary, architecture-agnostic direction for improving LLM security.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.11495v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sri Durga Sai Sowmya Kadali, Evangelos E. Papalexakis</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anatomy of Capability Emergence: Scale-Invariant Representation Collapse and Top-Down Reorganization in Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.15997</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.15997v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Capability emergence during neural network training remains mechanistically opaque. We track five geometric measures across five model scales (405K-85M parameters), 120+ emergence events in eight algorithmic tasks, and three Pythia language models (160M-2.8B). We find: (1) training begins with a universal representation collapse to task-specific floors that are scale-invariant across a 210X parameter range (e.g., modular arithmetic collapses to RANKME $\approx$ 2.0 regardless of model size); (2) collapse propagates top-down through layers (32/32 task X model consistency), contradicting bottom-up feature-building intuition; (3) a geometric hierarchy in which representation geometry leads emergence (75-100% precursor rate for hard tasks), while the local learning coefficient is synchronous (0/24 precursor) and Hessian measures lag. We also delineate prediction limits: geometric measures encode coarse task difficulty but not fine-grained timing (within-class concordance 27%; when task ordering reverses across scales, prediction fails at 26%). On Pythia, global geometric patterns replicate but per-task precursor signals do not -- the precursor relationship requires task-training alignment that naturalistic pre-training does not provide. Our contribution is the geometric anatomy of emergence and its boundary conditions, not a prediction tool.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.15997v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jayadev Billa</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RFEval: Benchmarking Reasoning Faithfulness under Counterfactual Reasoning Intervention in Large Reasoning Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.17053</link>
      <description>arXiv:2602.17053v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large Reasoning Models (LRMs) exhibit strong performance, yet often produce rationales that sound plausible but fail to reflect their true decision process, undermining reliability and trust. We introduce a formal framework for reasoning faithfulness, defined by two testable conditions: stance consistency (a coherent stance linking reasoning to answer) and causal influence (the stated reasoning causally drives the answer under output-level interventions), explicitly decoupled from accuracy. To operationalize this, we present RFEval, a benchmark of 7,186 instances across seven tasks that probes faithfulness via controlled, output-level counterfactual interventions. Evaluating twelve open-source LRMs, we find unfaithfulness in 49.7% of outputs, predominantly from stance inconsistency. Failures are concentrated in brittle, convergent domains such as math and code, and correlate more with post-training regimes than with scale: within-family ablations indicate that adding current RL-style objectives on top of supervised fine-tuning can reduce reasoning faithfulness, even when accuracy is maintained. Crucially, accuracy is neither a sufficient nor a reliable proxy for faithfulness: once controlling for model and task, the accuracy-faithfulness link is weak and statistically insignificant. Our work establishes a rigorous methodology for auditing LRM reliability and shows that trustworthy AI requires optimizing not only for correct outcomes but also for the structural integrity of the reasoning process. Our code and dataset can be found at project page: https://aidaslab.github.io/RFEval/}{https://aidaslab.github.io/RFEval/</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2602.17053v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yunseok Han, Yejoon Lee, Jaeyoung Do</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
