<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.CV updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CV</link>
    <description>cs.CV updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.CV" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 05:00:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Saturday</day>
      <day>Sunday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>HyperCLOVA X 32B Think</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03286</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03286v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In this report, we present HyperCLOVA X 32B Think, a vision-language model designed with particular emphasis on reasoning within the Korean linguistic and cultural context, as well as agentic ability. HyperCLOVA X 32B Think is pre-trained with a strong focus on reasoning capabilities and subsequently post-trained to support multimodal understanding, enhanced reasoning, agentic behaviors, and alignment with human preferences. Experimental evaluations against comparably sized models demonstrate that our model achieves strong performance on Korean text-to-text and vision-to-text benchmarks, as well as on agent-oriented evaluation tasks. By open-sourcing HyperCLOVA X 32B Think, we aim to support broader adoption and facilitate further research and innovation across both academic and industrial communities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03286v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator> NAVER Cloud HyperCLOVA X Team</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CageDroneRF: A Large-Scale RF Benchmark and Toolkit for Drone Perception</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03302</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03302v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present CageDroneRF (CDRF), a large-scale benchmark for Radio-Frequency (RF) drone detection and identification built from real-world captures and systematically generated synthetic variants. CDRF addresses the scarcity and limited diversity of existing RF datasets by coupling extensive raw recordings with a principled augmentation pipeline that (i) precisely controls Signal-to-Noise Ratio (SNR), (ii) injects interfering emitters, and (iii) applies frequency shifts with label-consistent bounding-box transformations for detection. This dataset spans a wide range of contemporary drone models, many unavailable in current public datasets, and acquisition conditions, derived from data collected at the Rowan University campus and within a controlled RF-cage facility. CDRF is released with interoperable open-source tools for data generation, preprocessing, augmentation, and evaluation that also operate on existing public benchmarks. CDRF enables standardized benchmarking for classification, open-set recognition, and object detection, supporting rigorous comparisons and reproducible pipelines. By releasing this comprehensive benchmark and tooling, CDRF aims to accelerate progress toward robust, generalizable RF perception models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03302v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mohammad Rostami, Atik Faysal, Hongtao Xia, Hadi Kasasbeh, Ziang Gao, Huaxia Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mass Concept Erasure in Diffusion Models with Concept Hierarchy</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03305</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03305v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The success of diffusion models has raised concerns about the generation of unsafe or harmful content, prompting concept erasure approaches that fine-tune modules to suppress specific concepts while preserving general generative capabilities. However, as the number of erased concepts grows, these methods often become inefficient and ineffective, since each concept requires a separate set of fine-tuned parameters and may degrade the overall generation quality. In this work, we propose a supertype-subtype concept hierarchy that organizes erased concepts into a parent-child structure. Each erased concept is treated as a child node, and semantically related concepts (e.g., macaw, and bald eagle) are grouped under a shared parent node, referred to as a supertype concept (e.g., bird). Rather than erasing concepts individually, we introduce an effective and efficient group-wise suppression method, where semantically similar concepts are grouped and erased jointly by sharing a single set of learnable parameters. During the erasure phase, standard diffusion regularization is applied to preserve denoising process in unmasked regions. To mitigate the degradation of supertype generation caused by excessive erasure of semantically related subtypes, we propose a novel method called Supertype-Preserving Low-Rank Adaptation (SuPLoRA), which encodes the supertype concept information in the frozen down-projection matrix and updates only the up-projection matrix during erasure. Theoretical analysis demonstrates the effectiveness of SuPLoRA in mitigating generation performance degradation. We construct a more challenging benchmark that requires simultaneous erasure of concepts across diverse domains, including celebrities, objects, and pornographic content.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03305v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiahang Tu, Ye Li, Yiming Wu, Hanbin Zhao, Chao Zhang, Hui Qian</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VLM4VLA: Revisiting Vision-Language-Models in Vision-Language-Action Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03309</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03309v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Vision-Language-Action (VLA) models, which integrate pretrained large Vision-Language Models (VLM) into their policy backbone, are gaining significant attention for their promising generalization capabilities. This paper revisits a fundamental yet seldom systematically studied question: how VLM choice and competence translate to downstream VLA policies performance? We introduce VLM4VLA, a minimal adaptation pipeline that converts general-purpose VLMs into VLA policies using only a small set of new learnable parameters for fair and efficient comparison. Despite its simplicity, VLM4VLA proves surprisingly competitive with more sophisticated network designs. Through extensive empirical studies on various downstream tasks across three benchmarks, we find that while VLM initialization offers a consistent benefit over training from scratch, a VLM's general capabilities are poor predictors of its downstream task performance. This challenges common assumptions, indicating that standard VLM competence is necessary but insufficient for effective embodied control. We further investigate the impact of specific embodied capabilities by fine-tuning VLMs on seven auxiliary embodied tasks (e.g., embodied QA, visual pointing, depth estimation). Contrary to intuition, improving a VLM's performance on specific embodied skills does not guarantee better downstream control performance. Finally, modality-level ablations identify the visual module in VLM, rather than the language component, as the primary performance bottleneck. We demonstrate that injecting control-relevant supervision into the vision encoder of the VLM yields consistent gains, even when the encoder remains frozen during downstream fine-tuning. This isolates a persistent domain gap between current VLM pretraining objectives and the requirements of embodied action-planning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03309v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jianke Zhang, Xiaoyu Chen, Qiuyue Wang, Mingsheng Li, Yanjiang Guo, Yucheng Hu, Jiajun Zhang, Shuai Bai, Junyang Lin, Jianyu Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning-Based Image Recognition for Soft-Shell Shrimp Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03317</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03317v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: With the integration of information technology into aquaculture, production has become more stable and continues to grow annually. As consumer demand for high-quality aquatic products rises, freshness and appearance integrity are key concerns. In shrimp-based processed foods, freshness declines rapidly post-harvest, and soft-shell shrimp often suffer from head-body separation after cooking or freezing, affecting product appearance and consumer perception. To address these issues, this study leverages deep learning-based image recognition for automated classification of white shrimp immediately after harvest. A convolutional neural network (CNN) model replaces manual sorting, enhancing classification accuracy, efficiency, and consistency. By reducing processing time, this technology helps maintain freshness and ensures that shrimp transportation businesses meet customer demands more effectively.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03317v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1007/978-3-031-95901-1_5</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Yun-Hao Zhang, I-Hsien Ting, Dario Liberona, Yun-Hsiu Liu, Kazunori Minetaki</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Higher order PCA-like rotation-invariant features for detailed shape descriptors modulo rotation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03326</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03326v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: PCA can be used for rotation invariant features, describing a shape with its $p_{ab}=E[(x_i-E[x_a])(x_b-E[x_b])]$ covariance matrix approximating shape by ellipsoid, allowing for rotation invariants like its traces of powers. However, real shapes are usually much more complicated, hence there is proposed its extension to e.g. $p_{abc}=E[(x_a-E[x_a])(x_b-E[x_b])(x_c-E[x_c])]$ order-3 or higher tensors describing central moments, or polynomial times Gaussian allowing decodable shape descriptors of arbitrarily high accuracy, and their analogous rotation invariants. Its practical applications could be rotation-invariant features to include shape modulo rotation e.g. for molecular shape descriptors, or for up to rotation object recognition in 2D images/3D scans, or shape similarity metric allowing their inexpensive comparison (modulo rotation) without costly optimization over rotations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03326v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jarek Duda</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MMErroR: A Benchmark for Erroneous Reasoning in Vision-Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03331</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03331v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent advances in Vision-Language Models (VLMs) have improved performance in multi-modal learning, raising the question of whether these models truly understand the content they process. Crucially, can VLMs detect when a reasoning process is wrong and identify its error type? To answer this, we present MMErroR, a multi-modal benchmark of 2,013 samples, each embedding a single coherent reasoning error. These samples span 24 subdomains across six top-level domains, ensuring broad coverage and taxonomic richness. Unlike existing benchmarks that focus on answer correctness, MMErroR targets a process-level, error-centric evaluation that requires models to detect incorrect reasoning and classify the error type within both visual and linguistic contexts. We evaluate 20 advanced VLMs, even the best model (Gemini-3.0-Pro) classifies the error in only 66.47\% of cases, underscoring the challenge of identifying erroneous reasoning. Furthermore, the ability to accurately identify errors offers valuable insights into the capabilities of multi-modal reasoning models. Project Page: https://mmerror-benchmark.github.io</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03331v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yang Shi, Yifeng Xie, Minzhe Guo, Liangsi Lu, Mingxuan Huang, Jingchao Wang, Zhihong Zhu, Boyan Xu, Zhiqi Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RelightAnyone: A Generalized Relightable 3D Gaussian Head Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03357</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03357v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: 3D Gaussian Splatting (3DGS) has become a standard approach to reconstruct and render photorealistic 3D head avatars. A major challenge is to relight the avatars to match any scene illumination. For high quality relighting, existing methods require subjects to be captured under complex time-multiplexed illumination, such as one-light-at-a-time (OLAT). We propose a new generalized relightable 3D Gaussian head model that can relight any subject observed in a single- or multi-view images without requiring OLAT data for that subject. Our core idea is to learn a mapping from flat-lit 3DGS avatars to corresponding relightable Gaussian parameters for that avatar. Our model consists of two stages: a first stage that models flat-lit 3DGS avatars without OLAT lighting, and a second stage that learns the mapping to physically-based reflectance parameters for high-quality relighting. This two-stage design allows us to train the first stage across diverse existing multi-view datasets without OLAT lighting ensuring cross-subject generalization, where we learn a dataset-specific lighting code for self-supervised lighting alignment. Subsequently, the second stage can be trained on a significantly smaller dataset of subjects captured under OLAT illumination. Together, this allows our method to generalize well and relight any subject from the first stage as if we had captured them under OLAT lighting. Furthermore, we can fit our model to unseen subjects from as little as a single image, allowing several applications in novel view synthesis and relighting for digital avatars.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03357v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yingyan Xu, Pramod Rao, Sebastian Weiss, Gaspard Zoss, Markus Gross, Christian Theobalt, Marc Habermann, Derek Bradley</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guardians of the Hair: Rescuing Soft Boundaries in Depth, Stereo, and Novel Views</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03362</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03362v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Soft boundaries, like thin hairs, are commonly observed in natural and computer-generated imagery, but they remain challenging for 3D vision due to the ambiguous mixing of foreground and background cues. This paper introduces Guardians of the Hair (HairGuard), a framework designed to recover fine-grained soft boundary details in 3D vision tasks. Specifically, we first propose a novel data curation pipeline that leverages image matting datasets for training and design a depth fixer network to automatically identify soft boundary regions. With a gated residual module, the depth fixer refines depth precisely around soft boundaries while maintaining global depth quality, allowing plug-and-play integration with state-of-the-art depth models. For view synthesis, we perform depth-based forward warping to retain high-fidelity textures, followed by a generative scene painter that fills disoccluded regions and eliminates redundant background artifacts within soft boundaries. Finally, a color fuser adaptively combines warped and inpainted results to produce novel views with consistent geometry and fine-grained details. Extensive experiments demonstrate that HairGuard achieves state-of-the-art performance across monocular depth estimation, stereo image/video conversion, and novel view synthesis, with significant improvements in soft boundary regions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03362v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiang Zhang, Yang Zhang, Lukas Mehl, Markus Gross, Christopher Schroers</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RiskCueBench: Benchmarking Anticipatory Reasoning from Early Risk Cues in Video-Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03369</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03369v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: With the rapid growth of video centered social media, the ability to anticipate risky events from visual data is a promising direction for ensuring public safety and preventing real world accidents. Prior work has extensively studied supervised video risk assessment across domains such as driving, protests, and natural disasters. However, many existing datasets provide models with access to the full video sequence, including the accident itself, which substantially reduces the difficulty of the task. To better reflect real world conditions, we introduce a new video understanding benchmark RiskCueBench in which videos are carefully annotated to identify a risk signal clip, defined as the earliest moment that indicates a potential safety concern. Experimental results reveal a significant gap in current systems ability to interpret evolving situations and anticipate future risky events from early visual signals, highlighting important challenges for deploying video risk prediction models in practice.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03369v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sha Luo, Yogesh Prabhu, Tim Ossowski, Kaiping Chen, Junjie Hu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Novel Unified Approach to Deepfake Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03382</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03382v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The advancements in the field of AI is increasingly giving rise to various threats. One of the most prominent of them is the synthesis and misuse of Deepfakes. To sustain trust in this digital age, detection and tagging of deepfakes is very necessary. In this paper, a novel architecture for Deepfake detection in images and videos is presented. The architecture uses cross attention between spatial and frequency domain features along with a blood detection module to classify an image as real or fake. This paper aims to develop a unified architecture and provide insights into each step. Though this approach we achieve results better than SOTA, specifically 99.80%, 99.88% AUC on FF++ and Celeb-DF upon using Swin Transformer and BERT and 99.55, 99.38 while using EfficientNet-B4 and BERT. The approach also generalizes very well achieving great cross dataset results as well.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03382v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lord Sen, Shyamapada Mukherjee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Better, But Not Sufficient: Testing Video ANNs Against Macaque IT Dynamics</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03392</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03392v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Feedforward artificial neural networks (ANNs) trained on static images remain the dominant models of the the primate ventral visual stream, yet they are intrinsically limited to static computations. The primate world is dynamic, and the macaque ventral visual pathways, specifically the inferior temporal (IT) cortex not only supports object recognition but also encodes object motion velocity during naturalistic video viewing. Does IT's temporal responses reflect nothing more than time-unfolded feedforward transformations, framewise features with shallow temporal pooling, or do they embody richer dynamic computations? We tested this by comparing macaque IT responses during naturalistic videos against static, recurrent, and video-based ANN models. Video models provided modest improvements in neural predictivity, particularly at later response stages, raising the question of what kind of dynamics they capture. To probe this, we applied a stress test: decoders trained on naturalistic videos were evaluated on "appearance-free" variants that preserve motion but remove shape and texture. IT population activity generalized across this manipulation, but all ANN classes failed. Thus, current video models better capture appearance-bound dynamics rather than the appearance-invariant temporal computations expressed in IT, underscoring the need for new objectives that encode biological temporal statistics and invariances.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03392v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.NE</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Matteo Dunnhofer, Christian Micheloni, Kohitij Kar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eye-Q: A Multilingual Benchmark for Visual Word Puzzle Solving and Image-to-Phrase Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03400</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03400v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Vision-Language Models (VLMs) have achieved strong performance on standard vision-language benchmarks, yet often rely on surface-level recognition rather than deeper reasoning. We propose visual word puzzles as a challenging alternative, as they require discovering implicit visual cues, generating and revising hypotheses, and mapping perceptual evidence to non-literal concepts in ways that are difficult to solve via literal grounding, OCR-heavy shortcuts, or simple retrieval-style matching. We introduce Eye-Q, a multilingual benchmark designed to assess this form of complex visual understanding. Eye-Q contains 1,343 puzzles in which a model observes a conceptually dense scene with a brief description and must infer a specific target word or phrase. The puzzles are intentionally unstructured and cue-implicit, with distractors and contextual relationships that demand selective attention, abstraction, and associative inference. The benchmark spans English, Persian, Arabic, and cross-lingual puzzles. We evaluate state-of-the-art VLMs using an open-ended, human-aligned protocol that probes hypothesis formation and revision under lightweight assistance. Results reveal substantial performance gaps, especially on abstract and cross-lingual puzzles, highlighting limitations in current models' ability to construct and search over appropriate conceptual representations for flexible image-to-phrase inference; maximum accuracy reaches only 60.27%.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03400v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ali Najar, Alireza Mirrokni, Arshia Izadyari, Sadegh Mohammadian, Amir Homayoon Sharifizade, Asal Meskin, Mobin Bagherian, Ehsaneddin Asgari</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GAMBIT: A Gamified Jailbreak Framework for Multimodal Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03416</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03416v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) have become widely deployed, yet their safety alignment remains fragile under adversarial inputs. Previous work has shown that increasing inference steps can disrupt safety mechanisms and lead MLLMs to generate attacker-desired harmful content. However, most existing attacks focus on increasing the complexity of the modified visual task itself and do not explicitly leverage the model's own reasoning incentives. This leads to them underperforming on reasoning models (Models with Chain-of-Thoughts) compared to non-reasoning ones (Models without Chain-of-Thoughts). If a model can think like a human, can we influence its cognitive-stage decisions so that it proactively completes a jailbreak? To validate this idea, we propose GAMBI} (Gamified Adversarial Multimodal Breakout via Instructional Traps), a novel multimodal jailbreak framework that decomposes and reassembles harmful visual semantics, then constructs a gamified scene that drives the model to explore, reconstruct intent, and answer as part of winning the game. The resulting structured reasoning chain increases task complexity in both vision and text, positioning the model as a participant whose goal pursuit reduces safety attention and induces it to answer the reconstructed malicious query. Extensive experiments on popular reasoning and non-reasoning MLLMs demonstrate that GAMBIT achieves high Attack Success Rates (ASR), reaching 92.13% on Gemini 2.5 Flash, 91.20% on QvQ-MAX, and 85.87% on GPT-4o, significantly outperforming baselines.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03416v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiangdong Hu, Yangyang Jiang, Qin Hu, Xiaojun Jia</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WeedRepFormer: Reparameterizable Vision Transformers for Real-Time Waterhemp Segmentation and Gender Classification</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03431</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03431v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present WeedRepFormer, a lightweight multi-task Vision Transformer designed for simultaneous waterhemp segmentation and gender classification. Existing agricultural models often struggle to balance the fine-grained feature extraction required for biological attribute classification with the efficiency needed for real-time deployment. To address this, WeedRepFormer systematically integrates structural reparameterization across the entire architecture - comprising a Vision Transformer backbone, a Lite R-ASPP decoder, and a novel reparameterizable classification head - to decouple training-time capacity from inference-time latency. We also introduce a comprehensive waterhemp dataset containing 10,264 annotated frames from 23 plants. On this benchmark, WeedRepFormer achieves 92.18% mIoU for segmentation and 81.91% accuracy for gender classification using only 3.59M parameters and 3.80 GFLOPs. At 108.95 FPS, our model outperforms the state-of-the-art iFormer-T by 4.40% in classification accuracy while maintaining competitive segmentation performance and significantly reducing parameter count by 1.9x.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03431v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Toqi Tahamid Sarker, Taminul Islam, Khaled R. Ahmed, Cristiana Bernardi Rankrape, Kaitlin E. Creager, Karla Gage</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FROST-Drive: Scalable and Efficient End-to-End Driving with a Frozen Vision Encoder</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03460</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03460v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: End-to-end (E2E) models in autonomous driving aim to directly map sensor inputs to control commands, but their ability to generalize to novel and complex scenarios remains a key challenge. The common practice of fully fine-tuning the vision encoder on driving datasets potentially limits its generalization by causing the model to specialize too heavily in the training data. This work challenges the necessity of this training paradigm. We propose FROST-Drive, a novel E2E architecture designed to preserve and leverage the powerful generalization capabilities of a pretrained vision encoder from a Vision-Language Model (VLM). By keeping the encoder's weights frozen, our approach directly transfers the rich, generalized world knowledge from the VLM to the driving task. Our model architecture combines this frozen encoder with a transformer-based adapter for multimodal fusion and a GRU-based decoder for smooth waypoint generation. Furthermore, we introduce a custom loss function designed to directly optimize for Rater Feedback Score (RFS), a metric that prioritizes robust trajectory planning. We conduct extensive experiments on Waymo Open E2E Dataset, a large-scale datasets deliberately curated to capture the long-tail scenarios, demonstrating that our frozen-encoder approach significantly outperforms models that employ full fine-tuning. Our results provide substantial evidence that preserving the broad knowledge of a capable VLM is a more effective strategy for achieving robust, generalizable driving performance than intensive domain-specific adaptation. This offers a new pathway for developing vision-based models that can better handle the complexities of real-world application domains.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03460v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zeyu Dong, Yimin Zhu, Yu Wu, Yu Sun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental Comparison of Light-Weight and Deep CNN Models Across Diverse Datasets</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03463</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03463v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Our results reveal that a well-regularized shallow architecture can serve as a highly competitive baseline across heterogeneous domains - from smart-city surveillance to agricultural variety classification - without requiring large GPUs or specialized pre-trained models. This work establishes a unified, reproducible benchmark for multiple Bangladeshi vision datasets and highlights the practical value of lightweight CNNs for real-world deployment in low-resource settings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03463v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Md. Hefzul Hossain Papon, Shadman Rabby</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Latent Geometry of Taste: Scalable Low-Rank Matrix Factorization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03466</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03466v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Scalability and data sparsity remain critical bottlenecks for collaborative filtering on massive interaction datasets. This work investigates the latent geometry of user preferences using the MovieLens 32M dataset, implementing a high-performance, parallelized Alternating Least Squares (ALS) framework. Through extensive hyperparameter optimization, we demonstrate that constrained low-rank models significantly outperform higher dimensional counterparts in generalization, achieving an optimal balance between Root Mean Square Error (RMSE) and ranking precision. We visualize the learned embedding space to reveal the unsupervised emergence of semantic genre clusters, confirming that the model captures deep structural relationships solely from interaction data. Finally, we validate the system's practical utility in a cold-start scenario, introducing a tunable scoring parameter to manage the trade-off between popularity bias and personalized affinity effectively. The codebase for this research can be found here: https://github.com/joshsalako/recommender.git</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03466v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Joshua Salako</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ThinkRL-Edit: Thinking in Reinforcement Learning for Reasoning-Centric Image Editing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03467</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03467v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Instruction-driven image editing with unified multimodal generative models has advanced rapidly, yet their underlying visual reasoning remains limited, leading to suboptimal performance on reasoning-centric edits. Reinforcement learning (RL) has been investigated for improving the quality of image editing, but it faces three key challenges: (1) limited reasoning exploration confined to denoising stochasticity, (2) biased reward fusion, and (3) unstable VLM-based instruction rewards. In this work, we propose ThinkRL-Edit, a reasoning-centric RL framework that decouples visual reasoning from image synthesis and expands reasoning exploration beyond denoising. To the end, we introduce Chain-of-Thought (CoT)-based reasoning sampling with planning and reflection stages prior to generation in online sampling, compelling the model to explore multiple semantic hypotheses and validate their plausibility before committing to a visual outcome. To avoid the failures of weighted aggregation, we propose an unbiased chain preference grouping strategy across multiple reward dimensions. Moreover, we replace interval-based VLM scores with a binary checklist, yielding more precise, lower-variance, and interpretable rewards for complex reasoning. Experiments show our method significantly outperforms prior work on reasoning-centric image editing, producing instruction-faithful, visually coherent, and semantically grounded edits.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03467v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hengjia Li, Liming Jiang, Qing Yan, Yizhi Song, Hao Kang, Zichuan Liu, Xin Lu, Boxi Wu, Deng Cai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Reward Hacking in Text-to-Image Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03468</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03468v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Reinforcement learning (RL) has become a standard approach for post-training large language models and, more recently, for improving image generation models, which uses reward functions to enhance generation quality and human preference alignment. However, existing reward designs are often imperfect proxies for true human judgment, making models prone to reward hacking--producing unrealistic or low-quality images that nevertheless achieve high reward scores. In this work, we systematically analyze reward hacking behaviors in text-to-image (T2I) RL post-training. We investigate how both aesthetic/human preference rewards and prompt-image consistency rewards individually contribute to reward hacking and further show that ensembling multiple rewards can only partially mitigate this issue. Across diverse reward models, we identify a common failure mode: the generation of artifact-prone images. To address this, we propose a lightweight and adaptive artifact reward model, trained on a small curated dataset of artifact-free and artifact-containing samples. This model can be integrated into existing RL pipelines as an effective regularizer for commonly used reward models. Experiments demonstrate that incorporating our artifact reward significantly improves visual realism and reduces reward hacking across multiple T2I RL setups, demonstrating the effectiveness of lightweight reward augment serving as a safeguard against reward hacking.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03468v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yunqi Hong, Kuei-Chun Kao, Hengguang Zhou, Cho-Jui Hsieh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CroBIM-U: Uncertainty-Driven Referring Remote Sensing Image Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03490</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03490v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Referring remote sensing image segmentation aims to localize specific targets described by natural language within complex overhead imagery. However, due to extreme scale variations, dense similar distractors, and intricate boundary structures, the reliability of cross-modal alignment exhibits significant \textbf{spatial non-uniformity}. Existing methods typically employ uniform fusion and refinement strategies across the entire image, which often introduces unnecessary linguistic perturbations in visually clear regions while failing to provide sufficient disambiguation in confused areas. To address this, we propose an \textbf{uncertainty-guided framework} that explicitly leverages a pixel-wise \textbf{referring uncertainty map} as a spatial prior to orchestrate adaptive inference. Specifically, we introduce a plug-and-play \textbf{Referring Uncertainty Scorer (RUS)}, which is trained via an online error-consistency supervision strategy to interpretably predict the spatial distribution of referential ambiguity. Building on this prior, we design two plug-and-play modules: 1) \textbf{Uncertainty-Gated Fusion (UGF)}, which dynamically modulates language injection strength to enhance constraints in high-uncertainty regions while suppressing noise in low-uncertainty ones; and 2) \textbf{Uncertainty-Driven Local Refinement (UDLR)}, which utilizes uncertainty-derived soft masks to focus refinement on error-prone boundaries and fine details. Extensive experiments demonstrate that our method functions as a unified, plug-and-play solution that significantly improves robustness and geometric fidelity in complex remote sensing scenes without altering the backbone architecture.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03490v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuzhe Sun, Zhe Dong, Haochen Jiang, Tianzhu Liu, Yanfeng Gu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SDCD: Structure-Disrupted Contrastive Decoding for Mitigating Hallucinations in Large Vision-Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03500</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03500v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Vision-Language Models (LVLMs) demonstrate significant progress in multimodal understanding and reasoning, yet object hallucination remains a critical challenge. While existing research focuses on mitigating language priors or high-level statistical biases, they often overlook the internal complexities of the visual encoding process. We identify that visual statistical bias, arising from the inherent Bag-of-Patches behavior of Vision Encoders under weak structural supervision, acts as a contributing factor of object hallucinations. Under this bias, models prioritize local texture features within individual patches over holistic geometric structures. This tendency may induce spurious visual confidence and result in hallucinations. To address this, we introduce a training-free algorithm called Structure-Disrupted Contrastive Decoding (SDCD), which performs contrastive calibration of the output distribution by introducing a shuffled structure-disrupted view. By penalizing tokens that maintain high confidence under this structure-less view, SDCD effectively suppresses the texture-driven bias. Experimental results demonstrate that SDCD significantly mitigates hallucinations across multiple benchmarks and enhances the overall multimodal capabilities of LVLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03500v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuxuan Xia, Siheng Wang, Peng Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>REFA: Real-time Egocentric Facial Animations for Virtual Reality</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03507</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03507v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present a novel system for real-time tracking of facial expressions using egocentric views captured from a set of infrared cameras embedded in a virtual reality (VR) headset. Our technology facilitates any user to accurately drive the facial expressions of virtual characters in a non-intrusive manner and without the need of a lengthy calibration step. At the core of our system is a distillation based approach to train a machine learning model on heterogeneous data and labels coming form multiple sources, \eg synthetic and real images. As part of our dataset, we collected 18k diverse subjects using a lightweight capture setup consisting of a mobile phone and a custom VR headset with extra cameras. To process this data, we developed a robust differentiable rendering pipeline enabling us to automatically extract facial expression labels. Our system opens up new avenues for communication and expression in virtual environments, with applications in video conferencing, gaming, entertainment, and remote collaboration.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03507v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qiang Zhang, Tong Xiao, Haroun Habeeb, Larissa Laich, Sofien Bouaziz, Patrick Snape, Wenjing Zhang, Matthew Cioffi, Peizhao Zhang, Pavel Pidlypenskyi, Winnie Lin, Luming Ma, Mengjiao Wang, Kunpeng Li, Chengjiang Long, Steven Song, Martin Prazak, Alexander Sjoholm, Ajinkya Deogade, Jaebong Lee, Julio Delgado Mangas, Amaury Aubel</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>G2P: Gaussian-to-Point Attribute Alignment for Boundary-Aware 3D Semantic Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03510</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03510v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Semantic segmentation on point clouds is critical for 3D scene understanding. However, sparse and irregular point distributions provide limited appearance evidence, making geometry-only features insufficient to distinguish objects with similar shapes but distinct appearances (e.g., color, texture, material). We propose Gaussian-to-Point (G2P), which transfers appearance-aware attributes from 3D Gaussian Splatting to point clouds for more discriminative and appearance-consistent segmentation. Our G2P address the misalignment between optimized Gaussians and original point geometry by establishing point-wise correspondences. By leveraging Gaussian opacity attributes, we resolve the geometric ambiguity that limits existing models. Additionally, Gaussian scale attributes enable precise boundary localization in complex 3D scenes. Extensive experiments demonstrate that our approach achieves superior performance on standard benchmarks and shows significant improvements on geometrically challenging classes, all without any 2D or language supervision.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03510v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hojun Song, Chae-yeong Song, Jeong-hun Hong, Chaewon Moon, Dong-hwi Kim, Gahyeon Kim, Soo Ye Kim, Yiyi Liao, Jaehyup Lee, Sang-hyo Park</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Belief-State World Model for 3D Human Motion Prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03517</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03517v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Human motion prediction has traditionally been framed as a sequence regression problem where models extrapolate future joint coordinates from observed pose histories. While effective over short horizons this approach does not separate observation reconstruction with dynamics modeling and offers no explicit representation of the latent causes governing motion. As a result, existing methods exhibit compounding drift, mean-pose collapse, and poorly calibrated uncertainty when rolled forward beyond the training regime. Here we propose a Semantic Belief-State World Model (SBWM) that reframes human motion prediction as latent dynamical simulation on the human body manifold. Rather than predicting poses directly, SBWM maintains a recurrent probabilistic belief state whose evolution is learned independently of pose reconstruction and explicitly aligned with the SMPL-X anatomical parameterization. This alignment imposes a structural information bottleneck that prevents the latent state from encoding static geometry or sensor noise, forcing it to capture motion dynamics, intent, and control-relevant structure. Inspired by belief-state world models developed for model-based reinforcement learning, SBWM adapts stochastic latent transitions and rollout-centric training to the domain of human motion. In contrast to RSSM-based, transformer, and diffusion approaches optimized for reconstruction fidelity, SBWM prioritizes stable forward simulation. We demonstrate coherent long-horizon rollouts, and competitive accuracy at substantially lower computational cost. These results suggest that treating the human body as part of the world models state space rather than its output fundamentally changes how motion is simulated, and predicted.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03517v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sarim Chaudhry</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Physics-Constrained Cross-Resolution Enhancement Network for Optics-Guided Thermal UAV Image Super-Resolution</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03526</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03526v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Optics-guided thermal UAV image super-resolution has attracted significant research interest due to its potential in all-weather monitoring applications. However, existing methods typically compress optical features to match thermal feature dimensions for cross-modal alignment and fusion, which not only causes the loss of high-frequency information that is beneficial for thermal super-resolution, but also introduces physically inconsistent artifacts such as texture distortions and edge blurring by overlooking differences in the imaging physics between modalities. To address these challenges, we propose PCNet to achieve cross-resolution mutual enhancement between optical and thermal modalities, while physically constraining the optical guidance process via thermal conduction to enable robust thermal UAV image super-resolution. In particular, we design a Cross-Resolution Mutual Enhancement Module (CRME) to jointly optimize thermal image super-resolution and optical-to-thermal modality conversion, facilitating effective bidirectional feature interaction across resolutions while preserving high-frequency optical priors. Moreover, we propose a Physics-Driven Thermal Conduction Module (PDTM) that incorporates two-dimensional heat conduction into optical guidance, modeling spatially-varying heat conduction properties to prevent inconsistent artifacts. In addition, we introduce a temperature consistency loss that enforces regional distribution consistency and boundary gradient smoothness to ensure generated thermal images align with real-world thermal radiation principles. Extensive experiments on VGTSR2.0 and DroneVehicle datasets demonstrate that PCNet significantly outperforms state-of-the-art methods on both reconstruction quality and downstream tasks including semantic segmentation and object detection.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03526v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhicheng Zhao, Fengjiao Peng, Jinquan Yan, Wei Lu, Chenglong Li, Jin Tang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CloudMatch: Weak-to-Strong Consistency Learning for Semi-Supervised Cloud Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03528</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03528v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Due to the high cost of annotating accurate pixel-level labels, semi-supervised learning has emerged as a promising approach for cloud detection. In this paper, we propose CloudMatch, a semi-supervised framework that effectively leverages unlabeled remote sensing imagery through view-consistency learning combined with scene-mixing augmentations. An observation behind CloudMatch is that cloud patterns exhibit structural diversity and contextual variability across different scenes and within the same scene category. Our key insight is that enforcing prediction consistency across diversely augmented views, incorporating both inter-scene and intra-scene mixing, enables the model to capture the structural diversity and contextual richness of cloud patterns. Specifically, CloudMatch generates one weakly augmented view along with two complementary strongly augmented views for each unlabeled image: one integrates inter-scene patches to simulate contextual variety, while the other employs intra-scene mixing to preserve semantic coherence. This approach guides pseudolabel generation and enhances generalization. Extensive experiments show that CloudMatch achieves good performance, demonstrating its capability to utilize unlabeled data efficiently and advance semi-supervised cloud detection.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03528v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiayi Zhao, Changlu Chen, Jingsheng Li, Tianxiang Xue, Kun Zhan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EASLT: Emotion-Aware Sign Language Translation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03549</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03549v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Sign Language Translation (SLT) is a complex cross-modal task requiring the integration of Manual Signals (MS) and Non-Manual Signals (NMS). While recent gloss-free SLT methods have made strides in translating manual gestures, they frequently overlook the semantic criticality of facial expressions, resulting in ambiguity when distinct concepts share identical manual articulations. To address this, we present **EASLT** (**E**motion-**A**ware **S**ign **L**anguage **T**ranslation), a framework that treats facial affect not as auxiliary information, but as a robust semantic anchor. Unlike methods that relegate facial expressions to a secondary role, EASLT incorporates a dedicated emotional encoder to capture continuous affective dynamics. These representations are integrated via a novel *Emotion-Aware Fusion* (EAF) module, which adaptively recalibrates spatio-temporal sign features based on affective context to resolve semantic ambiguities. Extensive evaluations on the PHOENIX14T and CSL-Daily benchmarks demonstrate that EASLT establishes advanced performance among gloss-free methods, achieving BLEU-4 scores of 26.15 and 22.80, and BLEURT scores of 61.0 and 57.8, respectively. Ablation studies confirm that explicitly modeling emotion effectively decouples affective semantics from manual dynamics, significantly enhancing translation fidelity. Code is available at https://github.com/TuGuobin/EASLT.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03549v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Guobin Tu, Di Weng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SpatiaLoc: Leveraging Multi-Level Spatial Enhanced Descriptors for Cross-Modal Localization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03579</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03579v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Cross-modal localization using text and point clouds enables robots to localize themselves via natural language descriptions, with applications in autonomous navigation and interaction between humans and robots. In this task, objects often recur across text and point clouds, making spatial relationships the most discriminative cues for localization. Given this characteristic, we present SpatiaLoc, a framework utilizing a coarse-to-fine strategy that emphasizes spatial relationships at both the instance and global levels. In the coarse stage, we introduce a Bezier Enhanced Object Spatial Encoder (BEOSE) that models spatial relationships at the instance level using quadratic Bezier curves. Additionally, a Frequency Aware Encoder (FAE) generates spatial representations in the frequency domain at the global level. In the fine stage, an Uncertainty Aware Gaussian Fine Localizer (UGFL) regresses 2D positions by modeling predictions as Gaussian distributions with a loss function aware of uncertainty. Extensive experiments on KITTI360Pose demonstrate that SpatiaLoc significantly outperforms existing state-of-the-art (SOTA) methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03579v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tianyi Shang, Pengjie Xu, Zhaojun Deng, Zhenyu Li, Zhicong Chen, Lijun Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Detecting AI-Generated Images via Distributional Deviations from Real Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03586</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03586v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The rapid advancement of generative models has significantly enhanced the quality of AI-generated images, raising concerns about misinformation and the erosion of public trust. Detecting AI-generated images has thus become a critical challenge, particularly in terms of generalizing to unseen generative models. Existing methods using frozen pre-trained CLIP models show promise in generalization but treat the image encoder as a basic feature extractor, failing to fully exploit its potential. In this paper, we perform an in-depth analysis of the frozen CLIP image encoder (CLIP-ViT), revealing that it effectively clusters real images in a high-level, abstract feature space. However, it does not truly possess the ability to distinguish between real and AI-generated images. Based on this analysis, we propose a Masking-based Pre-trained model Fine-Tuning (MPFT) strategy, which introduces a Texture-Aware Masking (TAM) mechanism to mask textured areas containing generative model-specific patterns during fine-tuning. This approach compels CLIP-ViT to attend to the "distributional deviations"from authentic images for AI-generated image detection, thereby achieving enhanced generalization performance. Extensive experiments on the GenImage and UniversalFakeDetect datasets demonstrate that our method, fine-tuned with only a minimal number of images, significantly outperforms existing approaches, achieving up to 98.2% and 94.6% average accuracy on the two datasets, respectively.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03586v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yakun Niu, Yingjian Chen, Lei Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can LLMs See Without Pixels? Benchmarking Spatial Intelligence from Textual Descriptions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03590</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03590v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent advancements in Spatial Intelligence (SI) have predominantly relied on Vision-Language Models (VLMs), yet a critical question remains: does spatial understanding originate from visual encoders or the fundamental reasoning backbone? Inspired by this question, we introduce SiT-Bench, a novel benchmark designed to evaluate the SI performance of Large Language Models (LLMs) without pixel-level input, comprises over 3,800 expert-annotated items across five primary categories and 17 subtasks, ranging from egocentric navigation and perspective transformation to fine-grained robotic manipulation. By converting single/multi-view scenes into high-fidelity, coordinate-aware textual descriptions, we challenge LLMs to perform symbolic textual reasoning rather than visual pattern matching. Evaluation results of state-of-the-art (SOTA) LLMs reveals that while models achieve proficiency in localized semantic tasks, a significant "spatial gap" remains in global consistency. Notably, we find that explicit spatial reasoning significantly boosts performance, suggesting that LLMs possess latent world-modeling potential. Our proposed dataset SiT-Bench serves as a foundational resource to foster the development of spatially-grounded LLM backbones for future VLMs and embodied agents. Our code and benchmark will be released at https://github.com/binisalegend/SiT-Bench .</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03590v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhongbin Guo, Zhen Yang, Yushan Li, Xinyue Zhang, Wenyu Gao, Jiacheng Wang, Chengzhi Li, Xiangrui Liu, Ping Jian</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive Attention Distillation for Robust Few-Shot Segmentation under Environmental Perturbations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03596</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03596v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Few-shot segmentation (FSS) aims to rapidly learn novel class concepts from limited examples to segment specific targets in unseen images, and has been widely applied in areas such as medical diagnosis and industrial inspection. However, existing studies largely overlook the complex environmental factors encountered in real world scenarios-such as illumination, background, and camera viewpoint-which can substantially increase the difficulty of test images. As a result, models trained under laboratory conditions often fall short of practical deployment requirements. To bridge this gap, in this paper, an environment-robust FSS setting is introduced that explicitly incorporates challenging test cases arising from complex environments-such as motion blur, small objects, and camouflaged targets-to enhance model's robustness under realistic, dynamic conditions. An environment robust FSS benchmark (ER-FSS) is established, covering eight datasets across multiple real world scenarios. In addition, an Adaptive Attention Distillation (AAD) method is proposed, which repeatedly contrasts and distills key shared semantics between known (support) and unknown (query) images to derive class-specific attention for novel categories. This strengthens the model's ability to focus on the correct targets in complex environments, thereby improving environmental robustness. Comparative experiments show that AAD improves mIoU by 3.3% - 8.5% across all datasets and settings, demonstrating superior performance and strong generalization. The source code and dataset are available at: https://github.com/guoqianyu-alberta/Adaptive-Attention-Distillation-for-FSS.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03596v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qianyu Guo, Jingrong Wu, Jieji Ren, Weifeng Ge, Wenqiang Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling Text in Challenging Stone Inscriptions: A Character-Context-Aware Patching Strategy for Binarization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03609</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03609v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Binarization is a popular first step towards text extraction in historical artifacts. Stone inscription images pose severe challenges for binarization due to poor contrast between etched characters and the stone background, non-uniform surface degradation, distracting artifacts, and highly variable text density and layouts. These conditions frequently cause existing binarization techniques to fail and struggle to isolate coherent character regions. Many approaches sub-divide the image into patches to improve text fragment resolution and improve binarization performance. With this in mind, we present a robust and adaptive patching strategy to binarize challenging Indic inscriptions. The patches from our approach are used to train an Attention U-Net for binarization. The attention mechanism allows the model to focus on subtle structural cues, while our dynamic sampling and patch selection method ensures that the model learns to overcome surface noise and layout irregularities. We also introduce a carefully annotated, pixel-precise dataset of Indic stone inscriptions at the character-fragment level. We demonstrate that our novel patching mechanism significantly boosts binarization performance across classical and deep learning baselines. Despite training only on single script Indic dataset, our model exhibits strong zero-shot generalization to other Indic and non-indic scripts, highlighting its robustness and script-agnostic generalization capabilities. By producing clean, structured representations of inscription content, our method lays the foundation for downstream tasks such as script identification, OCR, and historical text analysis. Project page: https://ihdia.iiit.ac.in/shilalekhya-binarization/</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03609v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3774521.3774539</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Pratyush Jena, Amal Joseph, Arnav Sharma, Ravi Kiran Sarvadevabhatla</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Systematic Evaluation of Depth Backbones and Semantic Cues for Monocular Pseudo-LiDAR 3D Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03617</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03617v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Monocular 3D object detection offers a low-cost alternative to LiDAR, yet remains less accurate due to the difficulty of estimating metric depth from a single image. We systematically evaluate how depth backbones and feature engineering affect a monocular Pseudo-LiDAR pipeline on the KITTI validation split. Specifically, we compare NeWCRFs (supervised metric depth) against Depth Anything V2 Metric-Outdoor (Base) under an identical pseudo-LiDAR generation and PointRCNN detection protocol. NeWCRFs yields stronger downstream 3D detection, achieving 10.50\% AP$_{3D}$ at IoU$=0.7$ on the Moderate split using grayscale intensity (Exp~2). We further test point-cloud augmentations using appearance cues (grayscale intensity) and semantic cues (instance segmentation confidence). Contrary to the expectation that semantics would substantially close the gap, these features provide only marginal gains, and mask-based sampling can degrade performance by removing contextual geometry. Finally, we report a depth-accuracy-versus-distance diagnostic using ground-truth 2D boxes (including Ped/Cyc), highlighting that coarse depth correctness does not fully predict strict 3D IoU. Overall, under an off-the-shelf LiDAR detector, depth-backbone choice and geometric fidelity dominate performance, outweighing secondary feature injection.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03617v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Samson Oseiwe Ajadalu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shape Classification using Approximately Convex Segment Features</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03625</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03625v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The existing object classification techniques based on descriptive features rely on object alignment to compute the similarity of objects for classification. This paper replaces the necessity of object alignment through sorting of feature. The object boundary is normalized and segmented into approximately convex segments and the segments are then sorted in descending order of their length. The segment length, number of extreme points in segments, area of segments, the base and the width of the segments - a bag of features - is used to measure the similarity between image boundaries. The proposed method is tested on datasets and acceptable results are observed.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03625v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bimal Kumar Ray</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MFC-RFNet: A Multi-scale Guided Rectified Flow Network for Radar Sequence Prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03633</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03633v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Accurate and high-resolution precipitation nowcasting from radar echo sequences is crucial for disaster mitigation and economic planning, yet it remains a significant challenge. Key difficulties include modeling complex multi-scale evolution, correcting inter-frame feature misalignment caused by displacement, and efficiently capturing long-range spatiotemporal context without sacrificing spatial fidelity. To address these issues, we present the Multi-scale Feature Communication Rectified Flow (RF) Network (MFC-RFNet), a generative framework that integrates multi-scale communication with guided feature fusion. To enhance multi-scale fusion while retaining fine detail, a Wavelet-Guided Skip Connection (WGSC) preserves high-frequency components, and a Feature Communication Module (FCM) promotes bidirectional cross-scale interaction. To correct inter-frame displacement, a Condition-Guided Spatial Transform Fusion (CGSTF) learns spatial transforms from conditioning echoes to align shallow features. The backbone adopts rectified flow training to learn near-linear probability-flow trajectories, enabling few-step sampling with stable fidelity. Additionally, lightweight Vision-RWKV (RWKV) blocks are placed at the encoder tail, the bottleneck, and the first decoder layer to capture long-range spatiotemporal dependencies at low spatial resolutions with moderate compute. Evaluations on four public datasets (SEVIR, MeteoNet, Shanghai, and CIKM) demonstrate consistent improvements over strong baselines, yielding clearer echo morphology at higher rain-rate thresholds and sustained skill at longer lead times. These results suggest that the proposed synergy of RF training with scale-aware communication, spatial alignment, and frequency-aware fusion presents an effective and robust approach for radar-based nowcasting.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03633v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenjie Luo, Chuanhu Deng, Chaorong Li, Rongyao Deng, Qiang Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrackSegFlow: Controllable Flow-Matching Synthesis for Generalizable Crack Segmentation with the CSF-50K Benchmark</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03637</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03637v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Automated crack segmentation is essential for scalable condition assessment of pavements and civil infrastructure, yet practical deployment is limited by scarce pixel-level labels and severe domain shift across sensors, illumination, textures, and annotation conventions. This paper presents CrackSegFlow, a controllable flow-matching synthesis framework that generates photorealistic crack images conditioned on binary masks while preserving strict mask-image alignment. The generator combines topology-preserving mask injection with boundary-gated modulation to maintain thin-structure continuity and suppress texture-driven false positives. A second class-conditional flow-matching model synthesizes crack masks with explicit control over crack coverage, enabling balanced, topology-diverse paired data without additional manual annotation. We further inject crack masks into crack-free backgrounds to diversify illumination and surface artifacts and reduce false positives caused by shadows, joints, and pavement markings. Experiments on five benchmarks spanning four asphalt datasets and the crack class of a concrete-domain dataset demonstrate consistent improvements under an established hybrid CNN--Transformer segmentation backbone and a fixed training protocol. With real plus synthesized pairs, in-domain performance improves on average by 5.37 mIoU and 5.13 F1, and target-guided cross-domain synthesis yields average gains of 13.12 mIoU and 14.82 F1 using only limited target mask statistics. Compared with diffusion-based semantic synthesis, CrackSegFlow provides substantially faster deterministic sampling and improves fidelity and mask-image alignment for thin-structure crack geometry. Finally, we release CSF-50K, a public dataset of 50,000 paired crack images and pixel-accurate masks for large-scale benchmarking of generalizable crack segmentation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03637v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Babak Asadi, Peiyang Wu, Mani Golparvar-Fard, Ramez Hajj</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VideoMemory: Toward Consistent Video Generation via Memory Integration</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03655</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03655v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Maintaining consistent characters, props, and environments across multiple shots is a central challenge in narrative video generation. Existing models can produce high-quality short clips but often fail to preserve entity identity and appearance when scenes change or when entities reappear after long temporal gaps. We present VideoMemory, an entity-centric framework that integrates narrative planning with visual generation through a Dynamic Memory Bank. Given a structured script, a multi-agent system decomposes the narrative into shots, retrieves entity representations from memory, and synthesizes keyframes and videos conditioned on these retrieved states. The Dynamic Memory Bank stores explicit visual and semantic descriptors for characters, props, and backgrounds, and is updated after each shot to reflect story-driven changes while preserving identity. This retrieval-update mechanism enables consistent portrayal of entities across distant shots and supports coherent long-form generation. To evaluate this setting, we construct a 54-case multi-shot consistency benchmark covering character-, prop-, and background-persistent scenarios. Extensive experiments show that VideoMemory achieves strong entity-level coherence and high perceptual quality across diverse narrative sequences.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03655v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jinsong Zhou, Yihua Du, Xinli Xu, Luozhou Wang, Zijie Zhuang, Yehang Zhang, Shuaibo Li, Xiaojun Hu, Bolan Su, Ying-cong Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MGPC: Multimodal Network for Generalizable Point Cloud Completion With Modality Dropout and Progressive Decoding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03660</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03660v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Point cloud completion aims to recover complete 3D geometry from partial observations caused by limited viewpoints and occlusions. Existing learning-based works, including 3D Convolutional Neural Network (CNN)-based, point-based, and Transformer-based methods, have achieved strong performance on synthetic benchmarks. However, due to the limitations of modality, scalability, and generative capacity, their generalization to novel objects and real-world scenarios remains challenging. In this paper, we propose MGPC, a generalizable multimodal point cloud completion framework that integrates point clouds, RGB images, and text within a unified architecture. MGPC introduces an innovative modality dropout strategy, a Transformer-based fusion module, and a novel progressive generator to improve robustness, scalability, and geometric modeling capability. We further develop an automatic data generation pipeline and construct MGPC-1M, a large-scale benchmark with over 1,000 categories and one million training pairs. Extensive experiments on MGPC-1M and in-the-wild data demonstrate that the proposed method consistently outperforms prior baselines and exhibits strong generalization under real-world conditions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03660v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiangyuan Liu, Hongxuan Ma, Yuhao Zhao, Zhe Liu, Jian Wang, Wei Zou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PhysVideoGenerator: Towards Physically Aware Video Generation via Latent Physics Guidance</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03665</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03665v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Current video generation models produce high-quality aesthetic videos but often struggle to learn representations of real-world physics dynamics, resulting in artifacts such as unnatural object collisions, inconsistent gravity, and temporal flickering. In this work, we propose PhysVideoGenerator, a proof-of-concept framework that explicitly embeds a learnable physics prior into the video generation process. We introduce a lightweight predictor network, PredictorP, which regresses high-level physical features extracted from a pre-trained Video Joint Embedding Predictive Architecture (V-JEPA 2) directly from noisy diffusion latents. These predicted physics tokens are injected into the temporal attention layers of a DiT-based generator (Latte) via a dedicated cross-attention mechanism. Our primary contribution is demonstrating the technical feasibility of this joint training paradigm: we show that diffusion latents contain sufficient information to recover V-JEPA 2 physical representations, and that multi-task optimization remains stable over training. This report documents the architectural design, technical challenges, and validation of training stability, establishing a foundation for future large-scale evaluation of physics-aware generative models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03665v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Siddarth Nilol Kundur Satish, Devesh Jaiswal, Hongyu Chen, Abhishek Bakshi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TRec: Egocentric Action Recognition using 2D Point Tracks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03667</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03667v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present a novel approach for egocentric action recognition that leverages 2D point tracks as an additional motion cue. While most existing methods rely on RGB appearance, human pose estimation, or their combination, our work demonstrates that tracking randomly sampled image points across video frames can substantially improve recognition accuracy. Unlike prior approaches, we do not detect hands, objects, or interaction regions. Instead, we employ CoTracker to follow a set of randomly initialized points through each video and use the resulting trajectories, together with the corresponding image frames, as input to a Transformer-based recognition model. Surprisingly, our method achieves notable gains even when only the initial frame and its associated point tracks are provided, without incorporating the full video sequence. Experimental results confirm that integrating 2D point tracks consistently enhances performance compared to the same model trained without motion information, highlighting their potential as a lightweight yet effective representation for egocentric action understanding.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03667v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dennis Holzmann, Sven Wachsmuth</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BREATH-VL: Vision-Language-Guided 6-DoF Bronchoscopy Localization via Semantic-Geometric Fusion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03713</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03713v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Vision-language models (VLMs) have recently shown remarkable performance in navigation and localization tasks by leveraging large-scale pretraining for semantic understanding. However, applying VLMs to 6-DoF endoscopic camera localization presents several challenges: 1) the lack of large-scale, high-quality, densely annotated, and localization-oriented vision-language datasets in real-world medical settings; 2) limited capability for fine-grained pose regression; and 3) high computational latency when extracting temporal features from past frames. To address these issues, we first construct BREATH dataset, the largest in-vivo endoscopic localization dataset to date, collected in the complex human airway. Building on this dataset, we propose BREATH-VL, a hybrid framework that integrates semantic cues from VLMs with geometric information from vision-based registration methods for accurate 6-DoF pose estimation. Our motivation lies in the complementary strengths of both approaches: VLMs offer generalizable semantic understanding, while registration methods provide precise geometric alignment. To further enhance the VLM's ability to capture temporal context, we introduce a lightweight context-learning mechanism that encodes motion history as linguistic prompts, enabling efficient temporal reasoning without expensive video-level computation. Extensive experiments demonstrate that the vision-language module delivers robust semantic localization in challenging surgical scenes. Building on this, our BREATH-VL outperforms state-of-the-art vision-only localization methods in both accuracy and generalization, reducing translational error by 25.5% compared with the best-performing baseline, while achieving competitive computational latency.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03713v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qingyao Tian, Bingyu Yang, Huai Liao, Xinyan Huang, Junyong Li, Dong Yi, Hongbin Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Real-world Lens Active Alignment with Unlabeled Data via Domain Adaptation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03718</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03718v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Active Alignment (AA) is a key technology for the large-scale automated assembly of high-precision optical systems. Compared with labor-intensive per-model on-device calibration, a digital-twin pipeline built on optical simulation offers a substantial advantage in generating large-scale labeled data. However, complex imaging conditions induce a domain gap between simulation and real-world images, limiting the generalization of simulation-trained models. To address this, we propose augmenting a simulation baseline with minimal unlabeled real-world images captured at random misalignment positions, mitigating the gap from a domain adaptation perspective. We introduce Domain Adaptive Active Alignment (DA3), which utilizes an autoregressive domain transformation generator and an adversarial-based feature alignment strategy to distill real-world domain information via self-supervised learning. This enables the extraction of domain-invariant image degradation features to facilitate robust misalignment prediction. Experiments on two lens types reveal that DA3 improves accuracy by 46% over a purely simulation pipeline. Notably, it approaches the performance achieved with precisely labeled real-world data collected on 3 lens samples, while reducing on-device data collection time by 98.7%. The results demonstrate that domain adaptation effectively endows simulation-trained models with robust real-world performance, validating the digital-twin pipeline as a practical solution to significantly enhance the efficiency of large-scale optical assembly.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03718v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>physics.optics</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenyong Lia, Qi Jiang, Weijian Hu, Kailun Yang, Zhanjun Zhang, Wenjun Tian, Kaiwei Wang, Jian Bai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CSMCIR: CoT-Enhanced Symmetric Alignment with Memory Bank for Composed Image Retrieval</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03728</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03728v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Composed Image Retrieval (CIR) enables users to search for target images using both a reference image and manipulation text, offering substantial advantages over single-modality retrieval systems. However, existing CIR methods suffer from representation space fragmentation: queries and targets comprise heterogeneous modalities and are processed by distinct encoders, forcing models to bridge misaligned representation spaces only through post-hoc alignment, which fundamentally limits retrieval performance. This architectural asymmetry manifests as three distinct, well-separated clusters in the feature space, directly demonstrating how heterogeneous modalities create fundamentally misaligned representation spaces from initialization. In this work, we propose CSMCIR, a unified representation framework that achieves efficient query-target alignment through three synergistic components. First, we introduce a Multi-level Chain-of-Thought (MCoT) prompting strategy that guides Multimodal Large Language Models to generate discriminative, semantically compatible captions for target images, establishing modal symmetry. Building upon this, we design a symmetric dual-tower architecture where both query and target sides utilize the identical shared-parameter Q-Former for cross-modal encoding, ensuring consistent feature representations and further reducing the alignment gap. Finally, this architectural symmetry enables an entropy-based, temporally dynamic Memory Bank strategy that provides high-quality negative samples while maintaining consistency with the evolving model state. Extensive experiments on four benchmark datasets demonstrate that our CSMCIR achieves state-of-the-art performance with superior training efficiency. Comprehensive ablation studies further validate the effectiveness of each proposed component.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03728v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhipeng Qian, Zihan Liang, Yufei Ma, Ben Chen, Huangyu Dai, Yiwei Ma, Jiayi Ji, Chenyi Lei, Han Li, Xiaoshuai Sun</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MATANet: A Multi-context Attention and Taxonomy-Aware Network for Fine-Grained Underwater Recognition of Marine Species</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03729</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03729v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Fine-grained classification of marine animals supports ecology, biodiversity and habitat conservation, and evidence-based policy-making. However, existing methods often overlook contextual interactions from the surrounding environment and insufficiently incorporate the hierarchical structure of marine biological taxonomy. To address these challenges, we propose MATANet (Multi-context Attention and Taxonomy-Aware Network), a novel model designed for fine-grained marine species classification. MATANet mimics expert strategies by using taxonomy and environmental context to interpret ambiguous features of underwater animals. It consists of two key components: a Multi-Context Environmental Attention Module (MCEAM), which learns relationships between regions of interest (ROIs) and their surrounding environments, and a Hierarchical Separation-Induced Learning Module (HSLM), which encodes taxonomic hierarchy into the feature space. MATANet combines instance and environmental features with taxonomic structure to enhance fine-grained classification. Experiments on the FathomNet2025, FAIR1M, and LifeCLEF2015-Fish datasets demonstrate state-of-the-art performance. The source code is available at: https://github.com/dhlee-work/fathomnet-cvpr2025-ssl</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03729v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Donghwan Lee, Byeongjin Kim, Geunhee Kim, Hyukjin Kwon, Nahyeon Maeng, Wooju Kim</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RadDiff: Describing Differences in Radiology Image Sets with Natural Language</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03733</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03733v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Understanding how two radiology image sets differ is critical for generating clinical insights and for interpreting medical AI systems. We introduce RadDiff, a multimodal agentic system that performs radiologist-style comparative reasoning to describe clinically meaningful differences between paired radiology studies. RadDiff builds on a proposer-ranker framework from VisDiff, and incorporates four innovations inspired by real diagnostic workflows: (1) medical knowledge injection through domain-adapted vision-language models; (2) multimodal reasoning that integrates images with their clinical reports; (3) iterative hypothesis refinement across multiple reasoning rounds; and (4) targeted visual search that localizes and zooms in on salient regions to capture subtle findings. To evaluate RadDiff, we construct RadDiffBench, a challenging benchmark comprising 57 expert-validated radiology study pairs with ground-truth difference descriptions. On RadDiffBench, RadDiff achieves 47% accuracy, and 50% accuracy when guided by ground-truth reports, significantly outperforming the general-domain VisDiff baseline. We further demonstrate RadDiff's versatility across diverse clinical tasks, including COVID-19 phenotype comparison, racial subgroup analysis, and discovery of survival-related imaging features. Together, RadDiff and RadDiffBench provide the first method-and-benchmark foundation for systematically uncovering meaningful differences in radiological data.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03733v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoxian Shen, Yuhui Zhang, Sahithi Ankireddy, Xiaohan Wang, Maya Varma, Henry Guo, Curtis Langlotz, Serena Yeung-Levy</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HyperCOD: The First Challenging Benchmark and Baseline for Hyperspectral Camouflaged Object Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03736</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03736v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: RGB-based camouflaged object detection struggles in real-world scenarios where color and texture cues are ambiguous. While hyperspectral image offers a powerful alternative by capturing fine-grained spectral signatures, progress in hyperspectral camouflaged object detection (HCOD) has been critically hampered by the absence of a dedicated, large-scale benchmark. To spur innovation, we introduce HyperCOD, the first challenging benchmark for HCOD. Comprising 350 high-resolution hyperspectral images, It features complex real-world scenarios with minimal objects, intricate shapes, severe occlusions, and dynamic lighting to challenge current models. The advent of foundation models like the Segment Anything Model (SAM) presents a compelling opportunity. To adapt the Segment Anything Model (SAM) for HCOD, we propose HyperSpectral Camouflage-aware SAM (HSC-SAM). HSC-SAM ingeniously reformulates the hyperspectral image by decoupling it into a spatial map fed to SAM's image encoder and a spectral saliency map that serves as an adaptive prompt. This translation effectively bridges the modality gap. Extensive experiments show that HSC-SAM sets a new state-of-the-art on HyperCOD and generalizes robustly to other public HSI datasets. The HyperCOD dataset and our HSC-SAM baseline provide a robust foundation to foster future research in this emerging area.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03736v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shuyan Bai, Tingfa Xu, Peifu Liu, Yuhao Qiu, Huiyan Bai, Huan Chen, Yanyan Peng, Jianan Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I2E: From Image Pixels to Actionable Interactive Environments for Text-Guided Image Editing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03741</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03741v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Existing text-guided image editing methods primarily rely on end-to-end pixel-level inpainting paradigm. Despite its success in simple scenarios, this paradigm still significantly struggles with compositional editing tasks that require precise local control and complex multi-object spatial reasoning. This paradigm is severely limited by 1) the implicit coupling of planning and execution, 2) the lack of object-level control granularity, and 3) the reliance on unstructured, pixel-centric modeling. To address these limitations, we propose I2E, a novel "Decompose-then-Action" paradigm that revisits image editing as an actionable interaction process within a structured environment. I2E utilizes a Decomposer to transform unstructured images into discrete, manipulable object layers and then introduces a physics-aware Vision-Language-Action Agent to parse complex instructions into a series of atomic actions via Chain-of-Thought reasoning. Further, we also construct I2E-Bench, a benchmark designed for multi-instance spatial reasoning and high-precision editing. Experimental results on I2E-Bench and multiple public benchmarks demonstrate that I2E significantly outperforms state-of-the-art methods in handling complex compositional instructions, maintaining physical plausibility, and ensuring multi-turn editing stability.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03741v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jinghan Yu, Junhao Xiao, Chenyu Zhu, Jiaming Li, Jia Li, HanMing Deng, Xirui Wang, Guoli Jia, Jianjun Li, Zhiyuan Ma, Xiang Bai, Bowen Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MVP: Enhancing Video Large Language Models via Self-supervised Masked Video Prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03781</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03781v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Reinforcement learning based post-training paradigms for Video Large Language Models (VideoLLMs) have achieved significant success by optimizing for visual-semantic tasks such as captioning or VideoQA. However, while these approaches effectively enhance perception abilities, they primarily target holistic content understanding, often lacking explicit supervision for intrinsic temporal coherence and inter-frame correlations. This tendency limits the models' ability to capture intricate dynamics and fine-grained visual causality. To explicitly bridge this gap, we propose a novel post-training objective: Masked Video Prediction (MVP). By requiring the model to reconstruct a masked continuous segment from a set of challenging distractors, MVP forces the model to attend to the sequential logic and temporal context of events. To support scalable training, we introduce a scalable data synthesis pipeline capable of transforming arbitrary video corpora into MVP training samples, and further employ Group Relative Policy Optimization (GRPO) with a fine-grained reward function to enhance the model's understanding of video context and temporal properties. Comprehensive evaluations demonstrate that MVP enhances video reasoning capabilities by directly reinforcing temporal reasoning and causal understanding.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03781v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaokun Sun, Zezhong Wu, Zewen Ding, Linli Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comparative Study of 3D Model Acquisition Methods for Synthetic Data Generation of Agricultural Products</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03784</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03784v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In the manufacturing industry, computer vision systems based on artificial intelligence (AI) are widely used to reduce costs and increase production. Training these AI models requires a large amount of training data that is costly to acquire and annotate, especially in high-variance, low-volume manufacturing environments. A popular approach to reduce the need for real data is the use of synthetic data that is generated by leveraging computer-aided design (CAD) models available in the industry. However, in the agricultural industry these models are not readily available, increasing the difficulty in leveraging synthetic data. In this paper, we present different techniques for substituting CAD files to create synthetic datasets. We measure their relative performance when used to train an AI object detection model to separate stones and potatoes in a bin picking environment. We demonstrate that using highly representative 3D models acquired by scanning or using image-to-3D approaches can be used to generate synthetic data for training object detection models. Finetuning on a small real dataset can significantly improve the performance of the models and even get similar performance when less representative models are used.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03784v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Steven Moonen, Rob Salaets, Kenneth Batstone, Abdellatif Bey-Temsamani, Nick Michiels</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Brute Force to Semantic Insight: Performance-Guided Data Transformation Design with LLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03808</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03808v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have achieved notable performance in code synthesis; however, data-aware augmentation remains a limiting factor, handled via heuristic design or brute-force approaches. We introduce a performance-aware, closed-loop solution in the NNGPT ecosystem of projects that enables LLMs to autonomously engineer optimal transformations by internalizing empirical performance cues. We fine-tune LLMs with Low-Rank Adaptation on a novel repository of more than 6,000 empirically evaluated PyTorch augmentation functions, each annotated solely by downstream model accuracy. Training uses pairwise performance ordering (better-worse transformations), enabling alignment through empirical feedback without reinforcement learning, reward models, or symbolic objectives. This reduces the need for exhaustive search, achieving up to 600x times fewer evaluated candidates than brute-force discovery while maintaining competitive peak accuracy and shifting generation from random synthesis to task-aligned design. Ablation studies show that structured Chain-of-Thought prompting introduces syntactic noise and degrades performance, whereas direct prompting ensures stable optimization in performance-critical code tasks. Qualitative and quantitative analyses demonstrate that the model internalizes semantic performance cues rather than memorizing syntax. These results show that LLMs can exhibit task-level reasoning through non-textual feedback loops, bypassing explicit symbolic rewards.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03808v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Usha Shrestha, Dmitry Ignatov, Radu Timofte</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EvalBlocks: A Modular Pipeline for Rapidly Evaluating Foundation Models in Medical Imaging</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03811</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03811v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Developing foundation models in medical imaging requires continuous monitoring of downstream performance. Researchers are burdened with tracking numerous experiments, design choices, and their effects on performance, often relying on ad-hoc, manual workflows that are inherently slow and error-prone. We introduce EvalBlocks, a modular, plug-and-play framework for efficient evaluation of foundation models during development. Built on Snakemake, EvalBlocks supports seamless integration of new datasets, foundation models, aggregation methods, and evaluation strategies. All experiments and results are tracked centrally and are reproducible with a single command, while efficient caching and parallel execution enable scalable use on shared compute infrastructure. Demonstrated on five state-of-the-art foundation models and three medical imaging classification tasks, EvalBlocks streamlines model evaluation, enabling researchers to iterate faster and focus on model innovation rather than evaluation logistics. The framework is released as open source software at https://github.com/DIAGNijmegen/eval-blocks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03811v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jan Tagscherer, Sarah de Boer, Lena Philipp, Fennie van der Graaf, Dr\'e Peeters, Joeran Bosma, Lars Leijten, Bogdan Obreja, Ewoud Smit, Alessa Hering</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IDESplat: Iterative Depth Probability Estimation for Generalizable 3D Gaussian Splatting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03824</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03824v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Generalizable 3D Gaussian Splatting aims to directly predict Gaussian parameters using a feed-forward network for scene reconstruction. Among these parameters, Gaussian means are particularly difficult to predict, so depth is usually estimated first and then unprojected to obtain the Gaussian sphere centers. Existing methods typically rely solely on a single warp to estimate depth probability, which hinders their ability to fully leverage cross-view geometric cues, resulting in unstable and coarse depth maps. To address this limitation, we propose IDESplat, which iteratively applies warp operations to boost depth probability estimation for accurate Gaussian mean prediction. First, to eliminate the inherent instability of a single warp, we introduce a Depth Probability Boosting Unit (DPBU) that integrates epipolar attention maps produced by cascading warp operations in a multiplicative manner. Next, we construct an iterative depth estimation process by stacking multiple DPBUs, progressively identifying potential depth candidates with high likelihood. As IDESplat iteratively boosts depth probability estimates and updates the depth candidates, the depth map is gradually refined, resulting in accurate Gaussian means. We conduct experiments on RealEstate10K, ACID, and DL3DV. IDESplat achieves outstanding reconstruction quality and state-of-the-art performance with real-time efficiency. On RE10K, it outperforms DepthSplat by 0.33 dB in PSNR, using only 10.7% of the parameters and 70% of the memory. Additionally, our IDESplat improves PSNR by 2.95 dB over DepthSplat on the DTU dataset in cross-dataset experiments, demonstrating its strong generalization ability.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03824v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wei Long, Haifeng Wu, Shiyin Jiang, Jinhua Zhang, Xinchun Ji, Shuhang Gu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Monocular Depth Refinement via Neural Radiance Fields</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03869</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03869v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Monocular depth estimation has applications in many fields, such as autonomous navigation and extended reality, making it an essential computer vision task. However, current methods often produce smooth depth maps that lack the fine geometric detail needed for accurate scene understanding. We propose MDENeRF, an iterative framework that refines monocular depth estimates using depth information from Neural Radiance Fields (NeRFs). MDENeRF consists of three components: (1) an initial monocular estimate for global structure, (2) a NeRF trained on perturbed viewpoints, with per-pixel uncertainty, and (3) Bayesian fusion of the noisy monocular and NeRF depths. We derive NeRF uncertainty from the volume rendering process to iteratively inject high-frequency fine details. Meanwhile, our monocular prior maintains global structure. We demonstrate superior performance on key metrics and experiments using indoor scenes from the SUN RGB-D dataset.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03869v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Arun Muthukkumar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FLNet: Flood-Induced Agriculture Damage Assessment using Super Resolution of Satellite Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03884</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03884v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Distributing government relief efforts after a flood is challenging. In India, the crops are widely affected by floods; therefore, making rapid and accurate crop damage assessment is crucial for effective post-disaster agricultural management. Traditional manual surveys are slow and biased, while current satellite-based methods face challenges like cloud cover and low spatial resolution. Therefore, to bridge this gap, this paper introduced FLNet, a novel deep learning based architecture that used super-resolution to enhance the 10 m spatial resolution of Sentinel-2 satellite images into 3 m resolution before classifying damage. We tested our model on the Bihar Flood Impacted Croplands Dataset (BFCD-22), and the results showed an improved critical "Full Damage" F1-score from 0.83 to 0.89, nearly matching the 0.89 score of commercial high-resolution imagery. This work presented a cost-effective and scalable solution, paving the way for a nationwide shift from manual to automated, high-fidelity damage assessment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03884v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sanidhya Ghosal, Anurag Sharma, Sushil Ghildiyal, Mukesh Saini</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HemBLIP: A Vision-Language Model for Interpretable Leukemia Cell Morphology Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03915</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03915v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Microscopic evaluation of white blood cell morphology is central to leukemia diagnosis, yet current deep learning models often act as black boxes, limiting clinical trust and adoption. We introduce HemBLIP, a vision language model designed to generate interpretable, morphology aware descriptions of peripheral blood cells. Using a newly constructed dataset of 14k healthy and leukemic cells paired with expert-derived attribute captions, we adapt a general-purpose VLM via both full fine-tuning and LoRA based parameter efficient training, and benchmark against the biomedical foundation model MedGEMMA. HemBLIP achieves higher caption quality and morphological accuracy, while LoRA adaptation provides further gains with significantly reduced computational cost. These results highlight the promise of vision language models for transparent and scalable hematological diagnostics.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03915v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Julie van Logtestijn, Petru Manescu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FocusUI: Efficient UI Grounding via Position-Preserving Visual Token Selection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03928</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03928v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Vision-Language Models (VLMs) have shown remarkable performance in User Interface (UI) grounding tasks, driven by their ability to process increasingly high-resolution screenshots. However, screenshots are tokenized into thousands of visual tokens (e.g., about 4700 for 2K resolution), incurring significant computational overhead and diluting attention. In contrast, humans typically focus on regions of interest when interacting with UI. In this work, we pioneer the task of efficient UI grounding. Guided by practical analysis of the task's characteristics and challenges, we propose FocusUI, an efficient UI grounding framework that selects patches most relevant to the instruction while preserving positional continuity for precise grounding. FocusUI addresses two key challenges: (1) Eliminating redundant tokens in visual encoding. We construct patch-level supervision by fusing an instruction-conditioned score with a rule-based UI-graph score that down-weights large homogeneous regions to select distinct and instruction-relevant visual tokens. (2) Preserving positional continuity during visual token selection. We find that general visual token pruning methods suffer from severe accuracy degradation on UI grounding tasks due to broken positional information. We introduce a novel PosPad strategy, which compresses each contiguous sequence of dropped visual tokens into a single special marker placed at the sequence's last index to preserve positional continuity. Comprehensive experiments on four grounding benchmarks demonstrate that FocusUI surpasses GUI-specific baselines. On the ScreenSpot-Pro benchmark, FocusUI-7B achieves a performance improvement of 3.7% over GUI-Actor-7B. Even with only 30% visual token retention, FocusUI-7B drops by only 3.2% while achieving up to 1.44x faster inference and 17% lower peak GPU memory.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03928v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mingyu Ouyang, Kevin Qinghong Lin, Mike Zheng Shou, Hwee Tou Ng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ResTok: Learning Hierarchical Residuals in 1D Visual Tokenizers for Autoregressive Image Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03955</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03955v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Existing 1D visual tokenizers for autoregressive (AR) generation largely follow the design principles of language modeling, as they are built directly upon transformers whose priors originate in language, yielding single-hierarchy latent tokens and treating visual data as flat sequential token streams. However, this language-like formulation overlooks key properties of vision, particularly the hierarchical and residual network designs that have long been essential for convergence and efficiency in visual models. To bring "vision" back to vision, we propose the Residual Tokenizer (ResTok), a 1D visual tokenizer that builds hierarchical residuals for both image tokens and latent tokens. The hierarchical representations obtained through progressively merging enable cross-level feature fusion at each layer, substantially enhancing representational capacity. Meanwhile, the semantic residuals between hierarchies prevent information overlap, yielding more concentrated latent distributions that are easier for AR modeling. Cross-level bindings consequently emerge without any explicit constraints. To accelerate the generation process, we further introduce a hierarchical AR generator that substantially reduces sampling steps by predicting an entire level of latent tokens at once rather than generating them strictly token-by-token. Extensive experiments demonstrate that restoring hierarchical residual priors in visual tokenization significantly improves AR image generation, achieving a gFID of 2.34 on ImageNet-256 with only 9 sampling steps. Code is available at https://github.com/Kwai-Kolors/ResTok.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03955v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xu Zhang, Cheng Da, Huan Yang, Kun Gai, Ming Lu, Zhan Ma</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FUSION: Full-Body Unified Motion Prior for Body and Hands via Diffusion</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03959</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03959v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Hands are central to interacting with our surroundings and conveying gestures, making their inclusion essential for full-body motion synthesis. Despite this, existing human motion synthesis methods fall short: some ignore hand motions entirely, while others generate full-body motions only for narrowly scoped tasks under highly constrained settings. A key obstacle is the lack of large-scale datasets that jointly capture diverse full-body motion with detailed hand articulation. While some datasets capture both, they are limited in scale and diversity. Conversely, large-scale datasets typically focus either on body motion without hands or on hand motions without the body. To overcome this, we curate and unify existing hand motion datasets with large-scale body motion data to generate full-body sequences that capture both hand and body. We then propose the first diffusion-based unconditional full-body motion prior, FUSION, which jointly models body and hand motion. Despite using a pose-based motion representation, FUSION surpasses state-of-the-art skeletal control models on the Keypoint Tracking task in the HumanML3D dataset and achieves superior motion naturalness. Beyond standard benchmarks, we demonstrate that FUSION can go beyond typical uses of motion priors through two applications: (1) generating detailed full-body motion including fingers during interaction given the motion of an object, and (2) generating Self-Interaction motions using an LLM to transform natural language cues into actionable motion constraints. For these applications, we develop an optimization pipeline that refines the latent space of our diffusion model to generate task-specific motions. Experiments on these tasks highlight precise control over hand motion while maintaining plausible full-body coordination. The code will be public.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03959v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Enes Duran, Nikos Athanasiou, Muhammed Kocabas, Michael J. Black, Omid Taheri</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PosterVerse: A Full-Workflow Framework for Commercial-Grade Poster Generation with HTML-Based Scalable Typography</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03993</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03993v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Commercial-grade poster design demands the seamless integration of aesthetic appeal with precise, informative content delivery. Current automated poster generation systems face significant limitations, including incomplete design workflows, poor text rendering accuracy, and insufficient flexibility for commercial applications. To address these challenges, we propose PosterVerse, a full-workflow, commercial-grade poster generation method that seamlessly automates the entire design process while delivering high-density and scalable text rendering. PosterVerse replicates professional design through three key stages: (1) blueprint creation using fine-tuned LLMs to extract key design elements from user requirements, (2) graphical background generation via customized diffusion models to create visually appealing imagery, and (3) unified layout-text rendering with an MLLM-powered HTML engine to guarantee high text accuracy and flexible customization. In addition, we introduce PosterDNA, a commercial-grade, HTML-based dataset tailored for training and validating poster design models. To the best of our knowledge, PosterDNA is the first Chinese poster generation dataset to introduce HTML typography files, enabling scalable text rendering and fundamentally solving the challenges of rendering small and high-density text. Experimental results demonstrate that PosterVerse consistently produces commercial-grade posters with appealing visuals, accurate text alignment, and customizable layouts, making it a promising solution for automating commercial poster design. The code and model are available at https://github.com/wuhaer/PosterVerse.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03993v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>AAAI 2026 Oral</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Junle Liu, Peirong Zhang, Yuyi Zhang, Pengyu Yan, Hui Zhou, Xinyue Zhou, Fengjun Guo, Lianwen Jin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pad\'e Neurons for Efficient Neural Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.04005</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.04005v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Neural networks commonly employ the McCulloch-Pitts neuron model, which is a linear model followed by a point-wise non-linear activation. Various researchers have already advanced inherently non-linear neuron models, such as quadratic neurons, generalized operational neurons, generative neurons, and super neurons, which offer stronger non-linearity compared to point-wise activation functions. In this paper, we introduce a novel and better non-linear neuron model called Pad\'e neurons (Paons), inspired by Pad\'e approximants. Paons offer several advantages, such as diversity of non-linearity, since each Paon learns a different non-linear function of its inputs, and layer efficiency, since Paons provide stronger non-linearity in much fewer layers compared to piecewise linear approximation. Furthermore, Paons include all previously proposed neuron models as special cases, thus any neuron model in any network can be replaced by Paons. We note that there has been a proposal to employ the Pad\'e approximation as a generalized point-wise activation function, which is fundamentally different from our model. To validate the efficacy of Paons, in our experiments, we replace classic neurons in some well-known neural image super-resolution, compression, and classification models based on the ResNet architecture with Paons. Our comprehensive experimental results and analyses demonstrate that neural models built by Paons provide better or equal performance than their classic counterparts with a smaller number of layers. The PyTorch implementation code for Paon is open-sourced at https://github.com/onur-keles/Paon.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.04005v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Onur Kele\c{s}, A. Murat Tekalp</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thinking with Frames: Generative Video Distortion Evaluation via Frame Reward Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.04033</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.04033v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Recent advances in video reward models and post-training strategies have improved text-to-video (T2V) generation. While these models typically assess visual quality, motion quality, and text alignment, they often overlook key structural distortions, such as abnormal object appearances and interactions, which can degrade the overall quality of the generative video. To address this gap, we introduce REACT, a frame-level reward model designed specifically for structural distortions evaluation in generative videos. REACT assigns point-wise scores and attribution labels by reasoning over video frames, focusing on recognizing distortions. To support this, we construct a large-scale human preference dataset, annotated based on our proposed taxonomy of structural distortions, and generate additional data using a efficient Chain-of-Thought (CoT) synthesis pipeline. REACT is trained with a two-stage framework: ((1) supervised fine-tuning with masked loss for domain knowledge injection, followed by (2) reinforcement learning with Group Relative Policy Optimization (GRPO) and pairwise rewards to enhance reasoning capability and align output scores with human preferences. During inference, a dynamic sampling mechanism is introduced to focus on frames most likely to exhibit distortion. We also present REACT-Bench, a benchmark for generative video distortion evaluation. Experimental results demonstrate that REACT complements existing reward models in assessing structutal distortion, achieving both accurate quantitative evaluations and interpretable attribution analysis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.04033v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuan Wang, Borui Liao, Huijuan Huang, Jinda Lu, Ouxiang Li, Kuien Liu, Meng Wang, Xiang Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unsupervised Modular Adaptive Region Growing and RegionMix Classification for Wind Turbine Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.04065</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.04065v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Reliable operation of wind turbines requires frequent inspections, as even minor surface damages can degrade aerodynamic performance, reduce energy output, and accelerate blade wear. Central to automating these inspections is the accurate segmentation of turbine blades from visual data. This task is traditionally addressed through dense, pixel-wise deep learning models. However, such methods demand extensive annotated datasets, posing scalability challenges. In this work, we introduce an annotation-efficient segmentation approach that reframes the pixel-level task into a binary region classification problem. Image regions are generated using a fully unsupervised, interpretable Modular Adaptive Region Growing technique, guided by image-specific Adaptive Thresholding and enhanced by a Region Merging process that consolidates fragmented areas into coherent segments. To improve generalization and classification robustness, we introduce RegionMix, an augmentation strategy that synthesizes new training samples by combining distinct regions. Our framework demonstrates state-of-the-art segmentation accuracy and strong cross-site generalization by consistently segmenting turbine blades across distinct windfarms.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.04065v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ra\"ul P\'erez-Gonzalo, Riccardo Magro, Andreas Espersen, Antonio Agudo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mind the Generative Details: Direct Localized Detail Preference Optimization for Video Diffusion Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.04068</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.04068v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Aligning text-to-video diffusion models with human preferences is crucial for generating high-quality videos. Existing Direct Preference Otimization (DPO) methods rely on multi-sample ranking and task-specific critic models, which is inefficient and often yields ambiguous global supervision. To address these limitations, we propose LocalDPO, a novel post-training framework that constructs localized preference pairs from real videos and optimizes alignment at the spatio-temporal region level. We design an automated pipeline to efficiently collect preference pair data that generates preference pairs with a single inference per prompt, eliminating the need for external critic models or manual annotation. Specifically, we treat high-quality real videos as positive samples and generate corresponding negatives by locally corrupting them with random spatio-temporal masks and restoring only the masked regions using the frozen base model. During training, we introduce a region-aware DPO loss that restricts preference learning to corrupted areas for rapid convergence. Experiments on Wan2.1 and CogVideoX demonstrate that LocalDPO consistently improves video fidelity, temporal coherence and human preference scores over other post-training approaches, establishing a more efficient and fine-grained paradigm for video generator alignment.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.04068v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zitong Huang, Kaidong Zhang, Yukang Ding, Chao Gao, Rui Ding, Ying Chen, Wangmeng Zuo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Reasoning Consistency in Large Multimodal Models under Cross-Modal Conflicts</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.04073</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.04073v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Multimodal Models (LMMs) have demonstrated impressive capabilities in video reasoning via Chain-of-Thought (CoT). However, the robustness of their reasoning chains remains questionable. In this paper, we identify a critical failure mode termed textual inertia, where once a textual hallucination occurs in the thinking process, models tend to blindly adhere to the erroneous text while neglecting conflicting visual evidence. To systematically investigate this, we propose the LogicGraph Perturbation Protocol that structurally injects perturbations into the reasoning chains of diverse LMMs spanning both native reasoning architectures and prompt-driven paradigms to evaluate their self-reflection capabilities. The results reveal that models successfully self-correct in less than 10% of cases and predominantly succumb to blind textual error propagation. To mitigate this, we introduce Active Visual-Context Refinement, a training-free inference paradigm which orchestrates an active visual re-grounding mechanism to enforce fine-grained verification coupled with an adaptive context refinement strategy to summarize and denoise the reasoning history. Experiments demonstrate that our approach significantly stifles hallucination propagation and enhances reasoning robustness.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.04073v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhihao Zhu, Jiafeng Liang, Shixin Jiang, Jinlan Fu, Ming Liu, Guanglu Sun, See-Kiong Ng, Bing Qin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gen3R: 3D Scene Generation Meets Feed-Forward Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.04090</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.04090v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present Gen3R, a method that bridges the strong priors of foundational reconstruction models and video diffusion models for scene-level 3D generation. We repurpose the VGGT reconstruction model to produce geometric latents by training an adapter on its tokens, which are regularized to align with the appearance latents of pre-trained video diffusion models. By jointly generating these disentangled yet aligned latents, Gen3R produces both RGB videos and corresponding 3D geometry, including camera poses, depth maps, and global point clouds. Experiments demonstrate that our approach achieves state-of-the-art results in single- and multi-image conditioned 3D scene generation. Additionally, our method can enhance the robustness of reconstruction by leveraging generative priors, demonstrating the mutual benefit of tightly coupling reconstruction and generative models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.04090v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jiaxin Huang, Yuanbo Yang, Bangbang Yang, Lin Ma, Yuewen Ma, Yiyi Liao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GeoReason: Aligning Thinking And Answering In Remote Sensing Vision-Language Models Via Logical Consistency Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.04118</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.04118v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The evolution of Remote Sensing Vision-Language Models(RS-VLMs) emphasizes the importance of transitioning from perception-centric recognition toward high-level deductive reasoning to enhance cognitive reliability in complex spatial tasks. However, current models often suffer from logical hallucinations, where correct answers are derived from flawed reasoning chains or rely on positional shortcuts rather than spatial logic. This decoupling undermines reliability in strategic spatial decision-making. To address this, we present GeoReason, a framework designed to synchronize internal thinking with final decisions. We first construct GeoReason-Bench, a logic-driven dataset containing 4,000 reasoning trajectories synthesized from geometric primitives and expert knowledge. We then formulate a two-stage training strategy: (1) Supervised Knowledge Initialization to equip the model with reasoning syntax and domain expertise, and (2) Consistency-Aware Reinforcement Learning to refine deductive reliability. This second stage integrates a novel Logical Consistency Reward, which penalizes logical drift via an option permutation strategy to anchor decisions in verifiable reasoning traces. Experimental results demonstrate that our framework significantly enhances the cognitive reliability and interpretability of RS-VLMs, achieving state-of-the-art performance compared to other advanced methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.04118v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenshuai Li, Xiantai Xiang, Zixiao Wen, Guangyao Zhou, Ben Niu, Feng Wang, Lijia Huang, Qiantong Wang, Yuxin Hu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pixel-Wise Multimodal Contrastive Learning for Remote Sensing Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.04127</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.04127v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Satellites continuously generate massive volumes of data, particularly for Earth observation, including satellite image time series (SITS). However, most deep learning models are designed to process either entire images or complete time series sequences to extract meaningful features for downstream tasks. In this study, we propose a novel multimodal approach that leverages pixel-wise two-dimensional (2D) representations to encode visual property variations from SITS more effectively. Specifically, we generate recurrence plots from pixel-based vegetation index time series (NDVI, EVI, and SAVI) as an alternative to using raw pixel values, creating more informative representations. Additionally, we introduce PIxel-wise Multimodal Contrastive (PIMC), a new multimodal self-supervision approach that produces effective encoders based on two-dimensional pixel time series representations and remote sensing imagery (RSI). To validate our approach, we assess its performance on three downstream tasks: pixel-level forecasting and classification using the PASTIS dataset, and land cover classification on the EuroSAT dataset. Moreover, we compare our results to state-of-the-art (SOTA) methods on all downstream tasks. Our experimental results show that the use of 2D representations significantly enhances feature extraction from SITS, while contrastive learning improves the quality of representations for both pixel time series and RSI. These findings suggest that our multimodal method outperforms existing models in various Earth observation tasks, establishing it as a robust self-supervision framework for processing both SITS and RSI. Code avaliable on</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.04127v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Leandro Stival, Ricardo da Silva Torres, Helio Pedrini</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Klear: Unified Multi-Task Audio-Video Joint Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.04151</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.04151v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Audio-video joint generation has progressed rapidly, yet substantial challenges still remain. Non-commercial approaches still suffer audio-visual asynchrony, poor lip-speech alignment, and unimodal degradation, which can be stemmed from weak audio-visual correspondence modeling, limited generalization, and scarce high-quality dense-caption data. To address these issues, we introduce Klear and delve into three axes--model architecture, training strategy, and data curation. Architecturally, we adopt a single-tower design with unified DiT blocks and an Omni-Full Attention mechanism, achieving tight audio-visual alignment and strong scalability. Training-wise, we adopt a progressive multitask regime--random modality masking to joint optimization across tasks, and a multistage curriculum, yielding robust representations, strengthening A-V aligned world knowledge, and preventing unimodal collapse. For datasets, we present the first large-scale audio-video dataset with dense captions, and introduce a novel automated data-construction pipeline which annotates and filters millions of diverse, high-quality, strictly aligned audio-video-caption triplets. Building on this, Klear scales to large datasets, delivering high-fidelity, semantically and temporally aligned, instruction-following generation in both joint and unimodal settings while generalizing robustly to out-of-distribution scenarios. Across tasks, it substantially outperforms prior methods by a large margin and achieves performance comparable to Veo 3, offering a unified, scalable path toward next-generation audio-video synthesis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.04151v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jun Wang, Chunyu Qiang, Yuxin Guo, Yiran Wang, Xijuan Zeng, Chen Zhang, Pengfei Wan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diffusion-DRF: Differentiable Reward Flow for Video Diffusion Fine-Tuning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.04153</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.04153v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Direct Preference Optimization (DPO) has recently improved Text-to-Video (T2V) generation by enhancing visual fidelity and text alignment. However, current methods rely on non-differentiable preference signals from human annotations or learned reward models. This reliance makes training label-intensive, bias-prone, and easy-to-game, which often triggers reward hacking and unstable training. We propose Diffusion-DRF, a differentiable reward flow for fine-tuning video diffusion models using a frozen, off-the-shelf Vision-Language Model (VLM) as a training-free critic. Diffusion-DRF directly backpropagates VLM feedback through the diffusion denoising chain, converting logit-level responses into token-aware gradients for optimization. We propose an automated, aspect-structured prompting pipeline to obtain reliable multi-dimensional VLM feedback, while gradient checkpointing enables efficient updates through the final denoising steps. Diffusion-DRF improves video quality and semantic alignment while mitigating reward hacking and collapse -- without additional reward models or preference datasets. It is model-agnostic and readily generalizes to other diffusion-based generative tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.04153v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yifan Wang, Yanyu Li, Sergey Tulyakov, Yun Fu, Anil Kag</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ToTMNet: FFT-Accelerated Toeplitz Temporal Mixing Network for Lightweight Remote Photoplethysmography</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.04159</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.04159v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Remote photoplethysmography (rPPG) estimates a blood volume pulse (BVP) waveform from facial videos captured by commodity cameras. Although recent deep models improve robustness compared to classical signal-processing approaches, many methods increase computational cost and parameter count, and attention-based temporal modeling introduces quadratic scaling with respect to the temporal length. This paper proposes ToTMNet, a lightweight rPPG architecture that replaces temporal attention with an FFT-accelerated Toeplitz temporal mixing layer. The Toeplitz operator provides full-sequence temporal receptive field using a linear number of parameters in the clip length and can be applied in near-linear time using circulant embedding and FFT-based convolution. ToTMNet integrates the global Toeplitz temporal operator into a compact gated temporal mixer that combines a local depthwise temporal convolution branch with gated global Toeplitz mixing, enabling efficient long-range temporal filtering while only having 63k parameters. Experiments on two datasets, UBFC-rPPG (real videos) and SCAMPS (synthetic videos), show that ToTMNet achieves strong heart-rate estimation accuracy with a compact design. On UBFC-rPPG intra-dataset evaluation, ToTMNet reaches 1.055 bpm MAE with Pearson correlation 0.996. In a synthetic-to-real setting (SCAMPS to UBFC-rPPG), ToTMNet reaches 1.582 bpm MAE with Pearson correlation 0.994. Ablation results confirm that the gating mechanism is important for effectively using global Toeplitz mixing, especially under domain shift. The main limitation of this preprint study is the use of only two datasets; nevertheless, the results indicate that Toeplitz-structured temporal mixing is a practical and efficient alternative to attention for rPPG.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.04159v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Vladimir Frants, Sos Agaian, Karen Panetta</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ImLoc: Revisiting Visual Localization with Image-based Representation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.04185</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.04185v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Existing visual localization methods are typically either 2D image-based, which are easy to build and maintain but limited in effective geometric reasoning, or 3D structure-based, which achieve high accuracy but require a centralized reconstruction and are difficult to update. In this work, we revisit visual localization with a 2D image-based representation and propose to augment each image with estimated depth maps to capture the geometric structure. Supported by the effective use of dense matchers, this representation is not only easy to build and maintain, but achieves highest accuracy in challenging conditions. With compact compression and a GPU-accelerated LO-RANSAC implementation, the whole pipeline is efficient in both storage and computation and allows for a flexible trade-off between accuracy and highest memory efficiency. Our method achieves a new state-of-the-art accuracy on various standard benchmarks and outperforms existing memory-efficient methods at comparable map sizes. Code will be available at https://github.com/cvg/Hierarchical-Localization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.04185v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xudong Jiang, Fangjinhua Wang, Silvano Galliani, Christoph Vogel, Marc Pollefeys</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Choreographing a World of Dynamic Objects</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.04194</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.04194v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Dynamic objects in our physical 4D (3D + time) world are constantly evolving, deforming, and interacting with other objects, leading to diverse 4D scene dynamics. In this paper, we present a universal generative pipeline, CHORD, for CHOReographing Dynamic objects and scenes and synthesizing this type of phenomena. Traditional rule-based graphics pipelines to create these dynamics are based on category-specific heuristics, yet are labor-intensive and not scalable. Recent learning-based methods typically demand large-scale datasets, which may not cover all object categories in interest. Our approach instead inherits the universality from the video generative models by proposing a distillation-based pipeline to extract the rich Lagrangian motion information hidden in the Eulerian representations of 2D videos. Our method is universal, versatile, and category-agnostic. We demonstrate its effectiveness by conducting experiments to generate a diverse range of multi-body 4D dynamics, show its advantage compared to existing methods, and demonstrate its applicability in generating robotics manipulation policies. Project page: https://yanzhelyu.github.io/chord</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.04194v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yanzhe Lyu, Chen Geng, Karthik Dharmarajan, Yunzhi Zhang, Hadi Alzayer, Shangzhe Wu, Jiajun Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Listen to Rhythm, Choose Movements: Autoregressive Multimodal Dance Generation via Diffusion and Mamba with Decoupled Dance Dataset</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03323</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03323v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Advances in generative models and sequence learning have greatly promoted research in dance motion generation, yet current methods still suffer from coarse semantic control and poor coherence in long sequences. In this work, we present Listen to Rhythm, Choose Movements (LRCM), a multimodal-guided diffusion framework supporting both diverse input modalities and autoregressive dance motion generation. We explore a feature decoupling paradigm for dance datasets and generalize it to the Motorica Dance dataset, separating motion capture data, audio rhythm, and professionally annotated global and local text descriptions. Our diffusion architecture integrates an audio-latent Conformer and a text-latent Cross-Conformer, and incorporates a Motion Temporal Mamba Module (MTMM) to enable smooth, long-duration autoregressive synthesis. Experimental results indicate that LRCM delivers strong performance in both functional capability and quantitative metrics, demonstrating notable potential in multimodal input scenarios and extended sequence generation. We will release the full codebase, dataset, and pretrained models publicly upon acceptance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03323v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Oran Duan, Yinghua Shen, Yingzhu Lv, Luyang Jie, Yaxin Liu, Qiong Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Edit2Restore:Few-Shot Image Restoration via Parameter-Efficient Adaptation of Pre-trained Editing Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03391</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03391v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Image restoration has traditionally required training specialized models on thousands of paired examples per degradation type. We challenge this paradigm by demonstrating that powerful pre-trained text-conditioned image editing models can be efficiently adapted for multiple restoration tasks through parameter-efficient fine-tuning with remarkably few examples. Our approach fine-tunes LoRA adapters on FLUX.1 Kontext, a state-of-the-art 12B parameter flow matching model for image-to-image translation, using only 16-128 paired images per task, guided by simple text prompts that specify the restoration operation. Unlike existing methods that train specialized restoration networks from scratch with thousands of samples, we leverage the rich visual priors already encoded in large-scale pre-trained editing models, dramatically reducing data requirements while maintaining high perceptual quality. A single unified LoRA adapter, conditioned on task-specific text prompts, effectively handles multiple degradations including denoising, deraining, and dehazing. Through comprehensive ablation studies, we analyze: (i) the impact of training set size on restoration quality, (ii) trade-offs between task-specific versus unified multi-task adapters, (iii) the role of text encoder fine-tuning, and (iv) zero-shot baseline performance. While our method prioritizes perceptual quality over pixel-perfect reconstruction metrics like PSNR/SSIM, our results demonstrate that pre-trained image editing models, when properly adapted, offer a compelling and data-efficient alternative to traditional image restoration approaches, opening new avenues for few-shot, prompt-guided image enhancement. The code to reproduce our results are available at: https://github.com/makinyilmaz/Edit2Restore</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03391v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>M. Ak{\i}n Y{\i}lmaz, Ahmet Bilican, Burak Can Biner, A. Murat Tekalp</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inferring Clinically Relevant Molecular Subtypes of Pancreatic Cancer from Routine Histopathology Using Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03410</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03410v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Molecular subtyping of PDAC into basal-like and classical has established prognostic and predictive value. However, its use in clinical practice is limited by cost, turnaround time, and tissue requirements, thereby restricting its application in the management of PDAC. We introduce PanSubNet, an interpretable deep learning framework that predicts therapy-relevant molecular subtypes directly from standard H&amp;E-stained WSIs. PanSubNet was developed using data from 1,055 patients across two multi-institutional cohorts (PANCAN, n=846; TCGA, n=209) with paired histology and RNA-seq data. Ground-truth labels were derived using the validated Moffitt 50-gene signature refined by GATA6 expression. The model employs dual-scale architecture that fuses cellular-level morphology with tissue-level architecture, leveraging attention mechanisms for multi-scale representation learning and transparent feature attribution. On internal validation within PANCAN using five-fold cross-validation, PanSubNet achieved mean AUC of 88.5% with balanced sensitivity and specificity. External validation on the independent TCGA cohort without fine-tuning demonstrated robust generalizability (AUC 84.0%). PanSubNet preserved and, in metastatic disease, strengthened prognostic stratification compared to RNA-seq based labels. Prediction uncertainty linked to intermediate transcriptional states, not classification noise. Model predictions are aligned with established transcriptomic programs, differentiation markers, and DNA damage repair signatures. By enabling rapid, cost-effective molecular stratification from routine H&amp;E-stained slides, PanSubNet offers a clinically deployable and interpretable tool for genetic subtyping. We are gathering data from two institutions to validate and assess real-world performance, supporting integration into digital pathology workflows and advancing precision oncology for PDAC.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03410v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Abdul Rehman Akbar, Alejandro Levya, Ashwini Esnakula, Elshad Hasanov, Anne Noonan, Upender Manne, Vaibhav Sahai, Lingbin Meng, Susan Tsai, Anil Parwani, Wei Chen, Ashish Manne, Muhammad Khalid Khan Niazi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GeoDiff-SAR: A Geometric Prior Guided Diffusion Model for SAR Image Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03499</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03499v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Synthetic Aperture Radar (SAR) imaging results are highly sensitive to observation geometries and the geometric parameters of targets. However, existing generative methods primarily operate within the image domain, neglecting explicit geometric information. This limitation often leads to unsatisfactory generation quality and the inability to precisely control critical parameters such as azimuth angles. To address these challenges, we propose GeoDiff-SAR, a geometric prior guided diffusion model for high-fidelity SAR image generation. Specifically, GeoDiff-SAR first efficiently simulates the geometric structures and scattering relationships inherent in real SAR imaging by calculating SAR point clouds at specific azimuths, which serves as a robust physical guidance. Secondly, to effectively fuse multi-modal information, we employ a feature fusion gating network based on Feature-wise Linear Modulation (FiLM) to dynamically regulate the weight distribution of 3D physical information, image control parameters, and textual description parameters. Thirdly, we utilize the Low-Rank Adaptation (LoRA) architecture to perform lightweight fine-tuning on the advanced Stable Diffusion 3.5 (SD3.5) model, enabling it to rapidly adapt to the distribution characteristics of the SAR domain. To validate the effectiveness of GeoDiff-SAR, extensive comparative experiments were conducted on real-world SAR datasets. The results demonstrate that data generated by GeoDiff-SAR exhibits high fidelity and effectively enhances the accuracy of downstream classification tasks. In particular, it significantly improves recognition performance across different azimuth angles, thereby underscoring the superiority of physics-guided generation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03499v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fan Zhang, Xuanting Wu, Fei Ma, Qiang Yin, Yuxin Hu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Persona-aware and Explainable Bikeability Assessment: A Vision-Language Model Approach</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03534</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03534v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Bikeability assessment is essential for advancing sustainable urban transportation and creating cyclist-friendly cities, and it requires incorporating users' perceptions of safety and comfort. Yet existing perception-based bikeability assessment approaches face key limitations in capturing the complexity of road environments and adequately accounting for heterogeneity in subjective user perceptions. This paper proposes a persona-aware Vision-Language Model framework for bikeability assessment with three novel contributions: (i) theory-grounded persona conditioning based on established cyclist typology that generates persona-specific explanations via chain-of-thought reasoning; (ii) multi-granularity supervised fine-tuning that combines scarce expert-annotated reasoning with abundant user ratings for joint prediction and explainable assessment; and (iii) AI-enabled data augmentation that creates controlled paired data to isolate infrastructure variable impacts. To test and validate this framework, we developed a panoramic image-based crowdsourcing system and collected 12,400 persona-conditioned assessments from 427 cyclists. Experiment results show that the proposed framework offers competitive bikeability rating prediction while uniquely enabling explainable factor attribution.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03534v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yilong Dai, Ziyi Wang, Chenguang Wang, Kexin Zhou, Yiheng Qian, Susu Xu, Xiang Yan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>e5-omni: Explicit Cross-modal Alignment for Omni-modal Embeddings</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03666</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03666v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Modern information systems often involve different types of items, e.g., a text query, an image, a video clip, or an audio segment. This motivates omni-modal embedding models that map heterogeneous modalities into a shared space for direct comparison. However, most recent omni-modal embeddings still rely heavily on implicit alignment inherited from pretrained vision-language model (VLM) backbones. In practice, this causes three common issues: (i) similarity logits have modality-dependent sharpness, so scores are not on a consistent scale; (ii) in-batch negatives become less effective over time because mixed-modality batches create an imbalanced hardness distribution; as a result, many negatives quickly become trivial and contribute little gradient; and (iii) embeddings across modalities show mismatched first- and second-order statistics, which makes rankings less stable. To tackle these problems, we propose e5-omni, a lightweight explicit alignment recipe that adapts off-the-shelf VLMs into robust omni-modal embedding models. e5-omni combines three simple components: (1) modality-aware temperature calibration to align similarity scales, (2) a controllable negative curriculum with debiasing to focus on confusing negatives while reducing the impact of false negatives, and (3) batch whitening with covariance regularization to better match cross-modal geometry in the shared embedding space. Experiments on MMEB-V2 and AudioCaps show consistent gains over strong bi-modal and omni-modal baselines, and the same recipe also transfers well to other VLM backbones. We release our model checkpoint at https://huggingface.co/Haon-Chen/e5-omni-7B.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03666v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haonan Chen, Sicheng Gao, Radu Timofte, Tetsuya Sakai, Zhicheng Dou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visual Merit or Linguistic Crutch? A Close Look at DeepSeek-OCR</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03714</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03714v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: DeepSeek-OCR utilizes an optical 2D mapping approach to achieve high-ratio vision-text compression, claiming to decode text tokens exceeding ten times the input visual tokens. While this suggests a promising solution for the LLM long-context bottleneck, we investigate a critical question: "Visual merit or linguistic crutch - which drives DeepSeek-OCR's performance?" By employing sentence-level and word-level semantic corruption, we isolate the model's intrinsic OCR capabilities from its language priors. Results demonstrate that without linguistic support, DeepSeek-OCR's performance plummets from approximately 90% to 20%. Comparative benchmarking against 13 baseline models reveals that traditional pipeline OCR methods exhibit significantly higher robustness to such semantic perturbations than end-to-end methods. Furthermore, we find that lower visual token counts correlate with increased reliance on priors, exacerbating hallucination risks. Context stress testing also reveals a total model collapse around 10,000 text tokens, suggesting that current optical compression techniques may paradoxically aggravate the long-context bottleneck. This study empirically defines DeepSeek-OCR's capability boundaries and offers essential insights for future optimizations of the vision-text compression paradigm. We release all data, results and scripts used in this study at https://github.com/dududuck00/DeepSeekOCR.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03714v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yunhao Liang, Ruixuan Ying, Bo Li, Hong Li, Kai Yan, Qingwen Li, Min Yang, Okamoto Satoshi, Zhe Cui, Shiwen Ni</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PointWorld: Scaling 3D World Models for In-The-Wild Robotic Manipulation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03782</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03782v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Humans anticipate, from a glance and a contemplated action of their bodies, how the 3D world will respond, a capability that is equally vital for robotic manipulation. We introduce PointWorld, a large pre-trained 3D world model that unifies state and action in a shared 3D space as 3D point flows: given one or few RGB-D images and a sequence of low-level robot action commands, PointWorld forecasts per-pixel displacements in 3D that respond to the given actions. By representing actions as 3D point flows instead of embodiment-specific action spaces (e.g., joint positions), this formulation directly conditions on physical geometries of robots while seamlessly integrating learning across embodiments. To train our 3D world model, we curate a large-scale dataset spanning real and simulated robotic manipulation in open-world environments, enabled by recent advances in 3D vision and simulated environments, totaling about 2M trajectories and 500 hours across a single-arm Franka and a bimanual humanoid. Through rigorous, large-scale empirical studies of backbones, action representations, learning objectives, partial observability, data mixtures, domain transfers, and scaling, we distill design principles for large-scale 3D world modeling. With a real-time (0.1s) inference speed, PointWorld can be efficiently integrated in the model-predictive control (MPC) framework for manipulation. We demonstrate that a single pre-trained checkpoint enables a real-world Franka robot to perform rigid-body pushing, deformable and articulated object manipulation, and tool use, without requiring any demonstrations or post-training and all from a single image captured in-the-wild. Project website at https://point-world.github.io/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03782v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenlong Huang, Yu-Wei Chao, Arsalan Mousavian, Ming-Yu Liu, Dieter Fox, Kaichun Mo, Li Fei-Fei</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Staged Voxel-Level Deep Reinforcement Learning for 3D Medical Image Segmentation with Noisy Annotations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03875</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03875v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Deep learning has achieved significant advancements in medical image segmentation. Currently, obtaining accurate segmentation outcomes is critically reliant on large-scale datasets with high-quality annotations. However, noisy annotations are frequently encountered owing to the complex morphological structures of organs in medical images and variations among different annotators, which can substantially limit the efficacy of segmentation models. Motivated by the fact that medical imaging annotator can correct labeling errors during segmentation based on prior knowledge, we propose an end-to-end Staged Voxel-Level Deep Reinforcement Learning (SVL-DRL) framework for robust medical image segmentation under noisy annotations. This framework employs a dynamic iterative update strategy to automatically mitigate the impact of erroneous labels without requiring manual intervention. The key advancements of SVL-DRL over existing works include: i) formulating noisy annotations as a voxel-dependent problem and addressing it through a novel staged reinforcement learning framework which guarantees robust model convergence; ii) incorporating a voxel-level asynchronous advantage actor-critic (vA3C) module that conceptualizes each voxel as an autonomous agent, which allows each agent to dynamically refine its own state representation during training, thereby directly mitigating the influence of erroneous labels; iii) designing a novel action space for the agents, along with a composite reward function that strategically combines the Dice value and a spatial continuity metric to significantly boost segmentation accuracy while maintain semantic integrity. Experiments on three public medical image datasets demonstrates State-of-The-Art (SoTA) performance under various experimental settings, with an average improvement of over 3\% in both Dice and IoU scores.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03875v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuyang Fu, Xiuzhen Guo, Ji Shi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A low-complexity method for efficient depth-guided image deblurring</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03924</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.03924v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Image deblurring is a challenging problem in imaging due to its highly ill-posed nature. Deep learning models have shown great success in tackling this problem but the quest for the best image quality has brought their computational complexity up, making them impractical on anything but powerful servers. Meanwhile, recent works have shown that mobile Lidars can provide complementary information in the form of depth maps that enhance deblurring quality. In this paper, we introduce a novel low-complexity neural network for depth-guided image deblurring. We show that the use of the wavelet transform to separate structural details and reduce spatial redundancy as well as efficient feature conditioning on the depth information are essential ingredients in developing a low-complexity model. Experimental results show competitive image quality against recent state-of-the-art models while reducing complexity by up to two orders of magnitude.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.03924v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ziyao Yi, Diego Valsesia, Tiziano Bianchi, Enrico Magli</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CLAP: Contrastive Latent Action Pretraining for Learning Vision-Language-Action Models from Human Videos</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.04061</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.04061v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Generalist Vision-Language-Action models are currently hindered by the scarcity of robotic data compared to the abundance of human video demonstrations. Existing Latent Action Models attempt to leverage video data but often suffer from visual entanglement, capturing noise rather than manipulation skills. To address this, we propose Contrastive Latent Action Pretraining (CLAP), a framework that aligns the visual latent space from videos with a proprioceptive latent space from robot trajectories. By employing contrastive learning, CLAP maps video transitions onto a quantized, physically executable codebook. Building on this representation, we introduce a dual-formulation VLA framework offering both CLAP-NTP, an autoregressive model excelling at instruction following and object generalization, and CLAP-RF, a Rectified Flow-based policy designed for high-frequency, precise manipulation. Furthermore, we propose a Knowledge Matching (KM) regularization strategy to mitigate catastrophic forgetting during fine-tuning. Extensive experiments demonstrate that CLAP significantly outperforms strong baselines, enabling the effective transfer of skills from human videos to robotic execution. Project page: https://lin-shan.com/CLAP/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.04061v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chubin Zhang, Jianan Wang, Zifeng Gao, Yue Su, Tianru Dai, Cai Zhou, Jiwen Lu, Yansong Tang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MORPHFED: Federated Learning for Cross-institutional Blood Morphology Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.04121</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.04121v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Automated blood morphology analysis can support hematological diagnostics in low- and middle-income countries (LMICs) but remains sensitive to dataset shifts from staining variability, imaging differences, and rare morphologies. Building centralized datasets to capture this diversity is often infeasible due to privacy regulations and data-sharing restrictions. We introduce a federated learning framework for white blood cell morphology analysis that enables collaborative training across institutions without exchanging training data. Using blood films from multiple clinical sites, our federated models learn robust, domain-invariant representations while preserving complete data privacy. Evaluations across convolutional and transformer-based architectures show that federated training achieves strong cross-site performance and improved generalization to unseen institutions compared to centralized training. These findings highlight federated learning as a practical and privacy-preserving approach for developing equitable, scalable, and generalizable medical imaging AI in resource-limited healthcare environments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.04121v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gabriel Ansah, Eden Ruffell, Delmiro Fernandez-Reyes, Petru Manescu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>InfiniteWeb: Scalable Web Environment Synthesis for GUI Agent Training</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.04126</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.04126v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: GUI agents that interact with graphical interfaces on behalf of users represent a promising direction for practical AI assistants. However, training such agents is hindered by the scarcity of suitable environments. We present InfiniteWeb, a system that automatically generates functional web environments at scale for GUI agent training. While LLMs perform well on generating a single webpage, building a realistic and functional website with many interconnected pages faces challenges. We address these challenges through unified specification, task-centric test-driven development, and a combination of website seed with reference design image to ensure diversity. Our system also generates verifiable task evaluators enabling dense reward signals for reinforcement learning. Experiments show that InfiniteWeb surpasses commercial coding agents at realistic website construction, and GUI agents trained on our generated environments achieve significant performance improvements on OSWorld and Online-Mind2Web, demonstrating the effectiveness of proposed system.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.04126v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ziyun Zhang, Zezhou Wang, Xiaoyi Zhang, Zongyu Guo, Jiahao Li, Bin Li, Yan Lu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wow, wo, val! A Comprehensive Embodied World Model Evaluation Turing Test</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.04137</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.04137v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: As world models gain momentum in Embodied AI, an increasing number of works explore using video foundation models as predictive world models for downstream embodied tasks like 3D prediction or interactive generation. However, before exploring these downstream tasks, video foundation models still have two critical questions unanswered: (1) whether their generative generalization is sufficient to maintain perceptual fidelity in the eyes of human observers, and (2) whether they are robust enough to serve as a universal prior for real-world embodied agents. To provide a standardized framework for answering these questions, we introduce the Embodied Turing Test benchmark: WoW-World-Eval (Wow,wo,val). Building upon 609 robot manipulation data, Wow-wo-val examines five core abilities, including perception, planning, prediction, generalization, and execution. We propose a comprehensive evaluation protocol with 22 metrics to assess the models' generation ability, which achieves a high Pearson Correlation between the overall score and human preference (&gt;0.93) and establishes a reliable foundation for the Human Turing Test. On Wow-wo-val, models achieve only 17.27 on long-horizon planning and at best 68.02 on physical consistency, indicating limited spatiotemporal consistency and physical reasoning. For the Inverse Dynamic Model Turing Test, we first use an IDM to evaluate the video foundation models' execution accuracy in the real world. However, most models collapse to $\approx$ 0% success, while WoW maintains a 40.74% success rate. These findings point to a noticeable gap between the generated videos and the real world, highlighting the urgency and necessity of benchmarking World Model in Embodied AI.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.04137v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chun-Kai Fan, Xiaowei Chi, Xiaozhu Ju, Hao Li, Yong Bao, Yu-Kai Wang, Lizhang Chen, Zhiyuan Jiang, Kuangzhi Ge, Ying Li, Weishi Mi, Qingpo Wuwu, Peidong Jia, Yulin Luo, Kevin Zhang, Zhiyuan Qin, Yong Dai, Sirui Han, Yike Guo, Shanghang Zhang, Jian Tang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scanner-Induced Domain Shifts Undermine the Robustness of Pathology Foundation Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.04163</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.04163v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Pathology foundation models (PFMs) have become central to computational pathology, aiming to offer general encoders for feature extraction from whole-slide images (WSIs). Despite strong benchmark performance, PFM robustness to real-world technical domain shifts, such as variability from whole-slide scanner devices, remains poorly understood. We systematically evaluated the robustness of 14 PFMs to scanner-induced variability, including state-of-the-art models, earlier self-supervised models, and a baseline trained on natural images. Using a multiscanner dataset of 384 breast cancer WSIs scanned on five devices, we isolated scanner effects independently from biological and laboratory confounders. Robustness is assessed via complementary unsupervised embedding analyses and a set of clinicopathological supervised prediction tasks. Our results demonstrate that current PFMs are not invariant to scanner-induced domain shifts. Most models encode pronounced scanner-specific variability in their embedding spaces. While AUC often remains stable, this masks a critical failure mode: scanner variability systematically alters the embedding space and impacts calibration of downstream model predictions, resulting in scanner-dependent bias that can impact reliability in clinical use cases. We further show that robustness is not a simple function of training data scale, model size, or model recency. None of the models provided reliable robustness against scanner-induced variability. While the models trained on the most diverse data, here represented by vision-language models, appear to have an advantage with respect to robustness, they underperformed on downstream supervised tasks. We conclude that development and evaluation of PFMs requires moving beyond accuracy-centric benchmarks toward explicit evaluation and optimisation of embedding stability and calibration under realistic acquisition variability.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.04163v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Erik Thiringer, Fredrik K. Gustafsson, Kajsa Ledesma Eriksson, Mattias Rantalainen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generalized Logit Adjustment: Calibrating Fine-tuned Models by Removing Label Bias in Foundation Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.08106</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.08106v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Foundation models like CLIP allow zero-shot transfer on various tasks without additional training data. Yet, the zero-shot performance is less competitive than a fully supervised one. Thus, to enhance the performance, fine-tuning and ensembling are also commonly adopted to better fit the downstream tasks. However, we argue that such prior work has overlooked the inherent biases in foundation models. Due to the highly imbalanced Web-scale training set, these foundation models are inevitably skewed toward frequent semantics, and thus the subsequent fine-tuning or ensembling is still biased. In this study, we systematically examine the biases in foundation models and demonstrate the efficacy of our proposed Generalized Logit Adjustment (GLA) method. Note that bias estimation in foundation models is challenging, as most pre-train data cannot be explicitly accessed like in traditional long-tailed classification tasks. To this end, GLA has an optimization-based bias estimation approach for debiasing foundation models. As our work resolves a fundamental flaw in the pre-training, the proposed GLA demonstrates significant improvements across a diverse range of tasks: it achieves 1.5 pp accuracy gains on ImageNet, an large average improvement (1.4-4.6 pp) on 11 few-shot datasets, 2.4 pp gains on long-tailed classification. Codes are in https://github.com/BeierZhu/GLA.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.08106v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Beier Zhu, Kaihua Tang, Qianru Sun, Hanwang Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient 3D affinely equivariant CNNs with adaptive fusion of augmented spherical Fourier-Bessel bases</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16825</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.16825v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Filter-decomposition-based group equivariant convolutional neural networks (CNNs) have shown promising stability and data efficiency for 3D image feature extraction. However, these networks, which rely on parameter sharing and discrete transformation groups, often underperform in modern deep neural network architectures for processing volumetric images with dense 3D textures, such as the common 3D medical images. To address these limitations, this paper presents an efficient non-parameter-sharing continuous 3D affine group equivariant neural network for volumetric images. This network uses an adaptive aggregation of Monte Carlo augmented spherical Fourier-Bessel filter bases to improve the efficiency and flexibility of 3D group equivariant CNNs for volumetric data. Unlike existing methods that focus only on angular orthogonality in filter bases, the introduced spherical Bessel Fourier filter base incorporates both angular and radial orthogonality to improve feature extraction. Experiments on four medical image segmentation datasets and two seismic datasets show that the proposed methods achieve better affine group equivariance and superior segmentation accuracy than existing 3D group equivariant convolutional neural network layers, significantly improving the training stability and data efficiency of conventional CNN layers (at 0.05 significance level). The code is available at https://github.com/ZhaoWenzhao/WMCSFB.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.16825v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenzhao Zhao, Steffen Albert, Barbara D. Wichtmann, Angelika Maurer, Ulrike Attenberger, Frank G. Z\"ollner, J\"urgen Hesser</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Point Cloud Synthesis Using Inner Product Transforms</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.18987</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.18987v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Point cloud synthesis, i.e. the generation of novel point clouds from an input distribution, remains a challenging task, for which numerous complex machine learning models have been devised. We develop a novel method that encodes geometrical-topological characteristics of point clouds using inner products, leading to a highly-efficient point cloud representation with provable expressivity properties. Integrated into deep learning models, our encoding exhibits high quality in typical tasks like reconstruction, generation, and interpolation, with inference times orders of magnitude faster than existing methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.18987v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ernst R\"oell, Bastian Rieck</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Difficulty Controlled Diffusion Model for Synthesizing Effective Training Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.18109</link>
      <description>arXiv:2411.18109v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Generative models have become a powerful tool for synthesizing training data in computer vision tasks. Current approaches solely focus on aligning generated images with the target dataset distribution. As a result, they capture only the common features in the real dataset and mostly generate 'easy samples', which are already well learned by models trained on real data. In contrast, those rare 'hard samples', with atypical features but crucial for enhancing performance, cannot be effectively generated. Consequently, these approaches must synthesize large volumes of data to yield appreciable performance gains, yet the improvement remains limited. To overcome this limitation, we present a novel method that can learn to control the learning difficulty of samples during generation while also achieving domain alignment. Thus, it can efficiently generate valuable 'hard samples' that yield significant performance improvements for target tasks. This is achieved by incorporating learning difficulty as an additional conditioning signal in generative models, together with a designed encoder structure and training-generation strategy. Experimental results across multiple datasets show that our method can achieve higher performance with lower generation cost. Specifically, we obtain the best performance with only 10% additional synthetic data, saving 63.4 GPU hours of generation time compared to the previous SOTA on ImageNet. Moreover, our method provides insightful visualizations of category-specific hard factors, serving as a tool for analyzing datasets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2411.18109v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zerun Wang, Jiafeng Mao, Xueting Wang, Toshihiko Yamasaki</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BiPO: Bidirectional Partial Occlusion Network for Text-to-Motion Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.00112</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.00112v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Generating natural and expressive human motions from textual descriptions is challenging due to the complexity of coordinating full-body dynamics and capturing nuanced motion patterns over extended sequences that accurately reflect the given text. To address this, we introduce BiPO, Bidirectional Partial Occlusion Network for Text-to-Motion Synthesis, a novel model that enhances text-to-motion synthesis by integrating part-based generation with a bidirectional autoregressive architecture. This integration allows BiPO to consider both past and future contexts during generation while enhancing detailed control over individual body parts without requiring ground-truth motion length. To relax the interdependency among body parts caused by the integration, we devise the Partial Occlusion technique, which probabilistically occludes the certain motion part information during training. In our comprehensive experiments, BiPO achieves state-of-the-art performance on the HumanML3D dataset, outperforming recent methods such as ParCo, MoMask, and BAMM in terms of FID scores and overall motion quality. Notably, BiPO excels not only in the text-to-motion generation task but also in motion editing tasks that synthesize motion based on partially generated motion sequences and textual descriptions. These results reveal the BiPO's effectiveness in advancing text-to-motion synthesis and its potential for practical applications.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.00112v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Seong-Eun Hong, Soobin Lim, Juyeong Hwang, Minwook Chang, Hyeongyeop Kang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video LLMs for Temporal Reasoning in Long Videos</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02930</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.02930v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We introduce TemporalVLM, a video large language model (video LLM) for temporal reasoning and fine-grained understanding in long videos. Our approach includes a visual encoder for mapping a long-term video into features which are time-aware and contain both local and global cues. It first divides an input video into short-term clips, which are jointly encoded with timestamps and fused across overlapping temporal windows into time-sensitive local features. Next, the local features are passed through a bidirectional long short-term memory (BiLSTM) module for global feature aggregation. Moreover, to facilitate the evaluation of TemporalVLM, we present a large-scale long video dataset of industry assembly processes, namely IndustryASM, consisting of videos recorded on factory floors with actions and timestamps annotated by industrial engineers for time and motion studies and temporal action segmentation evaluation. Finally, extensive experiments show that TemporalVLM outperforms previous methods across temporal reasoning and fine-grained understanding tasks, i.e., dense video captioning, temporal video grounding, video highlight detection, and temporal action segmentation. To our best knowledge, our work is the first to incorporate LSTMs into video LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.02930v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fawad Javed Fateh, Umer Ahmed, Hamza Khan, M. Zeeshan Zia, Quoc-Huy Tran</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PhysDepth: Plug-and-Play Physical Refinement for Monocular Depth Estimation in Challenging Environments</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.04666</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.04666v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: State-of-the-art monocular depth estimation (MDE) models often struggle in challenging environments, primarily because they overlook robust physical information. To demonstrate this, we first conduct an empirical study by computing the covariance between a model's prediction error and atmospheric attenuation. We find that the error of existing SOTAs increases with atmospheric attenuation. Based on this finding, we propose PhysDepth, a plug-and-play framework that solves this fragility by infusing physical priors into modern SOTA backbones. PhysDepth incorporates two key components: a Physical Prior Module (PPM) that leverages Rayleigh Scattering theory to extract robust features from the high-SNR red channel, and a physics-derived Red Channel Attenuation Loss (RCA) that enforces model to learn the Beer-Lambert law. Extensive evaluations demonstrate that PhysDepth achieves SOTA accuracy in challenging conditions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.04666v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kebin Peng, Haotang Li, Zhenyu Qi, Huashan Chen, Zi Wang, Wei Zhang, Sen He, Huanrui Yang, Qing Guo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mitigating Label Noise using Prompt-Based Hyperbolic Meta-Learning in Open-Set Domain Generalization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.18342</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.18342v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Open-Set Domain Generalization (OSDG) is a challenging task requiring models to accurately predict familiar categories while minimizing confidence for unknown categories to effectively reject them in unseen domains. While the OSDG field has seen considerable advancements, the impact of label noise--a common issue in real-world datasets--has been largely overlooked. Label noise can mislead model optimization, thereby exacerbating the challenges of open-set recognition in novel domains. In this study, we take the first step towards addressing Open-Set Domain Generalization under Noisy Labels (OSDG-NL) by constructing dedicated benchmarks derived from widely used OSDG datasets, including PACS and DigitsDG. We evaluate baseline approaches by integrating techniques from both label denoising and OSDG methodologies, highlighting the limitations of existing strategies in handling label noise effectively. To address these limitations, we propose HyProMeta, a novel framework that integrates hyperbolic category prototypes for label noise-aware meta-learning alongside a learnable new-category agnostic prompt designed to enhance generalization to unseen classes. Our extensive experiments demonstrate the superior performance of HyProMeta compared to state-of-the-art methods across the newly established benchmarks. The source code of this work is released at https://github.com/KPeng9510/HyProMeta.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.18342v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kunyu Peng, Di Wen, M. Saquib Sarfraz, Yufan Chen, Junwei Zheng, David Schneider, Kailun Yang, Jiamin Wu, Alina Roitberg, Rainer Stiefelhagen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Novel Convolution and Attention Mechanism-based Model for 6D Object Pose Estimation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01993</link>
      <description>arXiv:2501.01993v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper proposes PoseLecTr, a graph-based encoder-decoder framework that integrates a novel Legendre convolution with attention mechanisms for six-degree-of-freedom (6-DOF) object pose estimation from monocular RGB images. Conventional learning-based approaches predominantly rely on grid-structured convolutions, which can limit their ability to model higher-order and long-range dependencies among image features, especially in cluttered or occluded scenes. PoseLecTr addresses this limitation by constructing a graph representation from image features, where spatial relationships are explicitly modeled through graph connectivity. The proposed framework incorporates a Legendre convolution layer to improve numerical stability in graph convolution, together with spatial-attention and self-attention distillation to enhance feature selection. Experiments conducted on the LINEMOD, Occluded LINEMOD, and YCB-VIDEO datasets demonstrate that our method achieves competitive performance and shows consistent improvements across a wide range of objects and scene complexities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2501.01993v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alexander Du, Xiujin Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FairT2I: Mitigating Social Bias in Text-to-Image Generation via Large Language Model-Assisted Detection and Attribute Rebalancing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.03826</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.03826v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Text-to-image (T2I) models have advanced creative content generation, yet their reliance on large uncurated datasets often reproduces societal biases. We present FairT2I, a training-free and interactive framework grounded in a mathematically principled latent variable guidance formulation. This formulation decomposes the generative score function into attribute-conditioned components and reweights them according to a defined distribution, providing a unified and flexible mechanism for bias-aware generation that also subsumes many existing ad hoc debiasing approaches as special cases. Building upon this foundation, FairT2I incorporates (1) latent variable guidance as the core mechanism, (2) LLM-based bias detection to automatically infer bias-prone categories and attributes from text prompts as part of the latent structure, and (3) attribute resampling, which allows users to adjust or redefine the attribute distribution based on uniform, real-world, or user-specified statistics. The accompanying user interface supports this pipeline by enabling users to inspect detected biases, modify attributes or weights, and generate debiased images in real time. Experimental results show that LLMs outperform average human annotators in the number and granularity of detected bias categories and attributes. Moreover, FairT2I achieves superior performance to baseline models in both societal bias mitigation and image diversity, while preserving image quality and prompt fidelity.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.03826v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jinya Sakurai, Yuki Koyama, Issei Sato</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deflickering Vision-Based Occupancy Networks through Lightweight Spatio-Temporal Correlation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.15438</link>
      <description>arXiv:2502.15438v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Vision-based occupancy networks (VONs) provide an end-to-end solution for reconstructing 3D environments in autonomous driving. However, existing methods often suffer from temporal inconsistencies, manifesting as flickering effects that degrade temporal coherence and adversely affect downstream decision-making. While recent approaches incorporate historical information to alleviate this issue, they often incur high computational costs and may introduce misaligned or redundant features that interfere with object detection. We propose OccLinker, a novel plugin framework that can be easily integrated into existing VONs to improve performance. Our method efficiently consolidates historical static and motion cues, learns sparse latent correlations with current features through a dual cross-attention mechanism, and generates correction occupancy components to refine the base network predictions. In addition, we introduce a new temporal consistency metric to quantitatively measure flickering effects. Extensive experiments on two benchmark datasets demonstrate that our method achieves superior performance with minimal computational overhead while effectively reducing flickering artifacts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2502.15438v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Fengcheng Yu, Haoran Xu, Canming Xia, Ziyang Zong, Guang Tan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U-REPA: Aligning Diffusion U-Nets to ViTs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.18414</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.18414v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Representation Alignment (REPA) that aligns Diffusion Transformer (DiT) hidden-states with ViT visual encoders has proven highly effective in DiT training, demonstrating superior convergence properties, but it has not been validated on the canonical diffusion U-Net architecture that shows faster convergence compared to DiTs. However, adapting REPA to U-Net architectures presents unique challenges: (1) different block functionalities necessitate revised alignment strategies; (2) spatial-dimension inconsistencies emerge from U-Net's spatial downsampling operations; (3) space gaps between U-Net and ViT hinder the effectiveness of tokenwise alignment. To encounter these challenges, we propose \textbf{U-REPA}, a representation alignment paradigm that bridges U-Net hidden states and ViT features as follows: Firstly, we propose via observation that due to skip connection, the middle stage of U-Net is the best alignment option. Secondly, we propose upsampling of U-Net features after passing them through MLPs. Thirdly, we observe difficulty when performing tokenwise similarity alignment, and further introduces a manifold loss that regularizes the relative similarity between samples. Experiments indicate that the resulting U-REPA could achieve excellent generation quality and greatly accelerates the convergence speed. With CFG guidance interval, U-REPA could reach $FID&lt;1.5$ in 200 epochs or 1M iterations on ImageNet 256 $\times$ 256, and needs only half the total epochs to perform better than REPA under sd-vae-ft-ema. Codes: https://github.com/YuchuanTian/U-REPA</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.18414v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>NeurIPS 2025</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Yuchuan Tian, Hanting Chen, Mengyu Zheng, Yuchen Liang, Chao Xu, Yunhe Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PM4Bench: Benchmarking Large Vision-Language Models with Parallel Multilingual Multi-Modal Multi-task Corpus</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.18484</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.18484v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: While Large Vision-Language Models (LVLMs) demonstrate promising multilingual capabilities, their evaluation is currently hindered by two critical limitations: (1) the use of non-parallel corpora, which conflates inherent language capability gaps with dataset artifacts, precluding a fair assessment of cross-lingual alignment; and (2) disjointed multimodal inputs, which deviate from real-world scenarios where most texts are embedded within visual contexts. To address these challenges, we propose PM4Bench, the first Multilingual Multi-Modal Multi-task Benchmark constructed on a strictly parallel corpus across 10 languages. By eliminating content divergence, our benchmark enables a fair comparison of model capabilities across different languages. We also introduce a vision setting where textual queries are visually fused into images, compelling models to jointly "see," "read," and "think". Extensive evaluation of 10 LVLMs uncover a substantial performance drop in the Vision setting compared to standard inputs. Further analysis reveals that OCR capability is not only a general bottleneck but also contributes to cross-lingual performance disparities, suggesting that improving multilingual OCR is essential for advancing LVLM performance. We will release PM4Bench at https://github.com/opendatalab/PM4Bench .</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.18484v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junyuan Gao, Jiahe Song, Jiang Wu, Runchuan Zhu, Guanlin Shen, Shasha Wang, Xingjian Wei, Haote Yang, Songyang Zhang, Weijia Li, Bin Wang, Dahua Lin, Lijun Wu, Conghui He</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Resolution Generalization of Diffusion Transformers with Randomized Positional Encodings</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.18719</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.18719v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Resolution generalization in image generation tasks enables the production of higher-resolution images with lower training resolution overhead. However, a key obstacle for diffusion transformers in addressing this problem is the mismatch between positional encodings seen at inference and those used during training. Existing strategies such as positional encodings interpolation, extrapolation, or hybrids, do not fully resolve this mismatch. In this paper, we propose a novel two-dimensional randomized positional encodings, namely RPE-2D, that prioritizes the order of image patches rather than their absolute distances, enabling seamless high- and low-resolution generation without training on multiple resolutions. Concretely, RPE-2D independently samples positions along the horizontal and vertical axes over an expanded range during training, ensuring that the encodings used at inference lie within the training distribution and thereby improving resolution generalization. We further introduce a simple random resize-and-crop augmentation to strengthen order modeling and add micro-conditioning to indicate the applied cropping pattern. On the ImageNet dataset, RPE-2D achieves state-of-the-art resolution generalization performance, outperforming competitive methods when trained at $256^2$ and evaluated at $384^2$ and $512^2$, and when trained at $512^2$ and evaluated at $768^2$ and $1024^2$. RPE-2D also exhibits outstanding capabilities in low-resolution image generation, multi-stage training acceleration, and multi-resolution inheritance.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.18719v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Liang Hou, Cong Liu, Mingwu Zheng, Xin Tao, Pengfei Wan, Di Zhang, Kun Gai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VisualCloze: A Universal Image Generation Framework via Visual In-Context Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.07960</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.07960v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent progress in diffusion models significantly advances various image generation tasks. However, the current mainstream approach remains focused on building task-specific models, which have limited efficiency when supporting a wide range of different needs. While universal models attempt to address this limitation, they face critical challenges, including generalizable task instruction, appropriate task distributions, and unified architectural design. To tackle these challenges, we propose VisualCloze, a universal image generation framework, which supports a wide range of in-domain tasks, generalization to unseen ones, unseen unification of multiple tasks, and reverse generation. Unlike existing methods that rely on language-based task instruction, leading to task ambiguity and weak generalization, we integrate visual in-context learning, allowing models to identify tasks from visual demonstrations. Meanwhile, the inherent sparsity of visual task distributions hampers the learning of transferable knowledge across tasks. To this end, we introduce Graph200K, a graph-structured dataset that establishes various interrelated tasks, enhancing task density and transferable knowledge. Furthermore, we uncover that our unified image generation formulation shared a consistent objective with image infilling, enabling us to leverage the strong generative priors of pre-trained infilling models without modifying the architectures.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.07960v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhong-Yu Li, Ruoyi Du, Juncheng Yan, Le Zhuo, Qilong Wu, Zhen Li, Peng Gao, Zhanyu Ma, Ming-Ming Cheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VISTA: Mitigating Semantic Inertia in Video-LLMs via Training-Free Dynamic Chain-of-Thought Routing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.11830</link>
      <description>arXiv:2505.11830v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advancements in Large Language Models have successfully transitioned towards System 2 reasoning, yet applying these paradigms to video understanding remains challenging. While prevailing research attributes failures in Video-LLMs to perceptual limitations, our empirical analysis reveals a cognitive misalignment termed Semantic Inertia, where models suppress valid visual evidence in favor of dominant language priors. To rectify this, we propose VISTA, a training-free framework designed to align perception with logical deduction. By dynamically routing inference paths and materializing implicit visual features into explicit textual anchors, our approach effectively counterbalances the influence of parametric knowledge. Furthermore, we incorporate a Latent Reasoning Consensus mechanism to mitigate stochastic hallucinations. VISTA showed outstanding results on a wide range of benchmarks, and outperforms its base model by 9.3% on Egochema and 5.6% on VideoEspresso, rivalling or even surpassing larger and proprietary models. Our codebase will be publicly available soon.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2505.11830v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hongbo Jin, Jiayu Ding, Siyi Xie, Guibo Luo, Ge Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adapting Vision-Language Foundation Model for Next Generation Medical Ultrasound Image Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.08849</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.08849v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Vision-Language Models (VLMs) have demonstrated remarkable generalization capabilities, yet their application to medical ultrasound remains constrained by the significant domain shift between natural images and sonographic data. The unique physics of ultrasound, manifesting as speckle noise, shadowing, and variable artifacts, often leads to suboptimal performance when applying off-the-shelf foundation models. To address this, we propose a novel Hybrid-tuning (HT) strategy for the efficient adaptation of CLIP-based models to ultrasound analysis. Our method introduces a lightweight adapter module integrated into the frozen visual backbone, featuring frequency-domain filtering to suppress periodic artifacts and dynamic noise estimation to calibrate feature representations. Furthermore, we design specialized segmentation and classification heads that employ multi-scale feature aggregation to maximize the utility of pre-trained semantic priors. Extensive evaluations across six multi-center datasets (covering lymph nodes, breast, thyroid, and prostate) reveal that our HT-enhanced models significantly outperform existing state-of-the-art methods, including BiomedCLIP and standard LoRA fine-tuning. The results highlight the superior data efficiency and robustness of our approach, paving the way for practical, foundational intelligence in automated ultrasound diagnosis. The source code is available at https://github.com/jinggqu/NextGen-UIA.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.08849v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jingguo Qu, Xinyang Han, Jia Ai, Juan Wu, Tong Zhao, Tonghuan Xiao, Sheng Ning, Yuqi Yang, Jing Qin, Ann Dorothy King, Winnie Chiu-Wing Chu, Jing Cai, Michael Tin-Cheung Ying</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MoTE: Mixture of Ternary Experts for Memory-efficient Large Multimodal Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.14435</link>
      <description>arXiv:2506.14435v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large multimodal Mixture-of-Experts (MoEs) effectively scale the model size to boost performance while maintaining fixed active parameters. However, previous works primarily utilized full-precision experts during sparse up-cycling. Despite they show superior performance on end tasks, the large amount of experts introduces higher memory footprint, which poses significant challenges for the deployment on edge devices. In this work, we propose MoTE, a scalable and memory-efficient approach to train Mixture-of-Ternary-Experts models from dense checkpoint. Instead of training fewer high-precision experts, we propose to train more low-precision experts during up-cycling. Specifically, we use the pre-trained FFN as a shared expert and train ternary routed experts with parameters in {-1, 0, 1}. Extensive experiments show that our approach has promising scaling trend along model size. MoTE achieves comparable performance to full-precision baseline MoE-LLaVA while offering lower memory footprint. Furthermore, our approach is compatible with post-training quantization methods and the advantage further amplifies when memory-constraint goes lower. Given the same amount of expert memory footprint of 3.4GB and combined with post-training quantization, MoTE outperforms MoE-LLaVA by a gain of 4.3% average accuracy on end tasks, demonstrating its effectiveness and potential for memory-constrained devices.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2506.14435v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hongyu Wang, Jiayu Xu, Ruiping Wang, Yan Feng, Yitao Zhai, Peng Pei, Xunliang Cai, Xilin Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking Content-Based Puzzle Solvers on Corrupted Jigsaw Puzzles</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.07828</link>
      <description>arXiv:2507.07828v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Content-based puzzle solvers have been extensively studied, demonstrating significant progress in computational techniques. However, their evaluation often lacks realistic challenges crucial for real-world applications, such as the reassembly of fragmented artefacts or shredded documents. In this work, we investigate the robustness of State-Of-The-Art content-based puzzle solvers introducing three types of jigsaw puzzle corruptions: missing pieces, eroded edges, and eroded contents. Evaluating both heuristic and deep learning-based solvers, we analyse their ability to handle these corruptions and identify key limitations. Our results show that solvers developed for standard puzzles have a rapid decline in performance if more pieces are corrupted. However, deep learning models can significantly improve their robustness through fine-tuning with augmented data. Notably, the advanced Positional Diffusion model adapts particularly well, outperforming its competitors in most experiments. Based on our findings, we highlight promising research directions for enhancing the automated reconstruction of real-world artefacts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2507.07828v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1007/978-3-032-10185-3_23</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>ICIAP 2025, Lecture Notes in Computer Science 16167 (2026) pp 286-298</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Richard Dirauf, Florian Wolz, Dario Zanca, Bj\"orn Eskofier</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sortblock: Similarity-Aware Feature Reuse for Diffusion Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.00412</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.00412v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Diffusion Transformers (DiTs) have demonstrated remarkable generative capabilities, particularly benefiting from Transformer architectures that enhance visual and artistic fidelity. However, their inherently sequential denoising process results in high inference latency, limiting their deployment in real-time scenarios. Existing training-free acceleration approaches typically reuse intermediate features at fixed timesteps or layers, overlooking the evolving semantic focus across denoising stages and Transformer blocks.To address this, we propose Sortblock, a training-free inference acceleration framework that dynamically caches block-wise features based on their similarity across adjacent timesteps. By ranking the evolution of residuals, Sortblock adaptively determines a recomputation ratio, selectively skipping redundant computations while preserving generation quality. Furthermore, we incorporate a lightweight linear prediction mechanism to reduce accumulated errors in skipped blocks.Extensive experiments across various tasks and DiT architectures demonstrate that Sortblock achieves over 2$\times$ inference speedup with minimal degradation in output quality, offering an effective and generalizable solution for accelerating diffusion-based generative models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.00412v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hanqi Chen, Xu Zhang, Xiaoliu Guan, Lielin Jiang, Guanzhong Wang, Zeyu Chen, Yi Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ViMoNet: A Multimodal Vision-Language Framework for Human Behavior Understanding from Motion and Video</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.09818</link>
      <description>arXiv:2508.09818v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This study investigates the use of large language models (LLMs) for human behavior understanding by jointly leveraging motion and video data. We argue that integrating these complementary modalities is essential for capturing both fine-grained motion dynamics and contextual semantics of human actions, addressing the limitations of prior motion-only or video-only approaches. To this end, we propose ViMoNet, a multimodal vision-language framework trained through a two-stage alignment and instruction-tuning strategy that combines precise motion-text supervision with large-scale video-text data. We further introduce VIMOS, a multimodal dataset comprising human motion sequences, videos, and instruction-level annotations, along with ViMoNet-Bench, a standardized benchmark for evaluating behavior-centric reasoning. Experimental results demonstrate that ViMoNet consistently outperforms existing methods across caption generation, motion understanding, and human behavior interpretation tasks. The proposed framework shows significant potential in assistive healthcare applications, such as elderly monitoring, fall detection, and early identification of health risks in aging populations. This work contributes to the United Nations Sustainable Development Goal 3 (SDG 3: Good Health and Well-being) by enabling accessible AI-driven tools that promote universal health coverage, reduce preventable health issues, and enhance overall well-being.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2508.09818v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rajan Das Gupta, Lei Wei, Md Yeasin Rahat, Nafiz Fahad, Abir Ahmed, Liew Tze Hui</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where MLLMs Attend and What They Rely On: Explaining Autoregressive Token Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.22496</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.22496v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Multimodal large language models (MLLMs) have demonstrated remarkable capabilities in aligning visual inputs with natural language outputs. Yet, the extent to which generated tokens depend on visual modalities remains poorly understood, limiting interpretability and reliability. In this work, we present EAGLE, a lightweight black-box framework for explaining autoregressive token generation in MLLMs. EAGLE attributes any selected tokens to compact perceptual regions while quantifying the relative influence of language priors and perceptual evidence. The framework introduces an objective function that unifies sufficiency (insight score) and indispensability (necessity score), optimized via greedy search over sparsified image regions for faithful and efficient attribution. Beyond spatial attribution, EAGLE performs modality-aware analysis that disentangles what tokens rely on, providing fine-grained interpretability of model decisions. Extensive experiments across open-source MLLMs show that EAGLE consistently outperforms existing methods in faithfulness, localization, and hallucination diagnosis, while requiring substantially less GPU memory. These results highlight its effectiveness and practicality for advancing the interpretability of MLLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.22496v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ruoyu Chen, Xiaoqing Guo, Kangwei Liu, Siyuan Liang, Shiming Liu, Qunli Zhang, Laiyuan Wang, Hua Zhang, Xiaochun Cao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UniVideo: Unified Understanding, Generation, and Editing for Videos</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.08377</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.08377v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Unified multimodal models have shown promising results in multimodal content generation and editing but remain largely limited to the image domain. In this work, we present UniVideo, a versatile framework that extends unified modeling to the video domain. UniVideo adopts a dual-stream design, combining a Multimodal Large Language Model (MLLM) for instruction understanding with a Multimodal DiT (MMDiT) for video generation. This design preserves the MLLM's original text generation capabilities, enables accurate interpretation of complex multimodal instructions, and maintains visual consistency in the generated content. Built on this architecture, UniVideo unifies diverse video generation and editing tasks under a single multimodal instruction paradigm and is jointly trained across them. Extensive experiments demonstrate that UniVideo matches or surpasses state-of-the-art task-specific baselines in text/image-to-video generation, in-context video generation and in-context video editing. Notably, the unified design of UniVideo enables two forms of generalization. First, UniVideo supports task composition, such as combining editing with style transfer, by integrating multiple capabilities within a single instruction. Second, even without explicit training on free-form video editing, UniVideo transfers its editing capability from large-scale image editing data to this setting, handling unseen instructions such as changing the environment or altering materials within a video. Beyond these core capabilities, UniVideo also supports visual-prompt-based video generation, where the MLLM interprets visual prompts and guides the MMDiT during synthesis. To foster future research, we released our model and code.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.08377v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Cong Wei, Quande Liu, Zixuan Ye, Qiulin Wang, Xintao Wang, Pengfei Wan, Kun Gai, Wenhu Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semantic-E2VID: a Semantic-Enriched Paradigm for Event-to-Video Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.17347</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.17347v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Event cameras provide a promising sensing modality for high-speed and high-dynamic-range vision by asynchronously capturing brightness changes. A fundamental task in event-based vision is event-to-video (E2V) reconstruction, which aims to recover intensity videos from event streams. Most existing E2V approaches formulate reconstruction as a temporal--spatial signal recovery problem, relying on temporal aggregation and spatial feature learning to infer intensity frames. While effective to some extent, this formulation overlooks a critical limitation of event data: due to the change-driven sensing mechanism, event streams are inherently semantically under-determined, lacking object-level structure and contextual information that are essential for faithful reconstruction. In this work, we revisit E2V from a semantic perspective and argue that effective reconstruction requires going beyond temporal and spatial modeling to explicitly account for missing semantic information. Based on this insight, we propose \textit{Semantic-E2VID}, a semantic-enriched end-to-end E2V framework that reformulates reconstruction as a process of semantic learning, fusing and decoding. Our approach first performs semantic abstraction by bridging event representations with semantics extracted from a pretrained Segment Anything Model (SAM), while avoiding modality-induced feature drift. The learned semantics are then fused into the event latent space in a representation-compatible manner, enabling event features to capture object-level structure and contextual cues. Furthermore, semantic-aware supervision is introduced to explicitly guide the reconstruction process toward semantically meaningful regions, complementing conventional pixel-level and temporal objectives. Extensive experiments on six public benchmarks demonstrate that Semantic-E2VID consistently outperforms state-of-the-art E2V methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.17347v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jingqian Wu, Yunbo Jia, Shengpeng Xu, Edmund Y. Lam</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ProCLIP: Progressive Vision-Language Alignment via LLM-based Embedder</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.18795</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.18795v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The original CLIP text encoder is limited by a maximum input length of 77 tokens, which hampers its ability to effectively process long texts and perform fine-grained semantic understanding. In addition, the CLIP text encoder lacks support for multilingual inputs. All these limitations significantly restrict its applicability across a broader range of tasks. Recent studies have attempted to replace the CLIP text encoder with an LLM-based embedder to enhance its ability in processing long texts, multilingual understanding, and fine-grained semantic comprehension. However, because the representation spaces of LLMs and the vision-language space of CLIP are pretrained independently without alignment priors, direct alignment using contrastive learning can disrupt the intrinsic vision-language alignment in the CLIP image encoder, leading to an underutilization of the knowledge acquired during pre-training. To address this challenge, we propose ProCLIP, a curriculum learning-based progressive vision-language alignment framework to effectively align the CLIP image encoder with an LLM-based embedder. Specifically, ProCLIP first distills knowledge from CLIP's text encoder into the LLM-based embedder to leverage CLIP's rich pretrained knowledge while establishing initial alignment between the LLM embedder and CLIP image encoder. Subsequently, ProCLIP further aligns the CLIP image encoder with the LLM-based embedder through image-text contrastive tuning, employing self-distillation regularization to avoid overfitting. To achieve a more effective alignment, instance semantic alignment loss and embedding structure alignment loss are employed during representation inheritance and contrastive tuning. The Code is available at https://github.com/VisionXLab/ProCLIP.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.18795v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoxing Hu, Kaicheng Yang, Ziyang Gong, Qi Ming, Zonghao Guo, Yu Tian, Xiang An, Ziyong Feng, Xue Yang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>$\mathbf{S^2LM}$: Towards Semantic Steganography via Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.05319</link>
      <description>arXiv:2511.05319v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Despite remarkable progress in steganography, embedding semantically rich, sentence-level information into carriers remains a challenging problem. In this work, we present a novel concept of Semantic Steganography, which aims to hide semantically meaningful and structured content, such as sentences or paragraphs, in cover media. Based on this concept, we present Sentence-to-Image Steganography as an instance that enables the hiding of arbitrary sentence-level messages within a cover image. To accomplish this feat, we propose S^2LM: Semantic Steganographic Language Model, which leverages large language models (LLMs) to embed high-level textual information into images. Unlike traditional bit-level approaches, S^2LM redesigns the entire pipeline, involving the LLM throughout the process to enable the hiding and recovery of arbitrary sentences. Furthermore, we establish a benchmark named Invisible Text (IVT), comprising a diverse set of sentence-level texts as secret messages to evaluate semantic steganography methods. Experimental results demonstrate that S^2LM effectively enables direct sentence recovery beyond bit-level steganography. The source code and IVT dataset will be released soon.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2511.05319v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Huanqi Wu, Huangbiao Xu, Runfeng Xie, Jiaxin Cai, Kaixin Zhang, Xiao Ke</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multivariate Diffusion Transformer with Decoupled Attention for High-Fidelity Mask-Text Collaborative Facial Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.12631</link>
      <description>arXiv:2511.12631v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: While significant progress has been achieved in multimodal facial generation using semantic masks and textual descriptions, conventional feature fusion approaches often fail to enable effective cross-modal interactions, thereby leading to suboptimal generation outcomes. To address this challenge, we introduce MDiTFace--a customized diffusion transformer framework that employs a unified tokenization strategy to process semantic mask and text inputs, eliminating discrepancies between heterogeneous modality representations. The framework facilitates comprehensive multimodal feature interaction through stacked, newly designed multivariate transformer blocks that process all conditions synchronously. Additionally, we design a novel decoupled attention mechanism by dissociating implicit dependencies between mask tokens and temporal embeddings. This mechanism segregates internal computations into dynamic and static pathways, enabling caching and reuse of features computed in static pathways after initial calculation, thereby reducing additional computational overhead introduced by mask condition by over 94% while maintaining performance. Extensive experiments demonstrate that MDiTFace significantly outperforms other competing methods in terms of both facial fidelity and conditional consistency.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2511.12631v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yushe Cao, Dianxi Shi, Xing Fu, Xuechao Zou, Haikuo Peng, Xueqi Li, Chun Yu, Junliang Xing</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back to Basics: Let Denoising Generative Models Denoise</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.13720</link>
      <description>arXiv:2511.13720v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Today's denoising diffusion models do not "denoise" in the classical sense, i.e., they do not directly predict clean images. Rather, the neural networks predict noise or a noised quantity. In this paper, we suggest that predicting clean data and predicting noised quantities are fundamentally different. According to the manifold assumption, natural data should lie on a low-dimensional manifold, whereas noised quantities do not. With this assumption, we advocate for models that directly predict clean data, which allows apparently under-capacity networks to operate effectively in very high-dimensional spaces. We show that simple, large-patch Transformers on pixels can be strong generative models: using no tokenizer, no pre-training, and no extra loss. Our approach is conceptually nothing more than "Just image Transformers", or JiT, as we call it. We report competitive results using JiT with large patch sizes of 16 and 32 on ImageNet at resolutions of 256 and 512, where predicting high-dimensional noised quantities can fail catastrophically. With our networks mapping back to the basics of the manifold, our research goes back to basics and pursues a self-contained paradigm for Transformer-based diffusion on raw natural data.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2511.13720v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tianhong Li, Kaiming He</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generating Storytelling Images with Rich Chains-of-Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.07198</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.07198v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: A single image can convey a compelling story through logically connected visual clues, forming Chains-of-Reasoning (CoRs). We define these semantically rich images as Storytelling Images. By conveying multi-layered information that inspires active interpretation, these images enable a wide range of applications, such as illustration and cognitive screening. Despite their potential, such images are scarce and complex to create. To address this, we introduce the Storytelling Image Generation task and propose StorytellingPainter, a two-stage pipeline combining the reasoning of Large Language Models (LLMs) with Text-to-Image (T2I) synthesis. We also develop a dedicated evaluation framework assessing semantic complexity, diversity, and text-image alignment. Furthermore, given the critical role of story generation in the task, we introduce lightweight Mini-Storytellers to bridge the performance gap between small-scale and proprietary LLMs. Experimental results demonstrate the feasibility of our approaches.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.07198v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiujie Song, Qi Jia, Shota Watanabe, Xiaoyi Pang, Ruijie Chen, Mengyue Wu, Kenny Q. Zhu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do We Need Reformer for Vision? An Experimental Comparison with Vision Transformers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.11260</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.11260v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Transformers have recently demonstrated strong performance in computer vision, with Vision Transformers (ViTs) leveraging self-attention to capture both low-level and high-level image features. However, standard ViTs remain computationally expensive, since global self-attention scales quadratically with the number of tokens, which limits their practicality for high-resolution inputs and resource-constrained settings.
  In this work, we investigate the Reformer architecture as an alternative vision backbone. By combining patch-based tokenization with locality-sensitive hashing (LSH) attention, our model approximates global self-attention while reducing its theoretical time complexity from $\mathcal{O}(n^2)$ to $\mathcal{O}(n \log n)$ in the sequence length $n$. We evaluate the proposed Reformer-based vision model on CIFAR-10 to assess its behavior on small-scale datasets, on ImageNet-100 to study its accuracy--efficiency trade-off in a more realistic setting, and on a high-resolution medical imaging dataset to evaluate the model under longer token sequences.
  While the Reformer achieves higher accuracy on CIFAR-10 compared to our ViT-style baseline, the ViT model consistently outperforms the Reformer in our experiments in terms of practical efficiency and end-to-end computation time across the larger and higher-resolution settings. These results suggest that, despite the theoretical advantages of LSH-based attention, meaningful computation gains require sequence lengths substantially longer than those produced by typical high-resolution images.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.11260v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ali El Bellaj, Mohammed-Amine Cheddadi, Rhassan Berber</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Human Intention to Action Prediction: Intention-Driven End-to-End Autonomous Driving</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.12302</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.12302v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: While end-to-end autonomous driving has achieved remarkable progress in geometric control, current systems remain constrained by a command-following paradigm that relies on simple navigational instructions. Transitioning to genuinely intelligent agents requires the capability to interpret and fulfill high-level, abstract human intentions. However, this advancement is hindered by the lack of dedicated benchmarks and semantic-aware evaluation metrics. In this paper, we formally define the task of Intention-Driven End-to-End Autonomous Driving and present Intention-Drive, a comprehensive benchmark designed to bridge this gap. We construct a large-scale dataset featuring complex natural language intentions paired with high-fidelity sensor data. To overcome the limitations of conventional trajectory-based metrics, we introduce the Imagined Future Alignment (IFA), a novel evaluation protocol leveraging generative world models to assess the semantic fulfillment of human goals beyond mere geometric accuracy. Furthermore, we explore the solution space by proposing two distinct paradigms: an end-to-end vision-language planner and a hierarchical agent-based framework. The experiments reveal a critical dichotomy where existing models exhibit satisfactory driving stability but struggle significantly with intention fulfillment. Notably, the proposed frameworks demonstrate superior alignment with human intentions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.12302v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Huan Zheng, Yucheng Zhou, Tianyi Yan, Jiayi Su, Hongjun Chen, Dubing Chen, Xingtai Gui, Wencheng Han, Runzhou Tao, Zhongying Qiu, Jianfei Yang, Jianbing Shen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I-Scene: 3D Instance Models are Implicit Generalizable Spatial Learners</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.13683</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.13683v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Generalization remains the central challenge for interactive 3D scene generation. Existing learning-based approaches ground spatial understanding in limited scene dataset, restricting generalization to new layouts. We instead reprogram a pre-trained 3D instance generator to act as a scene level learner, replacing dataset-bounded supervision with model-centric spatial supervision. This reprogramming unlocks the generator transferable spatial knowledge, enabling generalization to unseen layouts and novel object compositions. Remarkably, spatial reasoning still emerges even when the training scenes are randomly composed objects. This demonstrates that the generator's transferable scene prior provides a rich learning signal for inferring proximity, support, and symmetry from purely geometric cues. Replacing widely used canonical space, we instantiate this insight with a view-centric formulation of the scene space, yielding a fully feed-forward, generalizable scene generator that learns spatial relations directly from the instance model. Quantitative and qualitative results show that a 3D instance generator is an implicit spatial learner and reasoner, pointing toward foundation models for interactive 3D scene understanding and generation. Project page: https://luling06.github.io/I-Scene-project/</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.13683v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lu Ling, Yunhao Ge, Yichen Sheng, Aniket Bera</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generative Refocusing: Flexible Defocus Control from a Single Image</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.16923</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.16923v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Depth-of-field control is essential in photography, but getting the perfect focus often takes several tries or special equipment. Single-image refocusing is still difficult. It involves recovering sharp content and creating realistic bokeh. Current methods have significant drawbacks. They need all-in-focus inputs, depend on synthetic data from simulators, and have limited control over aperture. We introduce Generative Refocusing, a two-step process that uses DeblurNet to recover all-in-focus images from various inputs and BokehNet for creating controllable bokeh. Our main innovation is semi-supervised training. This method combines synthetic paired data with unpaired real bokeh images, using EXIF metadata to capture real optical characteristics beyond what simulators can provide. Our experiments show we achieve top performance in defocus deblurring, bokeh synthesis, and refocusing benchmarks. Additionally, our Generative Refocusing allows text-guided adjustments and custom aperture shapes.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.16923v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chun-Wei Tuan Mu, Jia-Bin Huang, Yu-Lun Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>V-Agent: An Interactive Video Search System Using Vision-Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.16925</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.16925v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We introduce V-Agent, a novel multi-agent platform designed for advanced video search and interactive user-system conversations. By fine-tuning a vision-language model (VLM) with a small video preference dataset and enhancing it with a retrieval vector from an image-text retrieval model, we overcome the limitations of traditional text-based retrieval systems in multimodal scenarios. The VLM-based retrieval model independently embeds video frames and audio transcriptions from an automatic speech recognition (ASR) module into a shared multimodal representation space, enabling V-Agent to interpret both visual and spoken content for context-aware video search. This system consists of three agents-a routing agent, a search agent, and a chat agent-that work collaboratively to address user intents by refining search outputs and communicating with users. The search agent utilizes the VLM-based retrieval model together with an additional re-ranking module to further enhance video retrieval quality. Our proposed framework demonstrates state-of-the-art zero-shot performance on the MultiVENT 2.0 benchmark, highlighting its potential for both academic research and real-world applications. The retrieval model and demo videos are available at https://huggingface.co/NCSOFT/multimodal-embedding.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.16925v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>SunYoung Park, Jong-Hyeon Lee, Youngjune Kim, Daegyu Sung, Younghyun Yu, Young-rok Cha, Jeongho Ju</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep But Reliable: Advancing Multi-turn Reasoning for Thinking with Images</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.17306</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.17306v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advances in large Vision-Language Models (VLMs) have exhibited strong reasoning capabilities on complex visual tasks by thinking with images in their Chain-of-Thought (CoT), which is achieved by actively invoking tools to analyze visual inputs rather than merely perceiving them. However, existing models often struggle to reflect on and correct themselves when attempting incorrect reasoning trajectories. To address this limitation, we propose DRIM, a model that enables deep but reliable multi-turn reasoning when thinking with images in its multimodal CoT. Our pipeline comprises three stages: data construction, cold-start SFT and RL. Based on a high-resolution image dataset, we construct high-difficulty and verifiable visual question-answer pairs, where solving each task requires multi-turn tool calls to reach the correct answer. In the SFT stage, we collect tool trajectories as cold-start data, guiding a multi-turn reasoning pattern. In the RL stage, we introduce redundancy-penalized policy optimization, which incentivizes the model to develop a self-reflective reasoning pattern. The basic idea is to impose judgment on reasoning trajectories and penalize those that produce incorrect answers without sufficient multi-scale exploration. Extensive experiments demonstrate that DRIM achieves superior performance on visual understanding benchmarks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.17306v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenhao Yang, Yu Xia, Jinlong Huang, Shiyin Lu, Qing-Guo Chen, Zhao Xu, Weihua Luo, Kaifu Zhang, Yuanyu Wan, Lijun Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plasticine: A Traceable Diffusion Model for Medical Image Translation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.18455</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.18455v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Domain gaps arising from variations in imaging devices and population distributions pose significant challenges for machine learning in medical image analysis. Existing image-to-image translation methods primarily aim to learn mappings between domains, often generating diverse synthetic data with variations in anatomical scale and shape, but they usually overlook spatial correspondence during the translation process. For clinical applications, traceability, defined as the ability to provide pixel-level correspondences between original and translated images, is equally important. This property enhances clinical interpretability but has been largely overlooked in previous approaches. To address this gap, we propose Plasticine, which is, to the best of our knowledge, the first end-to-end image-to-image translation framework explicitly designed with traceability as a core objective. Our method combines intensity translation and spatial transformation within a denoising diffusion framework. This design enables the generation of synthetic images with interpretable intensity transitions and spatially coherent deformations, supporting pixel-wise traceability throughout the translation process.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.18455v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tianyang Zhang, Xinxing Cheng, Jun Cheng, Shaoming Zheng, He Zhao, Huazhu Fu, Alejandro F Frangi, Jiang Liu, Jinming Duan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SpatialTree: How Spatial Abilities Branch Out in MLLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20617</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.20617v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Cognitive science suggests that spatial ability develops progressively-from perception to reasoning and interaction. Yet in multimodal LLMs (MLLMs), this hierarchy remains poorly understood, as most studies focus on a narrow set of tasks. We introduce SpatialTree, a cognitive-science-inspired hierarchy that organizes spatial abilities into four levels: low-level perception (L1), mental mapping (L2), simulation (L3), and agentic competence (L4). Based on this taxonomy, we construct the first capability-centric hierarchical benchmark, thoroughly evaluating mainstream MLLMs across 27 sub-abilities. The evaluation results reveal a clear structure: L1 skills are largely orthogonal, whereas higher-level skills are strongly correlated, indicating increasing interdependency. Through targeted supervised fine-tuning, we uncover a surprising transfer dynamic-negative transfer within L1, but strong cross-level transfer from low- to high-level abilities with notable synergy. Finally, we explore how to improve the entire hierarchy. We find that naive RL that encourages extensive "thinking" is unreliable: it helps complex reasoning but hurts intuitive perception. We propose a simple auto-think strategy that suppresses unnecessary deliberation, enabling RL to consistently improve performance across all levels. By building SpatialTree, we provide a proof-of-concept framework for understanding and systematically scaling spatial abilities in MLLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.20617v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuxi Xiao, Longfei Li, Shen Yan, Xinhang Liu, Sida Peng, Yunchao Wei, Xiaowei Zhou, Bingyi Kang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data relativistic uncertainty framework for low-illumination anime scenery image enhancement</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21944</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.21944v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: By contrast with the prevailing works of low-light enhancement in natural images and videos, this study copes with the low-illumination quality degradation in anime scenery images to bridge the domain gap. For such an underexplored enhancement task, we first curate images from various sources and construct an unpaired anime scenery dataset with diverse environments and illumination conditions to address the data scarcity. To exploit the power of uncertainty information inherent with the diverse illumination conditions, we propose a Data Relativistic Uncertainty (DRU) framework, motivated by the idea from Relativistic GAN. By analogy with the wave-particle duality of light, our framework interpretably defines and quantifies the illumination uncertainty of dark/bright samples, which is leveraged to dynamically adjust the objective functions to recalibrate the model learning under data uncertainty. Extensive experiments demonstrate the effectiveness of DRU framework by training several versions of EnlightenGANs, yielding superior perceptual and aesthetic qualities beyond the state-of-the-art methods that are incapable of learning from data uncertainty perspective. We hope our framework can expose a novel paradigm of data-centric learning for potential visual and language domains. Code is available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.21944v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.MM</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yiquan Gao, John See</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Real-Time In-Cabin Driver Behavior Recognition on Low-Cost Edge Hardware</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.22298</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.22298v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In-cabin driver monitoring systems (DMS) must recognize distraction- and drowsiness-related behaviors with low latency under strict constraints on compute, power, and cost. We present a single-camera in-cabin driver behavior recognition system designed for deployment on two low-cost edge platforms: Raspberry Pi 5 (CPU-only) and the Google Coral development board with an Edge Tensor Processing Unit (Edge TPU) accelerator. The proposed pipeline combines (i) a compact per-frame vision model, (ii) a confounder-aware label taxonomy to reduce confusions among visually similar behaviors, and (iii) a temporal decision head that triggers alerts only when predictions are both confident and sustained. The system supports 17 behavior classes. Training and evaluation use licensed datasets plus in-house collection (over 800,000 labeled frames) with driver-disjoint splits, and we further validate the deployed system in live in-vehicle tests. End-to-end performance reaches approximately 16 FPS on Raspberry Pi 5 using 8-bit integer (INT8) inference (per-frame latency &lt;60 ms) and approximately 25 FPS on Coral Edge TPU (end-to-end latency ~40 ms), enabling real-time monitoring and stable alert generation on embedded hardware. Finally, we discuss how reliable in-cabin perception can serve as an upstream signal for human-centered vehicle intelligence, including emerging agentic vehicle concepts.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.22298v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Vesal Ahsani, Babak Hossein Khalaj, Hamed Shah-Mansouri</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VULCAN: Tool-Augmented Multi Agents for Iterative 3D Object Arrangement</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.22351</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.22351v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Despite the remarkable progress of Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) in 2D vision-language tasks, their application to complex 3D scene manipulation remains underexplored. In this paper, we bridge this critical gap by tackling three key challenges in 3D object arrangement task using MLLMs. First, to address the weak visual grounding of MLLMs, which struggle to link programmatic edits with precise 3D outcomes, we introduce an MCP-based API. This shifts the interaction from brittle raw code manipulation to more robust, function-level updates. Second, we augment the MLLM's 3D scene understanding with a suite of specialized visual tools to analyze scene state, gather spatial information, and validate action outcomes. This perceptual feedback loop is critical for closing the gap between language-based updates and precise 3D-aware manipulation. Third, to manage the iterative, error-prone updates, we propose a collaborative multi-agent framework with designated roles for planning, execution, and verification. This decomposition allows the system to robustly handle multi-step instructions and recover from intermediate errors. We demonstrate the effectiveness of our approach on a diverse set of 25 complex object arrangement tasks, where it significantly outperforms existing baselines. Website: vulcan-3d.github.io</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.22351v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhengfei Kuang, Rui Lin, Long Zhao, Gordon Wetzstein, Saining Xie, Sanghyun Woo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Language as Prior, Vision as Calibration: Metric Scale Recovery for Monocular Depth Estimation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.01457</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.01457v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Relative-depth foundation models transfer well, yet monocular metric depth remains ill-posed due to unidentifiable global scale and heightened domain-shift sensitivity. Under a frozen-backbone calibration setting, we recover metric depth via an image-specific affine transform in inverse depth and train only lightweight calibration heads while keeping the relative-depth backbone and the CLIP text encoder fixed. Since captions provide coarse but noisy scale cues that vary with phrasing and missing objects, we use language to predict an uncertainty-aware envelope that bounds feasible calibration parameters in an unconstrained space, rather than committing to a text-only point estimate. We then use pooled multi-scale frozen visual features to select an image-specific calibration within this envelope. During training, a closed-form least-squares oracle in inverse depth provides per-image supervision for learning the envelope and the selected calibration. Experiments on NYUv2 and KITTI improve in-domain accuracy, while zero-shot transfer to SUN-RGBD and DDAD demonstrates improved robustness over strong language-only baselines.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.01457v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mingxing Zhan, Li Zhang, Beibei Wang, Yingjie Wang, Zenglin Shi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FastV-RAG: Towards Fast and Fine-Grained Video QA with Retrieval-Augmented Generation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.01513</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.01513v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Vision-Language Models (VLMs) excel at visual reasoning but still struggle with integrating external knowledge. Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) is a promising solution, but current methods remain inefficient and often fail to maintain high answer quality. To address these challenges, we propose VideoSpeculateRAG, an efficient VLM-based RAG framework built on two key ideas. First, we introduce a speculative decoding pipeline: a lightweight draft model quickly generates multiple answer candidates, which are then verified and refined by a more accurate heavyweight model, substantially reducing inference latency without sacrificing correctness. Second, we identify a major source of error - incorrect entity recognition in retrieved knowledge - and mitigate it with a simple yet effective similarity-based filtering strategy that improves entity alignment and boosts overall answer accuracy. Experiments demonstrate that VideoSpeculateRAG achieves comparable or higher accuracy than standard RAG approaches while accelerating inference by approximately 2x. Our framework highlights the potential of combining speculative decoding with retrieval-augmented reasoning to enhance efficiency and reliability in complex, knowledge-intensive multimodal tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.01513v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gen Li, Peiyu Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SortWaste: A Densely Annotated Dataset for Object Detection in Industrial Waste Sorting</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.02299</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.02299v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The increasing production of waste, driven by population growth, has created challenges in managing and recycling materials effectively. Manual waste sorting is a common practice; however, it remains inefficient for handling large-scale waste streams and presents health risks for workers. On the other hand, existing automated sorting approaches still struggle with the high variability, clutter, and visual complexity of real-world waste streams. The lack of real-world datasets for waste sorting is a major reason automated systems for this problem are underdeveloped. Accordingly, we introduce SortWaste, a densely annotated object detection dataset collected from a Material Recovery Facility. Additionally, we contribute to standardizing waste detection in sorting lines by proposing ClutterScore, an objective metric that gauges the scene's hardness level using a set of proxies that affect visual complexity (e.g., object count, class and size entropy, and spatial overlap). In addition to these contributions, we provide an extensive benchmark of state-of-the-art object detection models, detailing their results with respect to the hardness level assessed by the proposed metric. Despite achieving promising results (mAP of 59.7% in the plastic-only detection task), performance significantly decreases in highly cluttered scenes. This highlights the need for novel and more challenging datasets on the topic.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.02299v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sara In\'acio, Hugo Proen\c{c}a, Jo\~ao C. Neves</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BEDS : Bayesian Emergent Dissipative Structures : A Formal Framework for Continuous Inference Under Energy Constraints</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.02329</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.02329v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We introduce BEDS (Bayesian Emergent Dissipative Structures), a formal framework for analyzing inference systems that must maintain beliefs continuously under energy constraints. Unlike classical computational models that assume perfect memory and focus on one-shot computation, BEDS explicitly incorporates dissipation (information loss over time) as a fundamental constraint.
  We prove a central result linking energy, precision, and dissipation: maintaining a belief with precision $\tau$ against dissipation rate $\gamma$ requires power $P \geq \gamma k_{\rm B} T / 2$, with scaling $P \propto \gamma \cdot \tau$. This establishes a fundamental thermodynamic cost for continuous inference.
  We define three classes of problems -- BEDS-attainable, BEDS-maintainable, and BEDS-crystallizable -- and show these are distinct from classical decidability. We propose the G\"odel-Landauer-Prigogine conjecture, suggesting that closure pathologies across formal systems, computation, and thermodynamics share a common structure.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.02329v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Laurent Caraffa</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HOLO: Homography-Guided Pose Estimator Network for Fine-Grained Visual Localization on SD Maps</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.02730</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.02730v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Visual localization on standard-definition (SD) maps has emerged as a promising low-cost and scalable solution for autonomous driving. However, existing regression-based approaches often overlook inherent geometric priors, resulting in suboptimal training efficiency and limited localization accuracy. In this paper, we propose a novel homography-guided pose estimator network for fine-grained visual localization between multi-view images and standard-definition (SD) maps. We construct input pairs that satisfy a homography constraint by projecting ground-view features into the BEV domain and enforcing semantic alignment with map features. Then we leverage homography relationships to guide feature fusion and restrict the pose outputs to a valid feasible region, which significantly improves training efficiency and localization accuracy compared to prior methods relying on attention-based fusion and direct 3-DoF pose regression. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first work to unify BEV semantic reasoning with homography learning for image-to-map localization. Furthermore, by explicitly modeling homography transformations, the proposed framework naturally supports cross-resolution inputs, enhancing model flexibility. Extensive experiments on the nuScenes dataset demonstrate that our approach significantly outperforms existing state-of-the-art visual localization methods. Code and pretrained models will be publicly released to foster future research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.02730v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xuchang Zhong, Xu Cao, Jinke Feng, Hao Fang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Overview of Prototype Formulations for Interpretable Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.08925</link>
      <description>arXiv:2410.08925v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Prototypical part networks offer interpretable alternatives to black-box deep learning models by learning visual prototypes for classification. This work provides a comprehensive analysis of prototype formulations, comparing point-based and probabilistic approaches in both Euclidean and hyperspherical latent spaces.
  We introduce HyperPG, a probabilistic prototype representation using Gaussian distributions on hyperspheres. Experiments on CUB-200-2011, Stanford Cars, and Oxford Flowers datasets show that hyperspherical prototypes outperform standard Euclidean formulations. Critically, hyperspherical prototypes maintain competitive performance under simplified training schemes, while Euclidean prototypes require extensive hyperparameter tuning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2410.08925v4</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Maximilian Xiling Li, Korbinian Franz Rudolf, Paul Mattes, Nils Blank, Rudolf Lioutikov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FedDUAL: A Dual-Strategy with Adaptive Loss and Dynamic Aggregation for Mitigating Data Heterogeneity in Federated Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.04416</link>
      <description>arXiv:2412.04416v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Federated Learning (FL) marks a transformative approach to distributed model training by combining locally optimized models from various clients into a unified global model. While FL preserves data privacy by eliminating centralized storage, it encounters significant challenges such as performance degradation, slower convergence, and reduced robustness of the global model due to the heterogeneity in client data distributions. Among the various forms of data heterogeneity, label skew emerges as a particularly formidable and prevalent issue, especially in domains such as image classification. To address these challenges, we begin with comprehensive experiments to pinpoint the underlying issues in the FL training process. Based on our findings, we then introduce an innovative dual-strategy approach designed to effectively resolve these issues. First, we introduce an adaptive loss function for client-side training, meticulously crafted to preserve previously acquired knowledge while maintaining an optimal equilibrium between local optimization and global model coherence. Secondly, we develop a dynamic aggregation strategy for aggregating client models at the server. This approach adapts to each client's unique learning patterns, effectively addressing the challenges of diverse data across the network. Our comprehensive evaluation, conducted across three diverse real-world datasets, coupled with theoretical convergence guarantees, demonstrates the superior efficacy of our method compared to several established state-of-the-art approaches.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2412.04416v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.DC</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Pranab Sahoo, Ashutosh Tripathi, Sriparna Saha, Samrat Mondal</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive Anomaly Recovery for Telemanipulation: A Diffusion Model Approach to Vision-Based Tracking</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.09632</link>
      <description>arXiv:2503.09632v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Dexterous telemanipulation critically relies on the continuous and stable tracking of the human operator's commands to ensure robust operation. Vison-based tracking methods are widely used but have low stability due to anomalies such as occlusions, inadequate lighting, and loss of sight. Traditional filtering, regression, and interpolation methods are commonly used to compensate for explicit information such as angles and positions. These approaches are restricted to low-dimensional data and often result in information loss compared to the original high-dimensional image and video data. Recent advances in diffusion-based approaches, which can operate on high-dimensional data, have achieved remarkable success in video reconstruction and generation. However, these methods have not been fully explored in continuous control tasks in robotics. This work introduces the Diffusion-Enhanced Telemanipulation (DET) framework, which incorporates the Frame-Difference Detection (FDD) technique to identify and segment anomalies in video streams. These anomalous clips are replaced after reconstruction using diffusion models, ensuring robust telemanipulation performance under challenging visual conditions. We validated this approach in various anomaly scenarios and compared it with the baseline methods. Experiments show that DET achieves an average RMSE reduction of 17.2% compared to the cubic spline and 51.1% compared to FFT-based interpolation for different occlusion durations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2503.09632v2</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haoyang Wang, Haoran Guo, Lingfeng Tao, Zhengxiong Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S2Vec: Self-Supervised Geospatial Embeddings for the Built Environment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.16942</link>
      <description>arXiv:2504.16942v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Scalable general-purpose representations of the built environment are crucial for geospatial artificial intelligence applications. This paper introduces S2Vec, a novel self-supervised framework for learning such geospatial embeddings. S2Vec uses the S2 Geometry library to partition large areas into discrete S2 cells, rasterizes built environment feature vectors within cells as images, and applies masked autoencoding on these rasterized images to encode the feature vectors. This approach yields task-agnostic embeddings that capture local feature characteristics and broader spatial relationships. We evaluate S2Vec on several large-scale geospatial prediction tasks, both random train/test splits (interpolation) and zero-shot geographic adaptation (extrapolation). Our experiments show S2Vec's competitive performance against several baselines on socioeconomic tasks, especially the geographic adaptation variant, with room for improvement on environmental tasks. We also explore combining S2Vec embeddings with image-based embeddings downstream, showing that such multimodal fusion can often improve performance. Our findings highlight how S2Vec can learn effective general-purpose geospatial representations of the built environment features it is provided, and how it can complement other data modalities in geospatial artificial intelligence.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2504.16942v2</guid>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3787217</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>ACM Transactions on Spatial Algorithms and Systems 2026</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Shushman Choudhury, Elad Aharoni, Chandrakumari Suvarna, Iveel Tsogsuren, Abdul Rahman Kreidieh, Chun-Ta Lu, Neha Arora</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learn2Reg 2024: New Benchmark Datasets Driving Progress on New Challenges</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.01217</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.01217v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Medical image registration is critical for clinical applications, and fair benchmarking of different methods is essential for monitoring ongoing progress in the field. To date, the Learn2Reg 2020-2023 challenges have released several complementary datasets and established metrics for evaluations. Building on this foundation, the 2024 edition expands the challenge's scope to cover a wider range of registration scenarios, particularly in terms of modality diversity and task complexity, by introducing three new tasks, including large-scale multi-modal registration and unsupervised inter-subject brain registration, as well as the first microscopy-focused benchmark within Learn2Reg. The new datasets also inspired new method developments, including invertibility constraints, pyramid features, keypoints alignment and instance optimisation.
  Visit Learn2Reg at https://learn2reg.grand-challenge.org.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.01217v3</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.59275/j.melba.2025-gc8c</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Machine.Learning.for.Biomedical.Imaging. 3 (2025)</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Lasse Hansen, Wiebke Heyer, Christoph Gro{\ss}br\"ohmer, Frederic Madesta, Thilo Sentker, Wang Jiazheng, Yuxi Zhang, Hang Zhang, Min Liu, Junyi Wang, Xi Zhu, Yuhua Li, Liwen Wang, Daniil Morozov, Nazim Haouchine, Joel Honkamaa, Pekka Marttinen, Yichao Zhou, Zuopeng Tan, Zhuoyuan Wang, Yi Wang, Hongchao Zhou, Shunbo Hu, Yi Zhang, Qian Tao, Lukas F\"orner, Thomas Wendler, Bailiang Jian, Christian Wachinger, Jin Kim, Dan Ruan, Marek Wodzinski, Henning M\"uller, Tony C. W. Mok, Xi Jia, Jinming Duan, Mikael Brudfors, Seyed-Ahmad Ahmadi, Yunzheng Zhu, William Hsu, Tina Kapur, William M. Wells, Alexandra Golby, Aaron Carass, Harrison Bai, Yihao Liu, Perrine Paul-Gilloteaux, Joakim Lindblad, Nata\v{s}a Sladoje, Andreas Walter, Junyu Chen, Reuben Dorent, Alessa Hering, Mattias P. Heinrich</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DiFlow-TTS: Compact and Low-Latency Zero-Shot Text-to-Speech with Factorized Discrete Flow Matching</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.09631</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.09631v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: This paper introduces DiFlow-TTS, a novel zero-shot text-to-speech (TTS) system that employs discrete flow matching for generative speech modeling. We position this work as an entry point that may facilitate further advances in this research direction. Through extensive empirical evaluation, we analyze both the strengths and limitations of this approach across key aspects, including naturalness, expressive attributes, speaker identity, and inference latency. To this end, we leverage factorized speech representations and design a deterministic Phoneme-Content Mapper for modeling linguistic content, together with a Factorized Discrete Flow Denoiser that jointly models multiple discrete token streams corresponding to prosody and acoustics to capture expressive speech attributes. Experimental results demonstrate that DiFlow-TTS achieves strong performance across multiple metrics while maintaining a compact model size, up to 11.7 times smaller, and enabling low-latency inference that is up to 34 times faster than recent state-of-the-art baselines. Audio samples are available on our demo page: https://diflow-tts.github.io.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.09631v3</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ngoc-Son Nguyen, Thanh V. T. Tran, Hieu-Nghia Huynh-Nguyen, Truong-Son Hy, Van Nguyen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CaTS-Bench: Can Language Models Describe Time Series?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.20823</link>
      <description>arXiv:2509.20823v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Time series captioning, the task of describing time series in natural language, requires numeric and temporal reasoning, trend interpretation, and contextual understanding. Existing benchmarks, however, often rely on fully synthetic or generic captions, and typically neglect metadata and visual representations. We introduce \textbf{CaTS-Bench}, a comprehensive benchmark for \textbf{C}ontext-\textbf{a}ware \textbf{T}ime \textbf{S}eries reasoning across $11$ diverse domains, centered on a gold-standard evaluation set of $1746$ human-rewritten captions that measure how effectively models translate numeric trends into immediately interpretable narratives. To address the scarcity of human-annotated data, we also propose a scalable pipeline for generating high-fidelity synthetic captions, the quality of which we validate. We evaluate leading Vision-Language Models on our benchmark, revealing that even proprietary models struggle to capture numeric nuances in temporal descriptions, while finetuning open-source models on synthetic data yields substantial performance gains. Finally, we release a diagnostic suite of $910$ multiple-choice questions and tailored numeric metrics to gauge time-series-specific reasoning capabilities, establishing CaTS-Bench as a reliable foundation for grounded, multimodal language generation in numeric domains.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2509.20823v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Luca Zhou, Pratham Yashwante, Marshall Fisher, Alessio Sampieri, Zihao Zhou, Fabio Galasso, Rose Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChartAgent: A Multimodal Agent for Visually Grounded Reasoning in Complex Chart Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.04514</link>
      <description>arXiv:2510.04514v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Recent multimodal LLMs have shown promise in chart-based visual question answering, but their performance declines sharply on unannotated charts-those requiring precise visual interpretation rather than relying on textual shortcuts. To address this, we introduce ChartAgent, a novel agentic framework that explicitly performs visual reasoning directly within the chart's spatial domain. Unlike textual chain-of-thought reasoning, ChartAgent iteratively decomposes queries into visual subtasks and actively manipulates and interacts with chart images through specialized actions such as drawing annotations, cropping regions (e.g., segmenting pie slices, isolating bars), and localizing axes, using a library of chart-specific vision tools to fulfill each subtask. This iterative reasoning process closely mirrors human cognitive strategies for chart comprehension. ChartAgent achieves state-of-the-art accuracy on the ChartBench and ChartX benchmarks, surpassing prior methods by up to 16.07% absolute gain overall and 17.31% on unannotated, numerically intensive queries. Furthermore, our analyses show that ChartAgent is (a) effective across diverse chart types, (b) achieves the highest scores across varying visual and reasoning complexity levels, and (c) serves as a plug-and-play framework that boosts performance across diverse underlying LLMs. Our work is among the first to demonstrate visually grounded reasoning for chart understanding using tool-augmented multimodal agents.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2510.04514v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CE</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>stat.ME</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rachneet Kaur, Nishan Srishankar, Zhen Zeng, Sumitra Ganesh, Manuela Veloso</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Vision Language Models Cross-Cultural Theory of Mind Reasoners?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.17394</link>
      <description>arXiv:2512.17394v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Theory of Mind (ToM) - the ability to attribute beliefs and intents to others - is fundamental for social intelligence, yet Vision-Language Model (VLM) evaluations remain largely Western-centric. In this work, we introduce CulturalToM-VQA, a benchmark of 5,095 visually situated ToM probes across diverse cultural contexts, rituals, and social norms. Constructed through a frontier proprietary MLLM, human-verified pipeline, the dataset spans a taxonomy of six ToM tasks and four complexity levels. We benchmark 10 VLMs (2023-2025) and observe a significant performance leap: while earlier models struggle, frontier models achieve high accuracy (&gt;93%). However, significant limitations persist: models struggle with false belief reasoning (19-83% accuracy) and show high regional variance (20-30% gaps). Crucially, we find that SOTA models exhibit social desirability bias - systematically favoring semantically positive answer choices over negative ones. Ablation experiments reveal that some frontier models rely heavily on parametric social priors, frequently defaulting to safety-aligned predictions. Furthermore, while Chain-of-Thought prompting aids older models, it yields minimal gains for newer ones. Overall, our work provides a testbed for cross-cultural social reasoning, underscoring that despite architectural gains, achieving robust, visually grounded understanding remains an open challenge.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2512.17394v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zabir Al Nazi, GM Shahariar, Md. Abrar Hossain, Wei Peng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WebGym: Scaling Training Environments for Visual Web Agents with Realistic Tasks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.02439</link>
      <description>arXiv:2601.02439v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We present WebGym, the largest-to-date open-source environment for training realistic visual web agents. Real websites are non-stationary and diverse, making artificial or small-scale task sets insufficient for robust policy learning. WebGym contains nearly 300,000 tasks with rubric-based evaluations across diverse, real-world websites and difficulty levels. We train agents with a simple reinforcement learning (RL) recipe, which trains on the agent's own interaction traces (rollouts), using task rewards as feedback to guide learning. To enable scaling RL, we speed up sampling of trajectories in WebGym by developing a high-throughput asynchronous rollout system, designed specifically for web agents. Our system achieves a 4-5x rollout speedup compared to naive implementations. Second, we scale the task set breadth, depth, and size, which results in continued performance improvement. Fine-tuning a strong base vision-language model, Qwen-3-VL-8B-Instruct, on WebGym results in an improvement in success rate on an out-of-distribution test set from 26.2% to 42.9%, significantly outperforming agents based on proprietary models such as GPT-4o and GPT-5-Thinking that achieve 27.1% and 29.8%, respectively. This improvement is substantial because our test set consists only of tasks on websites never seen during training, unlike many other prior works on training visual web agents.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2601.02439v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hao Bai, Alexey Taymanov, Tong Zhang, Aviral Kumar, Spencer Whitehead</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
